Yes,
yes.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight,
our first sponsor.
It's been so long. It's the best
thing to fuck Joe. Nowadays.
I think I've come to the conclusion
it is no more girls for you.
It's just now it's not the best sex toy.
It's the best thing.
That fuck period I think.
Wow, that's sad dude. Sorry to hear that.
If you go to [inaudible] dot net
and entering the code name Rogan,
you could save yourself 15% off the
number one sex toy for men. Right.
And then for one still it's a number
one for everything and it won't give you
any drama and we'll give you an
live drama. Nope. Hmm. All right.
We're also sponsored by on a.com that's
so o n n I t, makers of Alpha brain,
the cognitive enhancing supplement that
I will be giving Chell son and at the
end of this interview because
I suspect he will enjoy it. Uh,
if you are interested in nootropics,
I suggest just Google it.
Go to go to Google and typing in the
word nootropic and aerobic and what they
are essentially as nutrients that
enhance brain function. And a,
there's a lot of interesting studies on
them and there's a lot of controversy on
him. So make up your own mind
about it. But if you're interested,
please do your homework first.
Then once you've done that,
if you're interested in Alpha brain,
the way we have it set up,
I want to make sure that
nobody ever feels ripped off.
If you order the first 30
pills and you don't like it,
you don't even have to send it back.
You just say this stuff sucks and you get
a hundred percent money back guarantee.
That's cause I,
I want to,
it's much more important to me that
people don't feel ripped off than it is to
make money. And all this shit is stuff
that I've used before I ever endorsed it.
And it's all stuff that I've, uh, I've,
I've been using nootropics for a long
time now and I'm a firm believer in
vitamins and minerals and,
and you can read up all about the various
ingredients that are in Alpha brain on
on it. That's o n n I t.com. And go check
that out. Entering the code name Rogan.
Save yourself 10% off any and all
orders. All right, you dirty bitches.
Chael Sonnen is here.
We're going to get down to business.
We got a Goddamn American hero here folks.
How about some respect?
Hey Joe Rogan podcast by night.
Fucked up worries horse though,
man.
All respect to Roy MacDonald. We need
to get a better copy of that recording.
We can get one.
I'll get one from the UFC.
UFC pulled all the youtube
videos down with in minutes.
Oh, did they really? Yeah.
Well Ladies and gentlemen,
what is your new book called?
Voice of reason you're VIP pass
into enlightenment. Voice of reason.
The Voice of reason written by this
Guy [inaudible] your hair. I'm here.
And by the way,
on that commercial you just gave,
that has gotta be the single greatest
guarantee in the history of fair trade.
You don't even have to send it back.
You just call it your word. You Go,
listen man, this isn't working.
And they refund it. That's amazing.
We had to make it the first 30 pills,
cause the way we had it set up was,
you know, any order, you don't
even have to turn it back.
So then people started selling
it on Ebay. I'm like, all right,
well you can't be that on. Yeah,
it's like the IRS is basically,
you're counting on honesty. You're
counting not, it's for oversight.
But I like that. I mean I can
tell you from personal experience,
I want to do that. I mean,
if it didn't work, I want to,
I want to lie to keep a couple of
pills. And I think honestly, I like it.
That's all. I think if you have
a product and you believe in it,
you would want people to
buy it more than once.
Especially if it's something
like a vitamin supplement. Sure.
So I'm just letting them know you're
going to like it. It's, it fucking works.
It's a fascinating little, uh, you
ever get into vitamins, nootropics,
anything like that? Yes. Uh, in college
and uh, I was sick all the time.
I was getting sick three times a
month, even if it was for, you know,
a day or something. And my mom said, look,
you've got to get started
on a multivitamin.
Do you think this is also
because of wrestling? Like
you just, I think so. Yeah.
You're, you're kind of in a good petri
dish for sickness. You're malnourished,
your overtrain and you're not getting
enough sleep with all the road trips in
different time zones. Perfect.
Perfect. Petri dish to get ill.
And I started in a multivitamin
known as centrum complete,
which has less nutrients than dog food.
That's what my doctor told me.
But it worked for me. Those small
nutrients made a big difference.
So when I realized, Geez, I
haven't been sick in a year,
then I really started getting involved
and now I want some really good stuff.
You can't even buy over the counter.
You've got to have a doctor ordered a,
it's called Husana. It's
very powerful. Uh, you know,
4,000 milligrams of vitamin D
goes on and on a u s a n, a, Ooh,
sauna. Oussama and it's a combination
of vitamins. What happens?
Yeah, something just happened. Some short,
quick blurb. I get it too, but we're back.
Um, combination of vitamin A nation
of vitamins and minerals and it's,
you can't get it in a GNC or so you
can't not know. And you know, and again,
let me tell you, okay, most
vitamins are 10% effective,
90% marketing. We all know that
about nutrition, GNC type things.
The ones that really
work are 10% marketing,
90% goes into the lab and making them.
Now that very statement I just gave you
may in of itself be the marketing that
the people have put out. I don't know,
but that's what who's sauna is doing.
You can't buy it. You've
got to order it. Uh,
they don't have enough to mass produce
it because it's so potent and effective.
But I have had a number of doctors with,
with, with extensive reading and say,
listen, this is the one. So do you have
to, you don't have to have a prescription.
You can just order.
Probably not. Yeah, but you,
you just got to have a doctor's
office call up and you know,
an 800 a doctor's office has to call
them for you when they got to call it in
for you. You know, that's something
they tried to get going, uh, years back.
They tried to label vitamins
as nutraceuticals and then
you were going to have
it so that you needed a prescription
to get vitamins, which get,
it gets a little weird,
you know? I mean, I,
I would appreciate a little regulation
so we know exactly what the fuck is in
everything because right now it's,
it's a little wild west when it
comes to things like supplements.
But I just think that, uh, having to
go to a doctor to get some vitamin D,
that seems like that's, I don't, I
don't want that. Yeah, no, I hear you.
But that comes back to my point that it's,
you know, 10% effective, 90% marketing.
You know, how many things that
GNC are made in the same lab,
but they're packaged different.
Whoever can get the word out more and,
and I can tell you,
you know,
I've tried everything at Gnc on the off
chance that something might work. Um,
yeah,
I begged my dad to take me there when
I was 12 years old and whoever the most
muscle guy or whoever, the most
handsome guy, whatever it was,
that that attracts you when,
when you're vulnerable at that age.
That's what I'm begging.
My Dad had put 40 bucks down and buy me
the protein drink for, so I fall forward.
I mean, people, people always
fall for it, so, you know, yeah,
they don't have oversight.
It's, it's trial and error,
but what's not. Yeah. Yeah.
What isn't, it is, it is
kinda crazy. But there,
there were a few things
that actually did work,
but they got rid of him very quickly.
There was one called Mag
10 and it was Sunday.
They used to have to go into that little
glass cabinet with the key to open it
up. You couldn't even get it out of
the regular video game, right? Yeah.
You got to let them know like
you want it some porn, I mean,
I mean that's your porn was testosterone
pills and mag 10 was fucking real.
They got rid of it really quick.
You would take an absurd amount of pills.
I think it was like 10 pills.
There were these clear pills,
but you would tell you,
I don't know,
who knows what kind of fucking
damage did your liver, but oh my God.
You'd feel like a fucking raging
animal. Yeah. Oh, okay. Great.
Wow. Yeah. I gained a
lot of muscle on it, man.
I gained like 10 pounds of muscle on it
and like eight weeks and it was legal.
You could buy at a GNC,
you could do like six to eight week
cycles on it and it was such a steroid.
It was so obvious because as soon as
I got off at my Dick would just crash,
my body would crash. I was like,
wow. I was like, wow, this stuff,
even though it's something you buy at Gnc,
essentially it's just like
doing a steroid. Sure. So,
so essentially they discovered something
that the government had it yet and had
a man and they got it.
And you know that's going on.
There's a drug out there right now,
and I shouldn't call it a
drug because it's not, but
it's, it's a natural product,
a known as Kratom.
I don't know if you've heard about this,
but it is absolutely an opiate.
It's absolutely a painkiller.
And you know those drive through
espresso places that they've got,
we've got a place like that in Oregon
and the guy sells kratom and he makes 150
grand a year and it's completely legal.
The government has not caught on that.
This is a painkiller.
I mean you get a high, you get
a low, you've got to crash.
I got a buddy that's coming
off of painkillers. He got,
he got addicted to the Vicodin and what
he's doing is he's going to buy in this
Kratom for $10 a pill.
He buys five,
it cost him $50 he goes every Sunday
and when he shows up at 10:00 AM Joe,
there's a line waiting for this stuff.
It's a drug,
but it hasn't been found illegal yet.
And I'm saying that because the story
you just told about being able to buy a
steroid over the counter, people are
going to think that's not believable.
That happens all the time. The government
just hasn't caught on yet. Well,
they don't know that they
should. Well, I don't,
I think going to be able to like when
balco came out with that clear stuff that
declare, you know, clear, right? Yeah.
It was like somehow or
another they're undetectable.
You know how many more of those
or possibly out there. I mean,
how hard is it to do something like
that? Sure. Well I wouldn't know,
but from what I've told,
and I read about this stuff all the time,
is that if you simply get yourself
good chemist, he goes, any changes,
one molecule, one element, and all of
a sudden the strand is something else.
You've got your band list,
you change one molecule,
it doesn't fall into that category.
They're looking for things in that
category and they pass, you know,
it's Olympic year and we see this.
Every games where an entire country comes
out looking different than every other
athlete, the whole country looks
different. You're like, okay guys,
you're all looked at that.
That way.
This whole team has gotten this much
stronger and more shredded and times of
picked in everything from track
to pull Volta to, to swim.
Everybody's better from your country.
What are you doing?
And that the 10 years later you find out
and it gets added to the banned list.
It gets really creepy when you start
thinking about shit like cycling and you
see all these dudes getting convicted
and all these dudes turning on.
I had a friend who was a professional
cycler and he told me everybody was on
crazy shit. She said,
they all are. I said,
there's no way you can compete at that
level when you're talking cycling as a
professional site. Sure. And I'm thinking,
well, you're talking about, you know,
shooting up on and off of a
regulation. Okay. So we're talking,
we're talking cycling like the WWE or any,
any high level cycling, Lance Armstrong
type toward the front. Shit like you,
you almost have to be on something
to repeat. Yeah. You know, it's,
it's getting really weird when it comes
to those types of shirts and what about
when a guy gets caught and so then
instead of just going, yeah, listen,
I've got to take my medicine,
he got to bring everybody else down with,
he becomes the tattle and you know, you
know, come on, what's happening here Jose?
Because that's the way it works.
She got brought down,
you got [inaudible] going to take
your medicine by Jose can Cincos uh,
that whole book and Publishing and
telling how it was really going down.
You know what I mean? That really
cost him people's love. Sure.
Like for his whole life. Yeah. I, that
guy, if you ever read his Twitter,
this is not comfortable.
Right. And I never have, wow,
he's got some dark shit in there,
you know? But what it was like,
what he had money and now
that he's got nothing,
he knows what people are
really like and you know, it's,
it's pretty dark and it all,
a lot of it.
The hate that this guy gets emanates in
the fact that he ratted out his friends.
Sure. I think there's something
to that, you know? I really do.
I mean I even as a kid, nobody likes
a tattletale. Nobody likes though.
He was telling the truth.
Yeah,
I did see a lot of stuff that he did
with his book and I did find it to be
pretty genuine. I tend to believe a lot of
people go, oh, he's an admitted cheater.
How can you believe it was like, man,
thanks for being pretty candid right now.
I do believe him.
Well when we start seeing guys like Mark
Mcguire's shrink down right after he's
done playing,
you know,
and then admit that he was on steroids or
you see Barry bonds and how big he got.
And then it's almost like, man, how,
how much regulation do we really
need of the human body? You know,
what does w what, what the fuck is
wrong with what Barry Bonds did?
What he took something that made
them stronger. You know, it wouldn't,
it shouldn't we be interested in
stuff that makes you stronger.
It makes you healthier. When you look at
a guy like Barry bonds, like that guy,
he looks like he was 30 years old. They
got better when he was older, you know,
as a, as a professional
baseball player. That's amazing.
It shouldn't that be something that we
would like look into and say that's a
good thing.
You know,
don't you want Roger Clemens
to keep throwing fucking
heat deep into his forties
like why would you want to stop that?
Sure. But don't mix the argument. I mean,
of course we love medicine and
advancements and that's wonderful,
but if you're talking about rules within
a sport and you want to just keep it
out for whatever reason,
but if that is the decision
that we're going to keep it out,
well then the guy can't bring it
in and cheat and lie about it.
I think that was the debate. But
I hear what you're saying. I mean,
if it is making people
healthier and better than good
for them, and by all means,
we should advance knowledge
and technology in that area.
But that doesn't mean that it's okay for
sport that's up to the governing bodies.
Right. But I mean, that's what's
going on in California. They just, um,
recently ruled on testosterone
replacement surgery, or excuse me,
a testosterone replacement therapy and,
uh,
also a medical marijuana and they ruled
positive on both those things. Sure.
And if you're, you're doing testosterone
replacement and you know, that,
isn't that essentially the same thing? And
it's essentially the same thing as, uh,
doing, uh, you know,
human growth hormone or anything
or anything along those lines.
They're doing something
to stop the aging process.
You're doing something to enhance the
hormonal balance of your body. Well,
it's been deemed legal then, so it
shouldn't be an issue. Right. Well,
look, if it's legal or illegal is where
it all comes into play. You know, I,
I can tell you I went through this in
California and they're acting as though
they're just made it legal.
That's not true. It's always
been legal here. Uh, their,
their commissioners. Did it
always recognize it. You know,
I went through this in California with a,
what was the official designation that
they recently just bestowed on? It would,
it would allow a disclosure process here,
let,
let me talk about myself because I was
such an expert on this cause I had to go
through it. I go out, I tell
him I'm on testosterone. I say,
can I compete in your state
while on testosterone? And
that's what you gotta do.
You gotta get permission? Yes, go
ahead. So I do it. I take my tests,
they coming back and they say, hey,
you're on testosterone. Well guys,
you didn't need a urine test. I told
you that well in advance in writing.
And you told me I could be on
testosterone. They go, well we don't,
we don't like this, but you made the
rules and you told me I could do it.
So it just ended up in this really
weird area where they said, okay,
but you didn't disclose it properly.
And they started changing.
The argument just got really weird too
where we could never narrow him down.
So they finally come to some resolution
within their own body and you know,
in the state of California, and I don't
want to turn on throw stones at them.
I want to be pretty diplomatic with
them, but look, they are not transparent.
And for you and I to two experts and
authorities in this sport to still not be
completely clear on what their ruling was,
I think speaks to their
lack of transparency.
And if they don't want people to keep
stubbing their and breaking rules,
just make it clear so that
we know what the rules are.
It seems like they're dipping
their feet in the water. To me,
they constantly do that so that
they can then pull back out and go,
that's not what we said. Yeah, it
seems tough. It seems weird. Well,
I mean they're in a tough position too.
It's a pretty thankless job to be the
head of an athletic commission and there's
very few guys that do it and do
it really well. But um, you know,
it's not an easy job trying
to figure out what's fair,
trying to figure out what the playing
field is. Especially a science
and medicine advances.
You know,
I liked the idea of a guy
like Roger Clemens being
able to play baseball because
he's taking, taking human growth
hormone and doing testosterone.
It doesn't bother me.
Like it's really sucks that this guy
that he can't actually just say that he
can't just do that. Especially in a sport
like baseball where I mean what, what,
how's it going to hurt somebody? I
mean even if he is enhanced, it's,
he's not going to hurt somebody.
That's where it gets weird like an MMA.
That's like the weird, we're the
real questions in MMA. It's like,
I mean if you really have something in
your body that makes you like hyper human,
you have like hyper human levels,
which people can do if they, you know,
if they use testosterone replacement
or something else on ethics.
Sure. You know, I'll tell you
Joe, one thing I admire about you,
you are oddly comfortable
in your own skin. You know,
you'd have no problem admitting anything
and being a real open book and, and, and,
and so I think that's one reason why you
can't relate to Roger Clemens is cause
a, you know, you're like, look, this
is who I am and this is what I do.
But that's a very rare trait. You
possess that. But not a lot of people do.
Everybody's got their secrets
not to necessarily on this topic,
but another things of their
life where they keep it private.
I think this is your rare,
this is a weird thing where yeah,
you know, his sport does not
allow you to do that to your body,
but I think it's a silly argument when
you're looking at a guy who's an older
man, like he is your like, how else do
you expect him to be able to do that?
Do you know anything about the, how
the body ages? Because guess what,
a certain point in time his body
doesn't recover enough anymore.
He can't throw the heat, but now he
can. He can because he takes this stuff.
Isn't that stuff. It doesn't that
mean it's like good for you, isn't it?
I'm like good for him.
Like shouldn't he be looking at it that
way so that it's such a weird fucking
narrow band of like what is, what
is cheating? You know, what is,
what is legal? What do we allow? Well
it's going to be a certain point in time.
Are they going to start genetic
engineering and what do you, what,
what is everybody going to do?
There's going to be a fucking pill
that take and it turns you into Thor.
You know, what are you going to
do? Are you going to not take it?
Why would you not want
to be like a superhero?
If I could give you a pill and it lets
you fucking fly through the air and
become bulletproof, you wouldn't
take it. Of course he would take it.
It would be amazing. No, I like
your argument. You know, and again,
it's Olympic year.
Olympics are my favorite sport.
I don't watch professional sports,
but I love every four year was
when the games come around.
So you might hear me reference that a
few times today. But you know, listen,
the athletes used to be done at
23 years old. That was 23 was it?
If you made 2121, that's usually no, you
know, look at the last games in Beijing.
We had Dara Torres who was 40 years old.
We're going to have 40 year old athletes
on our Olympic team this year vying for
metals. And that's a tremendous
compliment to medicine.
That's a tremendous compliment
to technology and what
we're discovering here in
America and abroad.
And then not label it,
don't label it as drugs or label it as
cheating. Look at the fucking advancement.
Look at what, what could, what's happened.
Sure. Well, and it's real interesting,
you know, because the only time you're
in hot water as if it's a banned list,
but you know, that's junk science
and it changes constantly.
Things that weren't our legal, that
are legal aren't legal, you know,
in testosterone replacement. Boy that's
just got such a, a bullseye on it,
but there's a number of
performance enhancing, uh,
agents that are perfectly legal and a,
you know,
you've got to still be within your limits.
Caffeine comes to mind.
As a matter of fact,
you know,
you want your caffeine levels as high as
you can get prior to competition in my
opinion. You know, I can tell you
for my body that's when I do my best.
But you still gotta be within the law
and there's a lot of things like that.
What's the legal limit? Is like a cup
of coffee. Yeah. Essentially, you know,
if you're in a poor compared to no dose,
which is something you can buy
at a local convenience store,
you can take two of them. Is that how
you do it? Do you regulate it that way?
That's how I rate just cause
there's no problems. If you do that,
it stays in your system about four hours.
You'll get it within that,
but you're fine. But coffee can
vary wildly. It absolutely canyon.
And there there's people that say,
and I'll listen to it and
they'll block you an athlete.
A lot of fans don't know this.
When you go in the locker room,
you cannot have anything other
than a closed bottle of water.
They want to see you open it and the
reason they're just trying to protect you.
If you go in there with a coffee and I'll
bring in there five hours before your
fight, you come in there
with some kind of a drink.
It could have something that you
don't know about. But you know,
I mean the caffeine caffeine
is just one that I mentioned,
but there's a number of
performance enhancing things.
And if a guy takes the time and get
surrounded with the right people that look
into that, cause often it's overlooked.
But you know, supplements, diet, vitamins,
as we talked about earlier, these
are, this is a very important element.
And have a guy inundates himself and
finds where his level should be and he's
legal.
Then he's legal good for him.
And so many people want to point a finger
and say there's something wrong, bad.
But there's not. And the
science continually change
continually junk science.
You can't get,
you bring five doctors in your jail,
you get five different opinions.
And you know what?
It's also assuming that nature's fair,
which I think is ridiculous.
There are some people that are fucking
incredible genetics and there's some
people that literally can't compete
with them. Absolutely can't.
They just physically can't
compete with them. You,
we both know guys who have
been non athletes that have
tried to wrestle or tried
to and they just couldn't do it. There's
guys that are born with freak bodies.
You know, there's, there's
guys that are without a doubt,
they're gifted genetically. You know what
I mean? That's, that's not fair either.
You know, it should we round people
up by genetically, you know, how,
what's their disposition should we,
I mean cause if you really want to
look at it like what's fair? Sure.
Like it is not fair that,
you know,
you can get a guy like what's his
name? Jonah Hill. Yeah. Right.
And a guy like Melvin man of exactly.
Jon Jones.
There's no way you can tell me that
those dudes have the the same hand. Sure.
Someone, someone got fucked. Yeah. Yeah.
The guy and the guy that you want to
win is whoever worked the hardest show.
The most dedication has the best
skills and that is a fallacy.
Some guys will be born with a better
skillset than other guys will be able to
learn over a lifetime. They just are, you
know, you see it with speed, you see it,
what the ability to jump you see,
and it's just a natural thing.
There's some guys that will
take testosterone and still
have a lower level than
a guy that was just gifted with
it and you see it all the time.
So I get your point.
Yeah.
It's not a fair playing field and the
ideas that your mind can allow you to
overcompensate or to overcome the
disparaging genetics. You know,
your mind and strategy is important.
Just as important as being physical.
But that's always assuming that big
strong people are dumb. And guess what?
A lot of them aren't sure.
A lot of those big, strong,
naturally gifted motherfuckers are
also really quick and they think quick.
You know, I mean, look
at a guy like Mike Tyson.
People would always talk about how,
you know, Mike Tyson wasn't bright.
My Mike Tyson was a fucking boxing
historian and maybe he wasn't educated,
but he figured out the best style
for his body. He figured out how to,
how to break a man down.
He figured out how to put up a pace that
other guys just couldn't deal with and
if you could just punch
faster and everybody else
could that no one could fuck
with them. He, he
figured all that. That's,
that's there's a intelligence to that
to get excellent at anything requires an
intelligence.
That's what's really scary about a gin
genetically gifted guy versus they could
easily be really smart.
Bert sugar just touched on that same
topic with Mike Tyson and he said,
he is very smart. He goes, I'm not saying
he's intelligent, I'm calling him smart.
He's very smart and I don't personally
know what the distinction is that he was
getting at. I think it meant, you know,
some of the bad decisions that, that,
that Tyson made around tech. Have you seen
Tyson, by the way? The show, you know,
he's doing this spirit of I heard it's
amazing. Do you know anything about it?
I have. No, nothing gets up and tell
stories. I got to tell you one story.
So let me set the scene real fast.
Dana white went and saw this.
Dana got invited and Mike or Buddy,
so Dana, you know, he's backstage,
she's having a great time.
All it is is Mike Tyson goes out,
he's got a microphone.
He tells stories of his life and they've
got to production. So if he says,
you know, Don King and a story, boom,
don king's face pops up behind
them on a big movie screen.
So he's telling this story and he's to
brings up the Robin givens era where you
know where he's beaten Robin givens and
he's doing these horrible things to her
and he's going,
listen,
the one thing Robin never told anyone
is that I was seeing her the whole time,
you know, the whole time we
were still seeing each other.
Now he didn't use the word scene.
I'm sure you can fill in the blank,
but he's seen her the whole
time. So he says, you know,
one morning at 1:00 AM I drive
over to Robin givens house,
my mansion that I bought her
that I'm not allowed to go to.
And I'm ringing the doorbell.
And this isn't all that uncommon cause
I do this a lot except today she doesn't
come to the door. So he says,
I'm walking around the house,
I'm looking in the windows.
About 15 minutes later I see her pulling
up the driveway in a Bentley that I
bought her that I'm not allowed to drive.
So she's driving my car,
she's coming to my mansion. It's one in
the morning. She gets out of the car,
she brought someone home with her.
So she brought a guy home to see her
into my mansion in my car that I'm not
allowed to be at.
And when the guy gets out of the car,
do you want to know who it is?
And on the screen up pop's Brad Pitt.
He was a waiter and she
picked him up that night.
His before he ever made it into the
movies. So Brad Pitt sitting there going,
hey man,
hey buddy.
You know I don't really know much about,
I know who you
are.
We joke we were going to watch some TV
man and my Tyson says I could kill you
right now. And nobody would. And uh, Tyson
walked away. Then he did the right thing,
got this car and he walked away.
But how great is that story?
That's a great story. Shit, Brad
Pitt, but he gets somewhere,
his production crew found an old
picture of Brad Pitt. You know,
some of them are out there where he's in
the chicken suit somewhere in la trying
to make it. It was one of those old school
pictures before he ever got his break.
Robyn brought him home to Mike
Tyson's house. Terrifying.
That must have been Jesus
k, man. Let's be cool,
man.
Isn't it
[inaudible] that someone
can get married to someone?
Just marry someone really rich for a
couple of years and you can just get
fucking paid.
You can just get fucking paid.
If a girl can do that, a girl can
meet a guy like Mike Tyson truck.
I'm getting Merriam,
manipulate them. Ropa man.
Ride it for a few years
and then just hurried
the rewards and in this era of reality TV,
we all know when that's happening.
It's just the guy does like do this.
Chris Humphrey really think he was in a
real relationship. I mean, God bless him.
I hate to see that he got his heartbreak,
but I'm watching it from my couch on
a biweekly basis when the girlfriend's
forcing me, I'm like, Chris,
this isn't an actual romance man.
This isn't how this works.
Do you really think you're
getting married to Kim here?
I think he thought it was real.
The whole rest of the world's going,
you gotta be kidding me? Well, he
would say insulting shit to her
that you should never take from a meat.
You know,
he said something and I, I was on a
soup with Joel Mchale, that's his name.
Oh yeah. Funny, funny guy, but very
funny guy. And he's got this, um,
uh, the sketch they're doing about Kim
Kardashian and Chris Humphreys. He said,
why would you care? You know, he said
something, they're like on the air, like,
why would you care in
a few years from now,
no one's going to care about you
anymore anyway. Oh, you know. Yeah.
And everybody clapped and we laughed
and I cried for fake, for TV,
but for real life. I look
at it and I go, well man,
could you imagine saying that to
your friend the way it can't move?
That would be to say to your friend, if
my friend said that to me, I'd be like,
bitch, what the fuck am I
doing hanging around with you?
I would cut that guy out of my life
instantly cause I'm not capable of saying
something like that. To a friend
and that's accurate, mean spirited,
but it might not even be accurate,
but who the fuck would have figured
out that you'd be able to do what she's
doing right now? That girls making
$60 million, whatever, a year. I mean,
it's incredible how you with
what he's going to see that the,
that she's not gonna be able to figure
out how to ride the tide. Maybe she can,
maybe she can stupid. She
already dead. Sure. Look what
she did. I mean, it's, look,
she's no genius,
but there is genius in what she's done.
This genius in making a living
by just being a person. Yeah.
Slowly. It's very rare. I
mean, you see it all the time.
A America always has to have somebody.
It's usually some famous blonde.
She pulled it off as a, as a Brunette.
You know, she was at your Pam Anderson's,
you're Marilyn Monroe's.
Well she also pulled it off
with them. Fuck table. The
black dude. Yeah. Very powerful. I've
heard that. Get out of here. You heard.
I don't know much about that,
but I, well speaking of Ya,
and it wasn't the gentleman involved, but
you know, Reggie Bush was at the last,
UFC was kind of, Bush has my
car supporting him. Right.
The second he's literally in your car.
I sold my Barracuda and the owner that a,
I sold it to sold to Reggie Bush. Well
that sounds like that's his car. You,
you do know how the sale works.
Well, it was my car should say,
I should have phrased it better.
I apology you got me. Uh, he,
I had a 1970 barracuda or wish
them luck with that fucking thing.
We need to be clear.
You've got to,
you've got a lot of tough guys as friends
and I see Reggie Bush rolling around
that common, I go take it back and honor
you. But now that I know it's okay.
It was a fair sale and he's got
the title then. Not only that,
it was Easter Bush hands with him and I
would change hands with him. Yeah, he was,
uh, he was dating Kim Cardiac. And I
know this. Why do I know this? I have no,
not who the president of Poland is.
I've no idea.
But yet I know who Kim Kardashian was
dating before she married this other
fellow and I'm doing my best to act
like I barely watch that show. But yeah,
I knew I didn't know it too.
I guess I should be ashamed as well.
Well you are so good at
promoting a online and,
and promoting and interviews.
Have you ever thought about doing some
sort of a limited version of a reality
show? Not too intrusive. I
never had, I appreciate the
compliment. No, I never have.
You know,
reality TV is still pretty new and does
some generations they don't know that.
Um, I, you know, I like it. I'm
a big Fan, but uh, you know,
I got asked to do the ultimate fighter,
our reality show in our,
in our industry and I just passed
it. Just want to coach, you know,
I love coaching.
I coach a kid.
See what I didn't want to do is go to
Vegas for five weeks and now with the new
format of live every Friday night
on FX there. It's a 13 week process.
That's what Dominic and your I are
going through. That's a long time.
It's a long time. You know the little
thing, chunks of your soul in that place.
For example, I have a dog.
I can't bring them to,
what am I going to put them in Vegas?
Is Dana going to get me a yard somewhere?
You know,
it's kind of too much to ask of any,
but I can't go 13 weeks without
the little guy. He'd forget.
Why was the smartest dog?
That's cute.
What kind of dogs are cute? It is. Please
say poodle. I love the, I love dog.
He's a rescue dog. He's a
terrier. He's, he's a a mix.
I actually don't know what completely is.
He's a cute dog is what he is.
Three years,
so you wouldn't,
I mean you could get a place you
could rent a place with a yard.
I guarantee you he's probably some fancy
schmancy high roller gambler type dude.
That would love to rent his house out
to chill son and for a couple months.
All right,
well well there you go.
Then maybe I will coach the reality
show after all you've saved.
That would be fun to watch. I'll tell
you that. Yeah, I appreciate that.
I think there's some,
you know,
I think that show picks up the one
problem I have with the show because there
was some reality TV I like for example,
big brother I got pretty into,
there was this crazy guy in their name
will for one season if you ever wash it.
I'm not seeing any nods.
I'm assuming nobody said he was fantastic.
It's absolutely fantastic cause he'd
go into the dark room and he would just
tell the truth. You know, I'm,
I'm going to tell this girl this and I'm
going to stab her in the back on Friday
and I have not even in Cleveland, the
bloody mass, you know, it was, it was,
he would say these crazy things and
then he would do it and then he won the
whole show.
At any rate,
the problem the ultimate fighter
has is they put them in teams,
but there is no team. And so,
you know, they'll go have a, uh,
the team will do a fight and if your
team wins, you need to win something.
You know, on the apprentice with
Donald Trump, if your team wins, boom,
you get a night out to dinner,
you know, or whatever it is.
Are you going to go meet with this guy?
You all get some money.
There's no team concept.
Why am I cheering for my opponent?
I want whoever the toughest guy is.
Well,
there's a my team or their team to lose
and then I want the next toughest guy to
lose.
I am in this to win this for myself.
And it's really important that
those guys start to get that. Uh,
and so they either need to do with the
team concept or they need to have a team
reward.
So there's a reason you would cheer for
one side or the other at this point.
There's no point.
So they just, just camaraderie
for the sake of camaraderie.
Right. And then as, as the numbers
dwindle down, now all of a sudden, hey,
you were on this guy's team,
now you over here.
And they mix it up and I'm
a supporter of our show.
The last thing I'm trying to do is,
is put down the show.
But I mean from a critical standpoint,
I'd like to see a reason to cheer for
a specific team or just don't even put
them in.
It's just fun because
the guy who's the coach,
I mean especially this one right now it's
going on with Uriah and Dominick Cruz.
What I like about is they're constantly
talking shit to each other and it's just
another way to try to win. Just another
way to try to win with a team. You know?
And people love to be a part of teams,
man, they like to pick team window. So No,
I'm on team mapple you know, people
love that. I'm a, I only get droids,
I'm sure I liked a droid platform.
You know,
people love to be on teams for soccer,
but I hear the ice cream sandwiches,
the share. Actually I saw, have you
seen the, what is it? The note? Yeah.
It's amazing how easy that
is. Like this big, I love it.
How much you want to urinate?
Chell son in jail, son is healthy.
That motherfucker drinks water.
Drink a gallon a day.
I'm sure Mike Dolce by what? By
the way. Just texted me. Yeah,
go right down there to the left.
Mike Dolce who's a fitness expert who
was a former fighter and a professional
bodybuilder I think at one point in time
where power lift or something like that.
Super Smart Dude when
it comes to nutrition.
So he's going to come on the podcast
and I'm going to have your diet
straightened down. Canyon mine. I need
to address a certain issues with you.
We're going to get you on all
vegetables from now on and uh,
and do some animals last night,
which he,
I had foie gras and and s for the only,
for a couple more weeks in California.
I know, but this place I went to,
it was called animal and
I highly recommend it's in
Hollywood and it's just kind
of all every single crazy, they had
veal brains. They had, they had,
you know, pig slice, pig head. I don't
even know what that is. My uncle,
he used to cook lamb brains. He used to
cook it on the grill with brains taste.
It doesn't seem like a good idea.
He brands, right. I was okay.
It was a really inexpensive, you
know, it was, it's like peasant food.
It was peasant food and then it becomes
slowly, it became like
sort of chic, you know,
fascinating that you're eating organs
and brains and stuff like that. But uh,
it wasn't the, it's not the best tasting
stuff, but fog wise, that's amazing.
Come here, take the her right
before it's about to get band. Yeah.
I took Brian to this place, nor that's
right down the street. And they have a,
they have a full law there for
only two more weeks. This mother,
he's silly pitches. You silly
liberals. What have you done?
You got rid of the best tasting food.
You're going to kill the doc that do you
really care if someone overstuffed this
doc before you kill it? The
you even watched the videos.
They ever see them. Oh,
force feed a doc. They
take the dock, they stick.
It's stupid head under this faucet.
They pour some grain down its
throat and then they pull it off.
It takes five seconds and you
think that that's terrible.
That's terrible to an animal that you're
going to kill and eat. Really it's,
it takes five, 10 seconds is not
screaming in pain. It's, it's for a human.
It would totally suck to have
of food shoved down your throat,
but they have a completely different
capacity, like absorbed grains and stuff.
I mean it makes their, their liver swell
up. It's like it's not good for them,
but it makes delicious food.
Is there a humane way to do it?
Like is there five or 10
seconds a day if that, you know,
it's quick, really quick, man. I've
watched him do it. It's ridiculous.
They take the thing, the
the, this is what we do.
We grab him by the neck and you'd stick
its mouth on it and they get sort of
used to it after awhile.
They just,
they just kind of like stat there that
they pump grain down their throat and
then they let them go and then
they're done for the rest of the day.
They wander around eventually
they gonna fucking kill them.
I mean that's why they raised him.
I mean he'd say,
what are we going to slowly
regulate that away? I mean it's not,
this is not real cruelty.
Veal to me is far more cruel and legal
and I'm more attached to veal because
it's a mammal. I don't give
a fuck about ducks. You know,
if you'd take a duck and you stick it
in there and you fill it full of grain.
I don't feel bad. I don't
ducks. I don't really like them.
I'm not like a fan of docs. I don't
know how to fail at any birds. I don't,
I don't really feel like any
affection for birds, but animals I do.
So we can do that for a little baby cows
and bend them up and feed him milk and
keeping the dark and they
never get to move around.
Legal fills a tough thing and I'm a,
I really like veal,
but if you see how that's
tough, it is tough. After
that, once you, once you know,
you know, I tend to agree with where
you're at because I'm from the country,
I'm from far. I see. And I
see this stuff all the time.
People are just trying to get
by and support their families,
but I am surprised to see you take that
stance. I'm very impressed by that.
I didn't know you had an open mind. I
thought you were. You were narrowed in.
I've misread GI Joe. What did you
think? I was like narrowly hippie style.
Very liberal. I heard that you
moved to Colorado at one point.
What's Joe doing there? That's a, I
told him I don't really, Oh, you know,
that's where I really learned to not like
hippies when I lived in boulder. The,
that's when the reality of
the hippie truly set in. You
know? It's like if you're,
if you're around hippies,
it least seven out of 10 of them are not
going to have their shit together. Sure.
Seven out of 10 of them are always going
to need to borrow sugar and you know,
send out a 10 and
park. Their car breaks down. They
need to borrow yours. They're just,
they just can't quite fucking get
it together. Well, you know, the,
the ECO movements, a tough movement
because if you go all the way with that,
if you go all in, you've got to start
killing people. You're anti human, right?
Because the humans,
the only thing that hurts the environment,
the craziest parasite of all time,
right?
We're sucking all the
fish out of the ocean.
They say within like a
hundred or something years,
it'd be no more wild fish in the
ocean. I mean, it's incredible.
So we're sucking all this and then
we're throwing all our trash in there.
So this is gigantic,
like island of floating plastic as big
as Texas in the middle of the Pacific.
And it gets bigger every day.
Mean we're crazy.
If you look at us from like if you were
an alien species and you were observing
earth, you believe it. We at
this one thing just fucking
everything up. Wow. Yeah,
for sure. If you really want it to go
eco, you'd have to start killing people.
You'd have to shut down power.
Everybody gets a bike either at you take
a bike there or that's it and hopefully
you don't get stuck somewhere north.
He didn't build your stupid house
somewhere where it fucking phrases in the
winter. Cause if you did well, guess
what? That's just where you are.
That's where you're going
to be walking around now.
And I hope your food supply last I
hope is plenty of animals around you.
You've got to make sure you keep them
coming because you know you don't have
cars anymore.
Stupid cars are bad for the environment.
I'm glad that you recognize
that though. It'd be, you know,
cause I hear this Eco Freako talk
all the time. It's like, you know,
be real careful because you're anti human.
If you know,
if you want to go all the way with that
and most topics that you get passionate
about,
you know,
I've got this one that chain himself
to a tree to stop construction,
gets pretty whack on. It's like, you know,
make sure what you recognize you're
turning on us and choosing us over a plant
that, you know, make, make sure that you
at least acknowledge that. Yeah. Well I,
you know,
my issue that I've always had with uh,
like people who are not just vegetarians
and vegans but are really kind of
aggressive about it and the way they
fuck with you. Sure. You know, you know,
hey man,
I just want you to reconsider.
I just want you to think about what you're
doing. You're killing life too stupid.
I fucking love plants.
They're beautiful and gorgeous and you
have to kill acres of them every year
just to keep your stupid fucking
fat face alive. All right.
That's an animal that's rather,
that's a life form that is light your
eating life, you're eating plant life.
You know, you can't get by without eating
the life, right? Life eats life, period.
So shut the fuck up.
I got a chapter in my book on this very
topic about cutting down trees and it's
like, listen, the older and bigger
the tree, the better with me.
If you're going to cut it
down, you know, let it go,
let it make some sunlight and let a
couple of new trees pop up. But you know,
that's the way that it works.
And we use those trees and we build
our houses and paper and then it's a,
it's an absolute necessity, but those are
here for us, not the other way around.
And uh, you know, you hear
these Eco Freekeh is, you know,
of course they only come out when CNN
or some local camera crew is there.
It's often about them not
about the environment.
And that's where a real frustration
comes in. But I hear what you're saying.
You know, in fact, we were talking
about Kardashians a minute ago.
Somebody just recently threw flour or
something on her over in England and yeah,
she's pressing
charges, you know, it's like, hey, there's
other ways to do it. You know, one of the,
anything you do needs to be nonviolent.
If there's anything we learned from
Gandhi or Martin Luther King, it's,
you don't come around using
violence to get your attention.
And that's where the Unabomber went
off course when people were a spraying
people's fur coats with red
paint. Sure. You know, I mean,
come on man. Now you now,
yeah,
you assaulted someone and this very thing,
one of the resources of that
animal's body is now you.
You fucked it up and I ruined it. And
people quit listening to your argument.
What you do that list I'm out.
They listened to your argument and you
have made that animal's death really kind
of worthless now because they're going to
have to throw this coat away cause you,
you spray paint in it like a fucking
asshole and it's, it's ridiculous point.
Now they're going to have
to go get another one to
replace that one. So, right.
The punishment becomes the crime. I get
it. While the whole thing is stupid,
it's stupid to try to enforce your
opinions so, so aggressively with paint,
you know, that's a salt. You're
a, you're a fucking asshole.
You'd been asked no matter what side
of the argument you were on. Sure.
You pick the side and you went full
asshole with that argument. Well, you, uh,
you know, you run out and try
to assault Ted Nugent. You know,
it's like that kind of Shit, you know,
it's like, oh, he likes to shoot animals.
Well, why don't you go down to the
fucking one, go down to the butcher, go,
go down in that place where
a thousand cows a day,
I have to stick their head into a metal
trap and a fucking pissed and slams
through their head. Go after them.
Go, go. What are you saying? You know,
you're saying that we should,
every animal that's ever lived,
she just live forever and take over
the earth. This is stupid, right?
You got to eat some of them. It's the
food chain. It's natural selection.
There's no,
there's no way around it.
And unless you want wild predators roaming
around, keeping them populations down,
you're going to have to fucking kill them.
So few people understand that.
They say they don't understand
how important hunting is
for population control.
They don't understand how important
it is for traffic safety. Sure.
The people who don't live in rural
areas don't. I drove home once,
I had a Gig in western Massachusetts and
I was living in New York and you have
to drive down,
I forget the name of the Turnpike,
but I had to go 2030 miles an hour cause
deer would just tart in front of the
car in front of the car. I mean,
it was an infestation. I mean,
I've never seen anything like it since.
I might've seen two,
300 deer and a knife driving down
this road. It losing incredible.
Maybe I'm exaggerating. Let's say 50
deal. Let's say 20 dear. If I saw 20 beer,
I'd be shocked. So a lot of fucking
cheer. I saw them all over three dear.
Most people can't relate to that.
You know,
and that's where our votes come from
is the city. And it's like, man,
you've got to listen to these folks in
the country that are dealing with these
actual things. Those things can fuck
your car up, man. Real dangerous.
People die all the time.
This are fucking wild video.
Recent one of a kid who's on a motorcycle,
he's going to 80 plus miles an hour and
he hits a deer and somehow or another he
hits it perfect. Dead on so he
doesn't even lose control of the bike.
He just went boom and the raw,
he pulls his bike over and his friend
comes over. He's like, do you go to died?
You could have died.
Did you just see what that,
he goes back and the deer is
just cut in half and you know,
he literally like the deer exploded
on impact. That is amazing.
I have not seen that as absolutely.
I mean I'm glad. Pretty wild.
I thought that's what you're going to say.
No, I don't want to even waiver. I mean,
he didn't even lose control. It was like,
like he was, if I ever lost narrowed by,
I didn't have like a saw.
You're saying basically and
at 80 fucking miles an hour,
he's the one time speeding.
Saves a motorcyclist and
Iraq. Yeah, no kidding. Yeah,
that'd be interesting to talk to. Talk
to a physicist and he was slowed down.
What would have happened? What have we not
cut it in half? It would have been him.
I Dunno, we'll because he hasn't like 80
miles and I was like, oh bullet. You know,
just being to run right into that
just probably just exploded. Well,
but the kid lived and there was another
video of a guy and it's another helmet
cam. Same thing. And another one where a
guy on a motorcycle hits the, a a deer,
but he loses the bike and he was in,
it was,
he was wearing like
full leathers with pads,
like racing shit where they have like a,
those really hard plates in the money.
And he got up and he was fine. And uh,
you know, and it was like telling people,
look, this is the reason why
you need to wear all this shit.
Cause something like this can happen
and this just saved my life. Sure.
But it's a you, oh that's a
video. It's about 30 seconds.
Zen when he hits the deer.
Wow. See that was, that was it.
Oh you're kidding me. No
back it up a little. Wow.
He does keep control of
that bike. Yeah. Well he,
he's a good fucking rider till you could
totally tell because he didn't lose it
at all. He's a bad motherfucker.
Cause when that deer hits him,
he has a little jiggly moments.
He that and see that little Gigli moment
going 80 fucking miles an hour he hit
to do it. This is the
Admin, the flats. Well,
people, uh, I mean, did this go viral?
That people probably know
what we're talking about here.
A lot of people know about this.
Like I got a bunch of tweets about it
and so then his friend comes running over
and they go back to see and
it's just splattered. Well,
I assure him glad that guys okay. That,
that would not have been pleasant.
I love bikes, but I can't do that. I
can't fuck with crashing. No. You know,
there's something about riding
on something that like, no,
I see that you see the
deer. I took, uh, my, uh,
safety lessons and I was ready to get
a bike and I saw one accident and two
friends saw to two other accidents in
the course of like three days involving a
bike. Wow. Yeah. What of them? Someone
like on a phone hit a car or hit a bike?
Just fucking nailed.
It wasn't even paying attention.
Guy Goes flying off the bike.
Another one I'm a friend of mine was
riding through the canyons. He hit some,
some salt or some, you know, gravel or
whatever the fuck it was. Lost his bike,
ripped his shoulder apart. And then, uh,
it was actually right around the same
time that Frank Mir got hit too when frank
got hit by a car and broke his femur
femur. It was like on his honeymoon.
I think it wasn't real.
I ain't go on his honeymoon vacation.
I know he's on vacation.
He was on his honeymoon.
Pretty sure it was in Vegas than it. It
wasn't really. See, I thought it was,
I thought it was overseas.
Like The Bahamas. I might be,
I might just be adding that element.
I used to be a historian. Joe,
you used to not need to consult and
Internet if you had me around I think.
And now they're about so many shows.
I've,
I've lost track thinking about Tito Ortiz.
Tito Ortiz was in Jamaica and
he got hit by a bus. Yeah.
Him and his wife on vacation.
That's what happened to frank.
Got that frank was hit by a
bus on a motorcycle. No, no,
no. Tito and his, uh, his,
I think it was his,
his wife or a,
they were hit by a bus when I think
he was on like a moped or some shit.
That's why price hurt. That happens, man.
There's only so much data. Sure.
Holding your brain after awhile. Those,
those stories get little Squirrley.
Yeah, no. Frank was hit, I think,
like right in Vegas. And uh, some
guy just fucking ran a red light,
slammed right into him and broke his back,
broke his thei,
sent him flying through the air and it
took a long time for him to come back.
You know, he's a really impressive
case of a comeback. Yeah. You know,
he's gone well because he didn't go
real smooth, you know, smooth it all.
You look at like the branded verified,
they paid it pano fight, you know,
it's like wow. Like where, what happened
to the, you know, the, the former champ,
right. What happened to the dynamic frank
Mir that burst onto the scene? You know,
they're the one that beat Pete Williams.
Just that crazy barbecue guard I remember,
you know,
frankly it was a beast and so
that, that set him back. Man,
I was a pretty pretty grueling injury.
He's one of my favorite guys.
I really like carrying smart guy.
I enjoy frank [inaudible] is
his wife's real nice. You know,
he's a local Vegas guy. He's a great
commentator, Second Amendment Guy.
He's very good. Common tastes better
than the interviews that he cuts.
Some days he does an interview on
and people are turned off by him.
They think he's putting out an
attitude or, so I don't see it,
but I read and hear about these things,
but he doesn't do any of that.
He's totally different persona when he's
commentating. And I like that. You know,
if he doesn't, if he doesn't see it,
he doesn't say it. He's pretty fair.
He's a smart dude and
he's a very smart dude.
He's a kindle with them all the time.
Was Kinda guys constantly read it.
I've had some really heavy conversations
with Frank Mir and you know,
that's why he's so good at Jujitsu.
He's got so much technique too
because he's like, you know,
he's like an encyclopedia for Shit.
The fact that he caught Noguera
and that Kamora and broke his arm,
did Jujitsu world just
exploded when that happened,
that Frank Mir not only did it,
he did it when Nogueira instigated
the ground game because he hadn't,
Frank Mir hurt and he wanted to finish
him off when that just shows you what a
bad motherfucker Frank Mir is.
That's crazy that he bested Nogueira on
the ground and finish while while dizzy.
I mean that's, if that
guy's not underrated. Damn.
That's really fucking impressed.
Oh, he's got his positions for sure.
You and I was cheering
for frank in that fight.
I was happy to see him
when you know as a fan.
But I took no pleasure of seeing though
Garrett injured at all like that.
That was a, that was a rough one.
That was a really hard one to watch,
but Noguera's back, somebody told me
no gear is booked for a card coming up.
Book for card coming up against
check Congo. Yeah, against Chicago.
So he shook it off, you know,
get the Nogueira. I don't
care. I don't know how. Wow,
that's amazing. I mean, how the fuck did,
I don't know what they
did to use plates or one,
I don't know how they put it back
together again. That was fast,
but good for them and mirror.
He's going to go fight for the world title
against those Santos who I will never
underestimate again. I under, I thought
dos Santos was dead in the water with,
I thought it was
a waste of a fight.
I couldn't believe.
I will never underestimate
dos Santos again.
He can throw heat, man. He
can throw heat, you know?
And I was really looking forward
to him against Allister. Oh,
starring him would've been a very
interesting fight, man. You know,
because Alister such a pure standup guy
and Allister is so good at incorporating
leg kicks and knees and
he's got a real tight guard,
especially now that he's so big, you
know, like, like Kinda like sure hunches,
everything over a protects himself.
Well,
he's a dangerous guy
to anybody that has to,
it has to enforce a standup strategy if
you want to just go and box with that
guy. He's got so many other tools
other than just boxing, you know,
and he's so technical with his attacks.
It's just a, it's socks that he, uh,
you know, whatever his
issue was. He's saying,
I think that he got some medication
that some doctor gave him the head
testosterone and then he didn't realize
it and it fucked up his testosterone to
epitestosterone. I don't
know what happened. I don't
know the story behind it,
but I guess he's suspended for like nine
months now. Something along those lines.
That was interesting. Now that whole
case was interesting and yeah, they all,
let's jump off that topic as quick as we
can. But you know, one thing about that,
he took a substance test.
He took for two of them were surprised
test no substance was ever found and he
came forward later,
I kind of volunteered head.
It looks like I might have
taken some testosterone,
but that wasn't what the test show. The
test didn't show anything. It just said,
hey,
there's something with your TD ratio.
Let's try to figure out why this happened.
The media really got paused wrong.
Well, here's what you got. Understand
Joe, so I'm really glad you asked this.
Here's your t and d. Okay,
here's your fee. Here's your,
he says Mastro's for folks at home,
strong epic test. They're very close.
You know they're usually even one to one.
Some allow commissions allow four to
one or even a six to one difference,
but the reality is most are one to one.
Now if your testosterone
went up or if it went down,
that gap is your ratio with the same set.
If you're Epi,
testosterone went up or went down.
That gap is your ratio.
That's why it's a very disingenuous test.
So when a guy has a TDE that's elevated,
the media immediately
assumed that he took his tea.
Could have been in the gutter.
His epi was at the norm and that guy,
he could have been unhealthfully low. Now
I understand that, that, oh, designate.
There's no distinction.
It's extremely disingenuous.
You will never find an endocrinologist,
not one in this country. Literally.
This is a challenge. You won't
find one no matter how disgruntled,
you won't find one to come
on and tell you that it's a,
it's anything other than a disingenuous
test for testosterone and these
commissions are missing this
left and right really, and it's,
it's absolutely horrible. You
know, in some commissions they'll,
they give you just enough
rope to hang yourself. They
say, listen, you're allowed,
go ahead, take testosterone, but make sure
you're within the levels. It's like, no,
wait a minute. That's not how it
works. There's a testosterone level.
You need to figure it out through taking
blood. Well, we can't afford that. Well,
you can't tell a guy he can take
testosterone, but he can't elevate it.
Financial issues as far as accuracy
of test, you have to understand this.
Alister was 14 to one a guy could be
100 to one and still be within the legal
limits.
A TDE ratio does not pertain to anything
and you won't find one expert now,
and I didn't say a doctor and it said to,
I said,
an endocrinologist not one expert
to tell you differently. Real.
It's absolute junk science and they can't.
It's only your in recognition that
does this. It throws off your TV. Well,
his tea could have been up at, he could
have been down his, he could have vote.
You can be dealt with.
Listen,
a guy has every right to manipulate
his testosterone every right.
The question is how did he manipulate it?
Did he use a legal substance or an
illegal substance and Alistair's test for
them too that were surprised,
showed no substance was found.
Now I understand if you want to,
if you and I is for me right here we were.
We're just two guys talking.
We can share our opinion.
But if you're a medium member, if you
sit behind a desk, you wear the suit,
you collect a paycheck
at the end of the night,
your your brand in an analyst
by your affiliated network,
you can't come out and say that he took
testosterone when the test and it showed
that he was never even accused of that.
And you know from Mark Cuban's
tax write off that nobody watches,
those guys could have to
miss the boat anymore.
They took pleasure in coming out an outing
him for something that the commission
ever accused about. ESPN missed
the boat. Everybody got this wrong.
And they were quick to say
that all he's taking tests,
well not according to
the test and [inaudible]
net it was, I don't think it was
anyone other than boss who was a boss,
was pretty sure that he,
you know, and he, and he's
got his own thing, you know,
boss it with golden glory is
very loyal to Golden Glory,
which I really admire with him.
But man, don't let that crossover.
If you're behind that desk,
you got to tell a story the way
it happened and they didn't it,
it's hard. You know,
it's hard. I, I have, uh,
I've done commentary before for friends
and they didn't like what I said,
you know, and then he got mad at
me and I would go, listen man,
I have to say what I see and if I see you,
you do,
you're doing something and then you
get caught doing that. It's because,
I mean I have to say it,
I have to tell people what to look for.
That's what commentary is.
I can't pretend that something different
is happening so that you feel better
about it when you listen to it.
But then the million people hear it or
not getting an accurate account of what's
going on.
I talked to, we had this conversation,
Joe in a bar, you and I in Boston and,
and you,
you told me a line and I've stolen it.
I've used it all the time cause it's
very accurate where you simply said,
if you don't see it,
you can't say it.
You can't go out and trying to hype a
fight, go, this guy's standup looks great.
If it doesn't, if it standup, look
shotty, willing to stand up, look shot,
it's not your job to try to cover
for him as an analyst and a,
I've taken that with me and now I'm
behind a desk and the suit and I took that
one line and I've educated other people
to just simply what that one line,
if you don't see it, don't say it. Okay.
Yeah. You have to let people know what
your real opinion of it is while being
respectful and that's where people
don't understand. Like just, you know,
if I'm accurate about something,
it's not disrespectful, it's just,
it's just uncomfortable. Yeah. It might be
uncomfortable for you,
but to label a disrespectful,
you're not saying what I'm saying.
I'm not saying there's anything wrong
with you as a human. I'm saying, you know,
when you, you, you know, you might
do a technique wrong, you might,
you might have an opening, you might, it's
not a disrespectful thing, but you know,
to a lot of fighters,
like it's a,
your entire identity is wrapped up in,
in what you do.
But you owe that to the viewer. That's
who's paying to hear you, not the fighter.
You know, I can tell you I
thought I beat Michael Bisping.
I thought it was pretty clear.
It's very close.
You had a different opinion and I never
sent you a text or was upset with it.
You, you, you have your opinion
and when you're on the mic,
it's your job to share that
opinion, you know, um, my opinion,
but I should clarify that my opinion
actually changed when I watched it again
when I watched it again. I, uh, I thought
your takedowns what a want it. Yeah.
I appreciate, I, you know, I had it
the same way and I'm pretty objective.
I'm not afraid to go look, I pulled
one out. I shouldn't hard though.
When you're watching it live,
you know, quite honestly I,
I honestly get a better view of fights
a lot of times from watching it at home.
The experience of watching on
paper you is fucking great.
I mean they always get to the right angle
immediately. It's never like, you know,
sometimes I'll look up and you know,
a herb Dean's right in front of me.
I can't see what's going on or
someone's in a post. I don't,
I don't know what's going on
in the box. Like when, uh,
Alan Belcher and who some are,
Paul Harris went at it the,
when they first went to the ground,
I didn't know that Belcher,
he instigated that position from the shot.
You know,
he's the one that pulled him into the,
into that position and
I didn't realize it.
I thought that Paul Harris was diving
on them cause I couldn't quite see what
was going on.
So you do sometimes get a better view of
a fight from watching it at home. Yeah,
sometimes you get hyped up in the
moment too. It's hard to and off topic.
But speaking of Belcher,
you know,
Dana gives a fight of the night fight
of the night easily was Alan Belcher.
You know, Pell Horse is
scary. He's flat out scary.
Nobody wants to fight him
because if it doesn't go well,
you're going to sit out for six to eight
months. He's going to rip your list.
Yeah. It can go really, really bad.
For the folks who don't know anything
about of UFC or Jujitsu and you're just
listening to this podcast, Paul
Harris is uh, one of the weirdest, uh,
like specialists in all
of the UFC because all we,
his number one thing is ripping
guys knees apart. It's terrifying.
Weird build weird technique.
Hulk looking dude. Yeah, sure.
I've ate and just built like a brick
shit house and just dives on your leg and
very set apart how horrific the way he
wins. People are screaming in agony.
Yeah. And you know, Alan, when I got Allen
did a great job, I was happy for him.
See the fire pell Horace went to,
because you know, if his backstory,
everything he's overcoming,
he's a great story too.
But I'm a huge fan of technique and
Paul Jarvis is techniques not just as
physical strength.
His technique is masterful the
way he laces up leg locks on guys.
The way he hit my Senscio.
I mean the way he lays his him up,
it's like it's so pure, there's no
fat in that technique. You know,
I'm a fan of of that,
but I'm also a fan of a guy like Alan
Belcher just figures out how to deal with
it. I love, I love that he just
works specifically with guys like
Dean lister and instead of saying,
well we want to avoid this.
He was like, fuck this.
I'll go to the ground with this guy.
I don't care.
I'll go to the ground with them. And I
think he blew his mind by doing that.
I think par is mine. Yeah, he blew mine
when he started going for the twist her.
I was like,
if he taps Paul horror is,
this would be the craziest fucking
thing I've ever seen. Yeah, he,
cause he talked about that
in his interviews leading
up. I'll go to the ground,
I'll put him in an ankle lock. I
was like, sure how many guys say?
And then he went out and did it. I
mean, he didn't go for the ankle lock,
but he went out and did it. He backed up
what he said good for Belcher. You know,
Belcher said moments, why watch
them and go, you are amazing.
And on a bad night he's still very good,
but on a good night, that guy's amazing.
Good for belter. Yeah. And
He's had some tough times,
you know with is a detached
retina you had for awhile,
which is very scary know to imagine.
I mean you're a professional fighter and
you start to lose your vision because
of fighting, so they have to repair
your eyeball and then you know,
you have to have the confidence and the
courage to go back out there and keep
throwing leather and letting people
punch you in that surgically repaired
eyeball. So he was off
for a long time. I mean,
you know how hard you have to
work to make up that ground.
Of those six months you lost. Now you
got another four before you got to work.
Double Time. Triple time. It's,
it's incredible. Just to catch up.
How long does it take just to catch up?
Happy to see Belcher doing well? Yeah.
Oh yeah. It takes, just to get back,
just to get word and not no
improvement in technique.
No improvement and conditioning.
Just to dreading catch up.
How long does it take to develop the
wind for a five round fight till like for
real, like you're rematch with Anderson
Silva that you're, you're training for.
How long are you in like peak
ridiculous hard training to,
to gear up for a five round fight?
You know,
the answer I give because it's Mike
is a lifetime. It's a lifetime. I,
I worked so hard,
you know,
till I was 23 and finished wrestlin to
go six minutes and it was so difficult to
go six minutes at that pace of a wrestling
match. Now you know, now 15 months.
Oh my goodness. It's so hard when you
start to break into those 25 minutes.
I don't know if the human being
is meant to do that. You know,
Saint Pierre keeps taking
a lot of criticism. Well,
the reality is you're asking
him to do a monumental task,
which is to go hard for 25 minutes.
It's,
it's an impossible task to ask somebody.
And there's a saying in boxing
that if you go for the knockout,
you will not win a decision and
you need to make your choice. Now,
if I go for the kill, you know Dan
Henderson Style and you don't get it,
and then you realize that show guns still
alive and you got to hang out for 25
it's not going to be afraid 25 minutes.
You know, you're crazy. Fight that. Yeah,
you gotta pace. And a lot of people
go, well Dan Henderson's not in shape.
Well that's not the case.
Dan Henderson's a human being and human
beings get very tired when they go for
the kill. So you've got a planet,
right? And George does planet right now.
If you want to see an exciting fight,
shorten the rounds and George will go
crazy. I guarantee it. He did before.
So you think it's just a matter of the
human body has to work too hard to fight
at a high clip for five rounds, you
know, 25 minutes. It's just too much.
There's no nobody sprints for 25 minutes.
How would you have it?
Would you have it? I always felt like
it's kind of interesting. There's two,
two schools of thought.
One of them is that MMA is more difficult
than than boxing and maybe the round
should be in shorter length,
but then the other school of thought is,
but it takes her a grappler a long time
to get his opponent down to work so hard
for a takedown and then only have
like five seconds left on the clock.
That sounds, that's
ridiculous. You need, you know,
a five round at a five minute round.
At least you take a guy down
within the first couple of minutes,
you have time to work, you hold
them down, you, you finish them,
you know you have time to
work. I hear you. But you know,
the competitor is a no sports
set the rules, it's the fans.
It's an audience that sets the rule.
So it comes down to meet if you are a
fan as well, you want a fan as well.
So if you as a fan, I mean taking
yourself out of the equation, what do you,
when you just subjectively with
all the knowledge that you have,
what would you think would
be the better format? Well,
it is how I would answer you. Professional
boxing is viewed to be very boring.
So they call boxing, very born on
boxing. So born well that's not true.
Boxing is fantastic. Go Watch the
amateurs. It's three three minute rounds.
They throw punches in flurries
nonstop for nine minutes.
So boxing is very pleasing.
Professional boxing where you're asking
a guy to do 12 rounds at three minutes,
36 minutes is on pleasing.
Know commentators have developed
this feeling out process.
There is no such thing. It's a unwritten
agreement. You and I are going to go box.
You and I both know we
can't go 36 minutes,
so I'm going to stand around
and move around a little bit.
You're going to stand around
Once we get to round five now
we both can do seven rounds.
Let's go ahead and fight.
There is no such thing as a feeling out
process in boxing. I boxed for years.
There's such a thing as
surviving a ridiculous time
frame that's put on you have
a half of an hour and so if you have a
guy hurt but he's got a good Chin and you
go for it, you're fucked. You're
screwed. I mean that is the same.
That doesn't mean you're not going to
find exceptions to the rule. But yeah,
the basic belief in boxing, and I
believe it too, if you go for the finish,
you will not win a decision.
Eddie Alvarez does that name ring a bell.
He's over in Balter. Eddie Alvarez
talks about this, you know,
you've got five rounds, you gotta fight,
how are you going to do it? And he says,
I don't train for five rounds.
I trained for two and Eddie Alvarez
was like 32 and two we had an amazing
record. Any finished guy after guy, but
he also had a totally different approach.
I'm going to go for the kill.
If I don't get it. Yeah,
I acknowledge I'm in trouble.
It's pretty 32 men that didn't
have an answer for it and I really,
I really liked when Eddie said this,
he and I were in Bodog together
and I heard him say that that, oh,
that's hyperbole. And I started
wanting to know he's serious.
He trains to sprint and finish you and
he does guy after guy and when it doesn't
work well he's got problems. Melvin
Manhoef I heard you bring him up earlier.
You know Melville do the same thing.
He's trained for three minutes,
three minutes of fury.
Well that's one of the things,
the reasons I love a k one I love watching
high level kickboxing's three rounds,
no big matches or three
rounds. You know, I mean I,
I used to love watching those three
round k one fights because it's about all
those guys could take the
way they were going at it,
the clip that they were fighting at.
I mean if you go back and watch like
Jerome Le Banner versus Peter Arts,
they're just fucking
swinging at each other and they take
turns knocking each other down air.
It's knocks down the banner with a high
kick and then the banner starches IRTs
with a, with a left hook. Both guys that
just got fucking waylaid on each other.
They, they kick like you'd swing a
baseball bat. I mean it's just violent.
You know, he's speaking to the
k one at guys that did well,
what's up with Bob Sapp now these aren't
real fights he's going to do in these
countries, right? Is the
opponent and on the gang,
like this guy that hits and
master the bell for five seconds,
he'll push and ask is a gentleman,
he's a sports.
He's going to punch somebody after
the bell and less than the back.
You worked it out. Hey, let me cover up
in the act. Mad about it. I mean, come on.
That whole thing looks so fucking lazy.
That couldn't be real.
Bob Sat kits a paycheck. I mean, this
is my opinion, but it doesn't look good.
The whole thing was bad.
And I think what made it worse was when
Pooja now's he kept hitting them after
the bell. Like, come on, put
your not going to do that
unless you know this looks,
this looks awful. It's like when Dan
Severn and in Shannon rich did their, uh,
their work. You know, Dan, come
on man, you're caught on this.
This is brutal.
And your interviews after the fact are
worse than the poor job you did in the
ring at fuller. Pc. That
fine. Oh, you didn't see it.
Do you know how to round off
is from gymnastics? It's a,
gymnastics is a handspring and you'll
use it to Dan Severn hit one of those in
the fight. I'll just let you know that
Shannon did something damn separate,
hits a round off in the middle of the
ring and he stumps. Oh God, it was so bad,
Joe. He was silly. And
then after the match,
they do their interviews
and their interview,
Jane Dan Severance cover up of the
work was worse than the work is. Well,
I was just fortunate to get
over on Shannon rich. He's
such a great competitor.
You know, Shanna Richie was
never want to fight. Dan Severn,
who was a former multiple
time world champion, you know,
absolutely legendary in our sport.
I was just fortunate to have a good
enough training camp to go, wow.
And you got to stop, man. You got to stop.
We've all been in the locker room
is Shanna. Rich walks in and says,
who wants the night off? All Right
Shannon, I guess I'll take it. You know,
this isn't a secret in the industry. Dan
quit, you know, come on, you got caught.
Just call it what it is.
Wow. That's weird. Well,
he always did a lot of pro wrestling
as well, didn't it? Horribly. I mean,
he got a stent in the WWE. They just
couldn't use them. They said, look,
you got to go. Just not entertaining. You
know, he just didn't get it. He couldn't,
he couldn't work.
You know,
if you watch a Shannon match and
you see how bad he did at PR,
it was so bad. Man. It was so bad. This
was the brilliance of pride. You know,
and,
and I get heat when I talk about Vandelay
and cro cop doing their fake matches.
But in America, if you're going
to do a pro wrestling match,
both guys will sit in the back and they'll
come up with what they're going to do.
They call it their spots. Okay, you
do this, then I'll do that. In pride,
what they would do is the promoter
would visit one locker room.
So if you're going to take
on Vandelay or cro cop,
you know your promoter shows up,
boom,
here's your 10 grand and here's
how this fight's going to end.
Vandelay isn't privy to that.
So when the guy goes down,
his celebration is genuine because he
doesn't know that the guy got his locker
room visit.
It's the same thing with cro cop that
thought one leg cemetery in one lake
hospital, no cro cop. Your legs
aren't knocking people out.
The promoter visited the back beforehand.
That's what's not going to.
And then I made this public,
I added these guys cause I don't like
either one of them was ordered to do word.
Absolutely. Some legit knockouts
for sure. For sure. And Cro cop the,
the second part where he kicked his
head. Yeah, I remember that fight.
I enjoyed their first fight to win.
Vandelay one,
I think they call it a draw and
draw Vandelay one, you know,
per our scoring system,
you know,
but as soon as I said also good ridge
and coal and all these guys coming in,
yeah, he's right. There's a
bunch of payoff. Well, there
had to be Takotna again.
I mean, come on. You don't have
to do the cotton and Coleman.
They'd have to put on your Colombel rain
jacket to figure this out. You know?
Excuse me.
How come I am 22 and oh in Japan and
can't win to straightened America.
Eddie Bravo.
Bravo got offered by a name
to lose or to twin rather.
Oh. To uh, to beat to Coro.
They were going to have it set up.
So,
but meanwhile it could have been a
double cross where he goes there and he
thinks to Coro is going to lay down
Carl Beats Shit. That's what we
call the screw job. Finished jet.
The Montreal screw job.
Yeah, there's a word for it
in a professional pool too.
I think it's a double dump.
They get dumped both ways.
Ah, I see. Is that what it is?
Yeah, because pool has a real hard problem
with that. Let guy like say if I, uh,
if I'm a pool player and you're
a rich guy, I said, listen,
shall I got a fucking game and I
can't go wrong here buddy. I am,
I am robbing this guy. Come on, let's put
up 500 bucks. So let's make some money.
And uh, I go to him and
I go, listen, let's,
here's the deal I'm going to lose and
we'll just fucking split this 70, 30,
and cut it up right now.
And we've got ourselves a big chunk of
cash and so there's no real match going
on in the first place.
Sure.
They had already decided that they're
going to dump and they were going to split
up this guy's money.
That's him and a friend and got together
and they pretended to be rivals so they
could gamble and he
would dump to this guy.
I can't fucking make a ball and I know
what's going on. Surely just gossip.
Typical digs, town
hustle sharing. You know,
the two of them get together after this
show and split up half his money or 70%,
whatever they, you know,
agreed upon different guys
from different deals. But it,
uh, it was always a, a big problem
to the point where they had a,
the only time Vegas allowed them to gamble
and pool ever. They, uh, they set it up.
So it was one of the big tournament's
and all they did was make the found who
was the number one guy most least
likely to what 40 to one odds. Okay,
we're all going to let that guy when
we're going to just get to gamble all of
our money and fucking
pay. Right. Allegedly alleged. Well,
that's unfortunate that happened. I mean,
I can see where that would happen.
That is unfortunate because in, in,
in some weird walk of society that
is sport that does involve timing and
accuracy and training. So it's
unfortunate when guys what it is yet.
But I think I get it. I mean, I, I guess
I understand that. I can understand.
I can understand betting on yourself.
I can understand if you're
some wild motherfucker like
Bernard Hopkins, he says,
I'm going to go bet $100 a
hundred dollars on myself,
you know, because that's how much
I know I'm going to win this fight.
I liked that. I don't like the
option of doing it the other way.
Betting on your pending on your mommy
and taking a dive. That's possible.
You know the fact that you
could get your friend to do it.
The fact that there have been
unethical dumps before without a doubt.
No doubt about it. I mean, we all know
of him. I don't know if you've ever been
better on a UFC fight,
but I don't know if you,
if you have it then you wouldn't know
this, but the way it worked, you know,
in a lot of gambling halls you
would imagine, well, if I show up,
it's four to one odds
and I put 50 grand down,
I got 50 grand in 41 it
doesn't work that way.
If you go to bed at a sports
book in Vegas on a UFC fan,
this isn't the same for for everything,
but for UFC because there's
not enough money coming in.
You can only bet x amount at a time.
Then they reset the line and
then you've got to bed it again.
I went in and bed on, well I bet on
Henderson when he fought Vandelay.
Now this was a number of years,
I think 2006 could have been 2007 and
they only let me bet 500 Henderson was a
three to one underdogs. I
go 500 505 and I, you know,
I got to my $3,000 limit and I had
to go to three different casinos.
Now I'm quite sure with the influx of
the sport that it'd be closer to 10,000
but I'm quite sure it's not over 10
how confident were you though?
That's pretty fucking bad ass.
Just going to casino casinos.
The header says it was good
and you know, that's what vanity,
I mean nobody could meet van.
He had that reputation like Mike Tyson
was, was hanging onto for a while.
You know,
but you're talking about Dan Henderson,
you're talking about one of the baddest
dudes to ever live. He's a fucking tank.
He's something else, man. And I knew
it was going to be a good fight too.
I didn't know was going to be walking in
the park. But uh, you got to bet on you
guy. Yeah, well you know, Henderson
is a fucking tank man. He's a tank.
He's one of those dudes were you pat them
on the back and it feels like there's
something wrong. Why? Why are you so
dense? Right? Like what the fuck is this?
And he turns around to look at y'all
stim or Limu. His teeth are out.
Hey, what are you doing? You know,
gives you some insult of some sort.
That's his way of saying
something mean spirited.
Knock that last for some reason
it's charming when he does it.
That's how I saw him. He goes, did
you get another fucking tattoo?
I got you sound like my mom.
He always,
he always is something
mean as his greedy you.
This is my favorite Dan Henderson story.
We were in Caroline's comedy club in
New York and there's this guy that was,
and he wouldn't shut the fuck
up. And I go, listen man,
if you don't shut the fuck up,
I don't want to have Dan Henderson and
come over here and hold you down while he
fucks your girlfriend. The
crowd goes nuts. And Dan goes,
why would I hold them down when
I could just stare him down?
I'm telling you the fucking place erupted.
The fucking place erupted.
And it was like one of the creepiest
things I ever heard a man say to another
man ever.
Like you can see the dude,
the dude just wanted to crawl out
of the room and just hide somewhere.
The feeling of looking over it,
that fucking savage after he just says
something like that too, and you're like,
oh, let me change. Let me get Outta here.
Well, in Henderson broke etiquette, you
know there's an etiquette men, if one
guys what the girl at one guy's, not
you, you're, you're always wrong.
You let him slit you let him
look like a hero, you know?
Then it comes back to you someday.
Well, I think in that situation it was,
there was 350 fucking people
in that crowd. That guy was
a jackass. He was drunk.
Dan Henderson was there and he was like,
well, I'll shut this fucking dummy up,
so I like it. It's a pss. Yeah,
essentially like a trumped
my heckler comment,
like I had shut them down
and then Henderson came along
and put the nuclear bomb
on top of it. Right. You put the age,
but the verbal age Bonolo each borrower.
That's good work by Dan. It was very
good work on the spot like that.
The best line you could have ever written.
Sure.
I can't write anything creepy than that.
Why would I hold him down
when I could just stare him?
Now that's a guy has to think like that
in order to have that thought in his
head in order to be able to
say that verbally. I mean,
if you're going to be a writer and
you're going to come up with that,
it might take you six hours alone doing
cocaine and drinking coffee to pretend
you're the type of guy that would think
that way to have that line come out of
your character's mouth.
Took Dan Henderson one half of one second.
He just waited.
Well this is the same guy that volunteered
to fight dos Santos three weeks ago
to move up arguably two weekly. You know,
cause truly he's, he's a middle way.
He chooses to fight at light heavyweight.
He doesn't like cutting weight. Right?
It's a truly be going up to way anyway.
And he's great and he's fucking,
he's an animal. This is
not the, and those guys,
they almost all come from wrestling. The
guys like that Henderson stock. There's,
there's guys that can push through pain
and then there's wrestlers. There's like,
there's another level of, of mental
strength of the ability to endure.
And when you were talking about
going through when you were a kid,
like being malnourished and fucking,
you know,
traveling on buses and wherever the
hell you're going to these different
wrestling meets to sleep and not getting
enough sleep and how difficult and you
had to do schoolwork as well or
how difficult all that is that the,
the mental toughness that wrestlers
develop from that ridiculous first of all,
from fucking cutting weight all
the time just to be able to,
people like to feel
good when they compete.
They like to feel great and
charged up and confident.
I had so many friends when I was
a wrestling that would be like,
there was this kid named Mark Collins
who is a really good wrestler, really,
really good, but he would, he
would cut down to like 118 pounds.
He was a little guy anyway, but he would
cut down like re maybe I'm exaggerating,
maybe was like one 20 something years.
We were in high school.
It used to be one 18 they used to be,
but the fucking guy was never happy.
He would always just have this
dour look in his face. Life sucked.
He was just walking around is always
hungry and you know, it's it stunted.
My friend, Steve's growth,
my friend Steve, all of his
brothers like six foot two,
six foot one six foot,
big fucking guys.
He's five six because all throughout
high school just fucking dieting, shy,
going through regular wrestling and
then going off to camps and never,
never allowed to like actually eat full
meals for a normal long period of time
and grow like a normal man. It's like he
essentially grew up impoverished. Right.
You know? Yeah. And
it's tough. You know, you're talking about
how hard the weight cut is. And for us,
for our sport of MMA, it's a 24
hour wait. I mean you weigh in,
the show starts 24 hours later in
wrestling. It's a one hour weigh in.
And not only that, Joe,
the national tournament,
the whole reason you wrestle is a
three day tournament with three ins.
So you weigh in, you do two matches, you
cut weight that night, you weigh in again,
you do two matches, you cut weight that
night, you come back for the championship.
So, ah, yeah. So I mean you're
talking guys that aren't
sleeping and they're just,
they're just, they're cut weight nonstop,
boom time to wrestle. I mean it had,
you know, how do you do it? And it really
is where the rubber meets the road.
Sometimes the best wrestler off that
had the best season 35 and will not even
place at the national tournament because
you know where he used to weigh in and
have 24 hours get on the mat,
he'd want a dual meet tournament style
one hour away and you're on the mat next
morning.
Weigh in again.
And so is that like um,
indicative of a style of competing like
some guys like Frankie Edgar don't cut
any weight at all. Other guys is the,
is that the case in wrestling as well?
Like some guys would try to
cut the most amount of weight,
but other guys would think that the best
way to do was be entirely healthy and
just be natural and deal with
a guy. Yeah. As larger. Yeah.
You see that all the time,
you know,
and there's some guys that went and they
got a little bit more speed. This guy,
you know,
he's going to come in the ring at two 20.
I'm going to come in at two Oh four
but I'm going to be a little bit
faster than him. And that's where
Dan Henderson's made 11. Yeah.
Dan Henderson's beat multiple heavyweight
world champion and one from a big Nog
to a fade or um,
here's what those are heavyweights. But
he went to use the little bit of speed.
Yes, he absolutely did.
But that was the rematch.
He fought him in a tournament
called King of rings. Okay.
So that wasn't really MMA.
Like you weren't allowed to do certain
things like strike on the ground. Right.
There was some stuff that was held back
and you could strike on the ground.
I want to say was open
palm, you know, open palm,
like definitely no soccer kicks or pride
rules. But I mean it was considered,
I considered MMA absolutely fuck Gilbert
Gilbert I but because when you're on
your feet you can do everything.
It was something about what the take down.
I believe it was an open palm to the head.
Isn't that crazy?
When you see like go boss route
and style Pancrase fights.
What a weird fucking hybrid of the two
for folks who don't know you were allowed
to kick with,
you know you have these like boots on
that had shin pads on them but you weren't
allowed to punch the face.
Instead you could slap people full blast
and Bas Rutten figured out a way at a
pull his hand back way far and when
he would throw slop, I don't know,
I can't even bend my hand
back the way he would do it.
And he would essentially be punching you
with his palms. Yeah, the palm strike.
He got so good at just punching, throwing
like punching techniques in the palms.
Whereas everybody else had kind of like,
they hadn't figured that out yet and
they were slapping each other was about a
boss as a master. I love to watch
of bosses, little fights over there.
Some of those were for Gazy to you,
but you know some of that paint cray stuff
you'd want us to go, no, wait a minute.
Come on. No doubt. No doubt. There was
definitely some, some fixed fights.
It's weird that some guys don't want to
admit that, but now I think they should.
I think they kind of owe it to history.
You know, we, we know that there was a lot
of real fights for sure, but there was
all, there was no question about it.
There was some that are a little funky,
you know.
But that goes back to the point I made
earlier that both guys aren't necessarily
in on it in Japan, Cro, cop,
those guys really think they want
and if you tell them they did it,
I mean you're talking about really
hurting a guy's feelings where he gets a,
you know who get fighting
mad a over that and you go,
hey listen what fights century history.
We'll, we'll, we'll come out and,
and show itself for what it is.
But you know what?
That's really hard because I don't know
all those guys name but cro cop fault.
One guy that wore a pro wrestling mask,
he is a pro wrestler.
He wrestles under the name
of via a host. Kairos? Yes.
A Alberto del Rio is what his name.
But of course you already know that.
That's what it comes out and says he's
very funny guy and he's talked about it a
lot. Yeah, they brought me on.
I don't even think about it.
I got to fight this cro cop.
He's officially,
he's going to throw a head kick and
I got to make it look real. You know,
he's talked about cro. Cop would be that
you'd be stunned to hear that. I believe.
I believe cro cop did not
know that these were fake. No,
I didn't have that realization when
I first outed him. I had it. I,
I came to when he responded to that.
You know what?
He's either an academy award winner.
He truly doesn't know.
And then you started to hear for
some other guys when they go look,
he didn't always know the promoter
to come to your locker room.
So that wrestling guy,
when cro cop kicked him though,
he really fucking kicked
that guy in the head. Yeah,
just the guy sort of like just took it.
Yeah.
And the guys just got
to go down in the boom.
The referee will eating the referee
we led was coming to the man.
This could be a deal. Is that the
same guy? Wasn't if it was fake,
what a fucking great
touch. Sure. As the mask.
If they had like a little blood pack
it there. And what cro cuts slaps it,
blood comes out. I mean what a great
touch that would be. But you know,
you see a kid come and he'd go, okay, this
is the one I got paid for. You take it,
it could cause a kick.
I had a buddy that went down and
he was by no means doing a dive,
he was just ready to quit. He was just,
he just wanted out of there. So you know,
in fighters,
we'll do this a lot where something's
not going right and they got it's time to
go home and you know, they'll usually,
the rear naked choke is the big one for,
Hey, get me out of here. But uh,
so my buddy decides that he's going
to go down on a, on a fake knockout.
So we're in code dog and Costa Rica.
Dan,
his guy named Dan Stevens to the big
viking guy used to fight in the UFC a
couple of times. They didn't Christianson,
is that what his name was? Anyway,
Dan throws the punch. My Buddy
Jeremiah goes down, the punch,
missed Jeremiah goes down,
but the referee,
Troy Wa doesn't catch it in time.
So now my buddy who's out cold,
well Dow Dan Christmas is going to come
down for the finish because the ref
hasn't caught it. So my buddy who's
pretending it has to come back to life.
You guys to come back to life to
like lay there and go for Tkis.
So when you watch on the replay,
like wait a minute,
I thought you were out called how
come when he came it was pretty bad.
But you know,
you see that stuff all the time and
that's not to say the score a sports for
Gazy, that's just, that's
competition. What you're trying to do,
what I'm trying to do when I'm
fighting is make the other guy quit.
What he does has to do when he's ready
to quit is make it look like he got,
you know, that's just part of it and
nobody wants to talk about that. In fact,
one guy did, one guy talked
about it in Ohio and the Ohi,
I can't think of what his name was,
a former UFC fighter.
Rashad kicked him in the head. Sean
Salomon. That's what his name is.
Sean talked about this
and this wasn't my night.
I gave him an arm and I tapped
out and got out of there.
He was very keen on there.
He got in canopy because they thought
he was throwing a fit and he's, and he,
but what he was doing was he was letting
people into the psyche of an athlete
who's breaking,
he's breaking and it's an ugly deep
secret and we've all done it as athletes,
whether it's in practice or in the
rain and we're greatly shameful of it.
So what he did is he just let people
know, look, this is what happened.
I broke down mentally the commissioner
comes out in and suspends him for it.
It's like, well commission obviously
you've never competed. We can,
we can see that. Yeah. That's ridiculous.
That is what exactly what it is.
When a guy gives up an arm,
he's trying to save himself and just say
a little dignity. I got caught. You know,
either. Yeah. That's
that. That is an issue.
The real issue of people
regulating athleticism where
they don't understand the
psychology behind being an athlete,
especially a combat athlete. You know,
like there was an issue that I had and
we'll, we don't name any names here,
but it was when you, uh, you,
someone had questioned you about you
fake tapping against a Polo Phelia a law
and you know,
and my take on that is to,
for you to ask a man what he's
thinking right then in the middle of an
incredibly emotional situation
where he's losing a fight,
he knows it's over.
He got locked up in it and he's thinking
there's got to be a fucking way out of
this. There's gotta be a way you want to
win so bad you say something that you're
ashamed of later.
But to say that that thing
that you were ashamed of,
it you did represents your character
or your sensibilities or your honesty,
I think is a bit disingenuous to be judged
in that moment. And that vulnerable,
awful,
devastating moment is not right.
It's especially for someone who has,
when you have competed at a high level
for a number of years like you have,
it's almost like you could be considered
like almost like a slightly crazy
person,
like your fanaticism for victory.
You're your need to compete and excel it,
be it.
The only way to get really fucking
good is you gotta be a little crazy.
You just have to be and you've
got to want to fucking win.
You can't be happy with any,
any other result.
You cannot be hat or you won't
achieve your full potential.
And that sometimes equates
to people fucking up.
It's sometimes equates to breaking.
It equates to mental lapses.
It equates to a lot of different things.
You know, I had to respond to that.
I had an uh, a person, again, let's
make sure we keep them on name,
but he wanted a response to that.
I'm going, Geez, you know, if I'm,
to be candid with you,
if I get tapped out in front of a sold
out audience that was aired on live
worldwide television,
and I then lie about doing it,
the only person I'm lying to
is myself. You know, that's it.
They only if I'm trying to fool, so if
I'm in denial, you know, and I, and me,
I could be anybody
could be chill or it could be, you know,
fight her ex. But if he's doing that,
if a person, look, Dylan person, you're
lying to yourself to the guy, fall up,
file a complaint with the
commissioner. Well that's
within the rules. Uh, you know,
you know, what did the guy do if you get,
if he's forcing you to make a ruling,
go ahead. But you know, to like you
said, and let's also not forget one,
when you file a complaint,
how much of that is gamesmanship because
you're trying to get a rematch anyway.
And the whole game is about making more
money. I'll tell you what, gentlemen,
my entire career, I couldn't name one
person that's ever filed a complaint.
I know they've been filed,
but I literally couldn't tell
you the one guy that's done.
And I know some guys think, hey listen,
there was a misapplication of the rules.
I really like a review and I
understand that. But again,
I couldn't say state a case for you,
but you know there's,
there's other things
like the First Amendment,
I've got the right to say I didn't
tap and any single fight that I want.
Okay. The second one, fight ends.
The marketing for the next fight begins.
And if a fighter chooses to do that,
he's got everywhere.
There's nothing within the rules of a
commission to say what a guy's going to
say in his post fight
interview. That's, that's silly.
So you will say you're,
you're essentially admitting that you
will say untruthful things just in order
to keep the hype going and that
people should not miss a turn.
There's a blurry line. Yeah. For
me, no wrestling, blurry line.
I'm not saying that for me, but
you know, if I, if I'm saying me,
I just meet an athlete in
general and it can be any sport,
but first I'm an athlete is not under
oath so he can come out and say whatever
when you're just a person. And
secondly, if one competition is,
it could be baseball or fighting
or whatever, the, the, the, the,
the makings and the matchmaking in the
and the shuffling and the politicking for
the next event begins.
And for somebody to come in and,
and want an answer for that and try
to attempt to regulate you is beyond
inappropriate. I mean I would, I
would want to say it's illegal. Again,
it comes down to the first amendment.
I can say whatever he wants and a post
fight interview or post-match interview
or game or whatever it is. I want to take
myself out of this now. Right. You know,
person in general come on,
you can say whatever it was naturally,
especially if you're considering
that part of you as a,
as an athlete to be sort of performance
art. You're, you're actually,
you have an act. I mean, and that act,
it enhances your overall
brand. I mean, when you,
when you go out there and you talk a
bunch of crazy shit whether or not you
believe in and people start talking about
you becomes monetarily it advantageous
to do that, you make more money that way.
Brock Lesnar, I think a perfect example,
you know, UFC 100 all of his fights, you
know, Brock was always fun to listen.
Do you want to know who else is fun? Is
Quintin Jackson Quinten finishes a fight.
We all sit there in the living room.
Wait, wait, wait, Quentin's about to talk.
And he says something funny whether he
gives you a hard time or you on black
crime and inviting people to an after
party. You know, it's funny. And that's,
and that's part of the
show that people paid for.
So that's not to say a fighter or again,
any athlete has to do that.
But if he chooses to,
he's gotta be considered outside the
scope of our, the regulatory body.
I mean about them overstepping
that.
That's beyond an appropriate,
well I certainly think you should be able
to ask a guy after he's fucking taking
a shower and tell us what happened.
I fucked up.
I said I didn't tab or I was just
losing my mind in there. Sure.
But even if he doesn't,
if he wants to take it to the gray,
let's not forget the guy doesn't owe
you anything. He's not under subpoena.
He owes you nothing,
including the truth if that's his choice.
So for a government official,
cause that's how this started is you
were talking about a government for a
government official to get involved and
act as though he's going to suspend or
uphold somebody's license because he
didn't like something that he said in the
media is inappropriate.
I agree.
Now what happened to you?
I'm, I'm a, I'm a fascinated,
I'm fascinated personally by
big leaps in development. I'm,
I'm always fascinated when you
hear about a guy, well yeah,
he was a blue belt and then something
happened and he went into Q,
a few seminars and before,
you know,
he's fucking killing everybody at the
Monday house you went from UFC was at UFC
60 that you find Jeremy Horn. Yeah.
You were having some tough fights.
Very impressed that you know that
by the way. Good job pat. Thank you.
See a lot of shows. Um, I can't
remember where my fucking car keys are,
but I can tell you a random UFC have
no idea what I put my cell phone. But,
but you,
um,
you fought Jeremy Horn and
then was something happened
between then and when you
had a resurgence, which
was, um, say what do you,
what do you attribute your research into?
Like what year do you
think it's really started?
I know where you're going with
this and let, let me jump ahead.
You know what you're saying is,
hey,
I had some major submission problems
and all of a sudden I started submitting
some guy, not just that man, you
became a more confident guy. You. Um,
I, I don't want to undermine your
confidence before cause I didn't know you.
I meant uh, I mean the, the way you
presented yourself I should say, um, you,
you got way better at marketing yourself
and you started fucking dominating Tom
Fly. It's like you hate
your own. You had a,
a personal wall and you got
through that fucking thing.
You got through that fucking thing and
you made a big leap, you know, and when,
when you fought Nate Marquardt,
I think that was the fight that really
opened up a lot of people's eyes.
Just like, Whoa, like channel
Sonnen's a motherfucker.
I remember me and Eddie Bravo had
dinner after that and it was like,
how bout that power double God.
Damn.
It's like Nate could not keep
you off of them. And we were,
we were thinking about it and was like,
wow, what a nightmare. It's like you had,
you had figured out a way to get all of
your potential out inside the octagon.
What happened?
I appreciate it
in and out. You don't know
and training either. For me,
I had a fight with you Chenault calm and
he was ranked number two in the world
and I was just one of those guys that was
kind of looked at as a top 10 that was
right before I fought my more, couldn't,
it gave me a lot of confidence.
But here's what happened Joe. I have
never lost a round of fighting. And,
and when I say that,
sometimes the guy,
I'll laugh giggle cause I've lost some
fights but I've never lost around.
I've never had a fight where a judge ever
scored around against me and tell last
match with Bisping.
So at the point of your story though,
I sit down one day and I'm looking at it,
I'm sure it all.com I bring myself up.
I'm looking at my record.
I've won every round I've ever fought.
I've never been in a tough fight. I've
never had stitches, I've never broken it.
I've dominated everybody and I've lost
eight fights and I lost all of them by
submission and I lost all
of them in the second round.
And I'm staring at that on the computer.
I'm staring at these numbers,
like a CEO would, his
spreadsheet, and I'm saying,
there's something going on
here and it's not physical.
There's something going on that I can
dominate eight minutes of a fight,
seven minutes of a fight,
nine minutes of a fight and
find a way out time after time,
after time in the same
round with the same move.
And so I find I wouldn't get it.
I wouldn't get help.
I went and got professional help and,
uh, I sought out a doctor, ed Versteeg.
Uh,
I hate talking about this because this
was a real seat as a real turning point
for me is when I went in, worked on
sports psychology, got hypnotized.
I was never the same. I was never the same
in practice. My attitude was different.
Uh, controlling my diet, being
disciplined, falling asleep.
The way I approached battle,
the way I approached the second round,
everything changed.
And it changed to the point where I hate
to say what I just said and now it's
too late. Uh, because I
felt like it was my secret.
I discovered and I don't
want other people to know.
I'll write about it someday in a
book. I'll talk about it, you know,
when I'm retired, but I'm not gonna
tell anybody cause its competitive edge.
And when I started seeing a sports
psychologist, when I finally came clean,
you know, it was like being an
alcoholic before you can get help,
you've got to admit you have a problem.
And when I finally admitted I got
a problem, when I finally said it,
when I finally could acknowledge and look
somebody in the eye and tell him this
is what's going on,
I'm finding a way to lose as opposed
to when I work harder than these guys.
I've been at this long drive, I'm
losing, I know how to stop submissions.
I'm finding my way into them. I'm finding
a way out and that's what's happening.
I had to acknowledge that. And
once I did it, I never lost again.
I lost to Paulo, which was,
you know the controversial one.
I lost a to Anderson after dominate,
you know,
I've never been beat since it says I saw
this doctor. That's incredible. Now, Joe,
let me ask you a question. Are you ever
allowed to give a shout out on the show?
Like, do you ever say hi to anybody?
Like if I was to say hi Brittany,
because my girlfriend just
texted musicians watching
the show and I mentioned
the name Brittany to earn myself special
points. Is that going to take you off?
Cause I won't go. And then
I'm going to say, Brittany,
if this is going to be like a cheap
plug in, you're going to get mad.
I'll do it. Hello Brittany.
Thanks for tuning in. Thank
you buddy. Very nice. Yeah,
that's a beautiful story,
man.
I knew there must have had to been
something on the mental side because, um,
you know, I, I remember as you
do that the [inaudible] was a,
an excellent performance and uh, I'm, I
remember being really impressed with that,
but even more so impressed with the
Nate Marquardt fight because, you know,
I knew that you should was a grappler.
I wasn't surprised that you were a,
a stronger grasp within him,
but I was surprised that Nate Marquardt
just couldn't stop you from taking them
down. He just could not stop you
and the way you were doing it,
you were ragdoll on him to the
point where we're like, Jesus,
like this guy is a fucking nightmare for
a of dudes, man. And we started like,
then we started doing the matchups, you
know, you start thinking in your head,
what about him? But when you fought
Anderson, man, whew, that was a,
that was a crazy fight man.
For four minutes or for a four rounds.
And how many minutes into the fifth round?
Four minutes and 31 seconds.
But who's keeping track? Four minutes and
31 seconds. Ava have a five minute round
motherfucker.
What was that like?
What was that like when it happened?
It was devastating. I'll,
I'll tell you what they,
I had no idea what was happening in that
fight. None. And when the fight was over,
I was devastated. And they, they, they, I
came to and I said to the ref, you know,
the typical thing, like a Doofus,
what happened? The referee,
Josh Rosenthal is a fantastic referee.
Simply says,
you tapped out and he
looks at me for a response.
Like I was going to argue and I
simply say, I believe you now.
I knew that because ESPN zoomed in on
that and showed it. But that's all I said.
I said, I believe you and I, and that was,
remember what happened when
you, when you were, did you, uh,
think of tapping and you went out?
Like what happened?
No, I, I remember
falling asleep. You know,
it's a very weird experience if you've
ever been at, and I know you practice it,
so you have been, but it's a
very weird experience. You know,
when you're actually going asleep
and you're, but you're trying to, to,
to stay within reality. And I remember
having a dream thinking, well, if I tap,
I could get out of this now let's not
tab and fight was over. And you know,
I had already tagged that if I hit
his split and I didn't fully know what
happened when it was over and I came to,
I didn't fully know what I'm trying to
figure out what just happened. Yeah.
Most people by the way,
who have never been choked out.
We'll never be able to understand that.
And they'll,
they'll call like fake tap and this
nap. But you, unless you've done it,
unless you've been choked,
you really don't understand
how confusing it is. Sure.
There's a lot of guys who don't,
they don't know what happened. Right.
When they wake up.
It's a mess.
And I,
and I'm one of those guys,
I was with the other people where
I would always see fighters go,
what happened after they got knocked as
it come on, dummy. You know what happened?
No, you don't. You're sure.
Especially from a concussion.
Yes. Especially from chaos.
Absolutely don't know. You know? So aside
from being choked, you know, don't forget,
don't forget, I've got fatigue issues.
I got blood and Vaseline in my eyes.
I got exhaustion, I got a anxiety. I
get it. See, I'm a normal human being.
I feel every emotion. So many people say
to me, Oh, you're never scared. Yeah,
I come on, I'm a human. It fill
it all. But uh, you know, so what?
So I lose the fight.
We go in the back and they bring
me the fight of the night check.
They pay you immediately. If you get a
bonus, boom. Here, here's your check.
And I remember thinking,
you gave me that at a sympathy because
that was such a boring fight. You know,
nothing happened. You gave me that
as simple, I'll take it. You know,
I'm fighting back the tears.
I'm just devastated.
Absolutely devastated by this defeat.
And later the fight gets named
not only fight of the night,
it was called fight of the year. We won
the award from a fighter's only magazine,
which puts on the award show,
uh, for fight of the year.
So it ended up being a really good fight.
But my point that I'm trying to get at,
that's how out of touch I was with what
was happening in the ring. You know,
at one point my cornerman told me it's
round four when it was around five or he
told me it was round four when it
was around, through whatever it was,
the corner had the
rounds off. Um, you know,
the instruction I was getting was a little
bit off and I just didn't fully know
what was going on. And in this
next fight I'd like to, you know,
as I visualize and plan for it,
that's one of the things I'd like to be
a little more aware and a little more in
touch with what's happening. But, uh,
it's hard. It's hard in the octagon, man.
A lot of stuff goes out the window.
You get hit, you get kicked, you get,
it's tough.
It's tough to stay focused.
How tough is it to describe to someone
who's never had that experience?
It's almost impossible. You know, I
almost can't do it. It's like when you,
you know,
an executive director comes at you and
wants to know that we were talking about
earlier, hey, why did you do this?
And you're kind of going, you know,
I don't really know how
to put it into words.
And I don't mean this condescendingly,
but obviously you've never been in
that spot because it's one of those
indescribable feelings.
And when you have victory,
that's also an indescribable feeling.
When you make that walk in front of
17,000 people screaming, cheering, booing,
whatever it is, that's also
an indescribable feeling. Uh,
so it's a very unique sport. And you know,
people will always ask me on Game Day,
are you ready? Are you excited
and a, are you scared? You know,
you'll get these questions.
And the answer is no,
but I can't tell you what I am either.
For all the human emotions
that have definitions,
I don't know how to describe
what it's like on fight day.
It's a combination of many things
and if we're going to be truthful,
most of them are unpleasant.
It's a very stressful situation.
You know, you're walking into
battle, you've prepared for this,
and it's all on the line and it's
on the line in front of everybody.
And there's a great relief if you
have victory in a great despair,
if you have defeat.
Absolutely.
Proportionately used a very interesting
word there that surprise me that you,
you, you, you said relief. You didn't
say happy. You said relief and Joe,
you could not be more correct.
I,
I had a fight with Brian Stann after I
was out for 14 months dealing after the
Anderson loss.
I had to deal with the commission.
I didn't go back and deal with these
guys. I got this suspension. I got it.
Everything puts me off for 14 months.
It was eight days later before I was
back to myself emotionally because all I
was for that week plus was relieved.
It was the ultimate exhale of
my life. I wasn't happy. I won.
I wasn't excited. I was
relieved. It was over.
I was just relieved that I
made it through, you know,
from the way into the
process to the licensing.
I made it through and got out of there.
That's very interesting that
you use that word. Well,
I used to experience a relief
from taekwondo tournaments,
which in comparison to MMA is
absolutely, it's benign. I mean,
it's not,
not even remotely as draining
as physically demanding,
as scary. You know? All the above, but
I still would get a great relief when,
when I was, when I was done, you know,
I go through a tournament, it'd over,
I could rest
for a couple of weeks.
It wouldn't have to thank,
and then when I finally
stopped competing completely,
it was the weirdest feeling ever.
This weird feeling of not worrying
about six months in the future,
like don't have a drink
now because if you do,
what if you want up getting drunk and
then you can't train as well tomorrow and
then six weeks in the future you're,
you're off and you lose because
you fucked up and you slacked off.
There was always this
impending doom cycle, but MMA,
it's gotta be 100,000 times.
That last time I tried to sneak
out of here to go to the bathroom.
You made an announcement, chill, you're
going to urinate. Don't tell anybody.
It embarrasses me and me just sneak out
like a little kid. So don't mention it.
I won't say I'm going to run out of it,
but I don't want you to tell it.
I won't even talk about it. Are
you going to snap it down? Joe,
I want to tell you this though,
when I come back cause I don't
know what our timeline is.
Story that I want to make sure I tell.
Do you know who DB Cooper is? Yes,
I do bring him up when I
come back. Okay. I will.
Powerful Chelsea on ladies and gentlemen.
I don't know what he's doing.
I don't ask a man. Ask
a man what kind of, uh,
movements he's doing so
that, that, that note,
that Samsung Galaxy note or whatever.
Oh,
we're talking about the giant cell
phones. Yeah, it's a, it's, if it has,
no one's seen it. It's pretty much
maybe this big. It's 5.3 inch,
5.3 so it's like, it's, it's like
almost like a small kindle or small
tablet and it's a phone and it slips into
your pocket and it has a crazy process
or really ridiculously fast.
Giant screen.
You can draw on pictures like socket,
I'm here with stupid.
He could take pictures and like
you could draw on them. You,
when you watch a web pages on it,
it's incredible.
It's the best cell phone
web experience ever.
There's been a lot of talks that the
iPads is going to have a smaller version,
like a seven inch version of it.
Unless the phone, I don't give a fuck.
They should make a five inch phone. Just
make it stop beds. We like big shit.
I use my phone half the time to
look at my email half the time to,
you know,
I mean between 50 and 60% of the
time is not making phone calls.
It's doing other cool shit.
Getting online,
got pocket things going
to be a pain in the ass.
I bet that note is just a pain like it
having an old trio pocket or something.
I'm glad you asked this Brian,
because I have recently gone back
to the fanny pack. I got a new one.
I ordered one from roots because Andrew
dice clay had it when we were doing the
podcast with him and the
other day I remember that.
Yeah, you got it. You got to,
I got dice class.
I did get a little jealous
of is fantastically designed
fanny pack. I was like,
that's a real goddamn fanny pack.
So I ordered one online and two days
later I got it and I'm very happy.
So I'd carry that note around
gladly inside my fanny pack.
I'm bringing back the fanny pack strong.
By the way, shout out to Chris Liebing.
There was photos of Chris Liebing in
Hawaii wearing a fanny pack. Way To go,
Chris,
keep on rocking in the free world.
You know, you, you bring up Chris leave.
But if I can jump in here real fast,
I don't know if I'm
interrupting something, but
uh, uh, I threw, in any event,
I throw an event,
it was like an after party with
jail and it was a colossal failure.
Nobody shows that we've got 18 people.
We've got this whole to ourself, you know,
we get drinks, we've got a DJ
with, it's a massive failure.
So we ended up turning the radio off
and we all just end up sitting down and
talking. And by the end of the night,
it couldn't have gone any better.
I know everybody, I, okay, this guy's
on his, uh, you know his honeymoon.
This guy's wife bought in presence.
These, these guys, it's their anniversary.
I know everybody in the room. I know him
by name. I know what city they're from.
We spent about three hours talking
and I'm telling them stories.
I'm telling them stories of UFC behind
the scenes stuff, you know. Um, and I'm,
I'm running out of stories. They're like,
tell us another story. And I'm like,
you know, it was great
stories. Is Chris leaving?
The problem is he never answers his phone.
So they're like, call Chris, you know,
so I'm getting peer pressure to do so
I'm calling Chris on Speaker. I call him,
he answers his phone. I go leave
and his tail. I'm at an afterparty.
You're on speaker. I've got about 20
people here. They can all hear you.
I've been telling stories and I'm out.
I need you to tell one. And he's like,
you want to tell him a story?
Why don't you tell about the time that
my mom hit a deer loaded in the back of
her hatchback for God about it for two
weeks. Then her and my uncle come over,
throw it on the kitchen table, cut it
up with chainsaws. I've been in my room.
I'd been punished because I got sent
home from school and a detention.
So they make me sample the meat to make
sure it's not rancid and I end up in the
hospital for three weeks with the Cola.
Why don't you tell him that story?
He doesn't miss a beat.
He just rattles this story off.
He puts this whole Party on its head.
I mean these people, nobody left.
They are in shock, including me. I'm
in shot. Wait a minute. Your mother.
I got to go, Chris. I gotta
go. Thanks. I just hang up.
And because he did that for me because
he told this story to this disaster party
that I threw. I've always been grateful
and indebted to him. Like Chris,
I owe you went, you know you saved me
a so there's my shout out to Chris Lee,
but how's that for a great story?
That's a fucking great story.
Cause it same shit when a childhood.
Wow. Oh he can go on and on.
Chris and Chris has some
other great stories. You know,
some guys have a rough man. That's
rough. Wow, that sucks. Yeah.
Chris is Chris. Chris, his aunt and uncle
greatly raised him. So he goes out on,
uh, what do you call it?
Jet Skiing or whatever.
Whatever you do on the water skiing.
And he's out with his uncle and aunt and
his uncle is drinking and they t bone
above and his, his aunt, the
uncles wife is back on the shore.
Sunbae then she doesn't go out with them.
The team on a boat and they hurt
the people. So the people, the,
the wife goes over and they're helping
the wife of the other boat is going over.
So they get the husband and the
wife and the boat and you know,
she's not that bad, but she fell over
in her boat, doesn't run anymore.
So the uncles tell him, listen,
listen, I've been drinking.
I don't have insurance,
but I really will make this right with
you if you just don't call the police.
As a matter of fact, here's
my name, here's my number.
Please call me and let's settle this. So
yeah, anything and just get us to shore.
You know, I got to get the
hospital, how my leg looked at.
They pull up to the shore,
the ant stands up cause she sees
there's some woman on the boat.
She wants to know what Hell's going on.
So she gets
a little bit closer and she sees this
woman is holding Chris's uncle's a piece
of paper with his name and number on it.
She has no idea. She's been t bunches,
no idea.
They've rescued him taking them to the
hospital and it's her husband's fault is
she?
She sees the number with his name on it.
It says that's my husband and bitch and
slaps the woman who's on her way to the
hospital cause she got t boned by the
uncle. So this is Chris's childhood.
So you like the Chris leaves or I could
go on and on and on. As a matter of fact,
I bought for $100 I bought a bunch of
Chris Liebing stories. But they backed by.
Yeah. But then he started telling people
that these were his stories. Chris,
that's not your story. That's my story.
That didn't happen with your uncle.
My uncle did and he doubled and I got
the idea from a Seinfeld where Kramer
bought a bunch of Peterman stories.
So I paid Chris everything.
He took the money and then he still was
trying to claim this stuff happen to him.
So I didn't really work out for me.
How did you keep his story
straight in your head?
Why just do cause he's got three crazy
stories and get the store manager to buy.
I bought them all. I bought the whole
gamut. We went to Japan together.
It's a nine hour flight. And so he told
story after story. So I bought ourselves,
give you 100 bucks for the story.
But he didn't know how it worked.
He apparently thought this was some funny
deal where he takes my money and goes,
buys a little Saki and Sushi
for the, just say, no, no, no.
Those are no mice or he didn't
get the Gig. He didn't get it.
So he double crossed me, took the
money and he took the stories back.
I got nothing. I had to write my own
book. I don't remember if I own stories.
Chris Liebing stories would have been
better. Oh, that's fucking hilarious.
I've never heard of anybody
buying someone's stories.
Paid $100 for it because
that was a lot of money.
But I only got $1,000
for the fight over there.
Holy Shit. That's funny. Oh
my God. That is ridiculous.
Now what the fuck was it like going to
Brazil? You went to Brazil recently,
you know,
after all this shit that you talked about
Brazil and minister to the Minotauro
Nogueira brothers. Okay. Nothing's
funny isn't that a bus was a horse.
That's funny you say that
because good for you.
Because sometimes when you're talking
about Nogueira people forget there's two
and they're our brothers. You know,
and you need to be specific, you know,
are you talking about the
big one or the little one?
Are you talking about the fat one or the
Baldwin or talking about the one that
used to be good or the one that never was.
And it's important that you say that.
So good for you for
saying there's brothers.
Cause a lot of people just think
it's the same guy filling in,
but it's actually to, what was it
like when you went to Brazil? Awesome.
You want to know what I had a
great time is really Brittany
got to go, uh, you know,
we go out with Dana. Um,
and we were only there for four hours
and you know, first off, Rio's beautiful.
And I've been to Brazil before. In fact,
I was at Abi Dhabi one that you were,
I don't know. I don't know if you would
have known who I was back then. But when,
when, uh, Eddie, uh, beat
a Heuler, what was it?
2003 I believe in Sao Paulo. In fact, I
was there, uh, Ryan Parsons was with us.
At any rate, I had been to Brazil before
you do it with Matt. And I loved it.
I wrestled myself. I lost to a cocker
Rico, Mr Guillotine. Remember that guy?
I think a strong, anyhow, Luke
to leave speed up the story.
So we get there and we got our own
security detail and it's tight.
I mean these are,
these are some bad looking dudes and a,
I'm surrounded with tough
looking guys all the time.
This was a whole nother level man.
These guys got the scars,
these guys got the bullet holes.
These guys got the,
the stitching and the whole bit where
you get that. Anyway, we're with,
we got this bad team now. I've never been
on a helicopter, but I love carnivals,
I love rides.
So we go everywhere by helicopter,
which apparently is
extremely common in Brazil.
It's like the number one a
hell port country in the world.
So these are good helicopters
with pilots are very reputable.
And next thing I know we're up in the air.
So this is the ultimate carnival ride.
Now we're there on a gorgeous day in Rio,
which is a gorgeous city and we've
got it from a bird's eye view.
I mean I would take that whole
trip, all the risk, all the danger,
everything that I had to go through
for that 15 minute helicopter ride. Um,
I'm a Catholic.
I went over this church.
That's like one of the wonders of the
world. It's not, it's not quite as, uh,
you know, eighth wonder of
the world, like the pyramids,
but it's close where you look at and go,
how in the heck did you build that
hundreds of years ago up on this cliff?
There's no roads up to it. You got to
walk. It's just, just incredible. Well,
there's a lot of speculation about the
history of Brazil. It's coming to light.
Recently I think there's
some Roman artifacts.
They found some really ancient
stuff and uh, some, uh,
there's some dispute about there,
found some offshore records or
something like that. So they, uh,
they're now thinking that maybe the Romans
had even a visited Brazil even before
the Portuguese.
Pretty a amazing country.
When you stop and think about the history,
the history of it. Yeah. You know,
so I have a feeling when you asked me
what was it like how are we received?
Is there any threads? And, uh, you know,
the way I like to tell it as that it was,
it was a scene, man. It was, we were,
we were, we were down in the trenches
over there. But you know the reality,
I really liked it there. And
it's interesting, everybody
knows who we are there.
You know, if I want to be famous in
America, Joe, I got to go to a fight.
If I go to a fight, I'm a big deal.
If I'm not at a fight, I'm not,
I'm just regular guy, which is
just fine. But I mean, you know,
sometimes people lose sight of that.
And in Brazil they all knew who we were.
You know, they definitely knew
Dana and they all knew who I was.
And I mean all of them,
from the bus drivers to the people,
to the people working the
desk to the cops, everybody,
the people at the airports.
And here's how Dana described it to me.
He goes to jail.
Everybody watches a playoff game
for the NFL in America. Right?
Everybody watched that go. Yeah, everybody
watches it play off. He goes, okay,
that everybody has 15 million Americans.
He said in Brazil,
80 million Brazilians tuned in when
Vandelay or rather when Anderson and v Tor
fought.
So those are the kinds of numbers.
That's how inundated people are with
this sport. And that's prior to us bring,
bringing them this new ultimate fighter
with Vandelay and [inaudible] that's
airing. So what I'm getting at is
this sports huge over there. And,
and until you're there, you
don't realize it. And uh, so
at any rate, you know, I'm getting
recognized left and right, and that's fun.
That's fun for my ego. I'm
having a good time. You know,
I'm somebody and they want to talk to me.
They want an autograph.
They're all very nice.
Now,
I didn't really have time to exhale
and enjoy this because I've got so many
death threats that are very legitimate.
You know,
guys not only telling me
they're going to kill me,
they're telling me how they're telling
me when they're telling me the,
the lake they're going to
drag my body into. You know,
I've got this security team because
the U of C's been warned, you know,
so I'm on edge constantly and I see
some kid. Is that the kid? Is that the,
is this the guy? You know, I'm constantly
looking around. I want, I'm only human.
This is how my mind's working. So by the
time we left, the experience was great.
Looking back at the time I was there,
you're on edge.
You know you're looking around. Who's
the God? Who's The guy? You know?
My Dad had a real basic rule when
you thought you were in trouble,
don't let anybody within arm's reach.
If the guide comes with an arm's reach,
hit him.
Don't wait for this first punch crap.
If you feel you're in danger
and it gets within arm's reach,
you strike first and get out of there.
Everybody's on you like this.
So I'm baking.
I'm going against the most basic rule
my own father taught me when I'm seven
years old. And that's let people
in close when you're scared.
So I've got my back up against the wall.
You don't have fallen his second rule,
but the first one is completely,
completely broken. But you know,
we had a good time.
We were you
like the fight was supposed to take place
for people who don't know the rematch
between chill and for folks
who weren't following MMA,
a lot of people that listen to this
podcast aren't even MMA fans. You, uh,
after, after the Anderson
Silva fight you, you said a,
a bunch of crazy shit about Brazil,
about insulted them quite a bit.
And then they were going to have the
rematch and an 80,000 seat soccer arena in
Brazil. But unfortunately because
the UN is having a visit there, uh,
two days before there was no hotels,
there was logistically almost impossible
to bring that many people into an
80,000 seat arena was just,
it wasn't going to happen.
So it's been moved to Las
Vegas. Was that good? Was it,
were you happy when it was moved to Vegas?
You
know, if I had, if I have to answer
yes or no, the answer is yes,
but there's also a tremendous no,
and the no is simply that I was going
to get a be part of history and the
current record is Toronto St
Pierre Versus Shields 55,000 live.
We were going to do 80 to
a hundred thousand live and
that would have been very
hard to beat. So I could have taken
that record for not only currently but,
but maybe into my future years and
pass that story down to generations.
And you know, again,
that's an ego boost and,
and there's something to be said for that.
If we're,
if we're being candid that I'd
want the other side of his, she's,
I don't want to fly 14 hours
anywhere while I'm cutting weight.
Now somebody has to, Anderson
did it the last time. Uh,
and we fought in California. So, and
fairness, I'll, I'll go out there,
but how much does Anderson
could, you know, I don't know.
He probably weighs about two 20. I've
been next to me, he looks as big as me.
I'm riding around two 20, a little taller,
so it's hard to judge. But uh, you know,
looking Anderson lives in California,
so he flies to hours to Vegas.
I'm an Oregon is two hours to Vegas
and we both got home field and manage.
What's the difference in that?
In that aspect of it?
Yeah. The cutting weight is a, it's a
very strange aspect of MMA isn't it?
It's really almost like an art
and a discipline in and of itself.
And a battle,
you know,
you could be a black belt in cutting
weight or you could be a white belt and a,
you know, to compare it to being like
martial arts. Like you said it is.
Some guys are skilled in it. Some guys are
experts. You get your mic, dolce chase,
they got more secrets than, than you
could imagine to get weight off in.
Other guys aren't either guys starved
because they don't know what else to do or
they miss wait, you know,
we see guys miss wait too.
And that's a big deal when you
sign a contract. That's part of it.
And you've got to honor that.
How,
how much of your thought process would
have been dedicated if there was a fight,
how much of it would have been
just to worried about your,
be worried about your safety, constantly
worried about your food being poisoned,
worry about someone fucking with you.
I mean,
what would have been like to compete
under that sort of an environment that if
folks who don't know, I've never seen
a crowd more nationalistic than Brazil.
It's amazing how patron
they get it, right? That's the way
you should be. They get it right.
You fucking get it right, your
back, your guy, they do that,
Lynn. But in England they also, when
when a fighter wins, the guy wins.
They applaud his skill. Even if a
guy beats a hometown guy, you know,
I've seen it in London,
I've seen them applaud when a fighter
beat a local English guy and they were
talking afterwards. But man, it doesn't
happen in Brazil. Mike Pyle one,
he beat Ricardo Funche and they were
all together chanting some sort of gay
slur, Portuguese gay slur. Yeah.
And I was like, no, I'm aware. You know
that's unfortunate when that happens.
You know, you don't want to behave
like a savage or or or, or uncivilized.
I mean we are in a society here and
if you're a fan of you buy a ticket,
you can share bu whoever you want,
but that's where it ends.
Don't touch a guy I won't touch. I don't
like all the fans. I like most of them.
I don't like 'em all but I never touch
one. But the same thing goes for them.
If you're a fan,
you don't reach over that rail and slap
it a guy and throw your drink on. I mean,
what do you think it would have been
like though if you would one in Brazil in
front of 80,000
it would have been a scene. I don't
think they could've controlled it. They,
they swore that they could,
they'd have presidential security there.
They were planning to have the president
of Brazil there so they'd have their
secret services. It's like,
guys, you can't do it.
Know there was just a soccer game.
There was just a soccer game and 73
people were trampled to death. You know,
you can't control crowds when they
decide to storm. You just can't.
It's displaced responsibility. I'm
a sociologist, I, I've studied this.
I've written papers on displaced
responsibility. You can't control that.
Especially when I'm the main event.
And the relevance to that is it means
the beer started pouring five hours
earlier. So now you're not only
talking to insightful crowd,
you're talking about a drunk crowd.
And a,
what I'm referring to is if I beat
Anderson up, I go into Brazil,
I stomped their he row. Uh, and then
I'm going to do an interview with you.
And it's not gonna stop and I'm not
gonna apologize to any one of them.
So how they thought they were to control
that, I don't know. But uh, you know,
if the, what did you think was going
to happen? I think they would have,
I think it would have been bad. I think
it would have been very, very bad and I,
and I would not have,
have,
have backed off one bit because
I'm not going to change, you know,
I'm going to dance with the one that
brought me. I'm going to be aggressive.
I'm going to be in your face. I'm going
to get my mind right, my approach right.
I'm going to do my job as soon as Bruce
buffer gets out of my way. And, uh,
and that's it. And I can't change,
I mean, I don't know how to change.
This is what I'm programmed
to do. And uh, you know,
I hate to talk like one of
those main x Oh, to give him
my life pub, Blah. But Joe,
I swear to you,
hand to God,
I'd given my life to win that
championship if I had to. Whoa.
I mean, let's not forget,
this is a tough guy talk.
I signed the contract to go to Brazil to
do the fight. And in my heart I thought,
I don't know how this is going to go.
I made my mother promise you wouldn't go.
You know, my mother doesn't
get it. She's an older woman.
She's got a ruby or a diamond
on every finger. You know,
you don't go into South America
like that level on a fight.
It was just one of those deals. But
it, look, this is what I'm going to do.
Wow. That's a crazy stance,
man. That's a crazy mindset.
I agree. I don't know that I'm
proud of that. I don't, I don't,
I don't mean to sit here and
sound like a big tough guy.
That's not really what I'm doing. I'm
just trying to be candid, but you know,
this is what I'm going to do
at work my whole life for it.
And if this is how it ends is how it ends,
but I'm going to get that before I go.
You can't really discount the amount of,
uh,
a boost the hometown fighter would get
from a crowd like that or the amount of
shock, the, uh,
the opponent would get from 80,000 people
bullying you and you are ready to jump
right into.
Well, that was one of my
favorite things. You know,
some guys beg for applause and I've seen
some fighters, it hurts their feelings.
You know, John John's golf,
she hates if anybody booze.
And I'm on the other side of that
man. I just, I like it. I like it.
I love it when they cheer too.
You know,
I'm not the guy that feeds off negativity,
but I do feed off of it. You know,
if a guy,
I'll pay three and a half dollars for
an overpriced drink at the MGM and throw
it on me. That's a compliment to me.
You know, if five incited him that much,
he's a fan. And how often does
that happen? It's happened
a few times. You know,
where they've thrown something.
I've actually never had a drink.
I had one guy so mad he took his own
hat off his head and throw it at me.
He missed. But you
know, you get the point.
I kind of felt like I was wanting to
hand it back to them. But you know,
it's one of those deals, but you know,
they get so insightful. But you know,
don't forget the other side of that coin.
Not only are they upset with me,
but they're cheering. They're guy. You
know, if you want to back your guy,
you're a fan man. You work hard for that
money. You took the night off, you know,
you, you talk dad into bringing
out to the fight, be a fee.
Don't touch anybody but be a fan
even if that means to bu. So what,
that's interesting.
That's a very interesting point of view.
I would prefer people not boo cause it's
kind of cunty and it's disrespectful
for someone who is doing
what is essentially the most
difficult sport known to
man and doing it for your
and just because it doesn't go the
way of the fight or that you like,
you're going to boo and
hiss and say stupid shit.
That shows a massive level of immaturity
that I don't necessarily think we need
in this world. I think it's, it's 2012
and you stupid asses need to catch up.
That's what I'd think. Sure.
I know. So fair opinion.
When I hear people blew at a good fight,
I'm like,
that can't be anybody other than a fucking
moron. Right. You know, and I hear that.
I'll hear that, but he doesn't. Sometimes
I bite my tongue and sometimes I don't.
But when sometimes people
are booing a good fight,
a good positional battle or you know,
a good, they don't understand it,
so they're booing or it goes
to the ground, so they're
born. It's just a, it's so,
it's so stupid and disrespectful.
Meanwhile,
these same dump Fox will sit
there and watch baseball.
They'll watch a live baseball game. One
of the most boring events known to man.
Something that you could never introduce
to another country in 2012 you could
never bring baseball today.
They'd be like boring as fuck.
Silly all with the stick game.
You look at football and people just
adored in this country. And again,
good for them. But you know, in
a four and a half hour NFL game,
there are seven and a
half minutes of action.
If you start the timer and you turn it
on, I'm going, you know, I, I can't,
I can't play along that. That's
exciting. You know, I don't know.
I don't know that I have add,
but I do for that.
You're going to do it and
then you're going to take a
break. And then these, the,
these big, large, but they're
all muscled up and they see,
they run to their mailbox.
They got to stop at the neighbor's kid's
lemonade stand there. So out of shape.
You know, these guys, they played
for seven and half minutes.
You know how many times they're good with
the water bucket? What are you doing?
Good. How are you possibly tired? I miss,
and you're doing your show for
several hours. I don't know.
I don't have anything to
drink. You know, what are they?
They're dragging down the Gatorade.
It's, hey, I don't get it. You know,
and some people cheer these
guys. It's like, you know,
good for you. I know. I'm the,
I'm the minority.
I'm the one missing out.
My life would be better if I can really
get into sports and have something to do
that because I'd have something
to do. You know, I used to,
I used to have to count down
you fcs, which were five a
year, you know, six a year.
And then pride would do four or five.
You know what?
I would count those days down,
literally count on dummy
and my dad would be titanic.
Abbott's going to fight this
guy. We yell, it's not missing.
We're going to have a party. And, uh,
you know, so what I'm saying is if I,
if I could get in that same passion for
other sports, I'd have a better life.
I'd have hobbies.
I have something to do like my friends
and sit up and they watch sports center
and somehow they're entertained by that.
I don't get as good.
I think you're better off without it.
And I don't,
I don't think it's bad to have one
or two sports that you're into.
There's nothing wrong with that.
But I know guys who their whole life was
just following other people doing shit.
And I hear you. I hear you. That happens
a lot. I can't get behind football.
I appreciate it.
I respect them as athletes,
some incredible athletes and
football. But it, to me, it's just,
I don't care what you do with that ball.
It doesn't mean anything to me. Yeah, no,
I understand. You know, I mean, I was
on Jim Rome earlier today and it's like,
you know,
Jim,
how many times have you had to sit
here and interview a golfer or a tennis
player or a Nascar guy?
Could you imagine being a NASCAR,
you push your foot down and you make
left turns all afternoon long and somehow
that's a,
that's a meaningful event to society. And
I'm scratching my head going, you know,
I wish that I was one of those
guys that enjoy this, but I just,
I don't get you're making left
turns all Sunday afternoons. What?
Damning appraisals of America. Yeah. And
I just, I don't understand it. You know,
I'm talking to Jim Rome and it's
like, you know, Jim, good for you.
You finally got that he's
somebody and you know, you're,
you're welcoming and he is very welcome.
He's an absolute ally to the UFC.
You know, Dana White went on a rant one
time. It was great against ESPN where he,
you know,
Dana was mad Esbi Mri and then he finishes
by going the only thing good as Jim
Rome, you know, he didn't, he,
he made sure to give Jim that property
cause Jim deserves it. He's one of the,
those leaders that came
out and he embraced, uh,
martial arts and the UFC to be specific.
Yeah. Good for him. I'm glad he did that.
Now I want to tell you this story.
Can I? Okay. So I wrote this book, uh,
the voice of reason
which comes out tomorrow.
Let me give myself a chip pass to
enlightened. Thank you very much.
Vip Pass the layman, the
hips, the bookshelves.
Tomorrow is available
right now@amazon.com. This
isn't a plug for the book.
That was a plug. I'm done. Okay.
I want to tell you a story.
I've only told the story twice in my life,
so I don't know if I'm good at telling it.
I told this e w when you
write a book these days,
you don't actually have to write anything.
You talk it all out.
It all goes into the stance of
whatever they call it. And then they,
they go back and they type it out for you.
So I tell this story and
I know who DB Cooper is.
Okay. I know who DB Cooper is.
My whole family knows and it's,
it's been like a family secret or,
or however for a number of years.
So you know who the guy is.
I know who he is.
He's alive and well and a lot of
times over the past few years,
somebody will be on their deathbed.
You know,
this just happened about four years ago.
The guys on his deathbed and he
comes out and says, I'm DB Cooper.
And he tells his whole family and they
go to the media and the media jumps
mining and says,
well,
it must be true because why else would
you want to go down as a criminal on your
deathbed?
And I'm sitting there and I told everybody
that would listen when they look into
these facts of this guy's putting
out, I assure you, that won't be DB.
I told everybody,
but I never told them why.
I never told him how I was so confident.
It's my big, big worldwide news.
DB Cooper case finally saw and then they
unraveled it. And sure enough it was,
if I told everybody that wasn't him.
Well the reason I knew it wasn't
him was I know who db Cooper is.
My whole family knew and it was a
secret and my father passed away.
So now the seat now,
now my oath to keep it a
secret has also passed away.
I don't feel that I, I can't reveal
the story. He's alive and well.
I know exactly who he is. So I tell
the story in my book and you know,
there's a lot of things that happened
in the DB Cooper case and so I need to
really make this shorter. I could take
up your whole a whole show with this,
but once folks who don't
know who db Cooper is, once
we explain that very famous,
he's the world's most famous hijacker
and I believe he's the most famous one
because he was never caught but two,
he may have been the first hijacker and
I want to say this happened like in the
70s and db Cooper hijacks a plane, he
makes it through security or securities,
totally different back then, gets on
board. He's in a cheap disguise. Uh,
he orders the plane, be touched down,
says he's got a device in a bomb,
a bomb in his, in his, in his bag,
shows it to a flight attendant.
They touched down. There he is, brings him
up on that. Now that's a sketch deposit.
Of course, nobody knows what he
actually looks like, but that,
that's the sketch deposit. If the
viewers can see that. So at any rate,
they touched the plane down,
they bring him as 200,000 in cash and
unmarked bills and they go back up. Well,
while the Rup he parachutes,
they don't know he's got a parachute.
Now where the story gets
interesting is he was never found,
but the money wasn't either. No sign of
him was found. His parachute wasn't found,
his body wasn't found.
And one of the things that was a problem
is where he jumped was a mass forest.
I mean miles upon miles,
hundreds and hundreds of thousands
of square acres of nothing but four.
So basically what any expert would
say is, look, he didn't make it.
If he even made the fall, he would have
been eaten by coyotes or bay there.
There's good reason why we never found
his body and it's not because he made it
out of their life. Okay, now you
need a couple of those details.
So how do I know him?
Well,
a family friend and I
put this all in the book,
I put all of this in the book
and the publisher didn't use it.
And the reason he wouldn't use it is
because I won't tell the ne I tell the
whole story and about to do that for
you now, but I don't reveal the name.
He goes with with how to name, I can't
use it. I go, wait, that's ridiculous.
I can touch on every single
detail you're not. And I,
and I'm telling my poster going, hey,
I don't think you know who db coopers,
I think you should.
I think you should Google him.
You know there's movies made on him.
Prison break just had a
character pretending to be
db Cooper folklore has been
made out of this guy.
Well where this guy jumped was,
was government land,
but that land backed up to Indian land
and this gentleman was part Indian and he
grew up in this forest.
This is where he spent his summers,
months after months.
They would go out and camp in there,
you know, in between school breaks.
From the time he was a
little kid all the way on,
he knew right where he was jumping
and if anybody could have made it,
it was this guy.
Now my dad grew up with this guy.
He was a family friend
and back then parachuting,
well much like now is very uncommon.
If somebody does it,
you go tell all your friends, I found
this parachuting class I'm going to do,
they take pictures and they showed up.
This guy was taking parachute and lessons.
He didn't tell anybody.
And uh,
and he started taking
motorcycle classes and stuff.
It wasn't telling anybody he was
racing these bikes. That's one of,
that's what my dad personally believes
that we never got the story that he pity
parachuted,
had a hidden motorcycle and rolled it out.
That's my dad's personal
theory. So, you know,
all this stuff comes down
and, and many years later, uh,
the statute of limitations is up and all
of a sudden this guy starts collecting
a,
a pretty good assortment of toys from
shotguns to four wheelers to motor homes.
My Dad's known him his whole life.
He knows what the guy does for a living.
He knows what his wife does and he,
what the heck's going on here, you know,
how come, where are you getting all this
money? And the guy says, well, you know,
I'm an Indian. And, and uh,
when you reach a certain age,
you get some Indian money and
there's some truth to that.
There is Indian money that's
given out. Uh, if you're, uh,
if you're a native living in America,
but you're talking about like $1,800
a year and when you get older,
about three grand a year, this guy came
into it. Why the assortment of money?
Well,
the sketches came out of DB,
Cooper and it's a spitting image of the
guy. That picture that we looked at. Yeah.
It's just,
wow.
There was different ones of him in the
disguise with the mustache and the whole
bit, but they're going, hey, wait a
minute. This looks just like you. So, uh,
you know, one night my aunt asks him,
they're there. They're at dinner,
they're all family friends. My parents
were there. My aunt and uncle are there.
This guy and his wife were there.
My aunt looks across the table and
flat out says, are you DB Cooper?
And he said, no, but
the way that he said no,
told everybody there that he was,
and they never brought it up again ever
now is it came out and my uncle asked
him a little bit in private,
Hey, well, you know,
that other night we were having
some Chinese food and you, well my,
my parents and uncles weren't the only
one that thought he was the government
did to. So the FBI had visited this guy
than he even moved away for a while.
I went to Arizona and then slowly
came back. Uh, but you know,
he was talked to by the FBI.
I thought he was DB Cooper as well.
So when my dad was on his
deathbed, uh, you know, we,
he and I had, uh, you know,
you ask me whatever you want,
I'll ask you and I'll tell you how
the story really happy. You know,
it's a bit of a fun moment,
uh, between father and son.
Everybody leaves the room and say,
hey,
Dan were really happened that night when
you came in at 2:00 AM smelling like
Bourbon. You know, whatever
really happened that day.
The principal called and claim
that you and your friends are.
So we kind of go back and forth and I
asked him flat out is Blah Blah Blah db
Cooper.
And my dad said,
well all the evidence
is saying that he is,
your uncle believes that your aunt
believes in your mom believes it.
I don't think he had the courage.
I don't think he was.
So my dad's final ruling on his
deathbed was no, he, he said he wasn't.
But uh,
he's DB Cooper.
I know. Real input.
Absolutely. There was another,
a theory that DB Cooper was a serial
killer. That he was a guy who, uh,
had killed his family.
I believe it's even fun that,
what are you looking at Ted coopers
as it some checkers claiming?
How is he looking this up so fast?
It's like you are,
I have the thought and he's got it
on the screen and nimble fingers.
That's very impressive. A few, but
I tell them to give you a massage.
They don't put in the book. He goes,
listen, I can't put it in a book.
If you want to say the guy's
name, go Mike, my father's
store. I can't, you know,
I can't do it. I can't do it.
It's pretty God damn good story.
That's one of those rare folklore type
stories and it just gets passed on and on
and nobody got jumped in Washington state.
You know the jump DB Cooper high end.
He jumped and watch the guy lived
in Oregon. That's where he went.
So you lived in Oregon most of your
life? Yeah, I'm still there. Big Foot.
Yes or no? Well, absolutely. Yes really.
But you know, the big foot makes it sound
like you're some conspiracy theories.
I believe there are Sasquatch.
Uh,
and I believe this because
people that I believe in trust,
including a doctor has said, look, I know
where they are. And it's very hard. Yeah.
He says it's hard to get
to and he's got this plane,
it's got this big grand plan.
He's a survivalist because this whole
plan lined up about how we can get to him
and his personal belief and you know,
it's just a theory,
but he lives in that park is big foot's
supposed to be from the northwest.
He lives in those hills where all these
big foot stories come from and he's like,
look, it's not a big foot like at
some wild monster living out there.
I believe there is a,
a pack of family of Sasquatch
there just haven't been discovered.
We haven't photographed
and learned about them.
I believe there's an entire tribe
of these big foot. Wow. Come.
Nobody's done nothing. No good pictures.
All the pictures are full shit.
All the stories have holes in them.
Oh, tremendously. Tremendously.
Never watched finding big
foot or anything. I do.
I'm embarrassed to admit to you that
that I think there is a Sasquatch.
Should we, you know, cause I know
the kind of people that, that, that,
that I'm asking because you lived up there
and that's where most of the southern
California when they
talk about the bodies,
but the truth is what bodies do you ever
find, you know, bears are out there,
kind of are out there.
Do you ever walk through the forest and
find bear carcasses? Coyote, you know,
you sure don't end to your point,
there's a number of hoaxes.
There's a number of guys dressed up in
a stupid outfit that you could buy any
Halloween run through. Those buddy records
it and they stick it on the Internet.
I get that there's hoaxes but there
is some pretty good footage. You know,
you said there was none. There's a
very good footage. Matter of fact,
I've done a lot of work in the movie
business and and, and stunts and stuff.
And this topic comes up on Hollywood
sets and these are the best guys on earth
for designing things to look like humans.
And they've said that there is one video
where as he moves the muscles in the
body apartment and stunt coordinators and
makeup and costume people in Hollywood
say there is no costume
created to do that. Okay.
They don't all say that. Some of,
I would love to hear what you,
some of them do say that
and I think they're idiots.
And I think if you look at that,
that's a man and a fucking monkey suit.
It's not even a good monkey suit.
And the man who did it
look up the Patterson big foot footage.
Um, the Guy Patterson was a con artist.
Not only was a con artist,
he was arrested for writing a bad check
to buy the very camera that made that
video. Oh God damn. And another guy.
Conveniently what we're looking for
big phobia, embarrass video. If you,
if you break this right in front of me,
cause I've looked into this too because
I live in that area, I believe in, right.
It fascinating. I believe
it's very possible. You know,
one of the reasons why I believe it's
possible because Jane Goodall said it's
positive it yes. This is exactly
kind of monkey suit, bro.
That doesn't even look good. It
looks stupid. Look at his big fat,
stupid fucking shirt as on
big hairy fucking shirt and
big stupid looking shoes.
That's a terrible monkey suit. And he's
just hunching over. Looks good to me, Eh.
Come on and looks good to me. They should
have again. There's other ones, Brian,
that have been a level c. That's the, um,
that's the footage of him falling down.
Some people have said to through
computers there, there you go.
There you see a better, it's a
better video of it. I, no, no,
we just saw it back then. You would
just, you just had it in the middle.
It's a better now again,
I do want to be clear before
I become the conspiracy theorists.
That's what it is. I'm sorry.
The beginning of his zoom,
zoom put, there's one monster.
I believe that there's a seminar and it's,
you know what?
I was told this by a guy that I tried.
That's how everything, they want.
Many ass fucking legs. I got a
ton is not, that's so stupid.
You're making a pretty darn good case
right now. I'm going to have to say I,
I'm starting to rethink that,
but this is video ours. Come on.
Look how dumb that looks.
It's got tits to, what's that?
They have double ds. Za is I what grills
have get the fuck outta here, bitch.
That's fake.
That's fake as fuck.
I have a good fake meter and it
just looks at that thing I look at.
It's big stupid looking shoes that
he's wearing. Those aren't feet.
Get outta here. That's a fucking monkey
suit and it's not even a good one.
They took a video of a guy.
The guy just so happened to be out
there looking for Sasquatch and Oh,
I fell off my horse and immediately
why I had my camera ready.
We saw the big foot to strolling along.
Not a care in the world.
Ooh,
make sure in fairness that if
we dissect that video when we,
when we decided that dice that that
video is garbage. That doesn't make
the whole theory garb. Know people
do. I do not not believe in big foot.
And one of the reasons
why is because where the,
the area where this most Sasquatch
sightings are is right at the end of the
Bering strait and between Alaska and
the northern coast of the United States,
or the, excuse me, the Northwestern
coast of the United States,
that's where all of the
Sasquatch sightings,
the huge majority of them
were for a long time.
They started spreading out
all throughout the country.
And who knows how many of them
are bullshit. The numbers weird,
but the American Indian had to,
the American Indians had over 200
different names for Sasquatch or 20 some,
some of the two something
with it to a bunch of them.
And they don't have like a lot of
mythical animals. They, this was a,
this was a real thing that they thought
lived amongst people and it's a real
animal that used to actually live.
If you follow the Bering Strait in Asia,
it's called gigantor. Pythagoras was an
eight foot tall, like good annunciation.
You're out a huge big foot. It was
essentially bigfoot is the exact animal,
you know.
Now I want to tie this school of
thought that you know, I said, yeah,
I think there's a Sasquatch. You said,
and then we both agreed on this video.
We have different opinions of the video.
However,
if we prove the video one way and
my favorite or yours, it doesn't,
it doesn't prove the answer to our,
our original thesis,
which is is there a big foot?
And you see this, this flaw,
this pitfall is we like to
call it in human thinking.
When it comes to alien encounter, how many
times have we seen somebody that says,
Hey, guess what? I was abducted by aliens
and I was given a special power. In fact,
approve it.
I'm going to go ahead and make that
light turn off by sitting in my chair and
not touching it.
And that will prove to you that I was
abducted by aliens and given this power.
So now I sit here, I make
that light turn off. Okay,
I've got a power to turn that light off.
But having that power does not prove
that I was given that power by being
abducted by aliens.
But there's a pitfall in human thinking
and oftentimes you can get people to
believe one thing,
one way or the other.
They can then connect that to a
completely isolated and separate incident,
which is,
which is what,
I don't want to happen with the video
because I'm realizing right now I'm
looking like a real doofus after looking
at that video, I don't need to get my,
my evidence together and come back.
Got Video was actually not
only was it proven a hoax,
but the guy who played big
foot wound up confessing.
So, uh, yeah. Or is that the
conspiracy? That could be good.
It could be just a guy who look, anytime
there's some sort of a serial killer,
people will come out of the woodwork
to clinic. Like the DB Cooper thing,
the same thing. People were full of
Shit. There people are crazy. Absolutely.
But that just stinks to me. I
look at it, it looks stupid.
I hear people to experts talk about, I'm
like, bitch, what are you talking about?
That doesn't even look remotely real.
It's just it looks dumb.
And the way it was created as the,
the just the odds of this guy finding it
and no one else has gotten a good photo
of it. But that doesn't
mean that it can't be real.
If you fly over the Pacific northwest
and you see how dense that part of the
world is. People, I don't think a lot
of people really truly understand the,
the amount of acreage of really almost
impassable rain forest to deal with.
And the Pacific northwest,
when you fly over these areas where these
people are talking about sightings and
they don't just have sightings, by the
way, they also have real sound effects.
These sounds that are at some sort of
primate that's screaming out and they've
sent these things to experts. You know,
people were just trying to detect hoaxes,
you know,
and these people that have been on
camping and hunting trips recorded these
things and these are primate noises.
They don't know what the fuck it is,
but it's a primate noise.
And one of the guys,
and I think he's a real credible
guy that has had an encounter,
is uh, Les Stroud. You
know the survivor man,
that guy was staying in Alaska.
He was doing one of those survivor
things in Alaska and he said that he was
asleep and he was a inside
is 10 or trying to sleep.
And in the middle of the
night he heard primate noises.
He heard primate noises in the woods
near him and he got out of his bed to try
to look and he heard just
something running and crashing
through the trees when
it hurt him. And to this day he has no
idea what the fuck it could be. It could.
He said it couldn't have been a
bear. He goes, it was very clear.
Primate type noise,
something along those lines.
Something that's just not a bear
and whatever the fuck it was.
He said it was enormous. It might
be possible if there's, it's,
there's enough dense forest that
there might be just a few animal.
I mean try finding a Fox.
Good luck.
Should go try to find a Fox because I do
have a day I was driving in studio city,
I saw a coyote. This motherfucker
just wandering around Cutco.
Try find a coyote in the wild.
Could you just go, go look for one.
And there's millions of those cunts.
Coyotes are everywhere.
To live in the Pacific
northwest to be a primate,
it might be possible of evolution.
So you're talking about a Sasquatch.
You're talking about a
derivative of a human. So you're,
you've got to assume that there are a
little bit more intelligent than say a
coyote. If it's hard to find a coyote
is can be very hard to find a Sasquatch.
If it's true. I mean, I'm
just fueling the fire again.
I don't want to come up with a gun.
I believe it cause the guy happened to
trust just says, look, I think it's true.
And so I'm choosing to believe him
more than I believe the evidence.
How many people do you know that? I've
seen one me at zero, zero. A zero.
Even the guy I trust has never claimed
that he's seen what he just said. Look,
I've looked at the MSI. Just
think they are. I think that there
Goodall,
she's a monkey expert.
She said a hundred percent
really hundred percent sun.
Why you shaking your head? You don't
think so? No. What do you think now?
What's the number?
You think the whole thing is bullshit.
But that goes back to
the alien and counter.
You get people who used to work at the
Pentagon and NASA that combat and claims
there's aliens, you know,
Corso and, and again, it's a,
it's a flaw in human thinking
because the guy works at NASA.
What NASA has got 3,800 desk.
You don't think a crazy
person can get a desk there.
Every now and then the same
thing goes for the Pentagon.
I used to work at the Pentagon. The
Pentagon is never employed. A mad man.
Get outta here. Right? You can show me
an alien, you know, show me in it. Don't,
don't give me a of a pitfall in human
thing. I actually covered this in my book.
It's on page 92 in the voice of reason.
I talk about human pitfalls and it's why
we're able to believe such outlandish
and crazy things.
Do you remember a year or 2000 y two K
we all went into a panic state home with
water I water and canned foods. I stayed
in as well. I didn't have my supplies.
I should have. I was a college. I didn't
have money for what? For the water.
Canned foods, but yeah. You know,
we all buy into it and it's,
it's this hysteria with no evidence.
Real loose evidence.
2012 December 21st end of the Mayan
calendar. That's another one. Huh?
Except recently they found newer versions
of the Mayan calendar that they a had
never discovered before that were more
complete that go far past December 21st
it's 10 year, 10 more years of
moneymaking. Yeah. You know what I mean?
You got 10 more years of Paul and son.
How you feel about that?
No. Thank you for that line. You'll
finally contributed today's show.
Besides setting the whole thing on.
Nice to see you pipe in over there.
You look like an intelligent guy.
You just haven't said much to them.
Do you think he looks like
he's an intelligent guy? I was.
It was really saying chill son and he
knows how to read a map right up right up
until that,
but he got all these
wires, man. I know he's,
I know he's done something
today that we couldn't, it
got an odd form of intelligence. It's
true. What would you describe it as?
What?
Why do I sent meant and meant by that?
My encounter is that it was Tim or
years for the people that are behind the
whole thing to make more money to say,
oh,
we said 2012 we met in
2022 there's a what books?
There's fucking products.
Why do you remember that one?
When we had Pinchbeck end and he's like
convinced that something's happening.
It's like anytime you're convinced
of anything, I'm like, what?
You know it's going to go down to come me
is falling apart right before our eyes.
It can rebound. I said it hasn't been
around a long time. Exactly. Yeah.
It kind of flexible.
Isn't there a bunch of people like fucking
with it right now and trying to put
it back together again?
You think they're not gonna be able to
figure out why they figured it out in the
first place? And do you even barely
understand it? Cause I barely do.
Or watch the stock market
scroll across my screen.
It might as well be Mayan Hieroglyphs.
Right.
I don't know what the fuck that means.
Do you know what any of that stuff means?
No. Yeah, and yet the ones without us.
Yeah. No, I, the bottom line
is relaxed. You know, it'll,
it'll, it'll work itself out.
Yeah, things might get tough, but how
spoiled are we anyway, you know, I,
I always hear these debates on
education. It's like, well look,
when my father went to school that wasn't
all that long. And I'm like, great grip.
My father, just my dad, when he
went to school and high school,
if you went for four years,
you graduated, that was it.
There were not standard setting.
You must pass this class.
You've got to have Algebra and you've
got to have geometry. And you got,
if you'll show up for four years,
you'd get a degree. And you know,
back in the olden day, there was no
first grade, second grade, third grade,
they all went to school together.
Everyone in the neighborhood showed up
to the same school and the teacher taught
them all.
And those are the same people that have
now built our bridges and our churches
and brought US technology and evolved
into Steve Jobs and apple and Microsoft
and Bill Gates and these wonderful things.
So apparently the education system, uh,
it doesn't necessarily need
this great revamping. I mean,
before we even had
textbooks and computers,
people were learning and people were
doing great things in this country. So,
you know, we, we've gotten so spoiled and
we've turned week, you know, we've, we,
we become feminized and our masculinity
is gone and a lot of things such as
having gritten digging deep,
and if the economy sucks and you got to
find a better way and you've got to cut
back, then that's what you gotta
do. But Grin and bear it. You don't,
you don't go build a,
a,
a hole in a cave somewhere and wait
for the end of the world man up.
Well, one of the issues with, you know,
trying to get by in today's society and
bringing your kids into schools is that
there's a lot of fucking people out
there that have done a real shitty job of
raising kids are real shitty job.
And when you put your kids around them,
your kids are in danger and there's
liabilities and there's all kinds of
bullying and stupid shit
that goes on and crime.
And if you can't figure out a way to
get your kids out of those situations,
they never even have a chance
to let the system work on them.
A big part of what school is,
is sending your kid to some sort of an
awkward fucking prison that they're stuck
at for many hours a day.
Especially if you lived in any sort
of economically compromise situation.
And he'd sort of place where
there's a lot of poor people,
any place where there's a lot of people
that are down and out and there's a lot
of fucking shitty parents and you've
got to go to school and deal with gang
bangers and all kinds of other craziness
while just trying to stay alive,
trying to stay healthy. Fuck learning.
Good luck. Half this country.
Good fucking luck.
Trying to learn something in public
school and how much energy is a,
our politicians putting on that.
How much has anybody changed, uh,
budgets where they're enhancing school
budgets and paying teachers much more
trying to make it commiserate
for what it's worth.
Make it commensurate rather for what it's
worth. Like, like, like, like a doctor.
Like having a, a, a good teacher is just
as important as having a good doctor.
You're having someone that develops
the way you fucking think about life,
not just shows you information that you
need to memorize for some stupid fucking
tests that you're not going
to absorb anything out of.
They show you how to think.
They show you how to live your life.
They show you good examples of people
who have lived quality lives and they get
you to think and pattern your
thoughts in a certain direction.
And most kids aren't
even getting that today.
Most kids are getting a shit
fucking experience in public school.
That's what the problem is.
Sure. People need to man up.
Absolutely fucking for sure.
But that comes,
it also comes with having kids and raising
your fucking kids and being a man in
the first place, raising your
kids properly and correctly. Well,
how many people are doing that,
man? It's a small percentage.
It may be 30% let's put a number on it.
Let's go crazy and say it's 30% that means
you're dealing with 70% possible fuck
ups. And not every kid that comes from a
fucked up household becomes an asshole.
But God damn,
a lot of them do.
How many times did you have to deal with
kids in high school and in college even?
There were just a fucking
mess all the time.
And it was always because
of the way they grew up,
it would always cause their
brother fucked them over.
Their parents fucked them over,
nobody paid attention to them.
And that poor asshole just gets jutted
into the school system and as to fucking
figure out his own way to the surface
of the water. That's the problem.
It is partly because people are
weak and sissified in this country,
but it's also because the
system is run by cunts.
The system is run by a
bunch of greedy cons.
Don't pay attention to the
most important resource.
This country has its children
the most important research.
You wanna have a a great,
powerful country.
You've got to have a smaller percentage
of losers and how do you have a smaller,
smaller percentage of losers?
We have to go into the fucking places
where there's the most losers economically
and help those fucking kids.
Joe, you are on fire right now.
I'm a sociologist is what I got my
degree in. You aren't fire right now.
You're saying this in a simple manner,
but this is actually very deep. You know,
the first time I ever came to one
of your comedy shows, you know,
I went through school, I went and got
certified smart. I sit in on lectures,
I've written papers,
I read every book and get my hands on.
I left your first comedy show.
I've never thought more than I than
I did at your show. And I thought,
I can never tell him that
or he's going to grow.
You're listening to a high comedian that,
you know,
I'm going to look like a
fool if I tell him this,
but I couldn't disagree with you more.
But you know,
when you say very simple things like
marijuana has never killed anybody and 14
people died last year cause coconuts
fell on their head. We're not,
we're not making coconuts illegal.
I can't help but look at that and have
to think and rethink my stance. You know?
And I'm like, I don't, I don't want
to agree with Joe. I'm on the right.
He's on the left. I don't like
this. But why don't I like it?
Because he's making a damn good point.
And what you just said could be two or
three chapters in any social logical book
and you are right on the money.
Well, I mean, I'm not on
the right or the left.
I'm on the right about a lot of
shit among the write about guns.
I'm on the right about punishment.
I'm going to write about a lot of things.
I'm on the left when it comes to people
having fucking freedom. You know,
you're a libertarian. I'm much more of
a libertarian than I am a a liberal,
you know,
there's a lot of like social,
I believe in a certain amount of
social Darwinism, you know, I think,
but I don't think it should ever
apply to children. You know,
I think if you want to be a fucking loser
and you want to go out and your life
and, and fuck it up, that's
one thing. But think a tribe
protects its children, you know?
And if we are anything in America,
I think we are a tribe.
We are a community. We're,
we're one gigantic fucking tribe.
And if we have any kids that are out
there that aren't getting taken care of,
then we're failing. We're
failing. So that's our foundation.
So it doesn't matter what the fuck we
do at the very top of the apex with,
you know, traveling to the fucking moon
and working on the star wars program.
That doesn't matter if our
foundation is full of shit. So the,
the very way our society is constructed,
it's to let you know that the
people running it are fools.
It's like a roadmap to retardation.
You see real clearly connected dots.
Oh,
you're just a bunch of greedy Douche bags.
This is it.
Again, that's sociology.
You're not talking psychology,
you're talking sociology right now.
You were the, you completely with you.
If you were the president,
how would you fix all this Chael Sonnen?
How'd you fix this world?
Well,
that's such a deep question and I think
about that a lot. You know, I ran,
I ran for office and all that.
Misstates man, I, you know,
and you know who I want to be president
as Brian Stan and he's got the resume,
could fucking do it.
He literally could become the president
of the United States in a heartbeat.
Yeah, absolutely. And you know, he's got
a guy that corners and made John Bardis.
John Bardis helped to get newt Gingrich
elected. Uh, he's out of Georgia.
Brian's out of Georgia. And that isn't
to Brag on Newt Gingrich. What I'm,
what I'm saying is Brian has the people
around him that know how to do this.
I mean, this guy's an all American from
the Naval Academy. He's a war hero.
He's a sports hero and he's
as squeaky clean as they come,
but intelligent, articulate
people love him. You know?
And when I make that comment,
or if he could be president,
people don't understand. No, no, no.
He really could be the
president and he should run.
And I like to throw these plugs out there.
So the right amount of people pushing me.
And that's how we got George Washington.
It's not a job he wanted to do.
People came to him and he was finally
willing to do that. So anyway,
I have no idea what we're even, oh,
what would I do if I were the president?
You know Brian Stann. Yeah, yeah.
I would definitely bring Brian
standing cabinet role. He, you know,
he would be somebody that you would
listen to a true leader of men. But uh,
you know, look, there's so many
things that need to be done.
But the first thing that I, president
page as a vice president, you know what I,
I would quit lion and every politician
in the country from the state level to
the federal level have all in the
last four years, which is two cycles.
If you're in the house,
have all ran on the same thing,
every one of them unanimously
in the country, all 50
states jobs in the economy,
they got to quit.
No politician has ever created a
job ever unless it's a state job.
And don't bring up state jobs where
you're taken from doers and given to non
doers k you where you're taking tax
dollars from hard workers and giving it to
people that are in a state job.
And I'm not saying those aren't important,
but don't count that as as create a
job. Look, if you're a lawmaker Joe,
you can do two things and two things.
Only tax and regulate in neither taxation
nor regulation is good for job growth
and they need to come clean
and just say that. So you think
the jobs are bad for job growth there?
They didn't
come about organically. Yeah, I just
don't think you can count it. You know,
when you're talking about creating jobs,
what you've done is grow
the size of government.
So now we've got more big brother.
We have more regulation,
more people looking at an example of
like a bullshit state job that they can
create. I don't think, well, okay, let's
look at the Department of Education.
Let's look at the Department
of Health. You know, what
are these guys doing? Right?
You can't get to nutritionalists to agree,
you know, you can't get them to agree.
[inaudible] there's so much
done on nutrition, you know,
and there's books written on blood type.
You know,
some people need more saturated fats.
They love to do it.
This whole thing about saturated fats that
are doing it right here in California,
you can't give out a happy meal if it's
over 500 calories at can't include a toy.
They're coming down on Mcdonald's
as opposed to telling parents, hey,
take responsibility in regulation.
Now what if your kid's an athlete?
What have your kids, you know,
wrestling like I had to do as a kid,
I need calories and I also happened
to need fat, so don't come on.
I should be able to have two big MACs.
And if it comes with a toy and it helps
me to pull through your drive through as
opposed to your competitors.
That's called capitalism.
And for the government to get involved
as beyond inappropriate. You know,
you brought up Barry bonds
earlier and Mark McGuire,
and I don't care what those guys did
either because I don't follow baseball,
but what I do care about is
that government got involved.
They had a congressional hearing
for Congress to get involved with.
Sport is beyond Riddick inappropriate.
And those guys,
that's what they should've said.
And if I was a congressman up
there and my fellow congressman,
it's my turn to Spock,
I'm going to say shame on you and
shame on you to the fellow congressmen.
I'm going to say get out there and do
something relevant and if people want to
quit going to the ballgame, capitalism
will fix that sport and nothing else.
Exactly.
The market will dictate where that's
silly sport is and it's a self regulating
sport to, they choose to agree
on what is in the contract.
There's a reason why the NBA doesn't test
for marijuana because everybody would
be tested positive. Those dudes are
blaze to the gills. So it's not like,
well we're going to eliminate all illegal
aspects of any basketball game. No,
they have shit they agree on and shit
they don't agree on and they put things in
contracts just to make sure
that they can, you know, they
can, they, they, they, they,
each side enforces their point. But
it's, it's a lot of, it is ridiculous.
Completely redid in congregational here.
Congress,
you're going to sit down with the people
that are involved at the highest level
of our government and
you're going to debate the,
hit the ball with the stick game.
Sure. Oh the guys too good at it.
He's taken some extra chemicals
and it makes them really good at,
they hit the ball with a stick game and
those little kids that are watching at
home,
I'm going to be real disappointed man.
You have to find out that that guy took
some extra stuff that makes them better
at, they hit the ball to stick
game, right? The fuck man.
No, I think, I think it's,
I think it's shameful.
I think it's shameful that Congress got
involved in that and I think you know,
to call a congressional hearing,
they call it under a number
of ridiculous things.
They call it on the poor guy from BP
because they got an oil leak out in the
ocean and that's horrible and I don't
want to see the ocean and get a leak,
but I assure you BP who's making money
doesn't want to see a leak either.
They want to see that taken care of.
They want to get that cleaned up.
They want their shareholders happy. Well,
it actually really can. The BP case,
if they had actually cut corners to
save money and made a shotty product,
that was a real fucking disaster.
That's a different situation.
That's a company that was, you know,
they're, they're responsible for that.
We fucked up. You didn't
build the, the uh, there,
there's two different ways to build
that valve and they didn't build the,
they took a shortcut to make it to and
make it happen quicker and they didn't,
they'd been warned about that too.
That was a fucking tremendous disaster.
We had members of Congress calling to
going on on shows and telling pundits,
hey, listen, we need to get the
military out there. Now of course,
they don't say what the military
is going to do. We don't have,
what's the military? They're going to
shoot it. They're going to shoot it.
The oil and what do they possible they
were talking about dropping into congress.
Somebody was talking about
dropping a nuke and closing them.
That's how they're going to close off the
oil. Drop a nuke on it. It's ridiculous.
You know,
and then you imagine what that would
look like and the British guy and just
dolphins and whales flying
into the fucking sky. Right.
Have you ever seen the video,
the photograph of that? Uh,
the bomb that they blew off in the
ocean Brion pull that picture up.
Its nuclear tests, Ocean
Pacific, something.
It was incredible. I don't know what
year this was. It was a long time ago,
but the,
the,
the actual explosion from this nuclear
bomb that they dropped in the ocean, the,
the water was so much bigger than
they thought it was going to be.
The set all these battleships around it,
like they were going to monitor this
thing and see what the impact was.
The battleships just flock
to get flown sideways.
It's like miles high water, straight
up into the air. It's incredible.
Why we're waiting for the video.
I'm going to play it. Just a photo.
The one up game and I don't want up you,
I'm going to come in second here,
but I want to,
I want to relate.
I had a friend that had to do two years
in a military prison because when he was
in Iraq during the war of 92 weight,
way back, but it was in my neighborhood,
he shot a camera with a law
and a law is a rocket launcher.
So they're out in the desert.
They got nothing to do with camel
goes by and he shoots his thing.
So you're talking about
wanting to see pictures.
I don't like that the camel had
to give his life. And you know as,
as the rumor goes there, they're
quite coveted it over there. I don't,
I don't say this to be a
disingenuous or denigrate it,
but I'm told you and you can
even marry one over there.
Whether that's true or not, I
don't know. But it's that serious.
He shot him with a rocket launcher.
Oh,
I don't want that port
Campbell to have to die.
But I do want to see that if there was
a video or a footage and my buddy had to
do the guy, my neighborhood has to
go to military prison for two years.
I at least need to see what happens when
a rocket meets a camel in the desert.
What did, why did they put them away
for so long? Two years along? Ask.
Extremely disrespectful.
I mean you're really talking about
offending people in that part of the Adobe
can see what you don't understand
that I don't, I don't get anything.
I was Campbell,
I watched one of those,
Anthony Bordain shows those reservation
shows where they cooked to Campbell.
They board the Kamma cooked it. Yeah,
they'll slow cooked it underground.
It's like whoa, green a camel. I
didn't even know they ain't camels.
I guess when you're stuck out there and
there's nothing but Campbell's you've
got to make do.
But he's like,
it was like a special dish that they would
only have like certain times I was in
trouble cause I
talked about the people in the streets
of a nuisance in Brazil eating monkey.
Well it's true.
They do and it's like,
listen now before you
think I'm making funny,
you might want to know what we put in hot
dogs right here at Yankee Stadium here
in America when we,
some pretty weird stuff too,
but it happens to be a true story
that they do eat monkey in Brazil.
But the point that I'm getting at is they
eat weird stuff around the world, man.
And I think I personally like it when I
travel, I like to try some of that weird.
I don't want to eat.
I eat pig intestines and Turkey,
but I didn't know that's
what I was eating.
I think the mere word intestine as
disgusting and I was pretty upset when I
found out I did. You never
let snail like s card. Yeah,
I've have had escar go on a cruise
ship as a kid. My Dad tricked me.
I don't like it. I do like caviar
and now that I've gotten older,
I didn't like it as a kid,
but when the Russians come over like
four for a wrestling or dual meter,
even the Russian fighters, they all bring
caviar that you can trade with them.
Try and give me money. I give you
caviar, but is worth a lot of money.
Their caviar, Russian caviars,
the most famous kind of caviar.
It's kind of like a Cuban cigar.
If you can get ahold of Russian caviar,
especially back with the USSR before
the breakup of the Soviet Union,
it was almost impossible to get
Russian caveats, one of those.
So we deemed it to be a little better
than it actually is, but it is coveted.
If you can get it. It says Russia on
the label, you'll be the hit of your
neighborhood party. It's like, yeah,
like you said, like Cuban cigars.
I've always thought it was weird
that it's an acquired taste.
It's so expensive and
it's an acquired taste.
Like why would you want to acquire a taste
for something that's really expensive
that initially don't like?
Sure.
Take it tastes like salt. You know?
I haven't like, cause now they,
they've eased us into it cause they,
they roll all of our local Sushi
rolls in a type of caviar real cheap,
that yellowy stuff. But you know, I've
learned to like it as we've gotten older.
They go on these gentlemen, tell people
that I have American loves caviar,
Russian caviar and anything else
wrapped his pitch up, bring it home.
I mean I had a great time. I got to
tell you to find a really good time.
I learned some things about you today.
You're not just that pothead comedian.
I thought you went there.
Uh, he got second amendment
and some deep thoughts and,
and you know, whether you know
it or not, you're a sociologist.
Listen to some of your arguments today,
whether you've been certified in it,
like I, you know, went to school or not.
You're a sociologist and I admire that.
Well, I'm gonna just a stand up
comedian. I think as extent of comedian,
you have to understand human beings to
understand yourself in order to move
forward, to advance, to evolve.
You've got to understand human beings.
You've got to understand
yourself. You know, I just, uh,
my observations is just a part
of life. Cool. Just like yours.
Just like your book VIP pass in
alignment with the first part of it.
Voice of reason. The Voice of reason,
which you can get right now on Amazon.
You could just go if you have a candle
and get it and you should get a kindle
because they're fucking awesome.
They are great insight about my
mom's, my, my mother's Day present.
I just said her kindle book now. I
could just send her books now. Yeah.
That's cool. Yeah, that is a
great service and it's amazing.
Battery lasts forever. I have a kindle.
The battery lasts forever. It looks great.
It looks like printed word. You could even
like make the print larger or smaller.
Like me, I'm going blind so I
have to make the print larger, so
it's amazing. It's an amazing product.
I have an IPAD and I'll, I'll,
I'll watch books on that too.
I liked the effect more the scrolling,
but it's better on the eyes. The kindle,
I think the kindle, so superior device,
it's the shape. I like audio. I love
audio books if they're red. Well,
but every now and then,
like I,
I bought a steep couple of Stephen
King books that were written or read by
Stephen King. Those are fucking
terrible. Roger, Roger Gilbertson.
He shouldn't have done
it. Roger. He's kidding.
That's a bad joke. The guys
got to know John. I know.
Don't don't do that. That's a
bad Karma. Takes you out of JFK.
I was at the Tom likesure. Why can
they, should they go? Yeah. How rude.
How rude. Anyway, that's the end
of this show. Ladies. Gentlemen,
if you want to follow chail on Twitter,
it's Suning c h. How did you get that one?
Why not just chill son and I didn't know
much about Twitter when I set it up.
I bet they could change it.
Yeah. And I wish, I wish it was,
has somebody else told me the
marketing the UFC to go up to that.
Now it's just somebody's got it. Unless
it's an actual Chael Sonnen, you know,
which I doubt how many channels
on do you ever met him?
I've met a few Joe Rogan's no chill
sentence. And so it's an unusual,
you get that shit on Twitter.
That's Sun NCH. Yeah.
And you say tell the UFC to go out.
What does UFC have?
Every department who do I could,
I called Twitter department.
Go after that call Donna, I'll call Donna.
Joe said go head of department. I met,
I met someone.
I bet whoever has the the chill son and
he would probably be happy to give it to
you. Hey, hey douche bag.
Who you squatter, stop.
Stop hiding and holding on to Charleston
instinct. Just give the password.
Well I take it from what
I could just stare at.
It would actually,
it wouldn't work that way because you
want to get all your followers and bring
them over there. How many followers
you got? I got 152,193 not,
not that I keep track or a camp.
You can't not have that. So that's,
you've got to have to figure out a way
to get Twitter to merge the two they did
with me.
I had a different nick.
I had a different Twitter name and they
merged it and made it Joe Rogan. Oh,
excellent. Yeah, I think I bought it.
I bought it. No, I bought my space.
I bought my mind
nick over at tap out his friends
with the creator of Twitter,
so maybe we can put him on that.
Maybe we can to him.
Go after it and let's make it happen.
All right,
so it's sun and ch for now
on Twitter. Um, and uh,
thank you to everybody that tunes in.
Of course. Thank you to the fleshlight,
our sponsor. Uh, go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for the fleshlight
and touring the code named Rogan and you
will save yourself 15%.
There you go,
skipper Ha.
We're also brought to you by on.com makers
of Alpha brain, new mood, shroom tech,
sport and shroom tech immune. For all
information on all of those products,
go to [inaudible] dot com that's
o, n n. I t. Use the code name,
Rogan and save yourself 10% tomorrow.
We are going to be here with Michael
Rupert. That's right. Michael.
Roomberg for La narcotics officer who
busted the CIA selling drugs in da hood.
That's d, a, h o, d. And
he'll be back to spread more.
What Brian Fox. Fox Magic. That's
right. So I'll see you guys tomorrow on,
and you're the fucking man, and good luck
to you, sir. We match for your title,
right? It is my title undefeated.
Undisputed that said, folks, boom.
Yeah.