Is it working?
Is it live?
Says it's alive.
Gregory,
we're live.
This is it.
This is it for.
There's definitely more of an echo in
this room.
We're going to have to do some tweaking.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is episode number one in the new
spot.
Oh,
Jamie's fucking up already.
Jesus does extra mics on.
I had all the mics on.
Oh,
the mics are off now.
that sounds bad.
Yeah.
It changed everything.
Your wizard.
How'd you notice?
You could feel it.
He could sense it in the room.
Should be behind a curtain.
Like the wizard of Oz.
Yeah.
What color was the wizard of Oz curtain?
It was green,
right?
Wasn't it?
Ain't no city,
right?
Yes.
Yeah,
right.
Emerald city.
Gregory.
Welcome.
I feel so happy to be here on the first
episode.
Dude.
I'm honored.
I'm honored that you're number one.
Yeah.
Perfect.
Yeah,
this is perfect.
Fuck crazy.
Right?
He just gave me a tour of this place and
it's like I,
I saw the first half and was like,
what the fuck's he going to do with all
this space?
The back half is bigger than the first
half.
Well,
it's going to be a gym.
Yes.
An actual full gym.
I don't like going places.
Do it.
Alright here.
Catch your,
your tank.
Your sauna does a 47 yard indoor archery
range in here.
That's going to be bad ass.
Yeah.
It's why not fuck it.
But the big thing is to set up the
studio and have it as close to the old
one as possible.
We basically,
we built it sort of the only
differences.
The Sky,
uh,
thanks to octo lights.
Now we have clouds in the sky instead of
stars.
Decided to mix it up a little bit,
changed the curtain color.
I love that.
It feels the same as the other one now
pretty fucking soon.
The dimensions or are they exact
dimensions?
Very close.
And this is,
this is a standalone.
I mean this was built so it was built to
the same size.
I mean this was,
this did not exist.
So this is all constructed.
Basically.
We just,
I had all these ideas like,
well I'll do it this way and I'll do it
this way and I'll make a table that's
different.
And then,
and then as time went on and I started
doing the planning and everything,
I said,
do you know what?
I don't,
I don't think I want to change much at
all.
Like this table,
first of all is giant.
Like I love this table and it's got all
this weird history to it.
A little bend to it.
Yeah.
Well when we got it,
the wood hadn't been killed.
Killed dry.
Kiln dried.
Yeah.
So it wouldn't,
would sits out or it goes and where it
gets damp and then when it dries out it
starts to warp a little bit and change
and shift.
So it's got a little warp to it at this
desk.
Got History.
It's got history and the red brick wall
looks exactly the same.
Pretty close.
Pretty close per Roland Cheney's over
there.
And his spot,
it's pretty close.
I mean it's like it doesn't,
I have to remind myself that we're in a
new spot.
That's perfect.
Yeah.
I mean,
after we do a few episodes here will be
like,
oh,
it's just,
this is the spot.
I'm sure if I companion.
Yeah,
yeah.
Especially once the booze and starts
again.
Once the boozing and the weeds start
again in November.
How hard has that been for you?
Easy.
Super easy.
Like is he the other day went to Mexican
food and I wanted a Margarita and I
went,
Damn,
I can't have a margaret.
Yeah,
that's it.
That's literally my only craving people
talk to you about.
His initial thing wasn't quitting.
We'd write.
The initial thing was just getting Bert
Kreischer to not die.
So like our idea was like,
let's see if we can get them to go sober
for a month.
Yeah.
And he was like,
I can run a marathon.
I'm like,
stop.
He fucked this.
You're not going to run a marathon.
Like,
listen,
how about instead of you running a
marathon,
we just have you do 15 hot yoga classes.
And they're like,
oh,
that'll be easy,
but she hasn't even done one yet.
You don't know if it's easy and now
they're,
they're slogging away through like,
I think they're all like number six or
seven.
Do we have video of a bird in a hot yoga
class?
No.
Video.
No,
but they,
they take videos after him and tom get
out and they're both,
you know,
beet red and it's covered in sweat.
It's pretty obviously drenched,
but burdens done amazing.
First of all,
his blood pressure has dropped
radically.
He was actually on high blood pressure
medication and after this,
after stopping drinking just
immediately,
his blood pressure dropped radically.
Yeah.
So like he doesn't even need blood
pressure medication if he doesn't drink,
that's amazing.
It's the only thing that's doing them in
is the booze.
Right.
So,
and then.
But people would come up to me about
the,
we'd see the weed wasn't in the
original.
The original bet was just no booze,
which I thought would be pretty easy.
And then they're like,
all right,
we're going to go,
no,
no weed too.
And I was like,
no,
weed,
fuck you.
Like I'm just doing this for Bert.
Like I don't want to stop.
And then they were giving me a hard time
about it.
They started this Hashtag pray for Joe
Campaign because I was addicted to pot,
so I initially thought I'll just get off
weed and not tell them until the end and
go.
It was fucking easy.
Pussies.
Yeah.
But then our,
he was making such a big deal out of it.
I would say.
Actually,
dude,
I'm not smoking pot either,
just to let the cat out of the bag.
Tom Ziglar already knew.
But people would come up to you like,
like you're not eating for a month like
you.
Okay.
Yeah.
Right,
right.
How do you feel you,
you off heroin for good.
You know,
but it's such a part of it for you is it
never seemed like an addiction.
Drugs to,
for my vision of you doing drugs.
It's always mind expanding and it's
always just to relax.
It's never like an addiction.
It never felt like you needed to.
I definitely don't need it obviously
because I've had some great sets too,
which has been very interesting because
I usually like to go on state.
Hi.
I haven't done that at all though.
No,
no pot for 17 days.
Today is what's today?
Seventeenth.
So no pot for 17 days or do you miss it
the most before going on?
No,
I haven't missed it.
Wow.
It's been weird.
I was like,
maybe there's going gonna be a moment
where like,
wow,
I'd like to have some weird.
I'm a little nervous about smoking
again.
Yeah,
because I know I'm going to get so high
that I'm be so paranoid and all these
demons are going to come creeping up
into my consciousness.
He gets paranoid psychic demons.
It is going to come floating by.
It's like that first orgasm after you
get your prostate removed.
Yeah man.
For Real.
You know,
like once,
once you're back,
you know,
it's just,
it just seems like it seems like it's
going to hit you way,
way,
way harder.
Right?
That's what everybody says.
You take a month off and then you get
back on the pot.
Then you know why everybody freaks out
when you get them high.
You know,
because we're so used to getting high
that will we get high.
It's no big deal,
but when people don't get high and
they're like,
oh,
I'll smoke a little weed with you,
but they haven't smoked pot.
Maybe like six months or something like
that.
Yeah.
Those people are fucked.
Right?
They're in a bad place.
Yeah.
I get a nice easy rhythm going.
I got the little vape pen and I'm seeing
when I'm on the road,
you know,
Thursday,
Friday night couple
hits and that's pretty much it.
And you never do it before shows,
right?
Never,
never,
ever.
And you took a long time.
Like when,
when I first met you,
we back in the day,
um,
when we first started out you would just
quit boots.
Just quit.
And you weren't doing nothing.
No Pot,
no booze,
no nothing.
Like what was it that made you realize I
could smoke a little weed?
It was New Year's eve of 2004.
Whoa.
So I had not smoked pot for 14 years or
drank or anything.
And then I'm standing outside of the
Improv in San Francisco and I'm with,
I won't mention the manager's name,
but it manager who smokes a lot of pot
that we all know and love and the entire
cast of the marijuana logs this Doug
Benson,
Tony,
a comedian,
and I'm Brian Hossein and they're all
there.
It's just like a weird thing where,
you know,
I don't know if you've ever done New
Year's eve in San Francisco,
but there's like three different venues
that all do comedy,
you know,
there's cops,
there's the punchline and then there's a
big theater that the pal,
a the palace of fine arts or whatever.
And then there's an after party at the
punchline and it's the greatest after
party because usually go on the road and
after your show you're just kind of
alone.
Maybe you got your opener or whatever
and you hang out.
But this is always like,
you know,
every Comic Sans Francisco comes
together and I'm standing up front and,
and they're standing there with a joint.
They hand it to me and I just,
I felt like this is the moment I'm
supposed to smoke pot again.
And I did.
And uh,
and then the weirdest fucking thing
happened is I went down to help molly,
you know,
she had a,
um,
the van coming from the palace and she
had a box of booze that had been the
backstage bar and she's carrying a
bottle of vodka and she's walking
towards the steps and this group we were
talking about San Francisco homeless
people before group of like,
you know,
they're like 21 and they're like street
urchins there.
Like,
you know,
it's almost like,
yeah,
the warrior has come out.
It's like that type of person.
And they grabbed the bottle of booze out
of molly's hand and I'm standing there
with Todd Barry,
Paula Tompkins.
And like,
I think Greg proops is like two guys in
suits.
And so they grabbed this bottle from
molly and she chases after them.
I'm like,
what the fuck are you doing this?
Not your booze.
It's the clubs,
booze.
And she runs right in the middle of them
and they,
uh,
she grabs a bottle and she's fighting
with this woman over it and these guys
are surrounding her and I run in and I
grab her and start pulling her out.
But at the same time,
guys a fist cocked,
waiting to take a shot at me and I'm
yelling to these guys,
hey,
how about a little help here and
nothing.
And so,
uh,
I kind of pull her out of there and we
have runaway.
And then as we're walking up the stairs,
they threw a blockbuster and m,
a o Jesus.
And it landed right near us and it blew
out o and m,
there was lesbian.
I don't know what that means is a
firecracker hold.
We're super bits and eighth of a stick
of dynamite isn't really that.
That's what an mat is.
Jesus Christ.
I didn't know it was that powerful.
Yeah.
I mean you feel it in your chest and a
blue out molly's hearing for like a year
and a people were crying.
It was like really traumatic.
And I'm high.
I'm like,
this is the fucking war.
After 14 years I was just like,
fuck,
this is nuts.
I was walking the girl back to the hotel
because she was sobbing.
I wasn't tig.
It was a,
it was a lesbian comedian who had a
girlfriend with her and uh,
yeah,
it was fucking crazy.
Whoa.
Yeah.
We were talking about how San Francisco
is just a little bit too lenient with
their homeless population.
There were just a little silly with it
and we were talking about how they have
it mapped out where people shit in the
streets now.
So you could avoid human shit.
Yeah.
It's either a website or an APP.
I'm not sure which one it is,
but they,
they're basically keeping up to date
human poo stats.
How do they know it's human versus dog?
Probably smells worse.
People are growing a little toilet paper
next to it.
Okay.
Dog
Shit all over the house last night.
My dogs.
I have a young dog and two old dogs.
Right?
And my big old dog is a massive and he's
super cool with every dog.
And the dog comes over who are doing.
Yeah,
he's super friendly,
but my little dog is kind of a twat
something going on with the lights.
Well,
it just dim.
Oh,
they're turning off.
Scary.
Spooky.
What kind of dog is the little dog?
What does that Jamie.
The motion sensor fire.
We're getting everyplace.
Oh,
so things were not here.
How do we fix that?
That's dumb.
Okay.
Anyway,
the little dog is a.
he's not that little.
He's a medium sized dog.
He's a Shiba Inu English bulldog mix,
right.
Nice.
And uh,
he has,
um,
he has an issue with any dark.
He's a little cunt,
like any dogs or her.
And the poppy is 11 months old.
I have a golden retriever.
He's the sweetest dog in the world.
He's the best,
but he can't go near the bulldog.
Bulldog beat him in his face when he was
a puppy.
No Shit really hurt.
I'm like,
put a big cut in his nose to the vet.
It was so to have the dogs sleep in this
one little contained area,
but they opened up the door and wandered
around the house and just took a shit in
the middle of the living room,
pissed on the wall and they did all this
because the other dogs in the house,
the other dogs.
And they're like,
well,
if he's in here,
we're just going to shit all over the
place and mark this place up.
They never,
never done that before.
So it was really interesting like dog
psychology.
Like they were pissed that the other dog
gets to be in better spots than them.
So they decided to shit in the living
room.
Wow.
That's a statement.
Their statement,
you know it.
It's funny because the big one,
I could have him with the new dog.
No problem.
He's,
he loves them,
they play together.
He has a great time,
but I just don't trust that other one.
So what are you going to do?
Shoot the other one in the head hunting
accident?
Uh,
just keep them separated.
I mean,
I,
I can have morale and together when I'm
there,
you know,
he just,
he's a cool dog.
He likes people.
He loves people.
Like people come over,
he loves you.
He's,
he's a very sweet dog.
He just doesn't.
It's apparently an English bulldog
trait.
They just do not like other dogs.
They just don't.
They want dogs and they and they have a
lot of health issues.
Say fucking wheeze.
He's had two surgeries on his knees.
Both his front knees are fucked up.
He's just got like,
they just,
it's a terrible thing what they've done.
Designing them like that,
taking them and putting them into this
shape that it's really not supposed to
exist.
Shortening their nose.
It's like it's really fucked up what
they've done.
Yeah,
just hit that breed may need to be put
down.
Lots of.
It's weird.
Like why?
Why did anybody decide to have a dog
that has a flat face?
It can't breathe.
You can't walk very good.
They just,
they're always in pain,
so they just want to lie down.
Like those dogs aren't done on ball
chasers.
You throw a ball to an English bulldog.
He's like,
fuck off,
I'm not running after that thing.
Everything hurts.
They just waddle everywhere.
You know?
It's weird because the original bull dog
was a dog that they literally used to
use for what they call bull baiting with
bull baiting is they would tie a bull
down and so it couldn't go anywhere and
then they would sic the dogs on the
bowl.
That's what a bulldog.
Yeah,
it's like sport.
What was the point of that?
I don't know,
just to fuck with the ball.
I'd have to look into it.
No,
I think it was like a betting thing,
you know,
so like a bloodsport thing.
That's originally what a bull dog looked
like.
Do you know what American bulldog looks
like now?
American bulldog is like sort of pit
bull ask,
but larger much larger American bulldog
has got kind of a pit bull,
like face,
sort of a flat nose,
but nothing like an English bulldog.
They're really smart dogs.
They're very good dogs.
Like a buddy of mine had one and it was
great dog there.
Tanks filled like this big jacked up
like,
but a totally functional dog.
They run,
they use them for protection,
they,
you know,
they're,
they're just really good dogs and the
English version of them is like,
what that dog is like.
I might be fucking this up,
but I think they took the dog and
somehow or another bread it down to this
really gross,
cute fat flat nose,
shitty breathing English bulldog.
Did they want it to look like the royal
family had the sisters only fuck your
sister only fuck your sister.
And then they took those properties.
No,
no,
you can't.
Fuck you.
Fuck your sister.
Okay.
And then the baby's fuck each other.
Your baby's fucking each other.
I'm fine.
And as Irish just,
I don't know,
just,
it's weird that they all came from
wolves.
You know,
a wolf could fucking English bulldog and
get it pregnant.
That's what's incredible.
It's like the shit.
The genetics are the same and they
didn't know this until like I say,
I want to say less than a decade ago.
They used to think that all wolves were
like wolves.
And then dogs.
We're like a combination of a bunch of
different things while candidates like
jackals and coyotes and all these
different things and that we had somehow
or another bread them down because
there's no real record of how anybody
ever did that.
And if you go back to the history of
domesticated dogs spans over 10,000
years.
So it predates human history.
We don't really don't know how the fuck
anybody made a Chihuahua.
We just know that it's Chihuahuas.
I know that the first domesticated dogs
were the ones that basically we're,
we're,
you know,
docile.
They could come near the fire.
Yes.
And so the ones that were friendlier and
nicer,
captain,
they killed the other ones.
I put up a picture on instagram
yesterday,
a re posted.
So he sent me with this fucking lady,
found a,
a young coyote and she thought it was a
dog and she washed it
and they put it up on facebook and she,
it's kind of aggressive,
but now it's sleeping and it's like a
little coyote and this lady's washing a
fucking chaos.
Just writing.
It's kind of a period that just fucking
lunges at attacks are.
There it is.
Look at that Chamberlain road.
No collar.
Seems a bit aggressive.
Also doesn't like bass,
but she was pretty dirty.
Took,
took most of the night,
but she's resting comfy now on the bed.
Look at that thing.
That is a fucking coyote obviously,
and it's obviously a little one too.
It's probably a young one,
like a yearling or something.
Yeah.
You can't domesticate a coyote,
but you can in a weird way.
I know a guy
who,
well I don't know him,
but I follow his instagram account.
I forget his name,
Shit.
But anyway,
oddly enough,
this guy has dogs that he uses to hunt
coyotes width,
which is really crazy to kill.
Hunt to kill.
And he found coyote puppies in a den and
so they found these coyote puppies in
the den and he felt bad that these
little coyote puppies,
like I don't know what happened to the
mother.
So they raised one,
so he took a coyote puppy in and now it
lives with them.
Wow.
Yeah.
And it gets a lot like the only problem
is when they feed it.
Is that him?
Yeah.
So he's a German shepherd.
I mean,
but he's had it since it was a baby.
The dog,
I think that is that.
I don't know if that's him,
but this guy has all this video of it on
his site of him with this coyote puppy,
with his other dogs.
They're all barking together and shit.
And he said the only,
the only problem they get along great
until it's time to eat.
And when Simon to eat the coyote is
like,
fuck off.
Fuck.
All right.
This is like full feral as soon as it's
time to eat.
But he's had the thing since,
I think he said it was like a couple
months old when he got it.
But just freshly weaned.
That's amazing.
Yeah,
you can.
You can raise them.
But they're wolves.
Wolves.
My friends have a Dingo.
What did it eat?
The baby
dangling.
A dingo ate my baby.
And this thing is the same way.
If you get some food on the counter and
it's four feet off the ground,
that fucking thing.
You leave the room for one second.
That food is gone.
Yeah,
they're just feral.
Yeah.
It's funny,
like my puppy was like that when he was
little.
It's like I was.
I mean that's how puppies are,
but I forgot because I haven't had a
puppy in a while and I was eating and I
put some food on his plate and he saw it
as like,
oh,
I want some of that.
They jumped up,
put his feet on the table,
leaned in and tried to try to bite it
and got a piece of meat in his mouth and
I was like,
hey fucker.
I
got to teach them this.
They don't know.
They feel like,
well the food's right.
They're trying to get the food.
There's the food.
Here it is,
it's right there.
He,
our neighbors,
we're having people over there.
We're having a party.
And I was over there and they had a
husky fucking bad ass Alaskan Husky.
And this thing was,
you know,
beyond puppy was big and they had
meatballs.
Swedish meatballs,
like for platters of them were right out
of the oven,
still fucking hot and they left the room
and they came back and they were gone.
He had all of them,
all the Swedish meatballs.
Hot.
He didn't give a fuck.
He's like,
here's my chance.
You have a full belly or have a,
you know,
or burn,
burn your tongue and have a full bay or
not.
No food and this is an Irish party.
This wasn't like there's Swedish
meatballs and there is a sausage.
No Irish.
This one fucking thing and now it's
gone.
The Swedish speak was dog eat all the
food.
Yeah.
Dot.
It's a weird relationship that humans
have with dogs because you know a lot of
people have dogs to sleep in their beds
that come with you places they hop in
the car and then then there's the
assholes that have those emotional
support dogs.
Yeah.
What is,
what is the jury out on that still?
It's fucking ridiculous.
Part of modern 21st century life that we
allow that stupid shit.
I was in a fucking restaurant,
like a really nice restaurant.
This lady came in and she's a lady from
real housewives.
She was one of those.
Uh,
no,
not the show.
Desperate housewives.
She's a famous actress.
I want to say her name.
Very pretty lady.
She hit the skids though.
Um,
but anyway,
she's bringing,
brings in this fucking dog and,
and people are looking at her like what?
It's a dog,
like a golden lab and a big dog.
Yeah.
And she brings his dog and then just
sitting there eating.
And there's dogs on the floor where like
you might drop a fry or your four can
pick it up and wipe it off.
And this dog's assholes just rubbing on
the ground right there.
I mean basically you have this,
this animal's Dick is like rubbing on
the ground and rubbing on things and
dirt on its feet.
It's probably stepping in shit.
And had people have allergies to dogs
for sucked up there night.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
And it's somehow or another they can get
a note from their doctor that says
they're too fucking week to exist
without this dog with them 24 hours a
day.
It's an emotional support dog.
Does a lot of comics that have them.
Yeah,
but it's a like a loophole.
Look,
Natasha has one,
but she like openly admits it's a
loophole.
I should take.
Bring the dog everywhere.
She's got a doctor's note.
Yeah.
So she's soft.
He.
Yeah.
I think is.
What's your name has to be allies.
Allies is.
Does she have it set up?
I sure that thing doesn't leave her
side.
Yeah.
She'll make you watch it though when she
goes on stage here.
Hold this.
Yeah.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
I know the people finger it.
I love.
I don't know.
A lot of people do and I just
want to hear her.
The dog waits for her to go out and it
just takes the task.
The air and starts running.
He had presents.
Just literally runs backwards.
She's going to hear this speech so bad.
We're kidding.
Eliza.
Don't call her.
Eli's either.
Get Mad at that too.
Eliza.
You know she doesn't use the last name
anymore.
Well,
neither does I.
Will Christina?
Is Christina pain now?
Really?
Sebastian Maniscalco was just Sebastian.
Now are white people getting crazy
lately.
Chicken is just tig.
Is that cultural appropriation two's a
white person to use only one name.
I always forget what's cultural
appropriation.
We need to constantly be reminded.
I tweeted something today.
I was reading a fucking article and I
almost punched my screen.
They're saying that hoop earrings are
cultural appropriation.
Now.
Girls aren't allowed to wear hoop
earrings.
Really?
Cultural appropriation.
Damn.
Cue How fucking privileged you have to
be like how sought legal hoop earrings
criticize as cultural appropriation.
Do you know how soft you have to be to
give into that,
to give you that and how?
How fucking dumb you have to be to say
that.
Yeah.
You have to be so dumb and racist.
I think it's the.
It's the cit is racist against white
people is racist against black,
but what their jungle jungle people that
only were giant fucking hoops in their
ears.
What I read was Latinas.
Latinas are criticizing it and saying
it's a part of their culture.
Their culture.
Yeah.
It's like people just pick them black.
That black people don't want girls to
wear braids.
Oh,
cornrows.
Cornrows.
Yeah.
You could wear like regular white people
braids,
but a little skinny brains.
That's cultural appropriation.
What about Goldie locks?
She was white.
What about golf shirts?
Are they allowed to work off?
Right?
They shouldn't be.
If we start crazy with these braids,
it's green pants.
Here's the problem with all this
bullshit.
The entire country is a melting pot of
cultural appropriation.
You dumb cunts.
Alright.
That is the whole idea of having a
civilization as that you get to share
each other's food,
share each other's recipes,
listened to each other's music,
listened to each other's jokes and
stories.
Get by each of those clothes.
You know,
there was this,
um,
is journalist that went to Japan and
they were talking about cultural
appropriation,
whether or not they thought that like
white girls like Katy Perry wearing the
geisha outfit was cultural
appropriation.
And they were like universally saying
no,
we're happy that people love Japanese
culture and that they do that.
They're happy.
Yeah.
But over here you get these fucking
dummies that are just looking to
complain and criticize and just call out
everything and everybody about
everything.
Yeah,
it's a,
Oh my God,
I,
I see this.
What is this?
No,
Jeremy Lin,
uh,
came out
with a,
a in the preseason.
I think he had dreadlocks in his hair
and a former NBA player called him out
on it.
Kenyon Martin.
But Jeremy Linds response to it was
actually really good.
If you want to check that out.
Hey Man.
It's all good.
You don't have to like my hair.
Definitely entitled to your opinion.
Actually,
I,
I legit grateful you Sharon.
It tbh to be honest,
at the end of the day,
I appreciate that I have dreads and you
have Chinese because I think it's a sign
of respect and I think as minorities,
the more we appreciate each other's
cultures,
the more we influence mainstream
society.
Thanks for everything you did for the
nets and hoops.
Had your poster up on my wall growing
up.
Oh Shit.
That's really classy.
I'm somebody really needed to tell him
like,
all right bro,
we get it.
You want to be black,
like we get it.
But the last name is Lynn.
All right,
well he's said that the other guy who
was the other guy,
Kenyon Martin is.
There was a picture of his but it's been
removed.
Yeah,
well he's a dummy and that Jeremy Lin
guys are very classic character for the
way you answered it.
First of all,
dreads or not black.
They were a sign of people not washing
their hair.
That dates back to the Greeks and the
Romans.
There's ancient sculptures of Caucasian
looking people with dreadlocks.
Dreadlocks were worn by the vikings is
not a black thing because some black
people wear them.
Does not mean it's the idea that this is
a real thing.
That's cultural appropriation that
people go around pointing at people
saying you can't wear your hair a
certain way.
Like we're limiting hairstyles and it's
just so many people are just looking
forward to criticizing,
getting shitty with people over almost
nothing.
Yeah.
It's just no.
The whole.
The whole energy of this country is
supposed to be complete assimilation.
Like you said,
let's pick the best shit from each
culture and may get just American
hodgepodge and that's what it's about
with gentrification.
You know,
you want people to not all live in one
neighborhood and all dress exactly the
same as each other.
You want there to be a merging of
different looks,
different addresses.
Sure.
Working in different trades,
you know,
they used to be.
If you were Irish,
you were a cop.
That's it.
That's what we fucking did.
You know,
we were cops are,
we were soldiers when we first came over
here and like the 18 sixties during the
famine,
they just got off the boat hungry and
they threw a fucking uniform,
honest and sent us into fight lines
against the south or you were a cop
and then after that they got into the
trades.
There's a lot of Irish people in unions.
Right?
And a lot of Irish in the Longshoreman's
union.
A lot of Irish in the carpenter's union.
Yeah.
But look,
fusion restaurants,
what's a fusion restaurant?
And take a couple of different cultures.
You combine their food and do some sort
of a unique thing and it's.
It was a big thing for awhile.
People loved fusion.
Yeah.
They love that kind of food and now
there's a ton of people complaining when
White People Cook Mexican food.
Yeah.
Like there's this famous guy,
I forget his name can be that famous
because he's not that famous.
I forget his name,
but he's a famous white guy who loves
Mexican food and he opened up a Mexican
restaurant and all these people got
pissed that this guy is a cooking
Mexican food,
but this guy has been writing books
about Mexican cuisine.
He goes down to Mexico.
He learns how to Cook Authentic Mexican
dishes from people that live in these
villages and towns in Mexico and and
like has a deep love and appreciation
for the culture of Mexico.
Yeah.
I mean this guy is essentially a Mexican
cuisine scholar and all these people
give is fucking poor guy.
That's his name.
What is his name?
Rick bayless and he's famous.
I mean I've,
I've read one of his books on Mexican
food and I've seen articles written on
them and video interviews and stuff and
this guy is getting in,
in trouble with other people.
When chefs become famous cooking other
cultures,
food,
you don't own your culture,
you fucking idiot.
You know why?
Because you didn't create it.
You didn't invent pizza.
You didn't invent pasta,
you didn't invent Chinese food.
It's been around for hundreds of years.
You were just born,
you were born with a certain ethnicity.
You don't own that ethnicity.
The idea that you can keep other people
from enjoying it and appreciate the
history of other human beings is fucking
racist.
It is stupid.
This,
this thing that we're getting into.
We were criticizing people,
you know,
based on various aspects of culture that
they enjoy.
It's insanity.
I know.
Think about how Italians have affected
the like fashion in this country.
I mean from high fashion all the way
down to like the disco era when all of a
sudden music were all calling themselves
Gadi and they were all calling the Al
Capone.
I mean,
come on man.
how many fucking rap songs like have
godfather lyrics in and just cut the
shit.
It's so stupid.
It's so stupid and that's my culture.
I'll tell you,
you can have it.
That's why I love one of the seminal
moments in American culture was
aerosmith,
getting together with DMC and doing walk
this way.
That was,
that's what America's bus today.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's kids today looking to point the
finger,
uh,
the world they see and looking to find
fault in it and find fault in each
other.
And it's this call out culture that we
see.
There's plenty of Shit is wrong in the
world.
There's plenty of shit.
And I guess this is just a byproduct of
people having the freedom to
communicate.
I mean,
I guess that's what we're seeing,
but there's,
there's plenty of shit to really pay
attention to.
Jeremy Lin wearing dreadlocks isn't on
that list.
You know,
girls that wear hoop earrings.
Then on that list,
it's just
fucking white kids that wear baggy
pants.
So what,
so what,
who gives a shit?
Yeah.
To me that's a sign that they're like
accepting black culture.
They want to enter intermix.
They want to hang out together and share
each other's fashions and ideas and
drugs and women.
Well,
the white people,
especially like from the suburbs,
have always looked towards black people
that grew up in difficult circumstances
and admired something about how tough
they were or how,
how,
uh,
you know,
street smart or how cool,
cool they were.
They were a people that,
look,
it takes pressure to make a diamond.
You don't make a diamond in Sherman
Oaks,
you know?
Yeah.
Whew.
We went to the gallery.
It was crazy.
Went to the food court,
were radical,
you know,
that's not,
those,
those people that live in these safe
suburban neighborhoods.
The one thing that the troubled kids
coming up want to be.
They want to be associated in some way
with something tougher,
something harder.
Something where,
you know,
people had to earn their stripes.
That's why they have this love of rap
music.
Especially Gangsta rap.
You mean?
That has always been.
That's always been an issue with young
white kids.
Like since since Gangsta rap was
invented,
there's always been like young white
kids who live in the suburbs.
Who Will it?
I mean,
it's always comical watching them sing
the lyrics,
talking about robbing people and
shooting people and dealing drugs and
meanwhile they're living in thousand
oaks or something.
Yeah.
Whose son was it was at like Tom Hanks
says yes.
The big rapper Tom Hanks' son as a
rapper and get so much shit.
Yeah.
I don't know if Tom Hanks has commented
on it,
but it's Kinda suck yet because he's got
to support him.
It's his son,
but the kid is like,
that's it.
Oh my God.
Is this a limo life?
Live a life.
It says that on his knuckles.
Oh,
good Lord.
Oh boy.
For eggs.
He did it.
He did everything right.
What did he do wrong?
Yeah,
but he didn't do everything right.
See,
because he's working all the time.
Yeah,
he worked too much.
Yeah.
If you're working all the time,
is that his son with the green hair and
the neck tattoos and the lower right
hand corner.
Let's say green day guys.
Is it?
I don't know.
Is it Tommy Hilfiger?
Son taught you son of a bitch.
Tommy Hilfiger son has limo life.
He's a rapper as well.
Oh,
terrific.
All you need is a neck tattoo here.
Let.
He's smoking cigarettes.
Yeah.
No,
it's true.
That kind of working too much.
Jane was racist.
All white people at the same time.
Yeah.
What's up man?
Can we do me and Tom Hanks thing,
right?
Same thing there.
Jamie thought that it would think.
Think what?
Oh,
he's jacked.
Damn.
He's good luck.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
It's probably getting all the pussy.
Oh,
Howard Stern.
Adam?
Yes.
No,
he fused with Howard Stern.
Why he threatens them.
Hold on.
Go to that site visit please.
What is that about?
What is this top me?
Scroll down.
We could read that.
Tom,
Tom Hanks,
rapper son,
feuds with Howard Stern.
Threatens violence.
Make that large place.
Tom Hanks.
Rapper Son Chester,
Aka Chet Hayes.
Oh,
his name is chet hates.
Took to twitter to threaten radio shock
jock Howard stern this week after
stirring question.
Hague's Hayes Gangsta credentials as the
son of a famous Hollywood celebrity.
Oh my God.
He joked at Tom Hanks.
Must be annoyed that it's someone
pretends to be a hardened rapper while
he grew up in a Tony,
California.
Sabra.
I always loved that word,
Tony,
and let people use it for posh.
Where'd he grow up?
Beverly Hills Stern joked.
That's what a fucking Douche.
Ah,
so what did he say?
What'd he say?
He's unleashed a torrent of tweets.
Threatening violence.
Calling him a fucking Jheri curl con.
What is he saying?
Oh,
you said Howard Stern.
Give your sorry ass.
White Yuppie.
Fencing entertainment.
Oh,
you can't say white Yuppie fans when
you're a white Yuppie and invite me up
there.
I promise I won't physically whoop your
ass.
After stern apparently stopped
responding to Hayes.
He took the threats up a notch.
How we do you have any idea how badly I
am going to assault you when I see you?
You can't run from me for forever and
knocked knees.
Haze.
Then knock stern for not having much
bread as my spread as much bread.
Oh,
it's his family.
Despite despite the fact that according
to Forbes Stern is worth an estimated
95,000,005,
he gets $500 million every two years.
It's something crazy like that,
right?
Yeah.
Howard Stern,
it's a shame.
You don't hang the same circles as my
family.
Not Enough bread for that because you
see,
if you did,
I would have already seen you tomorrow.
TMZ or Gawker will write an article
about a b o I t this rent and all I
gotta say is,
keep riding my Dick bitches.
Ah Ha.
Wow.
Magic as your kid.
Imagine if that was your kid,
I would choke conscious.
Fuck it.
Take him down.
I would take us back and I would put
them to sleep and then I'd take pictures
of my dick on his forehead.
Yeah.
An outline it.
That's enough.
That's intervention time.
Son of a bitch.
You're threatening the greatest radio
personality in the history of the known
universe because he said you.
You're a fucking goof.
Yeah.
And what do you do?
You act like a fucking goof.
Goddammit.
Assault you so hard.
But think about it.
Why can't a rich guy be a bad ass?
He maybe he is violent.
Maybe he's a little nuts.
He likes guns.
I,
I've never heard his rap.
Do we have even wrapped available?
There are.
I'm sure rich guys who grow up rich,
who severely overcompensate because they
feel like they live in this soft
environment,
so they fucking go to crossfit every day
and Tattoo Jitsu and become a hard ass.
Yeah.
I don't think he's on that list now.
I don't think Tom Hanks was beating his
ass at night.
I just don't.
I just think what he's doing is just
trying to be hard and trying to respond
to Howard Stern,
calling them out about that.
It's just like,
come on kid.
Like,
did you,
was your dad not around like and you
call him and talk to him about it.
He would say.
He would say,
what the fuck are you going to say?
Don't say that.
And how old is he?
If he's under 23,
I'll give them a pass.
It's almost like God son,
remember God is God.
His son was always trying to be a bad
ass son was a criminal.
Yeah.
I mean he was in the families in the
family business.
I guess it's different with the,
with the mafia,
but he's not like Dr Dre is kid.
Yeah.
You know what I'm saying?
He's fucking forrest gumps kid.
No disrespect.
Tom Hanks.
I'm a big fan.
I love Janet Green Mile.
He's a great actor.
He's the best dad.
He's a great actor and by all accounts,
a lovely person.
Yes.
I don't know if he did his job or not.
I mean,
I'm just talking shit about him not
being around,
but I just got to assume that if you're
doing that many movies,
you're not around.
It's producing to be.
Didn't he?
Didn't you have a studio also?
I don't know.
I think he's got his hand in a studio as
well.
That's always amazing to me.
It's like you're being handed literally.
If you're Tom Hanks,
you're the first guy that gets offered
every script.
It's in your age range that comes along.
What are you gonna you gonna fucking
produce.
Also what it would take on the headache
of producing movies.
Maybe enjoys it,
but what have been enjoying hanging out
with your family a little bit.
I got weirded out with him when he
started doing those movies about like
the fucking secret biblical fucking
Divinci Code.
Yeah.
I was like,
did you read these scripts?
Yeah,
that was bad.
These are terrible movies you got.
Damn.
Tom Hanks was a bad book.
Has It?
Has a bad book and it become a good
movie.
There were so clunky.
Yeah.
I was like,
this just seems to me like something
someone does when they don't have
anything else to do.
And the guy who wrote the book,
Dan,
something around Dan Brown,
he I think had a hand in the movie so he
would ever chance it had of upgrading
was destroyed.
Well,
I don't think they wanted to upgrade.
I think it's like.
I mean,
did they want to upgrade the fucking.
What is the vampire movie that the girls
like with the vampire is a lot of live
in the day.
Twilight.
They're not trying to upgrade twilight.
Right.
They wanted to give them,
kind of made it popular,
but I think they kind of did.
Are you a secret trial?
I got a daughter.
I've seen it,
yeah.
I've seen them and they're fucking
great.
We're just really well done.
Really well done.
You're getting emotional.
I could see the milk coming out of your
nipples while you're saying.
Yes.
Ridiculous.
Dude,
I just took her to see,
uh,
the beach boys last weekend.
Oh my God was real beach boys,
Brian Wilson and it was a,
didn't one of them die recently.
Um,
I think one of the brothers May die,
but it was a al Jardeen who founded the
beach boys with Brian Wilson and then
they had a couple other than they had al
Jardeen son who can hit the fucking
notes now.
His son is a bad ass singer,
but it was just fucking crate.
They play the entire pet sounds album
song by song and then they played all
the hits and it was just me and my
daughter just had such a blast because
she has,
she's 14 and she loves fucking like the
Mamas and the Papas and the allman
brothers and Cheryl Jam and she's got
amazing taste and she,
and she's a surfer.
She's been surfing for five years,
like three days a week.
The beach boys are her favorite,
sad pet sounds is their favorite album.
So that was my birthday present was two
tickets and I brought her and she was
singing to every fucking word and we
were laughing.
We had a contest about every time you
see a Hawaiian shirt,
you get to punch the other person in the
arm.
If you see a bald guy with a ponytail
that's two punches,
open toed sandals with a Hawaiian shirt.
And the ponytail was three punches.
So shoe must have beat the fuck out.
She fucking nailed me because I got bad
eyes.
She was spotted these guys from a
hundred yards away.
Well and um,
and a psychotic game.
Yeah.
Fucking beach boys concert.
You get beaten to death,
right?
Kennison had a bit about the beach boys
in the fucking eighties.
He had to beat a bit about the beach
boys phoning it in,
in the eighties,
I think it was.
You can tell they're just looking at
their watch away.
Big California Yoga.
Right,
right.
I'll tell you what though,
fucking gives you goosebumps when you
hear it.
Really,
it really because you will,
you realize he's not going to be doing
this much longer.
Right.
And uh,
you know,
I feel that way when I see the stones.
I want to see the stock and show.
What'd you see?
The stones?
I saw them in giant stadium and then I
saw them at the staples center.
I heard Mick Jagger is a very frugal.
That's a nice one.
I heard of you.
That's what I heard.
Yeah.
Like how could you be?
He's got to be worth hundreds of
millions of dollars.
Yeah.
He's still performing all over the
world.
All right.
Just saving that cash.
That's right.
Putting it away for a rainy day.
But he's got a lot.
A lot of kids.
A lot of wives.
That's right.
He's got a bunch of baby mamas,
but still the money.
Crazy money.
He's got a recent one.
Does he?
Yeah,
he knocked a checkup a couple of years
ago.
Mc.
She's hot too.
I think she's Brazilian and I think
she's like 28 or something like that.
And how old is he?
Seventy five.
Ballerina.
Feel like she's a ballerina.
So if he's 75,
you're guaranteeing that this child will
experience his father's death in the
first 20 years.
Of his life,
you don't want something really crazy
happens like technologically,
like medical technology gets to some
point where they can reverse aging,
which is apparently when you talk to
people who are like legitimate
scientists about this,
they're like,
this is not outside the realm of
possibility by any stretch of the
imagination,
like within our lifetime.
It is entirely possible that they
figured out a way to stop the aging
process dead in its tracks.
Yeah.
Well Silicon Valley believes it.
All those dudes,
if got think tanks gallon for a
cryogenically saving well cryogenics I
would imagine if you do it regularly,
I bet that difference.
You're talking about cryotherapy.
Cryogenics is actually freezing the
body.
Right?
Right,
right.
Yeah.
Therapy I would think would add some,
some time with,
as a company in northern California,
the takes the blood of young people,
injects it into the bodies of old people
and there's anecdotal research and
research with mice that points to the
fact that it's opposed to radically
improve behavior and energy and mice.
And conversely,
when they take the older mice is blood
and they put it in a younger mouse and
younger males like,
what the fuck?
Y'All just starts acting like an old
mouse shit.
Yeah.
And so we had um,
Eric Weinstein on the other day who
works for Peter Teal and Peter Teal is
that billionaire guy in Silicon Valley
who,
uh,
he was the guy that funded that Hulk
Hogan lawsuit against Gawker.
That crushed Gawker.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because they outed him.
Apparently they outed him as being gay
and he was really pissed at them.
They wrote some really shitty articles
about him and he was like,
all right,
fuck you.
How about I just use my money and crush
you?
So he went after that.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
Apparently he's offering the women who
have accused Harvey Weinstein of sexual
assault.
He's offering each one of them $100,000
to go after him.
Wow.
Yeah.
This guy,
he's,
he's like,
he's an interesting,
very interesting character,
but super rich,
super smart.
It doesn't give a fuck.
And so the rumor was that he was doing
this therapy,
but since I've been,
I've heard that does not confirmed was
that Jamie Teal is not harvesting the
blood of the county.
That's a good picture of Elon musk
though,
trying to work on some kind of life
longevity thing.
Really.
He's probably working on everything.
That fucker.
He makes me feel really stupid.
He was at a comedy show once that I did
with that chick that he just dumped
Johnny Depp's old girlfriend and uh,
I got legitimately nervous did he was in
the audience and the audience.
I have a bit about inventors.
Yeah.
I mean a guy like I as a comedian,
and I hope this doesn't come out the
wrong way in order for me to be able to
get on stage in front of hundreds of
people and take the reins and go,
alright,
you hundreds of people are going to all
shut the fuck up.
I'm the funniest one of them.
I merit you all being quiet for an hour.
You have to do mind games with yourself
sometimes,
like,
especially when you're starting out.
And so you have to some.
Sometimes if it's a Gig I'm intimidated
by,
I'll think to myself,
I'm smarter than everybody in this room
and I know I'm not,
but I have to tell myself that that's a
ridiculous.
And then it's so hard when you get up.
And um,
I remember I did a Gig at this very
hipster place in New York and Johnny
Depp was in the audience and he was with
some fucking model who looked like she
was literally starving to death and
everybody in the crowd was just in black
and they were all here.
And I really felt like.
And I said it on stage,
I go,
usually I just tell myself I'm better
looking and I'm richer than everybody in
the audience.
And tonight I realized I'm the poorest,
ugliest person here
trying to convince yourself I'm the best
looking down a of ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Greg Fitzsimmons Ball.
Rankled short
shimming onstage.
But that's the mind game.
That's the trick.
It's like visualization.
Why?
Why that trick you're supposed to.
Because I get scared.
I get intimidated.
Not Anymore.
But when I was starting out I used to
all the time.
Well,
when I come back and I look at like
starting out when you and I both started
out,
we were both like 21.
What the fuck does a 21 year old have to
say about anything?
Yeah,
we're so dumb.
I know.
Like I imagined myself today going on
stage at 21,
like being in the room,
watching myself going onstage at 21 and
just thinking what a fucking idiot.
Yeah.
Like you don't know anything about life.
You're basically fresh out of high
school.
Just paying your own bills for like a
couple of years.
Yeah.
And here you are talking into a
microphone.
We're grown adults.
Like I went on stage exactly 16 days
after it was legal for me to drink.
Yeah.
And you get middle aged people that have
real jobs,
mortgages,
back from the war.
People with college degrees,
master's degrees.
People have pulled people out of burning
buildings.
Yeah.
Okay.
I've lost friends and gunfights guy,
widows 21 year old talking to a widow,
trying to make them laugh.
Fucking idiot.
I was
but this.
But there's no other way to do it.
Like Dane Cook said this once and is a
very insightful thing.
He was like,
if I had to do it again,
like I've had to start comedy again.
I really don't think I could do it.
He's like,
it was just,
it's so overwhelming.
The idea of starting again,
like 10 years in,
you know?
Yeah.
But that's kind what
we've done with podcasting.
We start over again.
I mean we had momentum because we had
been in an entertainment,
but I feel like it was the healthiest
thing in the world,
the podcast for me because you know,
would have been all these years would do
and stand up and you get to a certain
point where I always think of it as like
your bottom and your top rise over the
years.
They should,
they should get to like the worst bomb
you're going to have now is so much
higher than the worst bomb you would
have had five years ago,
10 years ago,
20 years ago.
And so you do need to challenge yourself
and like with the podcast,
it's a whole different rhythm and if
you're not,
you're not getting immediate feedback
and,
and plus it's a business.
You've got to build it,
you've got to get your equipment and you
got to,
you know,
sell ads and all that shit.
And it was like,
for me it was really good at woke me up
again.
Like,
oh yeah,
I got.
It gave me confidence that I could do
something new.
That's interesting because you already
doing the radio show,
right?
Well,
I did the podcast about a year after I
started the radio show.
How long have you been doing the
apologize?
Like eight or nine years?
Yeah,
I didn't think of it at all that way.
I thought of the podcast is just fun.
Yeah,
it was something to do for a goof and I
did it for years,
like irregularly before I ever wanted up
committing to it,
but like every few weeks and then
finally in a room,
the green room we would do in the
greenroom.
Joey Diaz would always get mad.
Shut that fucking thing off.
You guys were always fucking online to
fuck around online.
Shut it off.
Joe Rogan.
He'll would get mad.
I'd be like,
people like it.
You waste your fucking time on the
Internet.
Yeah,
I was relentless.
That's like the biggest part of his
life.
Now.
His podcast is gigantic for him.
Yeah.
Yeah,
just did it the other night.
He was so high he fucking gave me the.
He,
I've forgot where his studio was,
so I said,
send me the address again.
So He sends me address if I fucking pull
up on this dark road.
And I go to,
I go,
oh,
he wants to suck,
fucking switch the studio or something
because this isn't the old one.
So I got her.
What the fuck?
It's a house I guess he's doing in the
back of his house.
I fucking ring the doorbell.
It's his house.
It was so high.
He gave me his fucking home address.
I'm texting him,
I'm out front.
I'm looking.
The fuck has street something.
Greg Fitzsimmons and I walk in and he's
chewing down those.
What are they?
Black start something.
He's got a bond going.
He's had mushrooms.
Least Siad is sitting there.
His eyes are shut.
I don't know how he does it.
Leaks.
We can't handle it
in his eyes sometimes.
Look,
I've been on the show before and when
someone says something,
I always feel like we're having a
conversation and someone says something
like,
well what do you mean by that?
Yeah.
And then we'll have a talk.
But if you say like Lee said something,
I go,
what does that mean?
And he was like,
lock up.
Like it's just way too high to have this
guy.
He was talking about how he
was like,
it seems like audio is the thing of the
future.
I go,
what?
What do you mean?
He goes,
well,
just seems like people like they always
on their phones while they're on tv or
the watched the movie.
They're talking on their phone or
they're looking through their phone and
they're listening to things while
they're doing other things are at what
I'll get you when you're listening to
things while you're watching TV,
you're watching who the fuck was playing
with their phone while they're watching
TV and he's like,
fuck it.
Paranoia.
Wash over him.
Like a tidal wave of my area that we
have this poor guy to hi.
Joey makes him do everything he does.
Not Always Joey do that.
Joey swaps edibles on him like,
please try this.
It's only 50 milligrams and it will take
a 500 milligram pot and they'll put it
in the wrapper of a 50 and twisted
backup.
Mild to smile.
I have four of them and so it gives him
enough to make you reconsider your
existence in the universe while he's
running the soundboard and he doesn't
fuck up.
He's a good engineer.
It's very good.
Yeah.
It's like,
I don't know if it's healthy to be
around joey all the time like that.
Like it can be really dangerous.
We'll also joey so good to him.
You know?
They just have like a very,
very unique relationship man.
I mean that's a,
that's a god shell,
that relationship right there because
Joe,
he's like a father figure to him.
Kind of.
Yeah,
and some insane way.
Joe.
He's a sweetheart.
As long as your on his side.
Yeah.
But the worst place in the world is a
guy who's against joey.
Joey's what the worst.
I've seen like God,
Joey have feuds with people.
It is a horrible thing to watch,
you know,
like,
because he's so passionate about his
friendship with people that when someone
turns on him,
like he's the,
as,
as loving and is friendly and as warm as
he is,
like you know how he is like when he
sees you,
it's all hugs and you know,
he calls you up because her greg
Fitzsimmons,
what's going on?
He said he's going to have you guys been
a dick.
You know what you're doing dog,
you know,
and he loves you.
I love Joey.
I mean he's my family.
One hundred percent.
But if you turn on him,
man,
it's a fucking horror.
I've seen him go after people.
It's airy.
It's crazy.
He's so like he's Cuban know.
And he came up.
He had a really fucked up situation
going growing up.
His,
he found his mom did when he was 13.
He was on acid.
Yeah.
I mean,
so he was raised by his friends.
Famous a tit that night too.
It wasn't.
Yeah,
it was second.
Some girls tit on acid found his mom.
Dad.
Yeah.
Boy.
Some symbolism in that.
Oh,
remember when Sugen until it was like,
oh,
it goes against.
I don't need anything better than this.
I still.
It's still my wife.
Thank God I could not have married a
woman that didn't have nice tits.
There's a lot of women out there with
little tips that are angry at you right
now.
Sorry,
you're not real women.
I'm kidding.
But I couldn't have married one.
I respect you and I'll hang out with
you.
I'll let you into my shows,
but I'm not gonna marry you.
If you get out of the Itty bitty shitty
committee early and you want to go see a
comedy show,
you know,
I,
I look,
I respect all women.
I just think I really told them.
What about mean ones that kill people.
Respect them even more.
They're fighting back their meat,
their meat tooling out there.
Huh?
Do you hear about the Hashtag?
Me Too.
No,
you're going to love this Joe Rogan.
There's a thing now because of Harvey
Weinstein.
There's a hash tag.
Women that have been sexually harassed.
Pound sign me to on their social media,
Jesus Christ and the end.
You sexually harassed,
I would say it's probably a 100 percent.
Yeah.
Because it's a murky definition,
right?
You know,
I mean some of the stories that you hear
and I look this Harvey Weinstein thing
is atrocious and guys that are like that
are the reason why guys like us have to
watch what we say.
All the sensitivity that we've been
talking about is because of a few,
not a few assets.
There's a lot of assholes,
but it's not.
I mean we're not talking about a person
trying to get late.
We're talking about a person who is
holding employment over people power.
And did you see the TMC thing?
We're TMZ.
They were describing the nature of his
contract that he had sexual assault and
um,
and sexual harassment lawsuits written
into the contract.
Again,
like a wave or find?
Yeah.
How much you would be fined.
And for one,
one,
one.
I'm the person saying it.
It was a certain amount of money for two
allegations.
Oh no shit.
It was more for three,
it was like he was like 100,000
to 57 $50 million
law written in like caps on how much he
should have to pay.
No,
like how much they would pay him like
your or how much he would have to pay
according to the contract.
If Weinstein treated someone in
properly,
in violation of the company's code of
conduct,
he must reimburse twc for the
settlements or judgments.
Additionally,
you Weinstein will pay the company
liquidated damages of $250,000
for the first such instance.
Five hundred thousand dollars for the
second such instance,
7:50
for the third and a million for each
additional instance to just imagine that
they wrote this in.
They're complicit,
they're all complicit.
There's another provision,
uh,
he can be fired for the purpose,
to purpose,
to Asian.
Have you
ever sent a perpetuation?
That's a weird word.
Yeah.
It is perpetuation by you.
A Weinstein of a material fraud against
the company.
Okay.
What does that mean?
The question,
where's the fraud?
Lance Mirror off a board member who
negotiated the Weinstein.
200,
15,
2015 contract.
Said in an interview,
and we've confirmed the board knew
Weinstein had settled prior lawsuits
brought by various women,
but they assumed it was the coverup
consensual affair.
Sure it was.
The board's assumption does not
constitute fraud on Weinstein's part.
Scroll up,
let's keep going.
More surprisingly is how twc fired
Weinstein's.
Suppose Weinstein.
No Weinstein supposedly without giving a
specific reason,
which could potentially violate the
terms of the contract.
Oh my God,
that's crazy.
Here's the kicker.
Even if Weinstein had committed fraud by
not fully informing the board of
directors,
the contract says before he can be
fired,
he has the right to mediation.
If that doesn't work,
he's entitled to arbitration.
He got neither.
He was summarily fired and sources
connected with Weinstein.
Tell tmz he was never given a specific
reason.
Wow.
Well,
he's fighting it.
Yeah,
I love that.
Where do you get the balls to fight
back right now?
I guess he feels like he's the only way
to sort of reclaim some ground.
Yeah,
I mean,
is that a way to look at it?
Well,
that's that mentality and you know,
at that level,
the power brokers that run Hollywood,
you know,
they're all fucking.
It's trump is like that too.
It's all aggression.
It's all come at you when you come here.
Yeah,
I mean it's got to be a crazy position
to be in,
to be the head of Miramax.
Yeah.
No,
I mean it's like,
it's the biggest,
it's one of the biggest,
right.
What's the biggest,
what is the biggest studio,
if it's not Miramax is universal.
Miramax,
so at the very least he's responsible
for some of the most iconic movies over.
Yeah.
Certainly the most Oscar is of any
studio in the last year,
20 years.
So everyone's kissing his ass.
Yeah.
Massive amounts of power and this
influence over people like royalty,
right?
Barks,
they all come,
you know,
everybody's at his whim constantly and
then tries to fuck all these starlets.
Like if he had just stuck with like
prostitutes,
it probably still would come out,
but it wouldn't come out the same way.
It wouldn't come out.
You will think about the fact that they
covered up sexual assault on it sounds
like a weekly basis.
I mean this,
this story broke what five days ago,
something like that and is already so
many women that have come out and now
you've got a bounty on more women to
come out.
Like somebody.
I think that somebody is offering
a certain amount of money for every
woman that comes out against him,
so it's going to be like cosby all over
again and you think about.
But God,
because bea was drugging and raping,
nobody just means it's another step.
Another step more evil though.
Right?
I'm just talking about like the
frequency of it and,
and the complicity of people that set up
the meetings.
You're covered up to lawsuits.
Oh yeah.
Gave the women work after the meetings.
You know,
a lot of them got script deals,
got roles in movies because that's a lot
of them didn't walk out of the room.
A lot of them gave him the back rub or
whatever else.
Yeah.
Well that was what Whitney was talking
about the other day.
Whitney.
Cummings was telling me,
her and one of her friends who's an
actress,
I did their show at the largo the other
night and they were in the green room
and they were talking about how many
women literally wrote into their
contract,
like not wrote into it,
but there was an agreement that they
would fuck him to get like editor's cut.
They would fuck him to get more lines
there.
Yeah.
Girls like prominent actresses had sex
with him to ensure that they got big
roles.
This was written down.
Some of it was agreed upon.
I don't know if they wrote it,
but these things were agreed upon and
that he always kept his end of the
bargain.
He was known.
She's known for hooking them up is part
of how he got this whole thing to work,
which means every director and editor
that kept those lines in new because
editors all the time or chop chop out
whole scenes because they don't work.
Yeah,
but that's only.
That's like say like when did it happen?
Did it happen before the film was shot?
Like she would give them final cut like
you would allow them to,
you know,
to be in the editing room or was it
like,
oh,
I will give you the choice part,
whatever.
It was like some sneaky deal.
Yeah.
I mean,
who knows who,
how he said it,
who knows how they did it,
but the idea that all these actors are
coming out and like,
I have no idea.
I can't believe it.
I'm so horrified.
How do you not know that I'm a road
comic and I knew about it.
I'm not in the middle of Hollywood.
Yeah.
I've known about it for 15 years.
What did you know?
I knew that he was a casting couch guy.
Everybody knew that he was the sleazy
fat.
I always would joke about how like I
think he makes himself less attractive
because it's more of a power trip for
him.
Fun.
Yeah.
To have his fat gut resting on their
forehead was shoots a load in their
mouth.
You got the part.
Yeah.
Doesn't blow.
Doesn't wash on purpose as his balls
just stink like locker rooms.
Yeah.
It's a weird thing,
man.
It's a weird thing that that's.
That went on for forever in this,
in this industry,
not this industry and the music,
the movie industry,
the music industry as well.
Sturgill Simpson was telling me some
story about some guy who was a known
peder asked who is like,
there's.
He's in a similar position in the music
business and like people know like you,
you can't have like young boys around
this guy.
He's some big time powerful guy.
He told me the guy's name.
I literally can't tell you who the fuck
it was,
but he was saying like,
man,
there's.
There are people in the music business
that everything the exact same situation
like they fuck people to have them move
on and move up and move forward.
Especially back when radio was a big
deal,
right?
Radio and record sales were inexorably
connected.
You could not sell records unless you
get on the radio.
The only band that that managed to move
through that was kiss,
kiss was rarely on the radio.
They were rarely on the radio,
but kiss had such a loyal following and
they put together such an amazing show,
a live show that they've.
They were selling millions of albums and
got almost no radio time selling out
arenas,
almost no radio,
and they were like mocked relentlessly
by people who really loved rock.
Yeah.
I never liked kiss,
but I respect what they've done.
I love kiss.
Really?
Oh yeah.
When I was a kid,
I loved them.
How many songs are there?
Do they really have good shitloads?
Depends on if you like that kind of
music.
Yeah,
look,
I mean it's like if I compare it to led
Zepplin,
like in terms of like,
like the style of music,
that depth of the composition of the
music and the lyrics and you know,
like they don't have anything that's
like a whole lot of love or anytime.
You know what I mean?
There's like,
there's certain songs that are just on
another level,
you know,
they don't have any of those.
Yeah.
But they have fun songs.
You know,
they're were a live band.
Yeah.
They have great live shows.
The live shows a great but and then some
of their,
some of their song like Beth is a good
song.
They have a bunch of good songs that are
like uncharacteristic for like what you
would think of when you think about
kiss.
Yeah.
But you know,
they had like the style of music.
It was like a fun party.
Rock'n'roll Ah,
well no.
Rock and roll and party every day.
Right.
I think that the couple songs I know
there is I like,
but when you think about the phenomenon
that is kiss,
they really don't have the songs to
support it.
Like I feel like the same way I'm going
to get shit about saying this aerosmith.
Sarah Smith has like three of the
greatest rock songs of all time.
Like literally my top 50 rock songs.
Let me,
three of them are error.
We'll walk this way,
dream on dream on.
And a mama can.
No sweet emotions when emotions.
Those three are my top in my top 50 and
then it ends.
Then he got love in the elevator and all
this shit that makes me go like,
I got to delete my files on this,
on these clowns.
What?
Well,
you know what happened to them?
Movies.
They started doing those movie anthems
should never
do those movie anthems.
They did those like armageddon
soundtrack type things where you know,
like this middle of the road popcorn
music for stupid blockbuster film.
They started trying to figure out what
the audience wanted and giving it to
them instead of being themselves.
I don't know.
I mean for whatever it is,
it's like you have two different schools
of thought in that band.
You have Joe Perry,
who I know.
He's a great guy who doesn't give a fuck
about fame.
Joe Perry's like a guy from Boston who's
just a bad ass guitarist who loves
making rock and roll.
Yeah,
he's awesome.
And then you've got what?
Steven?
Tyler Tyler,
who likes being famous and he likes
doing like what is he on?
America's got talent or one of those.
Which one of those was the on?
You did American idol.
Yeah.
It was just once he's an excel,
but that kind of shit like,
could you imagine Robert Plant doing
American idol?
Well,
I could imagine Mick Jagger doing
something like that and Keith Richards
pictures is like the,
uh,
what's that?
Just to bank checks just to bank checks.
But I think Mick Jagger and Keith
Richards have a similar kind of
situation.
Mick wanted to be famous.
Keith is just a bad ass rocker.
Mm.
Maybe.
I Dunno.
Huh?
I mean like there's nothing wrong with
wanting to be famous.
That's what you're into.
But when the music suffers or the music
changes,
you know,
you go from sweet emotions to some
nonsensical moron ballad that literally
like it.
It hurts your feelings.
Yeah.
He listened to some of those ballads and
he just like,
all right,
billy,
Joel's like that.
He's got some of the greatest fucking
son.
Remember last time we shot pool,
we listened to a few billy Joel's songs
and then you've got uptown girl.
I've got a billy Joel theory talks about
console.
Angry.
I know exactly what happened.
Christie Brinkley?
Yeah.
Too Hot.
A good little guy from long island.
All of a sudden he's banging the
supermodel that pitches hot today and
she's like,
yeah,
right.
It's hot as fuck.
She's like the hottest 64 year old woman
on the planet.
And have you seen pictures of her?
I just played.
I bowled with her recently.
Shut up.
Yup.
No,
you didn't look.
See that's when they were together.
That's when he lost his marbles.
Yeah,
that's when it was in the lane next to
me.
She looks fucking beautiful.
So where was this?
Venice.
She bowls and Venice and that crazy that
she's in her sixties and he would bang
it.
Right.
Would you tell him just because he
fucked her.
You fuck him because he fucked her.
Yeah.
I wouldn't go that far.
But do you think I would.
I would worry that you would break
because she's 64.
Send it home here at cracking in her
hips.
Is that her in the water?
How is that possible?
How does she look so hot and so many
women falling?
I didn't see Christie,
frankly.
Cindy Crawford.
I a new son of a bitch.
You just like Jamie.
Oh my God.
Look at her.
But Oh,
that's on her.
I was like,
that's insane though.
Oh it is her daughter.
No,
they're hugging some bitch.
Where's her?
But he'll come out of that.
But see that's the thing I didn't,
I don't think you can have a 64 year old
ass.
I think that.
Yeah,
every picture is like from the front and
noticed the bent leg to kind of hide
any.
Will they all do that?
It's hot as fuck.
Right.
But look,
you don't see your but go google
Christie Brinkley's.
But listen,
you're objectifying women.
No,
I'm just trying to.
I'm doing a on anatomical survey or
something.
Something that's a famous shot.
Yeah.
But that's like,
that's her sports illustrated shot.
Christine blinkers.
But at 60.
Well either way she's done a remarkable
job of staying attractive.
Very proud.
And I guess what that is is just
constant effort.
Right?
And maybe some surgery but at the very
lot of DNA involved too,
right?
Must Be.
Yeah.
But constant effort,
right?
Like constant gym time,
watching the Diet.
No.
All that stuff.
A lot of water creates,
you know.
And also they have take it all the best
skincare products.
Yeah,
I mean that's the business,
you know,
that's her business.
It's super shocking is when a woman was
like,
just some smoke and hot and then she
just lets it go.
Just let it go.
Like Kathleen Turner.
Ever Seen Kathy Turner today.
She could be Joey d as a starting level.
Would you have sex with a.
just to say you had sex.
Kathleen Turner though.
What do you think now?
No,
we'll get that picture.
Wow.
Dude.
She was fucking smoke and she had that
voice.
But I feel like there's a health issue.
Like she's so big.
It doesn't make sense a lot of times.
Um,
you know,
they have to take a steroid for
something and they blow up from the
steroid.
Oh Jesus.
Is that real good?
Make that bigger.
See,
I think it's probably alcohol too.
When you see someone that big,
it's like,
boy,
you have to eat a lot of foods.
Stay that big.
Yeah.
Unless your booze in it.
Like I know this lady,
she works out all the time,
but she boozes all the time.
Maybe you just can't.
Her legs are always like just thick and
weird.
Fuck the fucking empty calories and
booze for people who drink like
everyday.
Those everyday drinkers.
Man,
that's a,
that's a fucking drunk.
You're not a real health nut about what
you eat.
Pizza and fucking.
And then when you wake up in the morning
you feel like,
shit,
eat more shit.
Oh,
some P,
I dunno.
Maybe Kathleen Turner.
Maybe she made so much money and her
natural body is big and she just went,
fuck it.
I'm going to enjoy my life and not
suffer like Kathleen,
like I'm Christie Brinkley.
That sounds like something,
a woman who got really big would say no
one's natural bodies overweight.
That's just not that.
If you're doing that,
it's because you're eating the wrong
food.
You're not exercising,
you're definitely overeating and you're
most likely drinking.
Like that's not someone who's thick.
That's,
you know,
that's an obese woman.
Yeah,
I mean that's,
that's.
We'll get our dude.
She was the hottest woo.
She was hot.
Was that movie body heat with her?
And uh,
was that Jeff Bridges or William hurt?
Romancing the stone?
Oh,
that was like a rip off of Indiana
Jones,
right?
With Michael Douglas.
Yeah.
Those like Michael Douglas was like the
Indiana Jones character,
but it was kinda like a semi comedy.
Romancing the stone.
Yeah.
It was like he was the archaeologist.
God,
it's hard to remember why they made a
lot of shitty movies back then,
romancing the stone,
trying to go back and watch those
things.
You'd be like,
wow.
I know they were so dated Hirsi working
girl lately.
What's that?
It was a melanie griffith and she played
a girl from Staten Island who like is a
secretary at a law firm and she's a
paralegal or something.
No,
maybe an ad agency.
Yes.
No,
that's not her.
That's I'm Melanie Griffith.
Is it?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Because you know,
who else has got the big hair on this
movie is I'm Joan.
Joan.
Joan cusak.
Yeah.
So there's supposed to be like girl from
long island or something.
Yeah.
And they're working at the fancy
Manhattan office,
but they're like the gum chewing
cigarette smoking,
like that's real.
And then she,
uh,
she,
she loves her way up.
Oh,
it's a great fucking movie,
but it's so the fashion and the Harris.
She was hot back in the alien days,
right.
She was so hot.
It's a rough world man.
Look at Harrison Ford Hansen bastard.
It's weird that we're watching these
people age to like the point of decay
right in front of us because that really
wasn't a thing until about 50 years ago,
but if you really stopped,
you never got to see that.
You never got to see someone that age in
front of you like that,
like until mean 50 years maybe.
No,
maybe a little bit more.
Maybe let's get generous.
Seventy,
80 years like this is a new cultural
phenomenon to have visual evidence of
decay that you go over with a fine tooth
comb and never like this where I could
say,
hey,
pull that shit up Jamie.
Let's take a look at Kathleen turn when
she was young.
Oh yeah.
I'm
sure it didn't exist before.
After pictures.
They're already smashed together in some
photos for sure.
And it's like,
no,
you look at like Bette Davis.
She got to a certain age and then she
just went,
okay,
I'll be in my match and lock it up
behind me.
I'll see you at my funeral.
They just crawled out of the way,
like a pigeon that got injured or
Elizabeth Taylor.
She just kept marrying new gay guys.
Some new obviously gay guy.
She does.
She know like what the fuck's happening?
She was like seven,
eight.
They were like 45 year old gay guys.
Oh,
look at that.
Nineteen 83 smirnoff with Bette Davis
and add.
Oh,
Jim beam.
To have a kind of originals.
Why don't I say,
oh,
smirnoff vodka ad.
Wow.
Who was that?
The other one.
Diane.
What is her name?
Where it says in the ad right there on
83 smirnoff vodka.
What's the woman's name?
Who's Diahann Carroll.
What a weird way to spell diane.
D I a h a n n maybe she's a
photographer.
Maybe she's a lot of work.
She likes changed the spelling.
Her name be crafty.
There's a lot of Diane's d I a n,
e R,
not a lot of women.
I'm very definitely get mad when you.
Correct People d I a h a and yeah,
if you read it out,
dum dee had diane.
My name is Diane,
but why don't you spell it?
Diane?
Crazy bitch.
So phonetic language.
Yeah.
Who?
Oh,
she goes dynasty.
from dynasty.
There's a new dynasty apparently.
How good.
There's an ad.
It's hilarious.
It's a billboard and the billboard,
there's like a,
this guy and a couple of pretty women
behind them and one of the pretty women
has our tongue out like this,
like,
like showing you a little of her tongue.
That's something that unless you're a
Rockstar,
men just don't do like men never take a
picture.
Try to look sexy and like.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
Look,
just look at her tongue.
Oh yeah,
that fucking picture.
Like what is,
first of all,
it's on the CW,
which uh,
I don't even know if I have,
there's certain channels like I didn't
even know.
I don't have epics.
Direct TV doesn't have epics,
so I try to watch someone special on
epics and I was like,
oh,
I don't have that fucking thing.
So that one bitch is pulling the other
bitches hair with the tongue out.
Hung out like,
yeah,
don't want to violate.
I stick my tongue out to lick the tip of
Dick's.
Like,
what is that?
Like?
Who told her to stick her tongue out
like that?
Yeah,
baby.
Perfect.
I like it.
What if they didn't live it?
They photoshop their tongue out there
and she got the photos.
Just like,
what the fuck is this stupid shit?
Yeah.
What of my tongue out.
The editor made a choice.
An artistic choice.
This is the new like kiss,
kiss face.
The selfie face.
Who's the one that you just pulled up?
That gay picture you just pulled up.
Oh,
it was a bunch of guys.
While the guys are fighting,
the black guy's going to kick that white
guys.
Why?
We were pretending he's not.
Now he's eyeballing them that were
black.
I was going to fuck that white guy up.
I can tell by looking at their faces.
Yeah,
that's true.
You find that with mma you can
tell from the way ends and all that?
Nope.
Who's got an edge?
Definitely can't.
Now.
You think you can.
You're often wrong.
Yeah,
you can't.
You can't tell.
There's a lot of guys that look like
doughboys,
but they could fight.
They just know how to fight in.
It's also they know how to endure.
Sometimes guys,
when they don't look physically
impressive,
have had to deal with so many people
fucking with them their whole life that
the develop this sort of like Werewolf
personality,
like where they can just go,
oh yeah,
mother fucker.
And then they just keep coming.
They keep coming at you and they just
never.
They never get discouraged.
Yeah,
and those guys,
like a lot of times guys are not
physically gifted.
They have incredible work ethic because
they have to because that's the only way
they can compete and so they like,
they'll slowly break guys down just with
toughness.
The problem with those guys is they take
all the extreme beating,
right?
We're right and it's not sustainable.
And then one day they run into a guy who
was both like see there's discipline and
there's talent and a lot of times
talented people don't have discipline
and you just wish they did because then
they'd be the greatest ever will the
greatest ever or the guys with talent
and discipline,
like Anderson Silva or someone like
that,
like talented,
but also like physically superior just
moves faster and then also works
incredibly hard.
Right?
And then also can perform under pressure
and knows how to come back from behind.
Like knows that knows that it turned
around when he's getting his ass kicked.
Yeah.
That's the third aspect is you have to
have the psychological.
You have to be able to take it.
You have to be able to be the hammer or
the nail,
right?
You gotta be able to be the nail bar.
Guys can't be the nail.
They start getting hit on me like fuck
this,
I'm going to get out of there.
And some guys are great in there like
that some.
So there's some great fighters that just
can't take a beating.
It's a very strange.
Fighting is the weirdest of all sports
because it's not really a sport.
It may kind of is.
It's an athletic endeavor,
but it's so much more emotional intense
than just a regular sport like calling
it a sport.
It's just there's so much more to.
It's more personal.
Taken off to the bathroom.
Jamie can't handle it.
Jamie can't handle it now.
We don't get to see him sneak around
behind you anymore.
We have a new setup.
Yeah.
You should have a camera in the
bathroom.
You can get sued for that.
You can.
Yeah.
You ever hear about Chuck Berry?
Yes.
That came out.
That was another thing I knew.
I had heard rumors and again am I in the
fucking music industry.
I had heard rumors that chuck had hours
and hours
of footage of women pissing and shitting
and that he had cameras hidden in the
toilet seats of his restaurant in
Illinois.
I knew this shit for years and then all
of a sudden it came out in the news and
there was a class action law suit that I
believe he lost,
I should say,
I should say all of this with supposedly
allegedly don't get sued.
Allegedly.
Well,
he's dead.
He can get away with.
Oh,
is he dead?
But I mean,
it's amazing that this shit is out
there.
Bill Cosby,
I knew that Bill Cosby was molesting
women soda juice.
I knew it because when I was on the set
of news radio people knew him from
whatever thing and there was always the
thing that bill cosby drugs.
Women.
Yeah.
And I had heard it like what he does.
Like it was always some weird thing.
I never met him,
but I,
I don't even think I knew someone who
had been around him.
I think it was just like one of those
things where people just knew.
You just knew like that Michael Jackson
was probably Dylan kids.
We knew it because we knew,
uh Oh,
well that's a thing that's coming up.
What do we know?
Do we know somebody who did we know we
knew somebody who was sent a boy to the
ranch.
What's,
who's we?
I don't want to say on the air who it
is.
Somebody in the industry,
but when you say we knew like who's we?
You and I me.
Yeah.
I did not know someone who sent a boy to
the.
Unless I didn't know they send a boy the
ranch.
Maybe you didn't know.
You didn't know.
I'll tell you off the air.
Jesus Christ.
What about all these people that are
listening to this fence right now?
I know I shouldn't have brought it up.
Yeah,
you shouldn't have some of the pitch
night making all these people out there.
Don't know.
Girl.
Hanging out with Fred.
Who Was it?
Yeah.
Well I think it's one of the reasons why
we like really good stuff too,
right?
Because we can't imagine being able to
do that.
Right?
Like when you see someone who's like
playing like you see like Gary Clark Jr,
something playing guitar on stage.
Mesmer.
Damn.
That guy's good.
Like Holy Shit.
You know,
there's something about watching someone
who's mesmerizing that's equally
captivating as watching someone who's
awful.
Yeah.
Look at um,
what's his name from Queen?
Freddie Mercury.
Oh yeah.
I mean that guy fucking went for it.
He went for it back in the day when no
one even knew he was gay.
Right.
They didn't understand like what a gay
front man was like,
now you could be a gay front man now,
like Elton John is openly gay.
Everyone knows it and he goes out there
and sayings and everybody goes nuts and
back then you couldn't.
Then he Lindley stadium with a mustache
sticking out and a leather vast.
We have champions.
Yeah.
But you got to think he must gotten that
big
when they were playing bars and saloons
on their way up.
He must've been going big then.
Yeah.
Where it probably looked ridiculous,
but certain people got it.
Well,
he's so good that even when he was doing
those bars,
people must have heard that voice and
went,
Holy Shit.
Listen to this guy.
Right?
Because he could carry a fucking note.
Look at that.
Pretty sure.
That's from the movie that they're
making about them.
Oh really?
That's not him.
Oh Wow.
That guy looks amazingly well.
Can.
Yeah.
Oh,
I thought his name is Malik is the
actor's name was Brian j singer.
Is that that?
I think Sasha Baron Cohen wanted that
role.
Really?
Yeah,
he probably would have nailed it.
Yep.
Wonder whether they give it to them.
I mean,
it's almost like a keep bob.
Did you see that?
What was it?
Live aid where they were simulcasting
from London and Philadelphia at the same
time.
Scroll up,
scroll up there,
and he fucking stole the shell.
That's him for real live aid.
Where Sasha Baron Cohen stole the show.
Who now we're a Freddie.
Mercury.
Did know it was back in 80 fourish.
When did he die?
He was like one of the first big names
to diabetes.
Where you heard about you on what?
Right.
Fucked up man.
Ninety one.
Eighty one.
Nobody dies ways.
Now.
It's a very rare.
Yeah.
I don't say nobody,
but it's saying like nobody dies a
syphilis and you still can,
but she,
the California just recently reduced the
penalty of not telling someone that you
have HIV.
Oh,
did they?
Yeah.
Like wantonly infecting someone with HIV
is no longer a felony.
Why?
The guy who introduced it,
the senator,
there's a fucking picture of him.
New California law reduces penalty for
knowingly exposing someone to HIV.
Why the fuck would you do that?
HIV is a public health issue,
not a criminal issue.
California state Senator Scott Wiener
said in support of the bill,
which takes now Google that guy and find
a picture of him with his shirt off with
a leather vest on a six pack and a dog
collar around his neck and I'm not
kidding.
I'm not kidding.
Like there's a fucking image of him.
That's him,
but he's jacked.
There's.
But there's a photo.
Oh yeah.
Look at this.
Sorry,
not a dog collar.
He's got a leather tie wrapped around
his neck.
Might as well be a dog collar.
But look at this.
This is the guy.
If he's not gay,
he's certainly sympathetic to the cause
and this is the guy that's supporting
this bill saying that HIV is a health
issue.
No,
it's not a health issue.
If you fucking knowingly give it to
somebody via knowingly shoot a hot load
into someone knowing you have HIV,
you get back from the doctor.
Doctor says,
Greg,
I got some bad news for you.
You got the Hib and you're like,
well,
I got bad news for everyone's shooting
loads to because I'm not going to tell
them.
I like shooting loads into people.
I don't like condoms.
Like you're doing a criminal act.
It's.
It's a deadly weapon.
Your semen is a deadly weapon.
Not Today if you get treatment,
but what if someone doesn't like
doctors?
Yeah.
What have they're afraid of?
Doctors.
There's a lot of people that are afraid.
They're afraid to go into the doctor so
they don't go to the doctor.
HIV turns into a's.
They'd die of AIDS.
You fucking gave it to him that that was
that not a felony.
Right?
Who would want to reduce that crime?
Who'd want to reduce the crime of
knowingly exposing someone to a death
dealing disease,
a disease that's killed untold hundreds
of thousands if not millions of people
worldwide.
Right?
Mean,
I don't know what the numbers,
but it's probably the millions,
right?
Yeah.
But why would you do that?
Like who's clamoring for that to be
reduced?
When I think about how many guys are,
what do they call it on the down low
where they go out and they have sex with
men,
get sick and then have sex with their
wives.
A lot of wives get aids or HIV,
right?
I get HIV.
Yeah.
That's,
that's uh,
that's one of those diseases where they
essentially found a cure for it.
Right?
They have a treatment and that treatment
reduces it to the point where it's not
even.
You can't even detect it in the blood
anymore.
Oh,
it's that good.
It's undetectable.
Like Magic Johnson said that Jesus did
it for him.
Jesus made,
made my hiv go away.
No longer detectable.
That is so cool to magic.
Johnson accent is horrible impression.
But yeah,
they,
they literally have gotten into the
point where it's undetectable.
What does it say number of deaths due to
HIV AIDS estimates by country?
Yeah,
there was a million last year,
but it has no data for United States.
See,
the thing about that is,
and this is how it's been explained to
me,
so I'm sure if someone will correct me
if I'm wrong,
the problem with this distinction,
and this is one of the real problems
with the way they used it to describe
Africa,
they were saying all these people in
Africa get aids and die.
Well,
this doctor was telling me,
and he's just completely off the record
when he was telling me this because he's
like,
well,
progressive,
very smart liberal guy.
So like,
okay.
He goes,
what you're talking about is people with
extremely compromised immune systems.
That's from a variety of different
reasons.
He goes,
dude,
they're not getting HIV tests,
and he goes,
these people in these really poor areas
in Africa,
this is,
you know,
we're talking like early two thousands.
He's like,
they're not giving these people HIV
tests.
They're not flying to Africa and
administering these expensive tests on
these people.
He's like,
these people have extremely compromised
immune systems.
They checked their t cell count,
low t cell counts are very low,
they're very unhealthy and so they say
they have aids and that's how you get
funding and get funding.
As you say,
there's a million cases of AIDS in
Africa.
You don't get funding when you say
there's a million cases of people who
are malnourished,
who have a host of horrific diseases and
acceptable that we're trending to 50
percent of African American gay bi men
having HIV must end this health
disparity.
Why are you pulling that?
Oh,
that's.
That's wiener.
That's the guy.
His name's wiener,
which is hilarious.
Now they're wiener wiener,
but unacceptable that we're trending to
50 percent of African American gay bi
men having HIV.
Meanwhile he says,
must end this health disparity and the
best way to end it is to reduce the
penalty from knowingly giving it.
It's just,
I don't want to say that he has it and
he just wants to make it a little easier
on himself,
but it's.
Why would you do that?
Like why would you want to reduce that?
Owen Benjamin had a great tweet about
it.
Allow Charlie something about allowing
Charlie Sheen to,
uh,
California is allowing Charlie Sheen to
have less of a penalty for having
unprotected sex with unsuspecting young
women.
You fucking psychos like that.
Yeah.
Well,
it's,
you know,
the question is can you legislate
behavior,
right?
Kenya,
it's a tricky one.
Can you lead,
do you want to write?
Do you want to legislate behavior or do
you want people to just be like,
but you have to punish people for why.
Like if,
if you have some sort of an incurable
disease,
aids obviously is curable or HIV is
right.
At least at this point it's treatable.
I shouldn't say curable,
but if you have something like what
would it be?
Okay.
Like,
here's a perfect example.
Member.
When that woman came back from Africa
and they suspected that she had been
exposed to Ebola and people were
freaking the fuck out because she was
wandering around,
she was like,
I'm not,
I'm not going to be quarantined.
Fuck off.
And they're like,
this bitch is a monster.
Right?
That's much more communicable than HIV
is,
I guess,
but not much difference in terms of like
what it can do and then you're talking
about something that kills people,
right?
It's Kinda the same thing and a lot of
ways,
but we,
we tend to look past things that are
sexually transmitted because I don't get
fucked,
you know what I mean?
Problems,
you know,
don't do anything that Jesus wouldn't
want you to do and you don't have any
issues.
What do you take it in the ass,
you fucking piece of shit.
You horrible person.
No.
Now it's like,
now we're there.
Um,
they're allowing companies to not have
to cover women's birth control and it's
like they want to shame.
They want to shame people from having
sex.
It's the same thing with,
uh,
you know,
not paying for abortions.
Do you really think that's what it is?
I think orgasms are free and the,
and the,
the,
the haves fucking drives me crazy.
I don't think that's what it is.
I think it's a financial issue.
I think if you look behind it,
I bet there's probably insurance
companies that are involved in.
This was probably a lot of people that
look,
if you're,
if you have to pay or companies,
if company has to pay for your
employee's birth control pills and you
have 100,000
employees,
how many birth control pills you paying
for?
That's a lot of money.
I mean,
and you go across the board and also you
set a precedent.
If you have to pay for that,
maybe you have to pay for something that
comes along with similar to for men or
some other issue that women might have
that has to be covered.
I think it's all financial expensive
though to have women missing work for
pregnancies,
firearm,
fuck them.
It's kind of a weird thing,
right?
It's because.
Because if somebody works for you,
they don't just work for you.
Right?
We are assuming that person is dependent
upon you.
Just one of the weirder things about
employment.
It's like that's not just someone who
works for you.
You have to take care of that person.
You're supposed to provide them with
insurance.
benefits.
He's supposed to allow them to take time
off and it's a weird thing because
we're,
we're like,
we've settled into the idea that this
person is completely dependent upon
their employer.
You know,
I think I'm like this idea that if a
woman has a child that you have to give
her maternity leave,
we have to pay her while she has the
baby and that you have to maybe pay
child support or some sort of child care
while she has the baby that people
really want that they want that as part
of it because people,
the way people live in this country in
particular,
and we just assume that you have to live
this way because we compare ourselves to
people that live in,
like indigenous tribes are in third
world countries where they don't have
constant employment and they don't have
high overhead.
Right.
Rent,
bills,
all the different things that we have,
but we have this system set up where
once you're in the system,
once you start making that money,
you need that money and when the kid
comes,
you can't just quit work like no one
does that anymore.
Like we don't think anyone should do
that anymore.
We assume that woman is eventually going
to go back to work,
so she's going to get maternity leave
because the company values are as an
employee and then once she's done with
her maternity leave,
maybe there'll be some sort of
compensation or some sort of a and she
definitely won't be working long hours
or overtime anymore.
I've just got to get home and take care
of a kid.
You know?
That's the hidden thing in the whole
argument against the financial,
the difference in the amount of money,
like income disparity between men and
women,
but the big one,
one of the big ones is the number of
hours that women are willing to work.
There's a series of choices,
right?
There's the,
the,
the jobs they gravitate towards.
There's the number of hours that they're
willing to work.
There's taking time off when they have
children and another one of the big ones
is this is one that works sort of
against them.
That doesn't get discussed when men are
trying to say that the income inequality
thing is all bullshit.
Women are not as good at negotiating for
a better salary.
They're not as aggressive in negotiating
for a better salary
and even if they do just as good a job
as the man that that's the one area
where they sort of seem to fall behind
where it's like a rational distinction
that a woman is doing the same job as a
man and not getting paid as well because
when you look at the income inequality
between men and women,
you know it's like 77 percent cents on
the dollar.
It's really not real.
It's not like they're working the same
job next to each other.
You were telling me it's because they've
mental work more dangerous jobs that
tend to pay more.
Yeah.
More dangerous jobs tend to pay more.
Men are much more likely to die on the
job.
It's.
It's much more likely to get injured on
the job.
There's a bunch of fields that men
gravitates toward,
gravitate towards that are particularly
just interesting and attractive to men
that women don't gravitate towards and
if they do,
it's in lower numbers.
And this obviously these are gross
generalizations because there's women
who are MMA fighters,
right?
A lot of them,
I mean I see him all the time.
A lot of them are lesbians that a lot of
them with a few.
So it's like people are,
you know,
you can't like just pigeonhole people.
You know,
there's a lot of men that are florists,
right?
Is you can't.
It's very difficult to just like say a
man is this and a woman.
Is that because this trends obviously
for sure trends and to deny those trends
seems to be the state of discourse
today.
People like to deny those,
those trends and any accepting of those
trends is some sort of accepting of this
systematic oppression of women or
systematic oppression of gay people or
it's a very weird.
In this woman who wrote that book,
lean in.
I think it was a lot about that.
Like negotiate,
you know,
it shouldn't be mandated.
You should be able to go in and fight
for your salary,
get a better salary,
fight for the corner off,
as you know.
Don't,
don't wait for it to be handed to you
because the patriarchal system is not
going to suddenly just make things fair,
but it's a patriarchal system.
Real.
Is there a patriarchal system like
Weinstein?
I mean,
okay,
that's a different thing because that's
a power issue,
right?
And when you,
when you have absolute power like that
guy had and you're also a fat,
ugly fuck,
and you realize this is a way to get
gwenyth paltrow suck my dick.
You know,
that's,
that's a unique situation.
But also,
but I think the dynamic of it is that
since men do obvious,
quantifiably have more power positions
on boards of companies and management
partners,
that women are intimidated by that
they're intimidated to go up against it.
I think there's also a thing where women
don't want to be a bitch,
right?
They like,
men don't view a woman who's aggressive
the same way they view a man as
aggressive.
Like if you and I work in an office and
you're like always hustling and getting
ahead and always fighting for what's
yours.
Like Greg's Greg's and aggressive
motherfucker.
You get shit done.
But if a woman is doing the exact same
thing,
that fucking bitch,
I don't want to be around her.
She's such a bitch,
you know,
like a woman who exhibits the same of
aggressive tendencies
is,
it's negative.
Whereas the guy's an ass kicker.
Right,
right.
You know,
do you remember who was the comic up in
Boston?
Who had that?
She was like,
every comic had one great joke and this
guy's choke was,
uh,
behind every successful man is a woman
and behind every successful woman or two
guys calling her a lesbian.
Fuck was that.
Remember that guy?
He was Kinda,
he had a wire rim glasses.
He was a little bit Chubby.
Goddamn you remember that joke though?
I do remember it now.
He just said it.
I'm just trying to remember who the fuck
are really.
God Damn.
Who was I to give him a shout out if
he's still doing it.
I always wonder about like if guys like
that are still doing it,
I wonder if they do do it.
Look,
they just do it every now and then they
have a job,
right?
I'll give you have a regular job and
you're like,
go out on the weekends.
Do addict already Gig here and there.
Pick up 300 bucks over the weekend,
shock it,
fuck it,
and get and have a good time.
Have a good time.
Get some free drinks.
Maybe a if you're single,
maybe meet a one.
What better way to meet women than
getting on stage for you know,
if these guys do in 20 minutes or half
hour and then get off stage and mangle
better than fucking what?
Going to a beef steak.
Charlie's standing at the bar looking at
a rusty trombone on the wall.
Ninety nine,
ordering some wings and a beer and
looking around,
creeping people out.
Hey,
where are you from?
What we got?
And for a man to try to stand out,
it's such a grind for a guy to stand
out.
That's why guys peacock,
right?
You wearing like big watches and rings
and driving a fancy car.
Just trying to peacock.
Yeah.
Let me get everybody looking at because
we're gross.
Gross women are beautiful.
You don't see statues of men,
statues,
statues.
Men that don't look like us will
different.
And maybe a little bit,
maybe a little of that.
Somebody had a great joke the other day.
He was like,
the Greeks invented the difference
between the Greeks and Italians.
The Greeks invented making love.
The Italians did it to women.
Well,
I was thinking when we were with a guy
of course told me that joke.
We were both in Italy last summer and
uh,
it's like looking at the statues of the
men and they're like,
they're fucking beautiful.
Like their abs are just perfect.
And then they have dicks and it's so
weird because if you were to statue
that's that realistic in like the Grove,
some Christian would cloak it and they'd
carted off because it was too graphic.
And you gotta think like when you,
when you're the sculptor and you're
putting that much effort where the Deq
has like a slightly bent shaft and you
can see the crown and there's almost
like a slit at the tip of the day.
It's like after a couple of days you got
to look at the fit.
They,
the sculpted like,
okay,
we think you got it.
Yeah.
There's a puddle of drool on carving out
this car.
He's got his hand on the balls fall
follies working on this shaft.
Well,
here's what was interesting.
There's two different things that are
interesting about dicks in those
ancient Roman times.
One thing is that the original,
the early days,
these two days to have just the cock
hanging out,
right?
Then there came a period of time where
they started because of some religious
influence.
He started covering them with leaves and
that was like after the fact and they,
they,
they actually added leaves,
says dig under there.
Yeah,
some of them.
And then they start.
They started doing some statues where
they put the leaf over the Dick,
like as they were constructing it,
but they did retrofit some some statutes
for Dick's,
but he'll go back to that again real
quick.
Is pictures of Dicks.
Hilarious.
Here's what's interesting about these
dicks.
You look at these guys and these like
big athletic looking like wrestle
characters.
They all have little decks and one of
the reasons why they had little dicks is
because in this time of.
I mean this is my interpretation of it,
right?
And this is what I.
I had a really good professor that took
us on a tour in Rome of the Vatican.
It was,
we got super lucky.
We hired a professor and he was
fantastic and he loved that.
I knew a lot about ancient history,
particularly their use of drugs.
So like we were talking about that giant
pine cone that's in the middle of the
Vatican.
They have this outdoor area with a big
pine cone and he goes and he goes,
do you know what that represents?
I go,
that's the pineal gland that he goes,
how do you know?
And then we started talking and we
started talking about like drugs and you
know,
endogenous production of
dimethyltryptamine and shit,
like no shit.
And he and I like fucking ignored my
family.
We were holding hands and wander through
the Vatican together.
But as this guy was explaining that I
go,
why are their dicks also a little?
And he goes,
that's a very good question.
And he said that a large dick was
thought to be like a gross primitive
thing like this,
like to have a large Dick.
You were like a non evolved thing and
that hit when you think about how close
these people were to cave people,
right?
Like you're thinking about a thousand,
2000 years ago,
right?
Go back 2000 years before that.
And what the fuck do you have?
You know,
I mean you have ancient Egypt and a few,
but you have essentially like small
villages 2000 years before that you
don't have the wheel.
Okay.
So you're,
you're talking about the wheel,
I believe,
goes back somewhere around 5,500
years ago.
It's the first evidence of the wheel
that is super recent.
So these people were essentially
realizing that there's a better way.
Like now we have Rome,
we have a sophistication,
we have art,
we have culture,
we have music and wine and we're not
going to go back to those big dick ways,
smashing heads and just fucking like
wild animals.
And I think when they thought of like
the barbarian hordes that would come and
and you know,
just fucking rape and pillage,
they probably those big
fat,
juicy dicks were one of the reasons why
there was so horrible and so,
so base and vile and primitive and has
been hogs and smash and skulls and
raping and killing.
They were trying to move past that.
And one way that they tried to express
that was in their art,
this sophisticated,
incredibly anatomically correct art.
And they all have these little tiny baby
and these baby dicks were supposed to
represent like culture and
sophistication.
Sort of like how a fat woman was
supposed to represent.
Like a woman who ate a lot,
right?
As a woman of culture.
So they were attractive.
Like look at that guy.
He's built like Brock Lesnar and he's
got a dick like peewee Herman,
like,
look at that.
I don't know if people are hurting us a
little bit.
I always thought it was because over
time the Deq must've just got knocked
off and that's why they were so small.
No,
no.
They purposely represented these
gigantic muscular men as having tiny
penises which showed sophistication.
So there were almost in this
transitionary period of like the muscles
were big.
The body was obviously like very primal.
You know,
they were there obviously very fit,
but they had these little tiny cox in.
Wow.
What they,
what they admired.
If that holds.
I wonder if that translates to the myth
that the African American man has a big
penis goes to that as well.
And a myth pal,
you got news for you.
We have movies lacked.com
is a website.
It's called blacked out.
Yeah.
There's a couple porn stars that have
followed on twitter and they'll just
like post,
like that's the weird thing about
twitter.
Sometimes I'll forget that I'll follow
porn stars.
I'm going through my twitter feed and
like,
oh,
there's a dick and an ass just out of
nowhere.
There's a girl like taking a hot with a
face like like twitter is one of the
things that I actually love about
twitter.
Twitter in a lot of ways is still wild.
You know?
I think they're trying to get ahold of
it.
I'm trying to get jack from twitter,
the head guy on the podcast.
We've been going back and forth and he's
expressed some interest about it,
but a little trepidation.
He's a little worried about how to
because they're trying to censor people,
but the people they're trying to censor
or the people that are actively
harassing people,
the people that are using unwanted
sexual advances and sending unwanted
naked photos and things on those lines
to people right up ending elections.
That's a little different.
Here's something I thought was
fantastic.
Fascinating.
I fucking.
I retweeted it and accidentally
unreached tweeted it and then I couldn't
find it.
She never do things on my computer when
it's late at night and I'm barely paying
attention,
but someone posted something that this
person that was claiming they were from
Rhode Island,
uh,
posted the tweeting about Hillary
Clinton.
It was like in response to something
that Donald Trump had done really
recently that was fucked up and about
hillary and are deleted emails and they
left their location on and it was
Russia.
Oh No,
there's tons of that.
There's tons of,
a lot of these unknown accounts.
It was like Kevin Underscore 2012 or
something like that,
but a lot of these accounts where these
people are attacking Hillary Clinton and
supporting trump and he's like,
right wing talking points.
We literally have to understand this
isn't just,
this isn't just a trope.
This isn't just like some weird talking
point the Democrats keep using.
There are thousands and thousands of
fake Internet accounts that are designed
to attack people that are supporting
someone who's in opposition of their
interests and to support someone who is
on their side.
And these are these people,
these online,
whether they're real people or whether
they're bought,
they're all pro trump,
all of them,
and they're all
pro trump and a lot of them are like,
I'm stoking the racial tension because
that helps.
That helped trump get elected.
Oh,
of course.
Of course.
And it's just,
it's fascinating that people are denying
this.
You know,
that a lot of people in the right or
denying this and saying,
oh,
the Democrats are just whining and you
lost.
Get over it.
I've seen a lot of that.
You lost get over it.
You got to understand what's happening
here.
You're not necessarily dealing with real
discourse.
It's not really the right.
And the left communicating stand each
other's points.
Debating,
no.
There's a bunch of people that don't
have a fuck.
They're not even here.
And they're pretending that they're here
and they're talking shit about the left
and they're talking shit about Anthony
Wiener or Hillary Clinton.
And they're not even necessarily real
people.
They might be,
but they might just be people that meant
it might just have scripts that they
send out from hundreds of different
accounts.
They might be looking for key words like
there's a weird information war going on
right now and an influence war going on
right now,
and there's a lot of people that don't
want to admit it's real.
It's fucking a hundred percent.
It's 100 percent real.
I mean,
facebook has already gotten rid of
thousands of accounts because they found
that they were Russian accounts and the
ads that were being taken out on
facebook where they track the money.
They were ads that were bought by
Russian.
I don't know if it was the government or
just the oligarchy,
but they were purchasing ads on
facebook.
What is this?
The best twitter tool and you can buy.
Just googled real quick,
tell me what this is.
All this stuff you can buy.
It's called tweet attacks.
Product
is designed to run thousands of twitter
accounts at the same time.
Twenty four slash seven to auto follow.
Unfollow,
follow back,
tweet,
retweet,
reply,
favorite,
delete,
tweet,
unreached tweet,
unfavorite.
So they just do everything.
Every account can have its own setting,
dust,
preventing twitter from becoming
suspicious about the account.
Plus the software can simulate human
operation perfectly,
exclamation point,
$7.
So you buy this for $7 and you just go
on a goddamn.
Greg fitzsimmons promoting rampage one
day.
We notice at the bottom the syntax
designed for everyone's need.
That's not an American writing that.
No,
not limited by the twitter API because
we don't use it.
Exclamation point.
Okay.
We should do an experiment.
We should buy that and see how much we
can jack up your twitter account.
I love it.
Like what's your twitter account at
right now?
I don't know what's great.
Greg Fitzsimmons fits dog radio on 20
something thousand dollars.
Not a lot.
Just under 85,000.
80 5,000
are wonder if we could get you up to
like a quarter million and like a couple
of months at about 7 million.
Probably by the end of the week.
A million by the end of the week might
get noticed because I think that's it.
As long as we're really open about what
we're doing,
I think that will be really a
fascinating experiment.
You know,
and you do it well.
We use these things and then we,
we buy you a bunch of fake accounts,
right?
I mean not fake accounts.
Fake followers.
We get,
we just use it.
You can get fake followers.
Right.
How does that work?
Like I checked the other day how many of
my followers are fake.
I swear to God it was the exact same
feeling I had when I took an HIV test
and 93.
I was like,
whoo,
here we go.
It's like Kinda.
I kinda enjoy looking at the number of
followers I have and they were all
Russian bots,
not mine.
It's almost all real,
but the number of that the president has
is like 50 percent,
like 50 percent fan accounts.
I wonder if he did that.
I wonder if he hired or if they just
follow him because he's the president
and it's a good thing to have like a
fake account falling the president,
especially these Russian troll accounts.
I think this came up.
I feel like the first time when John
Kerry was running against Obama and they
found out they did like a twitter auto
in his account and found out he had a
recent influx of like a million
followers on his account and it seemed
like,
what did he do it or did someone just do
it to him?
Well,
I think people,
if I was running a campaign and I was
already a sleazy piece of shit running a
presidential campaign or some sort of
political campaign,
you got to think they're going to use
every tool at their disposal.
For us,
that's what they do right?
When they,
they muck rake and they fucking go after
people and pull out some shift from
their past and make up some shit about
their past and use every influence they
have.
Like,
look,
I think it's a good thing that we found
out that donald trump's kind of god that
wants to talk about,
hey,
just grab them by the Pussy.
You know,
it's good that we know,
oh,
this is how he really talks and behaves,
but make no mistake about it.
That came about through dirty pool day.
Dave went and searched and did their
best in the.
I know people that work at access
Hollywood or wherever and they tried to
find out what do we got?
What do we got on and we got to get
something.
What can I give you?
Give me this list.
Going to record it and just talking
about grabbing posters.
Oh,
bobby,
if you can get me that I will get
something for you.
I mean this is all like how these people
do this.
If you don't think that they would get
fake accounts.
Yeah.
Now I know a lot of comedians that have
done that,
that have built up to because club
owners look at that shit.
Oh yeah.
For sure.
Where they book you and come up with how
much they're going to pay you.
They,
they quantify you.
Yeah.
Like what do you think?
Uh,
what do you think we'd have to do to get
greg up to a million?
What do,
what do you have to do?
You got to talk into the microphone.
I listened to the podcast recently and
sometimes you have it off you because I
have the mic off sometimes.
I don't know.
I understand.
Um,
let me see what this says.
But I was listening to it.
I couldn't understand a word.
You're son will get up on the mic.
They get up on that bitch.
I'll try to eat it.
He Siad eats that shit.
I don't know exactly on this particular
one.
This one wants you to pay a fee per
month.
There's other ones that you can pay like
a one time fee and whatever you're
asking to happen will just happen over
just happen days.
It doesn't happen instantly,
but I've seen a couple of youtube videos
doing what you're describing.
They did it to an employee of theirs
without telling them like,
watch your instagram account what
happened today?
And like,
he's like,
I got 2000 new likes today.
I usually get 20.
That's an started felt like popular or
whatever.
You know,
the screening.
Get excited.
Yeah.
When do we get you up to give me a
budget and I can figure it out.
Let me give you a budget.
Okay.
What do you think how much we need to
spend 100 bucks?
500 bucks.
Could do a lot.
There's A.
I know a girl who did that and she went
from like 30,000
followers to a million on it.
Do you want to also bump up your spotify
numbers or your youtube numbers or
anything like that because you can do
that as well.
Instagram,
the
girl did it on instagram.
The way they found out people is not in
our business and another business,
but the way they found out that she was
doing it was because the amount of likes
that she got was the same.
The amount of likes or images got and
the amount of comments.
They remained the same but it didn't go
on portional.
Right.
Like if you see a like a have you put
something up on like,
okay,
let's for instance that picture that we
put a you when we first started this
podcast.
All right,
we did that a couple of hours ago.
Right?
And we'll go to it right now and it has
17,913
likes and 257 comments.
That's,
that means that's normal,
if that makes sense.
So like a photo of a funny comedian.
First episode on New podcast is.
Here you go.
There it is right there.
I look at you.
You said Bitch,
I put
up yours.
The picture you doing the exact same
pose.
Two thousand 48.
But that all makes sense.
So now if you,
what's going on with you,
with the,
uh,
the other one with the EU and the um,
the dentist was that photo kind?
I just got my wisdom tooth pulled out
the other day.
Yeah.
Oh Jesus.
Oh God,
Dude.
What happened?
Was it getting impacted?
Um,
no.
I,
uh,
it had a filling in it and I guess I've
a cracked you will,
I,
you know,
I have adhd.
So the doctor gives the last seven or
eight years I've been on,
I'm like Ritalin and it makes me grind
my teeth and I,
I ground my,
a crack into my wisdom is Christ dude.
So he went in with some pliers and it
took like two seconds.
I thought it was going to be like,
you know,
like his foot on my forehead and
sweating and pulling it.
He just went and popped it out through
some gauze on it.
I did three shows that night.
No worries.
No problem.
Really.
Some people have like a week long bad
reacts to it.
I got lucky.
Nothing just pop right out now.
And so what do they do now?
They put a like a crown in there or
something or a wisdom tooth.
So they just leave it out.
Oh No.
Yeah.
So it's got like a.
But you have to keep rinsing with
saltwater.
Otherwise you get a infection,
dry hole or something they call it
because your bone underneath is exposed.
Oh,
you need a blood clot to get in there.
And if the blood clot doesn't form then
your bone is exposed and your breath
apparently becomes like a fucking
nightmare and you get an infection and
you'll get a pain all the way through
your ear.
And it happens to like five percent of
people that get their wisdom teeth taken
out.
Do you know the people that get mouth
infections oftentimes get heart attacks
because of him?
I've heard that.
Yeah.
What the fuck man?
You would think you just have bad
breath.
Yeah.
No,
he could die,
dude.
What do you do when somebody you know
well has bad brown.
Do you fucking done that?
Yes.
No.
Well me too.
Yeah.
Tell me,
tell you my breath stinks sometimes.
I trick a lot of coffee.
That's my downfall,
my mind as well.
You also have your brush your tongue,
man.
You got to brush your tongue goodbye and
account that had 240,000
plus followers.
That's over five years old for 150
bucks.
Oh,
but that's all a whole account taking
over the account.
But when you switch the name of your
followers wouldn't know the difference.
Why does to count?
I was following.
It must have been some meme account.
I just noticed that it switched to like
booty pics or some shit like that.
I was like,
when did I start following like that?
Right.
But that's not,
that's not good.
So it won't be the same thing.
We could,
instead of having $85,000
tomorrow,
he will have $250,000.
Yeah.
But they wouldn't be the same followers.
Right.
I think it makes it blends them
together.
Oh.
So he adds those followers.
Weird.
What happens when that goes down?
So you,
he would add an additional 250,000
followers or 240,000
followers.
I'm in,
I'm
into that.
I'm apparently when you eat a ketogenic
diet,
which I'm on,
it's like a low carb,
high fat diet.
It makes your breath smell like fuck it
shit.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So I'm pretty cognizant of that.
I'm pretty aware I was it a lot.
Yeah.
Because the meat doesn't digest just
fat.
It's just fat burning.
See I did your body burns fat as a fuel
instead of protein,
or excuse me,
instead of carbohydrates,
like the standard American diet,
we eat a lot of refined carbohydrates,
breads,
pastas,
things along those lines.
And what I try to do is lean to a much
more fat based Diet.
A lot of coconut,
a lot of avocado meet things along those
lines.
I don't have very much carbs.
My carbon takes pretty low except when I
go off the rails,
I go off the rails like maybe once a
week or so I'll have like pasta or
something like that,
you know,
not pizza.
I haven't had pizza in a while.
That's my super off the rails.
Food.
That's when you're in New York for a
couple of days.
You eat a full pizza and then just feel
like a fucking slob too.
So disco.
It's amazing what I'm willing to do for
mouth.
Pleasure.
Just for that second.
Yeah.
So Trish and then you just feel like
shit for hours.
Like the taste only lasts for like 20
minutes,
but.
So what?
I'm willing to sacrifice hours of
health.
But what do you sacrificed for an orgasm
when you're single?
The amount of booze that you'll buy a
girl and conversation you'll listen to
and yeah,
but that doesn't have their own size.
Second Orgasm.
The only downside is you fuck someone
you don't really like and then you have
to talk to them anymore.
It's like those brutal days,
right?
You know what the most brutal move was
ever when I was young and stupid.
You would go on a vacation with a girl
that you didn't really know that.
Oh,
or invite her to come out with you on
the road.
Like,
Hey,
I'm working in Philadelphia this weekend
and Uncle Chuck Rolles fucker fest.
Fucking.
And you would have them come with you
and you know,
an an hour after you came,
you couldn't deal with them.
You would just like,
I can't believe I did this.
Like you thought it was the perfect
idea.
We'll get together.
We'll have some fun.
I'll take her to dinner.
We'll have.
She can come see my shows and back then
man,
like people didn't have cell phones so
we were like on top of each other and
didn't have anything to do phone.
Yeah,
right.
He got to.
You Got Cable TV and you're gluing had
cable and if you're on the road you a
lot of times just staying back then
you're staying in these terrible hotels.
Right.
He didn't have any money,
so you stayed in some bullshit ass hotel
was like three channels that you could
watch.
It's like one restaurant,
some Shitty Deli and you're.
You have nothing in common with the
person.
You just had sex with zero.
That's when you just start drinking.
That leads to the fight.
There's a bus stop involved.
Is it fucking trailways station
involved?
It's crazy.
You know,
thinking about like finding someone that
you are compatible with that you also
want to fuck.
Yeah.
Because those are two totally different
things.
Like you could find someone that you
have amazing conversation with but you
have zero sexual attraction to them,
so you have to find a combo.
You have to find someone that you're
sexually attracted to but you really
enjoy them as a human being.
Talking to and sometimes those are just
not the same things.
Like especially for guys.
I guess it's must be that way for girls
obviously can't speak for them,
but when you're a guy and you meet a
girl like who's got a little ways and
big tits and a big ass willing to put up
with a lot of nonsense,
you don't even notice.
You're not even putting up with it.
You're so fascinated by the looks at the
whatever she's saying.
It's just kind of flowing through bar
together.
She's talking nonsense,
but then she puts her claws on your back
and just rake some down a little bit and
squeezes you a little later.
The promise of pleasure.
She put her claws on a brow.
She told me,
came to the back scratch like,
you know what's going to happen
eventually,
you know,
and she's like,
I need my drink.
You have to get me my
what?
Like what would the annoying chick
drink?
I can have sex on the beach.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
I have to have a long island iced tea.
I need my long island ice tea.
I need it
that she drinks half of it or a few sips
pounds it.
That's better.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
It shrinks.
A few sips and just leaves it there.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I have.
Every she ordered is a fucking lobster.
Eats one claw.
Well,
there's some girls that don't like to
eat in front of men.
They don't like.
Dude.
First of all,
they don't want to be judged by you
eating by them,
eating in front of you.
They don't want you judging how much
easy eating this disgusting.
She's going to be a big car.
When she gets older,
she's just fucking shoveling in a face.
I can't afford the upkeep or keeping up
with this fucking food dispenser.
She's going to take a giant shit in my
apartment.
Oh my God.
What if a girl has to shit but tries to
hold it in?
She doesn't want you to know.
Uh,
I had a buddy of mine and he had a,
uh,
like a one bedroom,
not even a one bedroom.
It's like a studio and the bathroom is
right beside the bed was just like right
over there.
And he was dating this girl and she's
just sweating there and just wrecked it.
Just wrecked his bathroom.
And she's,
she would do it like every time she came
over she would just go in there and
records bathroom,
always complained about it and know what
to do.
He's like,
dude,
this is such a killer.
I would show her right to the door.
The first time that happened as she came
out of the bathroom,
I'd take her arm gently and say,
it's time for you to go.
Okay.
But what do you do?
What do you do
if you have to?
Shit.
Like what is you go over a girl's house
and she lives in a studio apartment.
He could take a walk.
You go to a Mcdonald's or something?
Yeah,
I'll be right back.
I left something in my car and you go
shit in the bushes shit.
And the bushes.
San Francisco.
You go ride on the sidewalk and going to
shit.
I mean even with my wife like I,
I closed the door.
I hide the shit.
She doesn't care.
Door open sits with their legs crossed.
You hear him taking a dump and it's just
so discouraging.
That echo from the fart before the shit
comes up.
PLOP.
No,
I gotta go race a race.
Bad memory.
It's so weird.
We know everyone shits.
It's like why is it so disturbing to us?
Like we have this idealized image of
like some movie woman,
you know,
and when it doesn't turn out to be that
way turned out to be.
She's an actual human who shits like
regular people were so discouraged,
which so sad.
Show upset.
It is weird.
When I see certain beautiful women,
I remind myself that they shit and then
I can't.
I can't process it.
I go,
no she doesn't.
She can't.
Such as Kathleen Turner Shits.
Oh yeah.
Giant dumpster.
Just probably never really wipes good.
Probably was disaster.
She just gives up halfway and starts
drinking.
She does one light no matter what.
That's her file as they got a flask
right there sitting on the bowl.
So she just doesn't even look.
One wife doesn't inspect,
just drops it.
No.
We got here,
one of those Japanese toilets and has a
button.
You press a button and it shoots water
up your ass.
Yeah.
Cleans you up.
Is that the one that's gonna have the
flotation tank in it?
No.
The one over here.
Oh,
right.
They're good to have those two to have
those things here.
What temperature is the water though?
It's always warm.
Arms War.
It's nice.
I need to go there before I leave.
I don't even have to.
Shit.
Just force yourself.
Yeah.
Well that's the thing.
If you shoot that water up,
your asshole,
you will have to shit.
Oh,
you do it before?
No,
you can if you want to.
I mean if you just want to sit there and
press the button,
it doesn't know whether or not you.
Shit.
It's not like Greg,
why do you want me to shoot water on
your ass?
You haven't even taken a shit.
This is a logical he ever.
Have you ever been a day?
That's so fucking dull.
I had one yesterday where you get,
you feel a shift coming and you get
excited.
Something to do.
It's something to do and then you shit
and it feels good.
I'm not going to lie to you.
It's that might sound gay or whatever,
but a big hard shit come out of my ass.
It feels enjoyable,
like some good relief chemicals are
released in your body or anybody denies
that.
I don't want to talk to them.
Yeah.
I don't have time enough time to talk to
you about that,
but if a woman tells you that,
would you get upset if a woman's like,
oh,
I love taking a good fat
shit.
This is something about taking a shit
feels so good.
You bombed out.
Well,
it would mean that she's up for ass
play.
Would it be sensitive anus?
Are you.
Absolutely.
Are you ready to take one in the d?
The asshole.
Not a dick,
but like a pencil or something with a
coke day.
Dude,
I had a girl do that.
She was blowing me way,
way back when in Boston.
This chick,
she was a guido from revere and I think
I met her with you.
As a matter of fact,
we were doing like a Katie.
Remember this?
A cable access show and revere?
Yes,
and it was too hot.
Chicks there do that with us too.
I probably Gucci.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That sounds like the line.
But we met these two girls in the girl I
met.
She had on,
she just had on like a college
sweatshirt when I met her hair was up in
a potato chip clip and you know,
the leggings and the high top white
reeboks that look.
Oh yeah.
Little Velcro.
Reebok's fell apart.
Reeboks aerobics shoes number.
So I asked her out and then she goes,
um,
she goes,
okay.
And uh,
and we drive.
She picks me up,
my car was broken,
so I go,
will you pick me up and we're going to
go do a Gig in Rhode Island.
She's like,
all right.
So I go down to Kenmore Square,
she's going to pick me up a Kenmore
Square,
a fucking white corvette pulls up.
This is not what I expected.
Hair is now done.
It's fucking up.
It's touching.
The top of the car nails are done.
She got on a hot little dress and I'm
like,
sweetie,
we're going to a fucking roadhouse in
Narragansett,
Rhode Island.
And I get in her car and we drive down
and we get to the club early and we
start fooling around.
And uh,
she sucks my dick before the show.
This like we haven't even had dinner
yet.
Sucks my dick takes her finger,
sticks it up my ass during the blowjob.
But the fingernail is like a scrape the
inside of my ass and it up.
I had blood on the toilet paper when I
went to the bathroom later that night.
What were you thinking?
Animal.
She started putting it in.
I've,
I opened up.
I didn't,
I wasn't thinking about the nail.
Did she?
Liquor finger first so she could score.
Drive.
She did that porn drool thing on the
finger,
just come off a big wine cobweb light.
Uh,
and then,
uh,
uhm,
and then we went into the club and it
was like this,
it was like a roadhouse,
just like in the middle of nowhere.
There was this just boxy kind of a room.
Was that a Brian deery?
Oh yeah.
Yes.
And we go in and uh,
I was doing this joke,
you probably remembered as one of my
standard jokes back then have like a,
they actually now,
I don't remember,
but it was about the sign,
no radio in car and people used to have
those signs because they didn't want
someone breaking into the car and stay
on the radio.
So I had a joke about how I had that and
that somebody then broke into my car and
they took the sign or Sunday took the
radio and the sign wood or whatever it
was.
And somebody yelled at it was probably
a.
and he said n word and I went,
what?
And I said,
Like I may,
I've repeated it to make them say like
as if to shame them.
And then somebody else on the other side
of the crack goes.
He said his dad was like,
all right,
let's wrap this one up.
And uh,
and I,
and I see her laughing like word.
Yeah,
she thinks she thinks it's great.
She's sucking that finger that she had.
And she drove me back.
She drove back to Boston and I,
at that time I was still a,
I was a banquet waiter in the morning,
so I used to have to wake up at like
4:30
in the morning and go down to the
Marriott and copy place and set up
coffee stations for these fucking
conventions.
I remember this story and so I get in
the car to drive home.
I fucking fall asleep in the car,
Inner Corvette as she drives me home and
then I get out at my house and I go to
kiss her goodnight and she just looks at
me.
She goes,
don't ever fucking call me again.
Whoa.
And I just lives.
You fold it in the door?
Yeah.
Whoa,
that's it.
She's angry that she was angry,
that I fell asleep.
That was it.
She picked me up,
drove me,
blew me,
and then I just passed out.
I passed out because she blew me.
That's what I do.
But how funny is that?
Don't ever call me again.
You slept.
That's what did it.
She washed her corvette word.
Not the finger in the ass like that.
All those were acceptable.
Sucking your Dick like moments after
meeting you all those.
Oh,
that's normal.
You know the horrible food.
I'm sure they served that gigs.
She probably had some Mozzarella sticks.
They were hard as a rock.
Funny is that.
That was all fine.
Asleep.
Pissed her off.
Yeah,
but people don't like that when you're
driving and you don't talk to them.
Yeah.
You can just pass out.
Wow.
That's great story.
I remember that.
I remember that story because I remember
you being like stunned that someone
yelling out the n word.
How long is it going to be before you
not allowed to say the n word,
like just that phrase.
The phrase describing the word.
How long before people think that's just
as bad as saying the word itself as it's
coming.
Yeah.
Let's come and just like hoop earrings
and braids and dreadlocks or getting
people in trouble.
Yeah.
People run out of things to get mad at
and then we'll go after people for
saying the n word.
Right.
You shouldn't even acknowledge it.
We need to get it out of our front
killer.
Completely.
Yeah.
By acknowledging it,
you're not helping.
What a fucking weird time.
I only just started saying the n word.
I used to say the n word on my radio
show.
I would just say it.
And why did you stop saying that?
Don't you think that by not saying it,
it becomes like this ridiculously
charged magic word.
You're not a racist like wire words.
Magic.
Aren't words supposed to be sounds that
you make that convey intent,
intent or description?
Both.
Well,
that's the difference.
You can use the n word or you can say
the n word,
right?
Well,
you're.
You're conveying intent.
Your intent is to describe a scenario
where someone said something in a very
particular way that showed racism.
Yeah,
right.
That's your intent.
When you say the n word,
you're saying the kid cannot be.
It cannot be altered.
It is sacred word.
It is a magic word.
If you say it,
candy man will come.
Now it's like,
it's very weird.
It's very weird that we've ever allowed
that.
It's one thing like you could say spic.
No one's going to get mad,
you know,
like it's not as racially charged,
you know?
Yeah.
And then,
and then there's other ones,
so like you can just get away with all
day,
like Irish ones,
the Italian bank or Guido or they don't
give a fuck.
Yeah,
you can call me a guido all day.
I don't give a fuck.
No one cares.
They get very upset about.
Yeah.
How about Google?
That's a really rough one now.
But the n word,
you won't say it.
Look,
look at you
nigger.
It's a charged word.
See?
But if you say someone,
if you're saying that you're at the club
and someone yells out,
it was probably in that gap,
which is probably exactly.
They said that that's not,
you're not racist.
Not being racist,
but by saying he yells out,
it was probably an n word.
Like you're putting all this weight on
that word.
Right?
Right,
right.
And you're not using it in any way,
shape or form.
You personally are not using it to
promote racism.
You're doing the opposite.
You're talking about what apes you're
doing standup for a.
This girl was laughing at those apes.
And also the crazy thing is that some
people can get Latino.
They can say,
they can still say it even like a,
you see Middle Eastern kids that grow up
in the hood.
They say it.
Yeah.
As long as you seem to be in some sort
of a marginalized group.
Yeah.
I've seen a lot of Chinese people use
it.
Yeah.
Yes.
It's interesting.
And then like into.
Yep.
People are really into hip hop.
Yeah.
You know,
they'll use it and they use with the a
on the end of it,
but black people just throw it around
like a beach ball to concert.
Well,
my son likes rap and I go and he sings
it and I go,
what do you do when you hit the end
where he goes,
I just say player friends,
they say,
player,
what do you think Tom Hanks' son says?
He says it be losing power.
Oh,
it's getting dark and that's back.
That's so strange.
What a stupid thing to have said that
like four times yesterday.
Did they set that up on purpose?
Now we need to switch that out.
I get to say for the first show,
it's gone very smoothly.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
we have a few hiccups that we need to
deal with.
I thought that echo was going to be an
issue,
but it seems like it's just those
microphones.
That was the echo,
right?
It is right.
Because it doesn't sound any different
than me.
I like the purple behind you.
It's fetching.
It's really for your skin tone.
Let me say.
Put me up on like,
oh yeah.
I like,
it's a nice change,
you know,
and the real,
the only reason in all,
honestly,
we want the purples because the guy was
doing it,
said,
uh,
I couldn't find red the first time,
so I'm going to look at his new places.
Like,
well,
what do you got?
And he said,
well,
there's a lot of the girls.
I go,
you've got purple.
And he goes,
oh,
we can get purple.
I'm like,
let's go with purple.
Fuck it.
Purple is the ancient.
A color of royalty isn't he had Jesus.
There was a lot of.
It was always a symbol of Jesus purple
because it meant,
it meant,
uh,
you know,
the royals.
I didn't know that.
Yeah,
it's a beautiful color.
It is.
Flowers,
tulips and shit.
There we go.
Royalty in Europe.
Since the time that the Roman emperors
wore a tie.
Tyrian tyrian Purple Poopoo A.
hmm.
Toga pray.
Well,
P r a e t e x t a.
How do you say that?
Pray.
Texta protect stuff.
Purple has been the color most
associated with the British royal family
and other European royalty.
Still use it as a ceremonial color on
special occasions.
What does that plant said?
Some purple cabbage or some shit to
cauliflower.
Cauliflower.
Pretty.
Pretty color purple.
I was associated with prince.
That's her right?
There you go.
That was the one of the biggest bummers
for me of,
uh,
of like celebrity deaths.
Prince was one of the all time biggest.
That's amazing.
I was talking to because when Tom Petty
died,
that one really goes a hard one too.
That was a hard one because he was such
the fucking soundtrack of our teen years
and older years.
I mean free fallen when I was in my
thirties and like his songs continue.
But somehow prince who didn't have,
you could name more than three prince
songs and yet I could.
Most people can't.
Yeah.
I was a dude.
Prince played a big part in my late teen
life.
Wow.
Yeah.
I was always a huge purple rain,
tight controversy.
Even before that,
I was a fan of prince from his first
cassette when it was just him with no
shirt on,
a on the cover looking very androgynous
like there was no one like him before.
I remember seeing that,
that cover somewhere and going,
what the fuck is this?
Like what is this guy?
And then I heard some of the songs.
I don't even remember what the big hits
were off of the first one.
This is pre purple rain though,
but I remember controversy.
Dan,
no controversy.
You remember that song now do I believe
in God to believe in me.
Some people want so they can be free
controversy,
but I've done it.
That's it.
That's the cover.
Look at them.
Just a little tiny patch of hair in the
middle of his chest now,
but.
But my point being for not knowing a big
catalog of his music,
it did mean a lot to me.
He was.
What was that released in the seventies?
Really?
What does it say?
Seventy nine.
Wow.
Released in 1979.
October 19th.
Wow.
Real close to today.
Real close to today in 79.
Almost 40 years ago.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Bit more of an impact on you than Bowie.
Yeah,
for me.
Yeah.
I mean,
I was a big Bowie fan too,
but the thing about prince that was a
harder than Bowie for me was that Bowie
died of a disease,
right?
Yeah.
Disney.
He had a.
was a cancer.
I think you have some type of cancer.
Prince died from painkillers.
Yeah.
That's what drove me nuts.
It's like that goddamn fentanyl.
They found fentanyl in his body and I
remember thinking at the time like,
God damn it,
I can't believe these fucking pills.
Gun prince like potatoes.
That was the Michael Jackson drug to,
right?
No,
no,
no.
Michael Jackson died.
Yeah,
he died from anesthesia.
He was so fucked up.
That was before he died.
He couldn't sleep,
so he would get a nest of ties.
Just stop and think about how many
demons you have to have where Ambien
doesn't work anymore.
The amazing thing is he would get up out
of that and they said he was first guy
on the set,
choreograph in his own shit.
Rehearsing harder than anybody.
Well,
I wonder when he started doing that,
because you know his last tour,
he was like that.
He was preparing for his final tour and
he was working his fucking balls off.
Yeah,
you can do that very long apparently.
Apparently that's part
of the problem was that stuff.
It limits your rem sleep,
which is,
by the way,
one of the biggest things that's been
happening to me since I'm not smoking
pot for all these days,
all these many,
many moons,
16 days that we said 17 days.
The dreams are way different.
Way Different.
Like intense dreams.
Like I have weird dreams man.
Like they're very vivid and I never
thought about that before.
Are they the same?
Same dreams over and over again?
No,
not at all,
but they're very vivid,
like way more vivid than when I was
smoking pot or like way more.
Because you think you're in a deeper
rems cycle.
I've heard things,
but I don't know what it is.
Jamie.
Pull.
Pull up that.
See if you can find out what it is.
What's the cause for it?
I thought it had to do with the Alpha
waves.
State that marijuana.
Does that make sense?
Because you can't.
Your body is not at rest or your brain
isn't restful.
It's to an Alpha Beta waves.
I think for rest.
I don't know what what it is,
but whatever the fuck it is.
When you don't smoke pot,
when you smoke pot all the time for
years and then you don't smoke pot,
you have some fucking dreams baby.
Whoa.
Like they're intense.
Sometimes I wake up to pee and I go,
what the fuck is going on in my head?
Like weird,
crazy dreams.
Like being in a plane where it comes
really close to hitting a mountain and
the next thing you know you're hanging
on the ledge of a building and the next
thing you know you're running through
the woods and next thing you know you,
you know it's fucking freezing cold and
you're trying to stay warm and you got a
fire going.
Kind of fucking Wacky,
primal dreams.
My going through here.
That's awesome.
It's very weird because I'm waking up
and I'm just like,
it's not going to wake up and I'm
scared.
I wake up going,
what the fuck am I doing?
Studies on cannabis and sleep were
conducted in 19 seventies.
Some information about the possible
effects of cannabis and sleep.
Low dose of Thc,
four to 20 milligrams.
Mildly decreased rem sleep in both
regular users and non users.
Interestingly,
deep sleep was increased when cannabis
was initially used,
but this effect disappeared after
repeated use with high doses of thc.
Fifty to 210 milligrams.
Now stop.
And think about Lisa.
I'd eaten $500 and that's edible,
which is way different.
Rem Sleep was decreased in both regular
users and non users.
Total sleep time was not affected,
but deep sleep was decreased when thc
was stopped,
some rebound in rem sleep was found with
reduced sleep time and increased time to
fall asleep.
Now this is interesting because what I
want to know who that some people do
have withdrawal symptoms when stopping
prolonged and heavy use of cannabis and
this can adversely affects sleep.
I didn't have any withdrawal symptoms.
Zero.
None.
Not One.
But what's interesting to me is I wonder
if there's any benefit to not have to
having those dreams rather versus not
having those dreams.
Like I wonder if in some way I'm doing
myself a disservice by smoking pot all
the time.
I wonder if there's like a,
you know,
is there like a point of diminishing
returns about [inaudible]?
Like there's a lot of benefits for
cannabis,
right?
There's a lot of benefits in terms of
the antiinflammatory effects.
There is neuroprotective effects of
cannabis that they found that regular
users like they think it might actually
like hold off Alzheimer's and some
people.
But I wonder,
you know,
what's the,
what's the balance?
Because I'm really,
I've never really considered that it was
an issue at all.
I always felt like there was zero
health,
like negative health effects of using
it.
For me personally,
I'm like,
I get my blood work done regularly.
I'm healthy,
I eat really well.
I take a lot of vitamins,
I exercise regularly and I like pot so I
smoked pot and obviously it's not
hurting me.
It's not like people drink all the time
and fuck up their liver and their body
and.
But now I'm wondering,
does it affect your memory?
A great memory.
It's pretty good.
Maybe it'd be better.
Maybe you know,
essentially what do,
what do you have here at Jimmy?
The longer article about alcohol and
marijuana effects on sleep,
but this is the marijuana part.
Oh,
okay.
What does it say?
Furthermore?
Can increase slow wave nrem deep sleep,
which is good because that's where
experts believe most of your actual
recuperation takes place.
However,
as you continue to consume your slow
wave sleep will get severely reduced.
Reducing the restfulness of your sleep
is supposed to provide.
Reducing rather the restfulness you're
asleep is supposed to provide.
Hmm.
So,
but here's the thing,
like what if I get high during the day?
Like why is it affecting my sleep at
night?
That's what's confusing because it's not
like I get high a lot at night.
Sometimes me and the missus we'll smoke
a little before it gave her something
like that.
Nice.
Yeah,
sure.
Feels better.
That one punch her.
You smoked that stuff.
Fuck.
Ugh.
Wow.
That's a hard.
That's why I'm scared of Chris.
He thinks he's too old.
She can't take it anymore.
I told you to duck Christy and I want
him to bleed like your butthole did that
day.
A couple days.
You know you have sex with someone.
They start breaking.
That's not good.
But I'm wondering,
I'm wondering like I need to know.
I want to find out like what's the deal?
I'm going to start looking into this
now.
Now is that different than a.
That stuff that.
A CBDS?
Yeah.
Very different.
Psyche psychoactivity disagree.
No,
you're.
I know what you're talking about.
You're talking about that Charlotte's
web.
Yes.
See she gets me high.
Yeah.
See it doesn't get me high,
but
I'm not.
I'm not sure if we have the same.
Obviously we have the same.
Don't have the same body,
you know,
what affects you,
food wise and everybody's different when
it comes to that stuff.
But Charlotte's web has a bunch of other
cannabinoids.
It's not just cbd and that's one of the
more beneficial aspects of it is that
stuff.
It uses the full plant so maybe cbd
wouldn't get you high,
but maybe that kind of hemp oil or more
comprehensive cannabis oil would get you
high.
That's interesting.
They get you high.
Like how high?
Nice high.
Just like mellow more like takes the
anxiety out and makes me just really,
really nice.
At the end of the day,
around 5:00
when you're reentering the family,
maybe you have maybe some of that
anxiety is coming from inflammation and
maybe what it's doing is reducing
inflammation and relaxing.
Yeah,
that's what I would guess.
Yeah.
Because it doesn't make people test
positive for thc.
So like if you had a company and you're
working for them,
I don't want to get anybody fired,
but I'm pretty sure they've tested this
stuff and if you had a company and
you're working for them and you know,
they piss test you and if you're taking
like Charlotte's web oil,
I don't think it doesn't even do.
I don't think it shows up.
Right.
How fucked up is that man having a job
that tests your pis?
Hey Greg,
what are you having fun over the
weekend?
Yeah,
you fucking loser.
Yeah.
It does the same job to tell.
You can't date anybody from work.
It's like,
all right,
so you got me working 12 hours a day.
I don't see anybody else in my life and
I can't date the women that I'm,
you know.
Yeah.
But that's complications,
man.
I know that they should make it illegal.
Fake,
true.
They can suggest.
It felt weird to tell people what to do.
They do.
They fucking tell a manager he can't
sleep with an employee.
Well that's because they're worried
about some harvey wants to.
Oh yeah.
Right.
That makes sense.
Because that's always the thing,
the boss fucking the secretary.
Right.
You know,
I know a guy,
a real recently,
a guy that works for this big ass
corporation.
They got busted.
Yes.
And then at home to the secretary,
Baby.
Oh Shit.
That office day in,
day out,
looking at each other,
giving each other a nod.
He done and then one day in the
workplace.
So they went to a hotel.
I don't know.
I don't know the specifics,
but he's in trouble.
You know him personally.
I know I can't talk.
I'll tell you later when you tell me the
story about the guy who gave babies to
Michael J.
Oh,
I know you're talking about.
that's right.
Even worse,
your story involves kids dying.
That got sent to Michael Jackson isn't.
It?
Isn't not what it is.
It's entirely possible.
Yes.
Now I know what you're referring to.
Yeah.
Oh,
I got other things to tell you about
that guy.
That guy.
We can't tell you folks because.
Well,
you don't want to get sued.
Yeah.
You just can't talk about certain
things.
But who knows what was actually going
on.
You Know My,
I've always had the weirdest theory
about Michael Jackson,
that he was castrated.
He's a castrol.
I would buy that.
The voice,
the voice,
the body extremely thin.
It didn't look like any muscle at all,
which is like what someone has been
castrated would look like no
testosterone at all.
Couldn't sleep super high pitched voice,
kept down high,
pitched voice deep into his fifties.
Yeah,
I mean,
I don't think the sleep thing,
I think just riddled with anxiety and
craziness and all the fucking plastic
surgery.
I mean he was an literally an exercise
in madness.
That was a person who went mad from
people paying attention to them.
Yeah.
With unlimited resources.
That applicant jacked.
Mm.
That doesn't look as Jack does.
A girl goes across with,
you know what's amazing though about him
is for a scrawny,
a feminine guy.
He acted like a bad ass in his videos.
Do you know what I mean?
He actually played the part of a guy who
is like,
you know,
going to kick somebody's ass mood
criminal journey,
have a sports jacket on,
and uh,
the thriller video,
like a Letterman's jacket.
Right.
When that plays out.
Yeah.
I watched thrilled the other day.
My kids love it,
man.
They love the scene where he turns into
a werewolf.
My youngest daughter go,
he's like a little cat person.
It's not even a wall to making it a
cartoon or some shit.
I just thriller in some way or another.
The Werewolf was so corny.
Look,
and now it's like,
it was so weird.
Like it was not really a werewolf.
It was like a werewolf cat sort of
thing.
You remember?
Remember what it looked like?
Yeah,
like the,
the whiskers grew out of his face.
I remember being like super excited
about it because it was rick Baker that
did it.
He's the same guy who did the American
Werewolf in London who did a costume
guy.
He's a makeup special effects guy.
He created those masks and all the crazy
shit that you,
all special effects that you saw and
like a lot of the,
like the really bad ass horror movies
back then like there.
That's it.
Like what is that?
That's not a wolf.
What are those whiskers like?
That's some like a monkey mouth.
Yeah,
you're right.
It's like almost like a baboon mouth.
Right?
What is that?
He's like a baboon's man.
Snake eyes.
It's like a lot of thing.
Yeah.
But that one looks like a werewolf.
Go,
go full screen on that one you got.
Oh See.
Ooh,
that's bad ass.
It was pretty cool.
It was interesting.
Yeah.
But it was a not aware wolf like you
would think of a werewolf like an
American Werewolf in London.
Werewolf that also had on the,
uh,
high school jacket.
Right.
Did he pull up the American Werewolf in
London?
I don't remember that.
Oh,
maybe not an American Werewolf in
London.
Maybe he did when they were walking
through the bogs because he was supposed
to be a college guy.
So maybe you had a college jacket on.
Oh No,
it's just a.
yeah,
it was just.
Yeah,
it was just a down coat.
Fuck.
That's a good movie.
That was.
I got to show my kids that movie.
Don't show them.
Oh,
they're old enough.
It's an intense movie.
Oh,
look at that.
Jesus Christ.
Go full screen on that.
I don't remember that scene.
Oh.
Oh,
obviously.
Whoa.
How old should my daughter before she
watches Bruno?
Once Bruno.
Oh,
that's the gay now buckets.
Okay.
Right.
Yeah,
she likes the beach boys show some gay
shit.
She'll ask me if she can watch a movie
at dinner and he's like,
I don't know what's appropriate anymore
for anybody.
My wife got mad because I showed the
nine year old,
the original alien movie.
Oh,
did scare.
No,
she's a little bad ass.
She hung in there.
She loved it.
She's like,
kids like that.
There's intention span is too short for
slow movie like that.
You really think I'm moving slow.
Oh yeah,
I heard blade runner.
The new blade runner is very slow,
but now the old one was very awesome.
Really?
Yeah,
I heard it's like super underrated.
People are like,
it's not doing well.
Yeah,
I haven't seen it,
but I need to see it,
but a lot of people are saying that it's
like really slow.
Yeah,
no movies are doing well this year.
What do you think that is?
Maybe people were watching Netflix more.
I think that's exactly what it is
because the movie experience is an hour
and a half,
two hours.
Right?
Plus get their parking a lot of money.
Yeah.
Netflix is like,
what?
Nine bucks a month and you can just
binge watch house of cards.
Your fucking head falls off.
Yeah.
I'm watching the OAA right now.
Do you know what that is?
So weird.
Supernatural thriller on Netflix.
It's really great.
It's great.
Although some assholes on twitter
thought it was a good idea to give me
some spoiler.
That's fucked up.
I shouldn't have said.
I was just trying to tell people that I
found a good show and then I fucked up
because again,
late at night I barely paid attention.
Read some of the comments.
I'm like,
God to go to wolf shirt on.
What does it say?
We don't need a season two of the.
Oh,
a Oh fuck off.
People just think it's such a great idea
to be negative and he's so much fun to
be negative.
Although I,
bad mouth aerosmith on this episode did
a little bit.
I'm a hypocrite.
I don't feel good about that.
Wow.
You did what you gotta do.
Oh my,
um,
you know what the best show I've seen in
a long time as the Americans.
It's on.
Um,
it's on Amazon prime.
It's about this couple that comes from
Russia and they've been,
they've been taught to be Americans from
the time they were like,
you know,
12 years old,
that's based on a true story.
Yeah.
Montclair New Jersey.
Dude.
Fucking the acting is Keri Russell.
I forget the guy's name,
but they're just so fucking good.
She's a bad ass.
Keri Russell will.
What else has she been in?
She was in that,
uh,
felicity,
which was huge 15 years ago on Fox.
Yeah.
But it's like,
oop,
I watched,
I watched six seasons of it in,
in six months and they fucked a bunch of
other people.
Right.
Like that was part of that is part of
their job is they both go off to fuck
other people and one of the people that
you ask the fuck.
Well I don't want to.
Spoiler alert,
settle it down.
You'll see.
Don't say nothing.
All right,
let's wrap this up and we're going to
talk about all the things we couldn't
talk about on the air.
Yeah.
Hey,
thank you so much for being on it.
On my.
My pleasure.
Can I give you some dates?
Fuck yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's do music.
Let everybody know where the fuck break.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Great Dog Dot Com.
[inaudible]
dot com this weekend in grand rapids,
Michigan.
The 19th through 21st spokane comedy
club,
November second through the fourth,
Atlanta punchline,
November 17 through 19 and Zany is a
Nashville December eighth and ninth.
Boom.
Management,
one of the great clubs,
the country.
It's a fun club.
I was one of the best.
Well wait a minute now.
I've never worked there.
Oh good.
Oh No.
That was one of the ones I remember.
I was telling you what Gersh kept clubs
from me.
Yeah.
When I was with them.
It was one of the ones.
It's a great spot.
Yeah.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that is it for episode one from the new
studio.
Thank you so much.
We'll be back soon.
Bye.