Here we go.
Three,
two,
one fucking year.
Philippe.
How are you sir?
Was so full.
Good man.
You have to have him have to say that.
I don't know.
It seems like it has.
Like you said,
what's up dude?
And then you said what's up fool?
You corrected yourself.
I'm slipping.
Was that like when you have such a cool
saying like you do,
you almost feel compelled to use it?
Yeah,
it all started like people in my
neighborhood would answer the phone like
that.
I was dating this girl and I called her
up and her brother.
I sort of porn with self pool.
That's normal,
right?
Yeah.
That is a,
a,
a cool Mexican thing to set.
No,
probably more like the hood.
More like the west coast Hoodie,
west coast hood.
That's not necessarily central Mexicans
and blacks.
Like we took it from the blacks.
Oh,
okay.
But it mostly like a west coast,
south central east La Boyle Heights.
Boyle Heights in the house.
Yeah.
What?
That's,
you know,
this is a contentious time for fucking
people when it comes to like,
um,
Mexicans and Americans with this whole
wall thing.
Yeah.
And I,
I went to,
I went to go,
um,
to look at the walls because they went
to Mexico and I was like right at the
border of the gate,
like the gate,
it's not a wall to the gate.
And across the gate they have like eight
wall prototypes,
like the ones,
like eight wall prototype.
Like there's one wall that's like a,
it's a wall was the man and it has um,
concrete.
Then there's another wall that's
different.
And then another one,
it's like they have,
you know,
when you,
when you go buy title for her house.
Yeah.
And they show you all the tiles.
Oh Wow.
The Hook.
What the wall is like little home depot.
Yes.
But like a sign,
like a placard with different.
Wow.
Look at that.
That's it.
I was reading,
I was there.
I was right in front of that.
Each one of those,
I think it costs $25.
Million each wall each.
Yeah.
What?
Someone's getting robbed.
This subcontractors right now in New
Jersey going,
wait,
wait.
Hey.
Hey,
what the fuck?
I could do that for 30 grand.
Anytime you have a wall.
Historically.
Shit goes down,
right?
People want to get over that wall.
It's natural.
People want to get out,
people want to get out,
but you want to get in going to be tall.
And here's what the craziest shit about
the wall.
I'm sure you've seen where it goes into
the ocean.
Yeah,
I was there.
Like how are you going to stop people
from going around that?
That is the silliest thing ever that is
like having this gigantic wall that is
like having like a gigantic,
huge impenetrable boundary.
But on one side there's just like a
door.
Yeah.
That's a door.
You go right around.
That may be hard to bring all your shit.
So what happens?
These guys right there on the Mexico
side and those guys over there on the
California side like that is the
weirdest shit ever.
Play volleyball with each other.
Do they really?
Wow.
The added another piece to that wall
right there.
So that was an old wall.
See that?
The construction of the wall that I saw
now.
Yeah.
Wow Man.
He can still swim.
But uh,
as soon as you swim,
you know the part of the postcards and
come get you.
That is so crazy.
Just what,
what a strange.
And people go,
you don't want a wall.
Relax.
I hadn't said any of that.
Not saying that.
I'm saying just look at this just as a,
use your brain.
Just look at this objectively and see
how bizarre it is that there's a
gigantic physical boundary to keep
certain people from going into a certain
area.
I mean,
I,
I think that that one day that has to
not be a thing anymore.
Right?
Wouldn't you say
that is a crazy thing to justify?
Like you can't come to the good spots.
Like the good spots are limited.
Well,
if they,
we let people in and there'll be no
more,
no more good spot.
It'll be just like the bad spots.
That's the,
that's the fear.
And here's the thing,
man,
that ain't not uncommon.
That's not a,
it's not an imperfect.
It's not a fear that's not totally
illogical either.
Right?
Like you would be worried if you lived
in a sweet place,
like a name of a city.
Not Too many people perfect size
boulder,
Colorado.
We have orders.
Cool.
Yeah.
Nice.
What if a million more people moved into
boulder?
Now all of a sudden it's a million
100,000.
You're like,
what the fuck?
What the fuck is this?
He can't go anywhere now.
Everybody's rude.
People start getting antsy.
That the way they drive that drive
faster.
That's what happens.
Be More more gangs.
Why do you fix that?
That's how.
That's what we need to fix.
Not like whether or not there's a wall
he fixed.
How do you fix people from getting
crazy?
I know man.
They shoot on later boulder,
Colorado Party.
We'll have a subway system to get other
people off the streets.
Yeah.
If they did,
if they did have a couple million people
moved,
they're like,
Bam,
start moving shit and sentence.
She would change radically.
That's what happens to places.
You get too many people.
They just fucking change.
It's a.
it's still strange.
Fuck.
See a wall.
It is to house.
I'm not saying that I can,
but it gets so big.
It's so right when he left with a bad.
What'd you just take two comedy?
Yeah.
All I'm saying is it's weird.
It's fucking weird.
It seems
to be something that should be perhaps
reexamined this idea of like,
it's almost like we have weird parents
that we have to listen to for our whole
life and that,
those parents with the government.
I know,
like when I was a little boy I would
live in Mexico and um,
my mother,
she to tie me up to a stump so,
so we'll run away.
Holy Shit.
That glaze to follow my dad to work
every day.
My Dad was like a,
I think he was like a steel worker or
something.
He worked on a lathe.
So he worked with metal at the time.
Yeah.
And I will follow him to,
to work everyday because I was a little
kid I guess,
and they couldn't.
I will run away every day and my mom
would tie me up to a little street store
with a rope.
I was her pet,
basically.
Jesus Christ.
Holy Shit.
That's a weird memory.
I know,
right?
That I lived in.
Um,
I remember I lived in Mexico for a
little while until I was three or four.
Then my dad took off.
Do you remember Mexico at all?
I remember a bathroom was outside
like an outhouse and we have to use a
flashlight to go outside and wow.
I remember mosquitoes everywhere and my
mom's family are living in like in one
big ranch with different houses and it
was fucking dusty.
I mean it was dusty.
I was living in Mexico and they used to
be a truck that will water the ground
everyday because it was too dusty and
there was no cement.
But then my dad took off to the United
States and we followed him.
We came here.
We were living in Tijuana,
Mexico for about two years.
Do you remember how you get through?
Yeah,
we met with my dad,
made it through first,
started another family then came and got
us now.
But that's what I thought.
He was gone for a long time man.
And then we,
we went,
we were living with my aunt,
her name was Julia and she lived in
Tijuana,
Mexico,
right next to that.
Where that,
where that gate is Polonia Tsa was up
and um,
we,
we went across with a,
you know,
a smuggler.
My mom pay them money and we got in his
car.
Wow.
We crossed and we made it through.
I remember we made it through,
but there was like a checkpoint back in
the day in San Clemente,
California.
The California Sheriff Department will
just,
the county sheriffs,
they will randomly stopped cars,
you know,
like too many people in one car and his
car too heavy.
So they got us and they put us in there
like in a holding cell.
My mind went one way.
We went the other way.
Oh.
And how old were you?
I was probably four maybe or five.
I remember there are three,
three little brothers.
I have my little brother was like three
in the other one was one or two.
Why would they separate you from your
mom?
Um,
I don't know.
That's,
I guess that's how they process web
backs are illegal people.
That seems kind of crazy.
She went to one when,
I dunno what I'm,
I don't remember crying or being scared.
I just know that we're watching
cartoons,
you know,
American cartoons,
that's all you remember.
And then they caught us.
We,
we,
we went back again and they cut it again
in another car and we got separated
again.
But this time we were held for a longer
time and I remember my aunt,
when she saw us in Mexico,
she said,
hi,
they catch you guys again.
Just jokingly.
Wow.
But the third time was like my,
my aunt and my mom came up with this
crazy idea because we have brothers.
We had cousins in Sunny California and
my mom said,
you know,
why don't we just borrow their
passports,
you know,
to cross.
And I don't remember this.
I just found out recently that what
happened,
my brother told me,
my little young brother,
um,
we just almost like a little girl,
like a full on little girl.
Um,
because at the we had like three
passports and two were boys.
One was girl and we took straws to
guests and my mom and my aunt,
they forced my little brother to be a
little girl.
How they make him look like a girl,
they just,
my little girl for two weeks just to
play around,
you know,
they give them a fake name and so and
so.
And he was playing dancing no more
dancing,
getting ready,
playing with Barbie dolls.
And so he was preparing,
preparing broke deniro,
bro.
Wow.
Getting ready for that row of his life.
How old was he?
He was two at least,
or three man.
He was young.
Wow.
We crossed and we made it all the way.
And um,
I remember that um,
some other car picked us up.
We jumped into another car right away
and then we jumped in another car and
then that car drove us to,
to southern California.
We were lacking content somewhere.
And Carson,
we're in a house that had the.
It was,
it was funny,
it was like a,
it was like a hub for illegal
immigrants.
Like everybody there was going different
places.
Okay.
Who are you going to go to?
St Louis.
This guy,
you're going to go to San Diego.
That lady,
her three kids,
they're going to go to boyle heights
because that's where the father is.
So that were granted boyle heights,
um,
didn't speak no English at all.
But um,
I picked up English right away,
you know,
because your little like watching bionic
woman and Shit.
$6,000,000
man,
incredible hulk dukes of hazard.
So you basically picked it up from TV.
We'll be like,
what kind of,
what kind of lessons did you take?
Lessons were in English or none.
Zero.
When I was,
when I was in elementary school,
it was different from now.
There was no,
like separating these kids who don't
speak Spanish have put them in an
English as a second language class.
I started,
I started kindergarten,
so.
So you just picked it up?
I picked it up.
The teacher,
the teacher never spoke Spanish to us.
She never said I'm okay Hawaiian,
you know what apple is?
That it wasn't nothing like that.
It was time.
It was like,
I don't got time for you.
You're going to pick it up or not.
Do you think it was because you were.
You were so young.
Your brain could pick up another
language really quickly.
Isn't that what they say?
Like young people,
their brains pick up languages quicker.
I think I picked it up really fast,
but to my pronunciation we're not there.
Right?
Like I didn't know how to stay bionic.
I will say in that kind of makes sense,
right?
That a part of your brain would really
develop and make it real easy to learn a
language when it's real young,
you know,
like,
okay,
how do I say this?
What do I give more of?
A desperation for figuring it out,
but I bet you a little kid that comes
from another country like you did.
Well,
you're a perfect example.
You learned from TV.
That's crazy.
So you learned from just talking to
people that are around you and
television,
television.
Nobody's saying this is how you say this
is a pronoun,
this is a Noun,
a verb.
Not telling you any of that.
Nobody told me that,
but later I had a cousin who lived in
Santa Paula and she taught me that stuff
like,
this is how you say this word because
her and I were playing.
We'll play like school together.
Yeah,
or she'll give me assignments that were
just should pretend to be a teacher.
Then a read.
You know what man?
For little kids,
that should be fascinating.
Learning how to speak like,
but for whatever reason we decide that
it's boring.
Like learning a language.
It's like,
ah,
it's so much work.
I've got to read another book.
Fuck that.
Fuck,
fuck up another book report.
Give you now to come on man.
Just get Rosetta stone.
I'm like,
imagine trying to learn Chinese.
Like what are you saying?
I'm going to learn how to read it too.
I could read that stuff and and say,
oh,
how much time would that take?
That would be crazy.
I took German in high school at for like
a whole year and I did an eight class
but I didn't learn anything.
See,
for me,
I think everything gets super squirrely
with,
with unusual,
like languages.
They use things other than our letters.
As soon as you use things other than our
letters,
like you see Russia and you're like,
ah,
what?
What the fuck is that?
Shit?
They have totally different.
Like ways of using our letters pull up
some like Russian pull up like Russian
translation,
like Russian tab.
There's they got wise in there and
yeah,
it's a champ.
It's such a powerful language.
It looks like almost like Viking runes
or something like that.
Sometimes like Braille.
That's a crazy,
crazy looking language like um,
another one is Arabic,
Arabic crazy.
Look in language when they go to that.
What the hell is that man?
That's the way it is.
You'll see in the movie Indiana Jones.
What is that thing that looks like a,
like a spade with a knife through a tart
take right there.
Stay at the hotel,
right.
That like what does that call Krillick
they call it Krillick.
Okay.
Look at the language.
Like look at it.
When you see it written down,
we'll get that weird double k thing.
K Left K,
e Dot k cave.
Look at that one.
They'll be folks here at crown to watch
a Russia willow fortunate give you the
six.
But they have our letters too,
but they're backwards.
Like look at it,
look at that.
Again,
this almost like look how they have
ours.
But they have a backwards capital are
what never backwards,
lowercase,
and then it looks like that's insane.
Like look at that,
you that you were the big Dick.
What does that does?
You have the big Dick and these ecu with
two dicks.
The Chair?
Yeah.
This is a fascinating language.
RSP.
SSC.
I think if we lived on another planet
and we were looking,
we were observing a giant culture that
had nuclear power,
but they all hadn't even agreed on the
same language yet.
We'd be like,
what are these crazy assholes do?
What are they doing?
They're all speaking different.
They can understand each other.
They all have nuclear power and they can
understand each other.
So you're relying on translators and
people to speak for you and
representatives.
And I know men.
Oh,
I watched that movie.
Clothing.
Cultural for the first time on
mushrooms.
Whoa man,
man.
Dude.
And you read about communication with
the community,
with the UFOS and hook thing.
Dude,
dude,
dude do.
Didn't they have like a hand thing?
Yes,
we would do with it.
That was amazing.
I was wondering like what if like humans
always think that they know what the
other person might be saying,
right,
but what are the whole time you're like
detonating a bomb with each other.
They add,
but the problem is like what they're
saying means different things in
different cultures too.
It's just hit on earth.
People just have different styles of
living.
You can't tell them they're wrong in
Africa or the right Norwegia Norwegia
region.
What does.
Nor we'd.
Norway,
Norway.
How funny is that in Norwegia I'm coming
up trying to come up with a cold
weather.
I was in the middle of Iceland.
I should've went with Iceland,
Iceland,
but any place like that,
these
freezing climates.
Who's right,
who's,
I don't know who's right,
like teenager,
we had a guest on our podcast.
He said that he said that will never
performing.
He said that they were spitting at them
and he will.
Why the experience you because of how
they say we love you in Argentina when
you're performing like they spit at you,
that people do weird shirt used to it.
Right?
How about,
uh,
in Iceland they eat this crazy shark,
it's like a,
a fermented shark and it's supposed to
be disgusting for everybody else,
but them,
like they love it.
It's like a delicacy.
It's this for an in Bordain,
aiden,
and he said it was discussed at the
bunch of people have eaten it on TV
shows and shit and been like,
what the fuck can assure you that for
some kind of fermented shark,
Iceland people are some strong fucking
people.
Man.
Those people live in Iceland.
Just think about how hard you have to be
for the huge man I seen.
I seen a video then working out.
Yeah,
there's like a disproportionate number
of the world's strongest men have come
from Iceland.
Big Ass pot,
bunch of giant motherfuckers,
a lot of fucking beer to drink.
Whatever the fuck they want.
Those are vikings,
man.
That's what's leftover.
The Vikings back before guns,
it's like that just ran through
villages,
man Motherfucka and those are the last
remnants.
Once people started developing guns,
then it became a fair fight and then
it's like,
oh,
okay.
Before that,
man,
the Viking showed up.
You were Foxville.
That was no Bueno.
So heavier to giant swords if they were
all,
if like the whole,
there was an actual country filled with
people as big as those strongest men
guys and they decided to just take over.
There was no guns.
They just take over.
That's how it works.
Arrows aren't not good enough.
Catapults not good enough.
So that was him in the legs.
That's good.
It's always good to have a little hyenas
brody's away for them motherfuckers.
What do you think it would be like if
everybody spoke the same language?
Do you think if the world spoke one
language,
things would be better or would find
other shit to hate each other for sooner
or later somebody will make a little
language.
Yeah,
you're right.
Like we're not going to call him Mike.
We're going to call him shit head.
Okay.
For Fun.
Right?
Like especially if people get to
Controli with the language soon as
people do.
Don't say that word.
Don't say this word.
As soon as people get controlling with
the language,
like let's make our own shit.
Like I was called problematic one time
for what would you do?
I was just a did a show and um,
the lady went on and he goes,
oh,
he's problematic.
He's um,
what did he say?
He messed
my shoulder with the word male
chauvinist.
Yes.
Yeah,
because I just did,
was a joke,
but she heard like the trigger word
against seven,
set her off.
So I guess she didn't hear that.
She didn't wait for the punchline.
I found that happened,
but it's weird like the lady you should
understand,
you know,
you went,
you walked into my show,
you know,
with your friends.
They should have warned you that I say
words,
but you gotta wait for the fucking
punchline,
bitch.
Yeah,
there's a turn coming up here hanging
there.
Like I remember doing this show and I
was just talking about my brother coming
in and out of prison a lot and they
booked me for the show.
It wasn't that much $200.
And I told my friend,
this comedian that I had worked with
named Steve Flies fucking dirty.
I sort please just be clean for 10
minutes please.
No surprise is brought up.
Pull your pants down,
just a quick eight if you have it.
So he did a quick eight,
50 solid.
Killed it.
I went up there.
It was doing okay.
I started talking about um,
whatever stretch marks.
This is that.
Then I said my brother had been in
prison a lot.
Every time he comes out worse,
the first time he came out,
a better thief.
The second time he came out racist,
like total racist.
I'm Mexican guy.
And then the third time he came out even
worse,
man,
he came out of a born again Christian.
The tumor away from me.
She didn't wait for the punchline.
He don't steal no more.
He blesses himself so you know,
and then she just took the microphone
away and the Fat Lady and she said,
that's enough for Mr.
Parsa
so crazy.
They don't let you say that.
She says thinking how foolish that is to
stop you from saying that like,
this is a problem.
There's a problem that people have.
They feel righteous.
When you're talking about standup comedy
in particular,
when you're setting up a joke like that,
you're gonna you're,
you're taking him for a ride.
They don't know what you're gonna say
next.
You know,
and it's funny and to pretend that it's
not funny because it's talking about a
certain subject,
it's just crazy because it's not about
not being able to talk about subjects.
It should be like if someone has a
heinous perspective,
like,
hey,
I don't have a problem with kids,
get raped and killed,
and they start trying to make a joke
about that.
Park a fuck man,
good luck.
You're on your own.
You know you have a obviously heinous
perspective,
but that's not a heinous perspective.
What you're doing,
talking about a guy going to jail and
getting worse every time it comes out
that that's also a reality.
It is.
It is a reality.
And to pay for people to deny that
people become hardened criminals because
they'd been in the joint three,
four times that joint.
What am I living in the fifties?
I'm going,
come on,
man.
That's crazy.
To deny that you're in there with
fucking criminals and you know you're
stuck in a cage,
of course you're gonna come out worse.
That's where it's fucked up,
right?
It's like nobody's getting any better at
doing that.
No.
No one ever re-engineered the whole
prison system.
No one ever re engineered the whole
people system and looks.
He goes,
why?
Why don't we just continue to have crime
emanate out of these unfortunate areas.
If you just fix those areas,
fix it.
You.
Is it possible that you could have no
like extreme poverty on earth?
Is it possible?
Do we have enough resources?
Do.
Does anybody know?
Like do people think that in order to
live the way we live now that somebody
somewhere has to live in extreme
poverty?
Is that like what they think or is it
just a,
a spot where stuck at?
Well,
I'm,
I think I'm the only one that will
happen if nobody really.
It would just be middle class and poor
than everybody will have something.
Yeah,
because cause I know it's just rich and
middle class and poor.
The rich would have to give half to the
middle class in the middle cloud to give
to the poor Jesus.
Not enough money to go around.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Is that.
Is that real?
Like if you had all the resources on new
resources,
people to volunteer,
man,
volunteer for what?
To help people like you.
Okay.
You care about dogs so much?
I don't see your work doing.
Putting it in eight hours and no
shelter.
Walking these dogs for free.
What does it say?
Billionaires make so much money.
Last year they could end extreme poverty
seven times.
She says,
where's the profit in that?
Oh my God,
that is crazy.
Roughly six out of the seven,
the top 500 richest people.
Southern network.
The net wealth created this year is a
staggering 259 point 4 billion here.
The top five richest people who saw
massive gains is here.
Oh boy.
Jeff Bezos in the house,
CEO of Amazon $35 billion to his net
worth this year.
Holy Shit.
I don't know how to say this gentleman a
ever grants chairman.
Background grew $25 million.
Yeah.
These guys are fucking making Bernard
Baby.
What's his name?
Barnard what?
Barnard?
Looking at cash baby.
Twenty 4 million Zuckerberg Zuckerberg
in the house.
$4,000,000,000
money.
Woo.
Yeah,
there's some.
But here's the thing,
man,
if you're going to have a game,
and I'm not,
I'm not advocating for capitalism or
communism or socialism.
Not Advocating for anything.
What I'm going to say,
if you.
If you're going to have a game and
you're trying to figure out what,
how much of a certain thing.
And if you own that thing,
you could do way more stuff,
right?
You could buy a private jet to get a big
house.
So what is it?
What are the,
what are the steps you have to take in
order to get that thing?
And is there a too much?
Could someone have all of it and
everybody else has zero.
Is that possible?
What if there's like there's no rule
that says you have to do something with
it either.
Like you could just
collect it all,
burn it,
but that'd be an asshole move.
But in every game there's rules.
Technically.
There's no rule here that says Bayzos
couldn't just when it.
For sure for sure.
No,
I'm not.
I'm not saying.
What I'm saying is,
is it possible that someone could get to
a point where they have all the money?
I mean,
if this has happened before what jp
Morgan had other money,
it was really.
Yes,
I saw that,
that Dr Ritu the men who built America
at one time he held,
he held a monopoly and all the steel in
the world.
Well,
one thing that people really resist is
if you try to make new money,
you know,
that's why people are like really edgy
about bitcoin.
You know,
what the fuck's going on?
This is their own real money.
They're buying houses with bitcoin.
People are selling houses with bitcoin.
Oh,
to a bitcoin.
Listen man,
in this day and age with the kind of
trust that people have in government and
government decisions when it comes to
economics,
that bit point stuff,
any crypto currency stuff becomes more
and more interesting to people because
they go,
these crazy fuckers aren't fixing
nothing,
man.
Well now when I was living in a while,
I grew up in a Pico Aliso people
gardens,
at least we'll build housing projects.
We had a,
we have,
we let our,
my mom didn't have money in a bank for
at first our neighborhood and have money
in the bank.
So they started their own little bank.
Like we had this thing called a,
I don't know how to say it in English
called Dina.
We get like I guess 10 families that we
know and every week somebody puts $100
in the pot.
So there's 10 of us and everybody puts a
$100 and we all take turns every week
collecting the pot.
So you and I in him and seven other
people were putting in $100.
That's a thousand dollars.
So that way this week Joe Rogan gets it
and next week everybody puts it $100
again.
And this time he takes it,
he gets 100,000
dollars and then the next week I get a
thousand dollars to everybody makes a
thousand dollars.
So that would be like the way we used to
learn each other out,
money in the hood.
It works hard on the,
on the honor system,
but it works out.
It never works out.
It always failed because usually like if
one guy really what do they want to pay?
Something will happen,
know it'll look bad on his family in
Mexico or we'll go hunt that food down.
But I used to do that with what I used
to be the guy that used to collect all
the money from these people when I was a
little boy.
I was like 12,
13 years old.
Walking in the neighborhood was a
thousand dollars in cash and passing it
to this house.
But no one knew that.
But there's this whole,
this is how money marketing worked in
the neighborhood while everybody was
borrowing for somebody could no weapon
alone,
a thousand dollars.
Right to.
That's interesting man.
That's a.
that's a really cool way to handle it.
That's a cool game.
Like our social game that everybody's
playing with each other.
That's a cool way to do it.
I'm not,
I'm,
I'm in commerce.
Could do it if they got together.
Oh fuck you.
You can't pay a rate.
Okay.
If 10 people put $100 each,
that's a great idea,
man.
That's a great idea.
And just pass it around.
That's a fucking great idea,
man.
That's something that's a social
security that you'd be happy to
contribute to get a group of your
friends and do that.
That's super smart because then you get
these little bursts of a big chunk of
money.
Yes.
Yeah,
man,
I like it.
That's a social thing too,
right?
Yeah.
I don't know who came up with it,
but we have a social thing.
Do you know,
it's something that keeps people
communicating with each other and
talking about shit and getting excited
about it.
That's bad ass man.
He was a hustler man.
My mom sewed.
We used to go to um,
because I live in boyle heights and
we're next to Delta Lane.
There's so many,
so,
so many fucking factories.
And my mom knew she was just,
you know,
like where everything was.
We used to go to this one factory and
this trash can,
we'll throw in a trash can.
I in the band it was nothing but I'm
synthetic cotton,
so it was like this fake carton made of
plastic.
We have to take it out of the trash and
put in hefty bags.
They were my would will go home and my
mom was sold me pillowcases and we'll
sell pillows.
Wow,
that's hilarious.
Dude.
You had a crazy life.
You know,
I couldn't imagine.
How did the the little boy do pretending
to be the little girl.
How did he do when he went to jail,
Bro?
He was sucked into it.
Who Do you think that he would have been
gay either way.
You never know.
Is it possible that wow,
maybe it was just gay.
Maybe that's why they chose him.
My brother fought like I had this joke.
I heard this story for many,
many years but didn't know how to.
How to put it out there.
Then my brother,
he told me,
hey,
you should do that.
Joke about how he crossed the border and
my mom made me dress up as a little
girl.
I saw you.
Sure Matt,
because people are going to call you
that.
They're going to call you and ask Julia.
That really happened.
So what?
So yeah.
So yeah,
he's,
I did it and he didn't care.
And um,
his,
his husband was a prize.
My brother married to this city planner.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
But it's crazy.
You know,
Joe,
like gum,
how naive,
you know parents can be because my
brother came out being a homosexual and
my mouth goes why?
And my father to why?
Why?
That's right.
You can't figure it out motherfucker.
You just have like a little girl.
There was two asshole.
Do you think that's possible?
Maybe.
Do you think it's the,
here's the thing,
he was destined maybe.
I don't know.
It might,
it might be,
but there is a possibility that uh,
you know,
people are malleable.
You can kind of steer them in different
ways.
The question is,
are those ways good or bad?
You know,
it's,
if he's happy and he's gay and they
became gay because he dressed him up as
a little girl.
If you really truly care about gay
people,
does that bother you?
It's a weird question,
right?
It's like,
wow,
man,
I don't know.
I could you firmly believe in equality
of,
of sexual orientation if you firmly
believe in total equality,
he should have no issue with someone
turning a little boy gay mean really?
You should,
but then there's the thing like,
no,
no.
I want people to decide their own
destiny,
but no one decides their own destiny
religiously.
Right?
Little kids get introduced into
religion,
but sexually it's work at super
important for us.
Yes.
We don't let the boy be a ball boy.
I don't know.
Fuck boy,
son.
Hey.
Give me some boxing gloves.
Get out of there.
Put the helmet on stops.
Third,
that Bo Jackson poster and a motorcycle
and fucking ride around with shirts off.
Yeah man.
Right.
It's like A.
People get super scared if someone
turned the kid gay.
Like what?
What happened?
Some people put up barriers though.
They allow their kids would just be what
they want to be,
but here's the thing.
I don't know if that's possible,
but I definitely think with no
intervention,
there's a lot of people that are just
gay.
They're just gay,
was crazy in that.
Isn't there like A.
There's like a spectrum of gay though,
right?
Oh,
those levels,
bro.
There's levels like there's the.
Well I know because of my brother a
negative.
He never.
My brother,
like there's my brother's friends are
really,
really cool and they're really funny.
But they're were flamboyant and my
brother not,
at least not around us.
You know?
Who cares if he is though,
right?
Yeah.
Who Cares?
Yeah,
they not.
That's a funny thing man.
Like flamboyant gay,
that the,
that,
the,
that the,
the gay.
I knew growing up the flamboyant one,
but we uh,
we celebrate that.
Right?
Like look at him.
Woo.
You see a dude with like a halter top
on.
You know what I mean?
Like days in cut off shorts,
like a rainbow striped socks on your
like kick damn go.
You go boy.
Flamboyant Gay.
Like we'd love flamboyant gay.
But like a,
a girl dressed like that.
It's like,
Oh,
you unfortunate you unfortunate child.
Like look at you with your 17 inch pumps
on with your shorts up to crack your ass
with your tiny top on.
That is so sad that you need that much
attention.
Isn't that weird?
Weird man.
It's weird,
man.
When it's a boy and he's gay,
we fucking celebrate the shit out of it.
Looking at me.
He's got all these crazy multicolored
beads on and he's just fucking blaring
gay.
That data.
Hell yeah.
We think that the rave,
but a girl that's just screaming out for
Dick.
Oh,
you poor child.
You stop that.
Stop it.
You stop it.
What do you.
What do you want sex.
She's like her mom.
You're not going to get love that way.
You're not going to get love.
You just going to get a bunch of guys
want to fuck you.
There's a lot of pressure on loose women
are the girls because a member like
growing up.
Oh,
she's a good girl,
bad girl,
bad girl.
And we're the good girls.
If you were a good girl,
I wouldn't be mad at you all the time.
Melissa.
Melissa,
can you be a cousin?
Jennifer?
She's a good girl.
I can't believe you did coke.
I can't believe my daughter.
Do people love coke?
They do.
You know Dundas Stove,
right?
No,
never just pot.
Right?
I drink,
I don't drink a lot,
but I drank.
I see him drink bud light once.
What?
Or the fuck?
Oh,
will last.
My biggest,
the one of my best memories,
man.
Comedian that you're drinking a bud
light.
It was like,
it was like,
it was like 1999 thanksgiving.
It was like the,
you know,
like things given already passed in
Friday.
It was like a,
you know,
the,
the Friday after Thanksgiving,
the Wednesday before thanksgiving.
It's totally like the best days for me
or anybody.
And for comedy too,
especially with the comedy show on
Wednesday.
And then the next day,
the stories,
the chicks everywhere.
Music,
the good times man drugs.
But this one particular time,
my brother Fernando or whatever,
um,
I call them up,
hey,
I'm going to,
we're going to go watch.
I have a show at the or,
and me and other comedians showed up and
then we're going to go see you.
That's when you had your,
your,
your fucking hot ass webpage to
oregon.net.
And you said you were going to perform.
So we went to go see you at the main
room right after our sets.
You fucking crushed it.
He's a fucking beard bit.
It was hilarious.
Crushed it.
But then after what you saying,
I heard you tell somebody that we're
going to go to the house of blues
because it was his birthday.
Yeah.
So I said,
fuck it.
Let's go to.
So we are winning and we were across the
street man.
It was like so many comedians have that
time at the House of Blues and Rick
James showed up.
Started playing the piano.
That was the shit man.
Yeah man.
That was a chewy.
Did quite a few shows over there.
How many shows did he do over there?
He did one every once a month on a
Tuesday too.
He was good and it was like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
This is chewy.
The dude who's the door guy at the
comedy store is a bad ass musician.
That song hate chewy.
What's going on?
That's actually,
that's a great fucking song.
That's a great song.
And I was sitting there going,
how crazy is this?
So we didn't know.
Our friend Chewy has this special gift.
He was good.
I would put big overalls.
It was cool to watch too.
Like it was a cool show.
Like we had a good fucking time.
He was a good musician,
Huh?
Dude.
He's a real good musician and he's our
friend.
It was so.
It was crazy.
It was both.
It was like you're seeing your friend on
stage and then you seen your friend
kill.
You're like,
damn,
he's good.
This is good.
It was awesome.
I remember one time mom dumped me.
He was doing his,
his jokes that the orn he said holly was
fucked up.
Like that guy right there,
chewy.
He.
He's a rock star.
Rock star once a month.
Kills it.
Right now.
He's telling me where the fucking park.
I think you'd like working there to be
honest with mailed the letter for me one
night when we're putting the letters up.
I always enjoy that guy.
He was always very cool to me to,
you know,
said people are scared of chewing.
Juliana.
I always got along great.
You know,
he just looked like the wrong dude to
fuck with him,
like hillbilly but Mexican,
but he's a gentleman,
always a gentlemen,
if you're a good guy to chew it,
he's a great guy to you.
But he's a talented musician.
Man.
It was crazy to watch.
It's crazy to watch your friend just
killing it at the house of Blues after
just say what's up,
what's up chewy?
You know that song.
But that song,
Hey Joe,
what's going on?
That's like,
he made a really good song.
Shoulders.
Right?
Did he kind of.
I'm trying to remember.
I'm definitely lifted it up.
It was fucking great man.
He was great.
Like he was like,
he's a,
he was a guy that I would actually go
see.
I was like,
this is amazing.
That's one thing I liked about being a
comedian that when I was younger was
hoping to do after where the was crazy.
You know,
like,
even when like for sometimes you know,
you go to like dark areas,
you know,
if you want to party hard.
Like I had a kid one time,
I was doing a short Montebello.
Remember Willie Barcelona?
Yeah,
really works,
said it,
had that crazy ass fucking wildly for 11
years and somebody came in and said,
I'm thinking this comedian yours.
He said,
hey man,
there's this guy,
they're looking for Comedians to perform
at three in the morning,
got a harder bucks.
And I said,
fuck it,
I ain't doing shit.
I ain't got alive.
So he gave him the address and we get
there.
It's like an undercover police officer,
security guard as his house in Burbank
and um,
we perform at three in the morning for
them,
but all the shit in their house.
Yeah man.
And what Joe,
the house was built for like partying,
like 80 style were like,
we don't,
you don't even know what time it is.
Like the coaches were there,
courteous all over the house.
You couldn't see the sun come in.
No more so lit perfectly like the house
look like at 5:00
PM all day.
Wow.
And all over the house there was drugs
but there were not openly out there for
everybody to take only like four people
who knew what was going on.
He had liquid coke.
They're like the,
you know the nasal sprays?
Yeah,
he had like those filled with water and
coke because they can do,
when you do coke sometimes the coke is
stuck in your knees and your nose so
you're going to pour a little water to
help it go down.
Jesus.
But this guy had little squeeze Varvatos
all over the house,
like nasal sprays,
Haley's.
So I will see people lean over in the
back of the house and then grab
something.
And so then I found out where it was and
I just,
instead of just putting it back,
I just walked it with.
I kept it God damn.
Because I stood at that House to 1130 in
the morning and I got there at two in
the morning.
But this is funny.
The Guy who owned the house,
he had nobody cleaning the house.
So everybody like it.
Like if you grab a little bit from his
house,
like,
like if Joe Rogan picked up those beer
through return trashcan,
he'll give you points.
Like,
like Doug,
he points his name was doug.
Joe Rogan got three points.
So if you get like,
so this house you got invited to his
house,
bike by text because Doug knows you,
but he knows you,
someone else invite to you,
but now that you got points,
you know enough points,
you get a personal call.
That's crazy.
It was crazy.
There was a guy walking around.
Hello Lynn,
Marilyn Manson.
But it wasn't Marilyn Manson just looked
like he was just hired for the show.
I guess for the Party to.
I hate to bring up this thing with your
brother again though.
I'm bringing it up.
But this is.
Do you think it is possible really that
if someone dresses their kid up,
all jokes aside,
is that possible that if you dress your
kid up as a girl for like a little bit
and coach them into acting like a girl,
that it turns them gay?
I don't honestly.
All jokes aside,
I don't really think it works like this
stop right when they got here.
Or did he keep playing that way?
No,
I don't think he,
he,
uh,
he stopped.
He was like a male afterwards.
But it could have been a total
coincidence.
I think was probably coincidence.
It just happened.
Yeah,
but no,
nobody wants to think that people that
susceptible,
but they definitely are in some ways,
right.
Maybe not sexually because that seems to
be like a biological thing,
but in terms of like behavior,
like racism for sure.
Right.
Racism carries from,
from parent to child pretty pretty well,
you know,
if they have a good relationship with
their parents and their parents are
racist,
that shit will carry in because a lot of
people who are racist,
they still love their kids so they're
really good at their kids,
but they're racist.
So the kids associate really good,
like love with family also with like
distrust of certain certain groups and
colors and that's a almost a thing that
they're taught by the people that care
about them,
like wild animals.
Man.
They're taught well,
wild animal behavior by their parents
and that's the same shit with people.
It's a weird thing,
man.
It's weird.
It's a weird thing that human beings are
malleable.
You know,
that the,
you can get them to behave a certain way
in Iceland,
but then a different way in Brazil or a
certain way in Japan and a different way
in China.
Like I was,
uh,
I was in China recently.
One of the things that's crazy is when
you're around large groups of people,
they just walk in front of you,
man.
They just walked through you.
They walked through little kids,
they walked through everybody.
And it's not rude,
it's just they have a different way of
moving around because there's so many
people and so many spots in China,
they're not being rude.
They don't consider it rude.
It's just different.
They're just trying to get there and
they don't mind everybody bumps into
each other a little bit.
We're like,
Oh,
you touched me.
I can't believe this.
That guy touched me with his hand
doesn't buy into their fucking head
butting each other,
but they're not doing it mean they just
kind of going through each other.
They don't mind touching each other.
So they're just,
you know,
you see an opening,
they're going in that opening.
Oh,
you don't look it,
you don't own the space in front of you,
bitch.
There's a little spot.
I'm going to go in there.
Boom.
And they don't think it's bad thing.
They do it here to Chinese people do.
Oh yeah.
Asian people know Armenian people.
Older people were trying to catch the
bus.
We were all trying to cut in a bus and
they run.
They rush in front of me.
They don't say,
excuse me.
That's why I know how to say,
excuse me,
and Armenian mixing.
You know when people don't mind being
jammed up like that in the winter in
Boston when they get on the team,
you know those trains,
like if you leave in fenway park and
it's like fucking zero degrees outside
in the winter and you get on the tea
together and especially if it's sunny
out so nobody feels creepy about it and
they shut those doors and everybody is
just jammed in there huddled together.
Who?
Penguins.
Yeah,
you don't mind.
You don't mind your fucking freezing.
So everybody has more of a sense of.
That's like a big problem with La.
It's too easy to just live here.
It's too easy to like physically
survive.
It's too hot.
The hot,
the heat's one thing,
but you could get by.
You get used to that.
You can't get used to the cold,
but you can't do it.
You can't stay out there.
You could stay.
It's the heat's way easier.
You could stay out there if you have a
shade and you have some water and live.
You literally can't live in Boston
outside.
No,
you can't.
You can't go to sleep there.
If you go to sleep there,
you'll die.
You won't make it.
It's zero degrees out.
You're not going to make it.
Oh,
it's.
You can't just sleep on the ground when
it's 30 below zero,
like in Alaska or some shit here in
panhandle and that code.
No,
and so you're going to be a hardy
motherfucker to survive those places.
It's too easy to survive la.
We don't have enough interaction with
nature.
We've got a distorted sense of where
we're sitting in this whole thing in
nature.
Go to Griffith Park.
Yeah.
We don't even have bugs,
man.
When I was in Thailand,
they got crazy bugs.
Do bugs.
Bite the fuck out of here.
We got this little weird bites all over.
You and mosquitoes are ferocious.
Those are real bugs,
man.
We got here.
Roaches.
We got nothing.
We got a few roaches.
We barely have any flies.
We ain't got shit.
No bugs want a part of this crazy dry
air.
That's the.
We're super lucky,
man.
Bugs don't like dry air bugs like the
crawley ones don't seem to mind,
but the fly,
once they fucking hate dryer,
lots of hummingbirds eaten them up to
do.
We do.
There's not lots of hummingbirds
anywhere else I've lived like there is
here.
We rehabbed a honeybee,
a hummingbird in my house and released
it.
We found a girls found a hummingbird
that was wounded and the,
uh,
nursed it back to health and then
rereleased it in the wild.
We have a little hummingbird feeders in
the backyard.
Dude.
Hummingbirds,
the coolest little animals ever.
They're so weird.
I'll put up a video of,
of this hummingbird.
It's so cute.
Like they fed it sugar water life super
fast,
right?
Dude,
do they fly so fast that you can't,
like if you see it with a stop motion or
slow motion photography,
slow motion videos,
you can't believe how fast it is.
Like you're,
you're,
you're watching.
You're like,
Whoa,
look at.
That's insane.
Like what kind of animal evolved like
that little tiny wings and they're going
like a fucking billion miles an hour.
Like look at,
look at that thing in slow Mo.
See if he could find one.
Like there'S no animal like that.
But imagine if an eagle did that.
I'm asking you how fucked everything
would be if an eagle could move like a
hummingbird or just a giant fucking
giant flying thing with knives for
fingers and it's just snatch and fish
out of water and it's as big as a Turkey
and it moves like a hummingbird.
What the fuck?
Like if you think about that's what a
tiger is,
right?
A tiger is a big thing that moves sanely
fast.
Look,
a little of those wings are too narrow
and never within their wings to it.
Now,
do those wines are so small that if they
were in a superhero,
if I saw a superhero and the body was
that big,
the wings without small
tap pitch couldn't fly.
Kid outta here.
That wouldn't even work,
bro.
Dynamically glucose,
small.
The wings are.
Look how big the body is.
It's fucking stupid.
I click on a little.
Those wings are men.
if you went to like one of those hot
wings places and they gave you a wing
like that,
you'd be so angry.
Oh hell no.
Release for this is the tiniest little
wings.
Such a small little animal.
But they're so adorable.
They have no legs are uh,
they have likes.
Yeah.
It was just tucked in there.
Tucked into the backseat.
Tiny.
Yeah.
They're so Beautiful.
Such an unusual little bird to who eats
them.
Oh,
I'm sure everything that can snack
dishes,
but I think good luck catching them.
Good luck catching that little fucker.
I told you I was listening at leonardo
book the other day and uh,
one of the weird things in the beginning
it mentions is that he had a very weird
fascination or it was written in one of
his notebooks that he wanted to,
I think it was he wanted to describe the
tongue of a woodpecker would.
This is like an obviously the 14
hundreds where you'd have to catch the
woodpecker,
kill it,
dissect it,
and then did the description of yourself
and I guess he does have descriptions of
it,
which at that time are so descriptive.
You would have to be a scIentist.
Like he was.
I wonder,
really crazy.
Wow.
You would catch a woodpecker.
How do you catch one of those fuckers?
Know why you would,
how you thought of that was making them.
Do you think he just shot it out of the
sky?
Came up with the trapper of some kind.
I bet,
I guess.
Right?
Yeah.
Imagine those dudes that were just like
initially studying species's,
like imagine just like writing down
drawing pictures of a cat that you just
found in the fucking jungle.
Like being one of those guys that
started the first people to document
what animals exist out there because
like how long have we known?
How long have you had a good sense of
what animals exist out there?
How many years has it been?
You think that people.
A good sense of all the animals in the
world.
Like right now we know about giant bears
that live in Russia,
right?
We know about komodo dragons,
we know about nile crocodiles.
We know about science,
we know about.
We know about all these animals that
exist because we've got all the videos
and the information,
but how long has that been a thing?
How long have people known what was in
all these different spots?
Has it been 2000 years?
Has it been three?
How many?
How many thousand years has it been like
reliable information?
No crackings,
no fucking sea dragons,
you know,
stop you making shit up.
like what did you really sick?
Like how long has it been where they
have a detailed account of what animals
exist.
I was one of the things he used.
I don't know the as they've been
apparent or the hollow,
there've been a pen or something to ride
on hold the first and they have a road.
Wasn't writing I think was like the
middle east.
I think it was all like sumir and those
places think that's where they think
it came from.
Do you ever see that writing man,
dude,
it's crazy.
look,
and it's called cuneiform.
It's like it looks like nails.
It looks like they're like old school
lead carpenter nails and they're going
left and right and up and down the
alphabet to.
Yeah,
look at it.
Oh wow.
That's,
I think I'm,
you know,
obviously I'm not an expert,
but I think they believed this is the
oldest written language.
See if that's true.
Is cuneiform the oldest written
language?
They think that was where it started.
That it started with these little,
uh,
like they look like nails.
Look at that shit dude.
It's such a fantastic looking language
because it almost looks like some crazy
computer coders.
it's funny how all this kind of
language,
someone in who's board in prison will
pick it up and learn how to write.
Let this with another inmate and give
each other messages for the guards.
Wouldn't know.
Look what it says this.
This is,
this is the one,
it's called a mil to mil.
I'm the oldest language comes from Sri
Lanka,
Singapore and to indian states to mill
is still spoken by approximately 70
million people across the world to is
one of the oldest literary canons of any
knowledge and the world with the
earliest piece of tamil writing sand
graham literature dating to
approximately 300 bce.
So that's 300 years before current era.
That's not,
that's not super old.
Uh,
see the thing language,
I think sumerian is susie.
It says sumerian first developed 3,200
bc.
Okay.
So I think they're saying what's the
oldest language and is active in the
world and that's two mill and that comes
from 300 bc.
But the sumerian language,
yeah.
Is the oldest shit ever.
So that's what we saw.
That's cuneiform.
So it was created using a read stylist
to make wedge shaped indentations and
clay tablets.
So they think as far as they know,
that's the oldest shit.
So that,
that's,
that's only 5,000,
300 something years to develop the,
to record transactions,
to keep track of money or to talk,
you think.
Which was more important to them at the
time transaction would be the two
probably everything.
Writing things down.
Try to figure out what,
what animal did not eat,
you know,
try to figure out what makes people
sick.
Keep track of who paid taxes.
We did it.
So 3,200
bc,
what is that?
That's 5,218
years ago.
Wow.
That seems so recent that I love that
man.
Five thousand years ago they figured out
how to write shit down.
Like what are you saying?
What did they do before then?
Wow,
fuck.
And we're in.
Nobody had raised the more I barely
hand,
right.
I suck at teaching them what I think
when I write,
I write.
My handwriting deteriorates rapidly with
every
stroke.
I barely do it anymore.
You still do this?
No,
I don't.
Logos.
What does that logo as you do that you
should do that as in high school when I
was bored at the superman logo.
Yeah.
I used to do all the band names,
like band logos.
I used to do the v and the,
you know,
the,
what did a day when we're talking about
George Washington.
I saw a fact and I was trying to bring
it up in time,
but I had to go back and find it and I
just remembered it because.
Well,
what you're talking about,
do you know when the first dinosaur
bones were discovered?
Dude,
we talked about this once a.
I don't remember what it was more recent
than something like that.
I don't know if he was already
president,
done with all of that.
All.
Everything that they had written and
talked about.
Everything we'd go back and discuss was
all before they even knew like dinosaurs
even existed almost.
Yeah.
Clearly crazy.
It is really crazy.
It's hard to believe that.
We mean imagine you have like,
okay,
we think we got an understanding of what
is here and what's been here.
It's probably been similar to what he,
what the fuck is this?
And they find a bone that's as big as a
bus.
It was like,
wait a minute,
what the fuck is this?
That's what it would have freaked me
out,
dude.
you imagined you find a bone as big as a
bus and you're like,
holy shit,
this is one animal.
What is this?
This is a leg.
what?
He keeps getting bigger and bigger
pieces and then you realize you have a
brontosaurus.
Just imagine finding all that shit,
not knowing it exists and going,
what the fuck is this thing that looks
like a rib and what is this thing and
that noise,
how big the world is.
So you'd think of.
There's another one around the world
that they live.
Yeah.
Oh yeah man,
for a lot.
You know,
they sent david spade or david spade
christ.
They spent david choe.
They sent david cho to the Congo and
advice.
This is how I found out about dave.
They they sent it and then I found out
about him again from bordain was telling
me how amazing is they?
They sent david's show.
David cho was already rich at the time.
This whole crazy david cho is.
He was wealthy as fuck.
Like he didn't have to do anything,
he'd already made a gang of money,
like gambling and shit,
and he decides to go down to the Congo
to go looking for a fucking dinosaur
man.
It's the craziest episode of vice
because these people,
some people that lived there,
or at least they're saying they're
convinced that there's.
I mean,
they could be just fucking with white
people.
That could be a thing too,
right?
Which could,
could be fucking with westerners.
Some korean kid comes by and they're
like,
yeah,
yeah.
I'll show her the fucking thing.
I was going to add about the davinci
thing.
He used to fuck with his friends with
the lizard dressed up like a little baby
dragon.
And he'd freak them out and like,
look what I look what I found.
Look what I got.
Davinci did that.
You'd have to believe him because he's
fucking davinci,
right?
That's hilarious.
Add things to creatures.
Pretend he's made a new space,
a new,
found a new species.
Look at dave.
He was young as fuck to men is a long
ass time ago.
And uh,
he went to the jungle wet looking for
these supposedly bronto sources that
people see in the jungle.
Can you imagine?
They found one.
I mean,
there's not enough jungle to hide like
someone else credible.
Someone will get a picture.
Everyone has a phone now.
Even people that live in the jungle.
Right.
What would it hide?
It would hide in the jungle.
He would have a dam or a cave in the
water.
You would have to be an enormous area
where people never go for a big thing to
be alive today that people don't know
about.
Like,
they'll find like a new dear,
you know,
they'll find a new dear sometimes like,
oh,
look aT this.
We've got a new frog.
Yeah,
we found a new dear.
This is incredible.
It's in the jungles of Cambodia.
It's a new.
It's a subspecies of this deer.
Rare footage shows the last surviving
member of an uncontacted uncontacted
amazon tribe.
Yeah.
I saw this support,
dude.
He's the last of the mohicans.
That's meanwhile.
That's a camera man.
They fucking gave him 50 bucks.
Just go out there and beats of trees.
I'm going to get some footage.
It looks like blair witch project and
have you just whack it against a tree.
I'm going to say you the last surviving.
We're bro.
We're going to get paid for this.
Come on bro.
You look like an old fucking guy that
lives in the jungle.
Just do it.
50 bucks.
Do.
I'll give you 50 bucks.
What else are you going to do today?
Since they've been tracking them since
the nineties.
That's crazy.
We live in by himself since the
nineties.
We got a weird problem with that,
right?
Like wow,
poor guy.
What if he dies out there like that when
he's going to die here in a different
way?
What are you talking about?
Whom he status living alone.
If he's sad,
he's sad.
If he,
you knoW,
he saw those people with cameras.
He probably chase out and with a blow
dart,
you know,
if he embraced it,
just thought what a way to go.
Got himself a nice pair of nike's,
you know,
gucci fanny pack or what?
I come out of the woods,
bro.
He shot at someone at 2005 or you're
wounded someone into with it.
Oh fuck.
Yeah.
You don't want that,
man.
That guy is going to shoot arrows at
you.
Imagine that he's a criminaL.
They haven't even gone and gotten them
shooting arrows at people.
You son of a bitch.
Let's do.
They didn't want.
He didn't want them to get saved,
but it's funny,
man.
We look at people that live in a way
that's different than the way we live.
Like,
oh,
we got to save them.
We got to save him.
We got to bring them over to the good
side.
I know we got to save him,
but someone living in their car,
he's paya.
Yeah,
yeah,
man.
Someone living in their car,
fine.
Until the guy.
That guy that's camping under the
freeway.
Normal,
normal,
super normal.
There was a guy living across the street
from my house.
I live in echo park.
He will live in instead of a bogle.
Whoa.
Here's the thing,
right?
They don't.
They let american tribes controlled
giant chunks of land.
they give them reservations in the 18,
whatever it was was like 18,
65 or some shit where they did all this.
The wars land never took,
nothing grows and they didn't want.
They didn't get many of the good spots,
so they give.
They give them all like think.
when did that happen?
Let's find out first.
That was my question was would you ever
allow them to live the much of tears,
right?
What is it?
18,
87,
87.
Wow,
that's crazy.
But would they allow them to live like
they lived before?
The europeans intervened,
like if you really just left them alone
and they live like fucking horseback
trading,
you know,
animals for bullets is really low like
they lived back then.
Indian land for sale find lands in the
west.
This is a crazy.
Add grazing.
Have your own easy payments.
Perfect.
Title,
possession within 30 days.
Indian land for sale.
Is this real?
Yes.
This is A real ad that they had back
then.
Brassica studies from Nebraska as
website,
okay,
this is,
this is the next art for the studio.
We need that.
That needs to.
That enforced.
They'll make a reservation.
Yeah.
We need that framed on the wall.
How much there is a bigger the land.
That's what we need.
We need that framed to that.
Ain't that long ago,
man.
That is not that long ago.
That is a crazy thing.
It's like,
look,
we captured this shit from these people
that will sell it to you.
Who wants to buy it?
There's a picture of the dude we jacked.
They got a picture of the dude they
checked.
There's a previous owner.
This is the previous owner.
Look at that.
$20 an acre in Wyoming.
Do you think that they had an acre?
How much of that?
No.
$20 an acre.
Wow.
Do that right now.
I mean it depends on where it is.
If it's in beverly hills,
that's why we $14 million or $15 an
acre.
15 bucks and acre in Oregon and here's
the.
But look at the dude that got the dude.
They got like the most regal looking
native american looks like a chief.
Let's look at his image.
Perfect fuck.
Like a perfect representation of like a,
an elder.
Like,
uh,
a wise,
powerful old indian like a chief,
right?
He looks like the dude they be running
shit.
like we got it from this dude.
We got the prime cuts baby.
Huh?
We got the fucking tomahawk ribeye with
the bone.
Come on bro.
For you indian land the best.
Nothing but the best.
We got it off that guy.
Look at him.
We said the highest guy on the totem
pole.
Could you imagine if there's parts of
this country where decided
to live like the native americans live
straight up,
full stop.
They wore animal skins.
They,
they,
they tanned from shooting them with bows
and arrows.
They made their own bows and arrows.
They did everything the way that the
people did before the europeans arrived.
They say,
fuck your technology.
Fuck your laws.
Fuck your bullshit.
Just give us a fertile,
gigantic swath of land that we could
live like we live before.
And then people just gravitate to that.
Do you know how crazy that would be?
People would fuck it up though.
They would do a reality show of it.
They would have certain.
Some of the horses were,
have like fucking cameras and you see
the fucking westworld and dick's
flopping out a loin cloth and people
would have to kill people the way they
killed people back then too.
They'd have to have tools aNd cit.
Scalpel,
I think.
I don't know who.
Who invented scalping.
Do you think scalping was invented by
the native americans or was it invented
by the white people?
By the white people?
They,
uh,
we covered this.
I used to collect them.
Yeah.
These bag.
What was it?
Their idea first?
I'm wondering whose idea it was first
because sometimes some of the shit that
people do in war,
you know,
they'll,
they'll copy shit from the enemy to like
enemies doing it.
They'll day,
uh,
we'll fucking do it was a bit of birth.
Oh,
he,
he did the worst shit of all time.
Brutal.
Give her a listen to that dan carlin
hardcore history series to after the
show I'm going to send to you gotta.
listen to it.
It's nuts if you've got the time because
it's like five parts and you get sucked
in,
but it just shows you how insane that
guy and his family were and what the
empire that he created.
This one guy,
his real name is too much and they had
all kinds of shit.
They had catapults,
light human bodies on fire.
They would.
They will do a quick as shooting
airwatch horseback.
Right?
That's what saved them.
Well,
that was one of their strategies,
but they were extremely stout people.
They were very,
very strong people.
Apparently.
All I know about that.
I'll just full disclosure.
All I know about is what I learned from
dan carlin's hardcore history podcast
and like a couple of articles.
I've never really read that much about
the mongols,
but what he said was that they had these
bows that required 160 pounds to pull
back,
which is just insane.
So they must be shooting heavier arrows
that could kill people better than
anything.
The smaller people or the weaker people
would would possess and they were a
nomadic horse people,
so they were traveling around,
living in tents like they despise people
that live in cities.
They were just the strongest,
most ruthless army the world has ever
seen at the time like nobody had ever
seen anything like this.
They would just.
They killed millions of people.
They thInk New York times had an article
that said they killed so many people.
They change the carbon footprint of the
earth.
There was less people,
a noticeable number.
If you go and you look through the ice
core samples and they are starting to
attributed,
or some people at least are attributing
that to gingiss con killing some
somewhere in the neighborhood of 10
percent of the population on earth.
The one out of 10,
he killed more people than aids.
Yeah,
definitely.
Right?
How many people didn't get killed?
If you had to guess,
someone was just talking about that
recently and say,
no one should die from hiv anymore.
No one should die of aids.
It literally shouldn't have to happen
anymore,
and that crazy.
This take medication.
Now.
We were kids,
everybody was terrified to aids.
Aids was a death sentence while eating
twinkies,
terrified of aids while eating the thing
that's slowly killing you.
Terrified to get into aids.
A little kid gets it.
Everybody will want to go to school no
more.
Remember that one kid go to school?
Yeah,
the magic god in there,
but they will.
All right.
Magic.
Got it.
I remember being in my car.
I was in my car.
I was living in revere Massachusetts.
Rear.
Yeah.
This,
uh,
apartment complex and I was driving my
car and I was on the high.
I was on the road listening to the
radio.
Like,
you know,
you see where the traffic lights are.
You see,
you see,
you remember it's like burned in your
brain.
like,
ah,
magic johnson has aids.
What in my car?
What's,
what's out?
I remember thinking like it was a scene
in a vampire movie monster movie or
something like a zombie outbreak.
Like,
oh my god,
now it's reached one of the greatest
basketball players of all time.
this is insane.
Are people going to just start dropping
off like flies?
Now we're going to start,
please just,
I wouldn't condoms right away
afterwards.
I don't think so.
We need,
you know,
animals bro.
Savage,
savage.
I mean there's a reason why there's 7
billion of us.
We stop.
People need to stop pretending that when
they're fully,
fully aroused that they're thinking
straight like you,
you are operating at about 10 percent of
your normal resources like aids,
whatever.
Who's got a.
He's still got a little bit with the
code.
Will the,
you know,
it's crazy that it was just primarily
gay people in drug users that we're
getting it.
That's what a weird disease man.
That's a.
That's a weird one man.
That's a strange thing when your body
starts weakening and shutting down like
whoa.
But when you really think about the
actual danger and death,
like I think even while aids was in its
height of killing people,
I don't think it was killing people as
much as the flu was right.
The numbers I'm finding now or depending
on worldwide or us.
So worldwide,
tuberculosis is now killing more people
than aids.
But this says that only one point,
1 million people today in the us are
living with aids and I think I saw,
but living with aids,
it's like you're at the border of
getting aids.
Is that what it is?
It's liKe,
yeah,
you have h supposedly this again,
I'm not a dOctor.
Right.
Supposedly it's like you have hiv,
your immune system gets weakened.
You catch aids,
which is acquired immune deficiency
syndrome,
which means your t cell levels have
reached a certain count where they
identify it as aids,
right?
Yeah.
IT actually did type in a tennis is
going to hiv.
So that's.
They're definitely connected.
So it's not people that also their
immune system fails.
That's outside of hiv.
This.
So I clicked on this.
I'll share what I clicked on.
So I typed in that end,
and this is showing this.
It says at one point 2 million people,
I received an aids diagnosis since the
early eighties.
Since the early eighties.
Okay.
So 1 million people.
And there have been 12,000
in 2014.
There were 12,000,
333 deaths due to any cause of people
with diagnosed hiv infection ever
classified as aids and what does that
mean then at $6?
A weird way of saying it with people.
I'll say it again.
It says there were 12,000,
333 deaths due to any cause of people
with diagnosed hiv infection.
Ever classified as aids.
Isn't that a strange way of saying that?
Yeah.
With the.
I don't know what that immedion could
lose the declassification if your immune
system gets strong enough.
I don't know.
It says with diagnosed hiv infection
ever classified as aids.
Okay.
Are the.
I don't know,
mayBe I'm too stupid for that because
what I also saw was that a million
people died last year from it,
but that'd be worldwide and this then
contradicts because it says a million
people have only been diagnosed and this
is only in the us and that other numbers
worldwide.
So it gets really sketchy anD it says
6,721
deaths were attributed directly to hiv.
Yeah.
So it seems that they,
they definitely think it's still killing
people.
Definitely still is tuberculosis.
But what is,
how many people die from the flu every
year?
What?
What do you would you think would be the
most?
The most ruthless,
normal killer would be the flu.
The flu would kill the most people.
Thirty 6,000.
Way more way more people Got jacked by
the flu every year.
Every year.
And what was the number from the aids
number was total,
right.
How many of those people that flu shots
though?
What is it?
Two thousand 14.
So it's a third or so.
So what's the third aids to the flu?
Aids is about one slash third of the
deaths of the flu per year on average.
I don't know if I'm that interesting.
It's like we're not scared of the thing
that kills us way more.
We're really scared of the thing that
kills less people because it kills them
through butts.
That's what it is.
It has to be.
We're terrified that it kills people
through
because like the flu,
it seems like we should really be
concentrating on that thing.
That thing's killing way more people.
People not washing their hands,
but they're like,
look,
we can't stop that,
but we can stop all of his buttocks.
Weird.
Right.
It's weird like when we have.
Maybe it's just because it's a new thing
that was kiLling people because it
didn't exist and then it did exist.
That's probably what it is,
right?
Like,
yeah,
because it came out of nowhere because
it was in like,
what was it during the eighties?
Yeah.
Murphy said,
and you're walking around with the a's
on your lip.
Oh,
was that,
was that delirious?
Do you remember sam kennison his bid on
it.
He goes,
they say sam shouldn't make fun of aids
aid.
Sam Is a communicable disease.
Straight people can get it to.
He goes,
no,
it's not our dad's.
He had this crazy dangerous bit about it
and like way back then like,
whoa.
It's like a cro in around like 1980.
I don't know if that's accurate,
but.
So 1980 was the highest peak.
Maybe it's in thousands.
So yeah,
it seems like low.
So it seems like it seems like late
seventies,
right?
Is that somewhere around 1980?
The one thing too,
I read that there's around 300,000
total deaths and a third of them are in
New York,
300,000
total deaths,
a third in New York and the flute and
this is all told ever.
Again,
just the stats are all multiple pages.
So here's how many of the.
See I get so confused about all this
shit because uh,
some people believe that a lot of these
people also were shooting heroin.
A lot of these people were also doing a
lot of drugs.
I would wonder,
you know,
if they're really partying hard and they
also get aids,
I would,
I would always wonder like how much of
you partying hard is destroying your
immune system too.
LIke if you're,
if you have a disease,
like say you have cancer and you're
struggling with cancer and you just
decided to hardcore start smoking meth
and then you die from the cancer.
Like is it,
isn't,
didn't something else kill you too.
Right?
Not saying that the cancer's good for
you,
cancer,
certainly bad for you,
but if you have cancer and just decided
to go on a meth binge and destroy your
immune system,
it's got to contribute to your health,
but we don't consider that.
We will consider up.
They'll fucking cancer.
Got him.
Cancer.
It did get him.
He definitely did get them,
but he was also smoke and math all day.
Feeling good.
Doing robberies or robberies with
fucking skulls.
Painted out.
It's 7:11.
He was amped.
Dude was amped with cancer.
That's.
That's also.
I mean if he dies of a heart attack,
like all the cancer gave him a heart
attack.
Yeah,
probably.
That probably had something to do with
it.
DefInitely was not good.
It's definitely not good to have cancer,
but it's also not good to be smoking
meth while you have cancer smoking bad.
So how many of these people that got
aids were like extremely healthy folks
that like jogged on a regular basis and
ate a lot of fruit and vegetables are
hard to get that data.
I know I would like to get that data.
This is not like a prejudice
perspective.
I'm just as a curious person,
I would like to get all that I would
like to know.
What is it that actually does it?
Is it,
um,
is it the method kills you?
Is it a disease that kills you?
Is it a combination of all these things?
We always want to attribute death to one
thing,
but I would imagine that with all the
people that have died of the flu,
there's a number of deaths.
When you look at the fluid,
you're like,
man,
that the flu could just catch you.
The flu could just catch you and you
catch you when you're already week two,
maybe your,
your rundown,
you've been working too much and then
the flu hits you.
When your immune system's devastated and
it gets deep into you and gets you.
Everybody's vulnerable.
I mean,
the thing about diseases that's so
strange to me,
so some of them are associated with
certain certain groups of people like
aids,
aids is one of those ones is just so
associated with gay people that it's
like a really politically charged
disease and we concentrate on it like
really heavily.
But I think it,
I really think it wasn't just the gay
thing was also that it was,
it was new,
new,
there was a new thing that was killing
people.
We were always worried about that.
Right.
There's always these pandemic movies
where some new crazy disease breaks
loose,
just runs rampant.
We don't have an immune system for it.
People will start dying and they need to
get the medication to the people and get
it to the baby quickly.
People are putting it on subway subways.
Just always sOme shit like tHat.
We always have some new shit that's
gonna get us swine flu,
flu.
So that was.
So aids had a dual,
a disadvaNtage one that is connected to
gay people and people are like,
oh,
what do they do over there?
What are they going to get it?
I'm lucky.
Yeah,
exactly.
TheRe was that and then there was also
blood transfusions,
car accident.
That's right,
right.
People were worried about getting from
blood transfusions,
so that means back then they were never.
They were like just letting random
people donate blood without checking it.
I don't think they had a test for it for
awhile.
I think for awhile they didn't have a
task for it.
Then they have to find like I guess they
have to find like antibodies in your
blood or some shit and like.
But it's so weird that wall.
This is all going on.
How many people were dying from cancer
every year just from smoking cigarettes.
It'S fucking crazy numbers.
Crazy numbers.
People dropping like flies and no one
thinks about that.
When you see a guy smoking a cigarette,
you don't think that guys killing
themselves.
They're like,
oh,
he's outside and for the restaurant
having a cig,
normal shit.
Now that guy's.
That guy's poisoning themselves.
Guy who delivers,
but it's just strange to me like we get
really specific about what fears we have
in terms of what way we die and when a
new disease comes along that becomes one
of the most specific ones,
but while you're indulging in all these
behaviors that will also kill you in way
larger numbers than diseases too.
Fucking weird man.
Very weird.
Human Beings,
me were so
strange.
So strange in the way we prioritize
things.
Always.
Yeah.
Do you get the flu shot?
No.
Joey diaz though.
I won't give up.
The joke is,
but I think had he has been born of the
best new bits about it.
I never got a flu shot,
but I've gotten the flu once and it was
like two years ago out of nowhere,
man just came up.
I hit a fat ass bowl to my legs,
got hot and my whole body felt hot and I
told my wife,
I think I'm going to get sick.
So you've hiT a bowl and that's when it
came on my own.
I want to stay with a bow,
but that's when I started feeling hot.
Huh.
So the,
we'd made you uh,
aware of it?
Yes.
But it wasn't the weekend though.
Hey asshole.
Yeah.
The.
We were struggling like,
hey asshole,
you got the flu.
You better pay attention to your body.
I got a couple of years ago,
I kicked it quick because of heart.
I caught it coming on.
I felt it.
I was like,
oh,
I know what this is.
And I just laid down.
They didn't do shit.
I just laid down and drank a lot of tea.
Chill the fuck out.
I didn't do shit.
I just lay down and relax and let my
body recuperate itself.
I got lucky that it was,
it happened during a time where I
wasn't.
I didn't have anything to do that day so
I can take time off.
I heard that when you get a real hot or
real a good flu,
it let your body fighting off something
inside your body.
Yeah.
Your body's basically going to war.
Fuck yeah.
You sweating up a storm.
The body's trying to chase out the
invaders.
You got people trying to get over that
wall in my body.
Your body has little organisms trying to
get over their walls.
You got wall set up to keep these things
from breeding and you know,
taking over parts of your body.
She got this immune system just going to
war.
You got a little war going on in your
body when you're sick.
I know that everything is fighting to
got pcp.
I we'd fight and got cracked fighting.
Yeah.
I mean people don't like when you judge
people's health and you know,
you definitely shouldn't judge someone
based on whether or not they're sick or
when what you're looking at when you see
people that are sick,
including yourself.
All of us where we're looking at as an
organism that is at war and we have this
weird instinct to kind of get awaY from
them.
Like,
oh my god,
I could get that.
I could get that organism,
whatever that.
Well,
I got to get away from it.
What if one of the troops,
troops jumps off of him and hops into
me?
I can't afford to take time off work
now.
Get away from me.
I don't have.
I don't have time for.
I don't got time for your coughing,
blood,
don't pump blood on a zombie man.
But look how many people like um,
who don't have,
who don't ever really take care of their
body because I know like before I want
to coming stanley,
I never had healthcare how just gambling
with my body,
how do we go to other than go to the
hospital and I was really dying and when
I went to the hospital I went to this
cheap little hospital right here in echo
park.
Bad was iT,
it was fucked up man.
it was like,
it was real.
It was,
it smelled like an old elementary school
and they're sick all down and it smelled
like pine sol because the old korean
doctor there and I told her what was
wrong with me and she,
I told her I have a flu.
I got my butt hurts because I might have
a hemorrhoid.
I don't know what's going on.
I'm bleeding out of my ass.
Damn.
And she goes,
okay,
sit down.
And now she's all,
she and I paid $100 and which would give
you,
she gave me medicines for,
for The fourth of hemorrhoid because I
had been running for the first time and
then she gave me antibiotics for my flu.
What is hemorrhoids come from?
Does it come from.
You're trying to force your pool out,
man.
That's what someone told me my first
time.
I didn'T know man.
I was out.
I was on the road and opened the low
carb diet,
the atkins diet.
So I was fucking with.
I eat cheese and meat all week.
you're bound up and I didn't eat,
drink no water.
I drink soda so I must've been stuffed.
So joe,
I'm in my,
I'm in the bathroom,
like the show's over and like two days,
nothing right now.
And they could feel like,
um,
like my,
my butthole already felt like,
um,
have broken glass inside.
Oh,
that feeling.
So I finally,
I pushed too hard because I,
I pushed her like I was having a baby.
I waS like,
I was doing mas and then up on the
youtube screen please.
So I fuck it up while he's talking and
then I pushed and I pushed and then
like,
aw man,
I could just feel I saw like I wiped
myself and it might the toilet paper
like a fucking tampon.
And I was in pain.
Dude.
It says the veins around your anus tend
to stretch under pressure and may bulge
or swell swollen veins.
Hemorrhoids can develop from increased
pressure in the lower rectum due to
straining during bowel movements,
sitting for long periods of time on the
toilet.
Eddie bravo has a hilarious bit about it
being on his phone,
on his phone and taking a shit.
It's very funny.
Remember,
didn't he talk about it on here?
I think you've talked about it on here,
but it was crazy.
Yeah.
NOt good for your butthole to be sitting
in that.
How would describe the position of the
pain?
It feels like?
Um,
I remember talking about in a bit,
I said that it felt like every night
though,
the goals sort of siloed by using me.
Like,
fuck you in the ass at night.
How many days did you go before he took
a shut off?
Three days,
that's what the share,
that's one of the pain started and I
blew my butthole out I guess and then
like three days later I didn't shit
right without paying for like two weeks
I was afraid of fucking neat man
about to go to a doctor and they had to
literally break up the shit in his butt
hole.
They had to go up as bought with an
instrument and break it up
and flush him out.
Give him something.
I think he had to take something,
some sort of diuretic and some stool
loosening agent like some hardcore drugs
and then they had to go in there with
like a chisel and chop off this concrete
log that he at the bottom of his button
and then he,
you know,
he hadn't shit in many days.
Try to.
Yeah,
it was dangerous and he couldn't get it
out so he was literally plugged up and
it kept piling in.
It's not like it's going to stop eating,
it's just going to keep piling in.
So he's got a blockade of like shit
rocks at the end of his booty tunnel and
it's real property can be bad.
So real problem.
He had to go to a doctor.
My life finally came out and then a
clink clink,
but It was all bad with all dry,
with ugly,
painful.
You gotta eat your vegetables,
speed my speed.
And after I finished paying,
it was hurting my butthole after I peed.
I mean that's one thing that I freak out
about people that are on this carnivore
diet.
I hear this carnivore diet stuff and
they're like,
oh no,
no problem at all.
No problem at all.
You don't eat any vegetables.
You got no problem at all.
Wouldn't really kill you.
Eat some broccoli with that little kale
is elusive in that motherfucking line
up.
I just can't imagine the broccoli's
killing you.
I think if broccoli's killing you,
come on,
there's probably something else wrong
you should probably like get your blood
work done for.
I fiGured out what the vitamins are.
If you eat broccoli and you start
getting headaches,
bra,
eat broccoli.
Folks,
what about gains?
Are you broccoli?
I get a headache,
man.
People have been eating broccoli
forever.
Like,
how's that possible?
Like what?
When did broccoli ever become something
that you feel shitty after you ate?
Has anybody ever said that?
Like,
I eat broccoli,
I just fuck get hooks folks with my
immune system.
Dudes will claim that.
Now these carnivore guys,
a lot of them are claiming,
look,
I,
I eat a fucking salad,
bro.
I'm off for awhile.
People.
I typed it in back at the other way.
In general,
broccoli is safe to eat.
Any side effects or not serious?
Most common side effect is gas or bowel
irritation.
Yeah.
Broccoli farts caused by broccoli's.
High amounts of fiber.
All cruciferous.
That's a great word.
Cruciferous vegetables can make you
grassy.
Oh,
gassy,
but who's super gassy,
or are you a scIentist or not?
You?
Fuck,
okay.
When you're a scientist,
you scientific terms,
you don't say gassy with me,
but he's scared saying farts.
Gassy.
But the health benefits outweigh the
discomfort.
yeah.
So there's certain people like,
um,
that I think have a real physical issue.
Like Jordan Peterson is wonderful when
it describes like he,
he literally can't have anything other
than me and at this point in his life or
it gives them headaches and it fucks
with them.
I think certain people may all bullshit
aside,
might have a real biological issue with
vegetabLes,
which sounds insane,
but it only makes sense.
People have a problem with everything is
there's certain people that have a
problem with almost everything.
There's people that are to citrus as
people that are allergic to certain
cahtos yeah.
All kinds of plants.
There's people that are allergic to
grass.
Why wouldn't be allergic to some
vegetables?
So if you are allergic to some
vegetables and you just go on an all
meat diet,
all those symptoms of those allergies go
away.
Why wouldn't that make sense to people?
I mean there's so many people fighting
off the idea,
this carnivore diet that you're only
eating meat and you feel fantastic.
You're probably dealing with a bunch of
people that have undiagnosed
interactions,
negative interactions with vegetables.
This is probably something about their
system that does not go well with
vegetables,
so they should take vitamins.
I take vitamins and eat meat and you
better find a way to get fiber.
Kids.
I didn't want to get all backed up.
Vegetables are good.
I think if you eat like a really fatty
meat though,
you don't have that problem.
If you eat like a ton of rib eyes,
it just greases up that whole pipeline
and you're like,
ooh,
everything comes flying out.
I think when you start eating that lean
ground bison meat,
you know no butter.
Like you're gonna have a problem for
butterball.
Yeah.
You chew that shit down and pack it
down.
Then you water on top of it.
So it's like you go like the pack that
bison here and then you've got the water
behind that.
It's concrete a fine.
Find its way through your body.
Have some broccoli,
bro.
Kill.
Put some cheese on it.
Some people really firmly believe that
dairy is bad for you.
And that's something I've never tried.
I've never tried.
You know,
had dairy?
No,
no,
no.
To not have dairy.
I've never tried to like way off 100
percent dairy.
I don't eat much,
but if I do it's mostly cheese.
Hardly ever drink milk unless it's with
cookies and whenever I do,
I always feel weird.
No.
If I need milk I shouldn't.
Myself.
I've been my whole life to them tolerate
and I didn't even know that.
My mom never told me,
but every time I'm eating cheese I have
problem against the stuff.
It'll come out to him.
So I fought with almond milk and soy
milk now.
Yeah.
Do you fuck with vegan cheese?
Everything big.
only meeting no more.
When did you stop?
Why wouldn't have.
Fuck my asshole blew up.
That's good.
Move.
Fucked up the fiber.
And you feel good though.
You feel fat?
People don't believe me.
The theory.
Vegan.
You're a fucking fat.
What crops do?
Why are you opposed to eggs?
Oh no,
just the.
Just give it all up man.
I got so scared after I started bleeding
man.
And I said,
you know what?
God died on point.
You feel better.
I feel good.
I mean I don't have.
I don't have the runs.
Know that shit on myself anymore.
You ever try out this other types of
diets or is this the first one?
No,
I tried being a vegan,
I tried the atkins diet,
I tried the hollywood diet,
you know,
when you wake up in the morning and do
some coke and it sucked.
I never tried that one.
Yeah.
Um,
do,
are you trying to lose weight or you're
good?
No,
I mean I,
I couldn't lose weight but I was bigger
than I am right now because of a.
No,
there's not really a diet.
I just started this in 2011 or 2012.
And you said when your ass was bleeding,
that's when you decided that's where
they started.
Started off slow.
I just stopped drinking milk first and
then I thought was cheesed then meet
with the hardest fish.
Chicken little slow.
And what do you replace it with?
Like what kind of foods?
My wife,
she was raised vegan in dayton,
Ohio by her mom dam and you know the and
they were poor so they grew up in a,
in a trailer park.
So that must have been tough for them
being vegan.
So I just started little by little,
it helped me because she will not be
good at the time when I started being
vegan.
I got it.
I still love me,
man.
Like fuck.
Yeah man.
Like hamburgers,
ribs,
ribeye,
lobster,
jack in the box.
Number five.
Do you go and get your blood tested and
get yourself checked out?
I got my blood tested two years ago and
I'm supposed to get my blood tested this
week again,
him two years ago.
And how do you look like in terms of
your vitamins,
getting enough nutrients?
Do they do all that kind of stuff?
Tests your vitamin d levels.
That totally took my b levels.
It was for sugar and everything was
cool.
Yeah,
that's good.
He just told me that I could lose 30
pounds.
Yeah.
Well the first women I've watched your
videos every once in a while I'll try to
get into the ice thing.
You got into the ice things rough.
I want to know what's good to saunas.
Saunas are usually nine degrees.
Is that like a different side of the
head with the why?
Mca right now?
Saunas.
The same steam rooms,
dIfferent steam room is like if,
if steam gets out or.
Well it's a,
it really is like in the implementation
of it more than anything,
but if he did,
I'm a steam room,
most likely was a tile floor and you go
in there with a towel,
Florida oil last door and it just hot
steam and everybody just gets hot in
there and then they get to sweating and
they leave,
but the song is different in that it's a
dry heat so you go in there and it's
usually.
I think the idea is,
and I could be wrong here,
but I think the idea is that the steam
room can't get as hot as a song because
if it did,
it would kind of cook you because it's
wet.
It would be like hot wet air around you.
It kind of cook you as opposed to the
hot dry air.
That doesn't make any sense.
It's touching little hot.
The hot rocks at the sauna.
The sauna.
Yeah.
It's because it's conducted waters,
waters conducting the heat.
That's what it is.
Right?
So the air doesn't conduct the heat as
well.
The water does.
Okay,
so that's makes sense because of the
sauna.
You can get to a fucking,
a crispy degree,
crispy temperature before you body
starts to freak out.
That's like the old school.
Highlight the rat pack,
so not trying to sit around the song and
party all night and then take a little
steam in the morning,
get all the alcohol.
It doesn't really do that,
but it doesn't make you feel a little
better.
Yeah.
If you fucked up from drinking,
you could also run the risk of could you
might be dehydrated.
You could run the risk of blacking out.
You know,
if you're.
If you're susceptible to that and you
look at them all there,
he's on the phone,
matches on the phone,
is there in the sauna,
landau,
look at these guys.
That's hilarious.
Meanwhile,
how'd the photographer get in there,
but I call bullshit.
I call bullshit the phone.
I call bullshit with the photographer
during the ocean's 11 where we know
probably really happened.
I'm sure he did iT all the time and they
said,
yeah,
come on in and take a picture of us.
This is what we do.
Guys were having a good time,
highly.
I remember the time they were having a
good time man.
Too.
Crazy.
Like in their fifties there,
right?
Oh yeah.
They were older guys and they got
together and they just did whatever the
fuck they wanted and they'd go to vegas
and party and everybody wanted to go
party with them there at the sands
there,
the sand.
The says.
It's crazy.
When you look at those old hotels and
casinos in vegas,
they just decided to dynamite item,
but what would you give to to stay in
the sands today if they kept everything
up to date but current with the era in
which it was created.
like if you went there,
it was a total retro hotel room with
like fucking dial up phones and you
know,
just.
I mean there's god,
there's something to be said for it,
right?
Like if you,
if you live in a log cabin,
like there's something really cool about
a log cabin,
right?
Like you're,
you're living in a way that people lived
like this a thousand years ago.
Man,
this is real.
This is really how people live.
But no one wants to live like people
lived in the sixties,
you know,
like if they had a place like that where
you had all the same kind of furniture,
just updated all the same law.
Tensiles yeah.
But have that shit like they had it back
then.
How many people would want that?
Man,
let me,
like vegas was only made possible
because of air conditioning.
Oh yeah.
Water.
They couldn't have pulled that off if
they didn't have some sort of way to
cool the place down.
When did that start?
Because that's a good question.
I've got a bit hottest shit.
I don't.
Well,
the ice house where we do stand up was
his 58 years old.
Before that it was some sort of a,
I think it was some sort of,
uh,
an actual ice house where they bring it
at,
at some point.
It's history.
That's what it used to be.
It used to be a storage place where
people that didn't have frigerators
yeah,
that's what the whole place it would buy
a block of ice and they would take this
ice and they carry it home.
Jesus christ.
That wasn't that long ago,
man.
I mean that's less than 100 years ago.
That's insane.
So late 1947.
Bugsy siegel flamingo.
Yeah,
I bet it.
I bet it couldn't be.
I'm going to take a guess.
I feel like we've probably,
we've talked about this already.
I've just forgotten because I'm too
stupid to maintain all this information
anymore.
My brain's overfilled.
Um,
I want to say it happened somewhere
around the 19 twenties.
The 19 fifties.
What?
There was no refrigerators for the
fifties.
Refrigerators.
I'm sorry.
Is air conditioning in vegas as I was
looking at.
Oh,
sorry,
I missed.
I'm sorry I was rambling.
I was going with bulk of siena was going
with a mango,
so air conditioning and refrigeration.
We're definitely,
we went with the ice house,
which is a blocks of ice that they used
to use for ice boxes.
When do you think they invented the
refrigerator where they didn't have to
do that for the refrigerator.
The ice chest.
So I'll check,
but I think they pr man.
So with air conditioning,
the fifties.
So the,
the,
the big roaring times of the vegas
eruption was probably right after that
and he had to be like right after it was
invented.
Well there was different type of
condition that though the standard air
condition that we have now,
but I used to work at.
I used to work at sears roebuck's and in
boyle heights.
It's an old sears building and they 87,
it was a big earthquake and I was
working there and that's in all the
water came down.
They have a swamp cooler so it's like a
big show with a bunch of water in it.
And that's a really an old aIr
conditioner by the mid to late 1930
swamp coolers.
Homes by maybe 15 degrees,
but added humidity.
It was bad dude.
swamp coolers.
I liked the name and swamp coolers.
It was luck.
I had to clean one of them
motherfuckers.
Man.
It was huge.
It was bigger than that for the whole
building that it's crazy.
And it broke another one who came down.
Yeah,
man.
Air conditioning.
If you live in the northeast in the
summertime,
it gets wet.
Like I lived in boston,
there was a wet place like when,
when the summertime would come around,
you wouldn't,
it wouldn't just be that it was hot out.
It was hot and wet,
you know,
things get sweaty as fuck.
Mosquitoes are everywhere.
Yeah,
real muggy.
It's a weird feeling,
but it's cool because you're,
you realize it's not going to happen
very long,
you know,
so like when,
when it is muggy,
the thing about like real contrast,
whether that's one thing we just don't
get in California,
we don't get a contrast.
If you live in a place like New York,
you'll have a summer that is brutally
hot and muggy and people are walking
around and sweating and they're like,
holy shit,
it's fucking hot out.
Fuck fucking hot bag.
But you'll also have a winter where
you've got your shit pulled up to your
face.
You're fucking die and man,
you can't wait to get on that train or
the bus or hop in an uber.
You just got to get out of this fucking
cold.
Oh,
oh,
you're in the cab and like take you to
this place.
Cab takes you to that place you all pile
out immediately run inside,
man.
There's something about that that sucks
at the time,
but it's good for people who don't get
the hill here,
man.
Right here in turns 70 leg warmers.
Oh yeah.
People are hugging it up everywhere.
They dug it up.
I'm sort of bringing those boots too
soon.
They bring in the uggs when they weren't
short.
Girls are allowed to do that.
We don't say shit.
They can do whatever they want.
Basically.
They were running fashion for sure.
They decide.
Right.
That's why fanny packs went away.
it was because of girls don't like guys
on all right.
That's what happened.
If I didn't pay,
the tournament will come back.
I remember that with a fanny pack.
The only fanny pack away to get started
on goes enamel.
It was a fanny pack and then the inside
had a holster for a little 38.
Mm.
Yeah.
He tried to rob me son.
This video that bert kreischer just put
up on instagram of a dude pulling us
pistol out,
shoot himself in the leg,
try to be quick,
draw mcgraw
for the leg.
He goes,
I just fucking shot mYself and bert
kreischer with all the tears coming out
of his eyes.
Ha ha.
He's so funny,
man.
Bert kreischer has a new netflix special
coming out.
August 24th netflix.
Bert kreischer,
I forget what it's called,
a,
but bird's to be here the night before.
We're going to hype it up.
Secret top secret time will shave sns
chest for secret time.
He's a cool dude.
That guy.
He's a very good dude.
I've been on this podcast.
Very good guy.
We got a lot of good guys,
but yeah,
like comedy.
Today's a good time.
It is,
man.
It is.
It's a great time.
Funny peopLe
and cool people and it's fun.
Yeah,
it's fun.
Fun and happy again that the whole time
when I got that gig.
Yeah,
those were fun times,
man.
Tyler doubloons.
Yup.
Go across the street.
See chewy play.
Yeah.
When everything's good like that,
like it makes.
It's good for everybody.
It's like it makes the whole community
is like more a more positive and it
seems like we're helping out more young
people coming up and then they develop a
nice positive community too and they
realize,
hey man,
we're all trying to get somewhere,
but we're not against each other where
we should be supporting each other and
it'll help everybody.
It'll help you.
It'll help me.
There'll be more positive vibes flowing
around everybody.
Be happy like we inspire each other.
We were not competing against each
other.
Someone does well.
Don't say fuck him.
Say god damn he did it.
I could do it too.
You can see the amount of energy can be
put into both ways of thinking about it,
but one way is so much more positive for
you and for everybody around you and
still allows you to have a competitive
instinct because you're still competing
against yourself.
You competing to do better,
but you're looking at the people around
you as inspiration rather than its
competition,
and so you,
instead of having this negative,
combative relationship with everybody
around you,
that's also succeeding you have is
really cooperative,
excited,
feeling about it.
You know what I mean?
That's,
that's entirely possible in in business.
That's entirely possible and friendship.
It's like that's how people should try.
They should aspire to interact,
interface with things,
always try to be as positive as you can
to give the same amount of energy you
can give towards positive and still
fulfill all those same amount of
instincts of like kicking ass and doing
well or do it against yourself,
like compete against yourself.
Don't think about it as those other
people are taking something away from
you.
Think about as they're giving you an
opportunity to look at what's possible.
If you really dedicate yourself and you
should choose that as a valuable life
lesson like,
wow,
look at that guy doing so well or look
at this girl like kicking ass and doing
all this.
How does she accomplish that?
As you write all those things,
how does she make all these movies?
How does she do all these things like
fuck,
but people don't do that.
The natural instinct is to look at
someone who's like some crazy,
like super competitive person,
like the rock or something like that.
Like you see the raW,
he's in everything.
He's in everything.
You want to shit on him,
but he's such a nice guy.
You can't.
It's a real problem that he could do.
That guy could do terrible movie after
terrible movie.
No one cares because you such a good
guy.
You could.
He could do whatever he wants.
He seemed like a nice guy.
He's a very nice guy.
He's a and he's the real deal.
That's really what he does.
I mean,
that guy really does show up at a
fucking hotel room.
Four o'clock in the morning,
flies across the world and immediately
starts working out.
Wow.
He's an animal like a lead.
You want to be inspired.
That guy's worth more money than
everyone.
He makes more money than anybody that's
ever made any money in movies.
He's fucking junk or not.
he's so out of control.
Every movie does as a blockbuster.
Meanwhile,
he still shows up at a place they got to
fucking dig,
got one of them elliptical machines
waiting for him.
They got weights,
weight,
and for him he goes to town to do like
45 minutes of cardio when he fucking
land flying across the world,
lift weights for an hour.
Like He just keeps going.
He just keeps going.
He finds a way to not complain,
stay positive and just keep going.
I would have read half of his book and
I'm very like,
that's a lot for you.
I remember that.
Um,
when you,
when he was third string playing
football in Canada,
he was living up,
it will show the mattress with the guy
who got kicked out of a team.
Jesus fog to be a superstar.
I mean,
I don't even know how many millions he
makes a movie,
but everybody sees his movies.
He's such a good guy.
But here,
here's,
be really clear,
that kind of genetics,
like what that guy is that is just like
we were talking about with Iceland.
That's the same shit.
That's the same shit with the pacific
islands,
man.
That's some warrior dna son.
That's a giant man.
That's a huge,
super powerful man who fucking is so
driven like we are lucky.
We are lucky.
That dude is not on the biggest fucking
horse he could find with the biggest
battle ax.
I mean that's what these people come
from,
man.
You don't get to be that big if you
don't have like some sort of a,
a great lineage of warriors behind you.
You mean this,
that's so much bigger than most people
because the schwarzenegger,
he's so big,
but all those guys like that guy that
plays the mountain on game of thrones.
Like what in the holy fuck that guy so
big.
You know the dat dude came out of some
warrior bloodline,
some crazy viking blood line because
before guns,
that was what was most important.
So when you see a guy like the rock or
you see a guy and you're like,
wow,
that guy looks like a conqueror.
Yeah,
because that's what he comes from 100
percent.
Like is a worry warrior that due to
place store.
What's that dude's name?
Chris hemsworth is home worth that.
That dude.
Listen
that,
that dude.
He's a goddamn specimen.
Or aqua man.
What is this jamie?
Body comparison of the rocK to the
mountain.
Who is the mountain mountains behind
them?
One hundred 50 pounds on him.
Oh my god.
Oh,
the mountain from game of thrones.
sorry.
Holy shit.
Put that again.
Look how much bigger he is.
That's like,
that's significant.
Integrate like six,
seven inches.
He's so big.
A guy.
So big.
I'll tell you the six,
nine or some shit.
Yeah.
Six.
Nine.
Dude,
that is so crazy.
I weigh more than both of them.
That's not true.
Oh,
well no.
The mountain weighs like three 93.
80 six.
Three 86.
He's six foot nine.
He weighs 386 pounds.
Like to put that in perspective.
A former world boxing champion.
um,
fuck is his name.
The crazy gypsy dude.
I'm sorry chris.
I know the guy.
He's the last guy to beat vladimir
klitschko.
God damn it.
How am I not remembering his name?
Tyson fury,
right?
Yes,
that's it.
Sorry tyson.
That guy's a beast.
Tyson fury.
He's six foot nine and he weighs 2:50
fam and he's a world boxing champion.
He,
he gave up the title,
he was going through some struggles,
some health struggles,
some mental health struggles too,
and gained a shitload of weight and then
he got real fat and then got all the way
down to like a super healthy way to get
an.
I don't know if he's box since I feel
like he has shit.
Find out if he's box since.
When was the last time he boxed?
But he's going to bok soon.
I know.
and he looks he's in phenomenal shape.
So when was the last time he fought?
There's the wikipedia say I feel like
the last time he fought his,
when he outpointed vladimir klitschko
and then afterwards he had a real
struggle.
Maybe just because all of a suDden it
became,
the champion is freaking out and maybe
partying too much or something.
Uh,
in june.
He fought just recently,
right?
Yep.
Was literally last month.
Yeah.
And who did he beat?
Suffer severe.
Did he beat him by decision?
Uh,
doesn't say,
where is it?
Decision.
Rtd round for.
What does that mean,
referee something technical dakota?
No,
because it's td technical decision.
Maybe it's a.
If someone got headbutted and they got
cut,
what happened?
So find out what happened in that fight.
So you just google the fight.
We'll figure out what happened.
Anyway,
if you go to his instagram page,
he's jack now.
Shredded six pack pang pang.
Pang looks great,
but you gotta think he's 2:50.
That big motherfucker who's the same
height as him is a hundred and 40 pounds
heavier than him.
Just saying that as that is fucking
insane.
that's so big.
Hundred 40 stakes.
Take 140 t-bones.
Just slap them all over.
That dude's bought it.
Just shocked that I used to be.
Everything will be doing before acting
doorman.
Someone smashed when people just
randomly.
I don't know man.
I don't know about anywhere,
man.
He's the world's strongest man though,
is one of those guys.
He does those worlds.
Strongman competitions together.
Fucking straw.
The handles on the logs.
They horst along fat twin after fourth
round.
Say that again.
The guy retired after the fourth.
Oh,
the guy retire.
So he retired on his stool?
No.
So he said no mas sound like it was an
interesting event.
Was getting pissed and there was a fight
with stand by.
Was the Crowd getting pissed because the
fight stopped because dude quit.
Tyson fury is a beast.
He's a really good boxer.
But um,
you know,
he came up to weigh over 300 pounds,
got real fat and then lost it all,
got down to 2:50.
He's smiling and laughing on his
instagram.
So like you figured it out.
Like I like that.
Like when someone goes to the park,
lands then comes back.
He's a big fucker.
Look how tall he is.
Six nine.
And he can box his ass off.
He's very slick,
like deceptively slick.
You know,
he's a traveler.
He's like one of them.
Bad ass gypsy dudes.
Like there's quite a few of those in
boxing right now.
These are tough fucking people and he
can perform under pressure to like,
he,
he gets loose.
This huge man.
He's so big dude.
Kenny box.
He can box hIs ass off man.
I just don't know why this guy.
So they're just standing in front of
each other and like they were fucking
around like two rounds and then he
landed some blows.
Go down here and see what happens.
Let's see what happens at the end
because if the guy just quit and there
was no,
there was no poInt where he was hurt
then it's disgraceful stuff.
So he's beating them up here?
Yeah.
Well tyson fury.
So yeah,
he's fucking him up.
He's of the jet woRld championship
caliber boxer.
He beat vladimir klitschko in his prime.
I mean at the end of his reign,
but he was still in his prime because
his next fight against anthony.
Joshua was fantastic.
Klitschko knocked joshua down,
had joshua deep,
deep trouble.
And then joshua came back and stopped
him and joshua knocked him down first.
Then he knocked joshua down second.
So it was like anthony.
Joshua was clearly,
if not the best,
at least it's between him and deontay
wilder right now until they fight the
best,
most dangerous heavyweights of our era.
And klitschko almost beat him,
almost knocked him out.
So when tyson fury beat him,
before that he was beating a prime time
klitschko and he just outboxed him man.
So the dude just quit.
What was he good?
Was he getting beat up our.
I was talking too much.
No,
go a little bit.
A little bit more.
So is the end of the round all the
highlights.
I mean theY probably should.
Yeah,
he,
he was getting hurt.
He was gettIng hurt for sure.
He right there.
He got hurt.
But,
but you gotta you gotta,
you know,
try to figure out a way to mitigate
this.
You know,
you've got to figure out when.
I mean he's going back to his,
his corner.
He's not wobbling.
You're supposed to be trying to figure
out a way to get past that dude.
And if you can't figure out a way to get
past that,
dude,
why'd you take the fight?
But I guess I guess he probably thought
he could beat that guy before he got in
with them.
And then while you're in the middle of
it,
you know what happens?
Who that happens to?
Loma chanko,
lemme chanko.
God's just quit.
Guys quit on their corner,
worldclass guys,
they're on their corner and they just
go,
fuck this.
I'm not going back out there.
There was like one of his more recent
fights against a really high level guy,
loma checkers.
So good.
He boxes guys out so convinced and
they're like,
look,
I'm going out.
Like this guy keeps teeing off of me.
I'm not making it.
We're cutting the shit short right here.
And they'll do it with a straight face
but like enough of this,
but that's because he's so much better.
Like what you've seen with tyson fury
there.
That guy was definitely getting beat up
and maybe he definitely needed to stop
that fight,
but the way he's getting beat up is not
like the same way loma chanko does.
Like when loma triangle does.
It looks like the end is near son.
You better get off this fucking train.
We're going right into a brick wall.
You think their mind's not in it when
you just give up.
Who knows man,
I mean we didn't watch the actual fight.
He might've tyson fury,
most likely,
I think probably hit them with some big
shots and you know,
we're looking at it from an outside
perspective,
but he knows he's in big,
big trouble.
It's a smart move.
I mean people get they boo and they get
angry when someone who's a real warrior
steps out of fight,
but I can
remember when nigel benn fought gerald
mcclellan and it was a big,
big fight at the time because they were
both just knockout artists and crazy
wild dudes with ferocious punching power
and gerald mcclellan cut a shit ton of
weight,
really way too much weight and he was a
really big light heavyweight and when he
went in there and fought gerald
mcclellan or when he fought a nodule
band,
rather,
they had a clash of heads and it was a
crazy like nonstop first round action
where jeremy mclellan hurt.
Nigel benn see if he could find that.
Jeremy clough,
gerald mcclellan hurt nigel benn knocked
him through the ropes and looked like
the fight was over and nigel band comes
back.
He gets back up and they're going at it
and there's a crazy headbutting there
too,
and during the headbutt I mean they're
throwing bombs back and forth,
but I'm gerald mcclellan takes a knee
shortly afterwards and then goes to his
corner and stops and the,
the people that are watching,
I remember saying like,
why is he doing that?
Like why would he stop a fight like that
doesn't make any sense.
And then boom,
he,
he's fucked.
And then they take them to the hospital.
And this is it.
This is what says around 10,
right before,
I think this is right before the
headbutt.
Yeah.
So during the first round,
I see,
I thought it was a shorter fight
through.
During the first round they had collided
and gerald mcclellan hit him with some
big shots and it looked like the fight
was over.
I'm pretty sure that was the first
round.
But when,
when whatever happened happened.
Oh,
look at that right hand by nigel pen.
that's ferocious.
Oh dude.
See,
I totally remember this wrong.
I remember a clash of heads.
Look at that.
I though,
man.
Damn,
I 100 percent.
Remember this wrong,
see,
because he got up and he's in trouble,
and nigel ben's hitting them again.
See,
I don't remember him.
that's interesting how that works,
man.
You haven't seen a fight in 20 years and
you have this stupid memory to have it
in your head.
Oh,
look at that upper cut he hit him with.
So I think this is the end of the fight.
So I think he was a greeley struggling
at this point.
I think he waited out his whole count.
That's it.
He waited out his whole count on his
knee and I think some people were
critical of that at the time.
This is crazy,
man.
So anyway,
after this fight,
gerald mcclellan had severe brain
bleeding and was taken to the hospital
and he's never been the same sense.
Batman nodule ban was a beast man.
They were both beasts.
Gerald mcclellan was a knock out artist
at the time.
Man.
See if you google jeremy mclellan,
kao highlights the.
The thought was that it was going to be
one day joe mcclellen versus Roy Jones
jr.
They were going to have a super fight.
That was like a big,
like one of them pack.
Y'all may weather type fights for that
era.
Wow,
man.
He got hit hard.
Man.
Ain't hard getting hit in the face like
that.
Why do I remember him getting head?
Maybe I'm just completely delusional or
maybe that was somewhere in that mix,
but certainly it was the big bombs from
mcclellan that,
uh,
dropped him in the first round and the
big bombs from nigel benn.
I want to see the first round too
because from I remember it,
it was a crazy comeback because nigel
benn was really hurt and that first
round,
but just showed insane heart and figured
out how to keep going where a lot of
people like this fight is over.
This fight is over.
But you see in those,
uh,
highlight reels.
He was a knockout artist man.
But now he's,
he's in real,
real,
real bad shape.
He's in a wheelchair.
He from that fight.
He,
he went blind.
uh,
he had severe bleeding on his brain and
it never really recovered.
He could have died in the ring.
Oh,
he absolutely could have died.
So here's the first route,
look at this first round,
insane you're going to with nigel benn
falls through the ropes.
Go,
go back a little bit,
go back a little bit so you could see
how fucking insane this.
Go.
Go to the beginning of it.
You see how insane this combination is.
I mean,
mcclellan came out,
guns blazing and hit him with some
serious bombs.
Man,
look at this.
He hit him with a couple of good shot.
They're good,
right hand,
a good lead hook left hook to the body.
So this is the beginning of the fight.
You're thinking,
oh my god,
this is fucking over.
Look at that left hook,
left hook to the body.
Boom,
boom.
I mean mclennan was a destroyer.
Look at this and this is when he's
blasting them through the ropes.
You're like,
holy shit.
This fight is over.
Nigel benn comes back from this to win
like 10 rounds later,
which is insane.
Insane.
Look at them.
I mean clearly he's hurt.
He's kinda wobbly.
But jeremy mclellan just couldn't keep
this up.
Nigel benn survived and came back.
Those are Like mad and tangibles in a
fight.
That's why the best description of
fights is always the theater of the
unknown because you really never know
what the fuck is going to happen.
When did you get these two world class
knuckle slingers throwing fucking
haymakers at each of the slickest
mcclellan.
Oh,
not Japan.
Comes back with a right and he clenches
now.
Mclaughlin starting to get a little
tired,
right?
Knees.
They're given up.
I'm to kinda.
Yeah,
I mean he's gotta think what kind of
output he's putting.
He's trying to win this fight and jail
son and told me something once that's,
uh,
an old boxing,
saying something along the lines of if
you try to stop a fight and win by
knockout but fail,
you almost always lose by decision
because you just blow yourself out so
bad.
Obviously that's not totally the case
because some people have crazy endurance
and they can try to win a fight by
knockout and then recover around later.
But did the amount of output that you do
when you're throwing everything full
blast like mcclellan did in that first
round is insane.
It's like sprinting,
how many punches that up?
First round,
he threw a lot,
but here's the most important thing.
He's throwing a lot of them at full
power.
That's why it's so difficult to
maintain.
What most people don't realize is that
most of the time we see boxers,
boxing,
they're throwing punches fast,
but they're being loose and fluid and
when they heard a fighter,
that's when they expend the most energy
because then they're digging in and
drill and blast and they're winding up.
They don't normally do that,
so the amount of energy that it takes to
wind up and throw your hips in your
fucking ass into it and all you're
waiting to explode at the end.
That's much more than to be just a
technical boxer.
So when they're throwing technical
punches and they're moving fast,
they're.
They're not exerting the same amount of
energy.
See,
when when you're trying to knock
somebody out,
like mcclelland clearly wasn't this
first round.
You are running uphill with a weight
sack on your back and you can only do it
for so long.
So as we go into the second round,
like look,
you see he's already really tired,
so it was as much headshot there.
It was as much his weight cut as it was
his strategy to try to win the first
round as it was nigel ben's ability to
absorb punishment and come back strong
because ben is looking fantastic here in
the second round look at them.
But it was a big wake up call to a lot
of boxers that if you engage in wild
brawls,
even when you were one of the elite of
the elite,
like gerald mcclellan was at the time,
you could still get,
you know,
brain bleeding and be fucked up.
And a lot of people attribute that to
the weight cut because he had a,
he a dehydrate himself quite a bit back
then doing his game plan from his
coaches.
Get this guy out in the first round.
It could be,
but it could be that he heard him and he
figured he could get them out in the
first round.
You know what I mean?
Mcclellan was a killer.
THat was his thing.
If he,
if he hurt you,
he was coming after you.
So what's that?
14 straight knockouts and 10 were in the
first round.
Come on man.
That's what gerald mcclellan did.
So when it didn't work out against a guy
like nigel benn,
nigel benn figured out how to maintain
his energy better in that fight.
That's a,
you know,
that's a dangerous strategy.
Empty all your bullets out in the first
round.
He was just on the fence for the first
three relevant.
But meanwhile,
like the,
that's what was his success formula up
until then.
you know what I mean?
That was,
that was what was working.
You don't know.
It doesn't work until they don't work
anymore.
14th street and I called that way.
Yeah,
I mean do,
do you remember when we used to think
that nobody can beat tyson?
Remember?
Do were little when we were young we
thought,
I think it was like,
when did he lose 86?
did he lose in like 1986 to buster
douglas?
Yeah.
What year was that?
80 nine.
90 google that.
Um,
he moved.
He did it.
What it was.
I was definitely doing comedy at the
time and I definitely saw it with my
friend ron after the fact.
Great.
Eleventh,
19,
90,
1990.
Damn.
So from that point on,
we knew he could lose before that.
Every tyson fight like,
man,
I'm not gonna bother watching.
Why do people want even want to fight
that guy just getting killed.
What were the odds of him when he like
40 to 42 to the one.
Somebody got paid.
Somebody I paid some crazy number.
I think it was 42.
I think it was one of the highest
underdogs ever.
That one.
40 2:42
and he won by knockout.
Buster douglas was fantastic back then,
man.
You fucked him up.
Well dude,
buster douglas is a crazy example of a
guy who always had a tremendous amount
of talent.
He was always regarded as like people
that were in the know and boxing.
I'd heard them talk about him and they
would always talk about how smooth he
was in training and when he's at his
best.
He's literally like a world championship
fighter,
but he never totally put it together in
far as far as discipline and training
camp,
but then his mom died and he decided he
was going to fuck Mike Tyson up for his
mother.
Trained really,
really hard,
so it was a perfect storm of Mike Tyson
being king of the world.
You know,
he's just fucking.
Everybody up doesn't even feel like he
has to train anymore.
He's just just being.
He's just being the world heavyweight
champion.
That's what.
That's what they're like.
The reason why they become that guy in
the first place because they have this
ability to indulge and excess and go
crazy.
He's buying tigers and lamborghinis and
shit and all along the way,
buster douglas fir that fight train like
a demon and still almost lost.
Still almost lost.
That's how good tyson was when tyson was
in his prime is a knockout artist.
He was so lethal that even though buster
douglas and him fought in bus,
doug's eventually wind up knocking him
out.
He knocked him out after Mike Tyson
knocked buster douglas down and had him
hurt and don king after the fight even
protested and said that the,
the count was more than 10 and that when
buster douglas was down,
the referee gave him an extra couple of
seconds to recover that he shouldn't
have had.
I remember that was like a big protest
after the fight,
but even then,
I mean we even with shitty training,
you know,
be not taking this guy seriously at all.
Even then Mike Tyson still knocked
buster douglas down and almost knocked
him out with one punch.
What?
Run tHe locomote.
wasn't douglas the longest,
longest tyson fight ever had,
right?
I know he's had decisions.
He had decisions.
Yeah.
I think he had decision against bone
crusher.
Smith video here as both both knockdowns
simultaneous.
So you can see like the different 10
counts I guess.
Okay.
Let's say it.
Boom.
He clipped him an upper cut,
right?
There's
three,
four,
eight.
These atlanta three on the left.
He's like,
I'm five or six on the right.
Oh,
that's so different.
He was cultivated.
Yeah.
Oh man,
it was the end of the round was the very
end of the round,
so buster got a break.
So look that.
That's just how it go.
Go.
Go to the very beginning again.
Please take a second.
Go at the very beginning again so I
could see the punch right there.
Boom.
Look at that opera.
That's a beautiful uppercut.
Tyson nailed them with two to three.
Four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10.
You're out.
Buster.
Buster there.
No,
he's out.
He's out.
Like do that again.
That seems like he's out right,
doesn't it?
Yeah,
let's try it again.
Ready?
Boom.
He goes down.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10.
he's out.
Someone's distracted him.
A number eight.
Yeah.
Does that stopped the account?
Is that how that works?
As long as a lot of paul's second when
it turns her running away.
Seven,
eight on Mike Tyson here.
There's five,
six,
seven,
eight.
Just like none.
Real quick.
10.
Yeah,
that guy's way quicker.
Is that the same guy?
Oh,
that's ridiculous.
Dude.
You suck at counting in spanish and
other one.
That's a fucking crazy hard job,
man.
You're in the middle of the moment.
You know there's all this hype going on
and pay the fuck out.
Yeah,
but it's the same guy because a,
it's the same fight.
So how,
how does the same guy count?
Real slow for buster douglas and way
faster for Mike Tyson.
A description of the video says this
clearly demonstrates that he gave them
both the exact same amount of time.
Oh really?
That's not what I thought was.
So let's try that again.
Let's try that again.
Let's count for tyson will count for
tyson first.
Ready tyson goes down.
Boom.
What a combination.
Plus two,
3:00,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
You got knocked down a run around 50 on
the,
on the clock.
On the screen.
You can see it in.
How many seconds was it a.
He puts them up at 38 is when he knocks
on the track right there.
Okay.
She's like 13 seconds.
Yeah,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine.
They're both out both out.
Do the counting is definitely slower on
buster douglas with.
They're definitely both out,
but either
way,
if you said seven,
I bet butts in instead of,
you know,
for if you've sped the count up by a
second,
you don't think buster douglas could've
gotten up quicker.
I bet he could have.
I mean he was waiting for the guy to hit
eight so he stands up.
Right.
Which what you do,
you take as much time as you can,
especially after you got legitimately
hurt like that.
You're supposed to do that.
So the question is like,
would he have been able to.
If the guide countered a little quicker
and eight came where seven was or six
was,
would have been able to.
I think he probabLy would have the
questions would have tyson and been able
to get to him with one punch before the
bell that might have knocked him out.
Yeah.
You know.
Okay.
Fight.
You get them back up again and it's
three extra seconds at tyson.
Storms forward and connects with it to
head shots with a faithful dude.
Crazy shots.
There's this guy right here.
Watch the fight glove.
See the official counters?
The fda?
Yes.
This guy that's the finger bro.
He's famous.
His nickname is the finger.
He counts way faster.
watch.
Let's watch the finger.
Two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10.
Oh yeah.
By the fingers count.
That dudes out there both out cold.
I'm going with the finger forever.
Captain white glove.
Michael jackson.
Michael jackson will go with mike
magician.
Yeah,
man,
that's a.
That was an insane fight though because
you couldn't believe Mike Tyson could
lose.
Even when I watched it.
I remember I heard about it first and
then I watched it and they still
remember thinking,
I can't believe what I'm watching.
He's going to get up and he's going to
knock this dude out for sure.
Believe you lost.
It was like,
it's over.
Then you couldn't believe that he could
lose who that's people don't understand
today.
There's never been someone that was as
dominant for as like a scary moment in
boxing history than Mike Tyson because
even though you knew Roy Jones is gonna
fuck up,
whoeveR he found the way he was going to
fuck off,
but he knocked him out with one punch.
It wasn't going to be this horrific
storming by destroyer,
just common after your soul.
Roy jones had box your face off,
hit you with the lead left hooks and
straight right hands that are way faster
than anything you can duck.
He would fuck people up,
but he fucked people up with a certain
style and movement and speed.
Whereas tyson,
which just mugging you at the same time,
it's like all anger,
so fast hood and you end.
He was solid like sledgehammer 220
pounds,
but moved like 160 pound guy like he
couldn't believe it at the time.
They had never been a heavyweight like
him before.
There was heavyweights that that moved
amazing like ali ali had the most
amazing footwork of anybody just smooth
and flowing and change what the game
was.
It was in front of people.
The ropeadope,
this a crazy video of volley that
someone had on their instagram page,
one of those boxing pages where he's
fighting someone and the guy throws two,
three,
four punches in a row and ali's got his
hands down.
I just barely moving his head away with
each punch.
Just like pitch,
you can't hit me.
He just had a.
There was a magic about what he was
doing that you were like,
how is a heavyweight moving like that
tyson jab to tyson was a totally
different kind of strategy,
you know,
and those,
those strategies will be argued to the
end of time.
Like what would have happened if Mike
Tyson had a thought,
muhammad ali,
both in their primes.
What would have happened,
man,
what have happened.
It would have been fucking crazy.
I'll tell you that if we had Mike Tyson
in his very best before shit went
completely crazy.
He started giving out rolls royces.
Two cops walking around with his tiger
in his underwear before all that stuff.
They.
Yeah,
before for sure.
Before bite nears.
The bioneers thing was when amanda was,
you know,
when a van or beat him in that first
fight,
no one could believe it.
No one could believe it.
Even though tyson did last.
Buster douglas,
everybody assumed that tyson last
because he hadn't been training and he
really hadn't been been focused and then
when he went to jail,
came out of jail and he looked jacked
member way more jacked.
Hit a ridiculous six pack.
Remember that shit to another phase son.
Now he got the tattoo on his face
afterwards,
right after jail I think at the tattoo.
On his face.
Angel,
right?
I don't think so.
I think he had mild tattooed on his arm.
What does it say here?
Mike tyson opens up.
Oh,
that was when he got arrested by that
joseph though.
Joe,
our pio guy had to do time in that
Arizona.
He was living in Arizona for a while and
he had to do that.
Joe,
our pio shit,
when they maKe you wear pink,
got handcuffs on and
dude.
Mike Tyson though.
When he was in his prime,
like that was the one he just got out of
jail.
That was the Mike Tyson fresh jelic just
act does 95 first fight after release.
That was against a some unfortunate
white fella that looks like he would be
a.
What was his name?
Peter mcneely.
Yes.
Tough guy.
Just wasn't the video of him talking to
hype up.
The fight is hilarious.
You should go watch it now.
No,
he's hilarious.
He was like a a guy who'd be carrying
the money bag.
He'd be a guy that you'd say bring them
to peter and peter would break your
face.
Hey,
you owe money.
Fuck,
boom.
He was a irish guy.
I remember him.
Give me some volume.
Jim gray,
looking young and dapper for just a
moment.
Before you go out into the ring.
Your thoughts.
Tyson,
my grandfather,
my grandmother,
my father,
my mother,
my three brothers.
Last but not least,
snobby.
Mr mcneely.
what was it that you have told your son?
Huh?
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
It last but not least.
Medfield.
Medfield man.
A guy from medfield.
Dat.
Dat is a guy from beN.
if you've ever been to medfield,
Massachusetts.
No disrespect.
That makes sense.
Fucking fears in the house.
Dorchester.
That's hilarious.
Low tough.
Lowell lowell is a big one.
Man with hardcore micky ward came from
lowell.
I want me and my friend jimmy last.
We saw micky ward box,
somebody,
some famous dude.
I feel like he bought some old,
some old time to it.
Jimmy just told me about this recently
too,
and I forgot what it was,
but we were both like,
couldn't have been more than like 19,
something like that.
We went to see micky ward box was crazy
man.
Going to see live boxing.
So weird because there's no commentary.
Like I'd only seen it at home.
Do you ever see a live boxing match?
It's weird.
It's oddly quiet.
You know?
What does it say greg young that where
he fought in 95,
85.
Oh yeah,
that makes sense.
That's probably exactly it.
That means I was 18.
Yeah,
yup.
Yeah.
Lawrence,
Massachusetts.
He fought.
I guess it was this guy greg young.
Why did I think it was an older guy?
A couple more right here,
I guess in the same spot next year.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
I don't remember any of those names.
Unfortunately.
I erased all that.
Edwin caret.
Hold on when?
When correct.
Go back up.
That was in atlantic city.
Edwin credit is like a old,
old school as first loss.
Tough dude.
Yeah,
he lost a correct crit was a beast.
Micky Ward man.
Those fights with turo,
gadi.
Those are some of the all time,
most exciting and barbaric boxing
matches ever when two dudes are just
that close to each other like that close
skill wise,
like when they go out and just back and
forth and back and forth.
And nobody quits that.
Those fights were insane.
Man.
My dad,
um,
he,
he loved boxing.
He's toured the glove box scene to watch
mexican boxing at the forum,
hastily able every tuesday nights they
used to be these crazy mexican boxer,
but they were all featherweight
lightweight.
There was a guy named rubin olivarez was
lightweight,
pepino cuevas,
and there's this guy who was cuban guy
who will.
Awesome.
Mom.
I'm nepalis mckenna for less or less
what's happening in Mexico.
He fought hearns,
right?
He hit him up.
Hey man,
fuck them up.
but that's true.
That is way too,
man.
Yeah.
My friend does boxing now at um,
uh,
with a bet with duran.
Does the box seat now
and um,
for a golden boy,
no shit.
Yeah,
they are boxing.
Do my friend announces a fights?
Oh,
because they have um,
they have boxing every once in a while
in downtown la at some regular hotel at
a club.
And they have like young boxers.
He says ring set.
And he commented a lot of young incoming
boxers.
No shit man.
Yeah man,
that's a,
that's a crazy gig.
So as he traveled around with tattoos,
he'd go into all these international,
local,
the local ones,
like he does local ones like it when
they fight over there and stand up for
spring casino or more wrong go those
type of fights.
It was a good time right now for boxing.
Oh yeah.
Married.
Very exciting match ups.
a lot of people.
Canelo and triple g.
Whew.
I can't wait for that rematch.
Me too.
I'm performing the day before of where
I'm going to be at the hard rock cafe
the day before the fight.
I don't know.
Friday get there early people,
road trip,
road,
trip,
road trip.
I'll meet you at the way in who?
That is going to be an intense fight.
Man.
That first fight was intense.
I thought triple g one.
I just hold.
Nothing happens between now and the
fight will get injured.
Please don't get injured.
Nobody got injured.
Nobody tests positive.
Nobody hit nobody hitting a wall.
Nobody drive crazy.
Don't do anything stupid.
Jesus christ.
You're dealing with like you going to be
there right time.
Crushers.
What day is that?
I've been november or November 3rd.
I like watching shit at home,
man.
I want to go there.
Too many humans.
You know,
everyone's jammed in.
I have to do that so many times for the
ufc.
You know when I'm not working for the
ufc,
I like to be home watching you watch it
with your friends or loan,
chili.
That bowl.
Sometimes I just want to watch it by
myself,
but a lot of times the only time I'm
watching fights by myself with ufc
fight,
I'm not commenting.
It's because we don't have a fight
companion,
you know?
Like if we're doing.
We do tHese fight companions.
Like if we're home,
it's like a home and shop and eddie
bravo.
We're all home while the ufc is on the
road somewhere.
We'll watch it in here and we'll play it
and we'll talk shit fights going on.
That's fun,
man.
It's the most fun thing of all time.
Of all time.
Eddie bravo.
So he's busting out some ridiculous
conspiracies and crazy jujitsu talk and
then it goes to music.
We might just start with talking about
music for an entire fight and not even
pay attention to the fight.
It's a.
It's a fun gig man.
It's like we're such good friends.
We've known each other for so long that
when we get together is the one that
really fun.
Shamrock the hold,
right?
No.
Gracie.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Right now I'm wearing his dad.
Respect helio gracie.
If it wasn't for this dude,
man.
He's one of the most important people in
the history of martial arts right here.
This gentlemen know that.
That family.
Ooh,
that's a crazy contributing family to
the history of martial arts for sure.
The number one family in the history of
jujitsu,
I mean by and arguably the number one
family in the history of all martial
arts.
I mean,
that's a debate that people will have to
the end of the time,
but that,
that is a,
it's a pretty strong candidate for the
number one most influential family in
the history of martial arts.
Whoa.
Hold on.
How did they get started with that?
Um,
I'll get you started telling me you want
to go.
You tell me when you tell me where.
I'll hook it up for you.
We'll figure out where you don't talk
about where you live on the show because
people show up to training every once in
a while on the road show.
He trains like a motherfucker.
Dude,
joe,
he trains all the time.
It give me three,
four days a week.
He just got his blue bell blue bell
cocks.
Not glocks.
Legit.
And here's,
you have to realize joey diaz gets on
top of you.
You're not getting up.
Okay?
Except tHat he's strong.
Man is not just heavy.
He's a strong guy.
It has mad like booking catcher's mitts.
He's a gorilla.
He's a big old gorilla.
When when I met joey,
joey was only like 220 pounds.
He was a football player.
There's an old school photo of him.
I met him in like somewhere in the late
nineties.
He was like [inaudible],
just like a login enforcer,
like a big british guy,
you know,
he wasn't,
he didn't get that fat at all.
But when he got that fat was also,
when he got that funny,
it was crazy.
Like he just didn't give a fuck anymore
with anything,
with food,
with anything partying.
It became just a monster.
Could so funny.
I remember the first time I saw him
without the laugh factory.
It was late nineties.
Big dude cuban who I know and yet he had
the crazy man just joined karate karate
to revise that is for sure.
For sure.
My all time favorite character.
He had this and they had um,
a member of the dumpster.
Jelly karate though is the best karate
today.
You understand me here for the ufc
minute.
A lot of people see me in a medical
marijuana reports while people see me in
the sports reports,
but nobody really knows.
I'm a trained fucking assassin of cuban
black belt.
I lost my rank on the fucking boat ride
over green gumballs in China with
shanghai Hong Kong,
Bolivia.
That's who I trained with fucking
savages that these little fucking guys
flying through the air.
But you're lucky you caught me because
joy karate's and they give you a lock
for ufc and it's all about fucking
Brazil.
This week,
weekend,
he understand me.
My man picks it isn't a fuck people up
this weekend.
You understand me?
He went through.
He went through forest whitaker,
forest griffin.
this motherfucker,
first off,
that's a moon pie.
Shit.
You understand,
but not really a restaurant.
I'm fucking guy with a couple of needs
to the fucking head up on a psychic you
gentlemen to some fucking samurai or
some arm bar.
Choke them up.
It's that simple.
That's anderson silver.
You understand what any of those
traditional baby.
Don't forget ufc.
Catch me next week what?
All my otHer things that stand me next
week,
we're going cover stretching and flying
through the air.
Thank you.
Perfect music
to whoever did the music.
Nailed it.
That's a little way from now.
From then to now.
Oh yeah man.
A lot of weight.
He's a.
Is he a spokesperson for weight
watchers?
Is.
THat's what he's doing.
Is he really think he is?
I think he's doing something for
weightwatchers.
Julia.
Yeah.
Joey is he.
He likes weightwatchers.
He,
that's how he lost all his weight when
you lost the first time.
and then he's losing it this time.
It's used in that way too.
he said they,
they're catching up,
man.
They've got good science behind their
food.
But even they do.
They say you could have as many eggs as
you want.
You can have eggs.
Eggs are bad for you,
bro.
Choice.
So funny memory.
When he came here to the one bit about,
um,
he said,
I went to a do a show at the one in the
hotel,
had a bed you put a quarter in and a
finger comes up,
pulls in a frequent called joe.
So it goes in your ass.
I went through last week was let's do a
show two years ago.
The whole place is run down,
man.
The machine's broken.
You got to put your finger.
He was in the house.
How long have you been doing stand up
now?
Twenty years.
I started in 1996.
Late 95.
I prefer natural cafe and on melrose?
No,
on.
Yeah.
Melrose.
You one last comic standing.
One last comic standing.
How many people?
One that how many?
Uh,
how many different seasons they have
that I want to see them?
Seven and 10 now.
You know,
was fun.
Joe,
when I won my son's mom filed for child
support the next day and she just took
half.
She became the last baby mama standing
straight up dog bucket bitch that you
took the class.
I had kids with no one other than high
school.
And then there a penal child support in.
Oh well I could see your point.
We broke even,
you know.
Yeah.
You definitely owed some money though,
right?
Yeah.
No,
it's crazy.
When,
um,
when we were on last comic standing,
they do like a background check of
everybody.
Yeah.
And I noticed like some people were
slowly disappearing,
you know,
from the last comic standing because
that background check criminal records.
Some people were taken out of the photo,
like they were put in positions.
But you will take the photos.
My brother,
he committed a lot of crimes and he,
he,
um,
I didn't know it then he stole my
identity.
Oh no,
it was nbc investigated a couple notes
here man.
I see two files on your own to open
cases on you.
One of them for possessions of crack
cocaine,
possession of sale,
fader to go to court.
This is your brother's also gay noise.
Have another brother who's not gay.
He's a,
he's a criminal.
He's the one that came.
That was one that keeps coming out of
prison or worse.
Oh,
that one.
So,
okay.
My brother,
he liked the ultimate criminal.
He's not on facebook.
He's not on.
No social media.
You can't find him anywhere.
There's no photo anywhere.
So I had to track down his daughter on
facebook and said,
man,
is there a picture of you and your dad
somewhere?
ANd she sends me the photo of my brother
and then they do the comparisons of me
and him and they let me go.
That's hilarious.
That is hilarious.
They have photos of him like committing
crimes.
Like yesterday,
camera photo,
hearing court when everybody got
arrested for leap as far as uh,
my brother knows my birth certificate.
He know my birthday and he knows my
name.
So what an asshole shit,
bro.
My other brother,
the gay one,
your own brother out and shit.
And my,
my other brother,
the gay one,
he got pulled over for a traffic
violation and saves your name to my
brother.
My brother used his name and my brother
was,
was um,
they,
they put him in a prison in Arizona for
illegal immigrants also.
Your brother use both of your.
Yes.
Oh my god.
So my brother,
my gay brother fernando was on his way
to prison in Arizona for a crime he
didn't commit.
Oh no.
Luckily for him,
when he was locked up,
a guy that was with me in rehab knew me
and he,
he,
um,
my brother and him were friends and he
and my brothers back in prison a few
days.
Can you imagine going to jail because
your brother's a piece of shit and he
used your name to commit crimes.
How fucking mad you stole my identity in
prison knowing that this motherfucker
risky or your freedom just so that he
could get out.
He's like,
fuck cam,
cam.
you don't call me anymore.
I'm fucking social security number.
I know his name.
I know his birthdate.
I know her heart,
her heart.
I'll here.
That's so crazy.
What a psycho.
Damn man.
You can't pick your family problem.
Problem for some folks,
right?
You can't pick your family man.
Like anybody who thinks that there's a,
hey,
you fucking get what you deserve in this
world.
Bullshit.
Little babies are born in a fucked up
families.
You know,
sometimes your brother is a piece of
shit.
He's a piece of shit before you're even
born.
You didn't even know.
And you're born Later and he's just
ready to dominate you and be a fucking
asshole to you.
And you're like,
what?
You know?
That's what happened with gangs.
Con games.
Con became games con like later in his
life.
But when he was younger,
he killed his brother because his
brother was stealing fish.
They would go fishing,
his brother would take his fish.
He was like,
oh,
for real.
So he got with his other brother
and they fucking ambushed their older
brother and killed him with a bow and
arrow killed his brother.
What did dad say?
Mom was really pissed.
Shouldn't let dad's deal.
He shouldn't have let a my brother steal
my fish.
Fucking lock key parents latch key.
What does it?
Let's imagine that I'm in killing your
brother with a bow and arrow.
life was cheap back then or choking him
to death.
Jesus christ
or choking him to death because the mob
or whatever you're associated with,
your brother got to go.
So you don't know where your brother is
now?
My brother probably is somewhere running
around in Mexico.
Living in tj?
Yeah.
does he ever come back?
No,
no,
he lived in lower there.
Um,
he,
he works at some pick apart area over
there.
Pick apart.
He had like a pickup part.
You go there for parts for your car.
Stolen car park.
No,
it's illegal.
But you go in there.
He told my brother,
I'm looking for a,
for a door for us.
Seventy nine toyota and my brother go,
yeah,
you're going to go over there.
Junkyards junkyard.
Yeah.
Yeah,
man.
I know dudes who built cars.
They would,
they would go to junk yards.
Like,
ah,
I gotta get this fender are going to get
a good fan of her [inaudible] 70
chevelle.
I go and look.
And that's kind of fun.
You know,
if I had 100 lives,
one of the things I do is build cars.
I think that'd be the coolest shit in
the world.
You know,
I envy the fuck out of people who have
done that or have the time.
Yeah,
that's the thing is at the time.
But people who have learned how to do it
and get a frame and figure out how to
get the frame all sandblasted and powder
coated and then figuring out how to put
the suspension on and fenders and to
really take a car apart and restore it
and restore it and have it looked
beautiful.
Then drive around in it.
You see those guys that do that and go,
wow,
that's an admirable quality.
There's like,
that's like something very few men,
whatever do.
But every man admires him,
man,
and could do it.
Like,
oh,
me and my brother,
we restored this 1969 camaro.
I remember I read that matt hughes did
that.
Matt hughes,
who was also at the tIme ufc
welterweight world champion also
restored classic cars.
That's a man.
That's a fucking man.
Like if you take it,
you could rebuild a car and then get it
to the point where you did that.
That's a.
That's a manly activity right there to
life.
that's one of the most manly things you
can do.
Rebuild a car.
Guys would work on their own cars.
That's a rare breed son.
My that always worked on his car,
man.
He never went to the mechanic.
Yeah,
he will go out.
He'd be up there like changing the spark
plugs out of the 73 impala by himself in
the rain
dude,
changing them to.
He be out there In the parking lot,
man.
Like all over like team his own stuff to
take the motor out of the car
and put a new motor in and put it all in
different kinds of man.
And I'm in like in my,
like elaine,
like most dads would invite you a
flipper career.
Help me out.
My dad,
they want to know help.
the first time I tried to help you know
what?
Go peel your fucking toys.
You just pet me the wrong ranch hassle.
Oh,
judgmental daddy thing is to like date.
They get locked into that.
They don't want you to distract them.
That's the word they're escaping
escaping by working on this car and
wrenching things down.
Change,
carburetors and shit.
And those guys who could do that.
That's a special type of guy.
There's like this,
a special mechanic man,
like,
you know,
um,
a guy could do it because we're,
when you invite those guys to get
together.
Yeah,
they always look dirty.
He clean.
Like,
even even if you bring your,
your,
your invite,
you're cool mechanic for the
neighborhood to a party and you're
wearing a tux,
you'd be like,
damn,
there goes joel.
He still looked dirty.
Oh,
he's got crazy fingernail dirt grease
under their fingernails.
It just never comes out.
You don't recognize him standing up.
Hey,
here's a question.
How many,
how many people get sick from working in
gas stations?
I would think that like working in a gas
station,
all those fumes,
like,
that shit's got to be terrible for you.
Fumes and then all the grease and oil
and smashing your fingers and stuff.
Oh,
that's the worst.
Whereas guys are always smashing their
fingers and losing tips.
Taping them.
Fuck man.
They know the kid.
They used to be a guy that used to fix,
you know,
the toys of guy that in the neighborhood
that don't have to fix everybody's car.
Right,
right,
right.
And it was a guy named eli and they'll
come with,
they were a big family.
There were like nine or 10 people in
their family,
but this guy will fix your car.
But he also likes to party,
like party hard joe,
like,
like.
But he was the star,
but he was a volkswagen genius.
Oh,
bugs.
Bugs were his thing.
But he also was a main drug addict.
This is my friend juni.
He was getting his bug fixed from him.
He had a rag.
Top was the oval bag with beautiful bug.
This guy,
eli man smoked pcp.
Oh no.
He just holding him,
holding the wrenches and staring at the
bug for like three hours straight.
Not doing shit.
Wow.
Volkswagen.
A different kind of car,
man.
I could bug you.
Drive a bug.
that's a different kind of human.
You got to be a bug.
Guys would know how to fix a bug.
My friend jimmy,
that same friend that I went to,
the boxing match to see mickey word
fight.
He also had a bug hit,
a blue bug.
It was the most ridiculous car.
I remember being in it like we were
laughing how silly it was because it was
so,
uh,
he love cars,
right?
Oh,
love.
Cause I remember,
I remember,
um,
you and eddie griffin in the same car
and his was dead.
two years
was clean.
Well his arms was cool man.
You will come into a man like the
fucking,
like the cleaner in shit like harvey chi
town.
And I was like,
you know what I mean,
she gave me one of those,
what they cars are fast dude.
It wasn't the fastest car.
She looked cool.
Well here's the thing about those cars,
man.
They were really well balanced.
Like it was a good amount of power for
the size of it.
It was a very light car.
Like I want to say like the acura nsx
wasn't even 3000 pounds.
That Was it.
I had a silver one.
Ferrari.
Somebody bought mine,
you don't know at two silver,
one with the wolf had a silver one in
like the late nineties.
And then I had a silver one and the
early two thousands.
That's my.
That's it right there.
That was my car.
That's It right there,
so somebody owns it.
Somebody bought it because I think I
traded it in when I got something else,
but it was a joe rogan.
Thanks for modeling it to perfection.
That guy's got it.
That's my car to this day.
That was one of my all time favorite
cars.
Definitely not the fastest car ever
drove,
but it wasn't about being fast.
It was about like the experience of
driving.
It was More real.
Tactile.
It's a very light car and it's a mid
engine car seats with low right bucket
sEats and it's a japanese car.
It's a honda so you know it's never
going to break.
I never had a problem with those.
Like I had two of them.
I had one,
I had it for like three years when I
traded it in and then I got this other
one later,
but in between I had a porsche and that
shit broke down constantly.
I had a 99,
19 or nine,
nine,
six turbo,
which is like two thouSand two.
That shit broke constantly.
It just kept breaking man.
All kinds of crazy shit.
Like the shift,
linkage blue,
two separate times where I would go to
shift gears and it just disengaged and
was floating around on two separate
occasions that happened where I couldn't
shift gears and I was stuck one time.
Luckily it happened while I was driving
down the road,
so it was driving down the road and it
popped loose and I was in second gear.
I said,
okay,
I'm going to wind this bitch out and get
to the porsche dealership.
So I kept in second gear,
just drove around and second gear
through the streets,
like near ventura.
Ridiculous.
They just weren't,
they weren't durable bathroom.
That porch.
That's the new one.
So no,
I wasn't.
I wasn't really into driving fast.
What I'm,
what I like is a car that corners really
well,
you know,
I like a car like that.
Just it has a connection to the road,
dude.
Look at that thing.
That's the new nsx.
That shit looks preposterous.
That's a preposterous looking vehicle
like knight rider.
yeah.
With.
The only problem I have with this car is
the problem I have with all these cars,
they won't let you,
uh,
use a manual transmission.
They don't sell them with a manual
transmission.
The problem with that is,
come on man,
we're not racing like I want.
I want it to feel good.
Like if it feels people need to remember
how much better it feels to drive a
manual transmission.
everybody wants to not learn.
And since a lot of people don't know,
I never learned that's the problem
because they don't want to stall out and
look like an asshole.
That's too much work.
Once you learn how to Drive,
he's still stalled out.
I stall out occasionally.
But the fund that you have with a car
like that with a manual transmission is
so different.
So you're engaged,
you're shifting things first.
Man,
there's something cool about that.
And for whatever reason,
people are forgetting that it's a
totally different experience.
when you drive a car that has a manual
transmission versus a car that's not a
magnet.
more control,
right?
Well,
not really.
Honestly,
you're better off with the automatic if
you want to be totally honest.
The automatic is going to go faster.
It's going to have a better choice of
gear selection than you are.
It's going to like like a lot of times
when these race car drivers to take like
an automatic porsche,
like one of the new ones,
they take it on track.
They don't even take it out of
automatic.
They don't shift the gears themselves.
If it's a double clutch gearbox,
they put it in drive and they just go
because things are so good at picking
the right gear.
Why fuck around,
so it's better that way really is
better.
You have more control of the car that
way,
but that's not necessarily what makes it
the most fun than what makes the most
fun is you're engaged in the car,
you're shifting the gears,
but smooth car.
Yeah.
Quiet.
He could learn how to drive a stick.
It's not hard.
I did it one time.
This guy taught me in rehab.
Huddah hood drivers take shifts.
We're going downhill though.
Oh well that's ridiculous.
Uphill and it was the worst,
the top of los anica you get to the top
of laci and you're right when you get
the sunset,
it's like a super steep hill.
You've got to have an outbreak,
and the new ones they don't have.
He breaks the new ones have a bullshit
button,
e-brake,
so you'd have a handle that you just
lift up and lift down those nonsense.
Fix that.
Like that's the whole deal.
If you're stuck in,
unlike san francisco street,
oh my god,
and need a red light and you got to go
forward and in a stick shift.
That shit isn't heart attack inducing.
I'm always afraid of rolling back on
that car.
Of course,
yeah,
you have to have an emergency brake and
it's hard to do when you're a young kid
and you're learning how to drive one and
you want a crazy steep hill at the top
of the hill.
There's a stopLight like,
oh no,
that's designed for automatic cars.
If you have a stick shift,
that's a fucking pain in the ass,
man.
I can't even read a motorcycle.
Motorcycle stall out too,
right?
Same way.
So most motorcycle guys would probably
be able to transition to a stick.
Pretty easy,
pretty simple.
Being a neutral.
Yeah,
I don't.
I never wrote him a motorcycle.
It took some classes for a little bit.
But then while I was taking classes,
a couple of people I knew wiped out
pretty bad.
I was like,
fuck this,
this is too dangerous.
Ceo wrote a mini bike one time.
And um,
where were they in san jose?
This comedian named butch.
He let me ride it.
Many bucks.
Cool.
Someone without too much power.
It's cool.
It's when you get into
these like high abuses,
you know,
you could just go and buy something that
goes zero to 60 in a second.
The fuck is that.
You can just sell that to somebody.
You.
All you have to do is get a license.
You get a license.
And the dingo by the most insane two
wheeled vehicle of the world could have
ever.
You couldn't even imagine something like
this existing 100 years ago,
like 100 years ago,
if you went back to what,
19,
18 and somebody got a higher boost and
brought it to you.
He be lIke,
what the fuck is this?
What is this that the rocket?
Yeah,
this is.
This doesn't even make sense.
People would try it and go flying off of
it.
We would do wheelies and fall on top of
them.
They'd be like,
what in the fuck is this?
What are you doing with this thing?
And then someone could show it.
Someone who knows how to ride some real
motorcycle race car driver guy,
evil knievel.
now like one of those guys that does
this aisle of.
What's that irish?
Is it isle of man?
What does that irish.
A crazy race.
They do where these people are.
They're goIng so in sanely fast and it
looks like they're going through the
woods and shit.
I can do this.
Is that it is isle of man?
Yeah.
Why is there a car there in front?
Is the car for the cars driving with
them?
Oh,
that guy just wiped out right there,
son.
Or these people that are driving
when it's not the race.
This might just be your normal time.
There might be doing their own race or
something.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Maybe so.
I think so.
Hey,
this is the actual race.
This is the isle of man race and I don't
think they allow cars on the road while
they have the race.
But do these guys go fast as shit?
It's crazy.
They take hills and they're flying
through the air when they hit the hill.
So I look at that.
Fuck bro.
What is this like a fast.
He's going 171 miles an hour right
there.
Yup.
And people to the left and to the right.
That is so insane.
Bikes are so insane.
And the fact that,
you know,
this is a fairly new thing in human
history.
I mean this is new.
Within the last hundred years we had
anything that you could do that with
this speed that they could do it with.
now it's just fucking crazy man.
Like your,
your moment where you have to make a
decision.
like if something jumps out in front of
you,
how much time do you have be?
I'm still waiting for the jet pack.
Could look.
People are fucking stupid that someone
wouldn't want to just go,
I'm going to run when he comes by,
as soon as I see them,
I'm going to run and I'm going to get
out of the work and then he tries to
correct for you and wipes out there.
Watch.
Yeah.
It's like he was doing a wheelie before
he could even get off.
God this was that.
You
have to be so tuned in like I don't
think we could even imagine how
heightened your senses have to be to be
able to stay on top of this where
there's cars to the left and right and
from you that alert man trees and shit.
His trees everywhere.
These guys are animals.
Look at him.
Fly over the top like that.
Fuck.
That is so bananas.
That is.
We watched them in.
There's a video in real time with them
all going over this hill.
Yeah.
It's like that.
Like zoom.
You really get a sense of it right there
when you're.
When you're riding in the pov there pov,
you get a little bit of a sense of it,
but you really get a sense of it when
you watch them pass by stationary
cameras.
What else?
These guYs are.
My cousins sort of like this.
I know they like crazy people that
pilots,
fighter pilots,
guys that go.
There are risk taken fools man,
and again,
this is just like what we were talking
about,
what those strong men dudes.
These are the peOple that are.
They're hard Wired to do incredibly
dangerous things and I guarantee you
these same people that are hardwired to
do these kinds of dangerous,
risky things.
They would be like special forces
operators.
They would be navy seals.
They would be either.
They would be people that are most
scenarios,
yeah.
They can do things that other people
probably don't have the nerves for and
they're thrill seekers like,
but then you could take a thrIll seeker
that maybe would have joined the
military and put a meal on a bike or put
them In an mma cage or put them in a
boxing ring and you get that same type
of person like that.
Those people all exist because you
needed those traits.
You needed those traits in order to be
successful,
to keep your civilization alive,
needed big,
strong,
murderous people.
You need people that were crazy and
weren't afraid of danger.
You need a risk takers.
You need to reward seekers.
You needed people who wanted to be the
king and if you didn't have that,
you weren't going to survive because
there's other people that had that on
the other side.
That's what's crazy is we're figuring
out how to filter that shit into sports
now and all sorts of other aspects of
life,
but it's these same instincts that have
been around for hundreds of thousands of
years that have turned people into what
they are right now.
Fuck man.
It's a trip really as a trip when you
think about people,
just people in general,
like what?
The paths that people take to become who
they are right now to be this guy on a
jet pack going 100 miles an hour down a
street.
How fast is he going?
Delivery.
We'd very,
very fast.
Very fast,
right?
Yeah.
He's flying.
Jesus christ.
This is one,
but this is not.
I don't think the fastest one.
This one,
it looks like a halo of jets around
them,
but there's another guy that has one
that are on his arms like,
like iron man.
This is pretty new to.
This was like the earlier this month.
You know they're going to get it.
If batteries get any better,
god would festival of speed.
Yeah,
they're gonna get it.
They're going to figure it out.
We're going to get hummingbird,
bro.
That's what it's going to be.
His have some shit.
Well,
it's like,
well,
you're goIng to buy some cheap ones.
You know some from genki ones from
overseas and the hummingbird wings going
to break off and hit in the fucking
head.
There'll be people to in delta knockoffs
wings.
Yeah.
And then it would definitely be trippers
that would put like glowing lights on
them that would cause people to have
seizures.
You know,
like for sure like burning man style
lights over your hummingbird wings.
That would be amazing.
Come on.
There'll be one of the coolest things of
all time.
Burning man hummingbird.
Glowing flashing light wings.
That'd be bad ass.
Yeah,
man.
Burning man.
This artist wants to cover burning man
in a massive nasa engineered blanket.
It's like 10,000
square or it.
Sorry,
100 square meters.
For what to trip?
Fall.
What would happen?
It's supposed to reflect 97 percent of
the heat that would normally stay down
there.
So they're going to do a portion of it.
I don't know if they're going to take.
Obviously can't cover that.
It's funny,
I was just reading about this.
They tell you to take one of those space
blankets with you.
If you're going hiking in the woods,
I'll give you go on a camping trip.
And um,
you know,
you have like some survival stuff,
a survival kit.
One of the things they say is to get one
of those because you build a fire and
then you get under the blanket in the
fire and the fire reflects off the
blanket and it makes a big impact on the
amount of heat it gives off and they
think like for survival purposes,
it's a good move to have.
Where did I,
where did I hear that?
About a think I heard that on a podcast
trying to figure out which podcast it
was.
I'll try to remember.
But the um,
those little tiny blankets,
they don't weigh anything either.
So it's like a smart thing for people to
carry around with,
through the qbr.
Warm supposedly never seen one warmer,
but they're really good apparently for
a,
for reflecting heat.
Like they can keep your body heat in,
you know,
and,
and pretty effective compared to their
size and weight,
just like we're legit when they wrap
people around the chipotle burritos to
go.
I know they do.
Looks like there's nothing to it,
but maybe that's why chipotle,
he uses those wraps.
I got food.
Poison that you pull it twice.
You think you did in dc,
how do you know?
That's exactly where he got the food
poisoning of the last thing I ate.
right.
And then how much time did it take
between eating and you're getting food
poisoning?
One hour,
one hour,
but I felt like I felt like getting hot.
Then I just threw up.
And before that,
um,
one hour.
What did you eat?
Did you eat anything else earlier?
Okay.
It was,
it was the plane eight hours before the
food poisoning kicked in.
I don't know,
maybe three,
three.
The fly with hours.
I know that that's what I think most
experts have never talked to.
Food poisoning expert.
I don't want to bullshit you because I
think most people will say that it's
more likely that it was the food that
was on the plane that got you.
Why didn't you get in a plane?
Oh,
he didn't,
you know,
latin fireproof,
cloud.
You're nuts.
You might have gotten it from nuts.
You sure it was food poisoning and not
just like stomach flu.
I don't know man,
but it was bad for like three days.
I lost 14 pounds,
you know,
whenever people say I got food poisoning
from this,
I always go.
You might have,
but I mean people don't know how long it
takes to get food poisoning.
It'S a little chicken.
it was chicken.
You think?
How many,
how many hours does it take before food
wasn't chose that one to three.
One,
two,
three.
Oh,
maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe one of the cerner had dirty hands.
Maybe they used to think it was longer.
Did they used to think it was longer?
Because I used to hear that it was like
eight hours.
I thought you had to wait for it to
digest,
but you Can eat something.
That makes sense.
Then probably wester polar then.
But I would say if you had eaten three
hours earlier and then right after she
went.
Well,
if they're saying one,
two,
three,
one is one.
Depends what it is,
I suppose to roast chicken or clothing.
That's scary.
People get that from salad.
Yeah.
Run off man's runoff from the animal
areas.
Animal shit essentially.
Right?
A lot of times when they have these,
um,
these farms,
you'll get it rains and there's a lot of
runoff and the runoff is carrying cow
shit and pig shit and it's getting into
the ground and it's getting onto plants
and if they don't adequately wash these
plants and you get them and you eat them
raw,
you can definitely get sick.
See what google that eco lie.
What is the cause of eco lie in
vegetables?
I'm preTty sure that's the reason
sometimes when you,
when you want to drive to,
like when I do show them by salary or
bakersfield on the right hand side,
you know,
you pass by um,
these cows.
Yeah.
And then there's a lake and I always
thought that was water,
but it was brought off a lake and lake.
The whole lake full of culture just
didn't do that.
so dark.
there's a lake,
fill a pig,
shit outside this one pig farm on of
those factory farms that where they have
these warehouses filled with pigs and
they flew over with a drone to get
footage of it.
And you see This putrid disgusting body
of water.
That's just shit and piss and mean.
It's massive.
I mean it's like a lake that you would
think that you'd go fishing in the end.
Where are we going to put all that
stuff?
I don't know,
man.
It's going to go into the ground.
They're not supposed to do that.
You know this.
this thing of figuring out how to make
the most amount of money with having the
least amount of concerns for the life of
the animal is the total wrong way to
look at it.
It's just.
But when you're feeding 20 million
people and none of those people were
aware of where their food comes,
people start making based on money and
profit and then you get to this point
where someone allows them to where we
don't agree on what should and shouldn't
be done or we don't agree on what we
should and shouldn't have force in
force,
and then we get to this place where you
have these buildings that are filled
with pigs and you've got a lake of piss
and shit behind it and these things are
jammed,
these cages and they got a dead babies
on the ground and you're like,
okay,
what's that?
That seems like hell like you've.
You've created hell so that you can make
bacon like that.
That is a.
That's crazy.
That's a crazy way of contracting or
getting your food,
but bacon tastes so good.
I know ecolab is a large group of
bacteria with multiple strains,
most of which are harmless and part of
the normal flora of bacteria in the
digestive tract.
HarmfuL strains of ecolab produced
something called shiga toxin,
which can be deadly.
The strain an under cooked ground beef,
it's infected people through the
consumption of undercooked ground beef
some,
so it's a,
it's a toxin than exists in cattle.
Okay.
here it goes this time.
However,
the toxic strain of ecolab has been
found on romaine lettuce,
which likely became contaminated from
nearby cattle manure.
So yeah,
that's what It is,
is the recent outbreak and yeah,
it's.
I think it's happened before that I read
about it as well with the other stuff.
I think it was spinach.
I think they had an issue with spinach
in the past,
which was getting hoever when the,
when the news came out,
joe the other lower watching smith
perform and he had a spirit as job it
was,
but it was hilarious to us.
He said,
I'm spinach.
It,
um,
there's a,
the,
the thing of spanish.
And then he said it was a good time to
beat up popeye.
That's a typical phrase.
He's so silly.
He's a funny dude either,
buddy.
He's so silly.
Very nice guy though,
isn't he?
Yeah,
he's very nice guy.
Funny dude though,
that like that kind of joke.
Like,
wow.
No,
it's a good time to beat up popeye guys.
Yeah.
Um,
but that's not from the vegetables
themselves.
That's the thing like that,
those kinds of diseases or from their
environmental toxins from the nearby
stuff.
So the letter was grown.
It grew with equally in it on it,
it caught on it somehow.
The cattle manure.
So even washing that letter is you
couldn't not take it out.
Well,
thank you.
Can I think you can.
I think if you washed lettuce you can
take it out,
but if you cook it you much more likely
to kill it.
Like for broccoli and stuff like that,
you're much more likely to be able to
kill it.
You know,
kale stir fried kale.
But the crazy thing is like had that
happened in the first place,
like was that a normal thing that would
have happened on a regular farm?
Like if you just,
if you just had a farm that wasn't a
factory farm is just let the animals
roam around just be themselves.
Would that have happened?
Is it still possible?
Or is it only happened when you can
contain a certain amount of animals?
In a certain area,
and then also try to grow vegetables in
that same area too.
I mean,
I'm sure people got eco lie back in the
day.
I'm sure it's not a new thing that
people get sick from guest.
They didn't clean it well enough,
but the way they're doing it,
it's probably before refrigerators for
sure.
They probably got it right.
Yeah,
they must've got it like crazy.
I bet people got food poisoning left and
right before refrigerators.
Oh yeah man.
Oh,
before always had diarrhea before.
I know right before they was telling
you,
um,
come to our restaurant,
our shift washing his hands.
Do you ever catch your dog eating some
in the backyard and you're like,
oh,
well for short it's going to be sick
now.
Meanwhile,
nothing dead rat.
They can find a dead rat.
And you catch them chewing on a dead rat
and you're like,
what the fuck dude?
I thought we were friends while you
eating a dead rat.
Man,
that's so stupid.
Getting the house.
We've got nice next and sell the house,
you know.
And I'm thinking,
man,
he's going to be sick.
He had a rat,
nothing,
zero problems.
Ate steak.
One time I left in my car overnight.
didn't know us can be a great lunch.
All these tips.
It was so good eating it too,
and I was sick for like three days.
Oh,
so bad.
Bad lesson learned.
Did you try to reheat in the microwave?
Yeah,
I put it in a skillet to a thing.
I was working at a restaurant.
No,
we made all the time.
So you knew they probably had to cook it
again and you thought it would be fine?
Yeah,
I thought it was.
I thought it was in the clear.
I in like seven day old kfc,
but it was the refrigerator.
I don't even cook it.
Did that get you?
It was good.
No.
No kid would see cold rocks.
My favorite kfc is kfc.
Cold with hot sauce.
Like les hecka habanero sauce.
That green ship matea doesn't have the
kind of kick though a that need more.
I need more.
It doesn't have the cake.
The spice,
but not the real big kick.
Like although like dave's hot sauce,
maybe that's too much.
There's a line,
we're like,
what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Fucking,
you know,
do you want to stunt like why are you
eating that?
You have doritos are good though.
They're very good.
But I mean there's like a habanero,
so there's a level of hot.
How about middle of the fucking hot
though?
How many arrows?
How the fuck it's hot enough so I'm as
fuck like that.
You could tech.
oh shit.
There's a lot of good habanero sauces.
lot.
a lot of good ones.
But the habanero sauce on cold chicken.
Woo.
god,
that's good.
Does your favorite terrible chicken?
No chance?
No.
Uh,
I don't.
I mean I try not to eat it unless I have
to from starving and that's all it's
available.
But most of the time I think,
man,
how are they getting these chickens?
These are those tortured chickens.
They live in those boxes.
Yeah.
These tickets.
I have bigger breasts.
But then you pass by chick fil a and
you're like,
what's the line about?
What's the bonds of line?
So big.
must be delicious.
Oh,
I could taste a bond in the mayonnaise
chicken.
Sweet,
sweet,
juicy,
warm chicken.
I used to fuck with a little chicken.
Littles from kfc,
a little dollar sandwiches.
The thing is,
man,
what you know what happened to get that
chicken sandwich in your hand?
If you get a video,
if they give you a little fucking every
every chicken sandwich you put chicken
sandwich you,
it comes to the documented life of,
of the chicken,
you know you could get a number like,
oh,
this,
this number two,
one six,
and you go to the website and you can
access the video of the chicken living
from the tower to baby check.
So time it's grown up.
Check and a dude will fucking gloved
hand grabs this fucker.
Stuffs them in a cage and feed them and
it gets bigger and he's stuck in this
cage and they'd take them out,
whack his fucking head off,
throw them into the furnace to blow off
all his feathers,
pull the guts out of them,
cook them at kfc.
If you could see all that,
if you saw it from start to finish,
you'd be like,
what are the italian homeless doing
here?
They're going to tell you how much water
was used to food to feed this guy.
Well,
we need more water.
Yeah,
for sure.
But that doesn't disturb me as much as
like the life of a pig that lives in a
cage that's in a warehouse filled with
cages.
That's created a river of shit right
next to a swimming.
I like wild animals,
man.
I liked the way they taste.
I like the idea behind it was that most
days like it tastes good.
Tastes delicious.
Burgers.
At one time in beer,
my uncle would cook.
He would come and he will make it like
carne asada,
poor whatever.
Sausages.
And um,
it was good.
A lot of people saw a lot of americans
go to Mexico to deer hunt the evidence.
Another big deer hunting.
Yeah.
Um,
what is there?
There's another place where it starts
with an s.
So nora,
so nora.
So nora has a lot of big deer there.
People go there to hunt deer.
Scared as fuck.
They're scared.
Who going to Mexico?
We're going to get me,
get me while I'm over here.
It's weird,
man.
They hunt deer over there.
And turn them into tacos.
Does it all wild ranging a free ranging
a herd of buffalo in Mexico to really.
Yeah,
the most.
The shutter movie there one time and
brought in buffalo.
Then they left them there.
I wonder because I've helped buffalo's
buffalo's then.
So catalina island or I don't know
where.
Catalina,
right?
Yeah.
They asked.
Well how to get there while they shot a
movie.
Was that he brought in her buffalo.
They left them there.
Oh,
that's interesting.
They used to be an island like one of
those islands off the coast of
California that had all kinds of wild
animals that people brought all these
animals over there to try to turn into a
wild game park.
They had like deer and elk and all kinds
of shit.
Roman runs one island and then the
biologist said,
yeah,
enough of that,
like,
this is crazy.
You've got to tie.
ALl these things are breeding.
there's no predators.
Like this is eco disaster.
Then human beings have created.
So the store that I had heard was that
they decided to gun them all down.
I want to find out fast,
true jamie funnel.
If that's true,
channel islands,
is that what it was?
Channel islands.
It's one of those.
I did a show at a military gigging and
one of the islands.
St nicholas island.
Oh yeah.
You were telling me about this.
Yeah.
You told me about this awhile ago,
right?
Yeah,
it was,
uh,
it was a,
it was like a,
they do they do the test nuclear weapons
there in the ocean?
Yeah.
And um,
it was just,
it was just a quick gig at a bar and it
was crazy because the show ended at 10
and against the bar closes at 11,
but like five minutes before the bar
close,
10 military police came in and make sure
it's close.
Wow.
And then we left that one.
they say we're leaving at five in the
morning.
They're leaving at five in the morning.
There was no lagging.
Like I was running late that they almost
left without me.
Oh shit.
This was five in the morning.
We're supposed to get off your face and
head to your flight.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
you can't fuck around their son.
We did some.
Ufc isn't military military basis.
We did quite a few of them there,
you know,
did the one down in san diego we've
done,
um,
in Texas,
denim in North Carolina,
I believe denim,
a lot of different places,
but they get super enthusiastic man
fights on the basis and they would be
on.
I think they did it on spike tv.
I think there Was on spike at the time,
but a heavy shit man,
it's interesting.
Really interesting.
Might've did it on fox two maybe on fs
one,
uh,
one of those.
Fox sports channels.
Maybe fox sports one,
but it's not like nothing else man.
when especially with military guys
fight.
If one of the guys is Like a one time
tim kennedy was fighting and he's
fighting a hot towel who's a real world
class fighter.
Real tough fight.
And tim kennedy caught him with a left
hook,
just boom drops and with this left hook
and then he's on top of the cage and
they're cheering amendment.
I mean the we had gone to the break to
like,
it wasn't doing this for the cameras who
was doing this,
like to express himself to these people
that he just fought for their screaming
and cheering for them and the corn nuts
and he's pointing at them telling them I
love you.
I love you.
Then I'm doing this for you guys.
it's heavy shit,
man.
A fellow soldier is that,
that base and then they all cheer for
him and he wins like that.
It's intense.
It's intense human beings.
How appreciative of the people that are
for you guys.
Super,
super,
super happy with anybody.
Not just so
do you see anybody but to have like a
crazy event like a ufc on their base and
they get to go and see it,
you know?
So a great treat for them.
Break up the monotony.
That's good for the morale man.
Fall camp.
That's big man.
You got to have morale and the vikings
do that.
Especially did mushrooms.
People love like,
I'm pretty like people who listen to
your show man,
you don't know like how happy you make
them.
You know what I run into people when
they say,
oh bro,
for taking me on go and they always talk
about,
oh bro,
like they will say,
I wake up to you to you,
and they talk about you,
like they want to be here.
They like everything you say,
man.
And,
and I remember,
um,
when I was walking down the street the
other day and I ran into a guy and he
told me I'm a man,
I'm,
I was locked up in corcoran state prison
for two years,
for many years.
And um,
you are less coming.
You are last comic standing helped me
get through the hard times are whole.
You are whole.
Um,
our whole,
our whole lot.
A whole prison,
allie.
Oh guess what were they called it the
whole block was rooting for you.
You know,
we were going to write it if you didn't
win.
Wow.
And i'M thinking,
wow man,
fuck it.
Inmates are watching me and they're
voting for me.
Wow.
From,
with the phones.
And now remember that because one of
your guests with George Perez,
um,
I,
I used to write to him.
I remember one time I went,
I wrote them a seven,
a seven page letter to stay up,
you know,
and he will call me in the middle of the
night.
George perez from prIson,
like in the middle of like 11 at night.
If repeat what you're doing,
being free food.
Enjoying my freedom back.
Oh man.
What's it like after everything is doing
good man.
He will tell me that he was doing comedy
shows in prison for the guards for
extra,
extra lunch.
Electric chips,
Georgia.
Funny dude,
man.
The beast.
It's a funny guys.
Good joke writer too.
Yeah man.
Yeah,
yeah man.
I mean that's how joey started to,
you know jody has started in prison
making people laugh.
They would like,
they would have something going on.
It would be born and they throw the
cuban up there.
It's really cute.
Went up there and joe would go up there
and make everybody laugh.
That's how we got started.
Then.
That was a big part of like what katie
gave him.
The confidence when you,
when you started at you,
um,
go at it or that you go read a book or
like a minority we're going to do when
you started tandem,
how did you approach it?
Uh,
I just went to an open mic night and I
got real lucky that,
uh,
was uh,
available that you could sign up.
Was it boston stitches?
August 27th,
1988.
And um,
you could just sign up and you could
just go in there and put your name into
the hat and you know,
they got to pick x amount of people.
I forget how many 20 people or Something
like that and everybody does like five
minutes.
And uh,
I just got Lucky and went up and just
said,
wow,
I think I can do this.
You know,
I think I did.
It waSn't good,
but I was definitely thinking this
could,
this is a,
this is something that you could get
better at.
You could figure it out and you could do
it.
But I remember thinking like,
there's no way I'm going to ever be able
to have a real job.
I'm just too dysfunctional way to
dysfunctional.
I was way too crazy.
Like I had a lot of drive,
like the idea of being in an office and
being trapped like that.
I felt like a like a caged in alley cat.
Like there's no way man.
I gotta get the fuck outta here.
It was more out there.
I just want to add,
man.
You know what I mean?
It might not have even been an ambItion
thing as much of an intolerance thing
wasn't that I had this grand plan for
myself like I thought I deserved better
and I'm going to be the top of this
fucking kick ass.
It was that I couldn't do that.
I can't do it because there's something
about milk monotonous,
boring shit.
My brain is screaming for new
experiences.
Always does my number.
Like it's a good thing,
but it's also a bad thing because
sometimes you just can't.
You can't construct things because you
want to think about other things that
are better and more crazy and more
exciting,
more fun.
So it's like trying to manage that
mindset with a regular jobs almost
impossible to me.
I just couldn't do it.
I tried to,
I didn't give a fuck.
I wanted to quit done,
can't do this.
I felt like it was just a constant grind
on your skin,
just pulling your skin down and dragging
you into this state where you didn't
want to exist.
You know,
in some people are different.
Some people have no problem.
They find a great job,
they're super happy.
They make friends with the people they
work with and every day is a pleasure
and they just get in there and they
laugh and joke around.
But I'm too fucked up.
I can't sit still.
I have a million other things that I
want to do while someone's talking to me
about some boring shit.
I've got like five other things I want
to do.
I'm like,
I can't do this.
I gotta get outta here.
I can't take this.
So I was like,
stir crazy.
If I had a regular job,
mia,
I'm out of the rehab rehab picking 1992
of the drug rehab for crack without.
Somebody asked me,
um,
what are your goals in life?
Know what do you want to do?
And no mommy did with a bunch of heroin
addicts,
guys from prisoners,
you know,
it was a rehab and then he told to write
down five things.
So I never had goals before.
So I wrote down when to be a comedian.
I want to go to Italy to love olive
garden and I want to be sober
clove of garlic.
Said I want to go to Mexico because I
love taco bell.
How?
Yeah,
that's the same shit.
I know,
right?
I just want to do the whole one.
We'll do the real tour of editing,
legitimate plate.
So I didn't know how to go about it,
man.
I just went to the public library.
This was before social media and I
winded with my badass gangster bald head
and I told the old lady that is old
white lady.
Um,
I sort of listen man.
I don't know how to tell you this or how
to explain it to your k.
I want to be a comedian.
I want to do standup comedy,
but I wouldn't.
I don't know.
I don't know how to write.
I don't know how to,
how to put a job together.
So that she put me to the shoot,
she went to this big old big old
library,
a glossary card with,
and then she followed comedy writing and
then she got me this book called um,
comedy writing step by step by gene
perret.
Oh wow.
Did you follow it?
I did,
I followed it.
I learned that I will go back everyday
to rent videos of lenny bruce and
cassettes of george carlin for the
library.
And a friend of mine when I was a little
boy,
he had loaned me this vhs.
And back then,
um,
if you fuck with a vhs tape,
you could make it go six hours instead
of a three hour movie.
Oh yeah.
You downgrade the quality.
So I had like six comedy specials that I
watched and they're all hb owes it with
holly mandale,
regus when you were in as little
christmas sweater.
Sam kinison,
the young comedian show with five proud.
And I'm jeff.
Jeff,
what,
what?
Yeah,
ronnie with hosting and the dice melton.
That tape.
So I just got all that stuff and that's
what inspired you.
And I will go to a library and I just
write down like ideas when they are,
how old are you?
Twenty three,
24.
And you're like,
this is what I want.
And I day I paid 12 bucks and I went
into the main room to watch a real show
and I saw him in sia.
I saw some dude named the tod the time
and I saw this old white black dude with
a fedora white hat,
tyree,
tyree tyree.
And I saw the guy that does the props.
He used to inflate his body until the
elvis.
He's one of the blue color of comedy.
He just props.
He brings out people and I don't know,
it looked horace.
I saw luke torres who,
who was on one of the blue collar
comedians,
does props.
He used to a fleet himself,
but he's not a,
he didn't tour with them but within the
show.
Oh,
okay.
He used to like,
like put it like get an iron and burned
himself and they hit it off and then his
face will be on an iron as far.
They don't do that anymore.
And then he had like this bit where
there's like a,
he's like a football player and if
people chasing them and like a fake
football players behind.
Wait a minute.
Was this heat high?
She's high,
yes.
Yes.
Very funny guy.
Fucking hilarious.
It was a very funny guy.
Remember when you have to have the
church sermon?
Yes to choir rather behind them and they
would move around.
He had like these people behind them.
He had this whole contraption that he
was a really funny dude.
Yeah.
So that was a.
What year was that?
While it was like 1994 probably.
That's when I first started going there,
man.
Then from that I just went to the
natural fudge and I met Brian Levine for
soda l berman,
the twins.
Crazy lineage.
Man.
What's so interesting art form know you
get to know these really
bizarre people and you get to get close
to them.
Very,
very.
A unique way to live your life as a,
as a person in a strange group of
vagabonds trying to make people laugh
where it will hit dodger stadium.
And I used to work at a yoshinoya when
hidell no,
both plain.
Oh wow.
That was cooking food everyday.
like just making japanese food.
And every time I see a comedian I will
ask him for advice.
He knows I'm so young and I will talk to
tk carter.
Tk carter carter.
He was in the thing punky brewster who
the teachers.
But do you remember tk carter was in the
thing?
He was in.
He was in a bunch of big Time movie.
Yeah,
back then.
But he was in john carpenter's the
thing.
They know another woman there that was
part of the common use stores dry with
curly hair.
And she did a specialist power driggers
from prison.
She did it with them.
Yeah.
What did she do?
She did stand up comedy.
Uh,
hit her at him.
It was her poetry guests and Anthony
Michael somethinG.
Wow.
I forgot her name.
She's famous.
She's famous
old school.
Old school man.
Yeah.
it's interesting.
It's so much easier to get more inspired
or to get inspired rather today because
kids could just watch all that stuff
that you just brought up on youtube.
And youtube plus all the shit that's
happening.
Yeah.
Rides,
bus rides.
And you can do it anytime you want.
Anytime you're anywhere,
you know,
you put the headphones on.
Bam.
I sitting there watching a comedy
special.
Cool.
My first comedy album I listened to was
bill cosby,
my brother russell,
whom I sleep with.
Me and my friend jackie escalera.
Um,
he,
he put it in the little fisher price
record player and I memorized it and
never up until then I never memorize
anything.
It's crazy.
And then,
um,
which,
uh,
prior that niggas crazy.
That was a fun fucking album ever.
You could never get a tablet in the
ghetto unless you call up and say five
nigga clean white woman wears the body.
Simple bro.
And joel quick,
quick.
That's not good.
A broader racist jokes.
They're so easy.
They're so simple.
But eric come up with it.
Well,
that one,
I mean you gotta realize the world's a
different place.
When richard pryor was doing that man,
the world was a different place.
And to be first to.
Well,
he was not necessarily first I think is
what it is,
is there's like this progression and I
think that,
you know,
uh,
comedians get inspired by the other ones
that are around them and they were
really just starting it in the 19
fifties and sixties.
Right.
So then there's,
lenny bruce was probably the first guy
who does our style of comedy was just
talking about things like,
what the fuck is this?
like,
what is this?
Ladies and gentlemen,
why isn't this happening?
Who caused this?
What?
Instead of just telling a bunch of
jokes,
he's talking about things and point
things out that happened to be funny.
And then richard pryor comes on after
him and makes it way funnier because
what he did was like the same of thing,
but way funnier.
Like richard pryor had.
There was another level of evolution
that he achieved inspired off the work
of the guys that were before him.
The mort sols and the,
you know,
those guys inspired prior and prior of
course inspires everybody.
It all comeS from prior,
like in the early.
It's like lenny bruce is just this
genius mind opening guy.
That's dealing with people that are
asleep.
he's in a world of the 19 fifties and 19
sixties where people just asleep.
They're weird.
They're disconnected from the world
around them from critical thinking.
It's like they're just,
they're just starting to wake up
culturally and then boom.
Richard pryor takes that and turns it
into the funny shit that anybody had
ever laid my all time favorite comedians
always been richard pryor,
george carlin,
judith.
There's a lot of great ones,
male and a lot of great ones,
you know.
Did you get a chance to see richard
jenny at all?
I did.
A plaTypus.
Met.
Yeah,
he was funny.
He was funny.
He doesn't get the credit.
He deserved it.
He was really funny,
man.
He had like a lot of both the vh one
half hour specials and he was alive.
He was on arsenio hall many times.
Dude.
He was on everything.
Yeah,
he's done a bunch of letterman's
tonight.
Shows tonight show a ton of times.
He was a monster also.
Um,
I got to,
whenever we go to dodger stadium,
I saw one of my,
one of my favorite comedians and I was
working.
I remember joel so fucking dirty.
I was greasy bro.
I had fucking pieces of chicken on my,
on my apron.
And I saw steven,
right?
Oh shit.
He was buying a hot dog and I said,
and I was telling everybody,
you guys don't know who that guy is.
This kinda an oscar winner,
homie.
You don't know the full width bitch
made.
I'm super comfortable.
And yeah,
he got very uncomfortable.
FUcking steven,
right dog,
right.
Don't go nowhere.
You're that guy.
And I went around,
I went around and he goes,
you're going to pay for shit.
Right?
And he goes down because you're gonna
walk out of here.
He didn't want to shake my shake his
hand and he put his hand inside of his
hoodie.
Oh no,
he shook my head.
Was the city or no,
sorry.
That's all right.
Because he's,
he like a germaphobe,
germaphobe always.
He really didn't even know he didn't
want.
He didn't.
He shook my hand with content.
It's hilarious,
dude.
That's hilarious.
That must have freaked them out to ago.
Well,
you know you're a strong cup of tea
going to do.
He's a super white guy from boston.
I know matt because I was like,
oh no.
He don't go nowhere.
I get starstruck by.
Don't invite me to places.
Start but don't go nowhere.
it's a real problem statement.
When he said,
don't go nowhere,
it's like,
thiS is not what I'm looking for.
I'm looking for how you doing your
thanks.
Bye.
Don't move buddy.
He's looking for.
Hey steven.
Right.
Nice to meet you.
You really funny.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate it.
I'm going to get hot dog now.
Get the fuck out of here.
I remember.
Don't go nowhere.
I remember peeing next to john ritter,
a dodger stadium man started the song.
He held his feet and started walking to
the other side of the trough.
Oh,
that's so funny.
That's so funny.
Empty,
empty thing.
One mexican dude standing next to you
mean three's company.
You're rIdiculous.
And I'm the only one who recognized him.
He was wearing like a beard and shades,
but I know jack tripper on me.
I did an episode of news radio with that
dude.
He was a real nice guy.
It was Such a bummer.
When he died.
It was like,
what?
Hey,
that black girl in the show,
she was a girlfriend on the show.
She was.
Whose girlfriend?
Your girlfriend?
News radio.
No,
she wasn't my girlfriend.
The show.
I think there was thought you dated her.
That was one thing where,
I mean,
in real life,
no,
they didn't hurt to show you how to
crush.
I remember that.
Yeah,
that's what it was.
I was trying in real life.
I mean it was trying.
Whoops.
No,
I was not trying to real life in the
show.
My character was a supposedly trying,
but I don't think they were never
successful.
It's hard to remember so long ago.
You know,
I was watching a clip of it the other
day online.
Somebody put something up online with me
and phil hartman.
I literally didn't even remember it.
I was watching like,
it was something that wasn't even me.
I was like,
this is weird.
It's weird to watch.
You know.
It's weird to watch yourself when you
know it's yourself,
but you have no recollection of it and
it's from 20 years ago.
Sorry.
Is that really me?
Like what is that strange man?
You know,
when you look at last comic standing,
how many years ago was that?
Seven.
No.
Eight to freak you out and you go BaCk
and watch it.
Yeah.
SO what happened?
I'm going to look at that fucking grill
grill and now a grill.
My teeth.
What kind of grill iS fucked up bro?
Fuck you.
Fuck your teeth.
All were moved.
That put a lIttle nice dude.
So those are a manmade teeth.
Teeth that get put in my mouth.
Delicious.
Oh yeah.
Did my last teeth brother were like,
they were like separated by birth bro.
They fucking teeth didn't want to get
along bro.
They were like four different gangs to
get your teeth fixed like that.
Oh,
at first I was.
I waited.
I was trying to get the screw in my
mouth.
Yeah,
putting like good fake teeth and screw
them on.
But then my gov were too weak from meth
and crack smoking.
So I could have spit my teeth out.
I didn't,
I didn't need them to pull them out.
so they just know me and they took all
four teeth out.
They shaved my kids these,
I don't know what they're called.
and they took my teeth out.
They fund it.
They made a motor my mouth with four
perfect teeth and they just glued it to
my mouth.
Colluded.
Yeah.
So those are glued in place right now?
How long is that glue last?
Well to a long as I keep them good.
it just takes,
it just cemented.
it's permanently forever.
Wow.
With glue real veneers.
Burleigh.
It looks great.
You look fantastic.
Before ma'am,
I see what fucked up like an apple and a
little bit.
Three people bidding.
No blood flow.
Like I was like fuck bro.
Like people would make fun of me dark.
You floss with rope or what?
A bad dog.
So math is bad for your gut.
Bad crack is bad.
Too bad for the gms?
Yeah,
makes sense.
So you want to avoid bad t's?
Dump snored the drugs you do,
brush your teeth up to does nothing with
coke heads.
they always get jacked up teeth because
the code gets in your mouth.
Still gets in there.
So yeah,
I it throw it.
You're coughing,
you guys,
you get healthy crackers.
I brush after every puff.
That's a good move.
You gotta take a swig of listerine.
Alright for leaf a,
uh,
do already way over three hours,
right?
Yeah.
Crazy bro.
Was this a blunt?
We smoked at of the old ge louis 13
baffled.
Yeah.
This is.
We didn't smoke this though because I
ended know this,
uh,
jamie vernon and blow the glass tips.
Just things are going to mention.
I'm going to be in jacksonville this
week.
You certainly can.
Philippe's barza,
whoever is jacksonville at the comedy
zone this week and at the end of the
month I'll
be@theimprovandcheckoutmydataisworld.com
slash tour.
Go see philippe.
He's a monster.
Parked.
Got cocksucker.
What's up?
fool podcast available on itunes.
Everywhere podcasts are heard.
may show bro,
but you show.
I always tell people,
it's like being in,
you're like the oprah winfrey,
bro.
Thank you everybody.
Like people come here,
but I'm not saying everybody,
but to the people who are real mad,
they just.
The people sell shit man.
Like he liked you like word.
What were our store was?
You're like oprah podcast.
That's very nice.
And you say,
man,
power here Bro.
You Could change boats.
I don't want to do that.
I just want to get,
have some fun.
And we had some fun.
David used stood up,
But the kidS then the in the,
in the cages.
That was tight.
Oh,
the immigration.
Yeah.
Thanks man.
Thanks India.
Thank you for everything,
man.
Thanks for coming out.
I'm glad we
again,
philippe.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Go see ya.
Bye.