Confusion,
you don't get it,
you don't get it through about
subterfuge.
Tom Papa,
who has a special this Friday coming out
on epic.
Oh,
no way.
Especially comedy.
He tells me he is hilarious and
gregarious.
So
charming.
He's a fucking sour dough experts.
The sultan of sour dough.
Where'd you film your special Cleveland
Cleveland's font.
I love Cleveland.
It's a good place to do it.
I'm going there for a long time and I
love the people in Cleveland.
Would you do it?
What place?
Hannah theater?
Yeah,
and a playhouse square district kind of
thing.
Really Nice Theater and uh,
you know,
I've been going to Cleveland for a long
time.
I liked the people there.
It's got a good mix of,
you know,
hopefulness but grounded in reality.
But to make it a comeback,
it is that cities really making a
comeback.
Craft Stores and craft breweries and
nice restaurants.
And I know when I started going there
you couldn't eat healthy if you tried
like it was just corn beef and now,
you know,
15 years later there's Vegan
restaurants,
there's all these like,
you know,
these noodle places.
It's just,
it's completely come up,
but you know when,
when Lebron left,
they were devastated.
How crazy is that?
The one guy,
the whole city just throws a ball into a
hole completely.
They took his banner off the side of the
building and it was over and since he
came back and then one it.
Oh,
it's changed the whole place.
I don't remember how much they hated him
when he left.
I was like,
this is ridiculous.
Why are you so mad?
The guy had to get some money,
but it was real.
It was real.
Like there's a difference when you go
there now people are like a pride.
They're walking around like,
well they have the heavyweight champion
of the UFC to.
Oh,
do steep vimeo check.
He's from Cleveland to.
Yeah,
and the baseball team went to the world
series,
so they were like really?
Like pretty fuckers,
but they have the brands,
which always is that bad.
They're bad,
but they had Jim Brown,
they had Jim Brown that still haven't
won one game.
They haven't won one game this year.
How many games?
They played a.
we're up to nine or 10,
give him some time to work it out
though,
but I really love that,
that city and I really liked it for
standup and I figured it was a good mile
marker,
you know,
you do these specials and it's like,
okay,
this was this period,
you know,
and uh,
I figured this is a good place.
I'd like to commemorate my time in
Cleveland and this material at this
point.
And it was good.
How often do you like to do specials?
Um,
this is my fourth and they come every
like two and a half years.
Yeah,
it's pretty much the standard number
now.
Everyone seems to like a lot of guys
were trying to do them every year.
Like lily was doing one every year for
awhile.
But then he like,
you know what,
they're not
as good when I do it once.
A year later I call,
I called them a premise pilots.
There's a lot.
There was one of the last five years.
A lot of premise pilots,
like people just rushing them out.
It's like,
yeah,
that's a good idea.
Imagine in three years with that joke
would be,
you know what I mean,
and that's the thing I think even two
and a half years and I try and just do
it when it's ready,
but I feel like you see two and a half
years is kind of rushing it.
There's jokes if they stay in your act
for five years,
it's no joke that that thing becomes
something different.
They become better,
become better.
You find out where the beats are,
you find out where the pauses should be.
Find out where maybe there was some
tags.
Yeah.
You developed along the way that lead
you in a totally different direction.
You're thinking about it differently.
There's a confidence that you have in
delivering it.
That's different than you just pushing
it out there,
but you can't.
The way that people digest everything
now.
You can't wait five years.
Yeah,
isn't that the issue is that you have a
bunch of Tom Papa fans and they would
like to come see you again,
but they want to see new shit.
It's not like the rolling stones,
you know?
If you go to see the rolling stones,
you want to hear sympathy for the devil
even though they wrote it in 1967,
you know,
I know,
but you know,
I go back and forth on that because I'm
sure you've had it where you are in
shows and you,
you're at the end of your set or
whatever.
People start yelling out old bits that
they want to see.
Right.
And there's something I know that you
want to be new and you always want to
push and you always want to,
you know,
create.
That's cool.
But I think it sells these bits short to
think that nobody wants to see these
again because I could watch you do that
White House bit.
I know it.
I watched you working on it at the
store.
I watched you developing it.
I've seen it a bunch,
a bunch.
I guarantee I could watch that bit every
week and like it and think it's funny,
when I worked with Seinfeld for years,
I would watch that guy for about seven
straight years and I'd watch and hang
out and watch.
Not the whole set,
but I see when I came up to a favorite
bit of mine,
I was laughing.
I was laughing,
so I think you can.
I think we in our own heads think that
people don't want to see this,
but they do want to see it.
Some do,
but the ones who don't,
when they say,
Oh,
you're doing the same old jokes,
that's so devastating.
You gotta keep moving.
I know you're right.
That does kill you.
The people does kill.
You.
Don't like it.
That feeling way outweighs where people
that don't mind the old jokes again,
when I see people off after a,
after a set and like,
you know in the lobby or whatever and
they're like,
we see you every time you come through.
We saw you two times last year.
I completely go.
The first question is did you see some
new stuff?
And nine times out of 10 they look at me
like,
well yeah,
but it's all great.
Like they don't really care.
Like those fans really don't care.
I don't concentrate on those people.
Those people are too easily satisfied.
I concentrate on
the malcontents people that just can't
wait to get on twitter immediately after
the show was over,
I was still doing that White House
fucking premise.
So tired to break in.
Happened in 2015 bro.
Yeah.
You know,
that's such a unique wormy type of a
fan.
Yeah.
But those warming type of fans,
although they're not the happiest,
nicest people in the world,
they do keep you motivated in check.
Yeah.
The worst for sure.
What happened to a lot of comedians in
the eighties is that they never wrote
new material.
Yeah.
They just kept doing the same stuff.
They get 45 minutes and just wrote it
out whole career.
They had a set and that like Jay Leno
still does that.
Yeah.
He is a brilliant comedian.
Like if you go back to the early days of
like,
uh,
the tonight show and the letterman show
and yeah.
Leno was the edgy young guy.
Yeah.
That would come on.
And he was this great joke writer,
very relevant,
sit down,
boom.
But he put out a showtime special that
I'm aware of that I watched a long time
ago.
He might have found that and bought up
every copy of it and burned it.
Yeah,
never seen it.
He doesn't put out anything now.
Nothing.
When he goes on stage,
he wants the audience to have no idea
what his jokes are because they could
never see them on the Internet.
They can't find him anywhere.
He said that to me once.
He's like,
why would you?
Why would you record?
Why would you put out an album?
You're killing your act because you your
act fee to your actors with.
Why would you just give that away?
But it's a different thing.
It's.
It's changed.
I think the media,
how people can digest this stuff has
actually changed what a comedian is,
but with all due respect,
when people today think about Jay Leno,
they don't think of the great standup
comedians today.
They don't think of Jay Leno even when
even before the prior.
The rather cosby controversially went
down.
Cosby was still considered all time
great.
One of the all time greats,
right?
And Leno was in that ilk at one point in
time.
He's never.
He's not considered that.
No.
And you think that's because the tonight
show,
do you think if he could have done the
tonight show and put out?
Oh yeah,
for sure material he would have for
sure.
I mean he has his no body of work.
Right?
That's a big.
That's a big problem.
It's,
it's everything.
There's a lot of guys that are really
good that we all know.
Like Duncan trussell is a perfect
example.
Duncan trussell is a brilliant comedian.
Yeah.
His no body of work.
Like he doesn't have anything out.
Right.
I know.
And you know,
that's kind of where,
where my head is at lately is whatever
you're doing,
whatever you're hustling,
whatever you're trying to put out there,
it's all about making stuff.
It's all about making stuff that you're
proud of.
So you know,
this is like the fourth one.
So now I can look back like,
all right,
this is,
this is growing,
this is stuff I'm proud of.
And then if I'm writing something,
like I just want to create as much as
possible.
You know what I mean?
Oh yeah.
But,
but,
but there is definitely that side that,
you know,
I,
I came up during an era when you didn't
just make an album because you could
record it on your phone,
someone had to come and ask you,
you have to be good enough for someone
to say,
I want to make something with you.
So I still have that feeling that I'm
not good enough that.
So I don't want to put it out early
because I don't feel like it's ready or
it's worthy,
you know what I mean?
So I try and hold back as much as
possible.
I don't feel like because Louis puts one
out every year that I have to put one
out every year or to be so arrogant that
will Carlin did it every year.
Well that's George Carlin,
Carlin.
I mean it's hard to talk bad about
Carlin because he's dead and he's one of
the all time greats,
but there's some,
some questionable stuff in there.
Wasn't that good?
Yeah.
There's some specials where.
Yeah,
I mean he had some brilliant jokes.
No,
no doubt about it.
But when you're doing a new hour every
year,
some of it's just not up to the same
standards as some of your classics.
Like he has some classics.
Oh my God,
the best.
But you know,
at the end he was calling himself a
writer more than a comedian.
He said,
I like to be called a writer and that's
how he was doing the act.
He was writing out.
He'd be at the comedy Magic Club with
his printed out sheets,
memorizing like a play,
like memorizing all this material to
then take it out and that's a different
thing and you can put that together in a
year,
but it doesn't have the seasoning,
the confidence,
the ins and outs that if you just toured
with that for three years.
Oh my God.
What it would become.
Tours is a big thing too,
man,
because when I do a theater,
if I do a theater on a weekend,
like say if I do Friday night at a
theater or a Saturday night at the
theater,
there's a giant difference between doing
that and doing like a weekend.
The comedy works in Denver where you're
doing four shows,
two shows,
Friday,
two shows Saturday.
That's when bits come alive.
They get those extra taglines.
They get those extra.
You're so different from Thursday night
for show Saturday.
Last show.
First one.
You're.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm doing it and heal people.
Having a good time.
With Saturday,
you're just,
you're like a mat.
You can just kick back and just.
There's just this natural zone that you
can be and that you don't have the.
You just don't have the confidence.
You know,
I have to be out there all the time and
I think that's the hard part.
You know,
Jay,
back to Jay doing the tonight show.
He was working on that monologue.
I mean he was doing 12 minute
monologues.
They even just thrown those away.
Let me just tell you this right now.
I don't,
I've never liked the fucking monologue
ever in the history of late night
television is not one where I'm like,
finally the monologue dog shit just go
right.
Every joke sucks there.
It's a different type of them using it
best,
but he.
But he would disagree because he,
he,
he said that lead letterman was doing a
six minute monologue and people were
turning off and go into the commercial
and go onto the next thing.
So he said,
if I could keep it,
if I could do twice,
that people aren't changing,
and I,
he beat Letterman all the time from that
segment of the show,
the ratings were strong enough and he
held onto them.
This is just as business mind working
that he hung onto them and kept them in
there.
And that's why he was number one all
this time.
Well,
it was the hugh grant thing.
Remember when he ran on it,
he said,
what the hell were you thinking?
Right.
Which is a disingenuous question.
He was saying,
I don't want to get my dick sucked by
this hot black chick and I pay her
money.
She's going to do.
It was just awesome.
He knows what the fuck he taken.
But j dot really thought that the
monologue was his was his thing and that
he had to pour everything into it and he
would work on it.
As soon as that one was over,
he,
he would fly off and do gigs in Vegas.
He was working on it constantly,
sending jokes to his guy coming in the
next,
do 12 minutes of new jokes every day.
You're not writing your act.
You're not working on your act.
Right.
When you get busy and have other
projects and stuff,
your acts,
you know,
if you've seen Craig Ferguson to stand
up.
I have not.
He's doe does what he does now.
He's like,
he's a standup.
Yeah,
and he was doing it while he was doing
the show.
I don't know how much he did before he
did his show.
Yeah,
but then once he did a show,
like I would go places and they said,
yeah,
we had Craig Ferguson last night.
I'm like,
Craig Ferguson,
like that.
The talk show.
God didn't even know he was a comic.
Yeah.
And they'd go,
yeah,
he's a comic.
I'm like,
wow.
Interesting.
Just see.
Act.
Nope.
That's why I was asking you is what he
does now.
He just decided I'd rather just do stand
up.
Just.
Here's a weird one,
man.
They didn't get rid of him,
he just said I want to do it anymore.
I know he's one of the and then he's
hosting like two different game shows.
Is He?
Yeah.
What are they?
He's got this one show where it's like a
kind of like two teams and they do
charades against each other kind of a
show and he's in the middle of it and
then I did an appearance on his new show
on a national geographic or history,
I think it was history and he brought a
panel out.
It was me and lars from metallica and a
writer and we had discussed,
it was like little lists,
like I forget the name of it.
It was like the list of something and we
had to pick like the top five bands of
all time and it's just like this funny
game show talk show kind of a thing,
but he's always popping up and doing
that kind of stuff.
So he just didn't want to see what his
act was like because whenever.
Yeah,
whenever I hear that.
My first.
My first inkling is always probably
telling stories about celebrities.
Kathy Griffin style.
Yeah,
like you ever watch comedians and then
become famous and then they start
telling stories about,
oh,
this is when I ran into so and so in the
locker room and you know,
it's all celebrity stuff because they're
not living their life.
But Ferguson,
I had heard that like he used to write a
lot and he was always trying to like
come up with stuff,
so maybe it's a real act.
Well,
the people that worked at the theater
that I worked at or you know there the
night before they said it was funny.
Yeah.
So I would like to see it,
see what that's about,
but I always,
I always find it interesting when people
just,
they get some sort of a mainstream gig
that.
And they do it for awhile and like,
Oh,
I'm,
I'm done.
Yeah,
Well,
he got passed over for Letterman.
Oh,
is that what it is?
Is that why he quit?
He didn't get that job.
That's when it all went down.
Yeah.
Meanwhile,
that job sucks.
Yeah.
I'm going,
look,
it's a tough.
Just happened into core bear Kobe.
Nobody likes anymore.
I'm completely loved them.
I'm going to stuck with that other
fucking job.
Cold Bear as Cole Bear,
whereas.
Great.
Yeah.
Cole bear as whoever the fuck he really
is.
I don't like that guy.
He needed.
When he was on,
he had Gaffigan on and Maria Shriver and
they were all talking about how great it
is to be in a cat to be a catholic.
I'm like,
check,
please get the foot on the show.
Yeah.
Oh really?
The Catholics.
Amazing.
There's a billion of us.
I'm like,
what?
What really?
What am I watching?
Like because Kobe is like a serious
Catholic.
Yeah,
I knew that,
but I didn't know.
It was bizarre.
I'm doing that show on Thursday.
Yeah,
bring it up.
I'm going to show up.
Dressed like the pope.
See what they say.
You get mad at you just wear the wizard
costume.
It's a full.
It's a weird job.
It's a very weird job.
You're basically selling other people's
stuff.
[inaudible].
Yeah.
And all the time.
And you have these little short sound
bytes.
I did Conan back when he was in New York
and uh,
I,
uh,
it was,
I don't know how many times I had done
the show.
I did it a lot,
I don't know,
probably the eighth time.
And uh,
I was there with the show was over and
Conan's walking through the halls and
he's got his guitar with him and he
comes over and,
uh,
I said,
thanks for having me.
That's so great.
I love coming in here because yeah,
it's great for you because you get to
come in here and do the show and then
you get to leave and go about your life.
I'm here every single day.
He starts playing on the guitar thing,
thing thing every single day.
I never leave these halls every single
day.
I was like,
it really sunk in.
Like,
was he serious?
He was serious.
Was He bummed out?
It just a little,
you know,
one of those magic moments of,
you know who,
but your.
That's in New York now.
He's been doing the show for how many
more years?
Yeah,
I did it way.
That's a real New York and he had a
punching bag.
Yes.
In his office.
Was he get crazy when he gets frustrated
and shuts wailing on that thing.
Fucking network.
Wham,
wham,
wham.
I want the tonight show.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
that's a real gig.
I mean,
you just.
That's a different life.
You're.
That was a weird moment too in the
annals of Showbiz history when they gave
him the Gig and then they put Leno on
before him.
So crazy.
I'm like,
what are you doing?
Like what is this was on a 10?
Yeah,
and then you guys are cannibalizing
yourself.
Brutal.
You have to talk.
Show hosts in a row.
How do you choose who goes on?
What show?
Oh,
like what are you doing?
Who did that?
Whose idea was that?
Jeff Zucker.
I think Jeff.
I Love Jeff.
Jeff's a great guy and I know Jeff gave
me my first break on television,
but he was,
holy cow.
That was a weird moment.
Well,
did.
I mean,
imagine if your cone.
Imagine if you're the guy that you get
the tonight,
show your lifelong dream and then the
guy you took it from,
they tell you he's going to go on before
you because your ratings are so.
So we're going to put him on at 10:00.
Oh,
and then you've got to go out there and
give them a log.
How much time went by before they put
Leno on before?
Um,
uh,
it wasn't that long.
They don't give you much.
It wasn't that long,
I want to say maybe a year maybe.
But his,
it just wasn't hitting well.
It's one of those things where to,
in order for a show to develop,
it has to find its legs.
The guy like what?
You have to have faith in whoever's
doing it that they're going to figure it
out.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
But they don't always do that.
They don't always have faith.
And then they put tremendous pressure on
you.
And then advertisers don't want to spend
money because the ratings aren't high
enough.
So you bleeding revenue and you have all
these producers and everyone sketching.
Everyone has their own idea of how to
juice it up and then they have crashes
and pressure and what's so strange to me
in that scenario when it was all going
down,
when he had his thing in New York,
it was locked in.
He had his fans.
It was solid and doing the same thing in
a bigger studio across the country.
It was different.
It was weirder.
It was area or something was.
It was also on earlier.
There was more expectations.
It was more mainstream expectations like
that late thing is kind of like relaxed.
Like Carson Carson daily was on TV
forever and no one noticed and they
still doing it.
He's still just kind of get away with
that at 2:00
in the morning and just like,
hey,
we're good.
See You tomorrow.
Don't care,
and we're still doing it.
Yeah,
for it's still buying time on that show.
Does Not Dishonor Carson Daly at all.
It's very nice guy.
No,
but it's being protected.
You're protected.
You don't.
You don't have that pressure of
expectations being in that thing.
I was there for the very early days of
Conan because my friend Amir Mirror was
one of the writers on Conan show,
so I went to like one of the third or
fourth tapings and when they had the
monologue scripted and they had it on
giant cue cards,
it was really gross for the audience
because right behind Andy Richter be
someone holding a cue card and behind
Conan would be someone holding a cue
card and it had like Conan Andy and then
yes.
The words they would say,
so they would have a scripted like this
conversation were happening.
Yeah.
Would be scripted.
Weird,
bizarre.
It's crazy is if there's a bizarre right
after you.
Now you.
Now you go.
It's funny you mentioned that because
our next guest is weird as well.
Somebody had to go up to Kona to go,
listen,
we need to script your monologue and
then we need to script your dialogue.
We need to script your banter.
We need to script everything.
We're leaving.
Nothing to chance.
Just that.
It wasn't good.
It was very awkward in the day and I
think he found himself and became like
this sort of Zany.
His show on guy is still super creative.
It's still.
I mean it's,
you
know,
not that many people see it as compared
to the old days,
but he'd,
they're always doing original funny
stuff like it.
It's alive,
you know.
I don't know how you keep doing that for
that many years,
but it is a unique really funny place on
television for sure.
It's his job.
I mean that's what he does.
Yeah.
That's his thing.
That's his gig.
Yeah,
it is a,
it's a.
You know what else was awkward too?
Here's the thing that sucks the most
about those shows is that like you have
these six,
seven minutes segments where you just
sit down and you just kind of force a
bunch of subjects and to these sick like
he had drawn the other day and in one
thing there was like this really awkward
segway.
What about the NFL?
I know the NFL,
bob is.
He was like,
what?
Like they were just talking about trump
and then they just switch gear,
like super awkward segway.
Yeah.
And you're looking down at the car,
jumps right into it.
I'm like,
oh,
I guess he got to.
Yeah.
But you know,
I really feel as a comedian,
that's what comedians are the best
guests on.
Those shows.
Like you should just sit down and go,
just go.
I watch Rodney doing the tonight show
with Johnny Carson.
Did A,
did a six minute set,
you know,
standing there doing his thing.
They all right,
great.
And then he walks over,
he sits down and then four minutes
Johnny asked him one question and he
just went.
He just joke,
joke,
joke and it.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Joke,
joke,
joke.
Good night everybody.
I mean,
that's your job.
Why do we have to make this look like
it's a conversation?
Especially with a guy like Rodney.
He was just,
that's where he was in his element.
Oh,
just rapid fire.
Oh yeah.
My doctor.
Let me tell Ya,
you know the story of Rodney,
how he took more than a decade off of
show business,
but the entire time he was writing
jokes,
but he's selling aluminum siding and
trim.
Yeah.
Didn't keep the jokes like in a
briefcase or something,
I don't know,
but he just kept writing.
So when he came back and started doing
standup again,
which I believe was in his forties.
Yeah,
it was in his forties.
He had massive amounts of material.
Amazing.
I heard that he.
Is this true.
Have you ever heard this?
That he had switched acts with another
comic that he wasn't going anywhere and
his buddy wasn't going anywhere and they
switched acts if you ever heard that.
No,
no,
no.
I never heard that.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know if it's true or not,
but what a funny dude.
Apparently the risk like respect.
No respect at all.
God Damn it.
I'm trying to find out what,
what movie it was that caused him to
change it from.
I used to be like,
I can't catch a break,
like Hannah early.
Oh really?
Tagline.
And then he changed it to,
I don't get no respect,
no respect,
no respect at all.
And then clicks,
see,
see if he can find out the origin of
that.
Jamie.
That's amazing.
There was like a specific reason why he
went to from like this one cat to
respect.
Fuck.
I'm trying to remember who told me.
Someone who was like a giant Rodney Fan.
He was Dave Smith.
Was it Dave Smith,
the comedian that came in here?
Maybe.
So at some point he was saying things
just don't go well for me.
Something along wasn't.
It just wasn't,
isn't that weird?
Just those little words.
Just those and catchy and get her done.
Get her done.
Really.
I mean her dad is a classic.
Things are just.
They just catch why.
Remember when Chappelle could not go on
stage because dumb drunk white boys
would yell out,
I'm Rick James Bitch.
It was always white guys too because
they were so hooked on it.
Hooked on it.
I know.
Sorry Dave.
Sorry.
White guys do.
I'm a white guy myself.
So that was a giant,
giant problem.
Like he would saw him at the House of
Blues in Vegas and literally show it was
a clusterfuck because people just
yelling out,
I'm Rick James,
Bitch.
It's weird.
Like it's in the one side.
It's like people love you so much,
but the other side he's like,
you're killing me.
You're killing me.
Well that was a saying that people love
to say.
They just love to say I'm Rick James
Bitch.
So they would just see them right there
and they just want to yell it out.
I'm going to feel it.
I want to feel that sound.
Yes.
Sacha Baron Cohen.
Right.
How long was he walking around?
Like my wave.
Right,
right.
I have no catchphrases.
I always went,
when I was young comic,
I watched a guy.
I opened for some guy in like Virginia.
It was like one of my first row things
ever and this guy was really hacky and
he had a line in his act and then he
would sell the t shirt with that line.
Oh God.
And then he was also getting drunk,
you know,
as for the second show.
And he did the second show and brought
the tee shirt out at the end and there
was no response because he had forgot.
He was so drunk.
He forgot to do the hacky bit to sell
his t shirt.
I saw that and I was like,
I don't care how much money he's making
him selling these shirts.
I am not going down that road.
That's a big thing though for road guys
is merge,
merge.
They go nuts with the merge,
Such a bad businessman.
I just feel like it's all about the
show.
It's about the show.
It's about me on stage.
This was great.
I can't go to the lobby and start making
change for twenties.
I can't do it.
Can't.
I've sold t shirts and like one or two
shows ever.
And I show sold cds at one or two shows
ever.
And then I'm like,
I can't do it anymore.
Right.
What is that?
Why these people already paid this?
First of all today?
They could always get your stuff.
They can always go online and who wants
a physical copy of anything anyway?
Right?
A DVD or something.
Like what the fuck,
what?
My computer doesn't even have a slot for
it.
It's right.
Exactly.
You ever see what a Pablo does?
No,
not Pablo.
I'm Gabriel.
Gabriel.
No,
no.
Look all those Mexicans.
Third one.
It's not even a third.
Was the other one.
The other one.
Your guy.
The big controversy guy.
The Celia.
I'm in steel.
Yeah.
He records his set and then he
has a guy,
his opener when he's done goodnight
everybody.
The opener comes up and does another 10
minutes while on this disk drive.
They burn all of these little,
uh,
what do they call them?
Thumb drives of what you just saw.
So you can buy the original set of what
you just saw on your way out that smart.
Then he has another guy,
takes pictures and uh,
and sells those.
You can get a picture taken with it.
I mean,
it's a huge picture.
Taking is gross.
Huge.
Charging people to take a picture is
gross.
Yeah.
And then they put it in a laminate.
You can have like a degrees.
So go see Santa.
You can get the cocking get one copy or
you can get the thing in the laminate
with the snowflakes on it.
I kind of feel bad calling them in
steel.
You again,
like I'm shitting on him always down.
[inaudible].
I should just let it go.
But the photograph thing,
like charging people to take a
photograph.
There was always that he always did.
That was like,
that is just gross.
Just take a picture with people.
They're nice.
They want to take a picture with you.
It's not hard to do.
I don't mind going out and talking to
them and letting them take their
pictures and just saying hello to
people.
I just can't get into the selling thing
because I hear you.
If you're sensitive about your work and
you get through the set and you've done,
he put everything you had into it and
you think they had a good time.
Let's not judge each other for another
time on the way out of the building
with.
You know what I mean?
Let's just have a nice moment.
Let's not make it.
Oh,
now he wants me to buy a shirt from
them.
Yeah.
Would it be nice to just say hi to
people to not have to take a photograph
because I mean,
I know,
I understand that people want to take
photographs and I,
I'm happy to take them,
but it's like that moment and then
becomes this pose instead of like,
Hey,
what's up?
How are you?
Nice to meet.
Yeah,
right,
exactly.
You know,
like everybody,
like people can't meet anybody anymore.
Everybody has to.
You have to immediately get your phone
out and it doesn't matter what you're
doing.
People want to take,
like I went to see,
um,
honey honey and Gary Clark Jr the other
night,
late night show,
midnight at the down and out in downtown
La.
And while the show's going on,
like we're standing there watching the
show and people were grabbing my arm,
trying to get me to take pictures with
him.
I'm like,
stop not taking a picture.
I'd love that.
That beginning of,
uh,
of your special.
The first thing you said was put your
phone down yet because there's special.
Literally the first thing out of your
mouth was put your phone.
They can't be in the moment,
bitch.
Yeah,
meanwhile I'd take videos of Gary Clark
when he's on stage of the day.
I know it's all part of the experience,
but I wanted to promote them to c,
one,
six explained.
Oh,
the origin of respect.
Here it goes.
I had this joke,
I play hide and seek won't even look for
me to make it worse.
He looked for something and put in front
of it.
I was so poor.
I was so dumb.
So this.
So that I thought now what fits that
joke?
Well no one liked me was all right,
but then I thought a more profound thing
would be.
I get no respect.
That's not totally true.
There was a movie,
there was something,
there was a movie about some,
some movie that had something about
respect in it is wikipedia says pretty
much the same thing that it came from
like appearances on the Ed Sullivan show
and that this is like almost the same
thing.
It tells a joke right here.
No,
I'm sure.
I'm sure,
but someone told me the history of like,
deciding respect,
that it was based on some movie that was
famous at the time,
like maybe even a mob movie.
It's weird,
like when you look at listening,
not remembering Shit,
when you look at that list of comedians
and it's like Tim Allen had the EU and
then uh,
you know,
everybody does have a little hooky
thing.
Tennessee now that you might be a
redneck.
Oh yeah.
You might be a redneck was giant.
Yeah.
You know,
that was one of the first bits I saw
them in CSD now that.
Oh yeah,
redneck.
no.
Oh yeah.
Oh,
pre-internet.
How 90?
Four.
Oh my goodness.
That's when I realized I was like,
what your family tree does not.
Fork is one of those.
Really.
Yeah.
I was like,
Holy Shit.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
I feel like the,
the taking the picture is kind of better
than talking to them though,
because I always find like I want to.
They'll say something about the act or
something and then the first sentence is
great.
Be Like,
oh,
it was really funny.
I love when you did the thing.
Oh,
that's good.
I've been working on that and then I
want to talk real about it,
about the act and then they,
I always find myself like they meet you
and they're like,
oh this is great.
I get to talk to them and then you start
talking and then they ended up slowly
walking away and you're like,
I've been really working on this bit.
I'm having a hard time with the tag and
trying to just kind of drift away.
Like,
oh,
he's not as much fun as we thought.
Oh,
you mean you didn't just make that up on
the spot.
So I feel like if they take a picture,
we'd get through it and move on.
Yeah.
Well Jamie and I do this thing that I
stole from Steevo Steve Idea.
It's a great idea.
Steve takes photos,
but then you have to go to his website
to get the photos.
That way people don't fumble with their
cameras and I tried them once because
the phones take fucking.
Nobody knows how to use her God damn
phone.
Oh,
take my picture.
How does this work?
If you give someone an android phone,
you might as well give him a fucking
thesaurus.
Give them a book to read.
Nobody knows how to work a fucking
android phone.
I tried to do it.
I had my buddy take pictures and then we
posted them on the line and they could
go get them.
First of all,
everybody was so then you spent the
whole time saying,
can I just take it with my phone,
knows how we do it?
He got iris.
Say that a higher one.
Security people at the club say,
put your phones away.
The pictures will be available online
tonight.
This is the only way to do what you do
in thousands of photos though.
He's only one way.
Do it.
Yeah,
if you're doing that,
that's why I sit in the back and eat a
salad and wait for the second show.
That's good.
Move too.
I know that's a good move.
I know it depends on where you're at too
though.
Like that's.
Do you like comedy clubs or do you like
working theaters like this place in
Cleveland?
How many seats were there?
Uh,
it was about 600.
That's a good time or something like
that.
Yeah,
that was perfect.
Perfect size.
I did the fillmore in San Francisco.
That's where I did my special,
which is smaller than that.
It's like 4:50,
4:50.
Yeah.
Perfect.
Yeah,
that's good.
It's good.
It's.
It's perfect,
but it's not as good as the comedy works
because the economy works is a low
ceiling like,
oh yeah,
I had a high ceiling.
Low ceilings are where it's at,
man.
Those little jammed up like there's no
room at the comedy store rooms.
People don't realize what that energy is
such a real real thing.
It is a real thing given back and forth.
You're writing this.
There's a.
it's not a mystical just.
It's a real.
I'm getting from them.
I'm giving it back.
We're playing with this energy.
That's why if you do an outdoor show,
it sucks because it's just poof.
Just evaporating.
It's going up like smoke.
One thing.
Did you have any hecklers?
No.
Right?
Three out of four shows.
People heckled really three of the four
and they weren't even being mean.
They were just.
They wanted to talk.
They just wanted to get on the show.
They love you.
Even asked people before the show,
I said,
I'm filming here.
Please don't yell on it.
Anything.
They still did probably so mad at them.
People were so mad at them.
Oh yeah.
And then the crates this riff,
people like,
shut the fuck up.
She's taping now.
My,
uh,
my people were a little civilized.
Maybe your people are more civilized
than other people.
They're middle aged women.
They might get a lot of that.
I get a lot of,
uh,
I get a lot of family,
females,
a lot of,
a lot of side boob selfies at the end of
the show.
Drunk can lipstick on your teeth.
Oh my God.
They have their husbands taking their
picture and they're squeezing your ass
as they're squeezing and clawing your
back,
doing the finger thing on your back to
let you know they're interested.
Excited.
It's a nice moment for a married man.
Just grill.
Go back to your hotel.
Still likes me.
Put a little pop in your masturbation at
night.
What about her sleeping pills for
comics?
Yeah,
but no,
uh,
a hecklers.
It was pretty.
It was pretty smooth.
It was pretty good.
Yeah.
My crowd's a little wild maybe to calm
down.
Now they're passionate.
Bring them when you play.
We live.
When you just do live then you probably
don't care and you mess with them and
sometimes,
but you don't want them ruining bits.
And that happens all the time.
That's the word idiot.
Ruined Chris Rock's bit the other night
at the comedy store.
Really?
Oh my God.
Chris rock this rocket,
this bit about cops and this guy just
fucking interrupted.
And then Chris,
you know,
Chris was joking around with them at
first and then the guy interrupted again
and then Chris was like,
you dumb motherfucker.
I'm doing jokes up here.
Like,
what are you doing man?
And they wound up kicking the guy out
and as they're kicking the guy,
I was like,
whoa.
I can't open opinion.
Like fucking.
No you can't.
You can definitely have an opinion.
You don't want to interrupt
a performance like this agreement.
The audience has an agreement.
Okay.
The agreement is you're going to sit
there and you get to see what this
person is prepared right now.
Person's prepared,
but he came on stage with a fucking
notebook,
but that's a weird thing,
but that's the.
That's the,
you know,
that's the illusion that we create.
If you're good.
It does.
It sounds like it's just happening.
It sounds like it's in the moment.
It doesn't sound planned out,
so they think that they're in the moment
with you.
Well,
rock rock is so opinion heavy.
Like Chris Rock's premises are always
like,
yeah,
he's,
he's a master at taking a controversial
premise,
taking a controversial point of view and
then bring it around so that when at the
end of it you're just howling laughing
because he's figured out a way to like
he's right.
He's right.
I know he is the master bitter divorce
shit to A.
I've been waiting for that to come out.
I don't know if he had a prenup.
Seems like you didn't.
Oh really?
Yeah.
It seems like there's a lot,
a lot of fucking.
A lot of fuel was just talking about how
much money the lawyers make and a wife's
going after all of it.
Brutal,
and he was talking about how that's why
he's touring really has like,
I gotta make some money,
man.
God,
which is,
look,
if you've developed a nest egg,
like obviously has and all of a sudden
you're getting divorced.
Phil Hartman,
try to explain that to me once that I
was telling them to get a divorce for
his wife,
shot him in his sleep.
Ego will just give her half.
He goes,
he goes,
it's two thirds because the lawyers take
a third,
so it's a fucking scam.
He was.
He was just like,
oh my God.
Rabid about it.
It was,
oh my God,
I didn't think of that.
I was like,
Oh yeah,
the lawyers,
because they do.
They don't work for free.
You're not paying for your wife's lawyer
to fuck face.
You pay for both of them are brutal.
You pay for the the general of the army
that's fighting against you.
You pay for that.
General General is trying to rob you of
your resources.
Yeah,
and your checks and you've been selling
out arenas your whole life and they want
most of that.
They want the house that you sleep in on
everything they want.
They want to take away memories.
They want to steal the very foundation
of your happiness and prosperity.
Could Joe Rogan Joe Rogan have
everything go away?
Your kids are fine.
You your relationships,
cool.
Whatever.
Let's take that element out of it.
Let's just take the house,
the cash,
the bows and arrows.
It's all gone.
Could Joe Rogan go live in?
Let's just pick New York.
This is not a silly question,
but let's pick New York.
Could you go live down by Washington
Square Park in a studio,
apartment,
Heavier Act.
Have your fans go do your thing and kind
of be okay with a low bank account or
have you got.
Are you at an age now and you've,
you've had stability.
Do you feel like that would freak you
out?
Well,
it would definitely freak you out if you
all the sudden,
like one of the things that I've sort of
relied on is not needing anything.
Right?
So by not needing anything,
everything I do,
I do because I enjoy it.
Right.
So like if I do stand up I do it because
I enjoy it and if I do podcasts because
I enjoy it if I do the UFC is because I
enjoyed.
I enjoyed the money is done.
Don't get me wrong.
Sure.
But I'm not,
I'm not needy.
I'm not in a position where I'm like
worried about my next check so that
stuff.
So if I got to that.
Yeah.
No,
not even need that stuff.
Like neither stuff is kind of like if
you have a car and you can get around,
you've got food on the table and your
family's taken care of.
Everything else is kind of bullshit.
It's nice.
It's nice to have a good couch.
Like,
look,
we have a 70 inch TV.
Ooh,
this is nice.
It feels nice.
But Watch westworld and a 70 inch TV.
It's nice.
Look how big it is.
Woo.
Yeah.
But ultimately what really counts is,
are you nervous?
Are you nervous about your bills?
Because like,
do you remember that feeling?
Yeah,
that sounds terrible.
Feeling worried about where that's gonna
come from and what you're going to do,
but you still have your act.
You can still go make money,
but we're going to put you back at
square one.
We're going to put you in that studio
apartment.
Could you,
would you be cool with it?
Studios kind of small one like a four
bedroom house with a yard and some
working.
No,
but honestly the big thing,
and this is such a cliche,
but the big thing is do I still have my
friends?
Do I still have the same friends?
Because if I lived in an apartment
building and Ari Shaffir lived next door
and Duncan lived down the hallway and
joey was over the other side.
Yeah,
I don't have a great time.
Yeah.
We all lived on the same floor,
the same building.
I would have zero problem with that if
they knocked on the door.
Hey man,
you got any weed?
I'm going to wait.
Come on know.
Exactly.
That would be no problem at all.
It's like how much different is that
than when you stay on the road in the
hotel?
Because the hotel is like a studio
apartment.
Yeah,
and you're right.
Good percentage of our lives.
We stay in a studio apartment a lot.
I know that.
I really,
I,
I bring it up because I really.
I was thinking about it and it's like if
it all fell apart like you grew up,
you grab on to your lifestyle and what
you're doing so hard,
but if at all for whatever reason washed
away and you still go perform and you
still had your friends at this club,
you could see what it.
It's,
it's.
I could totally do it.
I could totally go back to I have
clothes that fit in this big of a closet
and just and just keep doing what I'm
doing,
but in those circumstances I 100
percent.
In some ways I think your.
You'd be lighter.
You'd be right.
A lot of people do believe that in a lot
of people do go towards that minimalism
life where they give up everything.
My friend Steve Maxwell,
he's a,
a really a world renowned fitness
trainer,
strength and conditioning coach for a
lot of pro
athletes,
a lot of fighters.
He lives out of a duffle bag.
Oh,
I saw that guy.
So you interviewed?
Yeah.
Uh,
he,
he used to have a big house and he had a
gym in Philadelphia you'd like one of
the very,
he's one of the very first American
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu black belt and he
had this gigantic jam where he's
teaching and he said,
you know,
he's an interesting guy.
And then he just decided he got
divorced,
right.
And he decided,
you know what,
fuck this.
He goes,
I'm going to live out of a van.
And he got like a camper van and he
lived out of that and he's like,
fuck this van.
I'm getting,
I'm just going to keep traveling really
now.
He just stays in hotels everywhere.
That's amazing.
And that's what brings it up.
It's the divorce.
I see.
I don't think,
I don't think willingly I would do it,
but if something was thrust upon,
like if you got divorced,
divorce or some something,
I would uh,
I could go back,
I could be like,
do,
but you're thinking about it so much
that you brought it up as a subject,
but this is something you wonder.
Uh,
yeah.
Not as far as the divorce part of it,
but just the simple life.
Yeah,
because I've built a life that's bigger
and more complicated and I,
uh,
you want to know what you want to know
what it was.
Last time I was in here,
I had had this back issue where it was
like shooting pain down my arm.
Yeah.
You had a cervical issue,
right?
Yeah,
and I was going to this really great
Cairo guy.
I was doing cupping,
I was doing all of this kind of stuff
and it was just making it worse.
I was just in words.
Oh yeah.
I was in,
I was in pain for like a year.
I was like in pain.
Gregg Rogell,
you know,
the comedian he tells me he had really
developed debilitating lower back pain
and he read some book I Read,
sorry.
He's like,
just read it and I got into this big
fight with him and,
and uh,
know him who owns the comedy cellar,
he's calling them a crack and it's a
crackpot and it doesn't work and all
this stuff.
And Greg is like,
just please read it,
just read it,
just read it.
And it's,
you know,
what it is.
It's just basically about that you're
carrying your brain wants to go to work
on something simple like pain in your
body rather than deal with issues of
stress and anxiety and anger that you
carry all the time and basically just
realizing that that's where the pain is
coming from.
Don't have to solve the anxiety or the
pain or the anger.
You just have to be aware of,
okay,
brain,
I know what you're doing,
I know what you're working on.
It just kind of alleviates that stress.
And then the physical manifestation of
not having oxygen go into your,
into your muscles and stuff starts to
slowly release and just it.
It's gone.
It's.
I have no pain.
I have no.
How long did it take after you read the
book and adopted the principles?
Like a month and a half.
Really?
Yeah.
So a year of pain and then a month and a
half of adopting these principles.
And what does he tell you to do?
Like what are the exercises that he
tells you to do?
He says,
just live.
Don't just a live your life exercise.
Whatever you were doing,
do it.
Don't live timidly.
Think I can't run now.
I can't do yoga now because I've got a
neck issue.
Do it live your life.
Don't live like in this preventative way
of I can't move or I'm going to mess up
my,
my body.
So what does he tell you about?
Like physical issues.
Like what if you have a herniated disc
and it's pressing against your nerve and
it's causing your hands to go numb and
your arms atrophying.
He says there's.
Those are very rare cases.
It's not that rare in my world.
I know.
Well,
yeah,
you're right,
but he said,
he says it's very rare cases where
there's like a real pinched nerve kind
of a problem.
It seems like crazy advice.
I know a lot of people that have like
real issues,
like real physical issues.
It's not a rare thing to have.
Like disc issues are gigantic.
Yeah,
because people,
they don't strengthen their spine
enough.
They don't drink near core enough and
they wind up doing something.
They Yank it,
they heard it,
and then they try to work around it and
they wanted to Rehab,
aggravating it,
and then it gets worse and worse.
You were saying that a lot of times
you'll have,
you'll have like your disk will be
bulging a little bit or whatever these
little imperfections are and we all have
these imperfections in us,
but when you are stressed and the
muscles are tightening around you and
becoming inflamed because you're
carrying this stuff that you're not
working through,
everything's constricting around it,
so then it's going to aggravate that and
that's going to become a bigger problem.
I definitely think that's true in some
cases,
but there's like there's legitimate,
like I had a conversation with a friend
of mine about this with the same sort of
a thing and I was like that.
That's all well and good,
but I know people who are very light and
happy people who develop a legitimate
back issue and it has nothing to do with
stress that they're carrying around.
It has to do with the soft tissue that
protects your joints,
bulging out and contacting a nerve.
Look.
There's a zillion of us out there and
I'm sure there's all different issues
for it,
but back to your original question of
why am I thinking about simplifying and
all this kind of stuff.
I am a pretty light positive person,
very optimistic,
very.
I kind of live in that world,
but when I just started reading the
book,
I'm like,
are things really pissing me off?
Am I stressed?
Do I have anxiety because I live in this
house because I'm trying to do these
things with my career because I'm trying
to always do this because I'm carrying
children and parents and all of this
stuff.
I'm trying to make everybody happy.
I'm just,
I don't know,
maybe just realizing that and thinking
about it.
I'm in no heavy meditation on it.
No,
just being aware that maybe that's where
it's coming from.
I'm telling you over a month and a half
the pain slowly went away and I don't
have it.
Hm.
Yeah.
That is interesting.
So what,
what was bothering you before?
Like I know that you're,
you know,
you're successful and you had a
television show for awhile and you've
got a bunch of projects going on.
You're always doing standup and
specials,
so you have had a lot of success.
You've got a lot of great stuff going
on.
What was,
what was kind of chewing at you?
I don't know.
I'm not really 100 percent sure of what
the sources,
but I do feel like I have a lot of
people on my back and it's all,
it's all quiet.
It's all in my head.
You know what I mean?
A lot of people on your back.
Yeah.
I've got a wife.
I've got,
I've got kids,
I've got pets,
I've got family.
I've got
in the end that you feel that was a
weird,
a weird way to bring,
bring,
bring this up,
but is that,
how much of that,
like having a wife and having kids,
obviously there's going to be
compromises and there's going to be
stressed that comes along with any sort
of relationship,
but do you feel like it was tipping more
towards the negative than towards the
positive?
Um,
I don't think it was.
I think I just,
uh,
the whole experience to me seems
positive.
My relationship with my wife is great.
The kids I adore,
I feel like it's all positive,
but I do carry the burden of everybody's
worries and everybody's wellbeing all
the time.
I was working on this axis,
this joke in my act before I started
thinking about all this stuff I had this
moment where I was standing in this
house.
I moved to this bigger house.
It's a really nice house to bigger,
bigger home and I was shutting off all
the lights is what I was working through
onstage and I was turning off all the
lights one night and locking the doors
for all the bad people that are coming
to get us and everyone's in their beds
and the cat's asleep and the dog's
asleep and everybody the lizard to sleep
and it just,
all my responsibility washed over me.
Like everybody,
every living thing here is,
is,
uh,
depending on my success.
If I don't keep going,
if I don't keep succeeding this,
everything here changes everybody's
little life.
Everybody's perfect little existence.
It's all washing over me and I can't
tell anyone about it.
I can tell you the audience,
but I can't go sit on my daughter's bed
at two in the morning when I have that
feeling.
Honey temper.
Do you ever feel like he just can't do
it anymore?
You ever feel like he can't,
he just want to stop.
He just wanted to take a break.
This whole thing about waking up my
daughter with my fears.
I can't do that.
I don't tell my wife that stuff.
I don't tell my kids that.
I just carry it.
So when I started reading this book I'm
like,
maybe I'm just taking all this really
seriously and feeling like
extended with the new home.
Is that it?
Because a lot of times I have a friend
of mine who did that recently bought a
big place and he can afford it,
but kind of.
Right.
You know,
it's like,
okay,
think about this.
Now I'm a.
I'm a big advocate and never doing that.
I don't think you should ever buy a big
place unless you're like,
hey,
we can get a nice place now.
I'm not even think about it.
Let's.
No,
we're totally.
We can do it.
And it seemed to be.
I hadn't really small place for a long
time and did all the right things,
so it's.
The outlay is no different from my
little place before.
It's all cool,
but when you walk into a place like
that,
it just feels bigger.
It just ain't no.
The first time I bought a home ever,
I had this little place in studio city.
It's a little,
you know,
I just,
I remember laying on the couch like,
hi,
I don't know if I can do this.
I've got to sign this paper and every
say years is a long back,
and every time the mail came for the
first year that I owned a home,
I thought it was going to be noticing.
You've got to get out of there now,
if you know what I mean.
I just was fearful about it.
Mortgages are weird,
man.
It's like you.
Here's a bill for 30 years,
right?
Yeah.
That's heavy.
That weighs on you.
Yeah.
So that's what it just brought me to the
feeling of like,
well maybe just going back and living
with my wife in that little studio
apartment in New York again,
wouldn't be so bad.
Kid's a freak out.
It would be.
The kids would free kids would hate it.
The kids would have to be gone,
dad,
you need to be more successful.
Take your pressure like a man.
What'd you downsize?
Who cares if your next crooked of a
bitch?
Who cares if your arms go numb?
I want to go to Berkeley.
Everything's clean your teeth,
so I don't know.
I mean because it's a little self-aware
moment because I do,
like I said,
I'm.
I feel like I'm pretty carefree,
but why the hell am was my neck so
well,
I think in stuff that was something that
resonated with Sarano,
his book and I remember a Howard stern
talking about it.
Yeah,
he had a similar situation.
I definitely think people carry a lot of
tension and then that tension sort of
manifested itself in physical pain,
but what I do is I do difficult things.
I like to do difficult things that are
way more difficult than comedy.
So if I'm doing Jujitsu or from
bowhunting for some of the workouts that
I do,
there's so much harder than,
than anything like out just yoga class.
Just a fucking 90 minute beak from Yoga
class in 140 degrees.
When you're going 100 percent,
I put 100 percent effort to every pose.
Like fucking pouring sweat.
It's difficult when you do that.
It seems to me,
at least in my,
with my fucked up brain,
that other stuff doesn't bother me.
It's not,
you're fucked up brain.
I equate this anxiety to stopping yoga.
I did yoga for,
I dunno,
eight years and I haven't done it in
three.
I'll get back in there,
man.
And I'm telling you,
I used to walk around like the biggest
advocate.
I'm like no.
Once I started,
you know,
stress here,
no pain here.
So everything.
But when you started giving those pains,
why didn't you just get back in?
I don't know.
I'll tell you what do I have no idea?
I don't know what the real answer is,
but in my head it's the classes from
nine till 10:30
and that's when I do my best writing
when the kids get out of the house and I
can write in the morning.
Oh,
okay.
That was,
that was my,
that's my lame ass excuse.
You just gotTa Force Yourself.
Yeah,
I forced myself just try and write some
other time.
You sit down and you don't sit down and
write,
write like you don't.
Oh yeah,
I do.
You do?
Oh yeah.
I thought you were a stage guy.
No,
no.
I'm a stage guy too.
Yeah.
Well I'm A.
I'm a firm believer like martial arts,
I think that you need to do.
I think you like if you wanted to be a
mixed martial artist and he only wanted
to work on your skill,
I think you're doing yourself a
disservice.
I think you need to do strength and
conditioning as well.
I think you need to do drills as well.
Spar,
I think comedy is the same way.
I think writing on stage and I think
there's a bunch of aspects that have
over the last few years.
I like to think that I've kind of got my
own way of doing it.
Everybody's got a different way.
Obviously everyone's got a different
style.
My own way though is a bunch of things.
One,
socialization.
I need to socialize.
Yeah.
I need to go out with friends.
I need to go have a drink or smoke some
pot with my buddies and we start
laughing and goofing around about things
or meet new people.
Talk to some interesting person like
this.
One of the things that I really like
about podcasts is to get to talk to
interesting,
cool people that kind of socializing
leads to new pathways of ideas get
expanded.
What made you think,
did you think of that are just
happening?
You look back like I remember thinking
somewhere along the line,
God,
I come up with a lot of great ideas for
bits when I'm having fun with people
having fun with friends or even with
people I don't even know if they're
like,
you know the occasionally you'll meet
someone that's really cool,
you enjoy talking to them and then you
have these cool conversations.
You see this perspective from a stranger
that's interesting and they say
something and then it fires something in
your own brain.
I think socializing is big and I think
that's one of the reasons why really,
really famous comedians hit a dead spot
later in their career because they're
circle becomes very small because they
only trust certain people and they.
They kind of get anxiety about hanging
out with regular folks and just going
out there.
Yeah,
they get isolated.
They drive limos everywhere.
They live in a mansion and they never
get to meet anybody.
Yeah,
so socialization is big.
Activity is big.
I need to do things you need to do.
I need to go places.
I need to see things.
I need to travel,
I need to.
I'm like,
I do a lot of different things.
I like to try to get as much activity as
possible,
but physical writing to me is a must.
I sit down in front of my computer and I
write.
I write all the time and I don't
necessarily write jokes.
I just write,
write,
and then the jokes come out of that
premise has come out of that stuff.
I'm more essays.
I love that.
That's one of my favorite parts of
standup is just being by myself and
writing.
Just that part,
that mining,
you know,
you're just mining.
Exactly.
And then once in awhile you get this
great stuff that comes out.
A lot of times nothing comes out.
That's the biggest challenge of writing
is getting out of your way and not
beating yourself up.
If everything that comes out isn't
great.
Yup.
Most of it isn't
great.
I think one of the biggest challenges of
writing is discipline.
That's one of the biggest challenges
because most people just don't know if
you're a writer of your comic and
someone does no one telling you you have
to do it because you have this open
ended schedule.
Like you could have gone to yoga.
Yeah.
From nine to 10:30
and he chose to write like you and you
might have chosen to write because yoga
is too hard.
You might've decided,
you know,
writing is too difficult.
I'm just going to.
Or Yoga is too difficult.
I'm just kidding.
Right.
I mean it could be one of one of,
you know,
either reasons.
Yeah,
it's a no,
it,
I should do both.
I should.
You said,
you know,
I,
I always try with writing also to not be
so rigid.
Like there was a time when I could only
write on the computer in the morning up
until 10 and it's like that's stupid
because sometimes I don't have my
computer.
Sometimes I just have a pad and I'm in a
coffee house after doing radio at 11,
so why not do that?
So my thing now is I just make myself
sit down for two hours at some point,
whatever.
It doesn't matter if it's late in the
day,
night,
whatever it is.
That's like your workout.
It's like you've got to sit.
Just sit.
Do you ever read on your phone?
Yeah.
You know what's amazing about riding on
the phone?
If you have an iphone or even.
There's actually a lot of them now.
Use notes.
Yeah.
Notes and um,
and then dictated.
Oh yeah.
Is it accurate?
Super accurate.
Really?
Yeah.
You never tried it like that.
I'll show you right here.
So right here,
press that button right there.
This is the iphone.
I've got an interesting story about
this.
Are you writing notes?
Go off.
Yeah,
that's it.
No,
it's a press.
The voice thing.
Tom.
Papa is a bad motherfucker.
Bam.
Wow.
Amazing.
Right?
It's so true.
This dude,
he writes in the morning when he's
supposed to be taken yoga,
his next all fucked up and he doesn't
know why,
but he's a good guy and he's hilarious.
Go see him this Friday on Epix.
Thanks Joe.
Man.
Hilarious.
Yeah,
it's all right.
It's not perfect.
No,
but that's pretty good.
Meanwhile,
what the fuck is hilarious.
Hey.
No,
that's a pretty bad.
Was worse.
It keeps.
It keeps dictating.
It still talking.
It's getting this whole.
It just said what the fuck is hilarious.
Do you do that when you're driving?
Yes.
That's how I do text if I have to.
If I'm driving.
I try not to do that though.
What I do when I'm driving,
this is a big one for me is I've turned
the phone upside down and I put it over
there.
I don't have a near me when you're
driving.
It's too creepy.
It's like too many people are fucking
driving and not paying attention and
they crash into each other.
I know it's the worst.
It's way too common.
So bad.
I fucking.
Every time I'm on the road and I see
someone weaving in and out of traffic,
I see the light of their phones in their
eyes and they try to text while they're
driving.
It's so dangerous.
I know.
My daughter is.
My oldest one is 14,
which means she can get a permit next
year,
like 15 and a half that she text.
She's not crazy.
She's,
you know,
she's like a normal kid but she's not
like really obsessed with it,
but I just,
it scares the hell out of me once they
start getting one little chips.
Yeah.
One nuts when things get so yes.
So crazy fucking.
Although the energy involved in
relationships for young kids,
you might get on kid.
They go from being 11 where hopefully
there's no fucking at all.
Yeah.
Two 15 where that's all you're thinking
of.
Yeah.
Just in you know,
40 something months
and then.
And then he doesn't call.
You are likely aware there's a problem
and you're waiting and you're checking
your phone every two seconds to see the
response and now you're driving to go
pick up milk for your mom and you hear a
ding and you reach over to check it.
Boom.
Hit a tree.
I can't.
Yeah.
My neck just started hurting again.
Oh,
the arms now.
Massive,
massive fucking hormones raging through
your body,
telling you to get pregnant,
telling you to get someone pregnant.
Could you imagine if we had phones when
we were going through puberty?
Could you imagine all the Dick Pics that
you would have?
Oh my.
You wait.
The begging,
the begging of girls to show me
something.
Do something please.
My God,
he'd be out of.
I don't know,
but on the other hand,
you'd be wiser.
Yeah,
because you'd be able to google things.
I mean,
how many bullshitters did we know
growing up?
It just would lie and make stories up.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Those people were out of business,
but not necessarily.
Have you been paying attention to fake
news?
Yeah,
big time of fake news stories.
A big time.
It's crazy.
Like I didn't realize until this pizza
gate thing,
which by the way,
it's a very controversial,
what's fake and what's not fake about
pizza gate because pizza gate is
connected to that.
John Podesta Guy who is a very
controversial character who still
friends with that Dennis Hastert Guy who
was the speaker of the house who's
absolutely a pedophile.
Yeah,
absolutely.
A confirmed serial pedophile admitted,
admitted,
admitted.
So the fact that that guy is friends
with that.
And then also Andrew Breitbart
apparently in 2011 was made a tweet
about Podesta being a guy who helps
people who fuck kids.
Yeah.
And it was like he made this crazy tweet
about him in 2011,
which five years later after Breitbart
is dead.
It's a.
it's a very interesting to read that
tweet and say,
well,
what did he know about Podesta before
all this spirit cooking and all this
craziness came out with the Hillary
campaign.
He fucking knew something,
you know?
And this was.
Yeah,
like,
pull up,
pull up the tweet.
This is from 2011.
How Prague,
Prague,
like Progressive Guru John Podesta isn't
household name as world class underage
sex,
slave op cover,
upper defending,
unspeakable dregs escapes me.
Now.
This was of course when hastert was
about to get convicted,
so he's been friends with hastert
forever.
Has stirred by the way,
was the fucking speaker of the house and
he had been fucking kids for years.
So anybody who doesn't think that it can
reach you could be a pedophile and
covered up and reach high levels of
government.
You are mistaken.
So it is possible Penn State football
program.
Exactly.
But that obviously wasn't government,
but yeah.
But did work with a lot.
I mean he had a god damn charity.
Yeah.
A lot of people trust and Dusky would,
would work with young kids and take them
on the road and fuck them.
Oh yeah.
Yay.
Monster.
Aye Yai Yai.
But the point is like fake news.
This podesta thing in this.
I mean who knows what's real and what's
not real is my point because like this
fake news thing is what people are
calling pizza gate is this whole this
comet pizza thing.
So some guy walked into that Comet Ping
Pong place,
uh,
yesterday with a loaded assault rifle
and a,
an ar and fucking shot around and the
ground and the building pointed a gun at
the employee and demanded to know like
where the sex dungeons were.
Really?
Yeah.
Cause he,
he was convinced that their,
their fucking kids in this school.
Oh my God.
Here's the thing with the fake news,
I had this discussion with,
uh,
with my daughter actually,
and um,
we were talking about like,
how are we just entering an era where
you're never going to know what's real
and what's not like thing is going to be
so sophisticated on both sides that
you're never gonna be able to Parse it.
And she had a great point.
She said,
you know,
when we do papers at school and my wife
who's in college now,
uh,
when they do papers for school,
they have to because of the Internet,
because there's so much stuff you have
to,
um,
provide the sources for where your
information is coming from.
When you're writing these papers,
you have to have a legitimate source
attached to any of the facts that you're
putting in there so that they know that
you did the research and stuff.
And there's point being there's like
real.
There will always be really legitimate
news sources where you can cite that
people agree that this is a,
a,
a place where it's been filtered or not
filtered,
but it comes from a newsworthy source.
You can't just spew stuff and just put,
you know,
such and such website and have that pass
in an in an academic setting.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Like there is that little way of
parsing.
The truth will probably end up being the
way that we all parsed the truth.
I agree with you to a certain extent.
I think that like legitimate studies and
things that were done by legitimate
researchers where they have peer
reviewed studies and everything's been
vetted out,
but news sources are so suspect now what
we saw from this past election,
whether you support trump or whether you
support hillary sport,
anybody.
What I saw from this election is very
little unbiased truth.
What I saw was a lot of,
whether it's pro hillary or anti hillary
pro trump or anti-trump,
I sound a lot of editorial influence.
Yeah,
and you saw that on television.
You saw that in the New York Times.
You saw them,
the Washington Post's.
Do you saw that in what we would think
of as legitimate news sources without
bias?
They're not.
They're just not anymore.
And you know,
there's some certain people that felt
like as a person with their own point of
view and perspective and thoughts on the
burden that one carries by having a
voice,
that it's imperative that they get out
what they believe about a certain
candidate.
Especially with trump.
It could be slanted,
but there's still,
there's still is,
did this thing happen or not happen?
You know what I mean?
Did your tax return really right?
Was that information like,
did we all see it?
You know what I mean?
You can slant things and you know,
Fox can put those dangerous things
that's dangerous even that's dangerous
because you could take one aspect of it
and completely ride it into the ground
and make it look like,
look,
here's one thing they were.
They kept harping on about the all these
conspiracy theories,
theories about Hillary being ill
bullshit.
She falls asleep while she's standing up
that's ill,
she's not healthy like.
And they would try to.
That was editorial influence on the fact
of her being an old lady who fell down
in 2012 and got brain damage,
cracked her head open.
He was like,
literally,
according to Bill Clinton was
convalescing for six months.
This is his perspective.
He said she was in real bad shape and it
took her six months to get out of it.
There was the wikileaks emails that show
that she had a seizure in 2015 during
the presidential campaign.
She's at that nine slash 11 memorial.
She passes out and all those six
security people scooping and catcher
because they were there quick like,
it's fucking happened before.
Like,
this is not,
this is not an unusual occurrence.
I don't think.
I think they did a real good job of
covering it up,
but there was so many media stories that
we're talking about the conspiracy
theory of her being ill or that there
was so much.
Um,
so many people were latching on to her
health and obviously she showed in that
debate that,
or helped was fine.
Well,
first of all,
she's on drugs,
but they put her on Modafinil.
That was another thing that was listed
in the wikileaks.
She's taking provigil,
she's taking this,
uh,
this stimulant that they give the
fighter pilots,
keep them from falling asleep.
It's a drug for people that have
narcolepsy,
like she's on this,
so like,
yeah,
that's probably why she looks stimulated
and she's.
She's artificially propped up,
so this is a.
This to me was a big sticking point.
It's like I'm not,
I'm not anti Hillary.
I'm anti a lot of the things she stands
for,
but I'm not pro trump.
I watched that.
I was like,
well,
you're not being honest with me.
She's,
you're not supposed to fall asleep while
you're standing up.
If you fall asleep while you're standing
up,
there's a real problem.
You shouldn't be doing anything.
You should be in bed and find out what's
wrong with you.
Yeah,
you should.
You definitely shouldn't be running the
world.
It just propping you up.
I really felt like every time you'd see
her walking out towards the podium,
that the biggest,
the biggest worry of hers was not
tipping over to just hear fall on the
jet when she got to the top stairs of
the jet and she tipped for the one
fucking on camera.
Did you ever see that?
And I never saw watch.
Pull that video up.
And then why we can't walk and why was
she was a little bit of a cold.
The fucking guy was working on this.
I don't know.
Maybe it does.
Coke.
Are you worried about sessions coming in
and ending all the fun?
Look at it.
First of all,
she can't walk without holding onto that
railing.
She's clutching that thing.
It's hard for everybody.
Shit.
She gets to the top.
She's slowing down.
Look,
she's slowing down a lot of steps.
It's probably all light.
Haven't headed.
All right,
here we go.
You're good to budget.
Good to do.
She can't walk.
So funny to stop.
This is not good.
None of this is good.
Fall down.
It happens the fuck out of here.
It doesn't fall like that.
I sometimes come across the stage at the
comedy store.
I have to make sure my foot's plan
turned around and I go like this.
I'm fine.
It's hard.
Walking around.
Bullshit.
Get on.
Was a lot of steps.
Nope.
That was a lot of steps.
My mind couldn't run the free world
while your mom shouldn't be president.
She's.
She's like Hillary's age.
She shouldn't be president.
I think physical health,
this is something that you should take
into consideration when you have an
unbelievably stressful job that looks
like it drains you,
like a vampire sucking on your neck.
I couldn't believe both of them were
still standing at the end.
I mean it was.
So when you think about the travel and
the speeches and the pressure groups,
both of them.
I mean really that was that they were
buying.
Yeah,
he seemed fine.
He did.
When he gave that last one at 1:30
in the morning and Michigan or whatever.
We're like six that day and he's just
like.
He just kept going.
Yeah.
Oh,
I don't know what fast food.
Yeah,
he's eating pizza.
Fried Chicken,
Taco bowls.
TACO false.
I remember that picture when he's eating
a Taco bowl and he goes,
I love Hispanics.
I'm like,
what in the fuck is this life?
He says,
I love Hispanics.
He's eating a Taco bowl in the office
where he runs his empire.
I'm like,
this is madness.
That picture.
Look at that.
A good look at that.
The Best Taco bowls are made in trump
tower grille.
I love Spanish.
That is so crazy.
It's so crazy.
The whole thing is insane.
Meanwhile,
he didn't even eat that.
He pushed that aside and they brought
him a fucking ribeye sessions is going
to come in and this pot fund for the
nation.
He really thinks so.
That's what they're saying.
Yeah.
That's not what they're saying.
If they're saying,
no,
no.
I've read all the articles.
It's all speculation and it's based on
his statements.
Maybe it's based on his past statements
about marijuana not being for good
people and also based on what he could
potentially do as the attorney general.
However trump has said that he's going
to leave it up to the states.
I think that trump is a populist and I
think that the last thing trump wants
his people more people,
especially the potheads rallying against
them and saying this is preposterous.
If you look at the actual fear that that
people have about marijuana versus the
physical effects of marijuana versus the
potential revenue gain by these states.
Look at what's happened in Colorado real
estate sales rep for 14 percent.
Drunk driving is down to the lowest rate
it has in decades.
A violent crime is at the lowest rate.
It's been a long time.
There's so many positive benefits to the
marijuana legalization movement.
It's amazing.
Isn't it amazing when you walk through
Denver with the change?
Prosperous.
Oh my God.
It's amazing.
I went in and uh,
I went to one of the shops when I was
performing there last month and,
uh,
I just wanted to go do it,
you know,
I wasn't even looking to get high.
I just wanted to walk in and buy
something legit and walk out and just
see what that was like.
Very rarely.
Now,
how about right now we're doing.
I do,
but I can't.
I got to pick up kids.
How frequently that if I do it my day
shot,
you know what we're talking about.
Difficult things that make life easier.
One of the difficult things I like to do
is edibles.
Yeah.
You know,
it's funny when you're special.
You actually talked about the gummy
bears.
Yeah.
And I bought gummy bears when I was
there.
This is how out of it I am now.
Like I used to,
I used to do it every day,
you know,
and now I haven't for like a decade.
I'm so out of it now that I got back to
my room with the gummy bears was like
scared.
We don't know how much do I take the
whole point.
That's.
Know what I mean?
I really believe that they're like
running an ultra marathon or something.
Like you should be scared when you take
those first couple of steps.
Like,
Jesus,
what am I getting myself into?
Yeah,
but it's.
I don't know.
I'm old school.
I guess I like it.
I'd like to see it and crumble it and
puff it and know exactly what I'm doing.
That's nice too,
but it's a different thing than the
eating and the eating and the eating it
because it's scary.
Oh,
be for that reason.
Yeah.
I liked the journey.
I like it.
It,
it makes me feel super vulnerable and it
makes me feel like really in tune with
any weird distractions I might have in
my psyche.
Any weird bumps in the night that are
haunting the back
of my brain.
It just drags them out like get out here
in the front,
pulls them and put a spotlight on the
click.
Tell me what's wrong.
I just want to get high and watch
narcos.
I like that to really.
So you do it literally.
Are you joking?
No,
no,
I'm dead.
I'm dead serious.
It's the little bit of the unknown.
Almost trippy kind of anxiety.
Like when you eat mushrooms or something
and you're like,
okay,
let's.
What's going to come out with.
Where are we headed?
Well,
that's why I liked the sensory
deprivation tank too because you can't
run from your thoughts,
traps you with your thoughts and you
have to confront them.
Right.
It's the what I call the hard work,
like doing the hard work,
the mental hard work.
It was like you got be like I,
I.
One of the things I've tried,
I have tried to pride myself in,
at least I shouldn't say.
One of the things I've done as a,
an exercise and as I've done it like as
a discipline is try to constantly and
consistently improve everything.
I do whatever I'm doing,
whether it's martial art thing or or
comedy thing and I feel like your
personality is in that too and even
podcasting is in that,
like anything that you're doing,
you just try to do better and I don't
always succeed,
but there's a,
there's a journey and a process along
the way and what I've found is the hard
work is the best way for me to really
judge my progress and all those things
because I'm forced to be alone with my
thoughts and to be at least the way I
approach it.
I try to be as objective as possible.
I'm my number one biggest critic.
Like I fucking hate everything I do.
That's why you're good.
Yeah.
When you sit alone with your thoughts
and you think about everything you do
and you could pick it apart and find
problems with it.
Yeah.
That's the hard work.
Yeah,
it's a,
that's a,
that's a big thing.
And,
and you know,
smoking,
let you come in the other door and take
a look at what you thought was okay.
You know what I mean?
If you think like if you've got the
structure and you think you're being
hard on yourself and then you come in
the back door and you're like,
oh,
maybe I'm a little hacky over here.
You can take some of this and go through
the fucking roof.
Like an asteroid.
Fuck that door.
You don't want the door.
I've got a lot of stuff in here,
buddy.
I went,
well,
what was funny was he was one of these.
Or put you on the moon.
What's that?
Chocolate cheese.
You can smell the pot through the
wrapper.
I need to know what I'm getting into.
Getting into death,
death and just the inevitability.
The only I can see from the pills.
Pills,
pills.
Let me see what they look like.
The only negative I could see one
walking around Denver was.
There's a lot of scuzzy skate pothead
kids that are like laying on the street.
You're always gonna get that.
Yeah,
but it's a little different.
That's just part of the problem.
It's,
you know,
you always get.
Yeah,
there's always the 14 always going to be
the case.
It was funny coming out with my bag,
filled with stuff and not being afraid
of the cops who just waved to me.
But then the pot heads who want it.
Sorry,
Geez,
I got stuff to do.
You'll be fine.
I'm like,
my secondhand smoke barely does
anything.
I'm like your pet dog.
I got my dog so high once I had a um,
a rescue dog and she was a big sweetie.
I loved her.
She had a rough life before I got her.
When I got her,
she had mange.
Oh ma'am.
Oh she,
I got her because someone who I knew had
rescued her like that day and uh,
it was in la and they had found her
eating out of a garbage can and she was,
she was all fucked up,
like main Ge.
And they contacted me and they said,
hey,
I'm just a long shot.
Do you want to adopt a dog?
Because I had a dog.
And I'm like,
well,
you know,
probably wouldn't be a bad idea to have
my dog,
you know,
get a companion.
I go and then they told me and I'm like,
oh no,
like,
wow,
that's a lot to take on.
And checked her out.
Was she older?
Um,
she was,
she had had babies for sure because her
nipples were extended.
We didn't really know how old she was.
She was probably in the neighborhood of
two or three,
but she was the sweetest dog ever.
She so sweet.
What kind?
She was a pit bull.
She had a rough life.
It was a rough life.
And um,
when I had her in my house,
uh,
Joey Diaz and I,
we,
uh,
went into my office and she would come
in the office and hang out with me and
we did bong hit,
bong hit and this poor dog got hot box.
Figure out what was going on because she
was freaking out,
freaking out.
And she was like hiding under desks.
Like she would run,
she would run across the room and they
just get under the desk or I guess
tucked in and we're like,
oh my God,
she's high.
The poor dogs.
Hi.
So yeah,
you can get someone,
you can get that.
Uh,
I uh,
I can,
I think that,
uh,
I hope you're right.
I hope that,
you know,
what the most interesting thing watching
this whole trump thing,
like I hope you're right about sessions,
I think it's going to be really
interesting.
I feel like we're watching one of those
movies where like the regular guy
becomes president and he comes in like,
well,
just fix the problem,
just the taxes and fix the bridge.
That's how it works.
And like these practical,
like things that you could do,
like let's just talk to Taiwan and
Siemens maybe they'll be okay and it's
like,
will this work or do or is the way of
operating with so immeshed in policy and
the way that things were,
do you need that structure to actually
steer the ship?
You know what I mean?
This is really kind of free form your
writing.
I think in that sense that's probably
the most positive aspect
of this guy being president is that we
really will find out.
Yeah,
it might be the only way we find out
where you're going to find out.
We've got to really find out to find.
And also he's going to fucking tell us
like if there's some shit is funky
behind the scenes,
you know,
like there's a lot of talk online about
trump lying and his tweets about like
fake votes,
you know,
like fake votes cost him the popular
vote.
Like he just sometimes he just says shit
man.
I don't know if he is doing it as a
strategy.
I don't know.
I mean,
I,
it's,
it's also possible that he doesn't
really believe it,
but that he knows that if he puts it out
there,
people are going to repeat it.
Yeah.
There was an article in recently that I
saw,
I forget what the magazine was,
Jamie,
maybe you could find it,
but it was about a guy who writes the
fake news and they track this dude down
and he just writes fake stories like
about George Soros paying protests is
350 bucks an hour to test against trump.
Like you just make stuff up.
Yeah.
And they asked him why he did it and
what he said was,
he said essentially he started out as
like an exercise we'll sort of to prove
how gullible these all right folks could
be.
Some of them,
at least some of them would just see
things without looking into it at all.
They would just start tweeting it.
Yeah.
You know.
And,
and he was right.
He was right.
But he started making a lot of money.
Right?
These guys are making like $10,000
a month writing fake store clicks of
clicks.
That's.
Yeah.
Then you're writing fake stories.
Now we're going to pass that up.
You know,
you're going to just write fake stories
now.
So like what you were saying earlier
about like us entering into an era where
you can't really tell what's true or not
true.
And like if that's the case,
I mean that's why it's so imperative
that someone like the Washington Post or
the New York Times cannot be biased in
any way.
You have to like,
as clearly as you can emphasize the
facts of every story.
Even if you feel like you have an
obligation to show how horrible person
president trump is,
just to let people know,
like,
this guy can't get in the office.
As soon as you start doing that,
you embolden the people who oppose you.
Like it's very dangerous for ideas in
general because it's so hard.
Like I.
I'm not,
I don't do it,
but it's so.
It's so hard for anybody to completely
be unbiased and establish just the
facts.
Even when they're disturbing and
uncomfortable.
They don't like that too.
People don't like that.
You ever watch PBS news?
The News Hour?
Yeah.
That's probably as pure as you can get,
right?
I mean that's just purely as factual as
we can put it out there and it doesn't
mirror a lot of anything else.
CNN,
MSNBC,
or Fox,
that's all that.
That PBS has.
Just it feels like it's the last place
where grownups work.
This person makes $10,000
a month writing fake news.
Yeah.
This
is just make stuff up,
but what is the website?
Jamie?
This one was from market watchers,
also an NPR story.
I think the Martin watches the one that
I read.
I think that's the,
the,
one of the problems with the fake news
too is I have a guy drives me to the
airport all the time and he's like,
no,
I saw George Soros is paying the people
to protest and my wife,
I saw it on facebook and my wife said,
no,
that's not a story.
And he said,
but look,
now it's on CNN.
They're talking about the same story.
So it is true.
The problem is all these people editing
these news organizations,
they're running with the story.
They're being tricked by the fake news
to begin with.
Wow.
Jesus Christ.
I know.
It's very slippery.
She see the fake porn going on at CNN
for 30 minutes of fake porn during
Anthony Bourdain show out like
Thanksgiving night.
Yeah.
It's a total fake story.
Everyone else did it.
That it was real.
Yeah.
That,
uh,
that was something somebody just thought
it'd be funny to.
Did he even have a photoshop screenshot
or something like that?
Yeah,
that's genius.
I mean it's,
you know,
the scary thing is a,
that's how wars start,
right?
That's how Vietnam started getting a
little carried away when they created
the take down a notch where we created
this fake stories,
Iraq,
same stuff.
It's,
you can manipulate stuff.
You can create big events off of that.
Well,
here obviously we don't know what really
has gone on that lead to people.
Right in that pizza gate stuff.
I don't,
I didn't investigate it enough to know
if it's bullshit or not.
I just didn't look into it and to be
honest,
that's it.
What if it was bullshit and if it is
bullshit and this guy thought it was
real and he goes in and what have you
shot somebody who's as.
I mean,
at what point is there some sort of
responsibility like as a,
as a culture,
like when,
if someone's inciting hate towards him,
very specific establishment that really
hasn't done anything wrong,
right?
Like that's kind of a criminal act,
In a way,
if you're saying like if you,
if you pick a donut shop,
yum,
yum.
Donuts side of yum.
Yum.
Donuts is where the elites go to fuck
kids,
right?
You just make all that up and then
people show up a yum,
yum donuts and just start shooting
people because you won't tell them where
you're fucking the kids.
That's decades.
Again,
this is just.
If it's a fake story,
I don't know.
Shit.
I'm just going to be real clear about
that.
I literally have.
I.
There's so much kids who.
Well,
you should look into it.
No,
I shouldn't you.
If you want to.
You go ahead.
Dear.
You cannot be responsible for every
fucking story that's in the news today.
You will lose your mind and I'm trying
to do less and less of that in my life,
but my point is what we know for a fact.
There's a lot of fake stories.
We also know for a fact.
There's a lot of creeps.
Yeah,
a lot of scary,
sketchy people that are in positions of
power and they have been forever and
they're starting to get exposed more
than they ever have been before,
so I don't know the
fuck the truth.
That's kind of the interesting thing.
That's it's the good and bad of the time
that we live in.
Everything can be exposed now,
which is great.
Like you can expose people being brutal
to another group.
You can expose crimes by just recording
it on your phone.
You can't get away with stuff anymore
because everyone's on video all the
time.
So in that way,
the truth has never been more clear.
But if it's.
But then you have this manipulation of
that truth in certain instances where
you don't have that video proof.
It's uh,
it's right.
I mean it's very conflicting.
Well,
it's what we were talking about earlier
when we were saying about fake stories
that it's,
we're getting to this weird era where
you can't tell whether or not a story is
true or not.
Like he gets really sketchy,
gets really strange.
I think there's going to be.
This is just pure speculation,
pure bro Science.
Nice.
Giving you a bro.
Science warning.
My favorite kind is the only kind of
understand I think the other doing these
things where they're able to transmit
words from person to person through the
Internet,
brain to brain.
Like somehow or another I can't,
I'm not going to do a good job
explaining it,
but they've been able to essentially put
a word in your head and then do it
accurately from a long distance away
through some sort of electrical impulse
or something that they blast into your
head,
but right now it's like like a word,
a word.
I think it's entirely possible within
our lifetime that one day someone is
going to figure out how.
If you can do that,
if you could transmit something from
brain to brain like that through the
Internet,
through some sort of an interface,
they're going to figure out how to.
How to broadcast intention,
so instead of a language,
they're going to figure out how to
broadcast what the feeling is behind you
thinking something like if I say,
Hey,
Tom,
papa has a comedy special on epics this
Friday night,
you should definitely see it.
He's fucking hilarious.
He's a great guy and I really want you
guys to check that out.
There's a feeling that comes with that
of feeling like,
you know,
I really love you.
You're a great guy.
You're hilarious.
I want your specialty to kick ass,
but so that's like an intention and that
intention is in some way trapped inside
a language.
It's trapped inside like language in
civilization and all the structures that
we've created around it,
but if you could somehow remove the
language and just what is the intention
behind.
I love you.
What's the intention behind?
I would like to paint something
beautiful like what is it outside of the
words you would use to describe it in a
sentence.
If they could figure out some sort of
maybe icon based or some geometric
pattern based language.
New Language you can express.
Yeah,
and we would have to learn that
language,
right?
But it would be an intention based
language where wouldn't matter what your
language,
whether you speak German
or French.
It's a little like minority report.
Then they will take take that you had
this intention to kill someone and they
come and arrest you before it happens.
Well,
I just feel like everything that's
happening in the brain,
right,
it's all trapped in the brain and then
gets expressed through either the
fingers or through the mouth right now
through the body,
but it's all.
These are all these ideas are rolling
around inside the body and then then
they get expressed through something.
Right?
What if there's a way to get right to
them?
You where you don't need the book.
You don't need to do the double birds,
right?
You don't.
You know you can.
You could express that through the
actual things that are going on in
between your ears.
Still Change.
Standup for sure.
It will be for us.
Walk out onstage that guys hilarious and
will be like blockbuster video of art
forms.
People will still want songs.
Songs will always be cool when you can
read minds.
No one wants to hear your stupid joke.
Yeah,
you're stupid jokes.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know if a.
sounds like that's a total stoner
science,
right?
Yeah.
That's definitely a long way off.
Now there's someone right now writing
this down because this dude,
he's got a spectrum,
but I can do it.
He's um,
he's ambitious and he's got an idea.
You can make it true.
Well,
if you have those htc vive headsets on,
have you ever put those things on you?
Jesus Christ,
they're a game changer.
But you mean the virtual reality stuff?
Yes.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's a couple different ones.
Now there's a rift.
I didn't,
I don't know the Samsung,
but the HTC is one.
Samsung has one that you slide right
into your,
uh,
like a phone,
right?
You can sign a phone to do it.
Oh,
you said your phone into the thing?
Yeah.
You have like a dog,
like the Google Pixel.
Is that too?
It was like,
right?
Yeah.
And you slide it in.
I did that with the New York Times.
Hadn't one.
They sent like a cardboard one and slide
it in and all of a sudden you're with
the refugees in Syria walking down the
street.
You're looking around you and there's
people behind you and in front of you.
Fucking bizarre.
Yeah.
It looks pretty intense.
Well,
they can do that now.
Like the processing power of phones is
pretty good.
The crazy thing is like you could take a
regular smart phone.
It's not bad,
but it's not as good as like the the
high end ones and we're in an infancy of
this stuff.
Most people don't even know what it is
when you bring it up.
Yeah,
it's coming to Dunkin has one.
When you're in this underwater
environment in a whale comes up to say
hi to you know,
and you're like,
Holy Shit.
Fuck in front of me.
You're like looking at the whales.
I.
You're like,
Oh,
this is so weird.
Because you really feel like you're at
the bottom of the ocean and these things
swim overhead.
You watched them.
Holy Cow.
Oh my God.
It's a mind fuck.
So you could walk in,
sit in the sit in the chair and watch a
standup show you one special,
100 percent.
Next aspect of doing your special would
be releasing it that way.
Great idea.
That is Kevin Hart's already done it.
He's probably,
he's done it in a football field with a
jet pack with a whale.
Comes through the middle.
Katt a on stage.
Did you ever see that and a fuck?
Yeah.
Kat Williams.
Thank you for being here.
He's the best.
Thank you for being alive.
That guy makes me laugh so hard.
He's fucking funny because he's so
crazy.
People kind of forget how funny he is.
Oh my God.
His early stuff like going after Michael
Jackson and stuff.
Oh,
so good.
So good.
He's funny,
man.
Pure,
original,
funny as hell.
Wild mother fucker.
Guys live a life.
He's not worried about back pain.
He doesn't have responsibility of.
He's not worried about getting his kids
to school.
He's just being cat.
He's cannon.
Fist fights with 17 year olds and losing
that's right in the yard.
The kid beat his ass around,
took his back and he's like super lucky.
That kid didn't give him brain damage.
I love how everybody else's realizing.
Wait,
I think that's Kat.
Kat Williams is getting into God Damn
Street fight with a young kid.
That was hilarious.
He sucker punched the kid.
Something tells me cats not sitting down
with that notebook every morning like I
have to do this.
Maybe.
I mean,
he seems like one of those guys that
just flies feel like he also,
like maybe I think he's a little smarter
than people give them credit for and I
think it's entirely possible that he
might in some sort of a weird,
whether it's conscious or subconscious
way put himself in these horrible
situations.
So he has funny shit to talk about.
I don't know.
My instinct is he just ends up in those
things and that.
So that's the beauty that comes out the
end.
You might be right,
but I don't think he's as calculated.
You might be right.
It might be.
It might be a little bit of both things.
Yeah.
But the thing is,
he's very smart,
man.
You can't be that funny and not be
smart.
He,
um,
said something that I,
I was like,
oh yeah.
Like I was listening to this video,
it was him in the backseat of a limo and
he's drunk driving around.
And uh,
there was talking about before he goes
on stage and one of the things that he
said was that he doesn't eat anything,
don't eat.
He goes,
you know,
I wanna I don't want to be full when I'm
onstage.
I don't want to feel like that.
You like,
you want to eat better off being hungry.
Like you don't want to be slowed down by
food.
I'm like,
that's a great idea.
Yeah,
I know that.
But yet I would still violate that if I
was hungry.
Like I'd rather like if I had a show at
8:00
and I was kind of hungry at seven,
I'll eat a fucking cheeseburger.
You would?
Yeah,
for sure.
I'm going to drink a milkshake really
for the longest time I would just eat
whatever the fuck I wanted to daily.
I could never do that.
But then I watched that Kat Williams
thing and I went,
you know what?
He's right.
You really shouldn't eat before you go
on stage.
Like you can always have like a little
bit in between chose.
But when you have a meal,
you go down enough.
You just slow down a little bit.
Yeah.
Oh,
absolutely.
You might be able to power now if
I'm in.
If I'm in trouble.
The hardest part about being on the road
is windy.
You eat.
I really feel like the timing of when
you eat and when you're going to perform
and all that stuff.
So if I get past the 4:00,
like if I eat like late early in the
afternoon and then getting too close to
the show,
it's not enough for a meal.
Then I'll try and a protein bar at to
get me through the show.
Something light that's,
you know,
I'm not going to be up there digesting.
I remember Jim Carrey,
there was in some interview the guy who
directed him in like ace Ventura or
something and they said get all of this
stuff before lunch because once he eats
he's a different guy.
Like that hyper hilarious Jim Carey.
You got to get that in the morning
because once he starts eating it's a
different guy.
No Shit.
Yeah,
it makes sense,
right?
I mean you get like,
oh,
I just want to nap.
Yeah.
You can't be like ace ventura,
pet detective,
you can't be pulling your ass cheeks
apart.
When you think about how over the top
that fucking movie was,
he was so over the top,
like he took over the top to a new
place,
a whole nother place.
You know,
like people who would say like,
you know,
like physical comedy doesn't really
work.
Like maybe if you have asset.
Yeah.
But if you go balls out like that guy
does,
you tell me.
That's hilarious.
Like pet detective till to this day.
I'll watch that and it's fucking
hilarious.
Just hiking his pants up is hilarious.
Observed human beings just get the
camera,
get the camera on this guy with his
facial expressions and running around
me.
Created this incredibly bizarre
character.
Like what the fuck am I watching?
But it was so over the top.
So funny.
He's hilarious.
When I was in high school,
I would,
I would imitate him.
His invitations.
Remember when he did,
he had that set where he was doing like
on golden pond.
He was like,
strawberries,
strawberries.
He did the whole,
the whole golden pond.
He did all these great impressions.
Oh yeah.
You can do a lot of impressions.
That's how I would,
uh,
try and impress girls.
Doing his impressions.
Yeah.
He's a fucking super talented guy.
Really talented.
Just the energy,
the pure energy.
And he changed his act break with
Rodney.
I think he was opening for Ronnie and he
was doing kind of straight standup and
then said he wanted to go this new
direction and start doing these
characters and voices and impressions
and Rodney kind of encouraged them to,
to go for it.
Like you can buy them on my show.
I don't care.
That's interesting.
You could bomb.
I don't care.
Get out there.
He's a bad motherfucker.
Yeah.
That was a painter who was on a.
He was on a movie set once and a friend
of mine was working on the set and he
didn't like his performance on the take.
He was just like,
fuck.
He's like,
he didn't,
didn't feel like it was up to his
standards or something like that.
Yeah.
So to burn off energy,
he just smashed his fucking car.
It was a car that was there,
like one of the production drawers.
He just smashed it with a bat.
I don't remember what he hit it with.
I don't remember what they said.
He picked something up and started
whacking this fucking car and you know,
this is Jim Carrey when it's at the top
of the heap.
Well,
just let him wreck the car.
Will just.
He doesn't get.
He's just,
he just wanted to get some energy out.
Fucking fucking fucking.
Just smashed fast.
Fast.
Okay.
All right.
We're back.
And then he went and did the sea that
like,
Holy Shit.
That must have been hilarious.
It's great.
Do you sometimes think that maybe you
should be crazier as a,
as as a comedian?
Oh yeah,
I know that feeling.
I know exactly what you're saying.
I know where you're going with that,
but if you were crazy,
you'd be funnier.
Right?
Like if completely reckless,
crazy person.
If you were more cat,
right?
Like I always hear the bit like he
always hear like the stories,
like they had to get the guy to the
show,
get the guy to the show.
Was there a half hour early going
through my notes.
I'm like,
I'm a square.
I know when I was young I did meditate
on purpose.
I stopped meditating for a long time
because I literally thought like when I
was 21,
22 fucking sucked.
I sucked.
I mean,
it just wasn't very good.
We never.
But we got energy.
Yeah.
But I thought at the time that if I,
um,
if I was moving toward enlightenment,
like if I was meditating,
the reason why I was meditating,
like when I was competing,
I would meditate because it would try,
I would try to move towards a place of
like balance.
But then as a comedian I was like,
you probably shouldn't be balanced
because the funny shit comes from the
people like Richard Pryor,
these problems and it's kind of crazy
and innocent and it was just crazy and
doing all those are my heroes.
Yeah,
I know.
But you know,
they're also not here anymore.
Same thing.
Yeah.
Same thing,
you know?
Yeah.
This is great.
People that are still around.
Fuck.
Yeah.
I think the best guys.
I really do.
I think right now between bill burr and
Dave Chappelle,
Louis C,
k,
Chris Rock,
Joey Diaz,
there mean there's Tom Papa,
Friday night in epics,
Friday night.
I was wondering when my pop and I lived
there.
I mean,
I think this is like honestly me and
keep going.
There's a,
there's a ton of like none of those guys
are funny comedians right now.
Yeah.
And none of them are really like super
reckless.
No life,
no like Louise.
Not at all.
Not even a little bit.
No,
no.
Bursa town disciplined.
Yeah.
Smart Guy.
Very a very um,
hard worker discipline.
Learning how to fly a helicopter and
knows how it's going to license.
I know cooks.
It makes his own pie crust,
like literally uses like shortening and
stuff.
I brought him a,
one of my sourdough breads.
I brought him and uh,
his,
his wife really wanted,
uh,
me to bring over his bread,
my bread.
So,
uh,
I went and brought it over and gave it
to her.
Of course they loved it because it's
amazing.
And uh,
right before Thanksgiving,
I think it was right before
thanksgiving.
Yeah.
Maybe or that weekend.
Uh,
he texted me and he's like,
dude,
can I,
uh,
I,
I want to drop off and he made this a
traditional kind of like a kinda like a
cinnamon and the apple kind of a bread
and eat the bread testing Indian world.
I think he was like,
you got bread.
I got bread,
I make bread.
And he brought it over to my house after
a set at the store and dropped it off.
It was a little raw inside.
He had a problem with is up and it
wasn't a big deal,
but it was.
Yeah,
he knows how to bake.
That's amazing.
I love how you gave him the thumbs up.
All right.
I'll tell you,
I'll try it out.
Oh,
except that he was a little pissed off
that his wife liked my bread so much.
Just a feeling of expertise
perhaps when you know they really know
something you use.
Talk about bread,
like you just took on right there.
Were you describing his Braille
bad?
Like you have an air of expertise when
it comes to the area of bread?
Yeah,
I'm in deep.
I'm a deep.
I islet when I see you talk about,
uh,
doing your bow and Arrow thing.
That's what bread is for me.
It's this meditative small thing,
small moves to try and get better.
I'm completely,
the rest of the world is out there and I
am in here working on this,
figuring this
mystery out when it comes to like Bono
stuff.
I'm like a good blue belt.
Right?
But I'm not very.
There's bankers.
They're run circles around me,
but yeah,
but you're in it just as much as that
guy is.
What's amazing about the bone Arrow
world,
I would say the archery world is how
much there is to know,
like you would never believe it.
It's endless,
right?
You would look at it and you go,
oh,
you pull the string back,
you aim,
you let the Arrow go.
And a lot of people that is what they
think.
That is what it is.
But then you get into it and you,
you understand like the physics behind
these things,
the cams and the fucking limbs that pull
back on these compound bows and how it's
all measured and weighed and balanced
and hoyt has to come out with a brand
new better bow every year and you're
crazy.
These minor improvements of engineering,
these things are getting faster and more
powerful and it's all about figuring out
how to get a executed shot correctly.
Using your skeleton and holding
everything perfect and having any
influence on the flight of the Arrow.
It's like it's maddening.
It would take you for a lifetime to
master it and would you,
could you.
You could.
Could you imagine you got into it?
I think if there's nothing physically
wrong with you.
I think bow and Arrow shooting archery
is one of the more easy things on your
body.
Like in terms of like you could be
really good at it deep in your forties
or fifties.
Like,
it's what I love about the reason I ask
is the thing I love about this bread
thing where you're talking about with
that,
with standup,
it's
kind of unknowable.
You can get great at it,
you can be a master,
you can be one of the people that
everyone looks at and says he's one of
the guys
and still it could be,
um,
that night or that moment or that pull
it's out of your reach.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I love that idea that you.
Because you know,
you have something you can work on for
the rest of your life.
Right.
You know what I mean?
I'll get calls from seinfeld telling me
he's completely lost with what he's
doing with this set.
You know what I mean?
That's to me is comforting because
that's what a craft is.
It's like I can,
I can get really great.
I can work so hard,
get really,
really,
really great.
And then have a night where you're just
off.
Yeah.
There's really no other way that you
can.
Um,
I mean,
just like for a guy like Seinfeld that's
so successful and is made so many
fucking standup specials,
how many specialists does he have?
Not that many.
Actually.
He's actually at least three.
Yeah,
four.
three.
Probably three big ones.
So he's at least put thousands.
I mean,
so many,
uh,
late night performances.
Right?
Oh,
that's right,
that's right.
There's a lot of those,
like several,
a year for 40 years.
And then in between that you put in the
show Seinfeld,
which probably took almost all of his
time.
Like he wasn't doing that much standup
while he was doing that in the summers.
He would go tour in the summer,
but because that's a brutal Gig,
putting together a giant hit sitcom like
Seinfeld,
that must've been a brutal gig.
He talks about it like he went to war or
something.
But the point is that guy that he,
that he has to still go through the same
process,
the same exact.
I just talked to him this morning and
all we talked about was how are you
writing?
Are you writing?
What are you doing?
When are you writing?
Are you writing?
You're doing it late,
you're doing it early.
Doing it here and I'm trying to get it
in an hour here.
Even if I sit and it was just an.
All that stuff was still 40 years in.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
it's the best.
That's what all that stuff is.
It's so awesome.
Yeah.
That's what the,
uh,
the only,
the only advantage I would say that the
bread thing has over the bow and Arrow
thing is I get to eat it.
Hm.
Good point.
You could eat elk though.
You can,
you can take a lot.
It takes a lot.
A lot of work.
Yeah.
If you want to get an elk or anything,
it takes a lot of work,
but I guess it takes a lot of work to
learn how to bake bread,
but it's a different kind of work.
It's different,
but there's all of this.
I mean there's a whole nother level that
I am not even sure of the Ph balance,
the humidity in the house that the
temperature,
all of this stuff that's got it dialed
in.
Is there like one bread where it's like
the,
like if you wanted to get a bow you
would get a hoyt fizzer one bread that
has like a,
there's so many.
Like when I literally,
when I'm on the road I'll go check out
these bakeries and like just go see what
kind of bread they're making and see
what,
who's doing what in this town.
And uh,
there's a place in Venice down by a day.
The Rolls Royce.
Yeah.
But it's,
you know,
they're kind of.
Yeah.
The Rolls Royce of bread.
For this area.
They're the Rolls Royce.
What's the name of the place?
It's called a Gusto.
Jay.
I don't know how you pronounce it.
It's j.
g u,
s t o or j Dot j dot.
It's like Gusto.
I call it cousteau.
Jake,
you walk in this place.
It's right by Gold's gym.
You know where Gold's gym is down there.
It's right there.
Like in this little shabby place I
worked out there.
Wants Brow.
I'd imagine.
I'd imagine bro cut in there,
Bro.
It was a good one bro.
Yeah,
Bro.
Yeah Bro.
Got a good lifting.
Nice,
Bro.
A lot of big dudes there,
Big dudes,
Bro.
You walk over there to that bread.
There's like this.
It's like this down and dirty and they
make these lows of rather just insane.
Like I brought that home.
I'm a hero in my family for making I
bake bread and leave the to go on the
road and just make sure that they have
their breadwinner there.
Everybody's very happy.
I brought this blow phone.
My daughter was like,
why don't you do this?
I don't even make it like this.
That's dark.
I have no idea.
There it is right there.
Hamp Nori.
Yeah.
Look at that.
Damn good.
Yeah,
that is.
Now I get it.
I get it now.
So that's a piece of art.
That's a piece of art.
It's an edible piece of art like they've
crafted.
It's a very appealing in the outside.
It looks very rustic and it's formed
like they put the little slashes in it
when they were baking it,
so it has layers to it.
I watched this girl,
she was in the back.
You could see them working and doing all
this stuff and this girl was back there.
She's beaten this thing of dough with a
pin.
I was like,
maybe I could work here for a little
while.
Maybe I could just work here for like a
couple months and just as an apprentice,
like for free.
Let me just figure out what the hell
they're doing.
It literally is to a level.
I don't know what they're doing.
That's a seeds.
It's a nine grain porridge loaf.
Yeah.
What the hell?
Whoa.
That's all seeds.
You're putting seeds on it.
Are you not into seeds?
I like succeeds guy.
My family doesn't eat seeds well.
My daughters will be like,
leaves a seed on it.
Don't like it.
What about poppy seed?
How could you not like poppy seed bagels
for the best.
What does that guy holding a bunch of
them.
You look at that guy.
Oh my goodness.
That looks good.
Look at those.
Oh my God.
We're talking about bread folks.
I don't know how.
If it's the check,
the they're changing up the flower or if
it's the intensity,
like to get that dark,
you have to have a really high heat and
beyond it.
I don't know if like my conventional
stove could do it.
Yeah.
What they're doing is almost like
burning it on the outside almost or at
the door or burning it almost.
See,
it's hard.
The contrast in this is hard to tell
because we might just be looking at some
weird shadows where the loaf in the back
looks like it's pretty burnt and the one
in the front looks burnt.
That's.
I'd like to see what it actually looks
like in the flesh,
but.
Oh,
it's so good.
It is dark,
which means I don't think it's looked at
bats.
No.
Let me ask you this,
how spongy that is though.
It's really good.
We're looking at the site people like,
what the fuck are they looking at?
We're looking at the side profile of
these little holes in it.
Yeah.
Let me ask you this.
It's called the crumb butter or no
butter.
Um,
I don't.
Uh,
I fucking knew it.
You don't use butter.
I like butter.
How dare you?
If you liked butter,
you'd like butter on bread.
Say That's where it sits best.
I know,
but there's this butter does its best
work is this other stuff?
That's pretty good too.
So anytime time we're butter you allow
it to be cold.
Huh?
So the only time where you allow your
butter to be cold and you spread your
butter on a loaf of bread.
Yeah,
that's when you don't mind the cold
butter.
Martha Stewart.
Tell me you shouldn't leave your bread.
Your butter out on the counter.
Oh yeah.
Tell Martha Stewart you shouldn't
fucking cheat on your taxes.
It's my girlfriend actually.
She inside traded.
I was wrong.
So insider trading.
Yeah.
She got a little tip.
I'm sorry.
She got a tip.
How does that work,
man?
Are you supposed to not respond to tips?
Everybody responds to tips.
They're all doing it.
They are.
I don't know.
I think they're all insider trading.
Of course.
Like to get them some of your bread.
Wouldn't you think these guys gave me
some bread?
If you give me a tip,
I'll get you a nice,
nice sour dill.
If I got a tip,
I'd be like,
look dude,
we have a big tip.
Might explain this to me,
but please do again because I'm
retarded.
Why is a sourdough have that flavor and
why it.
Someone said that it's like it's almost
gluten free,
that it's like it's not the same as
regular bread.
Is that true?
It is true and I don't really know the
science behind it,
but just giving it to friends.
I don't know,
but I've given it to friends that have
gluten intolerant problem and they they
are able to digest it a lot easier.
Tom Papa,
using his friends,
his Guinea pigs here.
Let's see if you shake yourself.
Have some gluten free bread crumbs.
Just eat it.
If you ask for gluten free at this place
where they spit in your face.
Good Americans.
I don't know.
Probably.
They are in Venice.
They probably.
I don't know.
Listen to me folks.
Bread is bad for you.
It's not make the best bad for you.
Do the best you can taste the best while
it's bad for you.
It's so good.
If that's the one car,
the fermentation time,
the bacteria that builds up stops or
breaks down the gluten proteins.
That's interesting.
So you need gluten for the structure of
the bread.
So it still has gluten.
Oh,
so it does have some glute.
Yeah,
because that's the framework that's
making it big.
If you don't eat the crust,
maybe you don't get the gluten.
No,
it's in there.
It's in there.
Interesting to do science,
but there might be some other stuff.
I mean,
I think the problem really my just gut
instinct is that when you're eating all
this gluten with other stuff,
it's so much other stuff added in there
that maybe interacting with the gluten
that's made giving you the problem.
This bread has three ingredients.
You sound like an apologist and water,
flour and salt.
That's it.
So you're not getting all this extra
additives and stuff that are in there.
I think that's what's giving people
really the problem.
So you think like preservatives and
bread that like commercial bakeries use
32 ingredients.
Ingredients are they,
you can't even pronounce them.
Oh,
you mean know what makes you make a good
point?
The FDA had to change the definition of
what bread was,
so they could deal with these commercial
breads.
That's not healing.
Yeah,
that's not really technically what a
bread is.
If you add all this other stuff,
it's not really bread.
Okay,
so like what is wonder bread?
A whole lodge.
Delicious.
A whole bunch of fun.
Oh,
look at this.
Take wonder bread.
Oh my God.
And it's popular.
Wonder plus white loaf with fiber
ingredients,
unbleached wheat flour,
water,
sugar,
haul fiber,
yeast,
soybean and canola oil,
wheat,
gluten,
salt,
natural soy flavor,
sour flavor rather,
bacterial culture,
soy flour,
cultured wheat starch solids,
vinegar,
soy lecithin.
Uh Huh.
Hm.
It says,
look at this.
Wonder bread.
Not Wonderful for your health.
The naked label.
Why not just make an article called de?
It's so fucked.
Things wonder,
bread's good for you.
Like that's like saying,
hey kids,
if you drink you'll get drunk.
High Fructose Corn Syrup,
wheat gluten.
Look at this last [inaudible] sulfate
dough conditioners.
Sodium sterile,
loyal accolade x soul oxalated.
Yeah.
With mono and diglycerides look,
look at this.
Go back to just that one might,
may or may not have actually been
wondering,
but it wasn't.
Well,
what is it says wonder bread
ingredients.
So let's keep fucking lying then.
This fake news is fake news.
Ammonium chloride,
W,
where do we stop your.
Oh,
calcium dioxide and slash or as old die
carbon.
Um,
but now I'm gonna Jesus Christ.
This ammonium chloride.
Ammonium sulfate and or Amano.
Calcium phosphate.
Calcium propynate.
Innate ammonium sulfate.
Ammonium in your bread.
Jimmy.
You must find that.
If that's real,
now you have perplexed.
I have to pee.
Can I pay?
Yeah,
please.
We'll just keep reading the ingredients
for right off the bag.
Okay.
Right off the combine.
So it's all those things.
That was all those things we were just
talking about.
So all that stuff really is in there.
Wow.
That's nuts.
It's I guess,
boy,
you know,
you run into that thing where you say,
well if you want to have bread on the
shelves in places where they're not
growing any food,
like in order for it to be fresh enough
for you to eat and not get sick,
you got to have some sort of
preservatives in the bread.
Just like would one.
I would like to know definitively how
much those preservatives have an effect
on your health.
You know,
like everybody assumes they're really
bad for you.
Right?
Don't you assume they're really bad for
you?
I do too.
I would like to know what the fuck they
do because what they're doing is they're
not allowing bacterial growth.
Right.
That sort of preservative is.
So if you have a loaf of bread and you
put preservatives in it,
it's stunting bacterial growth,
which will eventually take over and you
brought your bread will get moldy.
Right.
So that's a,
that's a poison.
So you've got some sort of a poison on
your bread.
Yeah.
It keeps it from being edible.
The bacteria.
So instead of eating bread while it's
fresh,
when you're supposed to eat it,
the only time you're supposed to lead
it,
you've got some chemicals pumped into
it.
What's that doing to your body?
Exactly messing it up.
I mean,
what do you think?
It's doing,
what it's doing physically to your body.
It's probably making it difficult to
digest things.
You're probably not transferring real
food into this nutrients that you need.
Your system's going to work on this
thing,
right?
Anything you put in your body,
your body seems to react right and deal
with it has to deal with it.
It's probably dealing with that and not
slowing down some other processes.
That's bro Science for you.
But I bet your bro Science makes lot of
sense and I also bet your bro Science
could point to that.
If you're taking in these things that
are anti,
they essentially they stunt.
This is again super pro science there
stunting these microbes growing on bread
and mold growing on bread,
but you have a bunch of gut flora
[inaudible].
So if you take that stuff and you put it
inside your gut,
your gut flora has to be dealing with at
least some of that interest.
How much is left,
how much of the preservative is in the
bread while your body's trying to break
it down?
Where this gut flora is used to
digesting organic material,
now it's dealing with sodium lauryl icon
of fucking plastic,
right?
Calla fragile listic.
It's probably taking out some of the
stuff that you need to fight off other
stuff and you're percent man.
That's why antibiotics are so bad for
you.
Not because they don't cure diseases,
they definitely do,
but because they also wreck your whole
biome,
like you have to take a bunch of
probiotics and try and get your system
back to operating.
People have sometimes problems for quite
a long time after operations because of
the probiotics,
which are important to keep you from
getting infections,
but they're not without a price like
your.
Your body pays a price for that.
I mean,
look,
there's been times when you walk in and
you're like,
you had a bread,
like a,
an Italian bread that you bought this
from the supermarket and you're like,
three days
later you're like,
oh,
this is probably no soft.
I could eat,
I could eat.
This is like a week later.
It's like,
that's not good.
How long is a loaf of bread supposed to
last?
If when you cut it,
it should start getting hard
immediately.
Really like by the next day like that.
That part,
that part that you've cut to expose the
stuff that's under the crust,
you know,
it could last for,
three days,
four days.
My grandfather lived in a hard though,
an Italian neighborhood.
All Italian neighborhood in North New
Jersey.
Oh Nice.
And when I was a little kid,
we used to go to the bread store.
He used to go to the bakery,
to the bakery,
like every couple of days they would
have a loaf of bread.
It would sit on the kitchen table.
They would chop from the white paper
wrapper and pull it out of the wrapper a
little bit,
cut some slices,
push it back in the wrapper,
Kinda roll it up,
but everybody knew it was good for a
couple of days.
Couple of days later my grandpa would go
down to the bakery and get it again,
and this same place had been in
operation since the 19 twenties and
stuff like that.
That's great.
And it was just a cool little
neighborhood bakery.
It's the vast.
And then till you would go,
you would do that with all your foods.
He would do.
Then you go to the fruit guy and get
that.
Then you get your meat from that guy and
it was all.
It wasn't all meant to last forever.
Yeah.
You know,
I think when I think about the time,
like we were talking about how hard it
is to eat when you're on the road and
like you know when you're pressed for
time,
if you're running between obligations,
you have all these different things
you're doing.
It's,
it's hard to get good food in your
system.
It is,
you know,
that's.
I did this weekend and I was eating.
I ate horribly,
I felt I was dragging all weekend.
I just was putting crap in my body in a
pinch and a w.
It made it so hard.
Sometimes you're in a hotel and you're
like,
is there a side vegetable?
Can I have a,
just a site and they know.
And what do you mean?
No,
you don't have a vegetable for me.
It's,
yeah,
it's really bad,
but that's why I'm,
I've made two loaves at a time and I
literally have to go back to New York,
uh,
tomorrow and I just got in yesterday.
So while I,
I got in fed the starter to get the
bread going and now when I go home and
then I made it into dough.
This morning it's rising now I'll go
back and bake this bread and then
they'll have bread for the week until I
come back on Friday.
That's awesome.
That's my job.
That's so cool.
It's my job at the house.
That's so nice because that's something
they're going to think about you every
time they eat your bread.
Daddy makes this.
It's funny because my kids will send me
pictures of sourdough from when they're
like at a restaurant with your friends
or something.
It'd be like not very good what I was
going to get out though.
When you're on the road and you're on
the hustle and you're doing so many
different things,
you don't have a chance to eat well and
you definitely don't have the chance to
like have a loaf of bread and take some
slices out of it and then get loan and a
couple of days,
like most people that are way too busy.
But what I was going to get at is it's
Kinda like what you were talking about
before that could you downsize,
could you downsize,
and if you did,
would you be happier?
You might be.
You might be happier if you did less
stuff.
You might be happier if you calm down
more.
Might be happier if you went and got
bread every couple of days where you
made your own bread every couple of
days.
Whatever is keeping you.
I can't do that on too busy.
Whatever that is might be the problem.
Like we,
we might in our rush to be successful.
I think a lot of people.
I think it's totally possible that you
overshoot the happiness spot.
Yeah.
No,
I know.
I mean,
look,
if,
if I,
if I was the Tom Papa that started stand
up for the first week and you'd showed
me where I'm at now,
I would think,
oh,
pure bliss bliss and now I am where I
am.
And I'm like,
I don't know.
I think that old guy might've been a
little happier.
Piglet guy who's just doing a spot for
five bucks at the comic strip.
That guy was pretty happy.
Especially.
Yeah.
Now when you know that you're going to
wind up being successful.
Yeah.
That's the thing about like when the
unknown is very stressful.
That's true.
At that time you were like,
am I ever going to get on Conan?
Yeah.
And we all know that one guy,
at least a few guys.
That was really funny,
but for some reason didn't catch on.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
I know there's a ton of those guys a ton
and so you'd always think about them
like what about that guy?
Whatever happened to that guy.
Yeah.
No,
I know that.
The wall of death at a comedy club and
you're like,
all these people go,
yeah,
the store has got a fucking haunted wall
to wall.
Some of the wallet guys just stopped.
They just stopped doing it.
To us,
it's like someone.
One of the scariest things.
Right?
Terrifying.
So when you.
I think we have a romanticizing
instinct.
The human,
the human animal does.
We have a gigantic instinct to go back
to a time where shit made sense.
Make America great again.
Seriously is a novel thing.
Every girlfriend you were with was
pretty good.
Everything you did was pretty great.
That little,
you know,
all his little crappy ways.
You spend your time.
That was her fun.
Yeah.
I don't know.
At the time you didn't think so.
Probably so much.
You get in a fight with your girlfriend.
Think about your ex girlfriend.
She wouldn't have talked to me like
that.
It's because it's knowable,
right?
Like the future is unknowable.
So scary.
This change that the country was going
under.
Like what do you mean there's these jobs
are going away.
What do you mean we're going into soon?
What do you mean we've got to deal with
India.
What do you mean?
Technology's taking over my life.
That's scary.
No picket fence where it go.
When I get my bread and go perched on my
desk.
That's noble.
It's feels safer.
Or
You could break it down to an MAG.
A Mag,
a Hashtag.
Maga.
Faggots
becomes.
If you can't,
it's just a grunt type in a word.
Well,
whether whether he represents that are
not,
there can be no doubt that he is the
king of the assholes.
Like he figured out,
like he found people that are going to
support him almost exclusively.
Yeah.
Like there's a lot of assholes.
If you could tap into them.
Yeah.
Thanks a lot.
You just got to the.
This is the first one that made sense to
them.
They were never politically active for
Walter Mondale.
Assholes didn't step up for Ms Dot Mitt
Romney.
No,
but then trump came along and the dogs.
One of us boys going to make America
great again.
US.
This man that lives in this billionaire
and lives on the top of a tower in
Manhattan is one of us.
I saw a really amazing dark video of
this guy.
He,
he got a traffic altercation with this
black guy.
The black guy is holding the phone in.
The white guy comes up to the,
to the window and uh,
the one of the first thing he says,
he said,
trump all the way,
bro.
Trump.
Really?
He goes,
he goes,
you're telling me black lives matter.
He goes,
you can't say black lives matter.
You gotta.
Show me black lives matter.
Show me a reason because now you're just
saying it.
He goes,
and you cut in front of me and you,
you sped up and cut in front of me.
That makes you a nigger.
He's filming him while this guy saying
this.
Oh.
And I'm like,
wow,
man.
Oh Man.
That attitude that,
like he said,
opens up with trump.
He opens up.
It's no joke.
I'm not saying that everybody's a trump
supporters like that.
What I am saying is that don't even look
that video up.
I don't want to get that guy in any more
trouble than I'm sure you're already in,
but to to that feeling now you can.
Dad Feeling is like you're only gonna
attack that,
that specific type of feeling like
that's a no.
You got to avoid that.
Whatever that pops up.
Like that's terrible.
It's called hate.
Yeah,
well it's the.
The,
the angle that he went on it.
Look at these guys got into legitimate
traffic altercation and that legitimate
traffic altercation was because one guy
hit his blinker too late or cut in front
of somebody or something like that.
If you're a fucking human being with any
decency,
you discuss what happened and maybe you
fucked up and maybe you should apologize
and maybe he fucked up and maybe he will
apologize.
Who knows?
But when you open up with trump all the
way trump,
bro,
black lives matter,
you know,
you show me like,
what?
Where?
Where's your head at?
This is.
This is how you're communicating with
the person.
Really tap.
He tapped into all degrees of that.
Yeah.
All degrees of that.
When when people are being bombarded,
when white guys in Ohio who are going
out trying to work as a construction
worker and that guy has got three kids
and he was told white men are over,
white men are done.
Right.
It was became like a trendy thing.
Anybody that it is,
it's in all the media is just people
saying white people had done white
people are done with treatment.
Different sites.
You reading the white people were done
websites.
Jamie.
I've seen people say that on twitter.
Yeah.
Even like having them post.
You go to black twitter though,
you're always on black.
Twitter even having imposed.
It's always about white males.
Oh,
another white male gets the job.
Either way you're going to say
salon.com.
Next.
I'm saying that's a big thing and the
people that guy who's being told that
the jobs aren't for you.
Right?
It's where these other people,
that's what's coming,
but you're sitting there with your wife
and two kids and you're like,
all right,
look,
I get it.
White guys had a good run.
You're saying white guys are kind of
passe.
We're done,
but I got,
I got Christmas to pay for and they got
these I got,
but I think that's such an extreme
perspective on it that why people are
done.
I think the big perspective,
the much broader perspective on people
that are trying to encourage diversity
is that they feel like people are
discriminated against in the past.
It's time to balance that out.
It doesn't mean that white people suck.
It just means that everybody's great,
but that's ever bring them all in like
that's the right way to look at it,
but you're going to have the extreme
that go.
White people saw white people stand
down.
White people should just shut the fuck
up and let us talk now,
but that's always going to be the case.
You're always going to have fluctuations
inside of a good idea for sure,
but there's.
It resonated.
I think white,
white people.
I tell this is a the morning after the
election,
morning after,
right?
That whole night of what the hell?
What's happened?
Who's what?
I get up in the morning and were like,
I have a new puppy.
I take my puppy outside at 6:00
in the morning,
6:30
in the morning.
I'm outside with the dog and I here in
the,
in the distance.
It's a quiet,
you know,
upscale neighborhood.
I hear,
Huh?
Yeah.
Can you believe it?
No Way Michael.
I'm like,
this has gotta be it's gotTa be about
the election there.
So like,
I know I couldn't believe it happened
either.
Peer through.
I go through the bushes and I see a
white Mercedes.
It's a white Mercedes.
A guy's talking to another guy.
They're talking.
I can hardly understand what they're
saying and as the guy leaves,
he's like,
all right man,
I'll see you soon.
White lives matter and takes off.
This is a guy doing well in a Mercedes
living in this nice neighborhood.
And that was the first thing I heard the
next morning.
There is a,
you can't,
you can't say that anybody else doesn't
matter.
You can't put.
Make people feel like they don't exist
because they,
they will fight back on all sides all
the time.
That's a very good point.
And that's unfortunately with some
people here,
like if you hear black lives matter,
were you here as well?
That means white lives don't or that
means white lives do less or that means
we're trying to call,
call,
call attention to one very specific
only.
Right.
And even though I completely understand
why they're doing it,
I don't think there's anything wrong
with black lives matter.
with the idea of it.
But I think I didn't have this reaction
to it.
But I know that some people probably did
they immediately go,
yeah.
What about what people just debts up
fucking knee jerk or.
And that might not have had to happen.
Like I think sometimes ideas the way
they're displayed,
like sometimes people,
they do it because it feels like the
right thing to do at the time of the
right way to say it at the time.
But anytime you're inviting any sort of
like anger or dispute,
it feels like you want to do that to
push back.
But that shit is going to come back this
way.
It's way easier said than done.
But I think that all a lot of what we
see from this reaction to to anything,
it's like a aggressively progressive.
Like people when they feel like they're
pushed,
they're like,
you have to listen to the way we see the
world,
and then they want to go the fuck I do.
You know,
like they want to push back and almost
ramp up,
doubled down on the racism,
doubled down on their xenophobia,
trying to correct wrongs.
That kid.
It could come off as being aggressive
and bullying to those people.
Yeah.
Especially if you don't agree with them.
Like,
here's the thing,
man.
Everybody thinks they're right.
Whether it's you're on,
you're on the right or the left.
Everybody thinks they have a moral
imperative.
Everybody thinks that they're doing the
right thing unless your piece of shit.
Right,
right.
Let's assume people aren't for the most
part,
are pieces of shit.
They think they're doing the right
thing,
but this is the way they've grown up.
There's just so much of it as cultural.
When you look at the world today,
we're,
we're all just human beings,
but there's people that are living in
parts of the world that must behave a
way different way than we are allowed to
behave because they're entrapped in a
religious ideology that dominates their
community,
so it could be these poor kids in Africa
that get that female genital mutilation,
like how many of them haven't done to
them.
It could be that it could be growing up
Mormon and Utah and a crazy fucking
house filled with nutty mormons or you
know,
there's a million different
possibilities.
Roll the dice that you ended up there,
but apparently people are just super
flexible.
Our behavior is really malleable and
were adaptable and we can fit into
whether it's a horrible ideology like
what happened,
what happened in World War II,
what happened with the Nazis.
They fail into a horrible way of of
living life,
but that's a possibility that's going on
right now in North Korea.
There's always a possibility for people
to fit into these little weird little
packages.
So if you see someone that has a weird
package of existence that you don't jive
with,
you gotta look at it like what would you
do if you were them?
Like if you had their life and now
you're looking at this from their but no
one from your perspective.
Try.
If you can do imagine what it would be
like to look at it from.
There's,
I mean,
it's so random it.
especially like growing up here,
it's like you,
if you had been born just 200 miles
south in Mexico,
your life is.
Oh,
totally different.
Totally.
So there's no like,
divine the,
it's just you just got lucky that your
parents ended up a little north.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
It's just,
it's,
it's really,
uh,
it's really unsettling.
It's unsettling.
And that's one of the worst parts about
the really simple build that wall,
build that wall,
that really simple sentiment.
There's a problem with that man.
It's different
between pride in what you are and having
an enemy to that you need this enemy to
take people down.
But I mean,
that's the way
saying before,
man,
it's like you,
if you're expressing fear,
you're going to get a pushback.
If you're expressing anger,
you're going to get a push,
right?
If all of a sudden you're like,
build a wall,
build a wall.
That seems to me to be a place that I
want to get in now.
Right?
You know,
and if you're a person who wants to do
something bad,
that's the spot that's way more evil now
because now you've got a big crazy wall,
right?
Like there's gotta be some sort of
recognition that will almost like it has
to come from the top.
It seems like it has to be this size to
be some sort of recognition that look
the reality of our existence here.
So we're extremely fortunate in the
reality of other people's existences.
They got terrible luck that this is.
This is an undeniable reality of babies.
Yeah.
One hundred percent of the time,
all over the world right now,
baby worked hard to get where they are.
It just showed up.
Roll the dice.
He might have the right body.
We're in Manhattan.
All right,
here's my mom.
Where are we live in Tribeca,
this great Italian restaurants here,
good schools.
What a great place to grow up and my
onesy it's made of so lucky.
Oh my God,
this is great.
Yeah.
No,
but the difference between that and
being born in a hut in the Congo,
you know,
I mean you just got lucky.
Yeah.
So that.
Build the wall,
build a wall.
I get where you're coming from.
I understand the motivation to think
like that,
but I really pretty firmly believed that
anytime you put something like that out,
you'd get something like that that comes
back at.
It's anything that has a little hate on
the edges.
You know,
there's a lot of people like that guy
you say in that video and you know,
they're just,
it's an aggressive.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah,
we got it.
We want.
This is our guy.
Here we come.
Scary.
I've never been in A.
I've never lived.
You know,
I haven't been here that long,
but there's never been after an election
where large groups of people were
scared.
That's never happened.
Unhappy,
pissed off.
I can't believe they're going to do
this,
that that assholes in office never has
there been large groups of families
really legitimately frightened of our
leader.
That's never happened.
I feel like Bill Clinton should just
step up and just say,
this is why we always rigged the system.
We're trying to avoid this.
Okay.
We're protecting you from your own
selves are a ridiculous desire to have
famous people live.
Congratulations.
Yeah.
It was rigged for a reason.
Greatest nickname for trump.
Somebody called them.
Cheeto Jesus.
Yeah.
I've been using cheeto
Jesus.
Yeah.
On election night,
it was really upsetting.
My was it.
My daughter was as a 14 year old girl
who just heard.
She's smart.
She's a high school freshmen and just
heard what this guy was saying about
women and just heard what he was saying
about,
you know,
handicaps or whatever.
Well,
that hand up thing.
Did you know that?
That that I'm not giving them an excuse,
but I don't think he knew that that guy
was handicapped.
I think he was trying to mock someone
who was dumb and he.
It turned out that the person who was
mocking was handicapped and that's what
everybody rent one.
I don't believe he had any knowledge of
that beforehand.
I don't think it was.
I'll give you that,
but even if he didn't know it,
to make that gesture and act like that
guy is just dumb.
Like as a guy running for president,
it just was.
It was.
It was a bully.
It was a bullyish move.
Whether the guy's handicapped or not
handing the girls not handing it.
Well he,
I think he just that
combative relationships like that or a
contest.
It's a war and he,
he'll go out then with his personality
and that's what's odd for us.
And it's from a president,
right?
Yeah.
There's no.
Right.
So my daughter was just crying.
She was just crying.
She's like,
so a guy that says,
grab your pussy is now my president.
I just,
this doesn't make sense.
This guy that says global warming is a
hoax.
This doesn't make sense.
Did he really say that?
Yeah.
You said global warming is a hoax,
a hoax created by the Chinese.
And she's really fucking said that.
And she's like,
she's like,
what?
Just,
what the hell just happened?
I thought he was just skeptical.
I thought he was just skeptical about
man,
man.
Influence global warming because that's
what they like to call it.
Right.
Influenced.
Yeah.
Have you ever seen like the ice core
samples of like what the earth used to
be like just a few,
you know,
few,
10,000,
20,000
years ago.
Oh my God.
The,
the,
the ice levels rise and the sea levels
rise and like the,
this is a constantly changing topography
and the like,
the natural shifts in the earth cycle.
And I'm not a climate change denier at
all.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let me just get this out because if you
talk about this,
people just get angry and a hair trigger
word.
It's not what I'm saying.
Yeah.
I mean,
I absolutely believe that we're fucking
up this planet.
That's not what I'm saying.
Yeah.
But without us doing that,
just without us doing that,
there's been a constant cycle of change,
violent place and it's sometimes really,
really radical,
like giant shifts of temperature up and
down.
And you know,
the big one being the ice age,
of course,
that we can measure fairly recently
this,
most of this country was covered up by a
mile to two miles.
I have ice,
right?
Miles.
Yeah.
So what's your point?
My point is this whole place is super
volatile.
I mean this,
for him to say that global warming is a
hoax.
It's coming.
It's coming with a.
You did it.
I did it.
If it's happening or the concept of
global warming was created by and for
the Chinese in order to make us
manufacturing noncompetitive.
November of 2012.
See,
he was probably one of those dudes that
believed in the Mayan calendar.
She's like,
fuck it,
I'm going to say some crazy shit before
December 20,
first 2012,
it'll all be done.
That was,
um,
that was,
uh,
something that people were saying back
then too.
That was a popular.
Uh,
he used to say a bunch of crazy shit
though.
Remember he used to say that Obama was
born in Kenya.
He was a truth or a birth or rather he
was the birther.
Yeah.
I mean,
he was the leader of that.
He would go and do,
but see you gotta wonder,
like,
how much of that is showmanship?
How much day?
I don't know.
I feel like we're,
I feel like it's the Chauncey Gardner
thing,
you know,
from,
uh,
when Peter Sellers became president,
right?
He was like the,
it was,
uh,
being there,
being there and it was just,
he was the gardener.
He just,
he had,
he was very simple and people just made
it ultimately made him president.
He just kind of wandered into the
presidency and I feel like that with
trump,
I feel like he wandered in and now
people are like,
well,
are these tweets genius or is he trying
to manipulate us?
Is huge.
Really intelligent is a really this,
I think he just usually is what he is,
you know,
I don't think I would believe very
talented,
very charismatic.
Uh,
rich's fuck,
richest fuck.
He's got a good sense of timing and
stuff like that,
but balling out of control.
It's kind of this empty vessel.
And you know,
the,
the big shore though.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure.
I'm pretty sure when you hear him talk
about different things,
he doesn't really know about a lot of
different types.
Home alone I did.
He was on the marriage riff.
It did
right next door.
That was right there.
He would make comments about make
comments.
It was all about husbands and wives.
You would,
uh,
show a real husband and wife and then
you'd talk about them in these.
You try and decide who's right and the
argument,
the husband and the wife and all of his
jokes were about the women's breasts who
said all of his jokes were about the,
well,
she's got these big things,
so she's a,
she'll be okay.
And then he would turn to me and give me
a wink,
like not for the camera,
not for anything,
just me on the side was just kind of
wink at me.
Like we're doing great here.
Right.
I felt like it this way before I knew
anything about him running or anything,
it was just like,
Ooh,
scheming me out.
I felt like I was date raped on my own
show,
but he walked in during that show.
Just like,
we're gonna do great ratings tonight.
We're going to do great.
We're going to kill it.
We're going to do great rating.
I mean,
he was always that way.
Just mantra the mantra,
the mantra.
I think I would be,
uh,
I would take it in like it was a show.
I would think I'd be psyched.
I'd be psyched to sit next to them.
Yeah.
But there's a,
you know,
how your next Tuesday,
John.
I'm sorry.
You have to like,
this is great,
but there's,
you know,
you get vibes from people and the vibe
was a little like,
you know what I mean?
I don't think you get to be that fucking
rich without a little.
Oh,
you just don't think you get there.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Stop along the way.
Like we were talking about balance and
perspective about realizing that,
you know,
maybe you know,
maybe you should scale back a little
bit.
Maybe you'll be happier.
Maybe you missed the happy spot.
He never thought about that for a
fucking second.
I know like now he's like 70 still
making deals with Argentina to put up
hotels.
Yeah.
Shit that was like there was one deal
with a foreign country that was an issue
because it was like right after he
became president.
He's trying to like push this.
They congratulated him.
He's trying to like push this deal.
Do you think he took the Taiwan call his
in September,
they're creating a thing in Taiwan.
They want to make it like Dubai,
like a hub for international Asian,
Asian travel and they're in the mix.
They had been talking to trump.
The word trump is worth so much more
now.
Oh my God.
It's one thing.
I mean,
and that's all he wanted.
So how do you not.
I mean,
how do you.
I can't pull away now.
We've made it.
This is the.
This is when we take over the planet.
I don't remember who had the original
thought,
but I agree with this thought.
Not Mine,
my thought originally,
but that what is interesting about trump
is that he cares so much about how
people like him.
So because of that,
the will of the people,
whether it's marijuana or whether it's
whatever it is,
maybe it's nonviolent drug offenders
that have been in jail forever for no
fucking reason.
That makes any sense to anybody now that
were the.
If you take and you put someone into Ge
in jail for life in 1975 for marijuana
because they smoked marijuana in Las
Vegas,
that a person person's still in jail.
Crazy.
And you're,
you're the president now,
Mr Trump,
please let them out.
Please just,
you know,
let's find,
let's find a way to get these people
jobs.
They weren't,
they weren't arrested because what they
did was wrong.
They were arrested because there was a
thing written down on a piece of paper
that said it was wrong.
It's not really wrong.
There's nothing wrong with what they
did.
Just because it was written on a piece
of paper doesn't mean we should honor
it.
So many years later when we would never
act accordingly,
you would never know the fuck.
No one in this country is going to go to
jail for the rest of their life because
they have a joint,
but isn't it entirely possible that
someone in this country has gone to jail
for the rest of their life?
For a joint?
Absolutely.
Especially if you get inside and then
all of a sudden you get in a fight in
jail,
which happens all the time and someone
dies and you wind up getting charged
with murder.
I mean that kind of stuff happens to
people over a nonsense bullshit.
Arrests aren't most people jail because
of
drug related.
We just pulled it up the other day.
I was like 46 percent nonviolent drug
offenders.
Forty six percent in jail.
It's a lot.
It's insane,
but the thing is,
like you say,
he wants to be popular and he wants to
be well liked in all.
The thing we're going to find out is on
what level does is he looking for that
approval?
Is it from the masses saying this stuff
or is it the guy?
The last guy that came in is it sessions
that comes in and says,
I think that we should,
we should go this way,
and he wants to get earned.
The respect of that guy.
When you have a lot of forces coming in
that we didn't vote for that are going
to be controlling a lot because he's
going to be just kind of delegating it
out.
We don't really know where he stands.
That's the most scary thing is that it's
kind of unknowable.
We don't know how much in control he is
going to be.
Are these other people going to come in
and fill that vacuum and they're going
to be in control.
Big argument against the NDA,
the national defense.
What are the National Defense
Authorization Act that with the NDA,
that was the one that allowed for
indefinite detainment don't need a
warrant.
You can just arrest people and detain
them indefinitely without.
They don't have to have a speedy trial.
The right to a speedy trial has been
revoked and everybody was like,
well,
that's fine because Obama is not going
to use that one.
Then the question was like,
okay,
Obama might not be using it,
but what happens if a new president gets
into office and he's crazy?
Everyone's like,
don't worry,
that's not going to happen.
Well guess what?
Yeah,
you fucked up so that Donald Trump has
the n,
d a on his side.
He can use it now
and add to that and incident.
Add to that some kind of nine slash 11
and then he really takes advantage of
it.
You never know.
One thing that should be taken into
consideration though is that he's a
businessman and one of the things about
things like legalizing marijuana or
going against legalized marijuana,
it doesn't make sense from a business
standpoint because there's too many of
us that smoke it.
Like Jamie put up the numbers.
What percentage,
let's just say Tom,
papa,
what percentage of Americans do you
think smoke marijuana?
What percentage of adult Americans smoke
marijuana?
I would put it at.
I'm going to put it like smoke it on the
regular,
so once a month.
More than once a month.
I would say that that number is at 46
percent.
I bet you're right.
I was gonna go in the forties to.
I was going to say like 43.
Yeah,
but I think 46 rang in my head too.
that's a good number.
I think you're dead on.
That's what I would guess.
It's hard static.
Find maybe Halep poll.
Gallup polls are bullshit.
Let's go with it.
Anyway.
Was it says one in eight US adults say
they smoke
marijuana.
How dare they?
One in eight people dumb enough to
answer a fucking pole.
Meanwhile,
pitches.
I had a little bit in my act.
It's based on true pole.
We're 46 percent of the people believed
in the creationist account of the earth
that the earth was
less than 10,000
years old.
Forty six,
46 percent,
but was a Gallup poll.
So it's 46 percent of the people that
answer the poll.
That was a little bit in my right,
so like how ridiculous.
That's not.
You're not getting a good test group.
So actually answering the question,
people are answering the phone,
talking to you about some different
aspects.
Percent said they have tried it.
Hm.
Okay.
So that's 43 percent.
If it was legal,
it'd be smoking pot and they currently
use it except for a few pussies that
couldn't handle the truth.
A thousand people.
So you can handle the truth.
Yeah.
It's not that many,
but it's enough to put a lot of tax
dollars into the economy.
It's true.
It's a tremendous amount of money.
I know.
If it's really 40,
whatever the hell it is.
Present.
Tried it.
What was the present of the trial at
1:43.
Forty three,
dude,
that's the number.
I just crazy,
man.
That's pretty good.
It's crazy to another question.
Shut the fuck up dude.
You ruin it was in those people against
you voting wise,
that's a pretty significant people like
the stoner dollar has been ignored.
Yes,
but you say who will make those
decisions as a businessman,
but the other people that are fighting
against that or all the pharmaceutical
companies and they have a lot more money
than these kids smoking pot.
So that businessman walks into his
office and says,
Hey,
this is the way it's really going to go.
This is what we really need.
That is permanent though,
isn't it possible that the people acting
collectively have more,
more influence collectively,
financially than a corporation?
It's been exposed.
Never.
It's not going to get any better because
of the Internet transparency there right
now.
The corporations have a lot more power,
right?
Right now,
right now.
But you know,
you watch,
uh,
you know,
Elon musk is not been torn down yet.
They're coming at him.
Oil wants to stop them.
They want to stop her from selling those
cars.
They wanted to do all this stuff.
But he's the will of the people is kind
of protected them,
put them through,
you know,
iron man is going to be president,
right?
I hope so.
This is deliveries last chance he's my
back around.
We need a running this thing.
We tried to assholes.
He's got a little mix of both designee.
Don't you want to see what happens with
the trump thing?
What if he can break down the
structures?
We're gonna point.
That's my whole part is like,
you know,
we are a revolutionary people.
Let's tear some stuff down and let's not
be afraid to break down some walls and
let's shake things up and move.
That's a little bit of a revolution.
Break.
This system that is broken anyway,
five percent.
Let's just hope that it's safe.
Let's hope that it's not empowering the
wrong people.
He's really interesting what he's been
trying to say about lobbyists to,
but when you know how long you need to
take a break after a job in government
before he should be like the lobbyists.
That sounds good.
A lot of.
Lot of good ideas.
That's not so bad.
Who knows?
That's okay.
Let's see.
Last comes in.
I'm rooting for him.
Two thousand 20.
He comes in riding the wave.
Ilan canty ladies,
we're going to be.
We're going to be on Mars by the time
he's getting them.
Ours Jetski blowing up.
He's getting.
He's getting them.
It blew up the satellite for the African
kids that are going to get the internet,
so the African kids so they could send
the Dick pics through the air and you
gotta fail.
You gotta you gotta fail to succeed.
It wasn't the facebook thing.
Yeah,
it was Zuckerberg's satellite for
Internet accidents.
He's got money or maybe space x is doing
just fine.
He's going to do fund NASA.
They say it's going to kick ass.
Glad you brought that up because he was
also a victim of some fake news.
There was some fake news articles that
were written about him that people
actually quoted on Ilan Ilan,
and about how much elon musk made off of
the government and like how much of his,
uh,
his businesses lose money and it was,
an anonymous account.
Like some,
they tried to trace the name of whoever
had written this article or more than
one article and they couldn't find who
the writer was.
Somebody.
It was a fake name.
The store didn't jive.
The numbers didn't pan out.
You need to do that stuff.
That's going to be the kid.
I want to know what the story is because
I'm just talking about it and find out
what that story is.
Jamie,
if you could find out the fake news
story about Elon Musk.
He's the greatest.
He got.
He got somebody wrote something 96
percent sure I know what the fuck I'm
talking about 43 percent sure you do so
much.
So much less confidence.
Now.
Something you can say with authority he
learned must calls out the fake news
troll called them a national disgrace.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
It is a fake news story.
Okay,
so what was it?
At least we identified fake news.
That's right.
The tractor comes wrapped up in the
package of a legitimate journalist.
Yeah.
They were at a coast.
He's being trolled by a a.
what's that word?
Shamira.
God,
I don't remember what that word is.
What does that?
Tumeric,
e r I c,
what does that word mean?
Where is it?
Right there by a chimeric writer calling
himself stepper Shepherd Stuart.
See that?
Troll buy tumeric,
writer Jamie,
Google.
That word flourish and may that all look
up in dictionary was I should say,
um,
look it up in a dictionary of itch.
Me Doing.
Hm.
That's a cool word.
It will like a fucking little animal.
Look at that little thing.
Little furry soccer ships.
Feminism or Shamira is a single org.
Thanks Jamie.
Relating to derive from or being a gym
genetic extra mirror or its genetic
material.
Okay.
Go back to the last one.
That was just like a rat.
They saying these rat lake [inaudible].
Click on that one.
We were just reading.
Yeah.
The whatever the one was to you right
before that one.
Well that's okay.
Let's,
let's just look at it right there,
but scroll down.
That little definition on top is a
little bit more lengthly.
There we go.
So a single origin asm composed of cells
from different zygotes.
Oh,
okay.
So a single cell like an Amoeba will
hold on.
Stop,
go back.
This can result in male and female
organs to blood types or subtle
variations and form.
Okay.
Now go back to that story again.
A chimeric writer calling himself
shepherd Stewart sold by this one celled
organism writer.
Yeah.
So that.
That's an insult.
I guess in the wake of the 2016 US
presidential election,
two major issues rose to the surface.
Dissemination of information,
fake news and accusations of bias
journalism.
Okay.
So Elon Musk,
can anyone uncover who is really writing
these fake pieces?
That's cool.
Call asking for the Internet to help.
Yeah.
His can't be this guy.
His work is better than that.
And then they click on that article,
click on that article and finance.
See if they took it down.
That's pretty great.
Elan musk versus the trolls.
Oh,
okay.
They switched it to this.
So it's just essentially Elon musk
calling out this guy for the fake
article.
I don't think the fake articles up
anymore.
I think the,
uh,
he's the coolest,
but I think that's just what you can do
now.
If this guy who was we were reading
about earlier,
this guy can get 10,000
bucks a month.
Yeah.
By just making stuff up,
just make up stories.
They so many made up an article about me
getting into a fight with a mountain
lion that killed them,
outline at the Ice House.
Really ridiculous.
My sister called me up and asked me what
is true.
Oh my God.
But they just do that all day.
So if they do that all the day,
you know,
a Jodie foster visited by real aliens.
If they do that,
you know,
like,
and then you'll have her sitting there
talking about it.
Like if you're a dumb ass,
you gonna send that to your friend.
Jodie foster was fucking coming out,
man.
Finally,
the agendas being new and the aliens are
real.
They're here,
Bro.
Yeah,
and just keep putting them at one of
them's gonna stick right in my head,
Bro.
Definition.
Oh,
another definition.
Unreal.
Imaginary visionary,
a trauma lyrical,
terrestrial paradise.
Wildly fanciful,
highly unrealistic plan.
Interesting.
Unreal.
Imaginary or visionary.
So it was an imaginary writer as well.
It sounds like a real writer with an
imaginary name.
So it's just a pseudonym.
Essentially a pseudonym with the fucking
person is a pseudonym.
Bomp.
I wonder if like businesses hire people
to do things like that to discredit
them.
Yeah,
if you're Ford and the Chevy guys who
are just getting a little too fucking
cocky and there was some dude like Henry
Ford type character over it.
Chevy,
some magnanimous,
gigantic larger than life figure and
start writing some fake shit about him
pawning money off the government and
eating pizza at this place where they
have pedophilia artwork.
In the old days they called it yellow
journalism,
the hearst newspapers.
They'd plants fake stories in the papers
and people would think that they were
true and you'd try and take down titans
of business that you were competing
against and all the rest of it.
It's always existed.
Well,
you know,
that's what William Randolph hearst did
against marijuana.
Oh,
that's how marijuana became illegal.
Really?
You know?
No,
I did not know the full stoner Bible
story.
Now,
the biblical creation story of the
Stoner myth.
Real.
Yeah.
This is what it is here.
That would been 19 thirties post right
after prohibition.
Alcohol prohibition.
The.
What happened was they came out with a
machine called the decorticator and the
decorticator allows them to process hemp
fiber more easily with this machine.
It cranks it through because hemp is
this spectacular fiber.
Like a buddy of mine had a hemp stalk
over his house.
My friend Todd Mccormick,
and he's like,
pick it up man.
And I picked it.
I was like,
whoa.
It's light like Balsa wood,
like,
but hard,
like a Mahogany.
It's weird.
Yeah.
It's a very,
very strange bamboo.
No,
no,
because bamboo is hollow.
It makes sense that it's light.
This is like a thing.
It was like a stock,
like a risk side.
Like my wrist.
That's bamboo,
right?
That's the hemp plant.
Yeah.
You can get it and there's different
forms of it and see that one in the
upper right hand corner like that.
So this.
Gotcha.
He had it like that.
Right.
So you would pick it up.
It'd be super light,
but ridiculously hard.
He's like,
dude,
it's alien.
It's an alien planet.
It's todd's very,
very smart.
He's written books on growing marijuana.
He was like one of the first guys to
ever get arrested for,
um,
growing medical marijuana.
And then when he went to court,
he found out he was not even allowed to
use the term medical.
So you're not allowed to say it because
they don't believe in it federally.
So even though it's legal in California,
what they did was they prosecuted him
with federal laws which don't allow for
the,
even the phrase medical marijuana,
he wasn't even allowed because it was a
federal trial.
He wasn't even allowed to mention that
it was legal in California.
So the people who were in the jury,
they get this totally skewed perspective
of what happened and you have to vote on
it.
You know,
as a juror,
you have to decide based on the law.
And the law is federally,
it is illegal.
There's no such thing as medical
marijuana.
So you can't even bring it up.
And if you brought in contempt of court
and her started all this,
he started.
And what happened was when they came out
with the decorticator,
William Randolph hearst owned paper
mills,
and he also owned these forests of trees
that they would convert into paper.
He made his own newspaper and print it
on that paper,
and then Popular Science magazine had a
cover that said hemp,
the new billion dollar crop,
and it was all about the invention of
the decorticator and how now they'd be
able to effectively process this hemp
because they used hemp forever because
he didn't have a cotton gin.
They only came out with the cotton gin.
A lot of people shifted over to cotton
because,
especially at the end of slavery,
because it wasn't really financially
sound until they spend all that time
processing all that,
that fiber to get cannabis or to get a
canvas where when you could just get it
out of cotton,
it'd be like way easier now with this,
a cotton gin,
the cotton gin.
So that changed the game.
And then the decorticator changed the
game again.
And that's when William Randolph hearst
came in and they started writing all
these stories about telling people to
write stories.
I'm sure telling people to write stories
about this new drug called marijuana.
It's forcing blacks and Mexicans to have
sex with white women and rape white
women and marijuana wasn't even a name
for,
for the camp,
for cannabis.
The word was a wild Mexican tobacco.
That was where.
That's what marijuana originally was.
Really.
So then when you called it marijuana,
they weren't like,
if you're talking to Mexicans about it,
they'd be like,
what the f like back then they'd be
like,
what the fuck you talking about?
That's that shit.
That wild tobacco type shit.
Well,
they called it marijuana because
cannabis was something that everybody
had used.
They used it for a textile.
They used it for oil.
There was so many people that were using
it already for close canvases.
Canvas is based on the word cannabis.
She's.
They use different cloth.
It's a.
it's a crazy cloth man and it works
really hard to break.
Like if you get a hold of.
I have a gooey.
That was a Datsun Sora.
Made me a Jujitsu gooey made out of
hemp.
They sell these hemp keys for fucking
things are like indestructible.
Yeah.
There's something about like when you
take hemp and you turn it into a fiber
or into a rather a cloth or into a
paper,
it's crazy how durable it is,
so why didn't.
So then he got laws passed to
criminalize it.
Exactly.
And do all that.
But yeah,
you had to have like a tax stamp to grow
it for him and it cut became more and
increasingly more and more difficult.
Why w?
Why?
So they were never able to separate it
as a drug and a thing.
No,
because it's too close.
It's too closely related.
Genetically,
you know,
it's basically you could,
there's different strains of it.
They grow it where it's specifically not
psychoactive,
but all the male plants are not
psychoactive.
So only the female plants that have the
flowers and you can contaminate female
plants and the.
There's some sort of a process that they
have to do when they're growing them to
keep them from changing each other and
hate each other.
Yeah,
they can.
You have too many males with females.
They can actually fuck up the females.
It's really kind of crazy,
but that's the only stuff,
so I guess the issue would be would have
somebody that was pretending they
weren't growing the psychoactive stuff
and that they were only growing,
but they were also selling it as a drug
and then you would have an issue are
legal.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
when you find out like hearst putting
out those stories,
you know,
to get his way and then you know,
big tobacco is putting all these
documentaries come out like 30 years
later of all these stories,
this guy was hired,
rose,
that one where the,
these,
this small group of scientists were
like,
oh,
there it was from the tobacco.
They were putting out stories about the
tobacco is good for you and all this
kind of stuff and they going to take
away for you.
And then they all dried up and now
they're on climate change now.
Now those same guys,
those same organizations are putting out
fake news and being,
talking heads for,
against global warming.
It's a,
it's a documentary documentary on what's
called the ministers of doubt.
Is that it?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's it.
Yes,
I think it's called ministers of doubt.
I mean so sure.
Yeah.
These,
this,
this fakeness has been happening
forever,
forever and driven by money.
If you have a lot of people that have a
lot of money,
that's why if someone becomes president
and then wins,
the president elect trump and then tweet
something that's not true about him
losing the popular vote because millions
of people voted illegally.
When you say stuff like that,
that's why people get scared and nervous
because there's a long history of people
who have what you're going to have.
Donald trump is going to have ultimate
power.
Yeah.
He's going to have that position to the
position of ultimate power,
but with that comes just a massive,
massive responsibility.
So for him to continue to do stuff like
that,
which is like a strategic fib,
he got to kind of let all that go.
Just like he said,
he was going to let all of his
businesses go is gonna,
let his family runs businesses.
It's going to completely step away.
I urge him,
let all that other stuff go to like try
to try to rise to this crazy position in
one of 40.
How many people have been president now?
Busy?
Forty slash 45.
40 six.
Yup.
Forty five.
40 six.
Merchants of doubt not administered.
Oh,
merchants of doubt.
Thank you.
Merchants of doubt.
There's a great documentary.
So when he tweets about Alec Baldwin
again on Saturday night,
what does he say?
He said,
son watched it.
Tried to watch snl again.
So not funny.
Total fail.
Totally biased.
Fail.
You know,
man,
you gotta realize it's funny.
It's funny,
man.
Is he doing that because he doesn't want
people to talk about Taiwan.
This is the funny discussion.
It's like,
is he brilliant or is he just crazy?
That's really what we're dealing with.
Izzy.
So savvy that he wants to everybody not
to pay attention to the Taiwan phone
call and changing decades of how we
treat Taiwan or is that way tweeted to
divert us or is he just.
Taiwan was one column.
This tweet is another thing.
The BS that I think it's just that
Taiwan thing,
he just avoided it.
Just not talk about it.
Like what is he doing?
What did he do?
Taiwan.
He,
he contacted Taiwan.
Yeah.
He says they content and that's he
tweets his defenses.
They called me.
Oh thanks.
The problem you uh,
the policy for 40 years is that you're
dealing with one.
China and Taiwan wants to be their own
thing and you don't treat them the same
way that you do greater China,
that Taiwan is part of China.
So you.
So the way that the diplomats of the
work that you're friendly with Taiwan,
but you don't recognize them as like
their own government.
You don't invite them to the White
House.
You don't.
Our leaders have never talked to their
leaders.
So he gets phone call and he's like,
Hey,
what's up?
Yeah,
we're cool.
And then China was like,
Whoa,
wait.
We have this whole structure of the way
the world works.
And in one phone call this is talking
about power one receiving one phone
call shook that whole part of the globe.
Let me just first of all,
start off with China,
sounds like a dickie friend,
Dickie friend that wants to control you
and we'll let you talk to other people.
So you wanted to make friends with this
new guy and the new guy wants to make
friends with you and China's like,
Nah,
fuck that.
No,
you don't even get to talk to them.
It's that part is pretty valid.
If that's everything to me,
that's everything.
It's all there.
Unless,
I mean that's something Taiwan's doing
what?
We're not supposed to talk to them like
North Korea,
like if all of a sudden he started to
like chat with North Korea and started
selling Taco bowls over there.
What does it say here,
Jamie?
This is from the Washington Post about
the call.
It says the message as John Bolton
correctly puts it,
was that the president of United States,
we'll talk to whoever he who,
whomever he wants,
if he thinks it's in the interest of the
United States and nobody in Beijing gets
to dictate to dictate rather to dictate
who we talked to.
Well,
that seems to make sense to me.
What are we going to talk to people?
Because if we do,
China gets mad.
That sounds like a shitbag relationship.
It's similar to Obama talking to Iran.
I've had friends like that where they go
like,
you can't talk to that person and look
if you,
if you have an enemy,
I'm not going to like cozy up to someone
that's your enemy,
but if you don't like somebody doesn't
necessarily mean that I don't like them
just because I like you.
Like I don't have to like everybody you
like,
like that sounds fucking crazy.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
No,
I mean Obama talking to Iran,
it's like,
well,
how is this ever going to get better and
less?
Our leaders talk to their leader.
Exactly.
You're never gonna.
You're never gonna get any.
If China tells you,
you can't talk to them.
Like what?
My right says who but here,
the thing with the thing with the phone
call is we don't know.
Did he just pick it up and not his.
He was he totally unaware.
Hey,
Brovara relationship with them.
He said he was brief for that phone call
and say,
Hey,
new.
He was doing.
I heard you were talking to Mike.
Man.
I thought we were clear.
You don't talk to Mike,
man.
What a piece of shit.
He just won't.
He did.
He called me.
No,
no,
no.
Mike's a piece of shit.
Fuck him and his whole yard.
I don't know.
He seems like.
Oh right.
I mean he just followed his.
You can't go over to his yard.
I don't want you to do business.
I just.
He's not that bad.
Fuck Mike.
He said some good things about you.
I'm done.
We're going to war.
Trying to sounds like the biggest
asshole.
Can you imagine what a fucking kid like
teenager,
China sounds like.
Well,
you can't even.
I can't even talk to them.
If I talk to them.
We're going to war.
Are we going to war?
Are you serious?
We're going to war over this.
I will totally go to war over this
financial war called the lawyers start
suing you.
What?
Why are you suing me?
Man?
I don't understand the whole.
I don't understand the whole Asia aspect
of our.
Of global policy at all.
Well,
let me tell you this.
I don't the UFC,
this is my,
what I understand about some Asian
businesses are at least chip Japanese
businesses.
The UFC bought this company called pride
and a boy,
they get hoodwinked.
Oh my goodness.
The way they did it was wonderful.
First of all,
the way that the Japanese have this
masterful way of negotiating business
where they talk to you about like,
maybe we'll do business,
we're thinking about doing business,
not today and maybe we'll come back and
discuss this at a later date and then
they would come back.
What we're really thinking about selling
his business and then the UFC and pride
started trading fighters.
They did like a goodwill gesture.
So what this did was elevate the brand
of pride and make print pride even
bigger in the United States.
Like they had family Silva come over and
he faced off with chocolate and
chocolate l went over there to fight
people and they had all this negotiating
stuff going on for a long time and then
finally the UFC comes in and buys them
out.
This big historic thing,
take photos,
shaking hands.
Turns out they bought nothing.
What they bought was essentially like a,
a library of fights.
All the contracts that the fighters had,
they're all bad.
They're all illegal and invalid.
They had like a couple of contracts,
some guys that they had to take over and
like,
oh Jesus Christ,
like it was just chaos.
But as far as they were going to like
run that business over there where they
got over there and they're like,
oh my God,
we can't run this.
Like you can't run it without the Yakuza
people that were all like,
you have to have the consent of the
Japanese mom to run the country company
over there.
And like that was like one of the
Chinese know Japanese,
Japanese,
Japanese.
That was one of the things that sunk the
organization when it was publicly
released,
allegedly allegedly that the Yakuza was
involved.
Everybody was like,
ah,
but they went over there,
they bought this,
they got this library,
and then while they had these UFC
employees,
the employees all started a new business
called dream and they just fucking
started up with a whole new thing of
nowhere.
So they weren't like.
They bought pride and pride is dead in
the same Japanese people like,
no,
we have dream,
and they're like,
but hey,
you guys were working for us.
Our show.
What the fuck is this?
It's like they bought,
they bought like air.
You know,
maybe we are all unknowable to each
other and this is why this is part of
Brexit went down,
is part of why trump won.
This is why Italy just hit their prime
ministers now leaving populist vote.
Everybody wants.
Everyone's like being told we've got to
deal with the whole world.
Globalization.
We had to deal with everybody and
everyone's starting to say,
you know,
it's not really helping us.
Do we have to talk to the Chinese?
Do we have to deal with everybody or do
we have to all be one Europe?
Everybody is starting to kind of
retreat.
Maybe globalization is an idea on the
paper.
Seems like it'll work,
but practically it's not taking hold.
We're all going to communicate through
Tesla,
hive mind because in the future
everyone's going to have to have an
electric car and Tesla is going to be
the first to figure out that the best
way to pilot your car is actually with a
headset,
so you're going to put on a headset.
Very light knows electrodes.
They're all be bluetooth to your car and
that thing will operate by your mind,
but the best way it would probably be
wise to do that is you've got to be on
Google hive minds network,
so then you download the thoughts or you
project the thoughts through the head
gear as pure intention so everybody
knows where everybody's going as they're
driving because you can see pure
intention from a mile away and that
becomes a universal language of human
beings.
When they realize the flaws of English
and Spanish and Chinese and Dutch or
Japanese and Korean and no one can
understand what the fuck they were
talking about through through Google
hive mind.
This is connected to the Tesla as it
drives around.
Is this,
is this an in the next update?
Whereas this in one more hit of that,
take another hit of that.
You'll have some good ideas.
One more hit of the.
I don't even know what the name.
I didn't even ask names or pot anymore.
It's all ridiculous.
Yeah.
I was pretty blown away.
I really felt like an old man in a pot
shop.
Like so wait.
She was like,
this is.
This is a King Kong or something,
and I was in.
I was like,
oh,
everybody knows this name.
I didn't realize.
I thought this was your own little
brand.
I was so lost.
They wouldn't let my mom in a pot shop
and she never.
She never id good for them.
You have to have laws.
Yeah.
I think she's legal folks.
I mean it's flattering and everything.
I'm sure she was happy.
Yeah,
I think they have to mark down who you
are.
They didn't pay.
Didn't know.
They just looked at your shit bro.
You don't even know Bro.
Oh,
maybe bro.
Bro.
You're right,
Tom.
We just did three hours,
man.
We did already know.
Yup.
This is a time where.
This is part of the hive mentality is
we're missing this place.
That's what happens.
It's weird.
It is.
I'm worried that if we moved studios we
will lose that magic of three hours just
disappearing.
When did you move out?
I don't know,
bro.
Bra.
We're working on it,
bro.
Brown moved to Sherman oaks,
Bro.
Go to Sherman oaks.
They get about it now I'm thinking.
No,
come on in.
There's lots of good space in Sherman
oaks.
Right by my Friday night.
Tom Papa on epics.
What time?
The new specials?
Uh,
8:00
I think.
And epics isn't like on Directv,
but uh,
everybody can get epics for free for the
month.
You can watch on your phone or your
laptop or whatever.
I'll just go to [inaudible] dot com and
you'll be able to check it out to your
special.
And then there's a lot of other specials
too that are on epix.
Jim Norton and I know as a Marin has
special.
All those are available as well online.
Like you can check them out on the
website for sure.
And then it goes to itunes next week.
Well,
I can't wait to check it out,
brother.
I appreciate it.
Thanks a lot,
man.
Motherfucking Papa.
Ladies and gentlemen,
maybe Instagram,
twitter,
facebook bakery near yourself before you
wreck yourself inside.
Joke.
All right folks,
thank you.
See You tomorrow by tomorrow.
That's a good one.