The Joe Rogan experience is sponsored by
the flashlight,
and if you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link and the right hand
side,
you can enter in the code name Rogan and
get 15 percent off.
Enjoy it.
And now here we go.
Buckle up.
Pinches jody is a good experience
with a backup generator.
Enhance.
So Diaz returns.
It's up vegas.
Last time Joey Diaz is here.
The fucking power went out,
man.
That's ridiculous.
That was ridiculous because by the time
the power came back on,
he was so high and we hadn't talked for
like 20 minutes and he was basically
asleep.
It was such an organic podcast because
shit happened and we just kept going.
We just fucking get it moved up.
Yeah.
We started an audio podcast while it was
all going on.
Red Band.
What's happening?
Are you doing what's going?
What the fuck?
Get out of the mic though.
I am.
I'm trying to just sort of general Keith
Richards head to toe.
Look at you look sharper than a
motherfucker.
Yeah,
I,
you know,
I've been noticing I wear hats way too
much and it's not like I'm wearing hats
to cover a baldness or anything like
that.
I just fucking hate fucking with my
hair.
I hate it.
I like being able to hide if I wanted to
try and right now he's trying to make up
for the fact that he's trying to look
sexy and is of like looking,
not look at this picture.
Joe.
This is the short answer is this is the
shirt we're going to be offering on
higher-primate.com.
It is a Joey Diaz shirt by popular
demand in the shirt.
Says Joey Diaz says if you ain't high by
two in the afternoon,
go fuck yourself.
I took attendance and that will be our
number one selling shirt for sure.
All those other monkey,
Buddha marijuana,
those are fine,
but this is going to take it to the next
level.
You got to get the word out.
This is a jump,
Brian.
I lost my in my ear where you were just
doing sound in your ear.
Okay.
Whatever you just did.
You just adjusted something and just
lowered something right there.
That's it.
Just turns it off like that.
Like off and on.
Oh,
that something's not right then.
it's weird.
I've barely touched it.
Oh,
well.
This is a big difference.
We got.
We got to fix that thing.
Anyway.
Whatever.
Uh,
so the Joey Diaz,
if you ain't high by two in the
afternoon,
two in the afternoon and go fuck
yourself.
The t shirts done.
The design is ready.
It's going to be printed up as soon as
we can get it to the,
to the shop.
Should be any minute now.
So I'll let you guys know and Joe Diaz
will be appearing where you have this
weekend.
This week.
I've nowhere nowhere you on Friday
night.
You were in the city.
I'm at the bitter end in New York City
on Tuesday at 9:00.
What is the bitter end to bitter renders
an old rock comedy club that Lenny
Bruce,
George,
Carl and him prior and.
Yeah,
but the last guy to do it.
What's the guy from the daily show?
It's a small little rustic place.
Yeah,
it's a small little rustic place in the
village and the guy's name is Peter
Fogel guy that I met him during the UFC.
I met them in Columbus.
We were both.
You guys went in without me and I had
had to go in Columbus.
They got a weird airport.
You just can't wait online.
You have to get a ticket and wait on
fucking lines.
So I waited an hour and Austin,
they're like,
you ain't got no ticket.
Neither did he.
So he has this look on his face.
He's furious.
I got to get to the hotel.
You guys leaving at 4:45
and for some reason I looked at him and
I just seen this pain in his face and
something.
I never do this.
Just maybe pull back and I go,
hey doug,
you need to but don't you?
And he looked at me like I was Jesus.
He goes,
how'd you know?
I left my weed on the fucking counter
and I went and my ball sack and they
just got it right there at the fucking
taxi cab line.
Him a.
He just looked at.
It looked at me like,
are you fucking crazy?
I was like a spirit that day.
Who gives you a line?
I bought a fucking weed at the airport.
Right there.
Online gives you weed out of their body.
That's the most important part.
That's the crazy thing,
right?
I would probably deny it.
I'd probably like.
No,
no,
that's good.
So I met him at the UFC after that.
And every UFC,
he's a devoted fan.
He goes to all of them.
He goes to the q and a's.
So when we spoke,
he asked me if I was coming.
I told him I couldn't and he goes,
why don't you to do a show a show it my
club now the village,
it's close to Chinatown.
So I just killed two birds with one
stone.
You know what I'm saying?
Wow.
So you're going to do a show with who?
Who's doing it with you?
Solo.
Solo show in between two bands.
Holy Shit.
Why not?
I like that thing.
Wow.
I love that.
I love that little stand.
Hope really created a monster with meat.
When he,
when he started the,
uh,
they're not doing the comedy club
revolution because I really liked that.
Every once in a while you got to step
outside of the comedy club and just get
down.
They only seek to 60.
The tickets are going to go.
And everybody's standing.
No,
no,
no.
Everybody.
They got little tables.
Isn't old fucking rap club.
Jimi Hendrix.
Neil diamond,
Bob Dylan.
You know this is old school.
Fucking geriatrics from the cafe was
off.
I mean this is a real little club.
So you know what?
I don't want to do nothing in Jersey for
my friends and nothing like that.
So I figured let me go into the city and
if I call a comedy club,
they're going to break my balls and
Columbia,
they're going to break my balls.
I'm going to put me up at two in the
fucking morning.
Eight 15 when this will be their wife.
Go through the aggravation one stop
shopping.
All we have to do is just pump it up on
twitter.
We'll pack.
That place will be packed.
So how do people get tickets?
I get tickets if there's no tickets.
You got to go that night.
Tickets go on sale that night.
Old School,
old school,
old school.
Push cash.
They take.
They take credit.
He got a credit card machine.
They got everything.
Wow.
So tickets go on sale when you get
there.
When you get there,
you just got to get there.
That sounds pretty good.
Idea of $10.
No drama.
Come on down bro.
It's a Tuesday night.
You know what?
I don't want a Friday and you don't dog
any fucking mobile on a Friday night.
Let me see you get down to the fucking
Tuesday night old school style.
Nine o'clock,
10:00
show.
Get out of that.
Go to Chinatown.
That's what I wanted.
And I'm on the rock chester the next
day.
So Suzanne and what are you doing in
Rochester?
I'm doing a club called the comedy club
at Rochester,
New York in webster.
It's a great little fluxes.
That's Wednesday.
That's Thursday.
Friday,
Saturday,
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday.
Yeah.
And how do they.
The comedy club can do they think I'm
some kind of name Bro.
It's rock.
Not announced out there,
but there's nothing up there but out.
You know what I liked in bodies?
Frozen bodies.
This is my third time.
I mean,
the first time it was January.
That's brutal.
I'll never do that shit.
Oh,
but then now I go at least towards late
March,
just because,
uh,
you know,
what don't you like to,
to name a comedy club.
Would that be a cool thing?
Yes.
So what would you name your county czar
tans or some shit.
Like the fuck up you baby joe?
Nothing.
My family looks great man.
Thank you.
Say it's amazing to know you a long time
to see what's come of your life.
They're fucking beautiful.
Thanks man.
That's amazing to have your wife and the
supremes as I call it.
That's what you have a bit.
You like the Anna Ross had the three
sisters,
the supremes.
Mrs Rogan has the supreme.
She got the three girls.
It's all over for you.
You like the manage.
Have they done any dance numbers for
you?
Yeah,
like a choreographed dance numbers.
Great.
Joe Rogan's.
Greg got tears in my eyes.
It's looking at you that were very,
very nice.
Especially you know,
you,
you didn't grow up in no fucking mansion
when you were a kid.
You had it,
you know,
look at your little family you've put
together.
He was very proud of you.
Thanks man.
You don't see this much in men and he's
great with them,
isn't he?
He's fucking great with them.
They love it.
They like,
that's big.
Motherfucking daddy came.
Rogan show.
Yeah.
I like your hair today.
Yeah,
it's really nice hair.
It's like you're going to come here and
look.
Yeah.
Let's see.
This is my first communion.
I'm bringing them back.
You know you're on your way to court.
Not on those.
Do you know what a fucking cop tried to
shake me down today?
What a fucking cop pulled me over and I
asked,
you know,
I know they have the camera on the cars.
I just asked him.
Is there any reason why you pull me
over?
Because.
No,
no,
no.
We had,
you're mistaken.
Then we ran.
You play in your.
Okay.
You're free to go.
Then what the fuck you pulling me over
for?
I think it was pulling me over to see if
I was smoking herb,
smoker room in my car.
So you fucked guy.
Really?
You don't think it might've been?
Just exactly what he was saying that
they just get confused.
I know how he did it.
I,
I parked in a different place by my
house and he was on my corner and as I
made a left I seen how he looked at me
and I was doing the speed limit.
I don't fuck around.
I went down and by the time I got to to
hunger,
he had made a u turn and got right
behind me.
Like,
you know when you're looking at your
radio and you look up and there's a cat
behind him,
but he couldn't have been that.
He just thought you were somebody else.
Maybe saw your haircut,
English attracted to you.
He never had another guy with fuck is
wrong with you,
Brian.
Strong possibility Brian.
He thinks so,
but no.
Maybe.
I don't know,
but I thought I was going to be awake.
That's why I called you.
That's why I said this mother fucker's
know.
Pulling me over.
I tell you what makes you think he was
trying to shake it down,
like did they really do that anymore?
You can see in your package.
Just see what's going on.
Maybe he sleep.
I was smoking dope in the car,
you know,
and then when he knows he's got weird
Joe,
you would smoke in the car everywhere
you would smoke in the car and fucking
Texas.
And I'm like dude this is not a smart
move.
And they would give me a hard time.
Don't smoke in the car.
Robin.
I just want to go to jail.
I don't know what else.
This is like,
this is not California.
I don't do it because of that.
I just don't do it because what?
Sometimes the daytime,
I don't need to be that fucking store.
They really gets stalled in the morning.
That's good enough.
If I take with me in the car,
I'd be a mess.
It's funny,
not a smart move.
It is funny how California makes you
totally forget that.
Like in Ohio I was paranoid about
smoking weed,
like a clean up the seeds for my car.
I mean,
I was like,
now I fucking feel like it's everywhere.
That's where their state's laws.
I mean that's how it's supposed to be.
It's not supposed to be that someone can
stop you from doing it,
but it is supposed to be someplace is.
Can decide.
It's okay.
What happened in West Hollywood last
night?
Did you hear about this?
I heard nothing.
All these we'd stores got raided and
some one of them caught fire res Res.
We'd store a is gone zen weed or
something like that.
Yeah,
it,
it's gone.
It's,
there's a sign that says it's closed
forever or something like that.
And since I heard that one of the places
they set on fire,
like,
I don't know if it was the grow yard or
whatever,
but there was one place on fire,
zed fucking you see best jolly rancher
candies.
Yeah.
You will ever eat in your life.
And I was eating them popular with
Ralphie May,
like they were candy.
He'd want a bag of this fucking vape.
And by the third one I'm at the Sushi
place.
I didn't even know where the fuck I was.
Do you guys realize how alien this
conversation is to most people listening
all over the world?
We had this conversation that 30 during
the morning you will learn,
called you and I said,
you know,
as a kid you expect jet packs and you
expect people to Mazda Shit never did.
I thought if any of my youth that at
eight in the morning,
that would be at,
uh,
we store bagels and smoking dope next to
the attorney and a construction way to
come.
Fucking cops up.
Medical marijuana license here to do.
I think so.
I think they're allowed to.
I don't think you can.
I don't think you can piss clean cleans.
Yeah.
Immediately.
I mean to get worse.
I mean I don't think they,
they're allowed to test them.
I shouldn't be talking about in my ass
because I don't know what kind of
testing they do once they're in office
or once they're on the,
on the,
on the job.
But to get to be a cop,
I'm sure they must have to Piss test
yet.
I think at the beginning of something
with a new psychological,
all that shit.
But man,
look,
there's too many fucking restrictions.
If you're a guy who's just got
a fucking job,
all right?
If you're just a guy who works at ups
and you know you've got a decent
management job and you like it and you
got to fucking piss new acup every
couple of months,
so you can't even enjoy yourself at your
brother's wedding.
Everyone's sitting around smoking a
joint,
listening to some good songs,
and you've got to stand over there by
the fan.
Isn't worried.
Yeah,
you're worried that shit's gonna.
Get your hair the fuck man.
That's nonsense that if you get high,
you're only hiring for like two hours at
the most and then it goes away.
Unless you're really high,
unless you eat it.
And even then with the fuck,
by the time you get to work,
most likely you'll be sober if you ate
so much weed that you're still high the
next day.
Have you behind the car guys and
something happens that you go that was
close,
like you missed an accident or somebody
who was next to you and you just put the
blinker on it.
When you realize I've done that so much
and when I'm not high though,
so I can't really judge if that was.
If I would have done that regardless if
I was hiring not,
you know,
like something where you're like looking
down at your shoe or something like
that.
Like what's on my shoe?
I've never been shy and I slipped.
I said,
wow,
that fucking was close something.
No,
no.
I'm,
I'm very conscious of two things.
I don't drive.
If I'm high like that and I don't ever
not pay attention to the road.
Paying attention to the road is
variable.
I always paid.
You'll never catch me texting.
I don't text in my car.
Get the fuck Outta here.
And you know,
I was in a car and once with a check,
she was a publicist for one of the clubs
and she was driving me to radio and
she's fucking texting on the highway.
I'm like,
you got that kind of control over your
car.
Really.
You're gonna.
You hit a rock and that steering wheel
twist to the right and you got this,
you got this.
You're really paying attention to what
you see in front of you.
Are you crazy?
We're going 80 miles an hour.
I had to tell her stop.
I said,
please stop doing that.
You know,
if you're going to text,
you know,
let me drive.
You know,
don't do it.
It's not worth it.
But for a lot of people,
man,
it's too God damn easy.
It's too tempting.
You know it's right there.
My car has a little thing.
BMW has a little knob that you can dial
the phone from all this,
so you got like your,
you know,
your,
your ad just shows up on a screen.
You could scroll through it so you never
have to take your eyes off the road.
You can,
you can just,
you know,
you're right there,
man.
Very Lord has a button.
You just go dial Joe.
Then we have that to BMW.
Has.
They all have that now?
But my point is like,
even that's tricky even that you got to
watch what the fuck you're doing when
you're cooking gas and okay,
but at least you're looking ahead and
you're getting the peripheral in there.
At least you know,
you're getting a decent vision.
But man,
fucking people texted their car,
freaked me out.
I see it all the time.
You're,
you're holding a giant metal machine,
70,
80 miles an hour around a bunch of other
ones and you're not even fucking paying
attention.
You can't do think eventually,
uh,
us as a race is going to get to the
point where is just common.
Like you can do it super easy.
Like you just get trained in,
grown up and effective it.
There'll be another input.
I mean,
it's going to get to some sort of a
neural input at that point.
But,
you know,
that's,
that's all coming.
You know,
we're,
we're resisting all of that.
But I mean,
look,
everything we've got today is fucking
witchcraft.
Three hundred years ago,
witchcraft,
total,
and iphone is sorcery.
Man,
that Shit would fucking burn you at the
stake if you showed up with an iphone.
And now it's here.
What,
what comes next?
We're going to have to get over this,
this human machine interface.
We're going to have to get over the idea
of implants.
People are going to have shit implanted
into their body and you're going to be
able to communicate with,
with other machines.
And uh,
another,
uh,
other people who have chips implanted in
their body,
the human body will become a computer.
My buddy of laughed because my buddy has
a joke.
They did a Texas.
He did a what?
Did either the club,
the part of the Texas that was so
backwards that the opening act was the
magician that they thought he was a
devil worshiper.
Magic.
It was magic.
One of the funniest bit.
And he goes,
Joey,
it was a night from hell.
Oh,
because they were all like White
Christians and this guy was in there.
Vacant birds disappeared shit.
And the devil,
they will like get that devil out of the
building.
They pay them.
That's the fucking lead.
That's beautiful.
That's hilarious.
I thought it was the fucking devil.
You know,
man,
this is a thing about religion.
You can tell me you believe in God all
day,
but as soon as you started talking about
the devil,
Holy Shit.
Did you throw yourself in a box?
Because you can't be all spiritual.
You know,
even spiritual people like,
well,
I didn't believe in religion,
but I'm very spiritual and I definitely
believe in God,
you know?
But they don't go well,
the devil's real.
I'm pretty sure of that.
Yeah,
pretty sure.
The devil's real like,
lives under ground.
Joe.
The devil.
Come on the fuck on.
Come on.
Really?
I can't fucking say you'll.
You believe in the devil.
That's where people draw the line.
When you're saying you believe in the
devil,
you're just going deep,
deep,
deep.
You're going fire brimstone.
Fucking dragons.
This resolved this morning out in the
fucking morning.
Oh,
I get back and I'm just going through
the channels.
I put the news on it.
It was like spiked from last night
watching the UFC countdown without like,
it's this,
the fucking excesses at nine.
Oh,
five in the morning.
Spike is lost at Goddamn mind was on
spike,
probably just people that don't have
this in perspective because it's 2011
and you've had some amazing,
you know,
fucking Avatar type movies and movies
just there on such another level now
than they were back then.
But when the extra ces came out,
dude,
that was the scariest movie of all time.
When that little girl spun her head
around and starts stabbing herself with
a crucifix going,
your mother's sucks.
Cox In hell and she's,
it's meat stabbing into the meat of or
pussy with a.
It was
about will taste them.
I watched the movie this morning for 20
minutes while I was making breakfast and
I sat there and it got me to turn it off
and get the fuck out wrong.
They find that little devil in Africa
and that's why I feel that Africans
always fuck that devil.
They found them that Africans never
looked back.
There's always something going on in
Africa.
Always something dog.
Somebody is getting killed.
There's a war.
Oh Egypt,
this.
Think about it.
Look at Africa.
Every week they got something,
except this week my prayers go out to
fucking Japanese people.
It's crazy.
Every day that gets crazier and crazier
with it,
but you know,
this exorcise was brilliant.
What's the fucking movie with no
interruption?
No,
it's a brilliant move on that movie.
Like a lot of problems,
like a lot of weird things that the
studio burnt down.
It was just fucking crazy.
You know that really.
I think the guy named my cat after
there's a cat in there when she's the
rocking chair and she keeps telling the
priest that priest to be a boxer.
That's Jackie gleason's motherfucking
son in law.
Really?
That's,
that's a shit.
Whatever his father,
real life.
He's enacted.
The kids are active,
but that guy never dimitria remember
like his name is Demetrius and she used
to call them dd my,
you do this to me.
And that was the boxer.
That was the boxer briefs.
Cigarettes and act yet he just beats the
fuck out of the devil.
He got up and live the blessed taking on
the bottom position and then she just
throws them up and let me get it up and
he just goes out the fucking window.
It's a brilliant movie.
They can't do that.
She'll never get.
They don't have that kind of writing.
They don't have that.
Well,
it hadn't been done yet,
so when it was done,
it was.
They went so far with it to you.
He didn't want me.
There wasn't some arguments about
whether or not they should have her stab
herself in the pussy with a cross.
There must've been some studio
conversation back then.
Thought she's screaming,
your mother's sucks.
Cox In hell,
and she's stabbing herself in the
position.
Yeah.
That has had a crazy hats,
but here's the point.
I was wanting.
Terrifying man was brilliant when she's
one of the devil first coming into the
house,
there's a fight one night and her house,
she's having her because she's an
actress to mother and she's having like
a party and the guys,
Germany,
the waiter and the guy keeps saying
something to him,
you fucking Nazi and two days later they
find the guy in the bottom of the
stairway with his neck twisted and they
couldn't figure out.
I mean,
it's a deep.
It's a lot deeper memory.
When she goes up to the astronauts,
she goes,
you're gonna die up there.
Yes.
That was like the first creepy little
girl.
Like in movies.
There's nothing.
I mean the Stephen King,
the twins and shining.
Those are creepy little girls.
Those are kind of interesting.
You know the one.
What does that?
The Japanese one.
What does that one?
Oh the fuck.
Is that the a TV girl?
Yeah,
that the fucking TV.
What?
The TV that crowds out the TV and an
goddammit.
There's an American version of it to
write whatever it is.
That spooky little scary Japanese girl.
I would have sex and the movies.
Would you?
Yeah,
you would.
You fucking idiot.
She was like,
well,
these little twins,
the twins that did full House and Oh my
God.
Yeah.
They were on TV.
They never got to have a childhood bitch
that Blair was putting across and how
Pussy at the age of 12 the somebody went
to Linda Blair said,
Linda,
hi,
can you sit out for a second one,
your mother in the room in this film,
we want you to take a fucking cross of
putting in your little Twat and say,
this sucks Cox and how can you say that?
Repeat that to me.
This movie fucked her up so much.
She ended up hanging out with Rick James
Twenty years later wishing that she was.
She never recovered from that film.
That was one of the.
How could she.
How could you do a movie when you're 12
where you're.
You're stabbing yourself in the pussy
with a cross.
How could you do that and then walks
back and be normal in the house and
she's screaming it.
Mother's sex and that crazy voice.
That was the first original.
Really scary movie because there have
been monster movies before like Dracula
and shit,
but there was nothing that seemed to
real show scary when I was at great one.
I never,
I never saw accesses as a kid.
I saw it as an adult,
but creep show was fucking used to freak
me out.
I used to have old hbo all the time.
Commercial hub of rate creep show is
great.
Elm Street,
the first one fucked my world up a
little bit.
Yeah,
that was a total on xylophone.
Brilliant,
Bro.
That's fucking brilliant.
I don't give a fuck what I believe says
when he goes to pick that up in that
little tongue starts moving.
Yeah.
We were talking about this the other
day,
but the silence of the lambs still
fucking hometown.
There's movies that still night they're
going to do a whole thing on and I've
seen it before about the making of that.
Yeah.
How much went into that?
How about this character movie is a work
of art.
He's a bad motherfucker.
She's bad.
She's so bad ass.
Even when she's nervous,
like she's talking to him like,
you know,
Mr Lichter,
like the,
like her nervousness.
It's like so fucking real.
Like she must've made herself nervous
for that.
Like the way she's doing it.
It's like these little weird twitches in
your lip that you can't even fake.
You know what I mean?
Like you,
you would literally have to be nervous
to be having these little twitches and
quivers in your mouth as she's
communicating.
She's having a hard time getting it out.
She's brilliant dude.
And he hammered vertigo.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Anthony Hopkins.
Come on,
man.
You're just a fucking.
There's so much about that movie that
was so bad ass.
The way he got out of the jail,
the way trick them and got out of the
jail and it's like this suspension of
disbelief.
You don't need much of it.
When he's spiderman,
he throws commenter.
Remember Meigs Meigs made.
That was my nickname from one one
friend,
my friend Jon Jon Tobin,
he used to call me migs because of that.
Why is fucking crazy?
He made Miguel killed himself.
Yeah.
I'll talk to him.
Tell him to kill himself.
Yeah,
nobody's done that.
Since Robert Duvall in Godfather to
talk,
the Freddy is angles into,
to kill himself with a TUB member.
He goes to visit them in jail and he
goes at the end of the party,
that robe is,
we'll get together and eat fruit and
then they'd slice their fucking risks
and the next day they played cards.
And uh,
what's his name?
He cut himself with the TUB.
What's it?
That's a fight.
Holy Shit.
I forgot about that.
Godfather two is one of the few movies
where it was just as good as godfather
one or good enough for me at least.
There's very few that are like that.
What a great fucking film like Alien One
and alien to the is debatable because
like alien too is kind of fun because
there was a lot of God damn aliens and
there was a big giant fucking alien.
It's still pretty bad ass,
but alien one was creepier.
It was a different thing.
It was scale.
You couldn't see it.
He didn't know where it was by the time
you saw that.
Got You.
Yeah,
and it was impossible to kill for is
alien to.
It's like you're killing them left and
right.
Like,
okay,
now this is a totally different thing.
Still ask because these things are
stupid now.
They were super smart and clever and
they would get you in.
Hi Don people.
Now there's like they're killing 10 of
them before one person gets killed.
Like that's silly.
So if you look at that,
but it's still a bad ass fucking movie.
So it's like not,
I don't think it's as good as alien one,
but Goddamn it's still one of the best
all time science fiction movies,
you know,
alien to it.
It just,
the alien one was so fucking bad ass
when that shit came out.
Dude,
I remember I went to see that and the
first thing I said when I got out of the
theater,
I said,
Fuck Star Wars,
Star Wars.
Like that's like written.
I'm a huge star wars fan.
I saw star wars like 13 times and I was
a little kid,
but when I saw alien and I and I was
like,
this dance,
what?
Aliens are going to be like,
man,
it's not going to be like some fucking
furry dude with a bandolier on it.
A gun,
the girl that's not going to be aliens,
man.
Aliens is going to be some weird
parasites that lock onto people and grow
inside our bodies and explode out of our
chests.
Weaver was a bad motherfucker,
wasn't she?
She's bad.
She's bad ass.
That is when she was young too.
You know,
she was fierce.
She didn't give a fuck.
There's a few,
you know,
there's a few people that make acting
worthwhile and they don't seem to need
that much attention.
They,
they seem to be pretty fucking like that
guy who's got my left foot,
Daniel Day Lewis,
that guy,
that guy's a brilliant actor and he
picked you barely even fucking hear a
peep about that guy.
He's never going to like events and
making a big deal about things and
holding press conferences and fucking,
you know,
sitting in talk shows and you know,
crossing his legs,
talking about his fucking vacation,
you know.
No,
no,
no.
That guy's hiding in Ireland.
Learning how to box.
You know what I mean?
He's fucking eaten girl and living in a
prison because he's got to be in a
prison movie was no light to that.
I really respect.
I really respect that part of the ass.
He's the baddest motherfucker of all
time.
Daniel Day Lewis.
Between him and Gary Oldman.
It's like it's a toss up,
you know Gary Oldman even in this stupid
red riding hood move in with us.
He red riding.
I just was that good by the way.
I don't think he ever said it's okay.
It was decent.
You know what it was?
It was like,
it was,
it was.
It was entertaining,
but it was part of it will you say,
wow,
this could have been really good.
It could have been really good,
but it got a little twilight id at the
end.
It got a lot twilight e at the end,
but there's parts of it that.
But Gary Oldman's a bad motherfucker.
Even in a silly movie,
he still comes across like the creepiest
motherfucker.
You makes you uncomfortable when you see
him,
you know,
like a shit.
He's here like you feel it when he's in
the room.
I came.
No fucking cardboard cutout of a
villain.
He's thinking like a fucking villain.
He's,
he's.
His eyes are lit up like a killer.
Like for real.
He's not,
you know,
there's some dudes that don't,
don't know how to do that or they can't
do that.
I don't know what it is.
I,
I can't do it.
I don't know what it is they did.
They do it.
I don't,
I've never been a successful actor,
but whatever the fuck it is that those
guys have those like,
what's his name?
Russell Crowe.
He's got it too.
They can just become somebody.
They can just really become someone
different than who they are.
There's only a few dudes who can do
that,
but those guys were valuable.
You know those guys.
That's a,
that's a crazy trick man.
When you know when you,
you don't.
You know what this guy really fucking
talks like and it's not weird new out,
but all of a sudden he's got this
strange accent.
Like,
you know what Russell Crowe really talks
like,
but all of a sudden he's playing some
guy from Brooklyn and you buy it.
How are you buying into this?
Why?
Why come on?
I know what his real voice sounds like,
but yet I'm still roped in.
He does that good.
You know who's worth $12 million of
funding twice.
You know who's the worst at doing that
though?
Michael stairs.
My flyers.
I mean every single movie is the same
fucking character.
Exactly.
Well,
it's different when you're trying to be
funny.
You know?
He's just trying to fucking act is
listening.
That's a motherfucking actors that could
act as fuck.
And when they.
They're around around
you though that xcel.
Marlon Brando,
that chick from the Postman always rings
twice.
That Jessica Lange bitches were
treacherous.
Willie's fucking little bitches that I
couldn't deal with these,
this tray hanging out at the fucking on
Hollywood.
You'd take half.
These motherfuckers could run with
Marlon Brando when he was swinging Dick
in his day.
Are you fucking kidding me?
They went down a pot.
What's that movie?
Get on the island when he met with him
before he bought the island of Dr
Moreau.
No,
the one before that with a treasure with
warner brothers said,
yeah,
go down and have a blast.
They went down,
wasn't even directly.
He was banging fucking chicks at a time.
He had some water boy fucking film at
the fucking movie.
He had footage in bolts go in birds.
They're like,
what the fuck you been doing on the
months?
That wasn't even going to give the
godfather because when they were like,
we don't even want to hear that fucking
name.
That guy flew eight months of all we
went down and his wildlife or drawing
pictures were sending checks out here.
He pulled the fucking island.
Really?
You don't know about?
Well,
I knew he lived on an island and then
for superman that trying to call them
up,
come back.
He's English and I read the scripts.
I me 100 grand.
You had to pay him to read the script.
When he grabbed you want them to show
up?
That's 100 grand for a.
But I come off the island dog,
so 20 grand to 100 grand to.
Why did they hate dive?
He hit the them wall for 30 fucking
years and they couldn't do nothing,
bro.
The guy showed up at the Oscars,
didn't even show up.
We sent an Indian and go online and look
it up.
She's up.
Fucking shoot this guy last week.
Oh,
well what's this little fact name?
Anne hathaway and the guy all.
They wouldn't be your pitch back to know
what happened.
What happened?
What happened there?
People complaining online that he wasn't
funny.
Bitch you James Franco.
Marlon Brando set the fucking Indians
with a feather that to pick up his
Oscar.
They went Buddha.
That's real Hollywood.
Steve Brown,
Steve McQueen.
Those.
We've had this conversation.
Well that was their only outlet to
express themselves back then.
They didn't have twitter or the internet
or anything like that.
You couldn't like stage a protest fresh
yourself if you wanted to do something,
you wanted to protest something.
Yeah.
You had to do it in during an award
show.
Like on television.
It's good for people to see.
I,
I'd never thought about that completely.
Not only that,
people wouldn't really see it.
How do you receive.
There was no reason you had to make,
like if you wanted to make a stand,
making public stance was very important
back then.
There's the only way you had a voice.
They'll put more in the movement of
those black guys at the Olympics.
They held their fists up and the black
gloves on the black power fist,
you know,
because they're tired of being fucking
treated like their shit their whole
life.
And finally they get to do something.
They will,
they win the Olympics and then like,
look bitch,
you know,
stop all this nonsense,
all this racial hatred.
And everybody looked at it like as if
they're their racist,
you know what they're doing.
Oh,
they're black separatists,
whether they're dangerous.
So that's a reaction.
It's a reaction to the society that they
lived in and where else are they going
to make that protest?
That's the praise.
That's exactly the right place to do it.
They did it subtle enough for me.
They,
they hold their fucking fist up in the
air.
That's subtle enough for me.
That's how the fuck else use.
I'm talking about that message that they
sent.
Sixty.
You know what it was 1960 something.
What did he say?
What does public enemy?
We got a solid.
Raise your fist to the music.
United we stand yet you're violet.
We fought together.
We cast that tall brothers.
Got To work it out.
Celltech sometimes realize it's super
bad.
What's up?
Be bitches.
Look at him.
I'm watching your Brian.
Just fung.
Correct?
He's a very loyal,
very boy.
Swinging slinging.
He's breaking everybody's records.
Let's get that pop star or whatever.
He's looking over it.
Whatever.
So over.
I'm going to do a food truck.
What the fuck?
Brian?
What fucking do you guys ever gone to?
What's up with these food trucks?
I don't know if it's like this
everywhere,
but in la the food trucks have attacked
La.
Like now food trucks are so popular.
They have twitters where you like go on
twitter and find out where the truck is
and they called melrose.
The other date,
the whole street was this food trucks
lined up.
Thousands of people everywhere.
This is a new recent trend,
right brandon?
No,
it's perfect for la because the mobiles
are out there with,
at twitter and you know,
where is he?
Oh my God.
We can't live without the food.
The food's okay.
Grilled cheese.
When have you been chief?
And there's another one that's Papa's
top.
Top.
Top is God.
Damn.
And they don't pay rent.
There's no overheads.
The food's very cheap.
You know,
it's not
bad.
Pretty bad ass.
Say happened in front of skinny.
So there's that to have an open mic at
skinny's.
You'd go in there and do comedy and
other way.
I got these fucking trucks everywhere.
So.
Wow.
I see those Mexican ones,
I don't take the chance.
No,
they're like,
there are those upgraded,
you know,
like nowadays they're like,
it's like a restaurant.
I think about taking a chance though
sometimes like there's a video in the
valley who I'm going to take you there
if you want to go get some real Mexican
food talk you.
Yeah.
They're always deads legit.
It's um,
I think it's in woodland hills.
It's on.
I'm like van owner,
something like that.
That plays in the jet dude there.
Their pork tacos.
Carnitas.
Oh,
last night though.
They have the dirty bowl of pickled
Jalapenos and carrots just sitting out
there.
Anybody could just stick their fucking
hands in there.
No one cares.
Big little play to Jalapenos and and
radishes and shit like that and those
Jalapenos will fuck your world up.
These are the Jalapenos they grew.
You know what I'm saying?
Like they grew these shits in their
backyard.
They got these new Jalapenos that'll
make your ass bird like just when you're
shit,
they stay there all day.
It's subtle fucking Berg to remind you
all day you're in the bathroom.
Triple wiping because you think you
didn't wipe right.
You think you have like the second
remorse coming out of your muffler,
but these new Jalapenos where they burn
your ass all fucking day.
New Jalapenos.
I had this last week or two.
My ass was on fire all fucking day.
I'm done with that stuff.
What?
You don't eat Mexican food.
How is that shit just fucked me up dude.
I make a cornea,
Sada burritos with fresh Jalapenos and I
chop them up in there when I chop up
like a whole pepper and a half and then
in one burrito and it just fucking
cleans the whole system out.
Sun snots from.
Oh God.
Tears are coming down your eyes.
Your tongue is on fire for God.
Damn.
Your body's like gets like a jolt.
It feels like you're.
You're fucking dusted off all the
bullshit.
Yeah.
You don't.
You don't get into it and shitting out
half a quarter likes,
mashed potatoes,
mashed potatoes and meatloaf.
No gravy,
please.
Thank you.
Do you have milk?
Mashed potatoes?
Have whole milk that a white bread.
I had a piece of Mesh meatloaf and last
night on white bread.
Wonder bread.
Shit on that motherfucking stopped.
Has another strong place to eat.
There's a place called chicks out here
in the valley.
And uh,
I think that's an calabasas maybe
somewhere around that.
Anyway,
this fucking place has made their own
rotisserie.
They throw wood in it.
It's a wood burning rotisserie.
Family owned.
They've owned this place fucking
forever.
You have to pay cash.
Yeah,
he'd been there before.
You have to pay cash.
They don't have credit card machines.
Fuck you.
Cash.
And they got this fucking brisket
sandwich dude.
It's a barbecued brisket with,
with mashed potatoes in the sandwich.
Those.
There's a layer of mashed potatoes and a
layer of this mouth watering brisket and
it's all in together.
And you,
you know,
it's a giant ass dude.
I'll take you there after
this.
You're going to shit your pants.
I'm,
I,
I ate it.
I added two days ago and I've had
irregular shits ever since then.
I am so backed up.
That's all from this thing.
It's giant.
It weighs 13 pounds.
It's the biggest sandwich you've ever
eaten.
I shit green like fluorescent green
today.
And the only thing I can think of
mushrooms,
the mushrooms now bro.
That's tripped your whole gates bro.
It was weird when I talk about that.
The I,
I dreamed your whole for my first time
in like seven or eight years.
I shouldn't,
uh,
two days ago.
Beautiful.
Can you get some?
I could get the fuck.
Are we not on the Internet?
Yukon.
Jesus Christ.
You guys are going to get rated.
No,
we're not going to get any fucking shit.
You fucking guys are a little too casual
about this weekend.
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm excited about New York.
Started to do a opie and anthony.
I'm so excited to do the Wayans.
Can't wait to do shows like Gotham.
Excited about everything,
man.
You Dot.
I'm sorry I missed you.
It was just that I didn't want to ask
you that really beloved gave me the rock
chest the week when I was there last
year and all of a sudden I see the UFC
is back to this year,
so I didn't want to leave for 10 days in
a row.
And Ashley.
Yeah,
no,
I understand.
No,
no worries man.
No worries.
I said fuck it because a,
I wanted to go back,
but I didn't want to go back there
because it's going to be busy the next
couple of weeks and it's weird because I
was telling you that I'm going to visit
a buddy of mine that wanted to tell you
the story just so you didn't know it at
83,
you know,
I was a fucked up kid and I was at a bar
one night and this kid came in and I
knew his whole family.
I knew his younger brothers and this kid
had gone to the Air Force Academy where
you had one you got onto the train or
something once?
No,
I went to the Olympic training center
and his other brother went to Brown and
we used to go visit his brother and his
brother used to be there with Kennedy
was on campus.
They were in the same fucking thing.
So we would go up there and watch jackie
o come to the campus and people would
throw shit at her and call her jackie o
Yukon.
It was fucking crazy.
But just to get back to the story,
uh,
I wanted to get out of jersey,
you know,
I wasn't doing the right thing,
and uh,
he came to me,
he's like,
I got a place in Colorado if you want to
come.
He goes,
we'll buy a car and drive out.
And I was like,
I'll give you the money for the car.
But I wanted to rob this dude.
Right.
I wanted to rob this drug dealer that I
used to hide three kilos.
They used to deliver three kilos a month
to his,
to his building and he would hide it in
his parking garage.
So if somebody slipped one night of the
party and said that his buddy got three
kilos delivered and he didn't want to
put the coke in his house.
So I was,
my plan was to rob the kilos now at the
time I used to deal with a loan shark
all the time.
And he was my,
you know,
he wasn't my friend,
but I knew him for years and I was
trying to set him up to.
I would make him payments.
Every resource that was going to do is
rob the drug deal is give him the five
grand I owe to wait 10 days and then hit
him for 50 and then take off the
Colorado.
If I was gonna do right.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
When I got lost dog,
I used to be the real deal.
I've been trying to tell you this for
years.
So you were going to pay him back and
then Robin,
I was going to pay him back.
I used to borrow from this guy
constantly.
Okay.
Years.
He owned a bar.
He was a mob guy.
We used to borrow from constantly,
constantly like you.
You fucking borrow $500 to 7:50.
So that was 10 weeks of $75 a week.
So people would come to me and said,
Bro,
I'm in a bind with George.
I'm in a bind.
Can you get me money from George?
And I would borrow it and I get a point
every week.
So I was lending out money.
So altogether my bill was six grand with
him,
but it was people that were paying the
guy.
Do you understand,
and I have a weird thing like lending
money.
Oh,
it's amazing.
It's an east coast thing.
This is huge.
It's not an east coast thing.
If everybody loans loan this loan sharks
in facts alone.
Sharks,
banks,
and that's.
Yeah,
no,
you're right.
Some people have a card business and
they really.
They're in a bind.
They legit people,
but they want to buy 10 cars.
They don't have the cash on him,
but you know what?
God Damn.
Could you imagine?
There's no banks.
How much it would suck if you had to
carry all your money around,
you know,
it's sort of you had gold,
one of your work like fucking second
there.
I come with a horse and stab me in the
fucking what the fuck?
That's when people used to like hold up
money and dig holes in the dirt and
burry shit it.
That's why they did because they
couldn't carry it on.
It's stupid.
I know how much money is buried still.
Whatever banks cost their worth and even
when they rip everybody off,
God,
it would suck if there's no banks.
He has no banks.
What?
Where's the money?
Monday doesn't even read the problem.
Money is.
It doesn't really mean anything anymore.
It's not like this hundred dollar bill
is worth $100 worth of gold.
It's not based on gold anymore.
It's based on like confidence,
like you have to like believe in,
in the money.
Silly.
That's crazy.
That's why everyone should just spend it
as fast as possible.
It doesn't make sense.
I mean,
gold makes no sense anyway.
even if you get to that,
I mean the fact that everybody was in
the gold,
you know,
the only thing that makes sense about
gold is that I guess it's,
it's rare.
You know,
it's,
you can't just have it.
You can't just like say,
look,
I've got millions of dollars because
it's everywhere.
Just go out into the woods and cut it
down.
It's hard to get.
But what the fuck man.
So can I just got to be a better way to
fucking go?
You right away,
right away.
You're poor.
Reveal with gold was thought about but
fascinating.
Fascinating.
$800 a fuck.
So you're ripping people off.
So I'm not ripping nobody off.
I'm going to set this guy up because I
wanted a new life in Colorado.
So we're gonna rob this drug deal.
I was going to take that money,
pay the loan shark off,
wait 10 days and go,
Hey,
I've got a line on a kilo Kokanee
$50,000.
He probably gave me 30 and I was gonna
move to Colorado and buy property,
whatever the fuck is.
And why didn't you think he was going to
go after you?
Because they don't.
They don't go outside.
Fucking New York City.
That's only in the movies.
These fucking.
These guys go to Miami and escape.
What I'm saying?
You know the people you grew up with in
Boston,
where do they go?
They go to the fucking whatever.
That the fucking pigeon place in Boston
in the summer and that.
Anything out of that area,
that comfort zone,
they fucking freak pro.
They can't take it.
You know?
The mob really lost a lot of credibility
when sammy the bull gravano got away
with everything.
Everybody lost credit.
No,
that was the most ridiculous thing.
I was like,
I thought for sure it was going to kill
that guy.
Right.
That's what happens.
You can't be a rat.
You know?
He walked the Donna up.
Whoa.
There must be like people coming after
him.
That's when you realize like,
Whoa,
this is not the organized thing than it
appears.
You know,
Sammy the book who Chicago cops were
putting together the murder.
Sammy the bull really to make money.
Yeah.
How much was the money?
I had no idea,
but they knew that there was a contract
that will and Chicago cops are going to
go down and blasting.
That's a crazy hand.
Used to be a dirty cop,
man.
You've got to really take a chance.
You got to really put yourself out
there,
you know,
and to get a bunch of other dirty cops
together.
Like you gotta like assumed that you're
all going to keep your mouth shut and
you're all wet.
But it happens all the time.
Man,
all the time.
They're always busting cops.
This is too much.
Too much power.
There's certification.
I've searched before.
There's tons of dirty cops on Craig's
list.
Oh Bro.
Like he stumbled on that one too,
so excited to get it out.
You know what's crazy man?
Because after a cop is a cop,
you know,
I can just imagine being living lawyer
life to protect your country and blah
blah blah blah blah.
And also one day you actually,
to be a cop,
you have to have a certain gene.
You really want to help people.
You really have to genuinely hurt help
people because it's $30,000
a year or it's just you'd want the job.
Some people just want that.
I think it's more than that.
Thirty 8,000
to start is that a little walk a beat
and carry a gun at people shoot at you
melodies.
Cops are getting fucking rich.
You got to be a cop for years and become
a detective.
And First Brad and how much can I
detective make?
Seventy,
80,000,
maybe 100,000.
A commander,
chief.
One hundred and $50,000.
I don't know,
but I don't think a lot.
That's why this dirty fucking cops.
That's why one day they go,
what the fuck am I doing right?
I have to take a little bit here,
take a little bit,
you know,
I'm making $38,000
a year,
you know,
and this guy wants to give me 5,000
so I don't.
Buses book making operations on the
corner would have fucking ain't
bothering,
you know,
that's how it starts and it's A.
I guess it's like,
Hey,
we were talking about the idea that you
had had a dick on and he said that
sometimes when you're doing a bad show,
you're so upset with yourself that you
resort to doing genome.
You're just not happy with you
conditionally your life.
And what's happened for a cop to.
It's fucking tough being a cop every
night and at the end of the day you go
home at eight in the morning after a 12
hour shift and you're making 40 grand a
year and people shooting at you and you
got to be out there in the rain and you
know,
nobody.
You know,
it's funny because only on tv if people
nice to cops,
cops put up on a lot.
On the other end,
you know,
people like me,
I was a criminal,
so I'm always a gentleman to cops.
I don't want to fight in that war and so
it was nice as honey.
I was nice,
you know what I'm saying,
but there's people that didn't have a
little money or take that bad to the
bone.
They're like,
why are you pulling me over for a bit?
You get a ticket motherfucker for
opening up like that.
So the officer was I doing something
else inside there because there's a lot
of people that are fucking crazy and you
need some protection from those peanuts.
You need somebody pulling them over when
they're weaving in between lanes.
He needs someone tackling them when
they're ready to shoot people in a
fucking mall.
You need cops.
People that don't think you need cops
are crazy.
I give this talk.
I go,
oh,
the older I got and the wiser you get.
I give my life to teachers,
cops.
Anybody who's a public servant,
you know,
all last week we're talking about this
fucking Mutt.
Charlie Sheen was basically a fucking
rich junkie.
If you come down to it that's just
sitting there talking shit,
do you have the balls to go on a plane
right now and go to Japan and helped
those fucking people?
Nobody talks about those fucking people.
Nobody really.
Nobody listens to a fucking doctor.
If a doctor did a fucking podcast today
and tried to tell you how to stay
fucking healthy,
you think you'd get the views.
You get all this fucking mole,
mole,
Charlie Sheen.
Now Dr Oz,
Dr Oz show.
Think about that fucking society.
Those guys in Japan right now picking
the fucking walls and there's kids under
the yelling,
the screaming.
They'll see things we wouldn't even
imagine seeing in a lifetime.
Those guys are going to come back and
next week we'll have another disaster in
Venezuela when Oregon and those guys
will never get.
Not even a fucking thank you.
You don't want that.
That that's always killed me.
I can never be a public servant.
I'm too much of a fucking piece of shit.
There's people out there that are just.
That's what they live for,
you know,
and they really believe in it,
bro.
The day after that earthquake,
think how many people just got on a
plane and they just came back from
somewhere else.
Where was there an earthquake?
They just.
They just got battling bucket,
Earthquake Zealand,
New Zealand.
When the church and the hotel.
A lot of God damn earthquakes lately.
Fucking dude was sitting here like
pigeons on a pond.
I don't know what the fuck we're doing
here and giggling like a bunch of
fucking wouldn't that.
It's either going to be San Francisco
oriented bias and more time and then
we'll fucking next because we need to go
to fucking taxes when shit goes down.
Texas is the best place to live.
At least all the guns are going to come
on and ship,
but think about all that shit last week
with these people.
Thinking about what it takes to go over
there right now.
One of those people get paid to get on a
plane and go help those Japanese people.
It's a good question.
Fucking I.
I turned down $50 fucking gigs.
If I got to drive an hour,
these motherfuckers are going over
there.
I think about that,
bro.
You know,
what can they even do right now?
Right now,
what they have to do is figure out how
to deal with those nuclei.
You can walk into a reactive place when
you have no idea who they are,
but people in this country give a
Frenchman fuck about that physical
sucker.
Charlie Sheen that's around the state.
I think no one cares about charlie sheen
anymore.
I think it's Ah,
it's fucking feels like,
what the fuck?
Who gives a fuck?
It's really quick.
It burned out quick.
I loved it for,
for the call,
like Belushi,
Dan Stream video killed it for me.
I think.
Yeah,
me too.
It's just all first one.
When the guy was playing the fart
noises,
I'm like,
Whoa,
these are the people he's hanging out
with.
That's when he dug.
Or you believe that shit.
That's.
Those are coke people.
Those Code People Are Idiots.
You know?
And that's,
that's what it is.
COPD people are these weird fucking
selfish,
indulgent,
self-destructed people to not fun to
hang out with.
There's no cool conversation.
I just did it for 30 fucking years and
for the first 10 I did it with people
because it was fun.
You know how it's fine.
Oh my God,
let's do as great.
After that,
I became this person that was inside.
I can be out with people,
but I'd never hung out with those.
I don't like it.
I can't listen to people when they doing
coke,
I want to kill him.
That's why after a while he came and
chicks hall because all you want
them to do is suck your Dick.
I got listen to this fucking story
again.
There's a line snot.
It sucked.
I'm fucking.
Well,
when everybody likes about this whole
Charlie Sheen thing is that this guy is
saying,
you know,
fuck it.
I'm just gonna have fun.
This is what I do.
This is how I roll.
You know,
you don't like it.
Fuck you.
I'm a rockstar and you know that he's
got this crazy confidence and everything
is doing,
you know,
winning next and everybody wants to be
able to think like that.
Everybody wants to be able to,
you know,
like people that are struggling and
they're going through some shitty job
like God damn,
how bad ass would it be to be fucking
Charlie Sheen right now?
It's really fun though.
You said something to me after the Vegas
show.
You took me aside and you're like,
ah,
yeah,
Joey,
you know you're standing up.
I can see you're working on it or
whatever the fuck you had to say to me.
Well,
the coke was doing the same thing to my
fucking stand though.
Instead of writing jokes,
all I used to say was fucking I'm Joey
Diaz.
I could bang it 50 percent.
I grew up.
There lies the Bro Drugs.
Coke cigarettes.
They lie to you this 80.
It's buying into some Columbia and I'm
not saying he's a,
he's on the money,
but I am saying that if he didn't die
this way,
what is he going to live forever and
cure cancer with the fuck differences in
May?
He's,
I mean,
the only thing that's sad and tragic
because his kids are gonna miss him,
but you know what I mean?
What is he doing?
What does he want to do with himself?
This is what he wants to do.
And what's a fucking party?
I don't think you should stop them.
Oh No,
you're kidding me.
Is so for swore.
I thought it was off.
Nobody important.
Felt right.
It happens to the Times I made the
mistakes to a call.
Of course it's sussman.
So yeah,
showrooming man was fucking amazing.
But you have a great honor.
It was visual.
It was to the point where the person I
was with,
I could see their like energy flowing
through their skin and then like we went
outside and the stars are going crazy
and then like shadows looked like they
had texture.
It was amazing for a,
for good our diary or anything.
Just just bright green shit today.
That's what kills me to the.
That trip when I was.
I used to get the diarrhea while I was
on the mushroom.
I that last time just got,
when I lived in Colorado,
I'd eat a mushroom in 10 minutes late.
I'm going to shit.
Trying to figure out how many trees they
cut,
but have you done the.
Have you done it the t way before that
seemed like it was so much easier on
your stomach and it didn't have any
proxy is fucking Greg's done.
The Tif.
A conscience.
That's great.
Had
the emoney to Mascara.
T what's that?
And how was that the,
uh,
the mushroom that they believe is
responsible for Christianity?
I was so crazy.
Red and white mushroom.
It looks like Santa Claus.
Is it like a mushroom mushroom?
Like our main psychedelic mushrooms,
psychedelic mushroom,
but it's a different sort of a
psychedelic.
It's very weird,
you know,
I don't know if what I got was good
stuff.
It is very strange.
And then Doug and I did it and the day
we did it was the day the war broke out.
Nine slash 11.
Yeah.
The day we went to war and we decided to
go this dude yawns house,
you know,
showing your shit,
Bro.
That's you son.
Anyway,
we'd go to this kid,
uh,
John's house and he lives out in the
middle of the desert.
Weird fucking town out in Palmdale area
or something,
you know,
not there,
but one of those towns where you're
like,
what the fuck?
WHO's out here?
Why?
What are you doing out here?
And we get blitzkrieg on mushrooms out
there.
And then we watched the news and the
news.
I'll never forget this,
I've talked about this before,
Doug.
Stan Hope said the guy goes on,
he goes,
war coverage begins at five and Stan
help goes,
holy shit,
there's a kickoff.
We're shroom to the gills to the point
where everything I see,
I shouldn't be social.
I should've been alone in the room
called closing my eyes and my back.
Oh you see the.
I saw the fabric of the universe as I
was walking.
Everything was a pattern in front of me.
It was all really intense,
complex geometrics.
It was like,
like the,
the,
the covering of the walls,
like wallpaper or doors or anything that
all that stuff was be.
It became transparent and you could see
literally the structure of the universe
through everything it was.
We were fucked.
I mean,
we were gone and,
and the fucking war coverage starts and
it was so strange that she's crazy.
I couldn't imagine it was so bizarre.
Man Just didn't seem real.
It's like it's 2000 and whatever the
fuck it was back then to three and I was
like,
this is how we're rocking it.
This is how we're rocking it.
We're just going to the fuck.
That probably fucked you up somehow.
You know,
it's really like burned into your mind
because mushrooms with nine slash 11.
That's insane because nine slash 11 was
crazy for everybody because that was
something they'd never saw ever.
You saw it in a psychedelic way going
off.
Not nine slash 11,
so nine slash 11.
I,
you remember when we were hanging out?
Interesting.
We went over to a Mike pavements house.
It was Eddie and Ralphie and Joey.
It was an interesting fucking day
because a boy at the shit had went down
and we went to Baja fresh and we had
some burritos and we were just sitting
there and shooting the shit and just
talking and not a fucking plane in the
sky.
That was one of the weirdest things when
they shut down on the flights,
not a plane.
This guy speaking,
a favorite man.
He has a new book out and he's been
actually doing real.
Yeah.
Tour like the morning show toured all
around and stuff.
Him and his other book?
Yeah,
it's a cookbook.
He writes it for camping for like,
like gourmet food while you're camping
and stuff or outside.
And I haven't ever eaten food but I hear
he's a bad motherfucker.
Chicken is chicken Lod puts on it,
but it's crazy because I did a,
a hit a window pane acid one night when
I was,
why do they call it window says was like
a clear acid.
It was like a,
it looked like a piece of glass.
So,
uh,
I did it one night and the people I were
with,
the one guy was with freaked out.
It was a Monday night football game and
he goes,
Bro,
I got to go home.
Like,
all right,
I fucking call.
I guess I'll trip solo.
So I went and I got a call for a buddy
of mine and knock on his door.
There's dances,
he's like,
Joey,
come on.
If I'm like Mr Bender,
I can't ya come on in and have a soda.
Wait him,
he should be back from the gym or
something.
So I sit down and I'm sitting at
tripping my ass off watching fucking
Monday night football with him and he's
telling me about the stats of the game.
It was the jet game and I'm sitting at
its dark.
He watched the TV and the dark and all
of a sudden Howard cosell comes on.
He goes,
I like to report something.
John Lennon has just been shot in front
of the coders and here I am tripping on
acid and I'm flying by this time and
he's watching tv,
the darkness and he's talking about,
and I'm thinking about John Lennon and
getting shot reports are coming in.
He's getting just got shot in the Cota.
We'll keep you posted.
Oh my God.
America.
I have a sad former beat or he just went
into the speed.
You could hear it on youtube,
but I'll never forget sitting there
thinking to myself,
you know,
like because when you,
when you're tripping,
you really can't comprehend the foot and
they go through you.
It's like John Lennon got shot and they
shoot the other Beatles.
Well,
I hope they shout out just fucking going
and you can't stop these fucking
thoughts.
But that was what happened to me that
day.
Like I just want to call for Brian and
he's like,
Brian ends up playing out of his league,
but if you want to sit and watch the
game,
weird.
When you remember when people died,
the jolt.
Like,
what is it?
What is it about memory that some
memories are so much more potent than
others.
Some memories just stay forever.
They just locked in and you just don't
get rid of them.
You remember where you were sitting,
you remember what the room looked like
or you think you remember what the room
looked like?
A,
but it would be a little bit different
if you actually saw in real life.
But when people died,
like I remember I was at my girlfriend's
house when I was like 18 and the space
shuttle Challenger blew up and I watched
it blow up on tv and I didn't realize
what had happened while I was flying to
the.
I'm not sure if I saw a replay of it or
if I saw it live,
but I didn't know what was happening.
And then it blew up and then I realized
what they were showing and then I had
turned the volume up and I'm watching
this.
I'm like,
Holy Shit.
Like it blew up in the sky,
but I can see the carpet,
I can see the walls of her room.
I mean I can see the whole thing.
I remember everything.
It's like it's a locked in on me know.
What is that?
Why,
why?
How come?
I mean is it just that we'd not have
enough capacity to remember shit like
that all the time?
I don't know if it's that or what,
because sometimes that kind of shit pops
out of nowhere though.
Like it wasn't deleted.
Like,
like Oh my God,
I forgot all about that.
And like all these memories come rushing
in like out of nowhere.
So it's,
it's almost wonder,
makes me wonder if there is a drug or
something that could just open all the
doors are open all the memory.
Have you access to all files?
I've been taking this five htp.
What does that shift from GNC where it's
supposed to be pumping more serotonin,
serotonin and stuff like that where I've
been only taking it for a week,
but immediately I already find my,
my mind working better in memory.
It really?
Yeah.
In a happy and happiness.
I feel like more.
Of course there's other reasons too.
Well,
you know,
Chris and I are
coming up with a,
uh,
like a supplement line.
We're going to figure out all the best
shit like we're working on right now.
He is working on it and we're going to
have pills where it's all of the best
vitamins for mental throw that shit in
function.
Throw that shit in there.
If he can do five act.
You know what I'm talking about that
I've never done it before.
But you know what I'm talking about,
right?
If I take a bunch of different stuff,
but that's not one of them,
what exercises me is what I really write
about a situation when I sit down like,
okay,
can I have on the right about the time I
tried off a freshman football and even
though I have no fucking idea about it,
and then the memories come back to that.
Everything.
Everything in that genre.
Yeah.
Everything in that genre that maybe had
to do with music music when we're
driving stuff,
nobody ever gets teary eyed in the car.
You hear a song man,
my buddy johnny be my best friend had
died and whenever I hear van Morrison,
marvelous knife for a moon dance,
that was like his son,
we would go to the diner.
These diners in New York,
they're all lot of them are here like
this that you split around a little bit.
Yeah,
and they had the fucking thing when you
can pick the songs to listen to and you
put a couple of quarters in there and
you can play songs.
Yeah.
You have like little shitty speaker,
two bucks and we'd be eating
cheeseburger.
Deluxe is at 3:00
in the morning after playing pool and he
would play moon moondance,
so now it doesn't matter where I am.
I was in Germany,
in the hotel and it's playing in the
lobby.
Marvelous knife or a moon dance and I'm
like,
mom saw you just think about that dude.
Things get stuck in there man.
But you know what?
Nothing gets stuck in there.
My Act,
no.
My old material shit on some of the
people will like yell out at a show.
Like I've had that a bunch of times,
especially when I was doing the q and a,
which I haven't been doing recently
because I'm trying to do more like a
tighter,
hard,
tighter id too.
I,
you know,
I thought of that after I saw Norton,
saw Norton in Austin and killed.
He had a great set and he only did it
like 50 minutes and I thought about.
I'm like,
man,
that's really all you need to do.
These hour and a half sets that I'm
doing two hour sets and a lot of it is
just quick q and a.
Some people like it,
but some people feel obligated to stick
around like it's just like it's too much
attention that you're asking for,
tell them your show's over and then do
the cube with A.
Maybe I'll figure out another way to do
q and a,
maybe do a night where it's just q and a
or it's not gonna make it real cheap,
you know,
just to pay for the room and make it so
that like one night maybe there's not a
standup show.
It's a q and a show because it's like,
it's a little indulgent.
But anyway,
my point is when people yell out shit,
like yell out,
you know,
do this bid,
do like Noah's Ark or something like
that.
Man,
I fucking forget a lot of them.
Like if you,
you yelled out,
Anna Nicole Smith was one of my best
buds ever.
But if I go back and try to figure out
how to do it now,
I'll fuck it up.
You didn't know his arc.
Pretty good.
The other day somebody would pull that
out because I was baked as Jesus was
Jesus on an asteroid.
Like I even forgot it,
I can't believe I remembered it because
that was the first time I had done it in
years and this guy asks for it.
I was like,
wow,
I don't even know if I can do this,
but I did it and close with it,
but that's,
you know,
that was a mistake in vegas too to do a
q and a in front of 2000 fucking people
and there's just too many people.
Too many people yelling shit out.
If I was going to do something like
that,
I had to do with microphones,
like have like a little line like we did
in Columbus when we did the DVD.
When does the UFC coming back to
Columbus?
Are they ever going to come and think we
are maybe in the future,
but we just did striked with aged
strikeforce.
Did the last Columbus Shell to Arnold
was just two weeks ago.
Yeah.
I was always a cool weekend.
He had the arnold show.
Fuck.
Yeah,
it was awesome.
that's why I did my special club.
That's funny bumps.
Great.
Did the theater that I did too was um,
what's it called again?
The southern theater,
the theater that we filmed the special
and Mae West used to perform there and
fucking Groucho Marx.
Wow.
Oh No,
no,
no.
Not Groucho Marx.
WC fields.
WC fields and Mae West perform there.
What the fuck,
man?
That's some history.
That's amazing.
Imagine trying to be an actor back then.
How fucking tough it must have been.
I mean,
shit,
there's,
there's no internet.
There's,
I mean you got to get picked to do
things.
You got to get picked.
The state studio has to choose you.
That's probably.
There must have been so much chicanery
going on back then.
What's that should carry?
I'm like in appropriate behavior.
It was different than it was
words like,
like,
like an African.
Sometimes the patient cracks like an
African person.
Huge word sometime.
I'm like,
what?
Gina is probably a big word.
That's how it even intelligent.
Where it's a silly word.
I think it's like a swine term.
Yeah.
But that's way different than the
vocabulary.
Then I met Joey Diaz.
Did you know what that word with?
No,
what?
I'll all,
I'm trying to remember what the fuck I
was trying to say about weird
because if you talk to people from them,
like even in Hollywood was different
than they'd move out here and you and
you suck everyone's Dick and then they
give you a script and get a loaf of
bread.
They gave you a paycheck every week and
you just got assigned different films.
All those guys that you see from the
sixties and fifties that way here.
They all lived in Burbank,
Burbank,
all those houses that look the same
shit.
You remember all those movies about like
jfk,
like they always have those belongings
that were with jfk that were like sort
of semi disposable.
They would always be like hanging
around,
but they never really addressed them.
Right.
That's like 90 percent of what came to
Hollywood.
People came here last looking to stick.
Some people stuck.
The people that did stick,
all the other people's had look,
they stuck,
looked a little stilted,
they stuck.
They're still there.
They're famous and they get sucked into
the system and wind up being one of
those little quiet girls.
And JFK is arm that's still happens
today.
Fuck yeah,
it does.
This is it,
man.
This is the land of dreams.
This is the strangest fucking place on
earth.
This is the place where you go to
maximize how many people who know who
you are,
what you can make a living.
Just on that.
Now you got to suck a little Dick and do
something where people pay attention to
on the Internet,
like Kim Kardashian and move.
Basically.
She started out blowing her boyfriend
and fucking him on the Internet and
videos obviously produced videos,
you know,
obviously produced.
Absolutely.
And then she's fucking macy's.
Now she's signing perfume bottles at
macy's.
I was in Australia and there was a
fucking billboard with Kim Kardashian on
it in Australia.
She goes around the girl,
good for her,
figured whatever.
I mean,
she's not diabetic dog.
This is,
there's nothing wrong.
But it's fascinating that this is the
spot where all this goes down.
This is the spot where everybody comes
to to make something happen.
It comes to,
to get some attention.
There's a lot of people that fall
through the cracks.
You know?
There's a lot of victims in this fucking
town,
so people have come and gone since
you've been a lot,
how have you ever gotten facebook and
saying,
hey,
no.
You're like,
Ooh,
those are creepy.
I just happened to that guy because I
forget about half the people that moved
to upstate New York member Laszlo
Laszlo.
He used to hang out at the comedy store
all the time.
A long time ago.
Laszlo.
He moved to Florida.
Anyway,
nevermind.
He's somebody that just slipped away.
Used to.
We used to talk to him like every week
it.
I do not remember that guy.
I remember.
I don't remember what it looked like.
What was the town coordinator?
When we first got to the store,
he hits me up.
He's like in fucking Jerusalem.
Jerusalem,
walking through Europe right now.
People have come and gone that had big
plans and deals.
Yeah.
Scripts and I've met with Pachino last
week.
These motherfuckers ain't God Jack.
We've seen a lot of the real estate.
I got an email last week on my regular
email from some dude and I call them
back and I'm like,
hey,
how you doing?
He was my first manager.
Whoa.
And He.
He was a filter.
His family was filthy rich and he went
back to sell real estate.
He's like,
Hey man,
I'm just calling you because I'm opening
up comedy clubs again.
What I'm finding steady goes the bottom
fell out,
but it's amazing that I forgot all about
that fucking dude.
That was fucking years ago.
Yeah.
Some people just decide it's not for
them.
What am I?
Just too much stress that we were
friends with that one day she
disappeared,
but we were friends.
How many friends and we had that got a
lot.
How many people with talent?
People that came to the store,
so I got a script I just sold and you've
got both.
A year later they're like,
oh no,
I'm doing radio in Wisconsin.
What the fuck?
You would just sell the script.
That paramount.
It's amazing how many people come and go
through it and get spit out.
Do this.
So many.
How about guys with talent?
How about Mike Ricco?
Huh?
How about Mike Greco?
Greco.
When I started out in 1994.
Mike Ricco was a funny fucking comic.
He's a funny guy.
I'm sure he's very funny.
I saw when I saw Mike Recur at the
store,
I remember thinking we were probably
around the same age or something and I
remember thinking,
this fucking guy is going to be huge.
This guy is funny.
He's funny.
He's confident up there.
He'd already had the article written,
written about them.
When I went to the store that was like
an article that was framed like in the
lobby,
like a little article about Mike Rucker
or think that's kind of fucking take
off,
but for whatever fucking reason to the
pieces,
don't fall in the right order,
you know?
It's just amazing.
It was a weird.
Chelsea Chelsea handler was up there
with us from day one.
She's going gang busters now.
That crazy bitch look at her.
She's kind of like sitcoms and she's got
her own fucking show,
like a reality show about her show.
So she's got her show and then she's got
a reality show about are so good for
her.
I hope she's the white drunk oprah.
That's what I hope for.
You know,
who I heard was on that reality show
about Chelsea?
Uh,
the girl from Denver that the assistant.
Oh really?
Awesome.
He's one of the characters.
Yeah,
she drove from Denver.
Remember the assistant that you to
always drive us around or the comedy
works.
Yeah,
I do remember,
but why am I blanking on her name?
Eve?
Eve.
Eva,
Eva.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
She's awesome.
She works with Chelsea handler now.
Yeah.
You know,
I'm fucking.
I'm always happy when someone figures
out a way to make it through the crazy
net that you know,
that like the salmon ladder or whatever
the fuck it is to get to the top.
You know,
I'm always fascinated.
we have like the people that I thought
were going to be fucking stars.
How have you been like Dane Cook?
You know,
I would have never guessed that Dane
Cook would have hit the way he hit.
No disrespect.
It's just.
I couldn't believe that he.
Dude,
you knew that he was going to get that
big.
I do it by one conversation we had after
the width of the lap.
Stop.
Really for the laugh factory.
I said to him,
what'd you think of the laptop when he
goes,
Bro,
it was good,
but it was too much fucking work.
I got to figure out how to narrow it
until one night and I knew right there.
I feel like that was a year before he
hit her to doing a whole month.
That was before the whole weekend.
Which is.
Yeah.
He was like,
that's just bullshit.
That's just garbage.
So you knew he was going to be that huge
though.
How could you have predicted that?
That's just had a feeling.
You just have.
All the arrows are pointing at him.
I didn't know he was the sell out
Madison Square Garden twice as dual.
Fuck that.
You know,
he's the first guy that ever figured out
how to really connect with people over
the Internet.
You know?
That guy is still to this day,
he's constantly answering emails,
constantly connecting with people.
Uses that say now thing gets on that.
That's on twitter.
There's twitter,
there's facebook for people to connect
with these guys.
That's why there's this podcast is a
fame.
I mean,
we started out this podcast,
Brian and I were just sitting in front
of a laptop with fucking snow falling.
Can remember we gave visual effects.
Let's try snowflakes.
Okay,
let's try rain.
Let's have a spinning apple.
It's amazing.
It's called black and red.
This economy,
what's going on right now?
You could do standup,
you know all the time,
but you need to open up different doors
for yourself and this is where this
comes in.
The podcast will definitely.
I mean,
you know,
where the podcast really comes in,
it comes in for everybody else.
It comes in for all these other people
that don't have people like us around
them.
You know,
it sounds arrogant,
but I mean there's a lot of people out
there that live in shitty neighborhoods
and they have dumb friends and they
don't have anybody to,
to,
to really connect with where they feel
like,
you know,
these people are also growing along with
them.
Like they're all growing
together.
It's a lot of people that don't have
that.
They just don't.
It's not available.
So this podcast gives them an
alternative way to look at things,
gives them a way to see how all of us in
our own lives are overcoming adversity
and dealing with situations and being
honest about ourselves and honest about
our friends and honest about life and
you know,
and that's inspires an ethic and that,
that inspires other people to be
likeminded.
And that's where it helps.
It helps everybody.
It doesn't just help like feel comedy
clubs and you know,
get people to buy your book or get
people to come see you in Rochester.
It also helps them,
you know,
this shit all helps.
Everybody will tell you what,
when I really got into this and when I
came on your podcast,
as you know,
people always ask what?
I'm going to come on your podcast for me
Bro.
I've always hated radio.
If you've noticed on the road,
I don't show up.
Yeah,
you don't get.
They don't like to do it.
I don't want to hear that shit.
Well,
it's awesome.
I don't want to hear about you
promoting.
You don't want to hear about you talking
and that's what the podcast avenue has
done for all of us.
That's why these people come here and do
well on your pocket.
It lets people come up here and want to
sell jokes.
The date,
I don't want to sell rock,
just myself.
The other place I came up here to open
up about what's on my mind today.
Well,
weekly.
I don't come here.
That's why I don't like doing this shit.
That's why they were doing radio.
So tell us why you don't like flying.
And I got to go into a job like comics
unleashed.
They'll fuck you.
So I want to be me dog.
I want to talk about the loan shot I
owed the.
That was going to beat you.
That's what this entails.
That's why I hate radio.
That's why I hate going down there with
these fucking fake MCS that try to be
fucked up.
Can you write down what we did was the
last time I came here and fucking a lead
and get the fuck out of my coming here.
It was from the heart and that's what a
podcast is and use it and your podcast
will is people come up and they try to
force the funding and the podcast don't
work and you know the fucking fun and
I'm the other end of it and the other
end of it,
I get emails and twitter messages and
facebook messages from some really
fucking cool people.
Interesting people and you,
you get,
you get something out of it when you
connect with them and we're all getting
something out of.
I was in San Diego of moon dog and the
nicest guy in San Diego,
art dot Com.
He drew a picture of Charles Bronson for
me was to me in the mail.
This is fucking beautiful with him,
with his hat and we've become friends
like he shows up to the gigs of San
Diego.
We smoked the bone.
Oh Gee.
Last night was a lot and it was just
great to connect with somebody.
I mean,
listen,
there's good and bad on par or whatever.
It was pure.
Either be cute,
dress on soldier,
but deep down inside,
especially with the podcast,
I've always tried to put myself in this
way,
so if you don't like people Mcginn
fucking faggots.
Don't listen to me,
don't talk to my fucking show.
This is what I did.
This is who I am now,
let's work it out.
I go fuck yourself.
And a lot of people liked the honesty
and they come up.
You know what,
if you come out,
I always talk to you.
I don't like smoking dope but everybody,
because next thing you know you're
writing your mind on the way home.
You smoke 80 joints body.
But I like meeting people.
This is part of this fucking business.
You know,
it's interesting.
The connection between human beings is
becoming,
you know,
it's becoming more and more expansive.
You know,
it's like,
you
know,
you have like a,
a network of people that you interact
with now and you could just develop a
really cool network and only be around
really cool people for the most part.
Like twitter.
Overwhelmingly,
I've kind of like 280 something thousand
people on there now.
Overwhelmingly Nice.
Overwhelmingly,
it's very rare that someone will say
something,
do should you be on twitter when they
do,
you just block them and it you just
click a link,
a pink block.
It's really simple and then you don't
have to deal with that guy anymore and
then you're nice to everybody and
they're nice to you and you try to
fucking know have a little exchange.
Every day.
People were sending me cool shit on
twitter every day,
some new fucking thing on the earthquake
or a new video of a tsunami or new crazy
monkey that they found in Liberia or
whatever.
You know what I mean?
It's like every day there's some new
fascinating shit.
It's a network unlike any other.
I've never.
There's never been a time where you had
so much access to interesting people and
information and ideas.
Never.
You know,
when we were kids and we liked the band,
there was none of this from the album
covers and the sleeve of an album.
We paid for the tickets or one interview
on television.
Nobody ever got this personal and is
down and dirty with people now know this
is why I do these things.
This is why I come up here with you
guys.
I do the podcast with.
They're not fake.
That's why people love you too.
I mean that's why fake comedy guide dog.
That's not my bag.
Oh Shit.
We're up here talking about what's in my
heart and what's in my.
By the way,
I was thinking of you guys today.
Not in a sexual way.
I had a ticket that because I got home
late last night.
I went through the why this morning I
got home like I take it that when I was
better I got like a Roddick and I want
to go back with that.
So I backed out but it was on my bed so
I couldn't come because if my wife would
go like,
hey,
on my side of the bed.
So I'm like,
what am I going to wipe the sweat?
So I had a soccer.
I wanted to like pigeon pose and I took
the sock off and just because I always
hold the top of the egg roll.
It doesn't slow me too.
He thinks that's crazy.
He never heard that one of the pigeon
pose.
I hope you hold the top of the turtle
neck so it doesn't blow up like a
volcano.
Right.
And I just came into the sock but then
it was fucked up.
I took the sock on the floor and I woke
up.
I went to put it on a bucket shot would
shit big.
Both these a sock would come in and
they'll sit there and go,
Huh.
So you pinch it to like at the top and
keep it like a little pig.
Something like a Kiddie pool size?
No,
it blow you're uncircumcised bolt,
right?
Let's not just loads up and I just go
and it's like your spider man.
He didn't know he was.
He's just been talking about being
uncircumcised and trying to figure out.
And it's like,
spoiler.
No spoiler alert.
Disgusting People.
Why do you.
Have you ever thought about maybe
getting it now?
Synthesize?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's what I want to do it now.
Thinking about getting my dick cut 50
Brian actually at this point,
who gives a fuck?
It's supposed to feel better and then
you have the skin over it.
If I can feel great,
if I had a boy bro,
I would absolutely not have them cut.
Have you them six girls.
Most girls think it's disgusting.
What the fuck them.
Tough Shit.
Crazy bitches.
They're all crazy bitches.
You're better off without them.
What might pick a swollen?
Listen,
they're not going to see my dick when
it's dead.
They're going to see it in full effect
and you just pulled the skin back and
all they see is down with anyway.
Can you like tie it in and not or
anything but like
girl that used to fuck,
I forget her name,
but she used to hang out with one of the
girls at the comedy store and she was.
She was having a dilemma because she was
dating a guy at first for the first time
was uncircumcised and she didn't like
the way it felt in her mouth.
She was drinking and she was telling
everybody I just,
I really like them but just don't.
It feels like like skin and
it probably feels like those little
rubber things mended.
Those things that you try to hold,
but you can't hold it.
It's like a little rubber thing filled
with water.
It's like a toy in.
Nevermind.
No.
You would have known what it was,
so you really would cut your Dick just
so girls would like it.
Like what if you were uncircumcised?
Just gross looking.
I think it's dirty.
I think it's pick one.
A condom on it.
That's exactly what your take is
cleaner.
It's not the fuck you talking about.
There's more.
You have more disease when you have so
much propaganda used.
Guilty motherfucking.
If you fuck a chicken and what it looks
like.
An elephant trunk.
That's what that song.
Evil Boys.
Yeah.
Eva Boys about.
They want to like.
There's a tradition when they come on
man,
they go and circumcise him with a
fucking rusty knife out in the woods.
That's why I was like,
you know my,
my Dick's only for penis.
Penis.
Brother is only for girls.
It's not for men know.
What's this?
Beaver boy,
he circumcised dee aunt word.
It's a.
it's a great fucking song put.
Please pull it up.
Pull it up.
No,
I don't want to hear that shit right
now.
Let's do.
I want to hear it.
It's good.
It's good goddamn song,
but it's about.
We're talking about traditions of
cutting people's skins off their dick.
It's ridiculous.
It's stupid.
Did you notice like throughout that
song,
there's a lot of references to south
park.
What cows?
Mom's a big fat bitch.
Is that what it is that who it is?
Cut.
It's Kyle's mom.
Mom's a big fat because that's what I'm.
Carmen would say.
Wow.
I didn't think of that.
I didn't even realize that.
I thought she was talking about someone
she knew.
That's what I thought too,
but it's a south park thing.
See,
look at that.
Kids growing up in South Africa,
getting some South Park influence.
Yeah.
It's weird.
That is funny though.
Yeah.
South Park.
Just to get the most reach ever.
There's never been a show like that
before.
It's been on for this many years.
It's still good.
Do you ever watch it,
Joey?
It's frustrating.
I'll watch it,
but I'm an adult.
We're like family guy.
I like family guy from time to time,
but that won't sit there and you like
family guy,
but you won't watch South Park to have
a.
Why am I mean?
It's not that like it.
It's that I watch it.
If I got 10 minutes.
Did you see team America?
No.
You did on Bro.
I wish I could do that.
Guys.
I wish we could do that.
Erase movies through your head so you
can rewatch it again.
Yeah.
Wow.
Interesting.
How
my mom died when I was 14.
I became a magnet for.
There was no fucking game stuff.
I don't even play.
I played monopoly two weeks ago.
We were talking to the guys pot all day
in place of his cat.
Listen to.
He's talking about he's a navy seal.
His mouth.
I crawl into the desert.
I've never played games playing fucking
cards.
Okay.
I don't have that time,
that luxury that you can play pool my
mom's bar and that was there.
That's how I babysat myself by playing
pool,
but I've never been a cartoon guy like
Popeye dog pain,
you know,
we grow up eventually and you know,
you move on,
it's cute ad,
but you got to go out.
It's a man's world.
Like James Brown said,
you know what I'm saying,
Doug?
And that's why I'm happy about going to
New York in the next four days.
I'm going to hang out with men for a
couple of fucking days.
You guys are going to die on the
twitters.
There ain't none of that shit.
I'm gonna go hang out with my buddies.
Like grew up with a couple of days to
different place over there.
You know,
you really realize that once you've
lived here for a few years and you know,
after a while you get comfortable with
wherever the fuck you are.
But there's a different thing over
there.
Just just as many Douche bags over here
as over there,
but they pretend to be nicer over here.
Listen Bro,
I got my people that I've known since I
was a fucking kid that was in trouble.
Those are the people I hang out with 40
years later.
I trust those people.
What do you think it is though,
about people over there where there's,
you know,
everybody always uses the cliche or
they're real.
People on the east coast are real.
What the.
What is that?
Is the weather.
The weather.
Make them do that.
Is it people are real or fake?
Fucking everywhere.
I got fake motherfucking friends here.
Sure.
I got motherfuckers will get stabbed for
me here too when I got back home.
Right.
But Dude,
don't you think the high percentage is
higher in New York of real people?
Because I do.
I think they're,
yeah.
I think there's more real people in the
east coast than there are here.
I think there's a lot of silly,
goofy Fox come out here from these
coasts.
There's a lot of that.
These are the creative artsy.
Yeah,
but I mean there's a lot of real people
here too.
I'm saying it's not like it's a
generalizations like it's not like it's
like one side is really in.
People always try to play that card.
East Coast is real.
West Coast is Craig now.
There's plenty of real people on the
west coast too,
but I think to Senate Manhattan,
there's tons of little cuts and men and
men of course.
It's just like the sunset bullshit.
Little young kids drinking water trick
of five hour energy.
Still dudes living in Jersey.
This.
I know what you're saying.
There's still ice think long island.
I think if you add it all up,
there's still more others on the suburbs
is a ton of shit.
I thought I grew up with my buddies.
I love my buddies.
They were there for me when I needed
them the most and they're still fucking
there.
You follow me on hold for five days to
smoke some dope.
I already fluent over there.
It's flown over there.
They got an ounce of earthquake and
announced the fucking moon rocks over
there and I'm taking a sour diesel and
man I got.
I got a sativa now at the fucking.
Oh,
an OCC.
They got a got a deer.
Sour diesel.
That's so fucking strong dog.
So I'm just going back to smoke dope.
Are you worried at all about all this
shit?
That's happening.
Are you worried at all?
But all these fucking people in the
Middle East are trying to overthrow
their government,
all these different countries at a fight
mile.
Where are we doing fucking 12 or is it
really of the world is not coming.
Two thousand 12 is this and all this
shit's going to go somewhere.
This radiation is going to leak.
Are these people going to fucking go?
What's this is all about adjustment.
What's our next fucking mood now I 2:12.
We might not be able to drink a water
ever again.
The something.
Something's got to work.
You know,
we might not be.
What's going to happen there?
We're going to have to all drink bottled
water and half of the ocean is
contaminated with oil.
Yeah.
You take your shower.
Japan should do it.
You should just have it.
Have a room
where you just get a couple of extra
bottles like arrowhead every week,
you know,
and just,
if,
if something really bad happens,
you gotta get the Fuck Outta here.
You know,
that's,
that's the reality.
The reality is California is massively
overpopulated and everyone is playing
musical chairs and everyone is hoping
that that fucking music doesn't stop on
their watch.
They're hoping that somehow or another
there are safely in the backyard,
not near any trees.
When the shit hits the fan,
you know,
just taking a guess.
Just hoping.
Well,
nothing's happened since [inaudible] 94.
Yeah,
but if you look over the course of human
history,
94 is a blink of an eye.
If you look over the course of the
history of the world,
it's not even that there's a lot of shit
that's going to happen to this place.
This did not,
was not shaped like this.
When you look out the window and you see
those mountains,
those didn't just.
They weren't like made with a mold.
Right?
That's the lava and the fucking ground
moving and the tectonic plates shifting
and you know there's a reason why it's
12,000
feet above sea level.
That shit rocketed over the course of
who knows how long the changes and we
know that the entire earth supposedly
had one content.
That's the whole pangea theory that
there was one content and they split up,
you know,
because of all sorts of different events
and became Africa and North America and
some shit's happening.
We just got through offer rotation a
little bit from that earthquake.
The fuck is that going to Japan?
They fit.
Yeah.
The shore moved eight feet by eight
feet.
There's a divide somewhere out there.
They said it's 270 miles long and 50
miles wide.
Where were the actual epicenter of the
earthquake was like what?
What happened was beyond our
comprehension and yet still nothing in
comparison to shit that's happened
before.
You know,
they still don't know what the fuck stop
the Ice Age.
The Ice Age was just 10,000
years ago,
which is nothing.
Ten thousand years ago,
most of North America was under a mile
high sheet of ice.
Wrap your fucking head around that.
Canada ice.
All the fucking North Dakota south.
That shit was a mile high of ice.
Woolly mammoths were running around
saber tooth tigers and shit.
It was a totally different world.
Just 10,000
years ago.
What that global warming because of
humans,
you know what,
what,
what caused that?
What caused that radical change in the
atmosphere?
They don't know what if it just keeps on
getting hotter and hotter and it turns
into a sun.
Like the sun was like the last earth.
That stupid.
They know more than that.
It's just like shit that you would say
when you were 14 before
you even went to any science classes
with the earth comes like a person who
says say,
stop polluting my water.
It doesn't take a fucking genius to tell
you that is either here or Seattle,
Oregon.
Yeah.
Fucking genius.
You know this whole,
this whole west coast,
all we could do is pray for Vancouver.
It could be vocal.
You bitches.
What iphone is?
You better make sure that shift hooks
up.
Leslie,
have you got an APP for your fucking
earthquake?
Right.
Great.
Absolutely.
Tell you where the earthquakes are.
Great maps.
It has no patient notification with half
and what it's going to be here like 10
minutes before Claudia.
Right?
Because that's the fucking app I need.
Well I need to get a dog.
You need to get a dog sit really close
to a fucking treach yet ultimately,
what can we do though?
What can we do?
Do we escape?
How do we live like,
like survivalists and moved to the
fucking mojave and,
and,
and you know,
by space and one of those underground
bunkers that you can,
you know,
you want to get probably go to the
middle of the country taxes Austin,
Texas.
Well,
what if that's where the fucking
asteroid hits one thing about Texas,
you know they're going to go down
swinging.
Yeah.
Down that the Mexicans were going down.
So I like Texas and I like Austin.
I would totally be down with taxes.
If they could just do something about
their fucking weed laws that we'd lost.
And yet we don't get this.
Trust me,
you don't get the same we'd,
I've friends in our days.
You do?
No,
you don't.
You can't get sativas Brown.
Not The shit.
It ain't easy bro.
It ain't easy and it's not the same
yield.
Like the reason why people grow sativas
is because there's a bunch of people
here are kind of sewers and that's what
they want and the people that have grown
at one,
but the people that are just looking to
make money,
it takes more time to grow sativas and
it does indiegogo.
They have to be grown indoors.
You can grow them outdoors here.
Yeah,
I know,
but there's weed snobs in Texas.
I'm sure there are easy to find and that
I get up at 7:30
in the morning and go buy a bag of dope.
One of the attorney and the construction
work to people.
That's the question.
Hey,
you know what?
As long as nobody else to find more
weed,
no,
I'm going to wait.
No,
you're wrong Brian,
because you got to deal with drug
dealers.
You got to deal with people that are
willing to go to jail because they're
selling weed and that's the reality of
the situation.
Ninety nine percent,
that's what we work on yet,
but it ain't as good as what we've got.
Now.
If you want to live in Texas,
you can live in Texas.
You could figure out a way to tell us
about where the fuck I lived in control
weed.
I'm telling you.
Do you hire some kid who's like a
fucking buy a big house and growth a
couple plants,
but you hire some kid is like a PA on a
set.
He'll listen buddy.
You wanna make a quick thousand bucks
and you give them $5,000
a week to take him to his body and you
put them on a greyhound bus.
I used to.
I mean I used to grow in my,
in my closet in Ohio and you know,
and it was great.
It was awesome.
We'd awesome.
See,
I've always been a real motherfucking
head since day one guys.
So the people I ran with were real heads
and we attract each other.
When I live in Colorado,
I some of the wildest fucking weed I got
gotten aspen to that high altitude in
boulder,
but the people I ran with our heads,
people who understand that concierge,
likeminded people will find.
Like when I find people,
I can tell when somebody's a
professional,
I can tell a fucking amateur and when
you run it through a professional pot
smoker just to look as good as a wink,
do a blind or they just give you that
look,
a real weed guy,
a pull you over like I did with that
dude.
I didn't know this motherfucker.
I didn't know,
but that's a nigger.
I fucking man.
I said to him,
you look how you look like this might
have looked at me like I was a fucking
genius.
He's like,
you know,
I left it on the dresser right there.
I went in my pocket.
Game of butter.
We a professor would say,
did you take this out of your boss?
Oh my God.
He's a professional.
I used to.
True.
You check it.
Believe it came out of your book.
No fractional pot smoker or looking at.
But in Ohio and go,
you're a bad motherfucker.
Guns.
We don't think.
Joey,
I don't think I'm a professional plasma.
This is 30 years ago.
This is 30.
I got news for you.
If you pulled the bed out of your balls,
I've been like,
no,
you smoke weed for.
That was in my fucking deal.
That's a professional though.
I don't play that stupid nonsense
shared.
Imagine showing coming.
I could.
You really don't imagine joey coming up
to you and go,
whoa guys.
I got some weed in my bars.
I don't say that when you're in an
airport and you're waiting to go outside
and get some and you're a professional
you for fucking three hours and then
trust me bro.
A professional will never let you leave
the house without.
We've,
there's things professionals do dog that
they know.
You call it professor two in the
morning.
I can't sleep.
They'll say,
come over here and get high with you.
They will not answer the fucking phone
professionals or different to you.
Um,
to take days off.
Every once in a while,
like Sundays or Saturday,
I'll take it off.
Take the whole day off.
How do you feel when you saw her?
Like a fucking,
like,
I can't put.
I can't focus.
I'm walking around confused now.
I've got to be honest.
It's kind of Nice to take a couple of
days off.
Yeah.
It's Kinda Nice.
I take many days off in a row,
but I still like getting high at night,
like sometimes at night just to sizzle
it,
you know,
when I don't take off when I'm writing,
I don't write.
I write hi everybody got to ride high
because I ran my.
Every time I get goofy.
Well I don't.
I mean I do read high.
I mean I do write sober sometimes,
especially when I wake up in the
morning.
A lot of times I do revisions on things
and I like to review it for a bunch of
different states,
but when I write,
hi man,
it's like a symphony playing in my mind,
you know?
It's like there's music,
then music comes through these words and
there's lights and and fucking there's
dancing going on in my head when I'm
high.
There's a lot of shit happening when I'm
sober.
I'm like slowly piecing it together.
It's like the difference between typing
with your fingers when you don't know
how to type.
When you're just using your index finger
and you're going t age a,
W,
n when you can type,
when you don't even have to look,
you know,
like right now I can type.
I don't have to look at the keys.
I know how to type,
especially if I get loose and get
relaxed.
Is that much of a difference?
It's like good flows.
It's like it connects you to whatever
the fuck it is,
whatever we're.
Whatever it is that makes you creative,
it connects you to it.
Blanket.
I like to be stone when I write the one
man,
Charlotte,
to be a little district side.
Really?
Are you still writing the.
You did that a bunch?
No,
this is completely.
This is the real deal.
This is from the time I came from Cuba
to me.
Finally,
and this is a new one that you're doing.
I'm doing the workshop April 20th.
I got to Hollywood and I got a producer
to put some money up and do it like in
Hollywood.
Nice.
I'm going to really wrap the Houseman
April 20th.
It's a Thursday night.
And where's it at again?
It's,
it's a.
it's something to do that this theater
in Lankershim just for 40 people,
you know,
just to get the writing down and have
people make notes to say Joe.
Yeah.
Like this way,
like this,
you know.
Uh,
April 20th.
Is that what you said?
It's a Thursday night I think,
or 20 baby.
So Wednesday night.
So now for the 21st 21st.
Yeah,
Thursday night,
yeah.
Okay.
Well I'm going to go there that,
you know,
it's really weird when.
And that's what I do when I'm having a
hard time writing comedy.
I ranked a one man show and I get myself
in a different state.
Like it's,
it's the one man shows a little sad.
It's about my,
you know what I'm saying?
It's about what was going up as a kid.
So you try to find the humor in it and
sometimes it's pretty fucking cool.
Dude is another quake that just hit
Chile.
There you go.
Bitches number
Santiago and Santiago Chile weight
number.
I Dunno,
I dunno.
Can I just say yesterday that said that
some guy predicted a from some weather
thing,
but it was going to either be on the
16th or the 17th,
it's going to be another earthquake.
So he was money.
He was fucking Melissa's.
Another earthquake was definitely gonna
Happen on the 16th.
Today is the motherfucking 16th.
This fucking this thing in Japan with
this nuclear reactor is freaking me out,
you know,
and we're,
here's what's freaking me out that they
didn't know what to do.
If the power went off,
they had like eight hours of backup and
then they,
the.
It starts a meltdown because they can't
call the rods,
so they're pumping ocean water onto the
rod to try to cool them off.
I can't believe that this is.
This is how they design these things
that you're living in a place where
earthquakes happen all the time.
Now if an earthquake happens and the
power goes out and if something goes
wrong,
you can't.
You don't have a way to cool this
fucking thing in the ocean water work
though.
No,
not really.
I mean it's doing okay.
It's keeping it,
keeping it from fucking exploding and
blowing a hole through the earth.
What they're doing right now is real
dangerous because all this shit is going
to get into the atmosphere.
All this radiation,
they can't really contain.
I mean,
unless they're gonna,
figure out a way to drop some sort of a
gigantic dome over the whole area and
seal it off.
You know,
a giant led dome.
How the fuck are they going to stop this
radiation from getting out into the
atmosphere?
Worst thing that.
What's the worst case scenario you're
looking at?
And another dude they're talking about,
see they tried to downplay it at first
saying that it's going to be fine,
but now there's on CNN,
there's a new official report and this
guy says that spent fuel rods are
exposed,
is heightened concerns,
so spent fuel rods and unifor of Japan's
stricken food.
Fukushima nuclear power plant have been
exposed,
resulting in the emission of extremely
high levels of radiation.
The head of the wild,
the nuclear regulatory commission set on
Wednesday,
this is the fucking dangerous shit man.
And what's scary is we have these things
all over the place.
There's like 150 of these in this
country.
You know,
maybe it will morph,
like get into the human.
I don't know.
Like do you see the map of the
radiation?
Like it's going to hit California.
I don't know if that was legit,
legit going to hit California saying,
oh,
well how do you know our ways?
Does that map real?
Really?
I Dunno.
I Dunno how it carries now.
What direction is like,
you know,
what's sad about Japan that they have
that,
that place called Oakland our where it's
beautiful.
It's the place in the earth where the
people lived the longest will inflate
their 100 and something that they.
That's where that coral calcium fad came
from.
Rent.
They don't take it.
They don't know if it's the fish.
Don't know if it's the island.
You know,
it just kills me that that's the end of
that fucking party.
That's it.
That's all going to be contaminated.
The radiation's gonna Make A.
Yeah.
What is gonna Happen?
I mean,
see,
that's the crazy thing about nuclear
powers.
Like,
yeah,
it works great,
you know,
and it's better than coal because coal
totally fucks up the atmosphere and
creates greenhouse gases and all that
shit.
But man,
when nuclear goes bad it goes bad.
I mean this is the idea behind is so
crazy.
You know what nuclear powers,
I mean,
you're harnessing the very power that
like the very thing that makes sons,
the very power of the sons is it's all
atomic.
There's,
that's you're dealing with shit that we
don't totally have control over yet.
We have control over for periods of
time,
but the bottom line about nuclear power
is no matter what you do,
you've got nuclear waste and you've got
nuclear waste that's going to be around
for you.
GotTa.
Figure out a place to put it.
You know what I mean?
That's what they do in,
in Nevada,
like all these,
there's always like the disputes and
debates about where to put this shit.
That's one of the reasons why Nevada got
gambling or the Vata was allowed to have
casinos.
They let them blow bombs off in the
fucking desert.
Shit,
let's move.
Here's the thing,
men move to where when you get a bunch
of million people like we have an la,
20 million people will fuck man,
how are you going to power everything?
You had a lot of refrigerators going on,
man.
You got a lot of gas machines pumping
gas.
You get a lot of trucks that have to
drop off that cash.
You had a lot of shit happening,
man.
Do people start leaving here?
If something bad does happen,
oh my God,
it's impossible bro.
We would all have to just walk out of
here.
It would take days of bumper to bumper
traffic to clear out la days and days
and no work.
No one to be able to go far but all get
stuck in the desert and cars will be
broken down.
People would be screaming,
let me in your car and your car can be
some Zombie Shit Bro.
It would be some Zombie Shit.
Shit.
It's really possible,
man.
It's really possible.
Our society's incredibly fragile and
we're starting to see it.
It's like this seems like a weird thing
that's happening because like everyday
things you see,
keep getting weirder and weirder.
It really does seem like we're in a
movie now like this Charlie Sheen thing
happens and even the Kim Kardashian
thing and it all seemed so surreal.
And then as all this is going on,
earthquake in Chile,
earthquake in New Zealand,
floods in Australia and it's just
constantly happening.
A million people dying with the fish
die.
Whether was was this piss test that
that's that.
The Algal Silva fuck that earthquake and
Chili's.
I have five point three that's bolted.
Earthquake.
It's still an earthquake every day.
I'm a map.
It's a five point three eight and I'm
scared.
So Joey Diaz is going to be in New York
this weekend for no bullshit,
but we'll say there's a big difference.
Tumbled.
Tell him what you were saying the there,
but northridge that the five point four.
What's the tipping point for every
point?
Is 100 percent stronger than the
proceeding point?
So five point one is 100 percent
stronger than a five point zero.
That is crazy.
Now the crazy one is the one in Alaska
apparently that happened in the sixties.
I think it was.
I think it was 65.
It was a nine point two,
nine point one.
One hundred percent stronger than the
one in Japan and it was 100 percent
stronger than that.
Wow.
Nine point two for four fucking minutes.
That shit rock.
Apparently you could.
You could feel it in San Francisco.
That's if,
if right now would have to happen in
Japan.
If you hold today at a five point three
earthquake,
you think it's the end?
Just when you think to like,
fuck it.
I just get to my hands and knees and say
a prayer.
I get the fuck out of my house.
I run right people.
Chili.
What they were thinking.
Five point.
This is the beginning of the year again.
They just got here a year and a half
ago.
Not even.
And you know guys.
The reality is that this is not the big
concern.
This is one small minor thing that you
can avoid by not living on a fault line.
The real concern is super volcanoes and
asteroids.
Those are the real concerns because
there's hundreds of thousands of rocks
out there in space that can fuck up
everything and they're flying around and
every now and then they collide with one
another and one of them gets hurled
towards earth and it slams in and that's
a wrap.
That's a wrap for this life.
That's a wrap for this generation.
That's a wrap for this developmental
cycle of,
of biological matter.
It's all going to have to regroup.
You're going to have nothing but rats.
Rats will survive.
A few mice and rats are going to be
picking off decaying flesh and surviving
on cannibalism until they slowly evolved
over billions and billions of years and
that's why you want to live in New York
or Washington dc or la because they
asked to.
Right.
If that really hit one of those places,
that would be too cheesy,
you know,
cheesy because that's what you would
expect that you would expect it to do.
That one even one that liked the one in
Nevada where you can go visit that
crater.
That crater was,
you know that.
That wasn't that long ago.
That was,
you know,
I think it was like $100,000
or 80,000
years ago when that fucking thing
Hitman,
it probably killed everything was in
miles and miles,
you know,
it's a half a mile long.
The crater I think are a mile.
Maybe what?
Whatever the fuck it is.
I mean that thing must have killed so
many fucking people are so many things.
Whatever was near it.
And when you think about something like
that,
landing right in the middle of La,
like right in the middle of downtown,
that's crazy.
Fuck.
Just a half a mile wide crater,
right?
We're downtown.
La used to be.
Nothing's there.
Boom.
Just a bowl,
a bowl and everything out.
We're all dead.
We're dead right out here for sure.
We're dead 30 miles away,
whatever it is,
hundreds of miles away.
You're probably dead people on Pasadena
dead.
People out in Pittsfield dead,
dead,
dead.
You're dead.
You're too far away.
I mean,
you can't get too far away.
I mean you probably,
even San Francisco people would be dead.
Four hundred miles.
I'd probably be dead and this happens
all the time.
It happens all the time.
The saddest thing was yesterday,
my wife said to me,
Joe,
something happened.
It would take me three hours to go from
work.
Wow.
Fourteen miles.
It's true.
Take you forever.
For her to say that to me.
I was like,
she had to think about shit like that.
Are you thinking too hard to bring a
pair of roller?
And the problem is three hours.
If she gets off work at six,
then you're dealing with creepy shit at
night.
You know,
you're walking home at night and who
knows what the fuck is happening by the
time these three hours are up or total
chaos has said.
And I asked him,
what would you do?
Would you walk on?
And she goes,
I would just stay right on the fucking
highway or something.
I don't know.
These concerns didn't even enter into
people's heads just weeks ago to just
this fucking earthquake just weeks ago,
weeks ago.
People were like,
immune to it all,
you know.
Now it's like slowly letting us know
it's on its way.
Stupid.
Yeah.
It was uh,
it was in a whatever that magic club,
the other,
you know,
wherever it comes in my.
Yeah,
and just go into her Mosa was kind of
like,
kind of weird because he would just,
I just got done watching all this Japan
shit and then being by the ocean just
kinda like,
yeah,
that's the stuff people died in
California,
Bro.
People who died in the tsunami,
they get sucked into the water.
There's a bunch.
There was a photographer that was taking
pictures in front of a crowd of people
and you just got sucked in northern
California,
sucked right off the beach,
man.
Wow.
It fucked up and they just stare off
screaming for him.
This guy's just drowned sea.
They pull it out,
you know?
I mean when,
when that tide comes in,
you know,
I mean,
you just see some of those waves.
It's been incredible.
The deal.
A lot of damage.
And Marina del Rey read a lot of damage
in docs.
Yeah,
I mean the tide went really high.
Fidelity it,
especially in northern California.
Apparently that's where it really hit.
But this support fuck was taking
pictures in front of a bunch of people
last week,
supposedly.
Good for the earthquake.
A bunch of fish would redondo.
I read something to still stinks over
there,
man.
Still stakes.
They said that May.
Most of stock,
man.
Most of stuck.
Really?
Yeah.
Fish apocalypse man.
It's not like worms smelling like really
old dead ship because there was a
million dead fish.
Do you think it had something to do with
your grade?
I don't know what the fuck it had to do
with.
Well,
they said that they died because of the
lack of oxygen and then they said that
there's some sort of a toxin in the
water.
So they.
They were poisoned by something so they
don't know exactly.
They don't get the full results of what
happened.
But what's really spooky is the same
thing is happening in Mexico in
Acapulco.
There's photos of all these fish that
are on the surface of the water.
It's the same type of fish,
so sardines and some macro and there's
millions of them and they're on the
surface of the fucking water and they
can't figure out why.
But people are driving up and boats and
they're scooping up these fishing
buckets and the fish can't go anywhere.
They're literally stuck the surface of
the water like it.
They don't know what they're trying to
do if there's no oxygen to trying to
like snap at the air to get oxygen into
their body.
Somehow no one knows exactly why they're
at the surface of the water.
It's a total mystery,
but people are just scooping them up in
buckets.
So this is basically sort of similar to
what happened in Redondo.
Something is happening to giant schools
of fish and they don't know why.
And they're thinking that,
you know,
in Redondo,
like I said,
they think some,
some sort of a poison,
but they don't have any idea why or what
or probably some kind of weird terrorist
act she imagined it was some crazy
Christian motherfucker.
One of these May 21st assholes,
all employees in the water just to get
their attention by some retard held,
chilled them.
The Lord is very mysterious,
crazy assholes.
This,
these billboards all over town are so
nuts.
Have you seen these,
Joey,
that God has come and May 21st you
mother wife,
May 21st.
I can't figure out why May 21st knows
the idea behind that is so ridiculous.
The idea behind the first of all that
you could predict the fucking day,
you know,
come on and then the days in,
what is it in the Bible?
Is that where you getting this day from?
I've never heard that before.
And not only that,
even if it wasn't the Bible,
the Bible is a translation of ancient
Hebrew,
which nobody really,
totally understands ancient Hebrew.
To this day they don't know all the
words and the letters double his
numbers.
You know,
like the,
there's no numbers in Hebrew.
So the letter a is also the number one.
So when you translate that Shit,
the Latin and you translate it to the
Greek and then to English,
who knows what the fuck it really said
in the first part,
you're not going to get made 21st out of
it.
Dude.
You know?
And even if it did,
you really think they were right.
I mean you really believe it all is.
It,
no.
Is it a religious thing at all or is it
a vision?
I mean,
he's just going to be a crackpot,
but this motherfucker's buying
billboards everywhere.
You know?
He's buying billboards everywhere and
got financing.
Yeah.
I get this money.
There's a lot of money and retards do
retards were everywhere and they want to
believe.
I mean,
look,
we're friends with Alex.
all right.
Alex Jones is a nice guy.
I like Alex a lot,
but there's a lot of people that follow
Alex that might as well be following
this guy.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean they just,
they just pick,
pick something to get obsessed with,
whether it's a the Mayan calendar in
2012 or it's fucking the Jesus
apocalypse more.
Whether it's Ufo shows.
It's all the same mentality to get these
motherfuckers obsessed with these
things.
But what got you off the Mayan County?
Well,
it was never on it.
I'm not attached or married.
I try not to be at least to almost
everything that I think everything that
I believe about everything I,
I,
I'm open to re-interpretation at all
times.
And the thing about the Mayan calendar
is I think with the mind mines did,
and I got this mostly from going to
teach an Eatsa and talking to this guy
was a professor who was our guide who
was really an interesting guy and we
talked to this guy for hours.
He gave us a tour for like five hours.
And he was like,
he loved.
Yeah.
And He loved the fact that I knew so
much about about the mind civilization.
So he was an individual guy,
like you hire him,
you know,
for the,
for the tour.
So he was like really into it because
the guy loved the culture man.
He was really obsessed with it and
obsessed with the fact that there's this
incredible society that basically just
vanished.
I mean these guys created some
incredible works of,
of,
of architecture,
these incredible designs,
incredibly intricate calendars and
really psychedelic languages of images
and shit like that.
I mean they're,
they're the way they,
they formed sentences and thought it was
very fascinating stuff.
And then on top of that there was all
this evidence of a massive deterioration
of their society.
Like it's human sacrifice and you know,
and that kind of shit.
Like what all,
what caused all this man,
it's all fucking fascinating thing.
But I was never,
I never believed that they had it wired,
that they knew that December 20,
first 2012,
the end of the cycle,
they don't even think that it's the end
of the world.
And knowing the Mayan calendar calendars
that say the world ends December 21st,
what it is is the end of the long count
and it's just another sequence of
events.
It's like,
it shows in a news cycle what that
means.
Who knows?
It could be a new consciousness,
it could be a,
uh,
an astrological or an astronomical cycle
where you know,
something in the cosmos aligns in a
different way.
I mean,
we know when the moon is closer to us or
they're moving further away,
it reacts to changes the tides.
It does things,
you know,
if there's some other astronomical body,
that cosmic body that when it lines up
with us,
it's gravity affects us in a certain
way.
And it changes some certain things about
people or some new understanding or new
appreciation or some new sort of a
natural disaster that makes us sort of
rethink the way we communicate with,
whether it's with cell towers or whether
it's with satellites,
the satellites get burned out.
So we have to figure out a way to
reinvent the whole idea of mass
communication.
But now that's all possible.
That could be the reasons why these
things,
while what's thought of that.
A new age is coming,
you know,
into the mayans predicted it because
they predicted there would be a new
atmosphere in earth.
There would be,
maybe it's,
you know,
something as simple as the polar ice cap
shift and it causes all sorts of fucking
havoc and chaos.
It could be solar storms,
it could easily be that man,
there's a lot of predicted solar storms
activity in 2012,
you know,
they think they could get unprecedented
levels of,
uh,
of,
of gamma bursts.
And they've had those before solar
storms,
like way,
way in the past where we didn't have
like all these satellites and shit.
You know,
there was,
I believe it was a fucking thing as the
19 fifties,
I think it was,
whether it was a giant solar storm like
on the one the highest one's ever
measured and they were saying that if
that's all restoring happened to us
today,
we literally would knock out
communication.
It would be fucked.
We would probably still have the
internet and a lot of areas,
but like a lot of our power grid would
be fucked.
A lot of our satellites would be fucked.
You know,
solar storms are really unpredictable
and when they happen,
man,
that really big ones really big ones
could toast this whole society and maybe
that's what happens in 2012 and maybe
nothing happens.
So fucking bullshit.
I mean the math,
David said that the math might even be
wrong.
It might even 60 days off.
You know,
we're going to have a good time,
bro.
We're going to be there in New York City
and then we're going to be in New Jersey
for the fucking championship over the
world.
Jonny bones,
Jones fights more resio shogun.
Who are.
This is the opportunity,
bro.
I'll see you in the city.
Yeah,
I'm staying in the city.
I'm going out there.
Yeah.
The last time I stayed in New York I got
tired of hearing sirens all throughout
the middle of the night.
All night there were sirens.
I was like,
okay,
I don't need to stay here.
I'll just drive here the next day.
So that's my new card.
Fuck yeah,
that was a favorite for that
motherfuckers.
Definitely.
Justin Bieber.
What are you talking about?
Just like Justin bieber derive favor the
same fucking person.
I think he thinks the motherfuckers once
every other week.
That's a great fight.
There's crumpled.
Great fights of his favor is a
fascinating dude.
I really liked talking to him,
man.
I did an interview with him and one of
the things he talked about is very
interesting.
He's a very inspirational guy,
you know,
he's like one of those dudes that gets
up in the morning and he has like a list
of like things that he has written on
the wall.
These are my goals.
I'm going to be world champion by the
end of 2011.
I'm going to meet the girl of my dreams,
have you know,
three kids and like he has all this shit
like on his wall.
I keys like the secret.
Yeah.
And when he's,
well he's big into setting goals and
working hard and accomplishing things.
Like he's Kinda a gang of different
things going on at once.
He owns like three different houses and
they,
all the fighters live in these houses.
They have on a block.
They all live together and they get
together and cook healthy meals and
hanging out together.
He imagined it accidentally robbing that
place.
Yeah.
And Talking Shit because the guy who
meets you at the door is only five foot
four.
Next thing you know,
you're flying through the air and landed
on your head.
Yeah.
This,
this is an awesome card man.
John Jones versus Shogun Hua is some
fascinating shit man.
Because Shogun is the oldest Acen and
Shogun used to be John Jones.
He was the 23 year old guy when he won
the middleweight Grand Prix.
Shogun was these young guy that was
fucking everybody up,
you know,
but he had a lot more competition and
had a lot of struggles,
you know,
he had heard Cheerio Nogueira that was a
struggle,
you know,
he had some tough fights.
He fought,
you know,
if it had some,
some real good competition over there.
He had some battles,
you know,
and they also had some fucking
destructing winds to mass shogun go out
and fuck people up.
Like,
uh,
like when I'm a rampage was injured when
they,
when they fought rampage came into the
fight with uh,
with a hurt rib.
Shouldn't never took the fight in the
first place.
Well,
I guess he just needed the money and
Shogun just fucking took it to them.
Man.
Shogun is up fucking killer.
Everybody doesn't have to.
Yeah.
Shoguns a killer.
He's a killer and he's been around a
long time and he's not going to get
rattled.
And you know,
and I'm not saying that Jon Jones is
because I think Jon Jones is the fucking
truth.
I think he's the real deal dude.
And I think he's a super athlete.
I think there's certain dudes that just
can do things that you can't do,
you know,
and physically you know,
and when you combine it with
intelligence,
which he has and work ethic,
which he has all the,
doing all the right things,
treating people the right way.
Good Karma.
I mean,
yeah,
he says some things sometimes and I'm
sure he'll regret,
but he's 23 years old,
you know,
it's hard to not be confident.
Fear of a black planet discussed this
already.
You said this a long time ago.
They may be super slaves.
They thought they were going to get the
bags,
bang out of your buck.
That's super slave league is called yet
motherfuck NFL and now they're taking
everything from us because they'll be
taking.
Look at film Mr Davis.
I didn't know he was fighting.
I told him,
you know Garrett,
Mr.
Yeah,
he's fighting.
Oh yeah.
They're both Antonio.
Antonio Hijirida and attorney Rodrigo.
But a Tara.
Tara,
the heavyweight guy.
And Rodrigo,
excuse me.
Yeah,
her Jericho is the light heavyweight
guy.
So who was fighting the light?
Heavyweight.
Okay.
So he's got.
He's still a bad motherfucker that guys
submitted Dan Henderson,
you know,
he uh,
he beat over him,
I believe.
I'm pretty sure.
And Him and him and Ninja or him in
Shogun had a fucking war.
They had a killer.
Warren Pride.
Yeah man.
He's a,
he's a bad motherfucker.
He's getting real good.
Hands to Nigeria does.
That's a great fight.
But John Jones,
man,
what I said about John Johnson,
I always say this is when he throws
people around,
it doesn't look like like a normal
person doing it.
You know what I mean?
Like when you watch a normal strong dude
that just horse somebody around,
like Matt Hamill when Matt Hamill horses
somebody around,
he looks like here's this big ass tufts
strong motherfucker and he's going to
grab a hold unit is going to slam you on
your ass.
And it just looks like it's supposed to
be happening that way.
When John Jones does it,
it looks like some fucking insect,
some insect that can just pick up a log.
You know,
there's something about how easy he does
it.
It just doesn't look right.
It doesn't look fair.
You know what I'm saying,
like you watch like a beetle move or an
aunt move like a something like ants can
pick up some big ass shit and move it
around like it's nothing.
It doesn't even shift their balance.
That's what it looks like with John
Jones.
He's just like,
he's got like Arachnid power or
something.
He's fucking Spiderman.
He launches dudes.
You know like when,
when he gets that double over hooks and
throws guys through the air,
who the fuck is doing that?
Who the fuck is doing that?
A kick.
You know how some people catch your kick
off call and spun around with an l but
hope Stephan Bonner,
he also taught deaf and bond over the
fucking over his heels.
Head over his heels,
his heels up in the air.
Who the fuck does that to?
Stephan?
Bonner and Stephen Bar has been around
forever.
Forever.
Because to show you how tough Stephan
Bonner is.
By the way,
look,
Jon Jones stops everybody and then stop
bar.
You know he gave him a beating.
But Bonner's,
that guy's an assassin.
He's tough shit.
This is an interesting fight,
man.
Very interesting.
Mark Wahlberg,
shoguns killer,
Bro.
You know,
I wished Miller had a full training
camp.
You know,
it's a tough fight.
Nate Marquardt a beast,
you know,
in Miller's toughest fucking and those
Miller boys,
man,
they'll take a fight.
You can call them 20 minutes before the
fight starts and they'll,
they'll change their shoes.
That was that middle of training for a
fight.
Yeah.
Well he's always training.
Those guys are real.
They're real conscientious.
Miller.
And they know that you always have to be
ready because anything can happen.
I don't know.
It was great.
Mark was a fighter and he's great with
these guys,
but I don't know.
Now this motherfucker's got.
This is Dan.
This is to New Jersey Bitch.
Yeah.
Got To go with the Jersey.
It's like the,
it's like the cowboys go with the 49
Avila one.
What do you think about cro?
Cop fighting still.
Does that freak you out?
He's uh,
he's,
he's fighting.
Brendan Schaub the kid who lost two big
country in the ultimate fighter.
I think that Brendan sharp is improving
so bad mother fucker.
And I think,
uh,
I think that cro cop and just try to
finish up his contract.
I don't think so.
But why?
I mean,
when the guy keeps getting knocked out
like that,
I mean,
I wonder what.
I wonder if he needs money.
Do you think it needs money or you.
It's like an ego thing.
He's not willing to be,
you know,
I don't know,
man.
This is his last fight.
I don't know.
I hope I was hoping that he was going to
walk away after the Pat Barry fight.
That was a good fight.
You got a nice victory,
you know?
But then he fights frank Mir and gets
knocked down and it just doesn't look
right.
You know,
you know,
like seeing a,
a hero.
I would hope the fucking guy could pull
it back together.
He will look.
The people don't know that Alistair
overeem was stopped like nine times.
He got,
he got beat up by Bobby Hoffman.
He got stopped by.
I think he got no Verdugo,
finished them for doom,
submitted them.
A bunch of guys have stopped him though,
including being stopped in k one and
being stopped.
And kickboxing chocolate down stopped
him guys.
Guys beat him.
Oh,
a surge.
A curtain off.
Knocked him out.
He stopped him.
So easy to look at all those guys that
beat allister.
And now alister is a fucking destroyer.
Like he bounced back fully.
What he did is he started lifting
weights and doing crazy power lifting
and shit.
He got a lot stronger,
got super dedicated,
really dedicated his whole life and 100
percent to training.
And now he's like one of the most
dangerous and scary guys on the claimant
by July 18th.
So you can't say cro cop is done.
He never say he's done.
But man,
it hurts me to watch him lose,
you know,
it hurts me to watch him be a shadow of
who he was.
So excited about him coming over to the
UFC because I thought about the cro cop
that fought Nogueira and pride.
I thought about the cro cop that fought,
you know,
um,
uh,
over,
um,
which feed or his brother,
uh,
Alexander Elamela.
Namco.
He fuck that dude up high.
Kicked Him Igor.
He fucked him above chanting.
I kicked him.
He owed him.
He was just jack and everybody back
then,
dude,
his standup was fucking nasty,
but by the time he came over to the UFC
man,
it wasn't quite the same.
You know,
we didn't quite have the motivation that
he had back.
There was something that was missing.
It's almost like he achieved so much
over there that it was like you went on
a mad sprint.
Here's a good fucking fight on this
card,
man.
Jim Miller and Komal shallow roots whole
year.
That's a good.
That's a good fucking fight.
Jim Miller is a beast dude.
Especially after he submitted that kid.
I'm Charlie.
I'm fucking.
What is his name?
Oliveira Charles.
That,
that really good Jujitsu kid with the
good Moitai.
This small kid.
But Miller grabbed a hold of him,
got him in a fucking nasty leg lock.
Quick.
Really surprised that kid when he tapped
down,
you know,
and Miller's tap.
Duane Ludwig off his back.
He's a fucking dropped.
Ludwig too.
Before that.
Which is,
you know,
Ludwig's is sick.
Kickboxer says Komal shallow roots.
Dude's a bad motherfucker to really
tough strong dude.
This Iranian,
I believe he's Iranian and uh,
he's a wrestler,
he's got a wrestling base,
but like a powerful punch and he comes
forward.
So that's a good fucking scrap right
there.
We got Mike power were caught on Beta.
Fuck.
Yeah,
that's going to be real good to,
you know,
Mike Powell is really fucking turning
that around.
My piles.
Tricky is fuck.
He's tricky and he's got a real good
guard dude.
Ever.
We got to be careful about that guy when
he's on his back.
Man.
And Kurt.
Bella Green glace and t there's a lot of
good fights in this car.
Yeah,
it was a lot of fucking good fights and
this car's slugfest going to be great.
Yeah.
And uh,
what the fuck is that dude's name?
Barboza.
He's fighting to Edson Barboza.
That kid's a fucking beast.
That kid's a beast,
man.
He's fighting Anthony Anthony.
Andrew Cohen is a bad ass stryker from
the WEC.
One of those guys.
Last couple of fights,
but still it's fucking real dangerous
kid.
But this barboza is a fucking assassin.
He's a bad ass striker due to bad ass.
Try.
Well,
I think the car,
the paper view card is going to be an
hour early this week.
So in the east coast,
if it used to be on at 9:00,
it's now going to be on at 8:00.
It's going to start a day or it's going
to start out.
It's going to start instead of nine.
It's going to start it instead of
tenants.
Gonna start at nine.
Six,
okay.
Yeah.
Six here.
So,
um,
so that's the deal.
I get off the plane at 4:45.
I go to my hotel,
take a shower like a shoot right back
after the exam.
We're going to have some fucking fun
next weekend.
Uh,
I am in Portland.
No,
where am I?
Seattle.
At the Moore Theater.
Yeah.
And there's still a few tickets left,
but not much.
So that is a,
that's on Friday.
It's,
it'll probably sell out that day.
So if you want and don't snooze bitches
and then following week joey will be
with me at helium in Portland.
Joe,
he can go to Portland.
Oregon is.
If Oregon is still there,
will be there too.
Which is a scary,
scary fucking consideration.
So we'll see you there at the end of the
month.
And Joey this weekend or this Tuesday
will be at New York City and then
Thursday through Saturday at comedy club
in Webster.
Motherfucking New York.
Come on down.
Buffalo,
Syracuse,
Rochester.
And I'll see you fucking animals in New
York City at 9:00.
Ready to rock.
And this is what st one,
47 bleecker street.
One 47 bleecker street.
Okay.
So now is a Tuesday,
Tuesday the 22nd and then you're going
to be in Rochester that weekend.
The following weekend where you were in
Portland,
Oregon.
Bam.
Bitches,
bitches.
That's it.
And we'll see you guys next Tuesday.
We'll have another podcast.
I don't know who's going to be honest
because we're unorganized as fuck and
that's how we roll a please follow red
band because he's very,
very upset that he doesn't have very
many followers on twitter.
Listen to the new new podcast with
Jaden.
Jaden coal is awesome.
Your new podcast that we're saying,
you're telling me are the people that I
don't have time for at the time on
airplanes.
And you got damn podcast.
Listen to this girl with her.
Okay.
You go find them.
I'd probably want.
I bet.
I bet I won't be red band tonight
tonight.
Sounds comedy club sales kind of sold
out.
You coming in today?
No,
I'm leaving for Anaheim.
Come on dog.
I can never come on dog baby.
On the way back on the way back dog.
Come on.
Go on after me,
man.
We gotta we gotTa Goddamn party at that
place.
Thank you to the flashlight.
If you go to tag it,
the flashlight.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click the link for the fleshlight.
Put in the code name Rogan and you get
15 percent off.
A Red Band is on twitter.
Red,
b a n and Joey Diaz is mad flavor.
One word.
Mad Flavor.
Have you been with facebook?
Check yourself before you wreck
yourself.
Gas is bad for your health.