Boom,
yes,
boom.
With live.
What's up brother?
How are you man?
How are you?
Joe?
You got a little pocket hankie there,
but I'll tell you,
so I'll tell you why I wear a pocket
square please,
because if you don't wear a pocket
square,
you have the appearance that you've been
squeezed into a sports jacket or a suit
for conventional reasons that your mom
put you in there or off the church or
something.
We got to the office.
As soon as you put a pocket square in
there,
you own the jacket if your idea and not
someone else's idea.
Whoo
dude.
You're thinking several steps ahead.
I like it.
We'll get to get into this outage.
We we're going to get into this.
Well,
we were talking before the podcast about
these press junkets and about how you
entertain yourself by forcing yourself
to use a certain word.
Yeah,
the danger.
The.
The worst thing in the film business is
press junkets and as you were saying,
that rather ineffective and that's my
suspicion too.
They're not that also inefficient and
ineffective because you sit in the
chair,
someone comes in and they ask you a
question,
why,
how,
how good an actor is David Beckman is
isn't on independence or whatever it is,
and you answer it and some facile
fashion.
And on the full time you asked answer
that question,
your starting to Swat flies that aren't
there.
You're starting to go mad.
So what happens is you have to play
games with yourself so you get someone
on the side to throw different words
that you like valued in area and,
or Marissa militude.
And then that keeps you occupied because
you're thinking when someone asks me
about Beckman,
his underpants have somehow got a stick
in a verisimilitude and I'll tell you,
it's not easy.
And your answers become very creative.
Did they ask someone to be sincere and
asked the same questions over and over
and over again to them like they're half
people.
Keep filing in.
A new person comes in and as I us.
So tell us about this film and how did
this get started?
And so who,
whose idea was it?
So,
um,
I sort of film jumbled medics caliber in
about 1990 and uh,
I was an impressionable young man of 10
and it was the first light knights in
shining armor film I ever spoke to me.
I wasn't particularly interested in
Errol Flynn,
uh,
or any inclination that they did in the
fifties in the Shell Nhra.
But John Boorman's one was rather good.
He's very aggressive and no one spoke to
one another.
They will shout it at one another.
So it took some time before you realize
that's why it was so intense.
It's quite camp.
So it had this sort of weird
juxtaposition of being camp yet
simultaneously aggressive and you know,
they had a budget of $25 and the visual
effects and lots of very shiny 19th
century armor.
And it made a real impression on me
because it was,
it was a voice,
it was a creative voice.
So I made an impression on me and then
somewhere in the attic of my mind,
I relegate it until the point where I
had enough creative ideas in my
reservoir to bring it forward to make a
film.
And then someone gave me money and
warner brothers wanted to make it and
Yada Yada Yada.
And then it was the challenge,
I suppose,
of trying to take us to join into this
world,
the fantasy epic fantasy,
medieval he lord of the Rings,
Econ of a world,
and it's completely out of my
wheelhouse.
So I find the challenge provocative and
exciting as well.
That's a fascinating era or a genre,
you know,
the fascinating world of fantasy,
nights and swords and bows and arrows
and that,
that realm for whatever reason,
has been intoxicating to people for a
long time.
Yeah.
It's an archetype.
So you're interested in farm and you're
interested in nurses.
Um,
you're interested in the superheroes
obviously.
I mean,
arguably Arthur was the first superhero
because he's the guy that extracts the
sword.
And Gallup,
we can do all sorts of wondrous things.
And this myth is 1200 years old,
1400 years old.
And it's as relevant today as it was
then.
But because it's an archetype that
somehow kids the dress up as firemen,
policemen,
soldiers or nights.
So we,
it's almost like we relived it.
It's like an outfit that we wore 1200
years ago,
so you feel familiar in it.
Yeah.
It's just.
It's fascinating that one genre,
that one sort of archetype is just
locked into the site.
Give people.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's there,
isn't it?
The other thing about it,
which is quite fun,
is you can take these kind of mystical
rides into metaphor so you can symbolize
things with 300,
four elephants,
which you can't do in some version of a
realistic world.
So it becomes.
You have broad poetic license to take
liberties are using CGI in this movie.
A lot of it.
Yeah.
Wow.
What's that like?
I'm boring,
but creative is three years.
The bank,
this movie I'm used to making movies
that take three months to write,
three years,
three years.
Wow.
Three months to write from beginning to
end.
Southern lot snatch was three months,
six weeks to shoot,
two months to edit.
So it's was three months to do the whole
thing or to write it,
to write it and to shoot it.
The whole thing from the beginning to
the way getting to the end of six
months.
Oh Wow.
And then three months safer editing.
So you wrapped and packed in nine
months,
10 months.
So this is a totally different kind of
commitment as far as your and
yeah,
if I really knew what I was getting
into,
I would have asked for double bubble on
the salary because you saw,
I think it could be a year and a half is
not a three years.
Like when you play on a movie like this,
a big epic movie.
Do you have an actual schedule of when
you think it's going to begin and when
it's going to end or do you do,
but you know the terrain filmmaking has
changed exponentially.
Like everything with technology.
So what was pertinent last year is not
pertinent in this year.
So release dates are a real dog.
So we had a release date which was
projected a couple of years from when
you start the babies.
So get right is checkmate the movie
you're coming out in?
It was.
We were supposed to come out and exactly
a year ago,
but then what happens is if you're not a
branded movie,
you get elbowed off that day.
You know,
Star Wars or something will come along
and then you don't get to compete
without walls,
so you got to move because you can't
compete,
so you got a very crowded market with
lots of brands.
Now this isn't something that we used to
suffer because everyone was equal going
into the equation.
You give yourself the advantage of
having a movie star or something,
but that doesn't exist anymore.
What exists now is the brand is the big
brother,
so he comes muscling and bullies his way
into a weekend and that's why you can't
really get new films breaking through
because there was occupy those weekends
are already occupied,
so trying to break through is a real
real struggle.
We had to wait a year for a day and the
date that were coming out on one weekend
after guardians now got into be vast hit
and it's very dangerous being within the
parameters of a of a big movie.
That's a really interesting thing that
only movies have to go through these
days,
right?
I mean,
it's one of the rare things where people
are getting out and going to see
something that's been made together in a
group.
You know that you're,
you're watching media like it's not a
live performance.
It's something that's been created and
it's going to press play at 8:00
PM on Friday night and everybody's going
to go to see it and you got to get as
many of those people together as you
can.
It's one of the rare things like that.
Yeah,
and it's becoming more polarized so it
means more now,
so you're opening weekend.
Everything is about.
They know what you're going to make by
Thursday evening,
right?
You're coming.
You're supposed to be coming out on
Friday and everyone knows what you have
to make.
By Sunday night on a Thursday evening,
there's enough clever people out there
tapping into clever little boxes and
computer says that,
that the data,
and they're seldom wrong now.
That never used to be the case.
Used to come out and films will get
discovered.
You said platform,
you start small,
go big.
That sort of nonsense.
Now you just got to come out bold
swinging,
and if you don't come out ball swing and
people get very upset and they think
that this is a failure,
it hasn't lived up to expectations,
even if it's a creative success,
nobody likes it.
It's,
well,
you know,
there's a bit of that,
there's,
there is an accepted set,
uh,
movies,
good movies,
good movies find their own way,
usually in the end anyway,
but the financial aspect has become
polarized.
It's too significant of a component in
the equation because,
you know,
it's an art form,
right?
At the end of the day,
it's entertainment and an art form.
And somehow you want to unify,
reconcile that.
So because they're essentially
different,
reconcile those,
put it in a nice little package.
So you put it in a pill with a sweet
wrapper around it and then you got both
and then you should be happy.
You should have the substance and you
should have the flavor.
Um,
but then now the focus is all on the
flavor and not in the substance.
And that's result orientated.
So you movie comes out and they go,
what am I not slow down,
son?
What's the movie line?
The question first of all should be
what's the movie like rather than what
did it mean?
And it,
it's just,
it's become too competitive and to
comparative financially and I love a
dollar bill and I like things that
successful,
but it has to be secondary to what's
primary and primary is.
What's it like creatively?
Well,
a film like,
no,
not to shit on it,
but fast and furious.
All I heard about was how much money you
made.
That's all you hear.
It's like the big story,
the big fast and the furious opening box
office.
Hundreds of millions of dollars.
All you see is like,
it's going to make a billion dollars.
Why don't you give a fuck?
Why does anybody who's watching that
give a fuck?
You're not gonna get any of that money.
Why is it so appealing that this movie
is made a billion dollars?
Because it's comparative and it's
competitive and it's why two people in
the audience
because it's voyeuristic.
Voyeuristic.
Yeah.
So you can.
It's like spectator sport.
Who's the winner?
Right.
You don't really care about how they
won.
You just care about the fact that they
did when
or like a floyd mayweather.
You want to find out how much money he
made.
He made $200,000,000
at five.
Oo.
People get excited about it.
It's an extra element.
Yeah.
There is a sort of,
um,
for carious life that people can have
through sports stars,
celebrities and success if they feel
somehow related to or they went on the
opening weekend or they are invested in
that.
If it's successful,
then somehow proliferate.
I'm successful.
Yeah.
That gets weird,
right?
It does get weird.
Yeah.
It's the
business of movies is a very,
very strange business because you are a
creative business,
but you're also a business enterprise.
I mean you're,
you're a financial business and when
know when it's a guy like you,
like your movies have a certain flavor,
you know,
like you start off with lock stock and
two smoking barrels.
Like that movie has a flavor to it.
And then your other films,
like people want to go to see that kind
of flavor from your film.
Do you feel like pressure in that
regard,
like to live up to those expectations or
to conform to these ideas people have of
your movies?
Yes and no.
It depends what mood you catch me in,
right?
Um,
I like what I do and I'm going to do it
anyway.
I just liked it very much when people
pay me to do it and give me the money to
go do it.
So I don't mind the financial aspect of
it.
I don't mind films having to compete.
I what I'm,
what I'm after is a reconciliation and
as I say,
the primary components,
you'd be on the quality of the work.
That should be what's primary,
but I don't begrudge films being
successful.
I'd like them to be successful.
I liked the competitive element,
but sometimes when you're talking with
executives,
you realize my priorities are on the
wrong thing here in the end it is a
creative medium and that is what has to
be primary.
Do they get in the way of a guy like you
though?
Like I would imagine the guy like you,
they give you a certain amount of
leeway,
they give you all the leeway.
That's beautiful.
Yeah,
and I,
I,
my experience with studios will be very
positive and they tried to encourage
your hopefully what is your individual
idiosyncrasies?
They want you to put your imprint upon
the work and they've been nothing but
encouraging in that sense,
but you know,
people betray their agendas whilst
you're in light conversation or they
portray their priorities.
So you want to trust the man because
he's a man of substance and to a degree,
independence.
So he's not looking to me to find
himself through me.
So you're not asking me to tell you who
you are.
And that's the ongoing battle of live,
right?
Where will asking other people to tell
us who we are and independence from.
That is a man that can be trusted.
I don't want anything from you and
thereby I can be kind to you because I
don't need to manipulate you.
You're no longer a crutch,
right?
So it's got to be very difficult when
you're in business.
When someone like that,
especially like an executive,
some slick character in a fine suit to
find out exactly what is real motives
really are than never in find suits.
Never,
never.
They dress in appalling suits.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean business is never encourage.
Find suits.
The pocket squares,
occasionally you find the token pocket
square,
but you can tell their heart's not in
it.
The wife stuck it in there because she's
so someone on tv that Adam razzle dazzle
about them and they thought,
oh,
I quite fancy model man wearing them and
they stick it in.
The old man's bit embarrassed about it
and tries to squeeze out of the way.
Suits are a thing.
The death of the suit.
It was the death of the suit.
Was the attitude toward ongoing.
No,
no,
go.
Yeah,
we'll put a tie on and I don't want us
to cow.
That's how I feel,
but that's what's happened.
We've been brainwashed to not dress line
gentlemen,
but I see a guy like you and I say
that's appealing.
Like look how you're dressed and you're
in a conservative suit.
This is a nice,
like I'm sure you could wear any suit
you wanted,
but you chose assert that has a certain
look to it.
Yeah.
I have spent some time asking around
with this Joe,
but a bit like that same reason that we
spent time asking around with they'll
pocket square.
It's.
I remember thinking how much I found the
suit repugnant and I became angry that
the suit had been robbed from us and so
I had to create an alibi away in to
understand why is that?
I'd like a suit.
This was the magic of Ralph and in the
magic of Ralph Lauren,
Nice Jewish boy from New York called
Lipschitz,
created a waspy empire is a wonderful
expression that,
you know,
think Yiddish,
dress British and Ralph Lauren created
this great empire and resold the waspy
world back to the waspy world.
Oh,
you actually not to the waspy world
because in England there was a sort of
resentment about savile row traditional
tailoring because it'd been robbed from
them.
The officers that come along,
the number crunchers that come along and
there was no creativity in the suit.
A suit needs to be creative.
The person that puts it on can't be
putting it on,
but because he's told to put it on,
he's got a one or put it on.
Uh Huh.
So what Ralph did is he fashioned up
there sort of cause I new England world
and salt.
He,
he took on a trope,
he took on a cliche and he refashioned
that cliche to give it a new sense of
life,
a new sense of breath.
He'd put black people in.
The suits were traditionally,
it was just a white man's suit.
He made it feel new.
We gave it a take.
So what he did is he tipped his hat,
the old world,
but also tipped his hat,
the new world.
And it allowed wasps to find their way
back into the world with an eloquent
narrative.
It was clever.
Um,
I'm getting fascinated by the way your
brain works because for you it's
important that the person wants to wear
the suit.
And I have a feeling that that's.
So that's symbolic of how you feel about
life itself.
Like the person has to want to be doing
what they're doing.
They have to want to wear that suit.
It has to be an authentic gesture.
Um,
did you ever read a book called extreme
ownership written by a couple of navy
seals?
That's Jocko Willink,
right?
No,
no.
That's.
I think it is.
Is it your job was booked?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But Jack on the show a bunch of times.
Important Book.
Why I've got them on once before.
What am I talking about a bunch of
times.
I've met him once,
but it's an important book.
Yes.
Now there's lots of books that I've
picked up on this theme,
but they were very eloquent about it.
If you don't own something,
you're not the boss.
You have to take full responsibility for
everything that you do.
Why be subservient?
You must be the master of your own
kingdom.
I feel you.
It makes a lot of sense.
You've got to own that.
You can't just walk into things with
your eyes half open.
You will walk into things with your eyes
fully open.
You got to know what you're getting
into.
You have to take possession of your
life.
Is this a thought process that you have
to constantly reaffirm or is this is
exactly that.
It's exactly that.
You drift on this point and it is
whatever form of meditation or Mantra
that you decided to espouse the needs to
be some period in your day where you
remember that there's a world out there
trying to tell you who you are and
there's a world in here that's trying to
tell you who you are.
Now,
where do you want to put your x?
Because the world outside is very noisy
and very tempting and as all the
Razzmatazz as all the tents and,
and all the glitter,
it's called the toys.
But that's because you don't think
you're enough in the first place.
Uh,
you don't think you're enough in the
first place.
The whole idea of the world to sell your
staff is first of all,
they have to make you feel bad about
yourself.
Less than in some way.
And I didn't resent this system by the
way.
It is the system,
but most of the expression about don't
hate,
don't hate the player,
hate the game.
Don't hate the game.
Love the game because you're in it,
mate,
so own the game except the rules and
move on into the rules so the world will
try and tell you who you are and you
have to tell yourself who you are and
there's this ongoing battle and somehow
that there needs to be a reconciliation
between the two,
but in the end you've got to have all
the eggs in your basket.
There's also an ongoing internal battle
though,
isn't there?
There's the you that you want people to
think you are and there's the you who
you are and trying to figure out like,
how do I,
how do I figure out who I am?
I am I do I have a correct assumption of
how the people are perceiving me and how
I actually am objectively or am I
bullshitting them world with this suit
and pocket square?
Yeah.
I would say that is exactly the scenario
that we're talking about.
The essentially one to two worlds is the
inner world of energy in this email to
weld of energy.
This,
those two identities,
ones,
real ones falls.
The external world is.
I'm asking you to tell me who I am.
That's what we're all playing at,
and as soon as you start playing that
game,
we run into all sorts of trouble,
call it ego,
call it whatever you want to call it,
but that's the dynamic that we're in and
somehow we have to
give ourselves enough confidence to
reassure ourselves that we are enough.
However,
I enter the game because I've got to
move on in the world.
It got crack on in the world and I know
there's loads temptations that come
along the way,
so I will own the suit.
I'm going to wear the suit.
I'm going to Wyoming.
The soup now don't mean by paying for
it.
I mean by owning it,
it's now mine suit.
It's my idea to put on this suit.
I have to personalize it in some way.
I have to understand a narrative that
allows me to own that suit and thereby I
put on my suit of armor and I come out
into the world and guess what?
I'm in a good time because I'm owning
the suit.
Now.
This is a very rock solid philosophy.
Is this something you've ever written
down?
It's what the essence of narrative.
I'm storyteller.
The essence of narrative is only about
this dynamic.
There is nothing else in a story other
than this dynamic,
so the struggle between other people's
perceptions and your own wants and
desires and who you truly are,
your your significant real self.
That's it.
That's all there is.
You tell me a story that didn't,
that we engaged in that famous.
That's not about this journey.
I'll give you an example.
The political son
parable,
Christian seems to religious doesn't
really make much sense.
You know this story?
Sure,
but why don't you lay it out?
So there's a father,
he has two sons and all of a sudden the
youngest son,
and he says to them who wants to spend
their inheritance?
The youngest has,
has made that dog and spend it,
and the younger son takes all the dough
and he runs off and sniff coke off
stripper's tits for a number of years
until he realizes this is getting pretty
boring and I'm in a lot of trouble.
He ends up feeding,
throwing food pics.
That's his job and he couldn't even eat
the food that he gives to the pics.
At which point he says,
Dad,
will you take me back?
That then goes to,
they don't meet.
This somehow happens.
Not through telephones.
It just happens at which point that goes
to the fatty carbs has killed the fatted
calf.
Older sons,
his own dad.
What's going on?
I've stayed with you since the
beginning.
I've been loyal to you and I hear the
stories of my younger brother coming
back who's been sniffing coke off
stripper's tits for the last God knows
how many years and you're prepared.
Kill the fatted calf.
What's the spa that I want another
story.
This is your son.
Don't worry about that.
You take a little side step,
little step to the side.
You'll always be with me.
You're a good boy.
At which point he goes out to meet the
product,
the wasteful son,
the waste some returns,
and he says,
you will also know you're found.
That's the end of the story is quite
hard to make sense of that.
In a literal sense.
You Go,
Oh,
dad was a bit unfair.
You should have been unkind to the
oldest son because he never ran off and
did anything,
but the essence of the story is that you
are the father.
You are enough.
Your oldest son is your intellect.
He says,
oh,
danger.
There's danger that is trying to
reconcile,
makes sense of a present and material
world.
The younger son being the wild feral
entity that is wants to go out and find
out what it's all about,
so when his recklessness and sense of
adventure,
he finds that he can't escape himself,
so we have to return to himself and at
which point he has to accept who he is,
which button the intellect is left out.
The equation pretty much is the older
brother because he can't understand the
significance of the journey of the
wasteful brother.
Any end,
you have to leave yourself to understand
the value of yourself.
You have to lose stuff before you
realize that all the stuff that you're
losing is a femoral and transitory.
It's not yours.
You are enough.
You are always enough,
but you've got to somehow prostitute
yourself before you realized you were in
value.
That is the essence of all stories.
That's deep guy.
Richie,
is that something you think about all
the time or is this.
I mean this is like a segmented
philosophy lip,
so king off stock you just made a man is
a king.
As a son,
the son,
the father is runs into a bit of aggro.
The son jumps into a little boat,
a little skillet,
and he's not scale it.
That's what you got your chops on,
isn't it?
A skiff.
Little skiff.
The skiff takes off down the river.
He gets found by prostitutes.
He's bought up in a brothel.
He understands the ways that the street,
he becomes a king on the street.
He works his way out that different
ladders and then he pulls a soul from a
stone at a certain point in his life,
certain point of evolution,
and then from there he goes on to be the
king as a bit of a tussle over along the
way,
lots of wrestling matches in the
endophyte,
his demons,
and he becomes the king.
So what's the significance of this
narrative?
That every man and himself is irs
socratic,
that he is his own king.
He takes the sojourn into the material
world,
has climb up all the different runs on
the ladder and ultimately has to return
to himself.
The significance of the extraction from
the sword,
from the stone is the stone is the
material world,
the material world,
which seems all solid because it
controls you whilst you're projecting
your sense of identity upon it.
The extraction of the stone is taking
back your own authority.
You're Rhone divinity around authority,
around identity,
whatever it is that you've got to call
it your own power.
You will no longer looking for a sense
of self outside of yourself and then you
have to face the demons that you've
created and your history by facing them
and fighting them and owning them.
You put them in the face of who you are
and that's a wrestling match.
You'd have to take away all these
crutches and that's all that we
struggled from in life is taken away,
are crutches.
Oh,
please tell me who I am.
please give me a bit more money so the
people think I'm clever or when they're
not.
Have a nice cut horn.
People think I'm clever.
You got to take away all these crutches
and stand as the man that you are and
you're liberated from your whole thing.
That is the story of King Arthur,
but it's not just the story of King
Arthur.
It's the story of all narrative.
Do you think that most people that are
watching the film,
we're going to get that though.
They're just going to get an
entertaining story.
They're just going to see a bunch of
cool stuff,
some drama play out,
but this is fascinating that you're
operating so many levels underneath it.
He bought him a storyteller on business,
so if I'm in the business of store,
I might as well understand story and do
you need to understand a lot?
I'm not sure if you do.
Depends where you on the ladder so you
can just go along.
I have a nice bit of entertainment,
good guy,
bad guy.
Everything is literal.
There's nothing wrong with literalism.
It is what it is.
It's the game you can glean what you can
glean when you're ready to glean what
you're ready to glean or you Joseph
Campbell Fan.
I am a Joseph Campbell Fan.
Yeah,
yeah.
That,
I mean,
that's a reoccurring theme in his work,
the hero's journey,
these underlying sort of narrative that
just really guides all,
all stories and all ancient tales and
that there's something inherently human
about them important about these stories
and they resonate with our wants and
needs and goals and even also maybe the
structure that we really truly need in
our own life.
Yeah.
I mean all the stories from whatever
period.
I'm sympathetic to this particular,
um,
to Joseph Campbell's philosophy on this,
but he's not the only one.
Right.
The weird thing about religion is
religion has done to this spiritual
significance of narrative.
Well,
the businessman did to the suit.
He's literalized it.
He didn't realize that putting on a suit
is putting on a suit.
Obama,
he's putting on something that's rather
spectacular.
It's just doing it for convention you're
doing for others.
You're not doing it for you.
And in all literal mind,
we look at a narrative and we see the
narrative for what we believe it to be,
the exterior aspect of the narrative.
So we completely,
we see the world upside down.
We don't.
We're not actually interested in the
essence of the narrative because we're
so busy pandering after the approval of
others.
So everything that we see,
every narrative that we listened to,
every film that you say,
you're not really interested in its
soul,
you're interested in it's body because
that's what we correspond to.
It's fascinating that you're comparing
it to suits because it resonates.
Like when you think of a guy showing up
for work or getting ready for work and
he doesn't want to go and he's putting
on the suit and it's just dredging
through it and putting it on and or you
think about a guy who was crisply
tucking in his collars and putting on
his cuff links and tightening up his tie
and he feels empowered by the whole
process of it.
It's very.
It's very appealing.
They're like,
have you seen in a film too?
It's very exciting.
This is a man of purpose.
They didn't mean streets,
I don't know.
You remember harvey cartel and getting
dressed to go up on a Friday,
getting dressed to go out Friday night
and it affected a whole generation of
people about the way they dress because
he,
it.
Yeah.
I never really thought about that until
this conversation because I just,
I don't really wear suits occasionally.
Very,
very occasionally.
But you'd been robbed.
I've been robbed.
You've been world.
There are so many aspects of life.
Food for a long time got robbed from us
and we've slowly managed to claw that
back.
It's true.
Um,
but clothes really.
You're a 45 year old geezer and you
still dressing like an 18 year old cast
is all about.
Well,
some people like to be comfortable
though.
I get that by the way.
And they liked that look.
Comfortable.
Your students comfortable.
It's comfortable.
You can get pulled into this completely
deconstructed on the inside maybe by a
chap called Brunello,
knows what he's doing.
So these are all handmade.
Um,
so it won't be handmade,
tailored a.
no,
I bought this off the shelf and I had a
couple of things tweet,
but it's as comfortable as a pair of
pajamas.
Really?
Yeah.
See again,
you have to broker a deal.
You can't put on things that are
uncomfortable because guess what happens
in the morning?
You're looking through your suit.
You'd go,
oh,
I like that one.
One with a comfortable one,
so they all have to be comfortable while
otherwise you don't get to play the
game.
Here.
I have a thing about ties though.
Go on,
I'd kill someone with a tie on for sure.
You can kill some 100 percent if I get
ahold of that.
Tie Your Dead Joe is conversation needs
to go on for longer.
Zip ties.
You're wearing a rope around your neck.
If someone just gets a deep grab.
Joe,
what are you thinking about?
Twist.
I'm not going to have a fight with
anyone,
but it's.
I mean you would have to in a deep
disagreement.
You'd have to wrestle that sucker loose
and take it off to be safe.
I'm not going to indulge this,
shouldn't you?
Should.
That's my own personal problem.
I just feel like someone with a tie on,
all you have to do is grab that thing
and that's a wrap.
Like if you went into a Jujitsu match
and you had a rope around your neck,
your Jujitsu practitioner,
right?
I am,
yeah.
So don't you've.
I'm sure you've been colored choke then.
Yeah.
Yup.
In Fun for 20 years.
Twenty years thing around your neck.
Like really by the way money game is.
I'm all about the gay.
I mean,
yeah,
I played a lot known gay,
but I've come back to the gay and the
reason I've come back to the gate is I
can quite tasty with the gay.
So tasty contests with a gay icon as a
couple moves.
I like to show it's a bit tricky on the,
on your with your t shirt,
but I'm all about strategy man with his
gay.
Um,
which somehow elegantly segues from the
tie.
I mean I'm all about creating what I
call the hangman's rope out of the
bottom of your gay.
Turning that into a thing.
So you're one of those guys that pull
the bottom of that canyon,
wraps up.
I'm that guy out there and I played this
game for a long time,
which is the wrapping around the wrist
or you know,
the,
at the eeg.
So you
get that little dinosaur flippy there,
so your arms out of action.
But then I discovered something,
Joe,
if you slipped back in through there.
So what he's doing for people just
listening,
he's talking like towards is on the
inside,
inside crack of his elbow and once it
comes in the inside
you can't get that hand out again.
That's it.
Basically the font server from the,
the fights over from there because from
then on you Umm,
the um.
Hm.
That's interesting.
We should have a little roller on it.
Yeah.
This job.
How long have you been trained?
In?
Twenty years.
What about 20 years from Enza.
Oh,
that's legit man.
That's seriously legit.
Do you think most people know that
you've managed to keep that on the dl?
A little bit?
Not so much.
Not so much,
no.
Well,
I think if you asked the average person
the street,
this Guy Ritchie a black belt in
Jujitsu,
they go,
no,
but just the average man in the street,
no black belt in Jujitsu is anyway.
I think they do now more than ever.
Yeah,
probably more now.
Well,
that's why when I see a guy that's
experienced as you were in a tie,
I go,
hmm.
Maybe just super confident about no one
being able to get to that time.
Joe was scaring off.
Well,
I'm a ridiculous person.
That's what's going on.
I mean,
you have your own ridiculous ideas about
owning suits.
I have my ideas.
Ideas about getting choked to death,
wearing a tie.
Like I said,
I'm not going to indulge your fishing.
I love fishing.
I'm honestly,
I do.
I really do have an issue with ties.
Okay.
But it looks wonderful on you.
Thank you very much.
I mean,
for real,
it's very elegant appearance,
the whole thing from the top to the
bottom.
When did you start training a under who
were like,
where were you?
Um,
first of all,
I did karate for 15 years.
I did shut a it,
which I was obsessed with.
Go second down in that.
And then acl went twice on the right leg
and I watched choke.
Can you remember chuck?
Sure.
And I want to choke.
And that was a,
it was a revelation because old man,
what was his mother?
Julio,
Elio,
Elio Element.
India was on the map it for in that
video I thought,
well,
I'm not getting any younger and if I'm
going to take up a martial art,
I love fighting.
So I'm very happy to talk about funding
for a long time.
I'm a fancy the idea that because if I
stayed with karate I realized I would
not be on the mat at 84.
So,
and back then there was no Jujitsu in
London.
That was judo and they had what was
called the Waza,
which is the ground game and they're
pretty tasty.
We got some good judo players.
Um,
so I went from crotty to judo,
but I was only interested in the ground
game.
And then Roger Gracie came to live in
the UK about 20 years ago.
And Roger Gracie went onto become the
world champion eight times and I started
taking lessons with him and his Dad
Maricio.
Then I ended up in New York for,
I think we lived.
I lived in New York for awhile.
My ex wife and I went to the Zos gym
when it was above the Methadone clinic
and I fell in love with pencil and I
fell in love with Jujitsu in a sort of
serious way.
And I became obsessed with it for a
number of years.
Hence I get me a lot belts.
Um,
I mean I should've got black belt 10.
Well,
I say I should've got a black belt.
I was,
I became lazy to a degree.
So I've got a black belt when I
should've got a black belt.
And as you and I know there's some tasty
blue belts out there,
can I have a lot of fun with me?
Um,
but I sort of drifted a bit.
I came in and out,
sustained a few injuries,
but if I was training hard,
you train hard,
you get black pound five years on you,
you got to be obsessed with kids.
Oh,
the kids are.
You can.
I mean,
I was a brown belt for eight years,
so he talked to them and I know that I'm
the same as you.
I was praying about for eight years.
I think it's a.
If you're a real fanatic,
you could get it in five years,
but it's super rare.
Like Bj Penn got it in three.
That's almost unheard of.
There's a few people that
done that.
Yeah.
There's some guys in our gym in London
in Roger's place that they're there five
days a week,
three hours a day.
They mean it and within six months
they're at proper pain in the ass.
Yeah.
Well,
once you become obsessed with the
movements and you start studying the
various positions and the possibilities,
it becomes a part of your life,
becomes a part of your.
Almost like your your operating system
and as you see these guys reinforce that
operating system,
you see their,
their game becoming more and more
complex and the beetle,
that chain attack after attack and being
able to anticipate the defenses of those
attacks and plan two and three steps
ahead and you see all this play out.
It's an uh,
may I,
I really,
really enjoy watching someone go from
being a beginning student to being a
killer.
It's a fascinating process because you
are literally watching someone develop
their comprehension of a language of
fighting and that language of fighting
is analogous to life.
It helps them in every single aspect of
their life because it's one of the most
difficult things that a person will do
in their day.
When you walk into a Jujitsu school,
you're,
you park your car,
you live in this normal realm of normal
people with normal problems and bills
and stresses and issues.
But once you go into that thing,
he put on that Gi or no gi or whatever
you're doing and you'd go into that
class.
Once you engage in these sparring
sessions,
he's sparring sessions with skilled
practitioners.
You're doing one of the most difficult
things.
Any person within a hundred mile radius
of you that's not fighting for their
life is doing,
and by doing that on a regular basis and
constantly reinforcing this language,
it enhances the all your possibilities
and your potential possibilities as a
person.
Very eloquent comment.
Couldn't,
couldn't agree with you more.
One of the great things I found about
Jujitsu is whenever I came to a city,
we just tap into a computer where the
next Jim was and we wrote down there.
I usually,
I'm usually with two or three people and
I've been out there.
He's also a black belt.
Um,
uh,
got a chaplet.
Uh,
I was with called bobby the tits,
who was an Olympic judo player.
I can usually say the chest on this
gaze.
At least that's why I'm so across
through and Ivan the terrible and bobby
the tits.
We used to hit these gyms and uh,
everyone,
there's a guest complete substructure
thereof.
If you want to be looked after,
they'll give you a gap fellow mate as it
going into the Brotherhood.
I suppose it's probably the same for
people.
Go to church,
I don't know,
but there is a brotherhood that I found
amongst fighters where everyone's like
game and friendly come around at the
barbecue and everyone's as whole sub
structure there that everyone will look
after everyone else and I've never in
the 20 years of fighting in different
gyms have I lost my temper or I had a
reason to lose my temper.
Is anyone ever been a bully?
If people a bit clumsy got bit carried
away,
but there's such a system of accountancy
that you can't get away with being a
bully because there's always a bigger
bullying and you know you're going to
get found out and I liked that aspect of
it.
Everyone gets found out.
Yeah.
Especially over time.
Right?
I mean if you're training consistently
with really difficult trading partners,
your characters going to be tested.
There's just nowhere.
There's nothing.
There's no way around it.
And sometimes I ended up training quite
a lot in at home.
Right?
I got five,
six mates to come around there.
It's not the same as going to a new gym
with new players.
Um,
and you've got to get out there.
I know a few rich guys that have got
trainers and they not bad players,
you know,
the train is good and the is a good,
but because they don't get outside of
their comfort zone and go to a federal
jim,
Jim on the street there that it's very
hard for them to really evolve.
Right?
You got to keep putting yourself in an
uncomfortable spot in uncomfortable gyms
and like,
as you said,
when you do that though,
you do see the kind of the same thing
over and over again.
The same type of human,
you know,
you just see them in London or you see
them in New York or Los Angeles.
You see that same type of human.
It's the great thing about a sport in
general,
but let's be specific because it's
something that you and I can relate to
is there are no barriers in Jujitsu.
No one's looking at you.
If you're poor,
you're black,
you're white.
It's completely irrelevant.
You come to the mat and if you get on
with the gays,
you fight,
you get on with the gaze that you
fighting.
Yeah,
and there's a complete clarity of vision
when you fighting so much,
just finding them and then you rate them
on their ability of how they fight.
Yeah,
and you carry that social hierarchy,
like what the wood.
What's important in that school is that
it is like who is proficient?
Who is very good that that's the best
currency.
The ultimate currency.
Yeah.
Right.
I had a name when I used to train out
here or in New York that they used to
call me Hollywood because I was young.
You said Liberty it person that you come
in and say,
oh,
well I only.
What'd you find that it roll around?
But that,
you know,
in a couple of people initially went,
oh yeah,
that gazer and that lasted all of 30
seconds and then everything gets washed.
Can you have no currency on the map
other than your currency on the mat?
And there's a wonderful clarity in that.
Yeah.
For a guy like you or any any big time
celebrity,
that's probably one of the only few
places where you really truly
experienced that,
like there's no bullshit in that role,
like in someone's going after you and
you're going after them.
It's 100 percent.
It is what it is.
There's,
there's all the.
The,
the bullshit veil of society has been
removed.
Yeah,
I mean on Monday the water a bit now.
So harking back to what we were talking
about previously,
I'm aware that you become less
adventurous as your ego grows in
Jujitsu.
Right?
Particularly with the guy that doesn't
tap tap.
You don't ever want to be the guy that
doesn't tap and you hung up when you
become a boring fighter and it's an
issue.
You know those guys.
There's a couple of guys that I can
think of.
One in particular that if you get the
better of him and by and large is better
than me,
but all of a sudden you realize is in
trouble just before I'm about to tap.
And he goes,
oh,
stop that.
Once I go.
If you just moved a little bit to the
instruction,
those guys,
that's their alibi to get out them
losing face,
so what phase is it they're losing is
the crutch that they actually think that
being a Jujitsu player has an identity
in itself and it doesn't.
You cannot use it as a crutch and that's
the essence of all martial arts.
Martial arts was about find yourself
within that framework and be honest
about it and you meet the opponent and
his condo will tell you you're finding
it's about you fighting you in the ring.
What your other part of the mind to the
other bottom on that we were talking
about once I say it's about your
reputation in the gym and what people
think of it.
Again,
you're trying to find an identity from
outside of yourself by not tapping and
you know that feeling and by the way I
suffered myself because I didn't like to
tap either,
but it.
It makes my game.
It inhibits my game and it stops me.
Being creative.
Marcella Garcia has always been very
adamant about that,
that you have to open up your game in
the gym and it's the only way to really
truly progress and don't worry about
being tapped and don't have that ego and
there's a great video of him and Damien
Maia Rolling and they're rolling.
They have like they're putting almost no
like kinetic strength,
no explosive energy,
nothing,
no,
nothing athletic.
They're just going through the movements
and exchanging positions and they're
tapping each other left and right and
left and right with no ego.
It's really interesting to watch because
you see like Marcello Catch Damien and
they brought to a position and Damien
taps and then they go through another
position and Marcello does it and it's
just.
It's really fascinating because when
they're doing they're truly flowing.
There's no like real,
oh here we go right there.
You can see them do it,
but like when these guys would do it,
like as they're doing it,
they're obviously using strength and
they're countering with skill,
but everything is very smooth
and controlled and you're looking at two
of the very best black belts to ever do
it.
You're looking at Damien Maia,
who right now is arguably the top
contender in the UFC welterweight
division.
He's going to be fighting Jorge Mas
Vidar next weekend actually,
which is a really intense fight because
monster killer and then Marcello Garcia,
who's probably one of the all time great
strangulation experts has ever walked
the face of the planet.
I mean,
he's really revolutionized a lot of
aspects of the good team,
the rear naked choke and I was in
Brazil,
in Sao Paulo in 2003 when he burst onto
the scene when he choked out.
Chao Lin.
And uh,
to see these two guys rolling together
is really,
really interesting because this is
really kind of how you have to do it.
You just do it.
You know,
there's,
there's no one is saying,
I can't tap,
I can't.
No,
I can't put myself in a bad position
there.
They're exchanging positions to like
right there.
When Damian gets under hooks and these
goes for the deep half,
Marcel was just rolling with it.
They're just flowing.
Yeah,
but you need two to tango.
You can't have one with an ego and who's
not going to play the game and bunkers
down and screws himself down.
It makes the whole thing very hard to
do.
It's got to be.
You both got to be complicit.
Yup.
Yeah,
absolutely.
it's very,
it's very interesting watching like to
really,
really high level guys like this role or
like you know,
hydro Gracie and Braulio a steamer or
something like that.
England's got a great scene and there's
so much top level Jujitsu over in
England right now.
It's go some good players.
Yeah.
He used to be a time just a couple of
decades ago where if you wanted to
train,
it was very difficult to find really
proficient instruction and groups
training part 20 years ago.
It wasn't possible.
I remember because I was first into it
when we made snatch,
which is 18 years ago,
and that's when,
how'd you first came to town?
And before then it was just you to just
in the Waza yeah.
Well,
I mean you can certainly get something
out of that,
but um,
it seems like the level of A.
I mean there's some people that have
just one rock solid attack,
like Rhonda Rousey at that rock solid
attack with the arm bar and she comes
from that judo background.
That's a Jambo.
Oh,
it's nasty.
Her arm bar to this day I believe is one
of the best arm bars I've ever seen in
mma.
Not just because,
uh,
she's successful with it.
But when you watch her transitions,
you watch how she's able to adjust and
change.
And like the cat Zingano fight is a
perfect example of that.
Cat Zingano just charges out or like a
fucking bat out of hell.
And they have this mad scramble and
Rhonda realizes a position that she's,
she doesn't even utilize,
but she's,
she understands armbar so well.
She knows what.
I could just throw my hip over this way
and kick back here and I'll catch that
arm bar.
This is just overall understanding of
the position is so high level.
Yeah.
When someone has a movement,
but I used to find a bit with a Hickson
and Hixon use that thing where he ties
his hands behind his back and you try
and do something to it and you can't do
anything to
the level of sophistication when it's
like that.
He's so.
He,
so technical hixon that it was.
Well,
what I understand about Jujitsu is
really rather primitive.
Um,
but I'm aware I'm primitive and I'm
aware that my understanding of Jujitsu
is really quite primitive.
And then when you see something like
that arm bar come sneaking out of
nowhere always said that.
It's a magnificent thing to behold,
isn't it?
Yeah.
The when and what you're saying is kind
of interesting because that was
listening to this and go,
how has a black belt primitive?
What do you not primitive?
You're an expert,
but I understand totally because I'm
also primitive.
I know,
I know what I know.
Like I understand like there's what,
what Hickson's languages is a series of
words that you've never heard before,
spoken perfectly in the right order with
no pauses or ums or no filler and the
way he flows with it,
it's just,
he's got a level of proficiency that
very few other than Marcello and Damien
Maia can really appreciate the,
the true beauty of it all because they
just don't like,
I won't,
I won't see things coming.
It will be there.
They're too complex as it's completely
different language.
Yeah.
But you know enough.
I'm already good lines on my,
the other day that someone had enough
brains to know that they didn't have any
brains.
Um,
so you know enough to know that you're
in treacherous in deep waters here.
Yeah.
Otherwise,
your average gazes styles,
styles running around with one of these
good guys.
Bad guys,
jovial guy.
There'll be the same.
They got the same color belt on it.
Let's have a go with that.
Yeah.
You just get manhandled now.
Um,
you said you had your knee fixed,
you a blue.
Would you blow out an acl acl?
Done it twice.
Yeah.
Did you get um,
cadaver replacement or no?
Hamstring.
And then Patella hamstrings,
patella second to task stream blew out,
right?
Yeah.
Those things blow out a lot.
Uh,
yeah.
Eventually gave in.
I had the first one that was about 21.
Okay.
And then the second one down was about
31 and it was held together,
but they own needs a bit knackered.
Do you know about stem?
So yeah.
How are you feeling about the great.
I was that close to shoulder surgery and
I had some placental stem cells shot
into my shoulder and it's amazing.
And where did you have that done?
Vegas.
Really?
Yeah.
There's a guy named Dr Rodney Mcgee was
at the tip of the spear when it comes to
the technology that's involved today,
what was the issue?
And to show the punch of tears,
just stuff,
just years and years of abuse at my
cartilage is gone on the shoulder now.
My college has gone on the knee and I
didn't really know anything about stem
cell about two weeks ago.
And now that's what I'm hearing about.
Oh,
well I have a podcast.
I'll send you and it was me and Dr
Rhonda Magee that we did about a month
ago.
Fabulous.
He's amazing and again he's.
He's well up to date with the latest
technology and he's also very
conservative in his approach to it,
but what he's saying is that they are
able to regenerate cartilage and
meniscus tissue and this is the first
time anything has ever come along that
actually regenerates these tissue.
They've been able to trim it and do
things to it to mitigate pain,
but now they can literally regenerate
tissue there.
Even injecting it into people's discs.
Now the discs in the spine and they're
showing that they can regrow disc tissue
yet,
but you've just nailed my three issues.
This issue and cartilage.
Yeah,
that's the only issue is of course
meniscus and cartilage and disk and what
have you got going on with your back is
the traditional issue with those three
c,
whatever the ankles at the bottom of the
bag.
I'm going to show you something else
that you're gonna need and you're going
to get after we have this conversation.
I have a machine out back called the
reverse hyper and it was created by this
mad genius named Louie Simmons and what
the reverse hypers and machine that
decompresses your back and also
strengthens at the same time.
It decompresses it on the downswing and
then on the upswing it,
it strengthens all those muscles around
it,
but it literally pulls the back apart
and the compressed discs,
which is bad posture,
load a generation.
You can look up at the screen.
This is,
this guy's fucking crazy.
He's one of the craziest people I've
ever interviewed who was hilarious,
but he's a old time power lifter has
been doing it forever.
I mean he's got fake shoulders,
fake knees.
Everything's blown out.
He has no biceps.
Biceps are completely severed off of his
arm.
He.
What was he saying like He.
He was,
he had his friends were making a Max out
bench like five days after his shoulder
replacement.
He's a fucking maniac,
but they were trying to fuse his discs
and so he came up with this machine and
you see as it swings down,
when she's swinging down,
it's pulling her back apart,
like go to the.
Here you go.
When it's going down,
it's pulling the back,
an active decompression and as she's
swinging up,
she's strengthening all those muscles in
the spine in a real weird way where you
really can't get at them.
And was it.
This is the efficient because you can do
the suit might superficially I'm
struggling there,
but the coal underneath the superficial
muscles to had the MRI.
You could see all the fat in the
surrounding muscle,
a muscle around the discs and you could
see the fat in it and then as soon as
you hit the superficial,
you went,
oh,
that's fun.
There's nothing wrong with the
superficial,
so it's a need away.
A lot this year.
Just buy one of those men were you have
to beast through.
You'll superficial muscles to get to
your colon muscles.
Well,
it's just it.
It forces that area of the body to work
like you're sustaining a load and you
can you lift it up and you hold it in
that position and then as you let it go,
it's,
it's decompressing and in the
decompressed cycle you,
you,
you're feeling your muscles relaxed and
you can actually feel it pulling like
you feel in the lower back in a weird
way.
You feel it kind of polling and
separating and then a couple of seconds
later you're and again,
and then you pull the and separated and
you're strengthened again,
and then I have another thing out back
that I bend over from the waist on and
it allows my lower back to just
completely relax and my upper body pulls
down on my lower body and it separates
and decompresses the lower spine.
I mean,
it's been tremendous.
A huge,
huge asset,
but there's a bunch of things they can
do.
Now.
If you heard a Regena cane,
do you know what that is?
No.
Regena.
Kina is something that was developed in
Germany that a lot of professional
athletes like coby Brian Mann and they
went over there and it's a blood
spinning procedures similar to platelet
rich plasma,
but they take the blood and as they're
spinning it,
they heated it up and when they heat it
up,
the blood has a reaction to the extreme
heat like it thinks you have a fever,
so it produces is very intense anti
inflammatory response.
Obviously if you're a scientist or a
doctor,
I'm butchering this,
but then they take this yellow serum
which is this an anti inflammatory
response and they can inject it into all
these areas that you have massive
inflammation like bulging discs and it
has incredible effect.
Had incredible effect for Peyton
Manning,
allowed them to get back to football
again.
I had a bulging disc that was making my
hands go numb.
Totally went away through decompression
and through this kind of stuff.
Yeah,
I heard this added 10 years to Kobe's
career.
Am I thinking?
Yeah,
that's what he thinks.
she didn't.
I didn't up until I'm 48,
[inaudible] 49,
almost 50.
Oh,
so I didn't think about any of these
things until this year,
so I accepted a acl,
has bit of a nuisance
except the garb of a creaky bank.
But in the last month I went to my,
something happened to my knee and I went
to the doctor a little a x ray and he
went,
well,
it cut up right for the 10th time I've
had an operation on that knee,
but you better off now waiting of
waiting for what to like if you knew
what a canal.
So he's talking about a replacement.
So you're talking about replacement now
he's saying just hold on.
Right?
So you're saying in 15 years from now or
whatever it is.
But it all changed.
And then a month after I went and had
the shoulder,
um,
x,
right.
And he looked at it and went,
well,
it could operate under,
knew where we would go in here.
You better apply until I give you a new
one.
Um,
now that Giza were
talking about fixing,
told you about giving me new ones right
now I hadn't.
So you know,
Ivan out there knows exactly what you're
talking about.
To me the word,
he wasn't a vessel to receive this
information.
Now in the last month I'm ready to
receive this information.
So in the next three months I will know
of what you talk about immediately.
I'm going to connect you with Dr Rodney
Mcgee.
As soon as we get off the phone or off
the podcast here,
I'm going to connect you with them and
he'll,
he'll be able to keep you abreast of all
the stuff.
And it changes constantly.
Like when I first went,
I first got a shot in July of last year
and I was that close to surgery.
I was trying to figure,
okay,
I was planning my time.
I was saying,
okay,
if I get the surgery I essentially can't
use this arm for at least a few weeks
and it's going to be pretty weak for at
least three months.
And I was really accepting that and he
said,
well let's just give this a shot.
And within a couple of weeks of getting
the shot,
I was like,
God damn,
this thing feels better than it's ever
felt before.
And so through a series of exercises,
like a lot of rotator cuff strengthening
exercises and I'm a bottoms up kettle
bells like where you.
You have to stabilize the kettlebells
ones.
Those are those.
Those are fantastic for stabilization
muscles.
And then it also made me realize that if
you're going to do something along the
lines of Jujitsu,
something,
it's very physically demanding.
You have to strengthen your machine.
I can't.
You can't just keep going to Jujitsu,
which is what I was doing for years.
Me Too.
That was my exercise.
I don't think that's adequate.
I think you have to strengthen the
machine and I think yoga is also a
really big and important part of
strengthening that machine because it's
lengthening,
decompressing the spine and it's making
you strong in these static positions,
which is very similar to the load that's
going to be pushed on those joints.
And on your back when you're doing job
to a traunch,
you go for a year.
I tried every day because usually I can
get into anything at some point or
another.
You've got to keep throwing enough hours
at it.
The one thing I couldn't get into
couldn't do it.
Maybe my approach was wrong.
I was doing the [inaudible],
my ex wife,
and it was incredibly painful,
incredibly challenging,
but while on come out and fight is
competitive element of it,
there's my enemy.
I can have a role around.
With Miami,
there's a tap,
there's winners and losers,
and for some reason that keeps me
motivated.
The idea,
I mean in essence,
I imagine it's the what I was talking
about in the end,
it's,
it's self again,
self.
With Yoga,
I just haven't made it that far to
access that struggle and enjoy it.
I feel like I'm always running on fumes
and yoga.
Yeah,
well you got to run on fumes,
but it's.
It's building a house,
one layer of paint at a time.
I mean it's.
It's not a,
it's not an easy thing to do and I think
that competitive element that you're
talking about is an internal struggle
and that internal struggle is you and
your breath.
Keeping your breath and calm and check
and focusing entirely on your breath
while managing the positions and then
slowly but surely developing more
proficiency in those positions.
More range of motion,
more dexterity,
keep going over and over again and then
one day you get to a point.
For me it was like maybe a year and a
half into doing it pretty regularly
while I'm like,
okay,
now I can finally hold this position for
30 seconds.
Whereas before I would literally count
to 10 and just try to get to 10 and then
I'd fall down and then I get back up and
try again.
Try to get to 10 and try to get my feet
would buckle,
my knee wouldn't be locked out and then
I'd try again.
Once you develop a certain of
proficiency,
then you can concentrate entirely on the
breath and that's where the real
struggle is.
And then keeping the mind on track.
Not Thinking about other bullshit.
Now thinking about the just just the
struggle of life and all the different
variables that you have to deal with on
a daily basis.
Thinking only of the breath,
the posture and the breath,
very difficult to keep on track so that
invariant,
that's the competitive struggle.
It's in your home.
See a consistency with the theme though.
That theme is this,
that that's all there is,
is the outside world of the noise and
what comes with that and there's the
internal self,
but everything is.
Everything is subject to these rules and
yoga in this sense is no difference.
Jujitsu's no different narrative is no
different.
It's being aware of what the dynamic is.
It's being aware of what's actually
going on.
That I think is fundamental.
Yes,
yes.
I'm pattern recognition.
Recognizing that it's the same for yoga
is for the essence of a narrative.
Absolutely.
Yeah,
and those things become a vehicle for
developing your human potential,
whether it's yoga or whether it's
Jujitsu and I think pattern recognition.
It's they take place in bold things in
yoga.
You Go,
okay,
I've been here before,
I know where this is,
I know I know what to do,
and you go right back into that thing of
concentrating on controlling the breath.
These big long,
deep breaths and these big long exhales
and then the focus is entirely on the
breath and those patterns,
they come up in Jujitsu as well that
that ability to maintain breath.
I mean,
I'm sure you've recognized that in a
person who just starts,
like one of the things you see about
someone who's just starting,
even if they're athletic,
they don't know what they're doing.
They started hyperventilating.
They don't know what to do.
They start breathing weird and they.
The breath is like the first thing that
you lose control over and Hickson from
the movie choke.
I mean that was the big thing that
separated Hickson from all the other
Jujitsu players is yoga.
Yeah.
His Yoga.
He made yoga sexy.
Yeah.
He,
well,
he was the first guy to make it
appealing at all to martial artists.
I mean,
that was with your wife did.
That's what your mom does.
It's what the housewives do.
It's not something that a man does,
especially not the top Jujitsu killer
ever.
It was a seminal.
It was a seminal documentary that
changed a lot of people's lives and it
sort of turned hixon into a rockstar.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I've had him in here.
He's an.
He's an amazing guy to talk to.
I've had him.
I've talked to him several times,
but having him in here and sitting down
with him and talking to him about
Jujitsu,
it's like,
it's like the.
It's like sitting down with Michelangelo
and talking about art.
I mean you're talking about there's
masters and then there's the master of
the masters and if you talk to any
Jujitsu master,
they all just go.
Hixon is the number one thing.
There's no dispute,
which is amazing.
There's very few,
like there's soccer players that are
just elite and there's basketball
players that are elite,
but when it comes to like who's the best
in Jujitsu,
there was always this one and while
he was competitive and especially while
he was young,
it was always Hixon,
which is to me amazing that he was able
to maintain.
And I think one of the things about him
was his physicality and his mind and I
think those two things in many ways were
enhanced by yoga.
I think he's got some disc issues now
that it doesn't.
It has quite a few.
He has quite a few.
Yeah,
I think he has eight bulging discs,
which is horrific.
Maybe you should send him to your mind.
Oh,
I'm going to 100 percent.
I mean,
I've talked to him about a bunch of
things.
Hixon those are a bit reluctant for
certain kinds of treatment,
you know,
I mean,
he's a,
he's just gonna eat mangoes and fucking
meditate and Shit.
I Dunno,
I dunno what he's,
uh,
what is,
what he's tried or what he's willing to
try.
But I would love to see him.
I mean,
I would love to see him rolling again.
that would be amazing if they could
regenerate this tissue to the point
where he would be healthy.
I mean,
that's the fear.
The fear for the first time for me is
that I've never felt any version of age
on the mat.
But when people are starting to tell me,
oh,
we're not going to fix it,
we're gonna wait until we give you a new
one.
Okay.
What side of the this night and when
they're saying that about your knee,
what is the issue?
Is that a meniscus issue?
Um,
it is a meniscus issue,
but I've lost 75 percent of the meniscus
of the cartilage.
I get confused between the difference
cartilage or meniscus.
What is the different cartilage is what
covers the outside of the bone?
Meniscus has the padding essentially
that's in between the two bones that
keeps them from touching each other.
Right.
Okay.
So they have both.
So it goes bone,
meniscus,
cartilage,
the Meniscus,
you can cut some of it out.
But when you didn't have had that done,
um,
my left knee,
they,
they did,
uh,
you know,
they go in arthroscopically and they
trim some of the torn meniscus.
Yeah,
it's,
it works.
But if it's less stable,
there's less tissue in there.
It's more subject to inflammation and
swelling.
It doesn't handle the load as well.
But I got stem cell shot into there and
I've never had a problem since.
It's amazing.
I had a problem with it for.
I mean I tore it for the first time a
more than 20 years ago and had an
operation I think in [inaudible] 95,
somewhere around there and then I had
another operation on it in 2001,
2002 and it was.
It's always been an issue since then.
It's just one of those things that he
gets sore.
I just deal with it.
Whether it's kickboxing or whether it's
lifting weights or whether it's Jujitsu,
it gets sore.
I just deal with it.
I take glucosamine and Chondroitin and a
lot of fish oil and antiinflammatories
and changing.
My Diet helped quite a bit,
but there was always that thing until
they shot the stem cells in there and
then literally within a few months it's
nonexistent.
Like I don't think I have this need that
acts up anymore.
Now I have a knee that never acts up.
It just doesn't bother me anymore.
This is very exciting stuff.
It's very exciting stuff.
And Tell me how thin I'm on the wedge in
terms of
this being new.
Well,
they've been doing it and experimenting
with it for a couple of decades
apparently according to Dr Mcgee,
but the understanding of the potential
and the possibilities and then the
practical application as over the last
10 years has really come to the
forefront.
It's really become something very,
very viable.
It's not just theoretical anymore.
Now they're actually seeing people
regenerating tissue.
They're seeing people where you have a
tear in your shoulder or something like
that and then go out and you're probably
going to have to get surgery.
No.
Then they shoot it in there and then
next thing you know it a couple months
later,
I mean I still got some floating tissue
that like pops and crunches and stuff
and my shoulder.
But when it comes to like the actual
strength in my shoulder,
I don't worry about it at all.
Like it doesn't bother me.
I mean there's,
there's occasionally some light
soreness,
but as far as like the functional
strength of the shoulder,
it's like 100 percent.
It's crazy.
So is this the thin end of the wage
then?
So is this gonna,
is this gonna turn into one of those
exponential?
It is.
Oh,
for sure.
For sure.
They're already generating.
They.
They built this woman.
This is very exciting.
It's tough.
It's as exciting as it gets.
The regenerating tissue,
they're real regenerate body parts.
They built this woman a bladder.
She had a.
They took skin cells,
stem cells from the skin and they with a
p in a petri dish.
They started this off and then built her
a boy.
She had bladder cancer and they built
her a bladder and then put it in her
body and it's functional.
It's amazing.
I mean this is all state of the art now
and when we're looking at like 10,
20,
30 years from now,
I mean you're looking at potentially
regenerating all sorts of things,
regenerating bone from people who have
bone cancer,
regenerating lungs and liver and spleen
and heart.
I mean,
they're going to be able to make body
parts.
They've created an artificial heart that
beats like with stem cells.
They've actually constructed a human
heart.
This is a subject,
you know,
selling,
you're bound to,
fascinated by it,
because what they're able to do now is
just a,
you know,
you're just looking into the future.
You get a window into this and it seems
like it's exponentially exploding.
I mean all over the world.
There's people experimenting with this
stuff and trying to figure out new ways
to improve things,
which is the fact that I'm having that
conversation and this isn't the first
conversation I've had in the last month
about this.
Yeah,
it's pot.
There's aunt gus.
No.
Oh,
it is now.
People are understanding it and people
know people that have had issues with
it.
Um,
you can't get it in America,
but in Mexico,
I know people that go over there and get
it done intravenously and uh,
you know,
boss route and you know,
boss boss route and the way he described
on this big character,
he's like.
And it was like I had energy coming off
my fingertips.
I had some pretty significant problems.
He's got fused disks in his neck and he
had major atrophy in his arm because his
disc was compressed and they.
It was pushing on the nerves so the
nerves
weren't getting.
They weren't firing correctly,
so his right arm,
he calls baby arm because his right arm
has kind of shrunk and so he's
experimented with a lot of these things.
He's kind of been ahead of the curve
with this stuff.
You should get Jason Statham and I would
love to you,
right?
Yeah.
It's very similar.
These go a couple of tweaks here and
there.
I met him.
He's a nice guy.
He had a bunch of stuff going on with
his body too.
I'm sure he's a martial artist.
Better condition now.
He used to be an Olympic diver.
You should die for England.
You know one of those,
right?
I'm fabulous athlete and he takes care
of himself.
I believe it.
A good name,
but you know he's got tweaks,
got their own knee.
That just never quite goes away.
Little thing that he does his much and
by the way,
get him on diet and he's off to the
races.
You can't shut him up.
He's got,
you know,
leave him there for three hours,
come back kind of cutlet.
We still banging on about it.
It's something that he cares profoundly,
but I can tell you now we're sitting in
now there'll be a battle about you
couldn't.
Who was good to say what to whom because
you'd talk over one another.
Um,
you should get him in,
in a way he relate to best,
you know,
I'm sure.
Do you watch your diet?
Are you a healthy eater?
Not as healthy as I'd like to be.
I'd go up and down.
I play.
I also liked with 30 pounds of extra
nonsense.
It's on.
Yeah.
Um,
now I'm weighing 190.
Now I should get one 92 actually today.
And I should be creeping around a good
fight and weigh about one slash 78.
So what is it?
Is it a booze Buddhist thing?
It's not the booze.
The booze isn't the issue in terms of
the canneries itself.
The booze is the window to the calories
itself.
The pizza,
the pizza pizza man.
But I do love a pub or a pub or they
love a pump and a,
a pack of crisps.
You don't really have packet kitty corn
chips over here.
Not Quite the same thing.
They're not,
they don't know an English,
an English crisp is a heavyweight chip.
Um,
and they worked particularly well in
pop.
So it's two pints of Guinness and a
couple of packs of crisps.
And you've it in a thousand calories is
complete nonsense in all about 22
minutes.
I'm the salt to is very appealing where
you're drinking a cold thing,
just work chances each other,
but it didn't take long before.
There's a heavy price tag that comes
with that.
I train the law,
recognized train weights three times a
week and finding bread on the three
times a week.
I love training Kebab and it's trying to
somehow reconcile that.
And every now and then I'll behave
myself a stay at the pub style off the
booze for three months and I couldn't
get myself down to one 78.
However,
it's been five,
six years since I've been there.
Now I dropped eight pounds the other
day.
Strictly I was strict with myself off
the booze because I'm off the booze.
I don't look at food in the same way.
The thing that the whole purpose of
boozers to relax trouble is as well.
Also reluctance to the rules.
Right?
Right.
Now,
when you're dealing with all these
injuries,
how are you able to train through all
the stuff you've got to shoulder they
think in one day might need to be
replaced and needs that might need to be
gone.
Crack on.
Yeah.
I found that and I'm sure you've had the
same through Jujitsu.
Whenever I get an injury,
a font,
if you stop messing around with it and
paying too much attention to it,
it kind of don't go on for longer.
Nine or 10 million injuries are just try
and through and there's almost a
bluffing game that you have with the
injury who was in charge had mailed the
injury and once the injury knows that
you mean it.
It tends to move,
walk out the door,
but there are more fundamental ones like
the shoulder and then the next,
and I shouldn't say that actually has
been giving me a bit of aggro recently.
Um,
so there were a few things that you need
to take it serious.
Now I can see you're onto this job.
I can see you're focused on this.
Yeah.
I know a lot about this stuff.
But you're invested.
Yes.
Right.
And you need to be invested.
If you mean it is,
it's ownership again,
your investment is ownership.
Well,
my good friend Eddie Bravo just at his
disc replaced.
He had to replace with a titanium
articulating lower back disc.
So he had some pretty significant disc
decompression or compression issues,
uh,
in deterioration.
And it got to the point where his lower
back was just constantly inflamed.
You know,
Eddie's worldclass blackpoll.
Yeah.
He just couldn't come anymore.
Why didn't you send them to you?
Oh Man.
Well it was before they were actually
shooting it into the desk.
He had it done about a year ago,
about a year ago,
eight,
nine months ago,
something like that.
So this might be one that whether you
just hang on.
Yeah,
I would say with stem cells,
with a lot of things,
hang on,
what some things you can hang on like a
acl tears once the tear,
once the ligament is removed you.
There's nothing you can do.
You have to ever replace a terrible
thing.
Yeah.
The acl and it's such a common injury,
but you know what's interesting is once
you get it replaced.
Like for me,
I had a Patella tendon graft on the left
knee and then a cadaver graft on the
right knee and had all sorts of things
done.
They.
I've done it all,
but neither one of them bother me at all
anymore.
And they're stronger.
Like the,
the.
When they do a cadaver graft,
they use the Achilles tendon,
which is a 150 plus percent stronger
than your original acl.
So it actually makes it a stronger
joint,
right?
Melinda's.
No.
Yeah.
Well,
the Patella tendon graft is still
stronger than when they use a Patella
tendon graft that is still strong in
your patella tendon is a very huge
tendon and you can,
you can operate with a third of it
missing,
which is essentially what they cut out
when they
my right leg,
which has had the two acl,
so I've noticed is atrophied and there's
very little I can do to beef up that
quad.
That's probably because you're favoring
your left side.
Yeah.
But then you know,
isolated and I'm beast the thing,
but I just can't engage it.
I can't get it flat leg like a can on my
left leg,
get it completely flat.
Standard it.
So it bends.
Yes.
Age or your courts does some stem cells
in that bad boy.
It's very exciting.
Sorry.
So yeah,
it's,
it's the real deal.
I mean it's something special.
Who's the years I've been living with
it?
Yeah.
They can fix you up,
take a fixture up.
But diet is huge.
One of the things about diet is
inflammation and I never really wrapped
that in my head and to see about three
or four years ago I had a pretty
significant back injury and then just
say in my hands were numb and it was
because I was ignoring it because I
would pinch it in Jujitsu and then I'd
go,
oh,
it's still going to roll light.
I'll just go in there and roll light and
then after awhile it was getting bad to
the point in my back was locking up and
my hand started going numb and I give
this pretty significant elbow pain,
so I started really researching all the
options and what's really going on in
one of the big ones that I've found was
diet.
That when you have too many inflammation
causing foods in your diet and reading
too much sugar and bread and booze and
all these different things that affects
it.
It affects like how your body carries
fat,
but it also affects where your body
holds onto inflammation and joints in
particular.
All the injuries,
spots were waste sore when I had a
shitty diet.
So give me,
give me the evils.
Um,
as Laird Hamilton calls them the three
white devils.
Sugar bread.
What's the other one?
Yeah,
what is the other one?
Booze.
The kind of white foam on bears.
White.
What is it?
You should know what?
The three white flour.
Pasta,
sugar.
I don't know.
What is either one.
Dairy.
I guess.
Mary.
There you go.
Yeah.
I like cheese though.
So do you don't drink alcohol?
Yeah,
I do.
we try not to drink too much.
I mean it's like all things in
moderation,
including moderation.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm not a big drinker.
I don't like.
I'm not drinking every night,
but if I go out,
you know,
and I have a drink or have a glass of
wine with dinner or a couple of glasses,
I'm,
I'm cool.
I think it's just a matter of just
controlling yourself.
That's really the thing.
So,
uh,
the three white devils,
you do subscribe to three white devils.
I occasionally will allow myself to
dance with the devil,
but the little three of them.
Yeah.
Well,
a little bit of sugar,
a little bit like last night I had some
linguine with clams.
I don't.
I go on an 80 slash 20,
which means 80 percent of my diet is
very clean and then 20 percent off fuck
off,
like whether it's Saturday or Friday or
whatever.
Had you feel about rural milk on
posturized love.
I Love Rob Melton.
I'm opening.
I'm opening a little raw milk dairy.
Are you really?
I am.
I'm having,
I'm very interested in this health
thing.
I'm more from a culinary point of view
that I am from a nutritional point of
view.
However,
I suspect,
I suspect that there's a sweet spot
here.
I'm opening a brewery.
I love a beer.
You're opening a brewery to brewery?
Yeah.
Which,
how much do you know about making beer?
Yeah,
quite a lot actually.
Have you been doing it on your own?
Done all that sort of asking around
underneath the stairs routine for years.
Um,
which is great fun.
I like any sort of form of caveman
chemistry,
Francis Mammon.
Mammon is,
it's big fan of that sort of thing.
I'm a bit of a caveman when it comes to
anything to do with food,
so I do like a nice steak outside.
I'll take my uncle if I say so myself.
I'm on good on a barbecue and I'd been.
I'd been doing that barbecuing for 20
years.
Good.
On a slow cook.
Take that quite seriously.
Um,
but.
So yeah,
only brewery beer.
And then when I'm on it I'm,
I'm putting a butcher,
a baker,
the candlestick makers to.
It's gotten a small hotel place in,
uh,
in England.
Fifteen hundred acres farm.
Got All that sort of nonsense going on.
So you're going to do farm to table the
whole deal.
I'll make your beer.
Yeah.
Raise your own animals.
Serve them.
Yeah.
The whole thing just got to get into.
So yeah.
Yeah.
I mean jeans traditionally in English
drink,
but I wasn't really into it until I came
to America and I've found since I've
been here in the last,
over the last week,
it's been quite a few gin and tonics
going on.
Yeah.
And,
and apparent is the easiest of the
spirits to mix all my little swing on
that too.
I'm good friends with maynard keen in
lead singer of tool and he went
essentially for for years,
just went and developed his own vineyard
at.
Where is he?
Arizona.
Yeah,
and not in a place in Arizona that's
known for growing wine,
so he had to manipulate the soil and a
baby's having a lovely time.
He loves it.
Yeah.
He's probably quite an expensive,
lovely time though,
isn't it?
I'm sure he's making money with it now,
but he's.
He's like a legitimate genius and he's
one of those guys that he cannot be
stagnant.
It's not even an option.
I mean his mind works a thousand miles
an hour and when you're talking to him
you just kind of kind of jumped on the
train and hang on there with them as
long as you can jump off and go,
Ooh.
But he's just a very,
very,
very intense guy.
And his,
his particular brand of intellectual
curiosity led him to start experimenting
with one.
His wine is absolutely fantastic and
these are legitimate wine expert like
you sit here and talk to them the same
way you and I can talk about boot
Chechnya or Hadzic,
racier,
Henzel.
He can talk to you about why and he's
also a purple belt in Jujitsu to so he
can talk to him.
He's an intense guy.
I liked the sound of this.
The one business I do find interesting.
There's something happen.
Learning with the whole craft movement
general,
that's very exciting that we are going
back to local stuff and people to a
degree it's ownership again.
Yes.
It's take ownership of your food,
take ownership of everything to do with
the important components of your life
and it'll got robbed from us.
Yeah.
You know,
what happened in the seventies in the UK
is all these breweries bought up all the
pumps and they brought up all these
small breweries and used to have all
these breweries with their own little
crafty beer going on and then they have
merchandised it and then he sold it back
to us and they gave it back to us with
that character and we just bought it
because we were stupid.
Right?
Yeah.
And then what's happening is we realized
that character is important and local
character is important and ownership is
important.
So there's this movement,
um,
and to a degree things like instagram
may have a dark side,
but it was as a light side is given a
voice to the craft movement on like a
man that makes his own knives.
Yeah.
And followed any of that stuff.
What are handmade knives?
All the time.
That's what I use to like cut my food.
Like they feel good.
I like it.
It's a completely different experience.
I have exactly the same thing.
We order a lot of army knives and when
you're cutting your food with a handmade
knife,
it's not what it used to be.
You realize a knife should be a thing
thing
and it got robbed from us.
Do you know Steve Kramer is a number of
days a guy who makes knives with media
rights?
Yes,
I do know I've seen him.
I said there's a little thing with
Anthony Bourdain.
Say now I'm sitting there thinking the
people dynamic he takes a chunk of it
came from space.
It's fabulous.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
I actually,
I got a feeling that might have been the
genesis of my interest in knowledge with
antibody thing.
There's a guy,
a mousy fire arts,
find that on Instagram,
but he just made me this Damascus steel
cutting knife and uh,
on a hunting knife to go with it.
And it's just.
I mean,
I cut with it,
but it's this.
I stare at it for minutes before I cut
with it.
I look at the blade and the handle's
made out a thousand year old bog would
like wood that was preserved from a
Bhag,
Bhag.
Maple.
It's amazing,
this is amazing,
but why is it so interesting?
But the faculty,
this is interesting.
Look at the pattern in the.
In the steel Damascus steel,
if you go to his instagram,
there's a picture of my knife in there.
You could see it.
He,
this guy is.
I mean that's it right there at the far
right.
Far those two.
Those are the two knives that he made
for me.
That's a sexy bit of kit.
Those ancient bog oak.
That's what it is.
What is it?
What's the bulk from?
Is that an American bug?
I don't know.
I'd have to ask him.
I just took his word for it,
but look at that thing.
That's lovely.
That's what I used to cut up.
Garlic all sold excalibur.
We've made that Domestica scale man.
Really?
I'm into a band.
Damascus stuff.
Did you have a blade?
Smith fashioned for your moving?
Uh,
yeah.
Wow.
So you had it specifically made for the
movie?
Yeah.
Poor old Charlie Hunnam who plays King
off there is.
It'd be waiting to receive this sword.
How much does it weigh?
I mean,
this motherfucker had to get in shape
for that thing,
right?
Yeah,
always in good.
Nick.
You're like,
you ever do those?
Um,
uh,
like a shield cast with a steel club.
You realize how difficult it is to
manipulate even a 15 pound club.
Yeah.
Bit of hard work.
Very hard work.
If those guys like sword fighters must
have had intense shoulder strength and
core strength.
Yeah.
But they think these guys are in the UK.
They every now and then they stumbled
across a body that's a thousand 500
years old and they realized the
deformity in the shoulders,
the right,
whatever you call that.
When you pull a biobank.
Yeah.
Um,
and they used to be in English law that
every Englishman had to practice for
eight hours a week to pull back above.
So you've go these skeletons that are
deformed from the enormous strength of
the soldiers to these on the shelf
deformed.
How so,
like what,
what is the issue with it?
It was the sheer Yolanda Joe,
you know,
a lot more about this than me,
but the,
they had become deformed through the
development of the muscle,
which in some way then changed the bone
structure.
Bone structure.
Yeah.
Wow.
These massive,
great,
right arms.
Those,
I don't know if,
you know,
in the UK,
in this country you do this,
the finger is,
is the single finger in the UK.
It's two fingers,
right?
But why is that?
It's for bows and arrows,
right.
Comes from the English wars and the
French was um,
and the Englishman we're famous for that
long bows and the famous battle of
agincourt where there was a couple
hundred of us and it was 10,000
of them and they're liberal.
They,
uh,
they had crossbows back then and we had
this long boat along the way was the
machine.
Yeah.
In the a bow and Arrow world.
And because the Brits,
that's what they did,
they were a,
as a week,
every Englishman have to do that,
that they were pretty lethal with these
things.
Anyway,
they annihilated the entire French army.
There was a famous battle of the French
have conveniently forgotten.
Um,
so what the French did thereafter,
if they have recorded Englishman,
was they chopped off two of his fingers,
pull back the bow.
So whenever a,
as,
as history,
then I'm made eloquent,
is that whenever you saw a freshmen used
to waive the two fingers up at him and
then since then it's now just become
ubiquitous fuck off sign.
Have you seen the way the Mongols did
it?
The Mongols,
they had these incredibly powerful
recurve bows and would take 160 pounds
to pull back and they use their thumb.
They would have a,
a thumb ring made out of bone.
Have you seen that?
No.
I have a bungalow.
They therapy.
There's a fantastic audio documentary on
the history of the Mongols,
the wrath of the con with Dan Carlin and
I listen to that.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
I'll even out there.
There's a bit of a fan of yours that he
keeps me up to date on the different
things that you're in because he's
interested in the same things.
I didn't know about the knives and
there's a couple of other things I
didn't know that you knew about,
but he's a big fan.
He got me onto this.
See those things.
We might,
I think he got onto this because you've
got them onto I'm sure,
but once you hear Dan Carlin,
I mean,
it is absolutely addictive,
but this is the ring that they would put
on their thumb and they would pull back
like that and then they would wrap their
index finger over the thing where the,
uh,
the thumb nail is and then pull it back
that way.
And then release.
That's how they would release their
arrows.
Well,
it didn't get very far,
did it?
Well,
it did for a long time until gang is
Kahn died.
I mean,
they killed 10 percent of the population
they killed.
I mean,
I was kidding.
Joking around.
They killed so many people that change
the carbon footprint of earth.
There was a New York Times article about
how many people died during gingiss
Khan's reign.
That it was so significant.
You could see it in the carbon data.
You're kidding.
No,
no,
I'm not kidding.
See if he could pull that article that
he killed between 50 and 70 million
people during his lifetime were directly
attributed to his army and his
decisions.
Fifty to 70 million people died.
The conservative estimate is somewhere
around 30 to liberal estimate is
somewhere around 70.
Nobody really knows what they think.
It's between that Mongol invasion in
1200 altered carbon dioxide levels.
It killed so many fucking people at this
time.
Earth where there was probably only a
million people kicking around on it.
I don't know how many people there were.
I thought there was a lot more than a
million because they killed a million
people in China.
They killed.
They killed people in numbers that we
can.
Even in Jen,
I think it was Jen China,
they showed up and this was part of the
Dan Carlin series,
the,
um,
the show,
the corpsmen and shaw sent a,
like an envoy,
like a party to go search this,
a city in China.
And as they pulled up,
they thought what they saw in the
distance was a snow covered mountain.
As they got closer,
they realized it was a stack of bones
and the roads were so deteriorated from
human bodies,
just rotting human bodies.
They had abandoned the roads because
they couldn't get their cars through
there.
Their wheels rather through because
their wheels were getting bogged down.
Their horses were getting bogged down in
the muck of deteriorating bodies as so
many people.
The Mongols killed.
What the Fuck I was at?
Just the design for empire.
It's a real good question.
First of all,
is the dehumanization of the enemy.
I mean,
his idea was that everybody who doesn't
live in a tent and anybody who doesn't
live the way they do these fools that
live in cities,
they weren't even human.
There were sheep like.
There was a certain disconnect between
them and the other,
which is imperative.
It's the most important thing in war.
You have to decide that that person's
not you.
Right?
You have decided that there the other,
whether it's the Vietnamese or the
Germans,
the Nazis,
the Japanese like whatever it is,
you have to decide that they are less
than you and they had this thing about
people that did not live like they did,
that they were pussies,
these,
these weak people that lived in these
cities with their walls and so they
would just find,
find these cities.
They'd stroll up and they would just
figure out a way to start attacking them
and they would light bodies on fire and
launched them with catapults onto the
roofs of these buildings.
But what was the.
What was the motivation?
It was just conquering.
Just conquering.
I mean,
they just wanted to expand their empire
and take over.
I mean,
it's not.
There's no noble pursuit and there is no
religious pursuit either.
I mean,
it's a expansion.
Yeah.
Will.
They just wanted to own it all.
They,
they felt like everyone they encountered
was subject to their rule and they had
to.
They had to establish that sip very,
very intense series.
Now remember,
I remember I caught into about five
years ago.
I don't remember the bone thing with the
bone thing in off,
but I've got mountains of bone.
Oh,
nice.
Now.
But uh,
I do remember some of that food.
How things drift.
You'd appreciate this.
This is a legitimate Samurai sword from
the 15 hundreds.
Really?
Yeah.
That's a real one.
Well,
that's quite sexy time.
Was this shock skin going on up here?
I don't know.
I mean,
I think that the,
uh,
the case is probably a,
a modern case,
but that blade itself,
that is a,
that is a blade from somewhere around
1511.
They think.
How'd you get your hands on this?
It was a gift from my business
associate.
Aubrey Marcus,
a good buddy of mine.
And um,
we're in business at onnit together and
he gave me this.
That's quite a thing.
Yeah,
it's quite a thing.
That's a real thing.
It's not one of these blades that once
you take out,
you go to draw blood,
is it?
No,
no,
no.
Anything.
We go this a military unit in the UK
called the workers that come from the
poll.
That's been a tradition for a couple of
hundred years and they have these funded
little knives hooks on.
Yeah,
they're weird.
Nice.
We ate the lives and once they draw
them,
once they're at the sheath that they're
not allowed to put them back into this.
Got Blood on him so they have to cut
themselves and the Catholic.
Anybody,
anybody Christ.
I was like a weird excuse to cut
yourself.
Yeah,
I mean doesn't that.
That's like a pretty rigid requirement.
Don't draw unless you're going to draw
blood.
What can I tell you?
I mean,
being a soldier,
tufts stuff,
it is as tough as it gets.
Yeah.
Now that says something about your film
I'm sure is you're dealing with a a
different time and that life back then,
although always precious.
The finite aspect of life is more
solidified.
It's more obvious.
It's more.
It's something that you're dealing with
on a daily basis as opposed to the way
we live.
Yeah.
I think there's all sorts of advantages
to that.
If you're looking down the barrel of a
gun,
nothing so busy looking down the barrel
of a gun and we've managed to distract
ourselves by be comfortable
liberal lives that we lead and that the
price for that is that we don't really
accept the full accountancy of life,
so we do give ourselves crutches where
you look down the barrel of a gun or
your crutches and taken away.
So I suppose in different periods of
time you didn't have to.
You didn't have the indulgence of being
able to worry about what people thought
of you because there were more important
things to worry about.
Yeah,
yeah.
There were more important things to
worry about than social media.
You have to worry about arrows.
Swords,
death.
Yeah.
Constant.
The thing is that even come back to the
Mongols,
so what was his desire for gain?
His desire for gain with the more people
appreciate and respect me.
Then the more I'll be,
is there anything else that kills people
other than that motivation?
Not like that.
Well,
not even like that.
I'm just doing about murder,
right?
The whole genesis of murder is based on
the principle that someone has more
power than me,
so I have to take that power away,
or my comparative sense of self feels
augmented if I can take that life away.
Hmm.
No.
Comes back to the same thing.
You're really asking someone to tell you
who you are and if you have
paradoxically and ironically if you
killed them,
that makes you more powerful than them.
Although they can no longer bear witness
or they did bear witness for a second,
but what does bear witness is the story
in your mind that somehow you are now
more powerful
or just fucking hate them.
You don't want them around anymore,
but why did you hate them?
Because they're threatening.
Yes.
Threatening to some way a threatening in
some way that somehow they can diminish
your idea of who you are or you find
them repugnant,
their actions,
repugnant dangers to their society,
something then that's not murder,
then it's just eliminating an enemy.
Right?
Or eliminating a threat.
Yeah.
If you could go back,
I mean I've often thought about this as
technology evolves,
like will there be come a point in time
where you can have a window to a certain
era,
like we'll,
we'll time machines ever be a thing
where there's a time where you could
actually go back and view the past.
Is there a period?
Yeah,
zero period that you wanted to quite a
lot
because of google earth on one of those.
I like a good porn on google earth,
so where I live in wheelchair,
the guard house in English,
countryside next door to stonehenge.
If you go on Google plus where they
plowed the fields,
you can see where there had been burial
sites for thousands of years.
Alright,
good.
Stonehenge is about five and a half
thousand years old,
but all around that area,
in these plow fields you can see they've
still got married,
old bounds and a burial mounds and
whatnot and the whole earth is littered
with prehistorical earthworks and burial
sites and there were burial sites that
we have this thing called Ordinance
survey which registers.
I mean,
but you will have the same thing.
He was registered is everything on the
earth,
right,
so everything of any historical value,
there's a map and they tell you what the
foot paths are and the roads are and
everything's been highly detailed,
how high the mountains are and the roads
and whatnot,
and I'm a bit of an Anorak for that.
You know the expression and right now
it's like a geek.
Okay.
You know those guys at trains and planes
and they usually wear those jackets go
down.
Anorexia is where the Christian
counseling,
so I'm a bit of an Anorak for
typography.
The history of typography,
so you go and Google Earth.
This was a bit of a wet dream as far as
I was concerned because I could spend
hours and hours pouring over landscape
and around my house.
You can find these,
all these burial sites that no one knows
existed and is only as good as google
earth.
It's just an arm confident that still
I'm the only person that knows these
burial.
These burial sites exist.
So how do you know their barriers sites?
Like what are you seeing?
Because you can build up a,
an understanding of pattern recognition.
Again,
you can see an established burial site
which is seen as a prehistorical
parasite bronze age or whatever it is,
and then you get step a mile to the
right and then you can find one under a
plowed field where they've got rid of
the mounds,
but you can still see the depressions,
which isn't exactly the same shape as
the depression's a mile to the right.
And then you can build up a whole
pattern.
So this is the area where you get crop
circles.
Yeah.
So.
And then you can build up a whole
picture which is a much bigger picture.
And then you can start to predict where
one burial site is going to be and it's
a bit like finding treasure and you go
to 100 yards that direction,
$200 and it should be about a bang.
There it is.
You can see half of these depressions
and then it runs into a word or whatever
it is.
But this staff that exists and you
wouldn't have known before Google Earth
came along.
How much work has been done on like
trying to study those things?
Well,
the thing is on Joel quite a lot,
but the thing is,
is prehistorical,
so they're really the only thing that is
there is arrowheads,
right?
And burial mounts and every now and then
they dig one up and then they find a
boat buried with a lot of gold and that
happens every now and then.
Um,
but there isn't much evidence that was
left behind.
So,
you know,
most of these things are just amount of
earth with few bones it.
But it's kind of crazy because that's an
area where people have been living for
thousands of years.
It's not like people went away and then
came back and now you're trying to,
like,
people have consistently lived in that
area.
Like,
and then the,
you see things like that horse,
that stone horse in the,
in the countryside.
Yeah.
The course was a big man with a big
willie to who's made that chalk chalk.
You can look him up.
He is a man with the big white willie.
Um,
anyone in that area that you have these
different emblems of what represented
tribes or whatever.
So we now live in the UK,
which is the United Kingdom,
but there is a legacy that,
I mean you'll have the same here.
There is a legacy there that you can,
you can trace back step by step for
thousands of years and we get,
you know,
get my not around the Romans.
That was a couple of thousand years ago
and the Romans been kicking around the
UK a couple of thousand years and then
they went and then in came the saxons.
Um,
and then after the saxons than the
French came in.
And then the French basically took over
the UK in 10,
66.
And then you have the culture that we
have now,
but you can see,
you somehow you forget that it go that
your culture goes on for thousands of
years and you accept really what we see
as history is the last 6,000
years old,
5,000
years.
But when you can have a connection to it
and it goes back further than that,
it's hard to get.
You're not around the Romans,
nevermind the bronze age.
Yeah,
and almost what is that?
There's the guy with the big willie.
Holy Shit.
What an odd.
How old is that?
Then I say I'm old.
It is.
There's lots of that that goes on around
the guy running that you fully erect
with a giant club.
How strange and there's a bunch of these
and they do.
They understand the origins of these
things and they know where they came
from.
I have no is the answer to that.
These are later.
They look quite primitive.
I think these are later.
How strange,
but that whole area is littered in this
sort of paraphernalia if you will.
Yeah,
and they don't necessarily know who did
it or why now,
but what's exciting to someone like me
is that you aren't going through any
other conduit and I suppose it's what it
is.
It's the mystery.
It's the mythology of all of this,
but it's your road into it as an
individual.
You're not cancer.
Any history books,
you're seeing it and it's like
discovering treasure.
You can access it on your own,
on Google Earth,
and you're thinking,
is anyone else doing this?
Why would they be doing it?
I started doing it because I wanted to
see.
I can't remember some aspects on some
poem Atlanta before.
No.
Oh look,
there's a burial site.
I'll have a little look.
And then before,
you know,
breadcrumbs lead to bakeries and you
find yourself filling your boots with
all the pastries in the world.
Um,
and it's something very exciting about
that.
So in reference to what it was that you
said earlier,
if I could go back to any time,
a lot of cut back for a minute,
I'm not sure I'd go back for for long.
I see that the period that we're living
in is the most exciting period to live
on this planet.
And not not least.
So because of what we've been talking
about stem cells,
is that going to be the thing that
allows you and I to age more gracefully
and without so much pain?
We have enough wealth that we can live a
comfortable life.
If you decide,
if you choose to live a comfortable
life.
We have medicine that we'd never had
before this period in history.
It is.
We are still complaining was still
complaining,
but if we could just remember what we
are comparatively,
where the position we are in history
comparatively.
It's an end to all complaints.
Yeah,
comparatively for sure.
It's interesting too when you're talking
about this,
the use of technology and how what you
can do now with stem cells in
comparison,
the pesticide,
because it's really exciting,
emerging time but similar like the use
of google earth to discover these mounds
and things and we see what's going on in
the Amazon now they're.
They're discovering evidence of
civilizations that were just rumors and
myths like the gold city,
the ancient gold city that there's that.
What is that movie that there is a lost
city of Z.
Yes.
They're finding these established
irrigation paths and city grids in the
Amazon jungle.
Thousands and thousands of years old and
they don't know the origins.
They don't know who was there.
They don't know why they're constructed,
what the culture was like,
but this was all at one point in time,
just mythological and now they're
realizing like,
no,
this is history and this is.
They've been told and passed down and
these fables and now we understand
there's an actual.
There's a concrete physical grid rather
that you can go and you could see like,
no,
these are real cities that did exist and
the jungle is sort of engulfed them.
It's taken over them.
It's amazing,
eh?
It's a thing bulaff oh,
it's incredible.
I mean it's allowing,
and this is only step one.
I think Google Earth is going to give
way to some sort of a magnetic resonance
type thing where they're going to be
able to look deep into the ground.
I think what we're seeing now is you're,
you're going to be able to.
You're right.
Now we're exploring the surface of the
earth and we're finding all these
characteristics that,
oh,
this is a body or this is a a burial
area.
This is a pathway that was probably
irrigation,
but I think they're going to be able to
come up with technology that allows you
to do the same thing but look deep into
the ground and then I think you're gonna
be able to find all kinds of crazy shit
the same way they can understand like
the complete topography of the bottom of
the ocean now and if you look at some of
those maps that show the ocean and
literally shows the depths at every
stage you,
I think you're going to be able to do
that deep into the surface of the
ground.
They're going to be able to discover all
kinds of crazy stuff.
Someone keeps opening that door.
What are you saying?
We got to get going.
This is why I don't allow people to come
ruined into a perfect God damn
conversation.
That's
all I've.
I know I haven't.
It's great because you biggest fan.
I'm a big fan of him.
You got some other commitments?
I guess so.
I do.
Yes.
I'm selling a film and I'll show you.
Go ahead and say it.
You're like,
fuck yeah.
I'm going to go see it.
I love all your movies,
man.
I'm a big fan.
I was really excited to have you in
here.
So,
uh,
when is it out this weekend?
Not this weekend.
Next weekend.
So that is Ivan.
Do you want to stick your head back in
and Ivan's.
He's scared now.
You scared him off?
I,
even if it's not this weekend,
it's next weekend.
Is that may the twelfth?
It's the weekend after guardians of the
galaxy is.
I believe that is may the twelfth.
Right.
Excited about it.
Yeah.
I love the film.
I like it was a tough out there that
brother.
I bet it is tough.
You've got a crazy business when you
decide.
And I'll just leave you with this.
When you decide like to commit to an
idea,
I'm sure you have a gang of ideas
bouncing around your head.
Like what makes you just go,
all right,
this is the one.
Let's run with it.
Telling how changing and it changes by
the year.
My next movie is Aladdin.
Oh really?
Yeah,
like the magic lamp.
That's the one really?
Yeah.
And in no small part,
because you know,
you get a weekend a right,
so that plays a little bit of a factor
in your motivation,
but it has to,
you don't spend three years on a movie
and no one hear about it.
Right a lot.
And they'll buy you would be very
fascinating.
I'll find it.
You know,
I liked the idea of taking the genres
that I don't know anything about retail.
Is it kind of excited you like doing
this King Arthur thing and in this
fantasy genre,
and this is sort of a changed your
expectations for possibly considering
other.
I sort of did English gangster films
from that.
And then Sherlock Holmes don't stop
doing those though.
Gangster films has to be TV.
It could be TV.
Were lots of that now because that's
where it's gone.
That's sort of interesting.
Netflix,
hbo type stuff,
that sort of stuff.
Um,
and then man from uncle,
which is like a spy thing,
and then he jumped to the spine genre.
So let me go.
Oh right,
okay.
I can go from this to that genre and
that's exciting.
And I've got five kids and he got five,
five kids.
Wow.
Which means I'm familiar with Disney,
right?
Of course.
So yeah,
all that.
What?
That world looks very attractive and
challenging.
Awesome guy,
reggie or bad motherfucker.
Thank you joe.
I Love Avenue in here.
Thank you.
It's been a great pleasure.
I enjoyed it enormously.
I was.
Do it again next time.
Your sound.
Something.
Come on in,
baby.
Thank you.
All right folks.
That's it for the week.
We'll see you soon.
Bye.
Much love.
Thank you.