I think what you said is dead on that
you got to go straight.
He's got to go straight African-american
because white people are just not heavy
and we're live.
This is what I think we need to
recognize the return of Dr Cosby and uh,
send a shout out to him and all the
folks.
So the barbershops,
I'm triggered.
You were saying before the show,
like what do you do if you're at a
comedy club and bill cosby walks?
Cause apparently bill cosby's doing
standup again.
They're like what do you do?
Why isn't he in jail?
I'm not even sure.
I'm like,
I'm not sure to be funny.
Why guy in jail?
Cause the first first trial was,
was it a mistrial?
Yeah.
Yeah,
there was a mistrial.
Um,
they couldn't agree,
which is hilarious.
Like I mean how many people have to say
that guy fucking drug me and rape me.
How many people?
Like is there some sort of,
could you imagine there's like 80 people
that are telling the same story of you
drugging them and raping them and people
like that.
So on the Logan,
here's what I'll say.
Like the soccer up two years.
No,
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
I just,
I don't want anything black a little bit
right now.
We're talking about bill cosby.
This is too soon for this.
I guess I just,
you know,
and it's interesting that this happened
after this weekend was the women's March
and I know like a lot of people want to
roll their eyes and I was getting a lot
of shit on instagram for like the
women's March.
You guys have it.
This is exactly the kind of thing that
I'm terrified of is that this guy is now
not in jail and he's just like back to
doing standup.
Yeah.
Because I don't know if we've got
desensitized or if we just forgot about
him or we just got sick of talking about
it.
Like how,
I just don't understand how people in
that plumbing,
I think he's the,
first of all,
he has an enormous ego and he's a
psychopath and I think that he is,
he's just,
he has enough fans in,
enough people in his community still
love him or he can go places and small
places and they accept him.
And then he's,
he's uh,
he's advertising it.
And what is twitter people that except
him with this?
Is it people who have their own
skeletons in the closet and they see him
coming back?
It's like they get redemption in some
way or maybe it makes them not be
incorrigible people or is it like a herd
mentality or is it just star fucking
like how do you rationalize that in your
head?
A little bit of Star fucking okay.
A little bit of dumb.
The fact that he's famous eclipse is the
fact that he is,
yeah,
psychopathic.
But then there's also,
do you remember how it was right after
Oj got innocent?
There was a guy,
and I want to say his name because I
respect him.
He's a comic and he went on stage.
He said,
no,
he's a black guy.
He goes,
my blackness will not allow me to think
that Oj did it.
And I,
uh,
I was interesting.
It was like,
what now?
What the fuck did I just hear like that?
It's insane.
Like,
okay,
all black people are innocent.
What does a black person comes in and
kills your family?
Will your blackness exonerate that
person?
Like how,
how are you going to handle it then?
And I don't know what the demo,
I mean,
what were,
do you know who was in that job?
Was it all black people?
I know.
Anything.
I can't read it.
Like I'm just,
I'm sick to my stomach.
You're going to be,
no.
If it's a,
I don't know if it's a blown bit when
rape culture on stage performing and
there's not like a complete melee of
disapproval.
That's really scary to me.
It is scary.
It's scary.
But I think that,
uh,
there's a certain amount of people that
get overwhelmed by celebrity,
so he shows up.
Like,
I can't believe he's here.
They don't want to say Manson goes up at
a jazz club.
It's like he's a celebrity,
but he's also a Charles Manson.
Less of a monster.
Here's why.
I'll throw this at you.
He never killed anybody.
Charles Manson actually told people to
kill people and they did.
And it's terrible that they did it.
Like Tex Watson did all the crimes and
um,
uh,
what was her name?
Squeaky fromme.
She was wanting to try to kill Gerald
Ford.
They,
they're the one who did the crimes.
He was just this crazy fuck who talked
these people into these things.
It's kind of the puppet master.
Yeah.
But that really scares me.
Raped,
who knows how many women and allegedly
it's also,
yeah,
um,
it just,
it scares me and shakes me to my core,
you know,
not that a psychopath does psychopathic
things,
but the people who permit it and who are
permissive and are okay with it and
don't resist,
like the fact that a bunch of people in
that club were just like,
okay,
we're good.
Okay.
We're all,
we don't really know what happened.
We just know that he was there and we
know that he's going to do another show.
And then he announced that he was going
to do some show at a jazz club.
It's like today,
I think,
is it today or tomorrow?
And is this jazz club?
I mean,
I don't know who owns it.
I don't know enough about it.
Probably tonight.
And I'm like frozen with disgust.
It's like,
that's the other thing is that
yesterday,
so it's already over.
It's as promised,
he performed at a jazz club today,
but this article is yesterday.
Wow.
That's promise.
Like,
oh,
he's a man of his word.
He might be a rapist.
He does not lie.
And he was wearing that hello friends
sweater that he always wears a fucking
night and he's got that um,
Bobby Brown thing on,
I don't know what that is.
The microphone or the microphone
headpiece thing.
And I mean,
I don't know.
It's just so tricky because it's like,
I was getting all these nasty comments
on instagram this weekend.
Like,
why are you getting nasty comments for
what I think with what's going on,
why,
why the guy was posting photos from the
women's March,
which was the march was about a lot of
things.
And I think just in the last month or
so,
there's been a little bit of eye roll of
like,
oh,
this is still going on.
You know,
like there's a lot of,
I think guys and women also who are a
little bit exhausted or I had one guy I
talked to a couple of weeks ago,
a friend of mine who was like,
I'm done with this.
What do you mean you're done with that?
It's like,
um,
we're done with,
uh,
sexual predators being,
um,
getting in trouble and getting fired her
and,
and getting cleansed from our society
and hustled please,
you know,
stopping from assaulting people in the
future.
And they were just to go,
just do feel like this has gotten
ridiculous.
You know,
there's,
I think a lot of people think it's like
a hysteria or it's like women
being dramatic,
um,
or something like that.
And then something like this happens and
I'm like,
oh,
are we not being dramatic enough because
this is crazy that he's just going on
stage and performing.
Like as if everything's just kind of
fine again.
Well,
I think he's a bad example because I
think he's nuts and I don't think it
makes any sense.
I think anyone who rapes is treating
people is not,
I think all of these people are not,
I think we're more nuts for just being
like,
okay,
I guess he's doing comedy,
but I don't think we are.
I think most people were like,
what in the far outraged,
I sent it to Tom Segura and that was
his,
his immediate reaction was like what?
He give me like a bunch of people who
are in that jazz club and the guy that
owns that jazz club.
Fuck you guys.
Um,
yeah,
we don't know.
I mean we don't know who these people
are.
If I'm in a comedy club in bill cosby
gets on stage and I'm like,
I got to hear what the fuck this bitch
has to say.
Like that's what I'm thinking.
I'm not being like awesome bill cosby's
here.
So maybe I should give them the benefit
of the doubt and assume that they think
they're seeing some kind of circus show.
I don't think I would say anything.
I don't think,
I mean I don't think it helps.
Like I don't think it was yellow.
I don't think I would do that.
But I definitely think I would sit there
and watch and like study him like some
weird fucking creature,
which is what he is.
He's,
he's an aberration in,
in humanity.
Like,
uh,
first of all,
he's an aberration a couple of ways.
Right,
right.
He's an outlier in terms of the,
the,
the popularity he reached,
he reached us insane level of popular
and he did in the 60s and the 70s when
the world was a different place.
Right.
And I really,
we've talked about this a bunch of times
as podcast.
I think a lot of people drug people back
then,
I think it was normal.
I think that dropping a mickey and
someone's drinks,
it was common.
Maybe not normal.
Yeah.
That's a better way to put it.
I think a lot of people did it and I
think a lot of people,
they will still do it.
Yeah.
Well,
but I think a lot of famous people did
it back then.
I think they were giving out pills.
And I don't think,
I think culturally we've evolved way
more than we are aware of.
I think we think of ourselves as being
very similar to people from the 1960s I
don't think we are.
I think we're way,
I think if you go from like 1810 to 1870
I bet people are pretty goddamn similar.
Interesting.
Yes.
Okay.
Good point.
Yeah.
I think technology's moving so fast and
adapting to that and the fact that we
have alarm systems
got a 1960 to 2018 way different.
Yeah.
Fucking way different.
What's acceptable?
How people think of things,
what we've w just as how people,
I think one of the things that's
happening and one of the reasons why
guys are eyebrow and about the women's
march is,
is that it's a new thing and this is an
overwhelming amount of energy that's
headed towards this thing.
And but what it represents is years,
decades of frustration,
women that had to work with guys that
were grabbing their ass.
I ain't trying to fuck them.
Pendulum swung hard.
It's like it snapped fast and,
and there's also,
we always talk about that.
And I'm obsessed with epigenetic
imprinting.
It's not just us,
it's our moms and our grandmothers.
This happened to,
and we carry that pain and that,
yeah,
suffering with us.
There's a lot of guys that say,
Hey,
I didn't do anything.
I shouldn't have to feel this,
but this is the thing,
these guys saying like,
I'm done with this.
You're not even a part of this.
Like,
how are you done with,
why is,
how is this inconveniencing you?
So like,
I don't understand how the stuck in
traffic.
Well,
I guess
that's it.
I mean,
that's exactly right.
So it's like a couple of,
I mean,
you're in La,
you're always sitting in women's march
draft it.
And I feel that we have who actually
better,
yeah,
the marathon and the gay pride parade
and the whatever.
So it's like,
I'm so sorry you're going to have to
like sit in traffic for an extra 20
minutes,
but like,
you know,
get your Amazon drone.
Why are you driving on a Saturday
anyway?
I get it.
I mean,
it makes sense.
If I just,
I guess I don't an office,
I fucking hate it.
I guess I just don't understand why this
is such a hassle for men.
I don't understand why it's such an,
unless you were raping people,
assaulting people,
hurting people,
nothing's being taken away from you.
And I feel like a lot of men thinks
something's being taken away from them.
And I don't know what that is.
You know,
and I'm just a little bit confused if
it's unfollow me.
I don't know.
Unfollowed if it's blowing up your
twitter feed and your instagram.
I just,
I can't wrap my head around why this is
such an inconvenience for guys.
So threatening
I don't think was that many guys that
are saying this.
Most men I think are recognizing that if
you look at the stories like the Harvey
Weinstein one is the worst and most
egregious example,
right?
I mean,
he's a guy that did it for decades.
They even enabled him to bill cosby's
worse,
right?
Because cosby was like,
Harvey Weinstein was an obvious
Predator.
It's like,
Hey,
don't,
don't go in the chicken coop with the
wool.
And here's something interesting.
I was also getting shit about this,
about,
um,
a lot of people were like,
well,
if you knew about Harvey,
why didn't you say something?
And it's just,
it's such a testament to how,
um,
who's someone said that.
Yeah.
Like I just got some comments that were
like,
well,
you knew about Harvey,
why didn't you say something?
You know,
when you knew about it 10 years ago or
whatever it,
you know,
but I,
I had heard like,
Oh,
he likes sleeps with actresses and he
like makes them fuck them.
But I wasn't really in that world,
so I knew about it.
But what was I going to call it?
The New York Times,
you'd be like,
Hey,
I was on comedy central for 10 minutes.
I have an idea.
Right.
You know,
like who was going to let you know?
And it's also,
it's like the kind of thing where we
didn't even know what we were allowed to
say and we didn't even know that there
was a possibility for change or that
there was a possibility that anything
would be done about it.
Like that's how I'm ingrained in our
psyche.
It was.
And how we just didn't know there was
anything.
We just thought that's how it was.
Well,
first of all,
you didn't know him.
You didn't work under him.
He did come to the comedy store ones.
I think you were gone.
And this isn't like my Harvey Weinstein
story,
like it's not close to how awful most of
the women's stories are,
but it is,
I think more like kind of funny.
He came to the comedy store and,
uh,
I,
I went on stage to the main room and
then I left.
And then Tommy called me and he was
like,
oh,
Tara Harvey Weinstein came to see you.
Um,
he's here,
you need to come back and talk to him.
And I was like,
I was like already at the Improv are
already like,
whatever.
And I was like,
I don't want to go.
And then the only reason I did not go
back at first,
I was like,
fuck him for just like summoning me to
come back.
I'm making $22 at the comedy store.
Like,
I don't,
you know,
and uh,
I'd already took me 40 minutes to get
out of the comedy store parking lot.
I can't go back in there.
And,
uh,
I remember literally just being like the
lighting in there as bad.
I don't want him to see me.
The lighting on stage is great.
Like he saw me at my best and I really
don't want to go back and like talk to
him.
I don't like know how to do small talk
with the producers.
I'm not,
you know,
me,
I'm like a neurotic mess.
Like I'm not good at like charming and
whatever.
Um,
but yeah,
that's a crazy way to think of things.
There was perfect.
Yeah,
that's a disaster.
Like you saw me at my best,
like,
let me just get the fuck outta here.
But like,
I didn't know how bad it was,
but I,
you know,
it's like the kind of thing that it's
like we didn't know what we didn't know.
Feel a little guilty though.
Like what you're saying,
what I'm getting is that you've people
saying that to you,
that you feel like,
ah,
I didn't do it.
I didn't,
I'm not
totally,
I think that there's a lot of women that
kind of have done nothing wrong,
but we're consumed with guilt and shame.
Like,
Oh yeah,
I,
I'm so glad to hear you say that cause
I'm just not hearing a lot of that.
I'm not hearing a lot of empathy and
maybe I'm just like zoning in on
negative comments.
Never had a female employee and I'd
never worked in an office.
But even though you hear all this sexual
harassment shit and any ego,
did I do anything?
Yeah,
you gotta you gotta check.
It seems like everybody did something,
but it's like,
but we were the same way.
It's like,
I mean I remember working on a talk show
and everyone's like,
oh well does that count?
That's not as bad as like getting
granular about it.
Like I remember I worked on a,
um,
a talk show,
late night talk show and a guy came up
to me in front of like a couple of the
writers and he took his hand and like
put it between my butt cheeks and just
went like swiped.
And he was,
looks like a credit card machine and
like everybody started laughing.
And of course I started laughing cause I
didn't like froze and I was embarrassed.
No,
he was like my coworker,
like,
you know,
and it was just kind of a Dick comedy
writer and I was like,
what do I do?
What am I going to do?
I mean at the time I had no concept that
it was offensive.
I was emotionally so naaman unconscious
in my twenties like I didn't even think
to do anything about it.
But looking back,
I'm like,
that was fucked up.
But what was I going to call human
resources and say that it just,
there's all these little tiny things
that aren't enough to be assault but are
too much to be appropriate.
And it's just like a gray area that I
don't,
you know,
it's,
it's hard for us to,
to delineate what makes sense of it.
Well it's funny how cautious you are
now.
I mean we're good friends,
but we're joking around when we had
these uh,
hoverboards and we're rolling around
these and you would not have caught me
cause you didn't want to touch me.
That's my fear.
But which you said was hilarious.
You,
you were under to say something about,
but you weren't sure if you could talk
about it because you were worried that
you bringing up the porn.
Yeah,
but somehow or another be sexually
harassing and I had to say like,
Hey,
that doesn't work.
You can't do that to matt.
Like you say,
whatever the fuck you want.
I ever give you license right now
publicly say whatever the fuck you want.
Forever.
Can't sexually harass me.
I didn't feel it too.
Like,
you know,
I don't want to,
you don't feel like,
I don't want to be a hypocrite.
You know?
I've been coming back to the comedy
store a lot and I hadn't been there in
the last like six months.
I've been working on something and I
noticed when I used to go to the comedy
store,
I used to feel like pray or any company
club.
It was like,
you know,
people would hug you too long and you
know,
you were just waiting to kind of like
have something inappropriate happened.
I went in the other night,
not one man hugged me.
Coloma lady like bowing at me.
No one would come near me like I was a
fucking leper.
Donnell Rawlings came up to me and gave
me a hug and halfway through he was
like,
Oh God,
I'm so sorry.
Am I allowed to do that?
And it was just like,
oh Whoa,
like this is,
this is fucking crazy.
The tables have turned because it used
to be women who are terrified of men and
now men are kind of terrified or you're
afraid of being called out.
There's a lot of that.
And a lot of guys going over the grade.
If you don't have skeletons in your
closet though,
if you're afraid,
if you don't,
are you afraid?
Because you know you have some shit.
Well,
here's the thing,
you don't have to have skeletons in your
closet.
Sure.
You can just have a bad relationship
where someone's mad at you.
Like,
this is these and sorry thing,
it's very bizarre.
Like this seems like he went on a bad
date and they took turns eating each
other out and blown each other and then
she didn't like it and she said that
there was like,
I don't know what the fuck happened
cause I wasn't there.
But there's a lot of people that are
picking sides on this and here's,
and I'm not accusing or supporting
either side cause I don't think there's
enough information yet.
And it all seems very like he had one
experience,
she had one experience and if they're
both telling the truth,
you know,
who fucking knows.
But here's what I'll say,
just about my experience in my twenties
as a woman is I was not fully formed yet
at 22 years old.
I didn't know.
I had literally no sex.
I wanted to have in my twenties I didn't
want to have you understand that now
that the frontal lobe is not really
fully formed and human being cracked,
cracked.
So Hey guys in your thirties and forties
stopped dating 20 year olds.
Just in general.
It's just a bad idea.
You know,
and I think that a really big part of
the conversation that for me a blind
spot is,
um,
sexual abuse victims.
So the statistics are a little foggy,
but like one out of six women are
sexually assaulted as children and those
are only the people that come forward is
that real one on a six one out of six
is,
is the statistic for people that come
forward that's not even including the
people that don't come forward,
which is a lot,
which,
um,
and not to get too serious,
but she didn't fucking Olympia,
I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but you see that Olympic thing makes me,
it makes me crazy.
The Olympic thing is insane.
The Olympic gymnastics coach or doctor
rather that was molesting all those
girls,
it makes me homicidal.
And when they're doing the testimony,
the girls that he's saying that this is
too uncomfortable for him to listen to
these girls
saw that guy on the street.
I think I'd kill him,
but my hands,
I'd have to,
I would go,
I would go batshit crazy.
So,
um,
I don't talk about this publicly because
I'm too embarrassed.
That's the other thing about this,
I think that guys,
some guys have this idea that us being
sexually harassed is like fun for us and
we like want to come forward and there's
some glory in it.
It's embarrassing and it's awful.
And I don't talk about my sexual
assault,
um,
publicly cause I just like freeze up.
Can
you're very self aware there are people
that take some sort of glory in being
victimized.
Maybe I can't,
I can't speak to that.
But I mean by that is to the point where
they will exaggerate any sort of
interaction with someone.
So there's people but men and women,
I,
so here's what I'll say,
that that could be true.
I don't know enough about the science of
that.
Um,
and I'm not a psychiatrist,
but my experience was the opposite.
I minimize mine.
I didn't how most people do.
I didn't come to terms.
The fact that I was sexual assault until
I was 32,
I'm 35.
Like I just kind of figured this shit
out.
And there's a lot of stuff that is still
blind spots that I don't want to deal
with.
And,
uh,
and I was only able to write about in my
book because I just,
I can't talk about it publicly.
Like I freeze up,
I get weird and scared and one of the
trauma responses of if you've been
sexually assaulted as a child is that
when the man moves towards you or you
have any kind of sexual,
see,
I'm like getting all nervous.
When you have a sexual interaction,
you freeze up because when you were
sexually assaulted as a child,
it didn't serve you to fight back and
you had to kind of disassociate.
That's why people get confused with it.
Fight or flight.
It's not just fight or flight free
trees.
One,
I have a freeze response or I'm sorry,
clear about what I'm saying.
So nobody misconstrues this what I'm
saying?
I'm not talking about real
victimization.
I'm talking about people that love to
play the victim.
Sure.
There are a lot of people that,
I don't know.
I'm talking about real vic.
When I say that is people take glory and
victimization.
I don't mean someone who's actually been
sexually assaulted.
I mean,
someone who may have had a weird
interaction with a person when they said
something.
Yeah.
And by the way,
I've done that,
like,
um,
you know,
I get bumped at the comedy store and I'm
like,
can you fucking believe I got bumped?
It's like I just am getting adrenaline
and,
and dopamine from like being self
righteous or having been wrong or
something.
I,
I know what you mean from that
perspective,
but I think when it's something real,
yeah.
My reaction is to complete as he is a
big one.
Yeah.
So it's like
so big one with a salt.
If people get,
not just sexual things,
but physical assault,
a lot of,
one of the things that happens to be
when they're confronted by someone in a
dangerous situations that panic and they
freeze,
they don't do anything.
They don't,
they can't,
they literally can't move.
So if at least 20% of women have that,
who knows what the fuck is going on in
some of these interactions.
So for me,
like in my twenties when a guy came
towards me,
I would freak out.
And people go,
why didn't they say no?
Why didn't they leave?
Cause I'm fucking frozen and I don't
know what to do.
So
is that has never been involved in any
sort of real altercation when they were
in danger?
Anyone?
He says,
why didn't you just,
well you don't know why you didn't do
things.
But there's times my life when I look
back,
I'm like,
why didn't I fucking say something?
Yeah,
but why?
Why didn't I tell that guy to fuck off
or what?
You don't know what to do sometimes.
I mean that was me and my whole
twenties.
Why didn't I tell him?
No,
why didn't I leave?
Why didn't I tell him to stop?
Like you know,
so,
so a lot of it I didn't even understand
cause I was too young too.
And I also,
I didn't,
it took me 58 years of a 12 step program
and therapy and Emdr to even be able to
save Emdr,
eye movement,
reprogramming and desensitization.
How the fuck would you expect anyone to
know what that means,
where you could just use
your fans are so fucking smart and like
there's such neurology nerds.
Yeah,
but that's off the deep end.
You will,
I need in my life it's uh,
uh,
post traumatic stress disorder or a
therapy.
Uh,
it was started for um,
uh,
Vietnam vets and it helps you to sort of
deactivate traumatic experiences.
Have you ever done ecstasy?
No.
Yeah,
it'll be,
therapy is supposed to be amazing for
people that have gone through trauma or
been told about this.
Yeah.
I'm going to go to Coachella next year
and try that.
I don't know if that's the place,
but it's supposed to be amazing for
people that have gone through real
traumatic experiences that are so
ingrained in their mind.
Like the memories of those experiences
are ingrained with trauma and horrible
feelings and somehow or another MDM may
therapy allows people to separate from
that and,
and lose the trigger and like lose,
lose this,
this right.
Sounds like a way more fun way to do it
because Emdr is like you sort of have to
relive the memory and then other shit
gets on earth and things start clicking
into focus.
Well,
the reason why they call it ecstasies
cause that's literally what you feel.
You feel so much love and what,
what his brain with dopamine.
Yes.
And I only did it once,
but the thing that stunned me was how
comparatively insecure I am in regular
life.
Comparatively insecure.
Can you say that again?
Comparatively insecure compared to when
you're on ecstasy.
Oh No.
Inhibition.
Zero.
You're so friendly and so warm and so I
try to be,
yeah.
Yeah.
But when your,
when you're on ecstasy you really
realize like all the hitches in your
personality or things that are holding
you back.
It made me,
I only did it once,
but it made me completely aware of
insecurity that I didn't even know
existed.
Fascinating.
Yeah,
let's do that.
you do it.
You'd trip out.
It's very interesting.
Super
into it.
I had another friend,
um,
recommend that and I'd be down because
it's also like,
you know,
and something else I'll say not to speak
for all women,
like I'm not the face of all women,
but like with this administration,
if you're a sexual trauma survivors
seeing this fucking guy on the news
every day can be really triggering post
about the women's march is twitter
literally can't read the news anymore
because I'm too activated and I'm just,
I'm,
I'm going crazy.
I'm way to activate it.
Like seeing a sexual Predator or someone
I deemed to be a sexual Predator with
all the women that have come forward in
the news every day is activating my
trauma response of,
I think he's a predator.
I don't think it's just sexual.
I think he's a Predator
and our business,
I think he's a Predator politics.
I think he's,
I mean if you look at the way he
campaigned,
you know,
like about the Hillary Clinton,
lock her up,
lock her up.
This is predatory fines.
Yeah.
Well he,
he's a,
he's a fucking winner.
I hate to say it that way.
And I was,
do you remember?
Um,
I think it was,
I don't know if this was the primaries
or it was like when Ben Carson was still
in the mix and they were all lined up
and I remember seeing,
and this was when we all thought it was
like a joke and he called all of them
out.
He was like,
you've asked me for money and you've
asked me for money and you've asked me
for money.
And I was like,
that's fucking hot.
Like this.
The reptilian brain was like,
oh shit.
Like that guy's a fucking winner and
he's not scared of anything.
And with the sound off,
I'm like,
that's the alpha.
If Shit hits the fan,
I'm following that guy's old.
He's lived a long life.
He's on speed.
He's a malignant narcissist.
The money.
And there's all these reports that he's
on diet pills.
Do you believe that syphilis,
Siri,
I don't know that when you have,
can you look this up as if you haven't
already today though?
No.
Is that like caffeine or is it like he's
on some sort of amphetamines?
Apparently according to several sources.
One of them that tracked his
prescription from drain read pharmacy in
New York from a few years back that he
was on this one type of amphetamine for
like eight years to take drug tests.
If you're the president,
and I don't even know,
wow,
this is amazing.
You have to take a drug test.
You work for ups,
you don't have to take a breath test if
you have the fucking nuclear football.
How is that not?
Well,
I dunno.
It doesn't mean while Jeff sessions is
fucking trying to take pot away from
everybody and Donald Trump's popping
pills,
I don't know if he's really popping
pills.
I should say this,
but what I've read is that what he's
taking,
what they believe he's taking his,
do you remember phen phen phen phen was
some shit that went,
went on in the 90s it was a diet pill
that they had to stop taking because it
was a super effective for people,
but it was essentially speed.
They lost her appetite and he stepped
back and everybody lost weight.
Do you remember that Diet pill?
I took that like when I was in high
school and had an eating disorder that's
similar.
There's all these things are similar
because they're amphetamines,
they're speed,
they're all,
they're all stimulants and there's one
of the ingredients in phen phen when the
two of them are combined together.
Phen phen is two different things and
see if he could find that story about
what they think that he's on.
It gives you delusions of glory of grand
jury.
That's the thing,
like literally one of the symptoms.
First of all,
think about the amount of energy this
guy had running for president giving
these longs teachers never seem tired.
Yeah.
Dot.
Rumer Donald doctor prescribed Donald
Trump.
Cheap speed.
Fucking fixer.
That bitch.
She's amazing.
Who made that picture?
Who's Jim?
Jim Cook.
You're a fucking wizard.
Whoever you are,
his neck looks like a fucking elephant.
Applause.
That made me laugh hard.
The orange is perfect.
It's like such an exact,
but just
exaggerate.
Just enough the eyes.
Okay,
you're enjoying this.
He looks like your rock salt lamp.
Got to be able to laugh while this is
going on and you can't,
you can't freak out.
Okay.
Rumors of trump's a predilection.
I love that word.
Predilection for stimulants first
started really popping up in 1992 in spy
magazine road.
You ever wonder why Donald Trump has
acted so radically at times full of
energy of manic energy,
paranoia and,
wow,
what does that word Garul lists
careless.
Darryl,
you ever use that Word Darryl?
This is like,
I thought like cheerful,
like garrulous.
Hmm.
Well your speed it up.
Well,
he was a patient of Dr. Joseph
Greenberg's from 1982 to 1985 at the
time,
Doctor Greenberg was notorious for
allegedly dolling out prescription
stimulants to anyone who would pay blah,
blah,
blah diet drugs,
which trump took a pill form and try it
drugs and also be fat because he's
eating a lot of terrible things.
Oh,
okay.
This is the stuff.
Okay.
Fen Phen,
it's called fin turn.
Rameen first gain notoriety in the U s
under the name phen phen a miracle
combination of phentermine and
fenfluramine another establish anti
obesity drugs.
The two of them together.
The only problem was with the patients
taking the drug began reporting damage
to their hearts and lungs.
Apparently the combination destroy the
patient's bodies,
so he's not taking both of them.
He's taking one phentermine mean on its
own.
However,
it's still prescribed.
Trouble with thinking,
speaking or walking,
decreased stability at exercise,
false or unusual sense of wellbeing,
insomnia,
nervousness.
And this is my suicide note.
Increase in sexual ability,
desire drive,
not true confusion.
Sure.
I mean,
so this is,
this is doctor prescribed?
Yes.
This is what I think.
Why wouldn't you just take out all,
well that's a good one.
Yeah,
but it's the same thing we bought
adderalls syphilis theory.
Trump adderall is essentially like
incredibly similar.
There it is a medical fear.
Many mental health professionals believe
the president is ill,
but one of the causes and untreated std,
apparently syphilis untreated
creates like,
like reddening of the face,
manic behavior,
uh,
the greater,
but I can't read this.
This face is Pale.
It's orange skin color.
Oh,
is that self tanner?
Yeah.
If you look at his eyes,
syphilis,
why his eyes are white like all around
his eyes,
like a raccoon.
There were white care.
Okay.
It's characterized by the development of
an ulcer.
Usually genital a few weeks in a few
months after sexual contact with an
infected person.
If the is not,
notice,
not a secondary stage of the disease is
seen in some patients weeks or months
later.
These patients may develop variety.
Thank you.
Have you,
you're leaning.
You're so upset cause I can't see
rajshree right.
I want to get to the um,
right behind you too.
Oh.
Can't swivel.
I hurt my back.
I told you that I hurt my back on your
fucking segue.
Shine.
Impress you.
I'm suing you.
Did following you.
We have video cameras everywhere in this
place.
Do you know how to use a bow and Arrow?
I'm not suing you.
Psychiatric disorder.
Neurosyphilis symptoms or neurosyphilis
or proteus.
Proteus changing.
Varying widely from one individual to
another.
Yeah.
Irritability,
loss of ability to concentrate.
Delusional thinking and grandiosity.
Memory.
Insight and judgment can become impaired
and he's got everything in there duking
it out inside of [inaudible] in the
fucking eighties,
from stormy Brown or whatever.
And now he's fucking got delusional
thinking and grandiosity.
It's stormy brown hair loss.
And then it also makes your hair like
fluffy and just exactly what you said,
fucking 90 years old,
you're going to lose your hair.
Uh,
there's like a history of Israel and all
those girls,
females.
Um,
anyway,
so I mean you can see why we're all a
little triggered.
Yeah.
But I don't think,
I think that people are reaching for
straws.
I mean he just got,
that was interesting.
The doctor that examined him,
examined him and said that he probably,
if he had a good diet,
he lived to be like 200 years old.
These couches,
great genes.
That doctor that examined him,
I was like,
this is this doctor's doctor.
The guy that killed Michael Jackson is
his doctor.
But here's the thing.
After he did that,
then Sanjay Gupta examine the actual
results and Sanjay Gupta said,
well,
no,
there's actually an issue here.
And the issue is something to do with
arteries and something to do with the
potential for a future stroke or heart
attack and he was going on.
He was basing it on actual test results
and obviously I don't know Jack Shit
about medicine,
but see if you could find out what he
said.
He's a common form of heart disease.
Yeah.
See a scroll up and see if you could
find what it said there.
Yeah.
Here it is.
This is what it is.
Doctor Ronnie Jackson disclosed trump's
basic lab measurements,
physical exam,
and the conclusion of a cognitive exam
known as the Montreal cognitive
assessment.
Additionally,
the president had an echo cardiogram of
his heart as well as the stress test.
Both scrubs is normal,
although is not a part of the official
medical records that were released
yesterday.
After further questioning,
Jackson also reveal the trump underwent
coronary calcium ct scan.
Now this is it.
His score was one 33 in anything over a
hundred indicates plaque is present at
the patient has heart disease.
According to trump's official records in
2009 his coronary calcium score was 34.
Does the president have an obligation to
be in shape?
I mean,
wasn't Robert Taft like notoriously
obese?
Like do you have to be in shape to be
the president?
I don't know the answer.
That's a good question.
Like,
do you,
are there certain boxes you have to
check?
Okay.
What I'm getting out of this is it's
Sanjay Gupta who is an unconnected third
party who's unbiased,
is going basically just offered these
coronary calcium ct.
And
what he's showing is the difference
between how it was in 2009 which was 34
2013 which is 98 and then 2018 which is
one 33.
You're saying it's increased?
Yes.
Basically doubled every,
it's bad.
Couple of years is bad.
Everything over 100 indicates heart
disease.
I'm not going to say anything else bad.
I'm worried I'll get death threats.
We worry that you want him to get this.
No,
I just,
I,
you know,
no one's on millions of fucking people.
Um,
you know,
but I think that's the other thing.
I think we're all sort of just,
just especially angry.
Like when you were talking about the
pendulum swinging so hard of of women.
It's like having to see this constantly,
everyday in the news.
This guy is,
it's,
it's hard.
It's really hard and depressing trying
to be objective.
This is what I find fascinating about it
is that obviously this is an aberration.
Like no one's ever seen something like
this before.
No one's ever seen a president.
There's a video that was on go to the
typical liberal instagram page.
There's a video of him saying no one is
better at blank than him.
And it's like a video that was actually
put together by people to mock him.
But the trump supporters actually love
it.
Yeah.
Play this because 24 things,
nobody is better at than trump.
Nobody can do it like me,
nobody.
Nobody can do it.
Like nobody's stronger than me.
Nobody has better choice than I do
better at the military than I ain't.
Nobody loves the Bible more than I do.
Nobody builds walls better than me.
Nobody's better to people with
disabilities than man.
Nobody's fighting for the veterans like
I'm fighting for them.
Nobody that's done so much for equality.
There's nobody more pro Israel than I
am.
Nobody more conservative than me.
There's nobody that respects women more
than I would be tougher on Isis than
Donald Trump.
Nobody's ever had crowds like trump is
crowds of people
and they couldn't corroborate it.
I know what it means.
Nobody knows more about trade than me
in the history of this country.
Has ever known so much about
infrastructure has Donald Trump?
Nobody can do it like me.
Nobody
do.
You know,
shed do the opposite.
They're like,
look,
I'm not a scientist.
I don't know that much about this.
Like are more humble about it.
I wish he wasn't president because I
love him.
I love what a character he is.
He's entertaining.
He's fascinating.
That's fascinating.
He has powers the problem.
That's the problem.
He's doing horrible to character and as
the host of a reality show,
he's a gem.
I mean,
it's such a free to be on a reality
show.
Great.
Sign me up,
but to be running the most powerful
country in the world,
I don't know,
maybe China is now is it's really,
really scary.
Well,
it's just fascinating,
the supporters
too.
Like I love reading his support his,
cause I'm always trying to figure out
which ones are Russians.
Okay.
How many of these are Russian?
Yeah.
A lot of them are women.
There's a few that are women.
Yeah.
But what are those women voted for him?
What's the deal with those girls?
Um,
you know,
I,
here's what I'll say,
and I have some family who voted for him
who are in,
um,
you know,
exile,
just working class.
And their whole thing is like,
we don't,
we don't care.
All we care about is the bottom line.
Our jobs.
It's actually kind of a luxury.
Um,
and that's,
I think a fair flaw with what's
happening with this.
You know,
women's movement conversation is right
now,
the people getting the most visibility
or fucking millionaires,
you know,
that's sort of the,
for the most part,
who's speaking up right now.
And like,
you know,
that's what time's up is for to
enfranchise people who don't have the
kind of resources to just be like,
you know what,
you're mistreating me.
I'm going to quit my job.
You know,
a lot of people can't quit their job and
they have to tolerate sexual harassment
and,
and whatever.
And they don't really have a choice in
the matter of they have to stay in bad
relationships because they can't afford
to get their own place or whatever.
But,
um,
but all they heard was jobs.
Their thing is like,
we don't care anything about his
character.
We think all politicians are assholes.
We just want jobs.
And that's what he said.
He was gonna promise and he lied.
You know,
I'm,
so,
they were just like sort of played well,
isn't there more jobs now than ever
before?
And isn't the unemployment as low as
it's ever been?
But he was,
but he was promised,
I mean,
health insurance,
I think they don't,
they also thought that they were gonna
get this like magical health insurance
reform,
which they didn't get,
but there was also,
um,
he was promising like coal mine jobs,
which is so crazy.
My family members,
like we're going to work in coal mines.
I'm like,
really?
So that's 50,000 jobs,
right?
And there it starting to become
obsolete.
So he promised kind of jobs that I think
the pipeline and shit like that.
So I think that,
you know,
and they just watch Fox News and they
believe everything that's been,
they think like liberal news is a lie,
you know?
So I think it's like the kind of jobs
that they promised.
And I know,
and I think that you're exactly right.
It's like,
um,
their whole thing is unemployment going
up is what helps women because more
women can get John.
But isn't it a case where,
when,
when you see like unemployment and how
more people were,
uh,
doing better than before and the economy
is doing better than it's ever been
before.
Hey,
isn't this like a natural cycle to like
wasn't it already charting in that
direction when Obama was leaving?
I was going to say,
I think it's the president that's like
four years prior.
That usually is what causes it because
you can't just like become president and
all of a sudden there's more jobs.
That's something that has to start a
little bit earlier.
I'm not saying Obama,
I don't know.
That's about it.
When Obama got into office,
everybody was blaming him like right
away,
even though that's probably what the
president before him.
Sure,
sure.
Here it goes.
So let me
gain a net.
Well,
11.5 million jobs,
the unemployment rate dropped below the
historical norm.
Okay.
4% average weekly earnings for all
workers were up 4.1% after inflation.
The gain was 3.7% or just production and
nonsupervisory employees after tax
corporate profits also set records as
the stock profits.
S and p 500 index rose 166%.
There was some story about how the tax
break that we got here because of trump
that people got,
um,
that California was going to somehow or
another impart some sort of a 10%
surcharge to counterbalance that.
But,
and I was like flat,
but then that they said it was all going
to like,
uh,
social programs.
I'm like,
well,
that's a good thing.
I'm all for paying more taxes if those
taxes can go to poor communities.
That's what I feel like.
I feel like if there's one thing that we
need to concentrate in this country is
people that are disenfranchised and live
in poor communities that don't feel like
there's any hope.
And then setting up community centers,
setting up some,
some education programs,
setting up but safe places where kids
can go and they don't have to worry
about gang violence and shit and just
making it safer for people and giving
them more opportunities to possibly get
out of that fucking horrible cycle of
unemployment and,
and,
and fucking welfare and crime.
And if so many people are stuck,
and I completely agree.
And when I think about that,
I'm like,
oh you know,
and this is just my point of view
because of what I come from and maybe
it's being a woman,
a female brain,
whatever.
But like when I hear that I'm like the
thing that perpetuates that cycle is
having kids too soon and having a lack
of access to birth control and education
and this administration is a huge threat
to that.
An enemy to that.
So I'm like what brain live?
Why?
What depletes you faster than a kid?
Was that just a straight up Republican
and pull this thing?
I'm so sorry.
I always have this problem.
We don't have it like I always do this.
Why?
What does it say about me?
Let me get like a fist.
Do any of your other guests have this
problem?
Okay.
Okay good.
I used to do it before I did a podcast
or radio shows.
It always yell at me cause I wasn't in
the mic.
But why is it thing,
it's always a republican thing to try to
deny women birth control to try to
restrict abortion.
This is always right
cause I think it probably boils down to
religion and I don't know,
I still can't understand why religion is
the reason that people think women have
to be cows.
And if I could have ever for religious,
this is what's so crazy.
Yeah.
Well he used to,
I mean I think a lot of it's kind of
like,
keeps conveniently now super pro life or
something.
Nobody likes the Bible more than I do.
Nobody hates abortion more than me.
I wish I could do,
I can't do an impression.
I was just thinking.
You don't,
you don't,
it's chilling.
I don't,
I don't want to hear it.
Last thing we need is more fucking trump
impressions at the comedy store.
I'm good.
Um,
but uh,
the burn has a really good one.
Really?
It's really,
it's really good.
I would not have seen that coming.
I didn't see it coming either.
He did it the other night and went,
Woo.
He nails it.
That's kind of amazing.
And he nails it.
Yeah.
I have to process that later as the
finger thing.
That's great.
I mean,
Alec Baldwin's is like fucking just,
yeah.
But um,
but yeah,
I think it's religiously sort of based
and uh,
and Hubris based.
I mean just the idea that women
shouldn't have control over their own
bodies.
It's just like,
why do you want me to have kids that I'm
not ready for it?
What seats are,
um,
economic system.
It means everyone else has to pay more
taxes.
It puts more people on welfare.
All the things that Republicans hate
did.
It's a vulnerability thing.
They like women to be vulnerable maybe.
Hmm.
Maybe.
And what they want control,
right.
Control over it.
Yet we have complete control over people
they'd never met.
Why do you want to control the uterus of
a woman that lives 10 states down from
you?
How does that
benefit?
There's a sick thing that people have
where they want to control people in a
lot of ways.
I think that's a lot of,
when you see people that are trying to
control people's language,
when you see people are trying to
restrict,
don't say this,
say this,
we're don't say this isn't a weird
instinct that we need to address.
When you are outside of ideology,
outside of you know,
political lines that you cross.
There's a weird instinct that people
have to try to control people.
It's just a fear based sale
I habits or thing that people do,
they don't have much control of
themselves and they want to control
their people.
And I think this is where bullying comes
from and I think this is where a lot of
what sexual harassment and just the
entitled meant the,
the way bosses behave when they're
employed.
Like this is one of the things about
Harvey Weinstein and I've found found
fascinating is that he would bark it as
employees and it would run and they were
terrified and ice date a girl.
And she was a,
when I first came to La,
wonderful woman,
beautiful,
perfect personality,
terrified of her boss.
She worked as an agent's assistant and
she couldn't have been an actual person.
Yeah.
And this girl would wake up in the
middle of the night,
terrified.
Sure.
That her agent that she was working for
needed her to do something.
She would freak out.
Sure.
She was like constantly worried.
And this guy,
I mean,
she made terrible money.
It was constant stress and she'd work
insane hours.
I mean they would make,
she would make like $400 a week and she
was working fucking insane.
This is before they had the rules of,
yeah.
You know,
you don't know what she really made.
I'm just guessing.
But she was always broke.
And then my questions for you or that
it's in Stockholm Syndrome,
super rail saying yes.
And then what was her relationship with
her dad where she recreated her
childhood circumstances?
It wasn't done.
That wasn't good.
Yeah.
The relationship and then the epigenetic
imprinting.
It's,
it's only till very,
very recently that we were not
completely dependent on men for our
survival and that you guys weren't
killing us in the street.
I'm like,
it's so recent in terms of human
evolution and um,
you know,
I did this movie with Neal Brennan and
uh,
we wrote a song called again called the
female brain.
And it's about all the shit cause I'm
obsessed with figuring out and you're so
good at delineating what's nature and
what's nurture,
what's a choice and what's not.
With biologically neurologically driven
and what's socially constructed.
I'm,
that's my fascination in life.
And like when all this stuff happens,
I'm always trying to figure out this
kind of behavioral stuff.
And then that we had talked a lot about
epigenetic imprinting.
So it's like even if your girlfriend at
the time had not gone through some sort
of trauma with a man,
her mom certainly dead.
And then her mom's mom certainly dead
and she carries that with her.
So all of a sudden you're in 2016 and a
man is yelling at you and it's like
flash back to 1850 when like one of your
ancestors was being fucking murdered by
a guy.
You know,
like we just don't think about that kind
of stuff.
But what I meant to say is,
um,
Neil had,
we used to have the storyline that was
about sexual harassment.
We ended up kind of changing it.
It's successfully strong and Blake
Griffin a storyline about her.
Um,
because women are generally for
consensus,
we get dopamine from consensus,
right?
Because we are physically weaker.
I know nobody wants to talk about it.
And when you mean by consensus,
what do you mean?
In terms of like if you guys are arguing
about something,
I mean,
we're on a show that kind of encourages,
you know,
healthy discourse and I know you guys a
little bit and I feel safe here,
but in general,
in a work environment,
I'm going to try to get everyone to
agree because 2000 years ago,
getting everyone to agree made my life
safer.
If I'm eight months pregnant,
I need protection from the whole tribe
and I want everyone to agree.
I'm going to pretend I agree with things
that maybe I actually don't,
don't make sense.
We get dopamine from harmony because I'm
less able to defend myself,
especially with men.
I need you to like me because I need
your protection.
Right?
We're not that different.
I mean,
200 years ago I needed your protection.
Like my brain has not caught up to the
fact that like it's illegal for you to
attack me and break me now.
You don't need anything though.
I think it means something to our
reptilian brains.
You know?
Legal part doesn't mean anything.
That's true.
No one,
no one's going to save you.
Totally correct.
That's correct.
You could kill me or whenever you
wanted,
but 200 years ago it was like,
you know what w w there was no phones to
even call it a report anyway.
It was just much more common.
Yeah,
I get what I'm saying today that like on
anyone saying that that fears alleviated
because there's laws against it as
crazy.
Totally.
Those fears are always there.
Completely.
Yeah.
My reptile brain,
just in my conscious brain,
I'm sort of like,
okay,
it's less likely that this is going to
happen because we all have this illusion
of being civilized.
You know?
That's all horse shit.
I get nervous when I interview Francis
and Gando after a fight,
like when I got,
when I had to interview him Saturday
night,
cause he's 265 pounds and six foot four
and he smashes people's heads and for
living and I stand next to him and I
feel like a little tiny person.
There's just no getting around that.
And here's the thing and that's why it's
like that.
He likes me.
I know he's not going to do anything to
me.
I see what you're saying to me right now
is what I'm trying to explain to people
that are like,
I'm nursing the Fuckin Women's moon.
Why are you guys freaking out in the
office?
It's not like we're talking to those
people.
It's,
it's like,
what are we going to rape you?
It's like,
yeah,
maybe I don't get an elevator's with
guys.
I just wait for the next one.
I'm scared.
We have tribal thinking.
It's in.
This is right now there's a tribal
boundaries that are being established on
the male and female side and people are
picking sides and there's a bunch of men
that are annoyed that people are talking
too much about women.
Yeah,
and there's a bunch of women that are
saying,
now it's my time to be a fucking crazy
bitch and go crazy and attack all these
men and take dad tried to go at all,
but there are some,
but there are so I know what I'm saying
is see,
see you saying that right there.
Yeah.
We are not trying to do this.
That's a crazy thing to say because
you're not all women.
It's all in together.
I'm not all men.
That's crazy.
Don't know anybody like that.
I do.
I don't who were on instagram.
People crazy.
Yeah.
I follow a lot of really insane people
on instagram.
There's a lot of,
like,
there was a woman that was,
she's like an editor for vogue or
something like that that said,
here's an unpopular opinion.
I am not at all concerned with men being
falsely accused of sexual harassment or
sexual assault.
That's irresponsible.
But they exist.
Those people exist.
There's the burn it all down people.
Yeah.
That fuck them or burn it all down.
It
doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
It's inherently tribal.
Sure.
This is a tribal thing.
Yeah,
and it's not,
there's no nuance to that.
There's no consideration of all the
different kinds of men.
I,
there was a lot of men that are
considerate and friendly and nice and
they don't,
and they're,
they're concentrating on themselves and
they don't want anything bad to happen
to anybody else.
But then there's men who like,
fuck these bitches.
Yeah.
Fuck all women.
All.
They're all whores bitch and they listen
to rap music like,
yeah.
I've been listening to a lot of like
really bad rap music lately.
Dennis,
one of the rare places where you could
still just be a straight up massage.
And then do you think,
and I'm always,
and I don't know the answer to this,
do you think,
cause I think porn definitely affects
our psyche and how we view w dehumanize
women just just right.
Especially young people watching it.
Do you think that a rap song going
destroy that Shit,
murder that shit,
beat that pussy up.
Do you think that that affects the way
men view women on like a cellular level?
It's,
it's impossible that it doesn't,
it's impossible.
When you have something that's
incredibly popular and you're repeating
the words to it over and over again,
I don't know what percent of an effect
it has on a 20 year old brain.
Right.
Whether it has a 5% effect,
you know over your parenting and what
your life experience is a bit.
Yeah.
All the various different variables that
come into your,
your psyche.
Like what?
What?
What makes you a human being?
I don't know,
but that's a factor.
It's a factor
and is in what is in what happens when
you hear beat that pussy.
Like is that,
why?
Do guys cheer for that?
Like aren't we also kind of on some
level wire to protect?
Why isn't it like I'm not,
I'm swearing too.
Is that a Tampon?
Tattoos.
What is that?
Oh it's a safety pen.
Oh yeah.
I'm trying to figure out what the fuck
that I do is on your wrist.
What kind of monster do you think I am?
What kind of monster would get a slow
burn it all down like a,
it's like a,
it's like a personal thing.
Okay.
It's too,
it's too much of a mom or you don't want
me to tell you.
Most of my tattoos are white.
I have white ones everywhere you are
fucking crazy.
Here's what I will say is that burn it
all down.
We'll talk that doctors or why I wanted
the payment.
I didn't want anybody fucking 5,000
tattoos.
You're covered.
Why am I crazy?
Cause you can't see mine to say saying
I'm not crazy.
I'm crazy.
I'm probably pretty crazy.
Yeah.
You hide it very well.
You channel it,
you manage it in healthy ways.
Yeah.
You get it out.
Oh,
if I didn't matter,
if you didn't work out every day,
would you just be monitoring and keeping
you in the streets?
Probably been to jail a long time ago.
You wouldn't be like breaking apes out
of zoos and fighting them.
I don't think that,
but I think I would have done something
really stupid a long time ago.
Yeah.
I,
but I think that there's a lot of men
that have terrible,
uh,
genetics and instincts and environments
that they grow up in and there's a lot
of violence in your life and you
will either find a way through that or,
yeah.
For me,
the,
the way through it was martial arts.
If I didn't find martial arts,
who knows.
Yeah.
And I think that is one of the best ways
for men to not be pieces of shit to
know.
Cause I think a lot of the way people
behave is to insecurity.
I think a lot of pride in other things
so that you have watch a San Duexis is
it give you dental help too,
but give you some security and give you
an outlet for your aggression and give
you some humility.
Like in martial arts you get humility,
you get strangled all the time.
You,
you learn humility.
You can't have any ego will you do it to
them?
They do it to you are,
but he does it and you hug and there's
like real genuine love and affection
between the guys that I do Jujitsu with.
It's very,
it's,
it's very intense.
It's as real as it gets.
And here's something,
sorry,
I just wanted to go back to that vogue
woman for a second or whoever that was
because it's like,
I think what I'm trying to do is
understand like what a man acts in a way
that's violent or whatever.
I'm like,
what's the root of that?
What's going on?
What happened in his childhood?
Like what's going on biologically are
genetically,
or like what has he been taught?
Like he was failed somehow.
If a guy feels the need to like rape a
woman,
someone failed him or he's a sociopath
and just should be locked up or as
mentally ill,
but like he saw it from his dad,
he learned it hurt people hurt people.
So it's like when a women says like all
men should,
I don't care if they're felt like,
I'm like what happened to her that made
her think that that's an okay.
That's her paradigm.
I probably met a bunch of fucking
assholes that something went wrong.
Yeah,
it was probably guys that she grew up
with,
guys that were in her life.
The sexual traumas.
Totally.
There's a lot of variables and I guess
I'm just trying to start a conversation.
It's like let's explore what happened
back then and how do we sort of stop
that shit from going on.
Whether it's like sexual abuse,
physical abuse,
whether it's like the messages we get
growing up of like,
and I don't know how you parent your
kids,
but the idea of like all I heard growing
up as calm down,
relax,
it's fine.
Be Seen that like the messages that we
give kids,
calm down,
relax before about what?
Anything.
Anytime I cried or I was injured or
whatever,
it was,
calm down.
You're overreacting.
That's what I heard as a kid growing up.
I think it did because overreacting,
it caused me to,
I mean,
I was a kid.
I don't know when we,
when kids,
kids should be assured like it's okay.
It's just a small booboo and you're
going to be fine.
Normally what kids do when they're
crying,
it's they're just testing to see how
available you are to them.
Right?
So when you go calm down,
everything's fine.
Let me teach.
I don't know enough kids.
They do that.
But then they also recognize that it's a
way that they can get attention.
So they will overreact on purpose about
them.
Yes,
they will have fits if they don't go to
the movie.
They like to see,
like if my two daughters want to go see
a movie and one of them wins and the
other one starts throwing a temper
Tantrum,
you gotta go,
look,
we're going to go see a fun movie.
Right?
Like you can't get pissed off next time
you'll get to choose.
Yeah.
This is crazy.
You can't stomp your feet and cry,
but she's seven.
Yeah,
totally.
This is like,
I have a chance explain
to her that he,
these feelings are natural light.
Yeah.
You're gonna win some,
you're gonna lose some,
but you can't hold on to that.
You've got to let it go and realize,
oh,
we're still going to go to go to see a
fun movie.
Right.
It's just not going to be this one.
It's going to be that one.
Right.
And you know what,
for whatever reason we made a decision.
Sure.
You know,
and we try to be as fair as possible,
but you can't have fucking temper
tantrums over and all the time,
oh,
we're going to the wrong restaurant
that,
you know,
kids do that.
Sure.
That's because they're little kids.
They're recognizing that there some
influence that they have some power over
you.
And then I'm going to see how much power
I can get.
Yeah.
And how much attention I can get and how
much I can play you.
So you just have to figure out the
difference.
I think for me,
I learned to invalidate my own reality
and stuff.
My field I ever met.
I remember a specific moment where I was
like,
you can't rely on adults.
They won't help you figure it out
yourself or don't have those feelings
are and validate those feelings,
you know?
And I think there's probably a that it's
bad parenting.
You know what your kid did go like if
I'm hurt,
don't tell anyone because parenting is
fucking confusing cause you try to
figure out what,
what bad parenting you received.
I was lucky in that my parents were very
busy so I didn't get a lot of parenting.
Yeah,
me too.
Same Way.
So it wasn't,
it wasn't like I got bad parenting.
I didn't get back there.
Yeah.
Don't let anybody who is mean to me.
I just got,
yeah,
it was alone a lot.
But then I found things to occupy my
time.
So that literally became like those
obsessions that I,
that I developed when I was young with
various things,
whether it was art or martial arts or
whatever.
Those things became my vehicles for
developing my human potential.
And that,
do you think you got a lot of eye
contact as a kid?
I never thought about that until just
now
fairly.
That's a big one.
Eye contact,
eye contact and physical touch in the
first couple of years
we're affectionate.
My family's always been affectionate.
It's always been huggy.
Yeah.
You know,
and I'm real hug you with my family too.
I think and I'm hugging with my friends
too.
I think that's super important and I
think it's also a very important to tow
your friends.
Like I tell everybody I love them.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
I mean I know I got really into John
Bowlby,
Siri of attachment because I couldn't
make eye contact until like two years
ago.
Like I would always kind of look here.
Yeah.
This is how I used to always look at
people and then I just recently started
making I and make,
it still makes me a little bit
uncomfortable.
It's like a muscle,
but I had something called infant
maternal disruption,
which is basically you just didn't get
enough eye contact.
So apparently the amount of eye contact
and doesn't know this because I'm,
cause I can't make it now.
But isn't that just an insecure guy?
I used to get real insecure.
I've talked about this before or talking
to a bank teller.
I'd freak out why?
I get nervous.
I was nervous,
but only bank tellers or just anywhere.
I remember being in the bank getting
ready to deposit a check and in line,
just two people ahead of me was the
times of the comedy story.
You didn't know if it will go through.
That was before the way before then.
It was before I did comedy.
Was it,
did it,
did it had anything to do with a man or
a woman?
No.
No,
it didn't matter.
It's just,
I just was nervous talking to people.
That's so interesting.
I like that too.
Like the couple of minutes you talked to
me all the time.
I get a little shade,
like I'm socially awkward in the
beginning and then I sort of settle in.
But I,
I do get a little shaky when I first
talked to people even now.
Well,
I feel that with you.
I feel like I have to say we're friends,
we love you.
We're friends,
we're friends,
right?
Yes,
we're friends right away with the porn
and the hoverboards you like this is
really shouldn't bring this up.
Like what are you talking get whatever
the fuck you want to say.
Um,
you know,
and I,
and I also have this condition called
codependence.
I'm working on it.
Um,
but I'm fucking dealing with it.
It's expensive to handle.
It's very time consuming to rewire your
brain around it.
But when I first meet someone,
it's like a,
it's like a chameleon response where
it's like,
um,
when you grow up in an alcoholic home or
if you have codependence the first thing
you do is you meet someone and you kind
of try to figure out what they want and
then you morphed to become what makes
them comfortable.
So I still have to fight that response
sometimes,
especially with,
especially with men and then with women
because though we didn't do that for
sure.
Like are you in a football are going to
be like who is this guy and how am I
going to make him like me?
That's kind of what codependence
well men do that with other men but they
also do that with women.
They'll become like what the woman
wants.
Like women will.
I see it a lot of times my friends with
the way they dress like the woman who
come along.
Yeah.
Well also the women are mold men.
Like women will get men in shape.
Like you should just lose someone
like in a relationship.
I just mean like when I first meet
someone my instinct is kind of like how
do I make an a specialty with it?
It has taken me so long to not be funny
when I'm not doing stand up.
Cause like the for my first instinct is
makes this person laugh,
make them like you and I kind of have to
like manually be like turn that shit
off.
You're not five and you're not trying to
get the approval of your dad.
Like not your dad
turn it off.
But what if you just see something
funny,
you're still free enough to just be
funny.
Can do that.
But it's like,
my motive is not,
I'm trying to make this person told me
my
all the time.
You know the people who are on all the
time,
just say his name,
his name,
genuinely.
Brian isn't trying to get anyone to know
he's not getting it,
but he's just really funny and he loves
being that Brian is at its best.
And I've said this before,
there's an innocence to it.
He's at his best in a group of people.
Correct.
Not on stage.
He's out of around 20 people.
If you've got 20 people and they're
going somewhere,
Brian's on guys.
Guys,
guys just want to show you something.
He'll just,
he'll just be this.
He's fucking,
I've never met anybody that makes me
laugh harder just in groups of people
other than Joe Diaz kills me.
But Joey Diaz is the opposite.
Joey Diaz is not trying to do,
he's just naturally,
it's not a performance.
I just wonder Brian callen knows the
difference anymore.
Like is there a certain point where you
don't even,
you can't even tell when you're
performing and when you're not.
It's like just tease,
morphed,
doesn't matter.
He doesn't care.
Yeah.
He has a bizarre ability to not fair.
If people were upset at him,
it's like he's got this weird almost
Peter Pan,
like way of moving through life.
It's cracked.
I am,
I am in therapy and a 12 program to get
the inner monologue of Brian Callan.
If I could just have an iota of the self
esteem that he has.
Do you do meditate?
I do.
I lost my dad last year and meditate
like suddenly and my meditation,
I started getting too sad.
Like I couldn't close my eyes for 20
minutes,
so I've stopped for the past like six
months.
But I'm trying because I need to build
those neural pathways.
Well,
I feel like you're always,
do you know that feeling when you're
running down a hill or it's super hard
to stop
this momentum?
It's like,
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
You're still up.
But it's fucking,
it's tricky.
That's how I feel.
You are like you're running on a slight
angle,
you know,
you're not flat.
Yeah,
it's not,
you're,
you're always like a little,
ah,
I'm fucking,
I am sometimes.
Um,
I think in the last,
yeah,
I agree.
I'm trying to answer in a way that,
uh,
makes you seem wrong,
but I realize you're,
you're pretty right.
And I think that also in the last couple
of years that we've gotten to know each
other I hadn't been doing is not as much
stand up.
And when I don't do standup,
I get a little manic.
I think that standup serves a really
important like release and Catharsis
purpose where I'm much more calm when
I'm not performing.
When I do stand up right here,
get it out right.
You get out those thoughts,
these,
these antagonistic protagonistic
thoughts,
all these deer weird little ideas that
are wrestling in your head.
Like you can put them into a comedy form
and then deliver that.
I'm on stage.
It's a very cathartic way of releasing
ideas sometimes.
And then when the audience laughs,
you know,
and you're like,
ah,
I nailed this.
I'm on to something here.
I got it.
And there's just,
I think that,
you know,
again,
not to beat the,
I come from a,
we as we all do tricky home and I think
that my brain seeks a con control or
even a false sense of control.
Soothes it.
And when I do standup,
you kind of get to have control for at
least the 20 minutes or an hour that
you're on stage and everything feels
like it's an order.
I know my place.
You know your place.
It is a very clearly defined rules.
I'm talking,
you're laughing,
you're laughing.
And that makes me feel really calm.
Whereas going through the world with
like,
I don't know who you are,
you're dangerous.
I don't,
you know,
like I have a hyperactive Amygdala,
so it's like during the day I'm just
very dysregulated and doing standup is
just,
I don't know,
I just feel very like,
I know where everybody's places and I
feel safe for that amount of time.
Do you get calmed down by working out
a little bit?
Because my motive for working out is so
fucked up.
It's not like,
you know,
I'm working more on like working out to
get strong and to get healthy.
But for the longest time it was like to
get skinny and to look fuckable,
you know?
So working out was like,
I was kind of hate fucking it.
I wasn't like doing it because I enjoyed
it or wanting to be doing it.
So I'm trying to sort of find a new
motive.
Um,
we'll kind of exercise.
Do you do,
I get bored and I used to work with a
trainer and I stopped and so I started
just started doing it myself,
like lifting and I've just want to have
a big butt.
That's all I really care about.
I'm just won an ass.
So I'm like,
used that machine.
Is it called the Jimmy John Vinci?
I don't know
the one that likes
Jimmy Dean each immedion sausage to make
my ass bigger than,
do you know what I'm talking about?
It's a,
it's a squat machine,
but it has like a little helper has
little claws.
What does that,
this machine is the,
uh,
the,
the rack where the squat goes up and
down.
It's just taught,
turn it forward to catch it.
Why don't you add to that?
Yeah,
that's a good machine to do.
It's good.
It's good to do on your own.
That's actually just,
Oh yeah,
that's a Smith machine.
Yeah.
That's what I do at the gym.
Cause those are good.
And then I do a lot of people don't like
those because you don't have to balance
them.
No.
The idea is that there's,
there's a benefit to all the stabilizing
muscles.
Like if you have a real,
uh,
a real bar,
I'm sure you do to add.
If I do that when I'm afraid I'll hurt
myself.
The Jimmy John Helps me to not,
I'm not like a professional athlete.
I'm just like,
should get a hug in pill form,
take it five times day,
whatever.
He just getting,
everything's going to be in here,
get a pill form.
But uh,
I was doing like soul cycle.
I was doing like spinning for a while
just because whatever,
there's a great episode of the
unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt,
man.
You ever watch that show?
No.
It's funny though.
I've seen a couple episodes.
Hilarious.
Gray went down for like two episodes and
I almost abandoned it.
Tell you folks if you're watching it
now,
because I've talked a lot of people in
to watching it.
When you get to like episode six of
season one,
don't panic.
It's sucks for two episodes and then it
bounces back wrong.
It's hilarious.
And they made fun of spinning.
Oh there's one with a nick kroll and
he's,
he's the spinach truck and I don't want
to give it up to any of that but,
but it's like,
it's a cult,
these fucking soul cycle.
Cycle and cry.
I'm not fucking kidding.
They'll play like sheryl crow or like
pain.
Like Neil,
Brendan always says that I have the
musical taste of a 45 year old divorcee.
I love an inspirational Kelly Clarkson
time.
I swear to fucking God.
Sheryl crow,
Alana's Morissette.
I will just get in there and you just
start crying because you were in a lot
of pain and you're working really hard
and you're just vulnerable and we feel
like it's okay to cry cause you're
sweating and it's like no one's going to
know sweater tears.
It's me and a bunch of book publicists
crying,
but Jim Publicist,
cause it's $35 a fucking class.
It's crazy.
You know that much.
I mean if you buy like a hundred
packages,
it ends up being like 28 I have a thing
called a Peloton bike.
Oh that's the,
no,
I tried it.
It's supposed to be amazing.
I tried somebody else's do a live spin
class with people.
We have it here.
So do you just spin it and you like it?
No,
they give it to me.
I use it,
but I have one here.
I can get in a groove and I can check
out and think about other things and
it's like a moving meditation for me.
That's how I feel about regular running.
When I run the hills I love running,
but now I'm running with my dog.
It's a different because I always have
to keep an eye on him,
but he's pretty good.
He waits and waits for me and then I run
and he's so much different than any dog.
She's just following now.
He's just running amazing.
Yeah,
he's great.
He's great,
but he's not at all.
My other dogs have been psycho so I've
had to have them on leashes cause they
would attack their dog dug holes.
I had a bunch of pit bulls so I'd run
with them and you know,
and my masters,
I just never ran with him.
He's too fucking big.
This thing is bad for,
it's hard on their bones.
He's limping a little bit too.
He runs around too much in the yard.
He loves.
Yeah,
he's huge.
They're too big.
There was sort of meant to just hang out
and I'm running really steep inclines.
Golden retriever.
Yeah.
That's great.
That dog is,
that's great for them.
Running with animals,
the best feeling.
But me and him have this crazy bond
that's like when we stop,
I'll stop on a run the hills.
I'll pause cause it's like,
you know,
I'm running this big sprint up to the up
the hill and then he'll,
he'll sit and wait with me and then he
just like,
I love you when they like jump up and
kiss me.
And I'm like,
I love you too buddy.
Like calm down.
But it's like he's so excited that I do
this with them.
He loves it.
We have grateful,
oh yeah.
This crazy bond thing going on.
Yeah.
That makes me so happy.
It's really intense.
But yeah,
I've always been like,
he's a sweet dog.
I bonded with them from the moment we
got him.
Yeah.
But we have this extra bond now that we
run three or four times a week.
Oh yeah,
totally.
We'll you're a pack.
Yeah.
A pack together.
And then if you're running,
you guys have a date.
He found some shit.
I don't know if it was his shit cause
usually shits in this area and he just
laid down on it,
started rubbing on it,
dog to hike and he came back.
He lie,
like let him go.
I was like,
all right,
let's see how this goes.
Let's see if this is going to end the
lawsuit for me.
And uh,
so I let him go.
He comes back,
he's covered in like,
he smells like,
like wharf.
I can't even explain the rancid smell.
I was just like,
what is that?
And he's covered in like,
he's got like stringy licks.
I'm like,
I said Spaghetti and then I keep
walking.
There's a dead deer.
He had rolled in a dead deer carcass.
Oh,
so you get all the water was just
covered in worms and guts and eyeball.
And I was like,
Oh fuck now I,
I'm,
you're up for adoption.
Weird dogs like they like smell because
don't they do it?
Cause my dogs,
um,
when a po,
coyotes,
coyotes.
Um,
when coyotes,
ah,
shit in my yard,
my girl roles in it.
Cause don't you do it so that the
coyotes think you're on the pack so they
don't kill you.
Ooh,
I think that's what you do at wow.
Fire up that Google and make sure I'm
not wrong.
Yeah,
they roll in the shit so that the coyote
doesn't kill them.
There's a guy I follow on instagram that
has a pet coyote and he hunts coyotes
and he uses this pet coyote help them
hunt coyotes.
I know like this person dogs and they
hunt.
Cut.
Well,
hunting coyote is important in areas
where coyotes attack deer.
Fawns and coyotes.
Is this in California?
No,
no,
he's,
he's a hunter.
I mean the guys that just a hunter
period.
One of the things that he's done,
he found a puppy,
a coyote puppy that had been abandoned
and so he adopted it and she lives with
them.
It's really weird.
Coyotes can attuned to human faces.
Like they're basically sociopathic.
They,
they're not like dogs.
You can't domesticate them.
Yeah,
maybe not true because this dog seems to
be very playful with him and like cause
biting his hand and I looked at and
then,
but not hurting him and these,
he's petting it and the dogs,
it's playing with other dogs,
you know,
but you can raise,
cause it's like it's a baby and work
with these,
this place wolf connection.
And essentially it's like,
I'm always like,
well which one's the most wolf?
Which one is the highest content of
Wolf?
Wolfen it like with the blood and
they're like,
it doesn't really matter.
It's back to the nature nurture thing.
It's that there are some wolves that
were raised by dogs that have more
doglike qualities and some dogs are
raise like waltz and have more wolf
light qualities.
It's like the nature and nurture thing.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
This Chi,
this is what does it got rolling and
feces.
They're really common and possibly dogs,
ancient instinct to mask his sent,
which then able to animal to sneak up on
their prey without detection.
Ah,
so you might keep her.
So all I guess dogs do it with other dog
poop as well.
But my dog doesn't roll in my other dog
shit.
Only Coyote Shit.
Why does it,
you know what I mean?
So anything or fucking tanks,
huge.
They're probably not worried about a
fucking coyotes hunt in fucking packs
and they learn are one and they surround
them.
And tell you the story about the guy who
worked at the pet food store.
I worked at a pet food store,
also worked at a veterinarian's place
and they got this dog in,
it was one of those giant pit bulls,
one of those like hundred and 20 pounds
and muscular damn pit bulls.
And it was covered with cuts all over
its body.
We're cool card,
hundreds and hundreds of stitches.
And so he asked the owner like,
what happened was,
I don't know.
He goes,
I came home and he had gotten out of the
yard.
He was covered in blood.
It was all fucked up because I don't
know what happened.
And so,
uh,
they stitch the dog up and then they
fall,
literally follow a blood trail up into
the hills where he finds nine dead
coyote,
his pit bull.
They lured him in and then the coyotes
ambushed him and he killed the mall.
It's,
he goes,
it was like Homie,
right?
That exactly.
It was like Vietnam,
dude.
He was like,
just next ripped open guts,
torn apart.
Arm snapped off.
He goes,
this,
this pit bull just killed the pitbull
had a head like a fucking fire and their
muscles are in their head.
Yeah.
It was a monster.
Don't I had my ear bitten off by one?
Yeah.
It happened so fucking fast.
I didn't,
I didn't feel anything.
Then you said it didn't mean mean to do
it.
Just paint didn't mean it.
It was like it,
it does.
I don't have to defend it if we talked
about it on the vodcasts.
Right.
So it's like,
but I just go fucking fast.
I didn't even feel it.
I felt no pain.
That's how fucking precise it was.
So they say about shark bites,
then you don't,
you don't feel the shark bite until you
realize your legs missing.
That girl Bethany,
she said it was like an orgasm.
It was like bliss cause so much dopamine
rushes to the area so that you keep
fighting like it actually felt good
thing.
I'm comfortable about a 13 year old
talking about orgasms.
Oh God,
we're going
to jail.
We're going to jail.
Maybe I'm,
maybe you're,
maybe I'm putting that in there cause I
want to fuck a shark.
Sorry.
Don't see me play.
I do feel myself walking on egg shells
around anything sexual all the time.
Now a woman,
I would say this right now,
you can say whatever the fucking next,
you know women are next and they
shouldn't be.
They should,
if women are predators and using their
power to coerce people,
they should.
If you see my Harvey Weinstein bit,
you haven't seen it?
No.
Okay.
I'll,
I'll see you Wednesday.
Yeah.
Wednesday.
Yeah,
for sure.
But I don't,
that's,
that's nonsense.
Any God,
well,
there are,
I know guys that have been victimized by
women at work.
It was a guy,
a tj.
Remember the amazing atheist was telling
the story about the woman that he worked
with.
Zoe's always grabbing his ass and making
them uncomfortable.
And she was like his boss.
He was real socially awkward and in this
fucked up situation.
But that's super rare.
And I think that this is a balancing
thing.
And then this,
this,
uh,
you don't want to thought it was the
most hilarious thing about the women's
march that um,
people were angry that these white women
were wearing pink pussy hats because not
all women have the justice because not
all women have vaginas because there's
trans women.
No,
women have that too because women of
color,
it's both their offensive to women of
color and Trans Women.
How many trans women were marching in
the women's March and
I didn't know they were trans based on
their appearance.
Calm Down Internet.
I know them personally,
so I knew that they would train and
Bluto oh,
sniff them out for
this fucking dude.
I'm a comedian.
There was a thread on my twitter that I
wasn't even involved with where these
trans people and these lesbians were
going at it back and forth and it was
fascinating because lesbians are one of
the few groups that don't feel
intimidated to talk shit to trans
people.
They're like [inaudible] against the,
yeah,
and they were saying that these trans
people are homophobic and these trans
women can't get it.
It was fucking crazy.
It was for days,
for seven or eight days that we're going
at it back and forth,
but essentially the Trans Women,
this is what the lesbians were saying,
that the va,
the violence,
the intersection,
no,
it's not the way you know the violence
between women,
women on women,
violence in relationships,
domestic violence.
The statistics were skewed because a lot
of it is trans women that were attacking
women that they were in relationships
with because these women that are trans
women,
they have the same behavior that men
have,
which the inclination towards domestic
violence check.
And so they were saying that and she was
citing statistics about how many of
these women that were the,
the,
the victimizers were not,
they weren't,
they would not specify their gender at
birth.
They were talking about their current
gender in,
which is like a weird thing now.
You don't have to like,
you could arrested if you're a
trans woman for beating up a woman and
they will say,
okay,
well you're a woman.
And they'll say,
yes,
I am a woman.
You're born a woman,
right?
It's none of your fucking business.
Like,
oh,
okay.
So there was this really deep,
that's fascinating because one of these
lesbians had started this with these
trans women was very educated about
these statistics and was,
was attacking these trans women.
And she was saying essentially like,
don't go round and say,
because you've been a woman for a
fucking year and a half,
they understand the struggle fuck off.
Right,
right.
And because you were just had male
privilege two years ago or whatever,
and you've had it your whole life.
What was that video that um,
that God,
that Comedians,
it's so I ran into him yesterday.
Kyle.
Don again.
Yeah.
I ran into,
on his twitter page.
I raise a thing that he did with,
uh,
with,
no,
it was bruce.
No,
Caitlyn Jenner.
Fuck.
That can change.
And I'm coming in here.
There's no pc shit allowed in here at
all.
Um,
but uh,
this,
this is it.
Hold on please.
Select from the beginning and give me
some volume so it will hold up before
you play it.
Before you play it.
No,
this is,
um,
so kyle dunning,
how'd he say his name?
Donald again.
Dot.
Kyle done again.
Did a face swap with Kim Kardashians and
Caitlyn Jenner.
And so,
uh,
take it from the beginning.
It's,
it's a,
hey,
how about this women's movement?
Ha Hr turn now baby.
You lived as a man.
Most of you had the bay [inaudible]
few sheer ish.
Bruce used to make me touch his penis
till he climaxed.
Yeah,
Time's up.
Me Too.
That was the you though.
Oh,
nice.
Can blame the Becca mentioned.
Nice.
What's your next question?
What was I wearing age?
Are you weighing?
It's super cat,
right Dash Donna Karan.
800 bucks.
That's right.
Fuck yeah,
it was worth it.
That's it.
But fuck.
Where did you find out his whatever.
Um,
no.
His instagram,
somebody sent it to me.
I think that's his twitter,
but somebody sent it to me on his
instagram page.
He does that.
I don't know him,
but he does a bunch of these in their
fucking hilarious.
Yeah.
He wrote,
he wrote an Amy Schumer's show.
It's really funny.
Really funny.
Hey,
do you remember back in the day he,
that cow comfort he did that cow
commercial back in the day was a chick
filet or something where he was like
dancing with a cow.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
We don't have to play that.
I come up with Chuck Blakeman.
Um,
but I just mean like,
it was something funny.
He's,
he's funny.
He's a tricep chick filet yesterday.
Why do you eat fast food occasionally on
Sundays.
Chicks please.
Fucking delicious.
But it's going to be too,
but I couldn't go on Sunday.
Terrible for you.
Five guys.
It's by,
can't use on Sunday because they are
open.
Oh baby.
Jesus.
Chick-Fil-A shit is fucking super
religious.
I'm going to go have an abortion in the
chick filet bathroom.
Don't do that.
Do you think that would upset any money
or we,
yeah,
I feel like I heard we're not supposed
to eat a chick flick into that you can't
eat anymore.
I was somewhere the other the other day
and I was like,
oh,
let's go to this restaurant.
They were like,
we can't.
That's a Mario Batali restaurant.
I was like,
I'll buck and can everyone stop raping
people so I can eat my favorite pasta
problem?
Monique telling everybody to boycott
netflix crazy hard.
I mean,
that's insane when we getting a half a
million dollars for an hour,
but it's like Mo,
for most people that's like good at Sane
fucking amount.
I mean that's an insane amount of money
as her comparing herself to Chris Rock's
not relatable,
she's not as famous.
There's a scale and pay disparity stuff
is tricky because if you get paid based
on the value that you bring,
you know else was going on that Kathy
Griffin,
Kathy Griffin was saying something about
Ib.
She did 23 standup shows,
23 standing ovations,
do a special,
she would be willing to do a special
bunch,
wants to make sure she gets equal pay
for equal pay for women and she was
making it a part of that like say no and
go somewhere else.
You know,
there's so many outlets now.
There's Apps,
there's fucking hoot.
There's so many places.
Just say no.
Here's the thing.
They pay you what they think.
It's worth it based on how popular you
are and based on how popular your
standup is based on what they think they
can get out.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's why Dave Chappelle gets the most,
that's why Amy Schumer got a lot.
She was selling out
arenas.
Monique's not doing that.
So for her to compare herself to those
two people,
it's fucking crazy angry and she's
basing it on her tickets,
like are their box office for movies
that she was in like,
Whoa,
whoa.
It's like you're not just getting paid
that amount.
You're getting paid when the special
areas that tickets are going to sell
because that's special.
It's streaming so crazy when they start
to boycott,
you need to book,
we need to boycott.
Netflix.
Could the head of Netflix who openly
lynch someone and not one person would
stop watching that?
They were in trouble though with the
Kevin Spacey thing.
They had to do something about that and
they did and they did.
They lost a lot of money on it.
Yeah.
They lost 39 million bucks.
Between that,
the Kevin Spacey thing,
they
rebel.
Yeah,
I saw them when we were,
when we were there.
Yeah.
Well,
that was where Gore vidal used to go to
bank dudes.
But I feel like that it had to get this
bad for people to be like,
you know what,
we're not going to hire these people
because it's going to,
it has to be like a bottom line issue.
Like I'm not going to hire a rapist
because it's too expensive.
Have you ever seen the Gore Vidal
William F.
Buckley documentary?
We're a details.
No,
no.
The opposite.
They hated each other.
William F.
Buckley was,
he was a British conservative guy who
was very popular during the day and this
is from the 1960s on television.
And they were debating back and forth.
Gore Vidal and William F.
Buckley,
liberal versus conservative,
but like on national television.
And it was like these really contentious
highly charged debates and it kind of
sunk William f Buckley's career.
Cause at one time Gore Vidal called him
a Nazi.
You called them a neo Nazi or something.
Something along those lines.
And then go William F.
Buckley said something called him a
fucking queer and I'll,
I'll punch your face up,
a sock you in your nose.
And you'll stay plastered,
like lost his cool on television called
them a queer on television and it was
like this whoa moment and William f
Buckley's career,
you get to see who really is.
Yeah.
You pressured like I love thinking about
what in 30 years or when we look back
and be like,
Yo,
I can't believe we used just fucking say
that.
You know like retard.
We used to just say retard,
but only the retards but not
just the human who does the word is not
the word is retarded means like to slow
the growth of something.
Retarded ideas,
you know like or like like okay,
like denying someone birth control.
That is retarded.
Retarded.
It's like socially retarded.
Tiding,
slowing progress.
Yes.
I don't think that's a bad word.
Yeah.
What I think is a bad thing is to mock
someone who has a disability,
but I don't think that you're always
talking about that when you're saying
that word.
I think we have a real problem with
language policing.
denying the use of sounds there.
So this is what a word supposed to be.
It's like you make a noise.
So I understand what you're saying.
I understand.
Like there's,
there has to be context.
Like I understand I have to,
it's supposed to be a sound that you
make so I can understand what you're
trying to convey and that's retarded.
And I go,
you mean,
you know,
that's missing a chromosome,
like,
it's like,
well,
that would be me saying that's down
syndrome though.
Oh,
that's true.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
I think it's figuring out what the
ideology is.
The word I did not know this happened
recently.
Someone said in a writer's room,
um,
she's uppity.
I did not know that that was a slave
term.
We all learned very quickly that that
was a term,
that's what it means.
Yes.
The ideology of it was to describe a
slave that was acting out and we learn,
oh wow.
I always thought up,
but he was someone who is like a high
Falutin like,
uh,
you know,
some rich person.
I thought it was just someone who is um,
or council Trent and would not
participate or who is resisting,
but it's actually has origins in it.
Same with like patty wagon is like
offensive to Irish people cause it used
to describe drunk Irish people.
Irish people don't care.
Trust me in one quarter of course it's
like non Irish people are the ones who
were offended and funny that one quarter
Irish,
I can't really say I'm Irish,
but if I was one quarter black I'd be,
you would be forever fucking Afro.
I would be a part of the community.
And then what's the other one?
There was another one under your thumb.
If you have someone under your thumb.
It's a rolling stones song.
But it was,
it used to be that was the thickness of
a switch that you could hit your wife
with.
It had to be,
it couldn't thicker than your thumb.
Yeah.
Like there's the,
like the,
is it ediology or etymology?
Etymology of,
um,
those words,
which I just did.
No.
Um,
do you know the term faggot where that
came from?
Uh,
cigarettes?
No,
that's,
oh,
that's right.
And do you know,
why did it turn into gay slur?
This is,
this will piss me off on Louis ck show.
They use this urban myth that what it
meant was that a bundle of sticks was a
faggot.
And so I'm a gay man was a faggot cause
they were a bundle of sticks and you
would burn them in a fire.
That's not true at all.
Did he know that?
I don't know.
It's convenient to ignore.
Oh you got to do is research.
It's not hard.
What a bundle of sticks was referred to
was a burden.
Some woman they would call a burdensome
woman,
a faggot because she was like a bundle
of sticks.
Very difficult to carry around.
It'd be awkward.
So a man who act like a woman was a fac.
Whoa.
That's what the term meant.
That's where it came from.
That's the no idea.
That's the absolute origins of that
term.
So when people say there was a gay guy
and Louis ck show that was saying that,
and I was,
it was him and Nick Depalo and Louie
were all playing cards together and
someone said some faggot.
And you realize why that's so offensive
is because,
you know,
they used to burn people.
There's no fucking history of gay people
being burned like witches.
You,
by the way,
even the Salem witch trials,
they didn't burn witches.
They drown them.
They drowned them and dogs.
This is how fucking insane the hysteria
around the dogs.
Two dogs in the Salem witch trials,
there were dogs were witches live is
mass hysteria.
Do you know why they think they did
that?
Why they think what,
why?
The whole witch trial thing happened.
Um,
uh,
religious fanaticism or got there was a
late frost and this has been proven by
core samples of the ground.
They had a late frost.
And when you have a late frost on wheat,
one of the things that happens is
bacterial growth on the wheat.
It re,
it essentially,
Ergo is very similar to lysergic acid,
very similar to lsd and cows were dying
and shit.
Right?
And they thought it was like witchcraft.
Well,
yeah,
there's a little bit of that,
but that could have been another symbol.
I'll just diseases hepatitis back.
But ergo is a psychedelic.
And so these people were literally on
acid and they were freaking the fuck out
thinking they were being heckled by
witches and they're paranoid was in
their mind.
Women,
why didn't they think men were being
witches as well?
I guess a couple of men,
men did die but and babies,
they kill a couple of babies.
She's just cries,
lost their fucking minds while they were
on acid.
But I think,
you know,
given the situation when men are in a
position of power,
which they almost always wore back then
and then something's happening to them,
they would go for the weakest thing,
which is probably a woman or a single
woman or a woman is weird in any way.
And just like that bitch.
I mean it's also just
that sort of annoying that now people
look,
this is a witch hunt,
this is a witch hunt.
Like,
without even knowing that that word is
actually something to describe when men
use to hunt women and now they're using
it as a way cause it's like,
I mean,
you know,
men thinking that we're like hunting
them or it's some kind of like mccarthy
I'm or something.
Yeah.
We'll witch hunt.
The idea is that you're looking for
something that's not really their
exactly.
Yeah,
Yeah.
You know,
and I guess I just don't know a lot of
people who are doing then.
Yeah,
I think there's a real problem we have,
like we said earlier about tribalism,
about being on trial,
naming.
It's a mass shaming.
When did you say there's definitely that
going on for sure.
But I'm saying what I'm saying is that
people identifying with all women or men
identifying with all men.
Yeah.
Like especially man,
I did it like I had this bit that I was
doing for awhile about um,
a bumper sticker that I saw in a car.
It said girls kick ass.
No,
it was like,
I hate that shit.
Some of them,
I,
some of them are lazy and even,
I mean,
we're getting into this too.
Have you seen the bit,
I do point.
The point is you can never have that
about men.
Like a guy have a bumper sticker that
said boys kick ass and be like,
pull the fuck over.
Yeah.
What are you doing?
What's in your car?
So yes,
I do have a lot of girlfriends who are
conflating,
you know,
empowerment with entitlement.
Hmm.
I it totally get it.
And I have a lot of girlfriends who
think they're feminists and they're
actually just assholes.
Like I have that,
I talk about this a little bit.
It's real right on stage.
If a couple of girlfriends who are like,
I need a man of respect me.
And in many respect me,
I'm like,
bitch,
you need to get those photos of you and
tank tops that say Rosie all day off
your fucking instagram before we have
this conversation.
Or not recognize who you are or,
but like I,
you know,
you then earn my respect.
You know,
you don't automatically get respect just
because you're a woman.
That's entitlement.
You know,
you still have to like watch a fucking
Ted talk and read a book every now and
then.
Like you still have to like be cool and
know what you're talking about.
So it's like,
you know,
I,
there's definitely some duds.
Well,
there's people that are,
you know,
they're now on the team that's attacking
and there's a tribal like,
yeah,
this is no different than someone like
the Patriots were fucking kicking ass.
Yeah,
that's,
that's tribal too.
It's the same thing.
It's a natural inclination that people
have,
but it's also at the same time,
like,
you know,
I think a lot of guys I've heard,
we look will,
you guys hate all men and you think all
men are assholes.
It's like,
for me it's actually the opposite.
I know a lot of really amazing men that
have cell phones stolen,
rich restraint that I'm comparing the
shitheads too.
You know,
like in your,
does
it say that though,
just or just what?
They're scared.
They're guilty.
They're saying that you hate all men.
No,
I get the people who are like,
you,
are you bitter?
You know,
feminists that hate men,
like you can't even say that they're
tribal.
Yeah.
You want to stand up for tribe.
Male.
Yeah.
Instead of just objectively looking at
this and well,
what's going on?
Well,
imagine being a woman,
man.
Imagine being a woman who's been working
in an office.
Yeah.
And dealing with this shit all of your
life.
Imagine being a woman who's been raped.
Imagine being a woman who's been,
you know,
how to walk down the street past a bunch
of guys and they grabbed her ass and
harassed or learn about the neurological
of that,
that
go on.
I,
he likes sometimes we can't speak out.
Sometimes we freeze like you said.
Um,
you know,
and I think it's just like nobody wants
to look into that research.
There are some women,
very few,
but there are some women that hate men.
There are some men,
I want to say,
so don't pull gender is a trauma
response.
Yeah.
That is a one person hurt me or a couple
people hurt me and I need to generalize
about all of them to give myself a false
sense of safety.
I have friends that have been divorced a
couple times and those are the trickiest
ones.
Cause those guys,
like they literally like they have this
idea that there's like a,
that the,
the women at the enemy and they take
your money and they,
they some new pretend they pretend they
like you and then eventually they turn
it on you and they get their lawyers and
they take your money and then I go,
what's going on with you that you keep
gravitating that woman.
Yeah.
That's my thing.
It's like what's going on with you that
you like you had no idea what people are
very different in the beginning of your
relationship with money is you people
have real personal sovereignty in the
beginning of a relationship.
I like interesting beginning of
relationship
you lock on like is this going to be the
person that makes me feel better about
life is just going to be the person that
brings me joy and this is going to be
the person that brings me lust and sex
and fun.
And then afterwards you get bored with
each other and then people get resentful
and Yup.
Yup.
And this is the thing about men with
money.
I've always said like when a man with
money as dating a woman who doesn't have
money,
then there's this weird dynamic like the
woman like it at first or some guys,
let me get it first.
Okay.
The man,
when the man with money is dating the
woman that doesn't have any money,
the woman is like,
Oh wow,
this guy's got money.
This is amazing.
But then when they get married,
she's got money to now it's like now
you're just another guy.
Like I'm a rich lady now.
Yeah.
Like now I have money,
like gone fucking divorces,
dude,
I'm,
I'm bridge.
Oh,
I see.
So,
and then there they get entitled the
money.
I would say I would never take money of
the guy of dating.
Well you had married.
That's different.
Yeah,
you're not,
I mean,
but that dynamic of the guy having all
the money and the woman being like a
waitress or something like that.
But that's a normal dynamic.
Yeah.
When it happens,
like men like it because like look at
me,
you know,
I have,
I'm so advanced in comparison to what
she had financially,
right where she is.
I have all these things that I can offer
her that she could never get on her own.
We've got to fly to Paris on a private
jet.
I'm going to blow your mind,
you know,
that kind of Shit,
right?
Yeah.
And then the woman marries his fucking
ass hole and then next thing you know
she is rich too.
She's got Gucci bags and a big diamond
and she's driving a Ferrari and she's
like,
you know what,
I don't want to suck this guy's Dick
Anymore.
I'm tired.
I'm tired of it.
I'm tired of the whole thing.
And then,
you know,
she's not impressed anymore because
she's wealthy too.
So she's not a wealthy guy anymore.
He's just a guy cause she's,
well
I see it there now equals and then he
doesn't have something that I can't
access on my own.
I don't need him anymore.
I don't,
I've never,
I've not had money before and um,
I've been hungry and poor before.
I guess I get that,
but I don't know.
Maybe it's just maybe things are gonna
change in terms of like maybe we'll look
back and 40 years and be like,
remember when 40 olds you just used date
broke 20
year olds.
Like,
I mean it's still going to have to
fight.
We're biologically wired.
You guys are biologically wired to want
to,
you know,
fuck women that are fertile.
I totally get that.
It might be a liability wired to want to
fuck successful or men that are,
that have their shit together.
They're more emotionally stable.
They're physically more together.
Yeah.
Are You my dad?
I've done it.
But this is not even just a dad thing.
It's just a,
a position of power like this.
Someone is like,
they've accomplished something.
Maybe that's looking to be the new
Darwinism is this is like,
I don't need to date a man who has
power.
I don't really need protection.
Right.
Cause we have alarm systems and I have a
lock on my door and whatever,
but we're still wired to seek men that
are Alphas and then have power and that
have resources even though,
you know,
we're not,
I don't think that's going to go anytime
soon unless we go full socialist.
Like we're not as vulnerable as we were
2000 years ago.
And you know,
yeah.
Well we're definitely,
I'm sure 2000 years ago,
men and women and had a much more
different dynamic than they have in 2018
yeah,
it's getting better.
I think overall we have less violence.
We have less crime.
We have less,
almost everything today than we did 2000
years ago.
And I think in,
but I think the amount of radical change
it's happening,
like we were talking about before,
between 1960 and today,
if we go another 50 years in the future,
it's gonna be even more insane.
But it just might be like,
like the got the people that thrive are
the ones that are able to have some self
control over their primordial brain.
So it's like you,
it's like I want a Ferrari.
Like I would love to,
but it just doesn't make sense.
You don't want to suck that Donald
Sterling Guy's Dick.
Do you know what I mean?
Totally.
It,
it seem worth it.
I love to eat pizza every night,
but I'll fucking die.
That's not hell.
I'll get fat.
You know,
you'll,
we'll just start to understand the
consequences of dating the person that
we are sort of primally attracted to and
just go like,
I know what that is.
That's what I want,
but I can't have everything I want
because I'm a fucking human adult.
I think there's also a real,
the way human beings react and the way
we even think and the way what we think
is acceptable and isn't acceptable,
changes with the culture.
And I think like,
it's one of the problems with going back
to like 1960 and being upset at some of
the way people behaved because it's
like,
man,
that is the way people behaved back
then.
We,
we know better now,
but to get mad and a man who uh,
behaved a certain way,
nothing.
I'm not talking about like drugging and
raping and stuff like that,
but certain,
uh,
20 years ago when it classic acceptable
sexist behavior from 1960,
that was just normal.
Yeah.
Like I think this is just a part of the
culture and people thought that's how
you behaved.
Now people are shifting and I think
we're,
and also I think one of the things
that's going on in this is one of the
things that's empowered the women's
movement in the powered a lot of other
movements is access to information.
It's radical.
It's happening so fast and it's,
it's inundating us and we have to catch
up to it.
It's like it's happening so goddamn
quickly that we,
we're just trying,
okay,
what does,
okay now?
What's not okay now what can we do?
What can we not do?
And access to each other.
Like never before have 10
women all assaulted by the same man,
been able to meet each other.
Well,
how else would we run into the grocery
store?
Hey,
were you assaulted by that guy by any
chance?
Like we were able to find each other
online.
Jamie,
where are you talking about Steve Corral
and the office?
Was it you that was talking about that?
What about you watched the old episodes
of the office,
which is not that long ago.
He was such a creep.
You can't really do that.
But he was kind of like bumbling,
you know,
like what was the difference?
I think the percepta sewed where a girl
shows up to sell purses and he's just
like,
makes a big to do.
Just like you can have the conference
room and guess what?
I just got this espresso maker.
Don't make me give it to you cause I
won't.
Oh,
do you need a ride home?
I'll give you a ride home.
But didn't feel creepy or did the ride
home thing was a very particular creepy
thing based today's world.
Right.
And I think what I know about the
English version,
I don't know what the intention was for
the American version.
The idea was to make him kind of
polarizing and it makes you
uncomfortable.
And He,
it's crazy that it wasn't that long ago.
Tangible.
It's hard to explain.
And I think this is why a lot of guys
were getting annoyed because when you
get granular about it,
it makes us seem like we're just being
crazy.
You Hug me at the comedy store and it
feels different than when,
let's call him Joe.
Blow hugs me.
There's just something creepy about Joe
blow and there's something not creepy
about you and I can't explain it and I
can't tell you why.
And I sound crazy and manic and history
doesn't sound because that's the same
way with gay guys.
There's certain gay guys and hugged me
where it's creepy.
There's certain gay guys that hug me,
hug me.
I'm like,
what's up?
Get my hug.
And it's all just warm and friendly and
it's cool.
It doesn't matter if the game,
but then there's other guys that they
hang onto me a little or they'll squeeze
my back a little and it just gets a
little,
little extra.
Females are kind of trying to,
the more granular stuff.
I know it sounds like I'm being crazy,
but I promise
proof.
And I don't know,
but the crazier I sound,
but it's just making me thirsty.
It's like a hug that lasts a little too
long.
I had a guy office
from a bad date.
It seems like you both eight eight each
other out and went down on each other.
It sounds like it sucked,
but then you're anonymous and then
you're,
you're 22 or 23 like this is like poor
judgment does a lot of cruelty involved
too.
Like somebody described it as revenge
porn for women.
Yeah.
Look,
this is not,
these are not comparable crimes and I,
I can't speak to saying who's guilty and
all that sort of,
I don't know what happened information,
but I
don't think that that this person is
coming forward equating it to rape.
I think women know that there's
different echelons.
There's rape,
sexual assault,
assault.
I mean,
look,
I don't know enough about it and none of
us were there.
But like I do know in my twenties I'm
not saying as he's as guilty,
again,
I don't know.
But in my twenties I had a lot of sex
that I felt I was coerced into that was
transactional sex that I didn't want to
have.
You know,
and this is something we talk about in
the female brain movie,
is that men are less able to read cues
or emotional cues on,
on faces than women are
so apparent.
So we have evolved to cry four times
more easily because men have a harder
time reading,
um,
emotional cues on faces.
That's why women crying until we crazier
because men are designed to sort of like
see movement and to hunt and to,
right.
You're not designed to sort of read
like,
oh,
is she frustrated or angry?
You know,
like,
have you ever been on a double date with
your wife?
And like,
um,
you think that hit her and the other,
I can't imagine you on a double date.
That was so weird thinking about it.
I've done those things really in the
very early stage.
But have you ever like,
yeah.
And you go on a double date and like you
have to fucking talk to the guy and he's
asking you a million questions about
hunting and you're like,
just listen to my podcast.
Why do I have to fucking do this for
free?
And then your wife is talking to the
other girl and you think it's going well
and the girl gets the car and you're
like,
oh my well,
and you're like,
she was such a bitch,
I couldn't fucking stand her.
And you're like,
it seems like you guys got along great,
you know,
like,
has that ever happened to you?
Okay.
She's just had it.
She just talks like if she,
if she thought something was bad,
she would let everybody know like right
away while she would just,
it'd be obvious or just,
just sort of like,
sometimes there's like,
um,
basically,
and we talk about the movie,
it's like,
it's just men are not as good at reading
emotions on faces.
So it's like,
if you were to say like,
Whitney,
how are you?
And I was like,
I'm fine.
You might just be like,
okay,
she's fine.
Let's move on.
A lot of guys can't understand that
there's a discrepancy between what I'm
saying and how I'm saying it.
And it's like about just reading,
like how muscles move on on human faces.
So it's like you can look up,
um,
sort of the difference and you know,
so I'm not defending men in that area.
I think that that an interesting
conversation that might come up at some
point as people who have autism are
really going to be fucked in all of
this.
People who can't pick up on social cues
because so much of this is nonverbal.
I fear that we're going to get to a
place where we're going to have to like
sign contracts and ship before we have
sex and stuff.
Because I,
you know,
I,
I know that in my twenties and I'm
freezing up just talking about it,
is that when men made physical man says
to me,
I would be giving off these nonverbal
cues.
Um,
and I wasn't saying no,
but my body was saying no.
And I'm not saying it's necessarily a
guy is supposed to like be able to read
my body language,
but that's what was happening cause I
froze up because of my trauma response
and I was scared.
And also we are conditioned to be
submissive to men.
Um,
I am conditioned to feel shame if I
don't fuck a guy in a certain amount of
time,
I spent totally the opposite.
I thought you would feel shame if you
fucked a guy too quick about a guy on
the first day and you feel shame.
But if you,
there's this sort of like unspoken rule
that you like kind of have to fuck a guy
on the third day.
Wow.
Yeah.
Oh totally am.
I do not think that Jamie's never heard
of.
So yeah,
I feel like guilt and shame and I'm
difficult and I'm a prude and I'm like,
would I ever,
yeah,
this might just be me,
but like every,
I mean every girl that I know that I'm,
maybe it's just my generation or
something and guy out there like,
oh,
I gotta do is just get three dates in
and we're in.
But think about all,
think about negotiate.
So just the,
just the tip is like something we joke
about,
right?
But it is based in the idea of
negotiating for sex.
So if someone is starting to say,
just the tip,
that means I've already said no,
and you're like,
well come on.
How about just a blowjob?
And then I'm like,
no,
just come on.
Just the tip.
It's like we joke about it but that
means it in negotiation is going on.
And then I've already said no,
and then you just get worn down.
And that's like transactional sex,
which I think women are kind of just,
I won't generalize about all women.
Um,
but I think some women are like sort of
like,
I don't want to have that kind of
transactional sex anymore.
And like,
like I feel like I'm being used as a
blow up doll.
And I think from what I understand,
that girl fell as,
she felt like she was like rush through
dinner and like went back and was just
sort of expected to be fucked.
And I think a lot of what's happening is
that men were promised something from
porn and women were promised something
from romantic comedies.
Men were promised that women like won it
all the time and women had been promised
that men like want to talk to us.
And I think these expectations are
clashing.
So I think it's a little bit of nature
and a little bit of nurture.
So a lot of it being media
misrepresentations of actual
relationships and that's the models that
people are acting on
maybe.
Yeah,
I think it's different for every person
because every person has a different
experience with sex.
Everyone has a different ability to read
faces,
everyone has a different nature and
nurture.
Everyone had different fucking parenting
problem with like sometimes you really
shouldn't be with that person and you're
there and you're there and what do you
do?
What do you do?
I mean I do,
I literally had sex before just to like
get out of there.
You're just like,
Oh God,
I don't want to argue with this person
right now.
But I feel like this first one feels
entitled to my body and I feel shame and
I'm embarrassed and like it's just all
this stuff that's really kind of hard to
explain and I think it probably is
annoying to the guy and I just like,
I don't want to be difficult and I've
been so gas lit to believe that I'm
difficult.
It just gets like really messy and then
by the time you figure it out you've
already had sex and you're just like,
okay
fuck,
can I have my parking pass back?
This isn't,
this is part of just being a human and
trying to navigate your way through the
fucking treacherous waters of just
social interactions,
sexual interactions.
I didn't figure it out until I was 32
years old.
I wasn't able to like articulate or
figure out whether I actually want to be
having sex or not.
So like my advice to all my guy friends
is do not have sex with girls and under
30 cause like I could not,
I didn't have the ability to even know
or say what I wanted until I was
for men.
A lot of men feel like if you have sex
with a girl who's under 30 then it's fun
and you can have fun.
But if you have sex with a girl who's
over 30 their biological clock is
ticking and the present time,
I should sound nice pressuring you into
this,
you know,
relationship very quickly.
What's your intentions?
Where's this going?
I want to know what we,
how we stand,
what are we yet
block or find another one.
There's tinder.
You can find plenty of women in their
thirties what have you like are you just
want to calm down and you swear like a
one.
Let's work this out.
I mean look,
we're going to have to like start
talking to each other I guess and like
setting expectations.
I know that sounds like a nightmare.
It doesn't,
it so much drama.
Oh BC.
But it's also,
it's like so funny.
This is totally like I,
I'm probably shouldn't say this,
but I was thinking someone was like,
yeah.
And then they had dinner and afterwards
they s whatever and she wasn't into it.
I was like,
that is already fishing.
I never want to have sex after dinner.
I think it's disgusting.
I'm like full of Lasagna.
Like I don't want anything in my body
after I've eaten.
Like I need a couple,
I like to have sex before I eat.
So He's going down.
You have to Fart.
Can we,
if we're going to,
if I'm just assume that not any sex
after dinner it's not consensual.
Super Normal.
Yeah.
I grossed out by,
Oh look,
if I just like eat chicken farmers,
like I don't want your,
you know,
stick together.
You know,
so I,
I just know that I've had a lot of sex
in my twenties that I didn't want to be
having that felt transactional,
that just didn't feel,
you know,
I think that,
who really wins and all those
prostitutes and sex robots.
I think
prostitution was legal.
See the problem we even would,
prostitution being legals is still
shameful.
It's still looked down upon.
Whereas massage keep your job,
you get to keep,
what did you get to keep your job?
I just say no.
I mean like if you're afraid of sexually
assaulting someone by accident or having
an inter personal relationship at work
and all this stuff that's going on,
just like having sex with a hooker,
like you're not gonna get fired,
they're not going to work
port you.
Yes.
But it's very problematic in that it
establishes this dynamic between a man
and a woman where it's very
transactional.
Yeah.
And uh,
yeah.
And then if you get accustom to
transactional sex,
it could make it worse when you're
actually what it's like then your
thought is just I just got to pay for
it.
Why?
Why would I deal with your bullshit?
I'll just be a grownup baby.
I decided to get my dick sucked all
I just mean if like men need,
cause I literally was thinking about the
other day,
I was like I would like someone to
invent like a virtual reality game so
that women can understand what sex feels
like from like,
it must be so amazing.
I was thinking about it
more amazing for guy than is for a woman
gets,
I'm like to be willing to like throw
away your career and take that big of a
risk.
That's not what it is.
No it's this what the way I described it
in one of my specials,
I said being a man is like having a
small 24 hours sperm factory with a very
shitty agreement with the union.
You got one delivery truck that's your
Dick.
Yup.
And you've got one warehouse and
packages are piling up every day
and you dig.
It's like these fucking packages
and the more it stacks up,
the more desperate you get,
the more you're willing to negotiate.
And then we do stupid things.
The nature of being a human being is men
are trying to get rid of calm cause
we're making it all day long.
All Day long we're making Kom were come
factories.
That's what we are.
And,
and when,
when a man doesn't have sex for a few
days,
you don't like I went through a,
I did an experiment on my website like a
few,
many years back where I didn't jerk off
for a month.
What happened?
It was like,
Holy Shit,
you get so desperate.
Like just touching people.
Just getting a hug.
Your Dick gets hard.
He's like,
this is bizarre.
Like,
cause most of the time guys handle it by
just jerking off you just like,
it's like a relief.
You just,
you're,
you literally a backed up.
I have pressure and you relieve it.
I don't know what it's like to be a
woman,
but one thing I do know is you're not
making a thing that you have to get rid
of you.
Like we have the end.
The difference between a guy being horny
on like day one of no jerking off versus
day 30 you're a totally different human
being.
You're a desperate,
you know,
and men who have had,
don't ever get touched and don't ever
get to have sex are extremely desperate.
And then we'll do almost anything that
we'll negotiate in very bizarre ways in
order to be involved in relationships.
That's why you see men that are quote,
pussy whipped,
like why are they pussy whipped and what
is that?
Well that's the only option they have.
These are weak people and the only
option they have is to acquiesce to
whatever desires and needs the woman
has.
You have to submit,
you have to submit,
and then she'll throw some pussy at you
like a dog.
It's some fucking scratch your way.
That's literally what happened.
And just thought of airborne posts.
Teddy has
all
these men had no lack of putsy in their
lives.
These which men?
Powerful men that are going down,
but this is whenever they want it.
Right.
But there's still,
there's well Harvey Weinstein thing I
read,
it
wasn't fucking,
I don't think he was a fucking addict
and I think he's a power addict,
sex addict and he's a fat fuck.
So he's a food addict.
Everything addict and power,
they baby it just stuffing things in his
body.
I mean he's a fucking
thing though.
Power and fame addict.
Then I'll tell you a story about bill
cosby.
I used to a,
I did this casino once and I talked to
this woman who was the one of the
managers that casino.
She said bill cosby would make the
entire staff watch him eat curry before
he would perform.
They would have to watch him eat.
It would come into his dressing room and
he wouldn't talk to them.
He would watch him eat and that's what
he would do when he wanted,
when he was eating his food before us
performance,
everyone had to watch him.
Then he had someone,
a security guard,
tuck him into bed at night.
They had a tuck him in,
so he laid in bed and they would talk
him in and then shut the lights off and
closed the door like he mental
illnesses.
That delusions of grand jury,
a separation
from normal society.
This thought that he is royalty,
right?
This is what I think.
I think the same behavior that kings
have.
You see that with dictators.
You see that with celebrities that are,
especially celebrities that again became
super famous 50 60 years ago,
like bill cosby.
You know,
he was famous 60 years ago.
Some people like Danny Masterson who is
young,
this guy's not,
you know,
the Danny masterson one is interesting
because he's a scientology
scientology.
I mean,
now I think he's left.
I don't know if they could embrace,
well this is Paul Haggis too.
This is one of the things that um,
they were saying about him because they
think that he's being set up.
I understand by right.
So,
yeah,
I know Leah Remini I heard her saying
that.
She was saying these are fake.
I don't know if that's true.
Danny masterson didn't leave like,
I don't think it was employee.
I've been hearing this for years.
The fuck didn't you cool?
Hey,
tell everybody this is my phone as a
phone.
Still look like that.
No,
if this is true,
but I'm going to tell you because I
don't want to,
you feel bad about it.
10 years from now I know.
Totally.
Like,
you know,
like I had heard creepy shit about him,
but it's like why didn't the young guy
like that?
Who can fuck anyone whenever he wants?
I have to do something like that.
And it's like,
I understand if you have all this,
the packages and the sperm building up,
but why can't you just jerk off?
Why can't you just fuck someone
consensually?
That's a different thing though.
The rape things at different things.
The rape thing is dehumanizing power
things.
It's like you,
you,
you say no fuck.
You don't say no to me,
I'm going to fucking do this to you and
you,
there's a that's not sex.
There's something way more.
Because if you can get hard when a woman
is crying and wants you to stop and
saying,
please stop,
don't rape me.
You know,
I don't want you to do this to me and
you,
you could still do that.
That's like some Viking Shit.
Really some because it's like,
I mean there could be some sort of,
obviously not to defend it,
but some sort of survival instinct in
being able to procreate with a women
who's not interested.
Like our biology has still not checked
for like overpopulation and the fact
that we no longer need to force
ourselves upon women to proliferate the
species.
There's gotta be some leftover ancient,
horrible rape DNA.
Cause there were a lot of people that
were,
I mean Genghis Khan,
his genes or in some ungodly.
Yeah,
pull this money.
Oh Shit.
Sorry.
I keep telling that neck again.
I can see,
I mean it's interesting like I'm just so
curious how things are going to evolve.
Like are the people that are going to
proliferate the ones that have the most
self control whereas it used to be your,
your masculinity or your value is
defined by how strong you are.
But how powerful and maybe the new power
is self control and restraint.
Well I think maybe people need to start
looking at each other as other human
beings instead of us versus them.
And I think that's part of the woman's
movement.
That's mission and part of the men's
side of it.
That's an issue I think we have to get
past.
Yeah,
I think
you know,
I'm Dan Harris from good morning America
was on the podcast the other day and we
were talking about in terms of politics,
he was saying toxic tribalism.
I love that term because that,
that,
that is,
that is across the board an issue in
this country,
right versus left.
Yeah.
That's an issue in this country with
basically everything.
Men versus women.
I think we have to just look at each
other as human beings and uh,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not pro men.
I'm not pro woman either.
I'm pro human and there's a lot of
really shitty men out there and there's
a lot of really shitty women.
Correct.
And it's,
it's a real problem if we lump everybody
into,
well,
women want this and women or not women
are not going to do that.
Women are not going to lie about rape.
Women are not going to lie.
Of course,
they are just like,
men are going to lie about it because
people are liars.
Great.
There's a lot of people that are just
poorly formed human beings and they are
now a part of a righteous tribe of
people that are attacking this other
tribe.
And it's like most people,
most women didn't March.
You know what I mean?
Right,
right.
Hey,
thanks.
In,
they did
50 million women were marching.
Most women did not give a fuck.
I mean,
but the numbers are pretty staggering.
Staggering.
But there is something interesting I
think about what happens when a group of
women get together.
Um,
cause I think that has,
at least in my experience,
especially like in the workplace and I,
and I was like trying to do some
research on this.
Um,
and I don't know enough about it,
but there's this thing called,
I believe it's called favoritism bias
and it's how women in a workplace
actually compete with each other because
they're afraid that the man is going to
think that they're favoring their
gender.
So they're actually shitty.
It's like Queen Bee Syndrome or
something where it's actually,
I've experienced a lot of competition
with other women because there was so
much scarcity for jobs.
It's like women just getting in the
workforce like in the last 10,
20 years,
this is kind of new.
So it's sort of like,
bitch,
this is bucking my job.
Oh Hell No.
So I think for women actually be on the
same team,
not to support toxic tribalism is
actually kind of a refreshing thing to
just be like,
like,
we're not competing for a man.
We're not competing for a job.
We're actually going to unite.
Like,
I think there's just some people,
there's something that kind of healing
about that.
At least for now.
Yeah,
I agree with
dot.
I've,
I've experienced women confiding in me
about other women in comedy and there
are so shitty and judgmental and
critical.
Yeah.
Like I've had women say things about
other women comedians.
I'm like,
what,
wait a minute.
You,
you really think she's like that?
Yeah.
Like,
yeah.
Oh,
she's a fucking hatch.
She's fucking terrible.
And this now I'm like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
She is funny.
Like,
what are you talking about?
No,
no.
They'll get really angry about it and
like,
like what is it like what is that like?
What is that?
I you complex.
Like there's,
there can only be one woman each show
and it's fucking her or me.
Or it's like,
you know,
and that's like a primal thing of
course.
Cause it's like I want protection from
the man cause of whatever.
There's all that sort of like old
primordial shed.
But competition between women like I
have,
this is the first time I'm kind of not
feeling that and it's kind of Nice for
the moment.
Um,
and we'll see.
Cause I,
I definitely know even though I think
that,
you know,
women are,
my concern,
I don't remember who I was talking about
this the other day is that basically
people are just going to stop hiring
women or stop hiring mixed,
like putting,
mixing people gender is up in offices
because it's just too scary.
I'm concerned and I'm concerned there's
going to be a little bit of a backlash
that guys are smoking dope.
It's not worth hiring a woman because
it's just going to be a nightmare.
I mean,
I know a lot of guys who are like,
I'm not,
I never hire pretty assistance or I'll
never hire a pretty girl to be in my
office because I'm just too scared the
way men are gonna Act,
which I think is a little crazy and
unfortunate,
but it's like,
but it's true.
No one wants to get sued.
Well it's not just,
no one wants to get sued.
You change the office dynamic.
If you have a really hot assistant and
she's walking around with all these
other guys in the office and the other
guys in the office like getting their
cups of coffee,
Matt,
Sarah,
her assistant and his men recognize that
like when I see a god it's like skis it
on a check and like Ah,
well if you have need an intern or
something and you have two women that
are equally qualified and one is
overweight and 55 and one is 22 and
gorgeous.
I don't know how that can be equally
qualified but whatever.
Like who are you going higher or you
kind of like,
Oh,
this is a liability.
Those could be a problem.
Well,
the 55 year old lady might be fucking
crazy and the know how to use dropbox.
She might be like really interested in,
you know,
some of the things that we're interested
in.
Make it easier to talk to her.
Or it could be the opposite of the 55
year old might be wise and you know,
very calm to be around it and you can't
like that's a good the individual.
I just need to mirror visual.
Oh my corporation or if your NBC or if
you're Disney or something.
I know there are a lot of conversation.
Yeah.
Oh,
like potential liability.
If someone has a 55 year old intern,
it's like,
well don't you need money?
Well that's a red flag in your money.
Yeah,
that's right.
I'm just,
I'm just a PA on the show that I was on
wants news 39 and I was like,
wait a minute,
why are you,
you're a PA and you're 39 and he turned
out to be out fucking nuts.
And he was on pills.
Oh No.
He was on.
He was like,
I'm like,
do I had to tell people I go,
do you see the way he's moving?
Like he turns really quickly.
I go,
that guy's on speed.
There's 100% and then you go,
they were like,
you sure I go watch him.
I go watch him.
He's,
he's twitchy,
swiveling around.
He's always talking.
He can never shut the fuck up.
He interrupts conversations and he
injects with these long,
boring stories of his own guys on speed.
100% 39 year old intern.
They fired him.
They want to firing him like right after
this one job that we did.
But that was like,
okay.
It was tricky though.
I've just,
I've talked to a bunch of people who are
like bosses and they're like,
fine,
I'll just stop hiring women.
Oh,
that's crazy.
And it's like,
Oh God,
that's cool.
Other kids,
they're just so afraid of getting sued
and they're so afraid of interoffice
relationships and that sort of shift.
So it's good backfire.
I am too free.
I'm to free to have input on this.
It's,
uh,
it's,
you know,
I think there's a weird dynamic when men
and women work together and you have a
really hilarious bit about it.
Like people working in an office
together like that,
they,
the way they interact with each other,
it's very strange.
Like honey badgers in a fucking cage,
which is weird.
Yeah.
It's like your,
this is your new family.
You're with
these people eight hours a day and the,
you're only asleep for five and then you
get,
you know what I'm saying?
How long do you see your wife every day?
No.
Two hours.
Maybe.
It's fucking weird.
Then you're in traffic for three,
right?
So like what,
what are you doing?
Like your life is these people and so
then your sexual situation gets weird
because helping bonds with them,
trauma bonds,
especially people
that never fuck,
but they want to fuck forever and they
just hug each other a little and they're
sweet to each other for it,
but nothing ever comes of it.
But they both know,
they both know they really want to fuck,
but they're not going to.
So they kind of a little flirty and a
little affectionately.
Yeah,
and they exchange the silly text
messages and then the wife will find out
this is an inappropriate emotional
relationship.
And you're like,
well what does that mean,
friends?
Yeah,
my work husband type thing.
I've had that sort of step off of that.
People do have,
I've had for people to openly talk about
their work husband,
I was like,
Whoa,
this is dark.
I mean I remember with Chris Taleah I
was doing a show that Chris,
Leah and we would spend all day together
every day and we were like having this
relationship.
I mean we're also acting his girlfriend
and boyfriend and we were sort of super
bonded.
And then because you spend all day
talking to each other,
confiding in each other,
sharing all these experiences,
by the time you get home,
do your actual boyfriend and you're
like,
can I?
And then you and then a month later I'm
like,
because remember when that director
yelled at me and they're like,
no.
And it's like,
I thought I told you,
you don't listen to me.
You don't understand me.
It's only because I've invested
everything and that other person that
all of a sudden it starts driving a
wedge between you and your actual,
so what you're supposed to do in
relationships is keep everything and
hold it.
It's like not ejaculating basically
emotionally.
It's like hold,
like if something crazy happens to me at
work,
I don't confide in someone at work.
I have to wait till I get home and bore
the shit out of my boyfriend.
I know this dude who is a very funny guy
and he brings this woman on the road
with them and when he brings this woman
on the road with him,
his wife freaks.
She does like it.
Yeah.
He's got a woman opening act and his
wife is fucking freaking.
Do you truly think I'm all for female
opening acts?
Obviously panicking.
Um,
do you think he has any interest in it?
No,
he just wants to,
I mean,
I support having a,
she's nice.
She's funny.
She's a good comic.
And he has her open forum.
Yeah,
I used to open for,
yeah,
I mean it's totally possible.
Yeah.
But,
uh,
you know,
it's that thing,
you're,
you're experiencing this thing that she
can,
no,
she's,
the wife is not a comedian.
That's another thing.
I think comics also have a bond that I
feel like the outside person can never
totally understand as well.
Way We joke around with each other.
Like if just the things you and I have
said to each other.
Yeah.
If we said these things in an office,
Holy Shit,
human resources,
it would both go to jail.
Yeah.
I think you'd go to jail more than me.
I am the worst.
But thank God that NBC lost it.
Those friends writers made a lot of
progress for us.
Okay.
So there's this famous lawsuit on
friends.
The writer's assistant sued
the writers in the writer's room because
they were saying something about the
actresses are sang like fucking them
with twigs or I think something crazy.
And um,
they sued,
uh,
the writer's assistant sued the writers
for sexual harassment and said I to hear
all this disgusting Shit and the writers
one,
because they said it was part of our
creative process.
But it is,
it certainly is.
And especially with Comedians,
we have said ridiculous shit to each
other.
Yeah.
I mean like,
well we just like guys,
first of all,
I callan Adelia mean that we will said
ridiculous shit.
Yes.
Like about each other off like like a
lot.
How loud?
Fuck you do the weird fuck you bro.
First of all,
I'm a top me,
I'm a top.
You're just going to give in.
You're just going to give in,
you know,
spinning your hand,
rub it on your butt and we will do that
to each other because it's how we make
each other laugh that we need something
really extreme in completely forbidden
to make each other laugh.
That's correct.
I think that is so fascinating.
I think Comedians,
we just have to go off the grid a little
bit every now and then.
Just too much porn.
Right?
Which is we need gags and fucking
Mascara running and fucking belt around
your neck.
We need the whole thing.
We need gagging to record the
conversation.
We have a certain threshold of
adrenaline we need or something.
Yeah.
When I get around calm it take,
it took
all long to delineate the difference
between like how to act around comics
and how to act around human beings.
And I also think like part of the reason
I'm a little manic when I first see a
comic,
it's like a puppy seeing its own or I'm
just like,
I know you just get so excited that I
get to be like,
ah,
bitch gon fuck.
Like I get to be.
Um,
yeah.
When you get to be free and I feel like
I spent all day just be more,
don't say that.
Don't say that.
Don't say it.
Yeah.
What's our,
our culture,
the culture of,
of comedy,
standup comedy.
It's very unusual.
Yeah.
There's the community.
It's one of the reasons why I'm very
protective of that community and it's
one of the things that I've thought was
the,
you know,
one of the things I've said about this
whole Louis C k thing,
I'm like,
he did it to one of us.
You did it to us.
It wasn't him.
Not that he should do it to anybody that
doesn't want to be a jerk off in front
of them.
Yup.
But it's,
I don't think fighters are interns on
our writing staff are the same as
standard too,
right?
Yeah.
It's like standups is one thing kind of
thing.
You just had a thing you'd like to beat
off,
pick on someone your own size.
You know what I mean?
Come shirt off in front of me.
Now as a 35 year goal,
I would love to see that.
And apparently he did do that to some
comedians and they laughed and he
thought it was funny.
Yeah.
Well there's some women that he did that
too.
It didn't come out and they thought it
was funny,
but there's a difference between Lake,
oh my God,
what are you doing?
And like,
stop please.
And I could lose my job if I challenge
you,
you know?
Right.
There'll be,
nobody is doing that now.
Right.
No one's beaten up.
Put them anybody anymore.
I think that's over most likely.
You still,
there's still people scared to talk.
Right.
I guess I just am curious what the,
what the neurology is of being,
being able to get an erection when a
girl is going stop.
The worst is if he didn't
get an erection.
It's like three quarters hard.
Like that's your thing.
If a woman goes like being humiliated as
an aphrodisiac or shame,
I think it's driven by shame.
Yeah.
There's a lot of weird shit to that for
sure.
I don't know.
I don't know where to go.
Like I was reading this thing about
pedophiles and like I'm not supportive
of pedophiles,
but like if you are a pedophile and you
have horrible thoughts,
there's nowhere where you can go unless
you can afford therapy where you can
say,
hey,
I have some really fucked up thoughts
and I want to fuck a kid.
And because shame is the engine a
pedophilia and you have nowhere to go.
Or if you dukes go somewhere,
people are going to go,
Ooh,
you're disgusting.
And they have nowhere to quell that
shame and stop the cycle.
Right.
And then if you act on it,
then you have more shame and then it
just makes it worse.
And most pedophiles were molested,
right?
So it's this just this fucked up cycle
and there's no social acceptable place
to go express that.
The wave in Aa you can go,
Hey I want a drink or I want to do drugs
or whatever.
There's no like place for them to go.
Yeah.
And it's also because it's your,
your thing is victimizing children,
right?
Like the zero tolerance for that
anywhere.
And people want to kill you.
They literally think you should be
killed,
but there shouldn't be a place like aa
or somewhere where you go to go.
Like how would we know if it even works?
That's the problem.
I know what works.
Bullets smell what's in your head,
what's in your head work.
Correct.
Someone's a kid.
Fuck.
How do you feel about the fact that if
you are a pedophile that means someone
molested you and you weren't.
You were a victim at some point as
victims become perpetrator.
So it's like how do you break that cycle
without just constantly shaming people
cause then you shame them into isolation
and isolation is where shame thrives.
Maybe one day we'll have some sort of a
form of therapy that can literally erase
inclinations and that can erase surgery.
That fucking takes out.
Oh that's what they were trying to do
right when they were like,
yeah,
great,
bring those back.
Like what ever you have to do with a
drill and fucking,
but it's like,
cause when you see,
I mean I was reading about the dark web
is the deep web or the dark dark.
I'm a hundred years old,
but like 90% of it is child pornography
and you're just like,
there's so many.
Like what the fuck it makes me homicidal
hero cop.
This guy was like a hero cop got his arm
blown off and it was like being,
and then they just caught them child
porn like Oh fuck no fucking vegas
shooter apparently had a bunch of child
porn.
Not surprised.
Yeah.
You know,
so it's like,
but like to stop that cycle is just so
it's like the same idea of like jerking
off on someone and being turned on by
them being scared,
being sexually aroused by a woman,
being scared.
There's something fucking going on
there.
And I dunno if its nature,
if it's nurture or if it's fucking
viking shit.
The pedophile thing is also,
it's such a forbidden topic that no one
even wants to express any sort of
sympathy for those people at all.
You don't want to be thought of as a
pedophilia sympathizer.
Correct?
Correct.
It's almost like a thing that you can't
fix.
Like they're the,
the recidivism rate is so high.
If there's a way to,
if it's an adult technically and
addiction,
I mean I think it's probably a mental
illness or if some sort of trauma
therapy because those people are
traumatized.
Right?
So if you're addicted to cigarettes,
yeah.
And uh,
you go through therapy and you kick them
and then you get back on the cigarettes
10 years later,
I don't care.
But if you're addicted to fucking kids
and then you live and then another kid
gets fucked because you couldn't keep it
together anymore.
Yeah,
I'm not,
I'm not willing to take that risk and
that's,
that becomes a real problem.
Especially someone who has young
children.
That freaks me the fuck out.
And I like most fathers who are hearing
my voice thinking about this right now,
I want to murder.
Yeah,
I just want to take that person out of
the food chain.
And that's,
you don't want to take that risk.
And I guess the one thing I would say is
like,
people you know have a lot of sympathy
for children who are molested or victims
of pedophiles until they grow up.
You know,
like a lot of women who are victims of
that ended up manifesting as the women
who can say no or the women who are
like,
you know,
traumatized and,
and freeze up and stuff like that.
But those women hypersexual that's the
other thing.
Torn stars.
A lot of women that get involved in the
adult industry were molested as
children.
Like a giant percentage.
What I say is all of them.
I don't want to say it's all of them
cause I know there's a lot of women that
do it just because they enjoy it and
that's totally cool.
But there were a lot,
there was,
there was some survey they did once,
what?
Back in the day.
And it was some alarming number.
Right.
A lot of people can never come to the,
to come to terms with that.
I was talking to a therapist who was
saying something about,
um,
plastics.
A lot of people that get crazy plastic
surgery do it because they were molested
and they're trying to change their face.
So when they look in the mirror,
it's not the person that got molested.
What they thought about Michael Jackson
and really?
Yeah.
That was one of the big theories about
Michael Jackson is his father abused
him.
Yeah.
You know my theory about Michael Jackson
telling me,
don't say it again,
tell me everything.
I think he's a Castrato.
I think he had his balls removed.
I think that's why his voice was so
high.
That was a common thing that used to do
with singers.
Really?
Yeah.
You ever heard of [inaudible] music,
but is she going to teach Whitney
Cummings?
They used to do that with opera singers
more than I do.
You know a lot of shit.
No,
I'm not to eat cookies while we're doing
it.
There's no sugar in those.
I'm so hungry.
Yeah.
There's very little,
those are no cookies.
They have very little sugar.
The glycaemic index on those as
extremely low,
get hungry.
I don't understand it cause my body
burns fat.
I eat very little carbohydrates.
Like this morning I ate eggs and a fat
beef.
So you never have life sugar spike or
sugar dips because you don't eat.
You have any spikes?
No,
I'm eating fat most of the time.
I mean he fat in meat.
That's what I eat.
Mostly.
God,
I need to just regroup here.
I need to start from it's way healthier.
It's way better cognitively.
This is what I don't get mentally this
way.
I take four naps a day.
I don't think any now.
It was always so fucking tire.
Well I'm on Beta blockers to,
I think that's a whole other thing.
But you're on Beta blockers,
Beta blockers,
Beta blockers.
I get really bad migraines and it's
hormonal.
But I think I figured that out.
Uh,
I lead a blockers are supposed to keep
you from getting nervous.
Yeah.
It stops like adrenaline,
I think from what I've understand,
I know a lot of archers use that test
for it because when you're on the like
an archery competitions and the nerves
will make you shaky.
So I produced a lot of adrenaline and
cortisol at the tiniest things cause I'm
a fucking trauma surgeon.
Every damn hug.
Women don't want to hug you.
I'm a fucking bad.
And so I was getting really bad
migraines because of my neuro chemical
spikes.
I would get too much adrenaline and too
much cortisol when I get nervous.
So I take two Beta blockers a day.
I'm a catch Jesus.
You had your balls cut off today would
be your place,
the way you're developing.
They do it to a boy when they're very
young.
There's actually recordings of cast
Trados from like the early 19 hundreds
see if you can get that.
What surgeon does?
Jamie got us pulled off youtube before.
Oh,
did it?
I'll pull it from there.
So,
oh wait,
because it's like um,
child porn.
No,
no,
no.
Because it's a,
because the recording,
it gets flagged by Youtube as being
their proprietary or their property,
their property.
And so anything that you use that
someone else's stuff can get you pulled
off of youtube.
You know like there's a shit load of
people out there that have like these
nature videos.
There's a big one we get,
it gives us pulled all the time.
Yeah.
People that own things for it.
Like the way you would license
something,
you would,
you could do something like that or you
could give them your ad revenue,
but you'd have to give them like all the
ad revenue from a show.
Yeah,
it's insane.
So like if we played a clip from the
office and we played it and you could
see it on the show,
we would totally get flagged and pull
them.
And if it happens more than one time,
you can lose your whole channel.
You could argue it that it's fair use,
but you don't have a license to do it.
And if you're making money off of it,
it might not be considered fair use.
So listen to this sound with this sound
is that we're hearing,
and Jamie,
what is the name of this?
This is a young man who had his balls
removed and one of the things that
happens to them as they get older,
they,
they never really develop masculine
traits.
This guy got fat because he had no
testosterone,
no testosterone is no balls and so they
have this haunting high pitched,
almost female but not quite sound.
And it was a preferred sound.
So much so that they would take children
and sell them off and they would get
their balls cut off at a young age.
So they would develop to be cussed.
Strados can't handle things.
Yeah.
This is my thought about Michael
Jackson.
I think Michael Jackson's voice was so
high.
It was so high pitched and like falsetto
was so pure.
I really,
I mean no one's going to know.
I mean there's no way to know,
but I'm a retard and I have my own
thoughts.
These are,
these are my thoughts.
The surgeon who did that surgery after
he dies,
why aren't I coming forward and getting
$5 million for this story?
Because that surgeon's going to go to
fucking jail.
You do that shit in America for saint to
took a kid,
cut his balls off.
You can't do that.
It might not even be real.
I might just be a stupid person.
It was a dumb idea,
which is more likely.
No,
I think it's a pretty good explanation.
I mean weird,
right?
Children.
They didn't sound anything like that.
You hear Jermaine Jackson saying he
sounds like a man.
Michael Jackson never sounded like come
down.
Yeah.
It was all weird.
Fishy.
The well,
it's also the abuse that he suffered as
a child and his incredible connection to
children.
This bizarre connections you get
stunted.
Yeah.
What?
Jamie?
The doctor that killed him or was in
jail for killing them wrote in a book
that his parents had him chemically
castrated.
Oh,
like taking those real,
sorry.
I mean that's what he wrote in a book.
I'm reading on some New Zealand new sub.
I don't know how
I could they do that.
They done that to trauma.
Lester's they've do.
They do that to trauma loss is to giving
them the option.
Oh,
so that you don't know Michael Jackson
chemically castrated by parents claims.
Dr t this is my fucking theory.
Damn,
and I'm writing.
I Bet I'm right.
Well,
the also his children were in his
children,
right?
He's a heterosexual man,
but heinous things happen to Michael in
his lifetime that actually changed or
had him morph into who he thought he
was.
One of those things,
according to Murray,
was his parents are arranging for his
chemical castration.
His testes were never remove,
but injections were given to Michael
Jackson to maintain.
His voice is high pitched voice of a
child that went long beyond puberty.
He places much of the blame for
Jackson's extrordinary but difficult
life at the feet of his family.
I fucking knew it,
so let me ask you.
It was right.
That stops testosterone production like
what's given to kids on are
transitioning and that sort of thing.
You're done.
That's why he was so skinny.
He never,
when he was a child,
they did that to him as a child.
Teen boys can you still go?
You still grow.
Women are tall.
You're tall.
You're taller than me.
Lot of Gmos.
That's why.
No,
it's just a different genes that didn't,
it doesn't stop you from growing tall
stops your muscles from developing.
Oh,
but and,
and then what does that have to do with
the vocal cords?
Cause something about your vocal cords.
Testosterone changes your voice.
That's why when a woman turns into a
transgender man,
their voice becomes a different food.
Is that legal?
No,
it's all legal.
Chemically castrate though.
It's fucking crazy because that's the,
that we talked about this in Roseanne.
It's doctors,
right?
If that doctor's right.
And I bet he is right.
If you wrote about this.
I bet he's right.
He self published it too.
Just what does that mean?
No one's giving them bucktail cause the
fuck's gonna give it a factual book deal
to the guy who killed Michael Jackson
idea.
Hello.
No,
they didn't.
They took it away.
Oh did they get there and he lost it.
He lost his book deal.
When the thing came out about a Hetero,
him thinking that it's okay for young
boys to have sex with gay men.
Not Great,
not great,
not a great brand.
Community has a different take on that.
Yeah,
they have a different take on it.
Then the straight community,
the idea of gay,
young gay boys having sex with gay men,
it doesn't bother them in the same way
with a lot.
I'm not,
obviously I'm not speaking for the
community and I don't want to
generalize,
but the reactions that I've had from gay
friends that talk about it say it's way
more common.
Huh?
Well that was the Bryan singer thing
that Brian Senior had those parties at
his house.
We had a whole pool full of fucking gay
kid
and Morrissey also demanded Kevin Spacey
about it and I'm like,
it's a difference.
Yeah,
exactly.
Like how like how do you know if you're
17 and like we were just talking about
the power dynamic.
How do you even know you're trying to
figure out who you are.
You're looking for a father figure or
you abused yourself.
It's like we just,
we don't know until they grow up and
figure it out in therapy.
If it was really conceptual.
Yeah.
I mean it's weird that we put this
arbitrary date to like 18 arbitrary,
right?
Well you can go to war now you're 18
like what?
I figured out it's 32 who I was when,
when she should be allowed to vote.
I say 50.
I say
didn't really,
um,
yeah,
I mean it's so it's like,
I mean,
you know,
should you be allowed to drive?
I drove like a maniac when I was young.
I just never should have had a car until
I was like 23 years old.
When should you be able to drink?
When should you be to at all,
if at all?
Yeah,
it's a good question.
It's terrifying.
And once you be able to have kids,
that's a good question too because you
only do it for a certain amount of time
and by the time you can't do it anymore,
that's when you finally know what you're
doing.
I feel like I'm 35 years old.
I finally am qualified to be a mother
and this is when you stopped being
physically capable than nuts.
Do you have a couple more years?
We can still shoot one out.
I have,
I have my shits on ice,
so I think I might have,
I might have more time,
but you have to find someone that you
would really raise a kid with.
Very different.
I have to find the perfect nanny.
No,
I have a guy that I think is a plus and
if he's not,
I'll just give the child to you.
You seem to maybe doing a pretty good
job.
Raise them,
raise them in the forest.
I mean,
and then you said it's just like it.
That's a very real fear.
I'm finally for the first time like,
Oh God,
I have to get my shit together on that,
but then I get super scared about this
world.
I'm like,
do I want to bring kids into this world
today
with all the books and medicine and
shit?
People were shitting kitchen floors.
That's why we're here to have water in
20 years.
Yeah,
we'll have water.
we're going to figure this out.
Can you be drinking salt water,
panicking,
freaking out.
But that's also why we correct things.
I think the technology ingenuity and I
also think is ironically as it seems,
a guy like Donald Trump as president is
going to really activate people.
They're going to start moving in liquid
at this fucking women's March.
Big Part of that is having to grab the
pussy president had to get this bad in
order for us to wake the fuck up because
we were all zombies.
Sleep walkers.
He's the reason why those pussy hats
that by the way,
whoever's making a wind fall off those
goddamn puts me out.
They should be thanking Dora people down
there.
Sally knows how to make pussy hats like
me.
What if he is behind the selling of
that?
Yeah,
no,
it was amazing to see all the
commercialization of it and everybody
capital I know
going to make us much more appreciative
of the environmental protection agency
and then the,
the,
all the restrictions at Obama put an
offshore drilling if anything goes
wrong.
Yeah.
Cause he's just opened up offshore
drilling everywhere.
You know that,
right?
Yeah.
Do you know what he's done and what he's
done?
I've heard that he's done a lot of
really crazy things with the environment
and with state,
with um,
you know,
uh,
whether it's bureau of land management
areas or um,
uh,
W W I don't know which,
which organization.
There's definitely state land that was
public land that's now being diminished
to state parks.
They're now being diminished and they're
opening them up from mining.
They're opening them up for extraction
of minerals and resources.
Yeah.
And all this is close to rivers and
watersheds and all these different areas
that are very important for different
ECOSYS tines.
Terrifying,
terrifying stuff.
In terms of the future,
Delaware,
well,
there's earthquakes in Oklahoma all the
time now that never used to happen.
And all that's directly attributed to
fracking.
They're drilling these giant holes in
the ground and pumping all this water in
there and fluids and all this shit they
used for fracking.
It's,
it's,
it's going to energize people and get
people to understand that the,
there's real consequences to just
thinking about money and yeah.
Also how ridiculous it is that a guy who
has more money than he could ever
fucking possibly spend is only thinking
about money in his thigh is in his mind,
he's thinking about America.
He's thinking about people prospering
and getting jobs and this not,
but clearly it's not just that,
it's clear it clearly there's some
personal profit that's being extracted
from all this.
And of course,
yeah.
Well,
yeah,
it's like his people,
it,
his hiring,
you know,
and look,
and I love Oprah.
She's a delight.
But for the left to go like,
let's have old purvi president and bcs
twitter page.
This is our president and Kendra letter.
No,
our president.
no,
no oprah.
Let's hire another celebrity who isn't
qualified to be the breath.
Wasn't it oprah?
I just wasn't telling anybody.
Do you guys remember the secret?
Remember the fucking secrets?
Yeah,
go back.
And when oprah was telling everybody you
could have anything you want,
you just kind of imagine it
like,
well,
like fuck,
are we watching?
He's just,
it's not great to also be like,
hey,
let's have this other celebrity be
president.
Wonderful Lady in her fault.
I don't have anything
problem with Oprah,
but I just think what we should have is
someone who is extremely educated,
who is incredibly nuanced and well
thought out opinions and things and
someone who's got a really good grasp of
what it takes to run it.
Yeah,
let's stop electing rich celebrities to
run our country.
Tried it didn't work.
It didn't work out so well.
Well you know,
or an oil
man.
Yeah,
maybe it worked out if in the mining
industry
and then it's like just tricky.
It's like the idea of being like,
I don't think oprah should be our next
president is like,
well you're sexist.
It's like Jesus fucking Christ.
You're racist.
No I'm not.
It's like we should be able to say we
don't think certain people are
qualified.
Stop yelling at me.
Do you read your comments on instagram?
Should I just stop and you never do so
smart.
Rarely.
Very rarely.
Sometimes they'll look in and I'll see
someone that's a dick and I'll just
block them.
That's like what?
Cause I tried to like engage and like
try to like see what's going on but the
kind of shit or just too insane,
it's not worth that.
You just put out good things.
Try to be nice.
And is that a crazy person or is that a
person that masquerades as being sane
and then behind closed doors?
It's crazy.
It could be both.
A mix of both.
Could be both.
Um,
did you ever hear about that guy that
got fired from reddit and he was saying
awful shit on reddit and posting all
these terrible things and they found out
his personal identity and they uh,
went after him and then got him fired
from his job and it devastated his life.
I think I was married with kids and it
takes life completely fell apart.
Yeah.
People enjoy being a con anonymously.
They enjoy it.
One of the things that I found on
instagram,
if someone says something really
particularly heinous,
you'd go to,
their pays are almost always private.
They're almost always have like a
blocked page because they're cowards.
There's just a lot of like very deeply
unhappy people that will lash out at
anybody that's in the public spotlight
like you.
Especially a woman.
Crazy question.
If a man this happened to someone I
know,
if a man is engaging with relationships
with other women on the Internet as a
character,
is it cheating?
No,
it's just he's picked,
he's having a character's.
Yeah.
Well who is he an artist is you're right
or no,
no.
Didn't have,
you know,
just sort of pretty adrenaline free job.
Yeah.
He's probably fucking completely bored
out of his mind and it gives them a
chart.
Is it like a video game?
Cause I was like,
this feels kind of like a video game in
a little,
in a little bit of a way.
It is.
It's role playing.
You know,
it's like a simulation.
Right?
And a little bit way it's just being
deceptive.
Right?
Maybe it's fantasy wishes he was someone
different.
Yeah.
Like is that if your wife has online as
a different person aging with men and
the pictures of her own pussy,
that's when it gets weird dicey.
Right.
Pussy flying through the air.
Literally,
you know who's here.
This is what's going to win flashlights.
I wonder if the same of flashlights,
it's going to go on robots.
That's what's going to win sex.
Robots.
Totally.
They're closing in to your point about
the right,
do you think that that also works a
muscle of to humanizing,
yes.
Yeah,
and also changes your reward system.
Like instead of like learning to be an
interesting charismatic person who's
caring and kind and reaping the rewards
of real relationships with people that
care about you and you care about them
and understanding real true love instead
of that you're fucking this robot I not
like,
is it cheating?
If he fucks a robot,
like I can't have that fight.
I can't,
can't do it.
Did you fuck
the robot or not?
I can't have that fight.
I can't do this.
What do you know?
Did He fucked the rob telling me the
truth?
Look me in the eye and tell them you
didn't fuck Siri.
I can't.
Is a robot bad but a fleshlight okay.
Yeah,
cause there's no head.
If there's eyeballs,
it gets very dicey.
Fake robot.
The robot is just skin here.
Is She prettier than me?
I just want to make sure the robots have
wrinkles.
A couple of crow's feet.
Yes.
I don't want them being to it.
We got to make sure these robots,
Ooh,
we got it.
They giggle.
They laugh at your badge.
You have to make sure these robots
aren't too pretty.
They gotta be ugly.
It's not going to happen.
I'm going to be hot as fuck.
They're going to be perfect.
I don't like this one bit.
You posted that thing of that robot
jumping
schedule.
Many of them carry.
Was she that episode of Black Mirror
though?
One metal head.
The new ones I haven't seen.
The new one.
New Season of black mirror is amazing.
Insane and one of the episodes has a
row,
a bunch of robots that are going after
people and it's called metal head.
I don't want to say anymore.
It's terrifying because very realistic
and t incredibly realistic and probably
represents something that's going to
exist in the future.
Or maybe it's going with the other way.
I'm to be like,
baby,
can you just fuck the robot tonight?
Maybe I'm tired.
That's when you know it's over eight,
two months.
Send them over to the robot that was on
your side.
Please don't,
don't impel Milo's maybe.
Maybe you'll allow him to fuck a robot,
but the robot has to look exactly like
you have a spare.
We'd get the robot.
We'd order it.
It would come in and be like,
is that what I look like?
And you'd put your hand up and just like
a mirror.
It would put its hand up and you'd both
like move perfectly in sync.
It was up to age with me though.
It would have to age.
It would have to get older.
When I get older to have to get wrinkles
and gray hairs and shit.
Trying to through the dirt look worse.
They're all Asian.
Did you see the Woman Grace Woo at the
barn?
Hello?
Is that a dick?
I've never seen.
No,
I didn't see a woman at the march.
What actress named Grace Woo who talked
about sort of the Fed,
the Fetis fetishization of Asian women.
Get over a pitch.
She's bragging.
That's what she's doing.
Everybody just had to fuck.
I'm so tired.
That's my thing of fucking free the
nipple.
I'm like,
only girls with great tits won a free
the net ball.
Now you're just,
you're just bragging.
Yeah.
No,
no.
Women in their forties or like,
let's free the nipple.
It's all like hot checks,
you know,
see what they're doing.
Yeah.
I don't want to free the nipple when he
comes this,
wrap this up.
Once you move you out.
February 9th,
the female brain.
It's about all of this shit.
Yeah.
It's about all of this sort of stuff.
Where would it be?
A,
it's going to be in movie theaters and
then it's going to be on Vod.
It's like,
uh,
got Blake Griffin will Sasso is in it.
Yeah.
Neal Brennan is hilarious.
Hilarious.
He's slick.
Steals here.
He has a scene with Blake Griffin where
he plays his physical therapist and it's
fucking hysterical.
I could not cut it.
Um,
it's really great.
What the Cummings Ladies and gentlemen,
give her a big hug.
Oh God.