Ah,
Josh is ABS.
We're live.
Hello mate.
What's up brother?
How you doing?
Good.
I've been all over the place.
You have it all over that,
but I'm wondering,
don't.
I'm not even in a huff post live
anymore.
I know you're wondering.
I'm a wonder here.
We,
the people now I'm all the way to
people.
The way I like calling myself
unemployed.
I think it's just more.
I think there's more.
It takes more to just say that you're
unemployed until you're like,
well,
I've got a lot of projects going on.
I've got a lot of fingers,
a lot of pies.
And I'm like,
I'm freelance now.
But aren't you self employed?
Yeah.
So that's not unemployed.
No,
but I like fucking with people.
Oh,
you make them feel sad for you and make
them feel because people,
people want you to immediately say like
that you're doing okay and unemployed
makes you sound like a bum.
So I like starting from the lowest
possible position.
You should tell people that you're going
to get a trailer and a,
you're going to travel across the
crunch.
You get one of those things dragged
behind your car is going to live out of
it yet,
and the national parks,
the mall wakes.
I don't have a full time job that strong
of my accent skin and get pale.
I'm just dammit nickname,
nickname.
Here's my trailer.
I haven't had a job in 15 years.
You can't go from Australian accent too.
Just did it.
Americans did it.
I just did it on allow that many people
say that things are impossible.
Joe Rogan,
but I'm here to prove them wrong.
Isn't it interesting?
How long have you moved to a place
you're not allowed to adopt the accent?
Like if an American moves to England,
like remember when Madonna,
she was only there for like six months.
She started talking like this and
everybody's like,
bitch,
fuck out of here.
Like we know that people talk like that
and we know it's a style of.
It's an affectation.
You decided to talk like that.
You don't have to talk like that.
You could obviously,
when you watch British actors play,
Americans do a brilliant job of talking
in an American accent,
like the walking dead people.
When people find out that rick is,
that he's,
he's from England,
from England,
the girl Maggie,
she's from England.
Everybody from fucking England.
Yeah.
And I'm in.
A lot of people don't know that those
are aussies as well.
If they're doing all over the American
accents.
How often does Russell Crowe and don't
have an American accent and imagery and
uh,
what's his face?
Fucking Batman.
Christian Bale.
He's Australian English.
Same Shit.
Don't get me started on the differences
between New Zealand.
Isn't Australians as well?
Does this whole thing about who fuck
you?
This is the same spot,
right?
Conduct condo.
It's about as different as Canada and
America.
Not really.
Not very rarely.
Barely close enough.
Uh,
there's a lot of dispute between the two
countries.
About which one that has to cut.
Mel Gibson.
Mel was,
I think born in New Zealand and there's
some bullshit about whether the reason
American Australian or New Zealand you
can have him as long as he's not
Australian.
Everybody loved him for awhile.
He was so good.
He was awesome.
Just couldn't keep it together.
No wellbeing,
a wildly antisemitic,
racist.
Um,
religious nutjob doesn't help.
Do you think he's a crazy person though?
I don't know whether,
whether that means anything when you're
that famous.
Of course it does.
It always means something.
I mean,
being that famous doesn't discount
certain biological realities of brain
function.
I think people are bad.
Livers or livers go bad.
People get lung cancer.
People without a doubt developed brain
diseases.
Whether or not it's a psychological
disease,
meaning is a disease of thought
processes and taking you down bad roads.
Those bad thought process become
ingrained and you continue them over and
over again out of habit or whether or
not he's obviously an alcoholic,
right?
So that's a real issue.
He,
um,
he's had some problems like tech,
lung cancer for example.
Obviously the things that you do to your
body going to have a large impact on
whether or not you're likely to get lung
cancer.
Sure.
And similarly,
I think that living in the rarefied
atmosphere of being incredibly,
outrageously famous probably put grooves
in your mental pathways that predispose
you to being odd.
Good point.
Yeah,
definitely.
And as you get older,
when things start to fall apart,
you know,
physically and psychologically and
maritally and you know,
when he was with that crazy lady,
I mean that's what that is,
is like the ultimate three court.
It's not midlife,
it's three quarters life like dilemma.
Yeah.
And how many people do you surround
yourself with when you at that level of
superstardom who were willing to call
bullshit on your bullshit,
right?
Like I think a healthy famous person.
We will know them as people who are able
to keep their head screwed on because
they still surround themselves with a
posse who were like,
ah,
get outta here.
What are you doing with this?
You've got a Latin mass still doing the
pre reformation Catholic,
like liturgies up on a hill in the
Hollywood hills and you're talking about
how Jews caused all the wars in the
world.
Get it.
What are you doing?
This is why people like buddy cop
movies.
Because in a buddy cop movie,
Danny Glover would straighten them back
out,
he'd be like,
come on man,
get it together,
and then he will pull it together and
you stop being crazy what?
He's by himself on a fucking mountain
and Malibu's screaming at the help
yelling at his Russian guy,
what's the name of his character?
And more open to doing what Mel Gibson's
and rigs rigs.
So Mel Gibson needs a danny glover.
The way that mountain riggs did.
Well,
he needs Danny Glover,
the actual Danny Glover,
because if you pay attention to Danny
Glover's twitter feed and his social
media feed,
it's all about like helping people out
and charities and spirituality and
consideration for the earth.
And Danny Glover has got a really
interesting.
I'll follow him.
He's a very open minded,
intelligent guy from the few things that
I've paid attention to.
I think Danny Glover's like paying
attention to the world.
They should be together for real.
I love,
I love it when people who you admire,
his craft you admire,
grow into being something more than
that.
And like sort of spiritually
enlightened.
It was like when Garry shandling died,
uh,
he had become someone who was super
interested in really interesting things.
I mean,
he was,
I didn't know.
I didn't know much about them.
I didn't either until I was following
him on twitter when the day that he died
I went to his twitter page to see what
his last tweets were and I saw that he
was following me for some strange
reason,
which makes me,
made me feel like all the more kind of
close to him and started going back
through all of his old tweets and he's
just interested in spirituality,
all kinds of shit that you and I are
interested in.
I didn't know him.
I met him like re very briefly,
like,
hi,
nice to meet you at the comedy and Magic
Club.
Never really got a chance to talk to
him,
but God,
what a funny guy.
Larry Sanders show was amazing.
I mean two of the most groundbreaking
sitcoms,
like all of the,
all of those sitcoms that now like
modern family and everything all have
the same.
Like,
this is a pseudo documentary and these
people are,
for some reason talking to the camera,
it doesn't really make any sense
anymore.
Like why is this documentary being made
about these modern family people?
How long has this documentary?
Why not always like it's been on for
nine years or something?
Where's the documentary crew?
Why are they talking to the camera dot?
It's the whole conceit has broken down,
but all of those shows owe they're
genesis to garry shandling,
to the fact that he did the Larry
Sanders show,
Larry Sanders show and it's Gary
shandling show.
He had some great stuff.
Really great stuff.
So what's this shit about facebook?
I just walked in here and uh,
and you,
you told me that there are these pieces
about how facebook workers are admitting
that they routinely suppressed
conservative news from the facebook
newsfeed.
Yeah,
I actually got it from Steven crowder.
He sent it to me and then I looked it up
and then I saw it was on Gizmodo and I
was like,
wow,
this is crazy.
Like this enforcement of a liberal
liberal ideas.
Former facebook workers says we
routinely suppressed conservative news,
so,
uh,
they would keep conservative news from
trending and they would,
uh,
they would inject stories that weren't
trending.
They would inject them into the trending
stories if they match their ideologies.
I mean,
this is so dangerous and upsetting for
me even if you are a complete,
like liberal fascist and,
and you don't believe in freedom of
speech or freedom of ideas.
But Jamie had a very interesting point
was that he was saying,
but when you look at the believers,
like the Justin Bieber fans,
they overwhelmed the trending to the
point where twitter became the Justin
bieber show and then twitter had to go,
okay,
all right,
settle the fuck down.
All these little 16 year old girls are
finger banging themselves and slamming
their fucking iphones and trying to get
this guy,
you know,
and try to pay attention to this guy
constantly.
Twenty four hours a day.
Those believers are out of their fucking
mind.
But that doesn't mean.
But what did twitter do?
Something about that.
And Actually de Justin Bieber tweets is
that long time ago,
like two or three years into twitter
starting out.
There's 10 trending topics I believe
that I remember is like seven out of the
10 were all Justin Bieber.
This I love Justin Bieber,
whatever it was at the time.
I forgot to bring that up with Dan are
back from the arcs and the black keys
when he was here because he'd got into
it with believers like they got into.
They got mad at him and done all the
people you could just in sheer numbers
it's like,
it's like taking on a fight with an army
of fire ants.
You're just not going to win.
You know what's interesting?
They get mad at you if you are older
than them.
But if you use twitter,
like one of the things that they love to
say like you fucking old man.
Why are you even on twitter?
Like as if my generation invented it.
What they're trying to do is they're
trying to.
They're acknowledging this is a stupid
behavior and they would assume that
you're old enough that you realize that
the stupid behavior and you should be
better than that.
I'm allowed to be an immature little
bit.
John Fourteen.
What's your excuse?
Just that there's something to that.
There's something that is a part of what
they're saying.
Part of the technology and the
ridiculousness,
the difference between de prioritizing,
believer,
tweet hashtags and you know,
and using your status as the most
important social media information
company in the world.
Unless you're a believer.
And then I don't see your point bro.
I went on twitter looking for what's
important,
what people are actually talking about.
They're talking about Justin fucking
bieber.
Did you know you got to facetime to know
Jamie told me why.
Tell me why do you even know these?
Jamie's beyond saying Jaycee's wedding
24 hours a day at any given time.
You can tack how's,
uh,
how's Bey and Jay doing right now?
They.
Okay.
And Jamie let you know what's the
latest.
Jamie's grinning like the Cheshire cat.
He's just like,
Yep,
that's me.
That's what he does.
He wears yeezys.
But he buys easy's.
What's the.
Where's Justin bieber's face said to
Jamie.
Right below his eye.
Let's say you look at it like a tear or
something.
What is it in that spot for Jesus to
Jesus Tattoo?
Please tell me.
You shitting me?
It's a Jesus tarries small.
Let's go with it.
It looks like it's a cross,
bro.
It does look like it looks like a mole.
That's as big as it gets.
Some of us have a better version of.
It's across though,
right next to him.
Oh No.
Gay Together.
They're begging me for.
You guys are banging each other.
You cannot tell the difference between
your tattoo and just a facial blemish.
You've got the wrong tattoo dude.
No,
he's got the right to that too.
Because you started off like that.
See what it is.
Is he wants to be like one of those
black guys like Birdman who has tattoos
all over his face.
Yeah.
She doesn't have that kind of balls.
So we're just going to go with a little
tiny thing that you eventually get
lasered off.
Whatever,
whatever.
Not that big a deal.
You know,
like who's got a lot of like stitches
says his name,
the white rappers got ak 47 tattooed on
the side of his face.
Have you ever seen him know?
Oh,
he's the best.
As far as the worst as far as like if
I've asked,
you mean the worst person in the world
and the best examples of.
Oh,
he's got more tattoos.
Oh Wow.
That's beautiful.
He's got them on his neck and his
forehead now.
And what is the coolest thing about it
is he's got like basically the joker,
a like scars coming out of the sides of
his mouth that looked like they've got
stitches.
Hence his name.
Stitches.
Yeah.
Well even has it on his lips,
like above his lips and to the sides and
left and right.
What is the latest thing that he's got?
He's got a star on his face to the AK
47.
Well,
he's got to start.
And where Justin Bieber has his little,
his little mold.
That's the hotspot.
Sent me one of those.
That's like the dumb dudes version of a
lower back tattoo.
It's like a tramp stamp or retards.
That's what it is.
It's just the visibility
of it everywhere.
That would.
That would freak me out.
I got a couple of tattoos,
but they're not in places where I'm
always going to be seen with them.
Not that it matters for Justin Bieber.
It's not like he's going to be going to
a job interview and having to impress
them.
That's true,
but oh yeah,
that's Gucci Mane.
Gucci Mane had an ice cream and an ice
cream cone tattooed on his face with
lightening bolts and it says birth be
our our.
You know why that is?
And he also had some shit written under
his eyelids.
What does that say?
What does it say on his eyelids?
Looks like old egg.
Looks like
a snake.
It's ingenious that he's said that he's
got borough written on the ice cream
because ice cream is cold and when
people are called they say so see what
he's done there.
Good point.
He's combined the Woodburn,
but the visual iconography of an ice
cream by linking these two formally
disparate concepts in one beautiful
tattoo.
How about the student copy them?
Got The guy next to him.
He'd copy Gucci Mane.
That's even stupider.
Yeah.
He went with [inaudible].
He was like,
man,
maybe I'll get to my Gucci's runoff
at the diner and be like,
Yo,
gooch,
they will stop.
You won't fuck.
Anyway.
The implications of a Justin bieber
being deprioritized on twitter,
I still contend template.
You're going back not as,
not as great
as the implications of Facebook,
uh,
hiding conservative news stories from
its uses on its news feed.
It's very unfortunate that someone did
this,
but it's very important that the workers
told us that they did this.
Yes.
Because it's supposed to be.
It's supposed to be an impartial.
I guess aggregator,
I mean,
what is,
what would you call facebook?
It's a portal where doe for stories and
things that are trending,
they've never,
they've never claimed that what you see
is just the most recent thing that is
coming up.
Right.
I mean all of it is algorithms.
So the things that you tend to click on
and the things that you tend to look at
and the things that you tend to like and
the stories that you tend to click
through to all go into their gigantic
algorithm crunching machine,
which I just imagined as being like a
big willy wonka machines with steam
coming up,
pink steam coming out the top and
a little munchkin toy trains circling
it.
You put in all of the data and then out
the other end of the Olympus compile
your facebook feed and so they're making
judgments all the time about what
they're going to prioritize,
but what they shouldn't be doing is
including any kind of their own
political preferences and we don't yet
know if it's actually true or it just
looks like this is one person who is
saying this
is.
Even if you.
Even if you don't these kinds of
policies in the.
You're a liberal.
You don't know what impact it's gonna
have and whether or not.
By putting this stuff out,
people are going to get more liberal.
Maybe they'll get more frustrated with
liberal ideas and they'll become more
conservative.
It's more likely to be that it fuels the
idea that being a liberal is being a
person's detached from reality,
and that's one of the the the major
points of criticism.
When,
when,
when the conservative people go after
the liberals,
one of the major
things that they try to harp on is that
liberals are out of touch with reality.
When you have something like this and
you're reinforcing the idea that there
are shielding certain aspects of reality
like that.
Some people have these conservative
opinions and if some people have a
conservative opinion and you disagree
with that conservative opinion,
that's where the open exchange and the
marketplace of ideas comes into place.
Now,
if you don't allow that exchange take
place because you deny that people think
that way because you hide the stories
you're going to alienate.
You're going to create these
confirmation bias forums.
You're going to create these places
where people like salon.com,
where people just.
They agree with each other to the point
and then they tell you why.
You know,
why is Josh Zaps the worst?
Will tell you why,
and then they tell you.
They ask a question like eight points,
like eight reasons why justice is the
worst.
Here's why he's terribly.
I'd give you a dozen,
but it's.
It's not news anymore.
There's so hysterically ridiculous is so
off the deep end.
I mean it used to be the case that we
thought of progressives and liberals as
being more pro free speech,
or at least I did.
I use the side of more inclusiveness and
more tolerance and it's becoming
increasingly not the case at all.
That there's more politically correct
bullshit and most censorship and more
imposing,
less tolerance of each of other people's
ideas on the lift.
Even though they're on the run.
I,
I 100 percent believed that,
but I believe it's the pendulum effect.
I think it's the suppression of free
speech by the Conservatives and the Bush
administration that fuck people up so
sideways.
They bounce back the other way,
ultra hard.
I think people got so angry at what was
going on with John Ashcroft covering
statues up with drapes and oh,
I loved that.
All the craziness that was going on in
that administration and all the
suppression of gay rights as everyone
know about that,
the fact that John Ashcroft actually had
the penis on a statue on an old Roman
statue and she was like in one of the
great temples down in Washington DC
covered up because he was so
puritanical.
He didn't want a naked penis from an
agent statue.
He was disturbing that that guy got into
office.
One of the,
one of the guys that uh,
I correspond with online.
He had something to do with some record
store and he sent me an album of Gospel
songs that John Ashcroft had made with
some other dude.
He was fucking and probably still is bat
shit crazy.
Well,
I mean they,
they,
they kind of,
what do you call it,
like when you stack like that basically
stacked the Bush administration with a
lot of crazy people like that.
Like the first,
especially the first administration of
the Bush administration,
the 2000 man.
You look at some of those paypal,
they basically theocrats.
I mean,
they're not that different from a
Christian version of what the Iranian
leaders.
Ah,
well,
not only that,
there's so caricature that they seem
like characters in a movie,
like a bad action movie.
I mean,
you think about what you've got.
You've got Donald Rumsfeld and Dick
Cheney to people arguably forged in the
center of the earth.
I mean,
they're fucking
straight up evil,
right?
Dick Cheney is straight up evil.
He got to a point where he didn't have a
fucking heartbeat.
No.
I mean the guy had an artificial heart
put in which was pumping his blood
through.
Still have no power.
You had a transplant it.
Oh,
does he have a live?
Have found some dude and cut his fucking
heart out.
You Bet your ass they did with one stone
knives.
We have to have a match your bullshit.
You happen to have a met.
She knew that they would have killed
somebody.
Has some secret service agent
disappeared.
One secret service agent and really
healthy diet.
Fucking that guy open like a fish.
You can just imagine they've probably
got like a tinder for,
for Dick Cheney,
where he's just swiping left and swiping
right on the people who they're going to
kill for his heart.
You got a 23 year old.
He did.
He and Ashcroft and uh,
there was,
there was a whole bunch of them
Wolfowitz.
I mean that guy looked like a demon,
you know,
think,
I mean all of those fucking that the
whole administration was filled with
chicken hawks that we're all about Jesus
and wanting to go over there and kick
some ass.
Fucking blow shit up.
It's interesting you mentioned Wolfowitz
because in terms of like what was saying
about the left is can be intolerant of
other ideas.
A lot of these guys,
especially Wolfowitz with Forma Marxists
when,
when Wolfowitz was young at university,
he was a revolutionary Marxist.
Whoa.
And it's interesting that oftentimes
people who who are hypo revolutionary
socialists can flip into becoming hyper,
an Randian idealistic reaction raise.
And there's the same kind of like when
you,
it's,
it's not that different when you think
about it,
like people think of them as being ideas
that are at the end of the political
spectrum,
but it's excellent actually more like a
horseshoe,
right?
Where at one end you think that you can
overthrow the capitalist system and
create a utopia in which everyone is
gonna be be equal and it's going to be
from each according to his ability to
each according to his need.
And then at the other end you believe
that you can wipe society is clean,
you can go into Iraq and raise
everything and then start from fresh and
democracy will spring up and people will
be able to live in pace.
I mean they're both basically kind of
mess niantic,
Utopian ideas about change instead of
the sort of change that I think actually
works,
which is just incremental grudging
change bit by bit.
Slowly Eking it out.
Yeah.
That's not what Chaney and Wolfowitz
think the world is all about.
No,
they tried to force change and force
change at home and abroad.
And that's where like the conspiracy
theories come in about nine slash 11
attacks and Dick Cheney saying that we
need something like an a
Pearl Harbor and that's where people
really freak out because they look at
how much people actually did profit from
that event.
So they go,
well,
okay,
is it possible that someone had a part
in letting that event happen or helping
that event happened or ignoring the fact
that event was gonna happen and allowing
it to happen?
Or is it a matter of people just
capitalizing on an event?
Which is what the most logical point of
view is that they.
There's incompetent,
the event happened,
and then they capitalized on it.
Like any good dictatorship.
Yeah,
exactly.
I mean,
I do think when you look at Helen
competently,
they managed Iraq.
When you're looking at and competently
they managed Katrina.
When you look at how and competently
they manage things that they wanted to
get right.
The idea that they could have pulled off
something like that within eight months
of entering office.
I find implausible like whenever the.
If I have to choose between in
competence versus a massive conspiracy,
I usually think people are just
generally incompetent.
Then do you even start that
conversation?
How do you even say,
listen here,
this out,
before you get crazy here,
the side,
I got an idea.
We got to talk some dudes into flying
planes into the world.
Trade Center towers one and two.
We're going to hijack planes,
fill with people.
We're going to talk these guys into
flying them into the,
into the buildings.
They'd be like,
wait,
what?
What,
what,
what?
What?
Who the fuck is going to do that?
Religious people,
you got to get them to believe that
there's a bunch of posts he waiting for
them in heaven and all they have to do
is fly these planes into buildings to
get that pussy.
Uh,
yeah.
But see,
Joe,
these plans had long been hatching as
they were.
They were camps in Afghanistan,
which we will funding.
Is that your Alex Jones impression?
I can feel it coming on with Alex Jones.
No,
Alex Jones would be yelling at me right
now explaining why I'm wrong.
Um,
I just.
So there's a much easier way to have
done it,
which is if,
if you wanted a pretext to go into Iraq
or you'd need to do would be.
I was talking to the national defense
guy about this.
He was like,
there was a no fly zone over Iraq.
The CIA could have painted a US plane,
the Iraqi colors and just faked a shoot
down a US or British jet that was
patrolling the no fly zone and you would
have a clear much clearer case actually
in international law to go to war.
Then the vague case that they did do,
because they didn't.
I mean it wasn't connected to nine slash
11,
so they have to make up this shit about
wmds and all that sort of stuff.
You could easily have orchestrated
something without bringing down the
world trade towers.
That would have given you a good reason
to go into Iraq.
Well that was one of the main reasons
why a lot of people bought into.
Do you know about operation northwoods?
Do you know that story that's only heard
you talk about it?
Yeah.
The operation northwoods,
that was that exact plan to get people
to go to war with Cuba to get us excited
about it.
They were going to blow up in American
drone.
They were going to send a jetliner up in
the air with no one in it and shoot it
out of the sky.
They were gonna arm,
Cuban friendlies and attack Guantanamo
Bay.
That was the main idea behind it was
like this would be the way we could get
people excited about going to war with
Cuba because you know that whole Bay of
pigs and all that fucking disaster that
happened when Kennedy was in office.
I mean,
and then the missile crisis,
there was a lot of tension going on with
Cuba,
so they had concocted this idea.
It's called operation northwoods.
It was signed by the Joint Chiefs of
staff,
so they went with it like there were
like,
sounds like democracy and they let's
just fucking lie to people and blow shit
up and kill Americans.
They were going to fucking kill
Americans in Guantanamo Bay.
Oh,
you've been blaming on the cube.
I'm sure they have because they're so
because there's such unscrupulous
assholes and they do all of they.
They do these legitimate conspiracy
theories.
That's what gives people reasons to
believe in the more than what I regard
as being that much more ridiculous
conspiracy theories,
but it would be a lot better if they
just didn't do any of this shit in the
first place and then people wouldn't be
out of their minds being so suspicious
about whether or not nine slash 11 was
an inside job.
Well,
there's also,
there was the word that Dick Cheney was
discussing the possibility of doing
something like that for Iran before they
left office.
They were talking about orchestrating a
false flag on a ran before they left
office and they never pulled it off.
Whether or not it's true or not remains
to be seen,
but it's not outside the realm of
possibility.
I mean,
it happened in so many different times
in history when Nero burned Rome,
when Hitler burned the Reichstag.
When I mean the whole.
What happened to get us into Vietnam?
Well that's right.
Like the Gulf of Tonkin,
Gulf of Tonkin.
They tended,
we got shot at.
That's right,
and there's also a little.
You don't even have to go as far as like
the Nazis,
just in terms of what the CIA has done,
encounter up counterinsurgency
operations in south South America and
stuff.
The involvement in the coup in 1973 in
Chile.
I was reading up about that lately
because I went to Chile a couple of
years ago.
I mean it's not that they absolutely
completely manufacture total bullshit
from whole cloth,
but they give voice to conspiracy
theories in those particular countries.
They fund a media outlets that are,
that are spreading.
We know what the CIA wants to get hurt
and they just basically put their finger
on the scales of something so that it
goes another way.
I mean the democratically elected
government in Chile was overthrown by a
brutal military dictatorship,
which then lasted for an entire
generation.
Thanks largely to the CIA.
I mean we don't even think or hear or
learn about that stuff.
And do you think that it's possible for
them to go,
listen,
you got to break some eggs to make an
omelet.
You want America to be America led.
The free home of the brave was the only
one wig.
We got to fucking lie to you.
We've got to kick some ass.
A lot of shit we'd like to tell you,
but the world works and really fucked up
way and you don't want to know about
that because you want to watch real
housewives.
Exactly.
What we're going to do now,
and I,
I have,
I actually have some sympathy for that
idea.
I,
a friend of a friend of mine was easily
former director of the CIA.
I spent a Thanksgiving with him once
down in Washington DC.
Did you look in his basement?
Tall skulls,
open the doors sculptural out in the
hallway.
And when I talked to people like that,
yeah,
I do understand that our vision of the
world is a very small sliver and can be
quite naive,
very naive.
Their attitude is when you're actually
working in the national security
apparatus,
their apparatus apparatus,
we might've made a word that'll do.
I just did it.
Just showing you think he made up a
word,
but it sounds.
I like it.
If you didn't just stop yourself,
then the apparatus would be a new word.
A lot of people at home would.
It went okay.
It seems like a smart guy.
If you actually work there,
then I think your outlook is basically
what you just articulated,
which is,
um,
it,
it'll be lovely if we all lived in a
world where with ice cream and candy and
where the lines slipped with the lambs
and the,
and the postman hug the dogs and we were
all dancing the streets.
But listen Honcho,
it's a tough world out there and either
the Saddam Hussein's and the Putin's are
going to roll it away.
And sometimes you have to break a few
weeks in order to make an Omelette.
And sometimes you have to do things
that,
uh,
that might not seem pretty on the
surface.
But I'll tell you what were the ones who
are standing on the wall watching God.
So you go about your business and we'll
take care of shit.
I heard the national anthem playing.
You really did.
Which won the Australian one.
Cool.
Who's cruise on?
Wait,
whatever.
It's all the same.
Even American.
I'm probably Canadian or something.
Barely America.
Uh,
America.
The beautiful.
Shouldn't be the national anthem.
Can I just say that?
That's better.
Stop bangled banner.
Start rockets in it though.
I'm going to probably stick with that.
The rockets.
Red Glare.
The bombs bursting in air.
What you bombs bursting in air.
That's in our fucking national anthem.
I love how warmongering so many national
anthems.
And I like the French.
The French one.
It literally has the lyrics about the
blood of our enemies will fill the
canals of France.
It's serious shit.
That's unrealistic.
People you have to call you just.
You guys are just lying.
There's no happened.
Bombs actually could burst in there and
do and have doubled the canals fucker.
You killing man killer.
But you'd have to kill everybody on the
planet to fill the canals of blood.
It'd be no one left.
Well,
I mean I killed a lot of Germans in the
gym.
Is killed a lot of Russians.
Have you seen some of the numbers?
There's a great graphic that I think
like vox produced or something about the
number of people in total who were
killed in,
in the world wars.
Each one represented like each thousand
dollars million.
He's represented by little block.
I don't even know what you're talking
about,
but it's just crazy when you start
seeing how many people look at you.
Like,
Oh,
this is a lot who were killed in,
for example,
Iraq war and it goes back to Vietnam.
You know,
what will one world war two,
the towards the final few years will
will to even excluding the Holocaust,
just looking at people like mainly
Russians,
which she asked state just millions upon
millions upon millions of people,
like 20 million people don't think
about.
The Russians have died in World War II.
There was a lot more of them died than
us.
And often,
I mean if you talk to a military
historian,
what really ended the war?
Yes,
Dj was important.
But,
but the Soviets won the war,
I mean it was,
it was the fact that the Nazis were just
hemorrhaging in the east.
That meant that they couldn't put up any
defenses in the,
in the West.
So Dj was a,
you know,
not to insult the are great forefathers
who fought there,
but data was a little bit of a walk in
the park in comparison to what was
happening on the eastern front.
Well,
there was a lot going on all across the
world,
but one of the scariest things about
France and what happened to them during
World War II is the amount of France to
this day that you literally can't even
visit because it's so filled with waste
from all the bombs that were dropped.
You seen as an area larger than Paris
that's completely fenced in and can't go
in it because it's got so much munitions
and so many bombs that were dropped
there.
It's so fucked up.
That will be that way for something like
100,000 years or something crazy.
I mean,
it's poison gas
bodies.
They're just still buddies,
just bones and shit.
There's this little town in northern
France called villas retina where the
aussies were,
I mean,
you know,
no one ever thinks about the [inaudible]
and then using this little countries who
were fighting there as well,
but of course they had their own little
little plots that they had to had to
fight and there was this big heroic
stand against the Germans,
which the aussies were in charge of it
villas retina and still to this day in
the little in the schools and the
elementary schools there,
they sing the Australian national
anthem.
They have little Australian flags flying
and stuff because they have failed to
just littered with the bodies of
Australians in northern France from the
world war.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Naughty.
What will we do it than to make any
sense of the side of the world should
have just stayed home?
Well,
I think we saw some of those Hitler
speeches.
One went,
oh,
we're going to have to do something.
Here is this guy,
this Guy Mike.
He might have the right stuff to fucking
become the real darth vader.
Yeah.
That's,
uh,
that,
that charismatic person who's completely
insane that wants to conquer the world
and gets a whole nation behind them is
so Donald Trump,
I mean,
it's so crazy and scary
will where he's not trying to take over
the world,
but it shows you how problematic
personality can be when it comes to
someone being chosen to be the leader,
especially to this day and in this day
rather were so soft this day of food
coming on these little styrofoam trays
and being able to pull up to Wendy's and
get a fucking cheeseburger and 15
seconds.
We're so weak and it's so easy to exist
that we're excited about this guy
possibly like overturned the apple cart
where people are
who don't have any people,
don't have any other options as well.
I feel like Bernie and trump with a,
with a ways in different ways that
people had the people who've been on it
for a long time.
White working class dudes mostly have to
like.
I mean when you look at the effect that
middle incomes of middle American has
been stagnating for the past 30 years.
Manufacturing has been in decline like
they haven't been.
There hasn't been a rise in working
class incomes in America since the
eighties.
I was surprised that Elizabeth Warren
didn't get more traction.
It seems like once that native American
stuff came out about her,
she just went,
Oh Kim,
just kind of stuff.
They think she believes that she is more
useful in the Senate maybe,
but you know,
the native American stuff where she
faked a native American heritage in
order to get some sort of a scholarship.
When I hear things like that,
I use my brain.
It just hits the.
This is probably a btob part of my brain
and it just goes straight out my ear
because I don't.
I don't really give a shit about that.
Stuff like that.
You don't care about someone faking
their ethnicity.
Why didn't I didn't look into it enough.
Me I
needed to.
She's a brilliant woman.
What?
Why?
Why was she doing it?
Well,
wanted to get into a university.
She have to go
pull that up.
Jamie.
Find out what the fuck that was all
about,
but I don't know.
I mean,
who knows if she actually did it,
maybe someone else did it and she sort
of went with it.
So difficult to talking to her.
If it's a Rachel dolezal thing with
someone who spent their whole life
pretending to be something that they're
not,
then I think yes,
that there's a quite a few of those out
there though.
Then I,
I do think that that's disqualifying,
but I feel like if the only thing that
you'll political opponents can dig up on
you is that you filled out a form wrong,
but that's not filling out a form wrong.
That's being deceptive about your
ethnicity in order to take advantage of
like people that are undermined by
society.
I mean,
when you go with your ranking,
let's kill her
to put her into trump's concentration.
We don't have any.
Uh,
yeah.
Trump isn't,
is fascinating,
isn't it?
I can't believe it's actually going to
happen.
He might,
when he,
he's real close to winning because I
just don't know whether or not Hillary
can hold up to scrutiny when you're
talking about her being under to
criminal investigations and the right
now.
Right now,
the immediate future,
this to criminal investigations going
on,
they just gave immunity to the guy who
set up that email server.
They deported him.
They brought him over to America.
Extra added them wanting to do.
What's that called?
They brought them over to America and
gave him immunity.
So what the fuck man?
What,
what is gonna Happen Now?
Well,
yeah,
we are one.
Uh,
I was talking to a guy hacked it rather
immunity.
Yeah.
Um,
I was talking to body laying on the,
on my podcast about them.
And that's not true.
Hold on a second.
They give immunity to go set up the
server.
The extradited.
The guy who created the hack that he
doesn't have immunity.
Where do you think I hacked?
I think he's from Romania.
The coolest,
coolest.
He's from Romania.
The Guy who hacked into the serve,
the email servers and exposed all that.
I want to say he's from a very small
rural town in Romania.
I'm not kidding.
Even if that's not true,
I liked that picture.
I like that image of him just in a shed,
in a bond in the middle of nowhere.
And icy cold remaining true though.
Romania.
Lucifer?
I breached Clinton server.
It was easy.
Yeah.
So this guy,
he got arrested and he's in jail,
but the guy was set up the actual server
itself,
by the way,
which is in her bathroom.
Okay.
What?
Why would you put a server in your
bathroom?
Exactly.
Okay.
Who knows?
But that guy got immunity in this guy
got so frustratingly paranoid.
Even if there was nothing,
even if she wasn't doing anything wrong,
the fact that she's so paranoid as to
need to set that up because she's so
terrified that someone's going to get
access to our emails.
Well,
you know,
they spent a million dollars to fight
off social media opinions.
Do you know about this?
Look at this.
The Pax correct commenters on Reddit and
facebook.
A million dollars to spend a million
dollars to fight off people that don't
like Clinton.
I mean they're what they're doing as a
trend of engineer public support,
public support that Bernie sanders has
got organically.
Yeah,
that'd be.
Trump has organically too.
Maybe we don't
know.
Well,
here's the thing.
What he does,
what he does have is even people who
hate him,
acknowledged that he is not full of
bullshit and that he's not being.
He's not spending someone else's lines.
He doesn't seem manufactured.
He's obviously not 100 conventional
politician.
I can dislike all of his policies as
much as I do,
but I can still regard him as being a
breath of fresh air.
Hold on.
You don't like his policies.
What about the wall?
The Wall's great idea.
Are you a big pink floyd fan?
I am a pink floyd fan.
Actually.
I don't think the wall is the craziest
of is even close to his craziest of
ideas.
I mean the craziest.
Keeping Muslims out of the country and
probably not allowing any noncitizen
Muslims into the United States.
This is not only crazy but incredibly
dangerous because I think that if we
want to be able to conquer a Islam,
Islam and jihadism,
Islamic terrorism,
we've got to find a way of.
I mean our best resources and moderate
Muslims inside the United States,
right?
Who can,
who have their ear to the ground,
who will notice mosques that might be
becoming radicalized.
You want to appear to be a friendly,
tolerant democracy and of course you
want to put in place all the security
precautions that unnecessarily and you
don't want to just be allowing millions
of,
of unscreened people to come pouring in
the way that they have in Europe.
But we don't have that problem here
because we've got ocean between us so we
can pick and choose who was also why it
gets really weird when you start talking
about the CIA and the CIA infiltrating
different organizations.
It's like that's where you kind of
support it.
Kinda support clan to Stein behavior and
sneakiness and deception because
they're,
they're pretty good at it.
They've been doing it for a long time
and they know how to get deep into
organizations.
You know,
like you ever see the show homeland.
Yeah.
Come on Bro.
Yeah,
I made a documentary.
No.
Uh,
I mean the idea of a wall to me,
but I come from a country Australia
which is surrounded.
It's an island.
So like of course there are not that
like the idea of people just pouring
across the border back and forth and
coming in for seasonal seasonal work and
like that to me does strike me as as
odd.
Yeah.
There's a.
there's an undefended border.
I don't,
I don't think it would be a good
investment of money.
I think it's silly.
I think it's a distraction.
If you talk to technology experts,
they say that there are much better ways
of securing the border than with a
physical wall.
You can have drones and things and you
can have all kinds of crazy shit,
but because people will dig under a wall
of the climate over,
well it's not,
it's not.
It's not nearly as sophisticated as the
kind of technology that you could use,
but I don't think there's anything
inherently like bigoted about it.
I think deporting every single person
who's here illegally is an overreaction
and that like,
have you seen the stats about how many
seven?
40 seven is full of people.
You would need to get all of all 11
million undocumented people in America.
There's more than 11 million in la by
the way,
this idea that there's 11 million
undocumented people in America,
it's fucking hilarious.
Four,
oh,
five at three the afternoon and look
around because there's fucking millions
and millions of people that are broken
that are from Canada,
millions of people from Mexico,
millions of people from all sorts of
spots that aren't supposed to be here.
That God visas and stayed.
That shit is rampant.
I know the bloody ozzy.
He's not to mention Monica,
if you guys don't let anybody in
Australia either,
like boatloads of people that try to get
come in legally,
that's spinning around,
light them on fire and push them out to
the ocean
and people don't fucking play over
there.
Australia Australia's policy has been
since the eighties that uh,
you have a heart,
a very high level of legal migration in
a high level of refugees.
Refugee intake,
like on a per capita basis.
Australia is one of certainly the top 10
most generous countries in terms of
people coming in and more than half of
the population of Australia has arrived
since the Second World War.
Really?
Yup.
So it's actually a higher immigrant
proportion country than the United
States,
even if you do it legally,
if you do it legally,
but we have this quite controversial and
pretty inhumane,
but I suppose defensible policy,
which is if you pay a people smuggler to
make your way all the way from
Afghanistan or Iran or wherever it is,
you're coming from Syria and you pass
through a bazillion other different
countries through Malaysia,
through Singapore,
you make your way down to Indonesia and
you're rich enough to get on a boat.
Then comes to Australia.
You will never be settled in Australia.
Really?
You ever,
ever,
never accepted,
and you'll be sent to a one of a couple
of Pacific island nations.
There's a place called Manus island in
Papua New Guinea,
I believe.
There's another place called Naru,
which is a country in its own right,
and they have set up these big detention
centers there and people can end up
there for years or even decades while
their cases get heard.
It's really barbaric people,
so they're fucking lips together in
protest.
One guy just set himself on fire in
front of United Nations inspectors who
were there.
It's really not pretty stuff,
but the government says,
listen,
we used to have under the law,
under the previous government which
relaxed these policies.
50,000 people died at sea trying to get
to Australia in boats,
including women and children.
Now almost nobody tries to come to
Australia by boat anymore because they
know they're never going to settle,
so what do you prefer?
A few hundred people basically being
stuck in indefinite detention on some
shitty Pacific island or 50,000 people
dying at sea trying to get here because
they think they're going to be
resettled.
Plus Australia remains awesome.
That's where it gets weird.
It's pretty fucking bad ass there.
So if you're trying to like look at the
end result might go,
man,
the result might justify the means
because like go to Melbourne.
It's fucking beautiful.
It's great.
It's incredible.
Yeah.
It's like paradise.
There's this thing about Australia that
to me it's like,
Ooh,
they might have it nailed.
There's only 20 million people in the
entire country.
It's a fucking huge country.
The landscape is gorgeous.
You don't have any ozone layer though.
No,
that's the problem.
You Get Sun burnt and you get cancer
into.
Yeah.
Know Australia has 23 million people,
so what's that?
About half the population of California.
California is about $40.
That's La.
Yeah.
So the greater the greater la area if
you,
if you include all the way up through
and.
Yeah.
And down to down to long beach and all
that.
Uh,
and that's in,
that's in an area the same size as the
contiguous United States.
Crazy.
And everybody lives in the edge.
Yeah,
the middle one.
The middle of crocodiles and Lizard.
Kangaroos and nuts,
man.
It's crazy place.
Yeah.
But Canada is kind of like that.
Canada's only got 35 million people and
it's bigger than the United States even
including Alaska,
but it's fucking frozen my good time yet
it's the site of Canada and Australia.
Kind of very similar in that they're
enormous,
but totally in hospitable.
I mean,
you could know sooner live in most parts
of Canada,
then you could live in most parts of
Australia where there's just no water
and no vegetation in Australia was
desert Canada is ice,
not really icy.
Probably be better off trying Australia
then you would see I'm going to try and
Canada.
Then you would Australia definitely.
Well you could,
you could get water,
you could make fires and stuff pulling.
If there's no water you're screwed.
Right.
But there's a lot of people that live
like.
I have some friends that live in
Alberta.
They live way up there.
They live in.
It's fucking cold shit.
The wintertime up,
there's like 30,
40,
below zero.
I mean he's crazy,
but they live there.
They're fine
with modern civilization I suppose.
Yeah.
And the other thing,
the best writer in Kennedy is,
as you say,
we all huddle along a very,
very narrow strip in Australia.
It's the coast and in Canada it's the
border.
Don't you think it's easier though to
live in a cold climate then in
hospitably hot climate?
Because you could dress for a cold
climate who can get in your car,
you drive around you all right?
You get in your house.
It's warm,
but hot climates are fucking scary.
Like it gets too hot to survive outside
for whatever reason.
That's waste,
Gary,
because you can't dress for it.
Like you could wear like really
insulated close and you can actually
stand outside at 10 below.
But you grew up in the northeast.
Right?
But if you're outside and it's 130
degrees outside,
you're fuck.
I feel like this is just.
This just comes from what you're used
to.
I reckon because you grew up in the
northeast,
you're not as scared of the call.
I've,
I,
I find like when I first moved to New
York,
I remember saying to people back in
Australia,
why is there even a city here?
Why?
Why did anyone ever come across the
ocean and build a fucking city here
where it's literally so cold that a
dog's piss on the sidewalk will turn
into ice.
It's like,
um,
it's like I'm in the TV show the dome
and it's just a giant freezer.
Because I'd never had the conception of
actually being sub freezing like shit is
just freezing.
You should not be living anywhere where
if you fell over drunk at night and hit
your head,
you would be dead by the morning.
But then again we get rid of some
dummies.
Should we send her a little bit?
You know if you're falling asleep out in
the street drunk.
I mean it's sad when that happens to
people.
You hear about it with like college
kids,
they freeze to death.
That happens like every other year.
So some college kid in New Hampshire
will get drunk,
fall asleep outside and freeze to death.
Shouldn't be living there.
Don't do it.
Move all of Canada and the North East
down to the mid Atlantic states and be
done with.
It's not though.
If you have warm
clothes,
if you have warm clothes you could
survive up there.
It's not that bad.
Well,
I mean if you have air conditioning,
you can even live in Phoenix.
But sub,
no,
but sub zero temperatures,
like if it's zero outside,
you can walk around,
you can go places like if it's 130
degrees outside,
you can't go anywhere.
That's true.
You can only go places when it's
subfreezing.
I have been swimming,
my sister in law is finish and in
Finland they go in the Saunas and then
they'd go out and swim in lakes in the
middle of nowhere when it is minus 22
degrees.
I've been swimming in a lake when it's
minus 22 degrees,
the whole thing is frozen over God.
They just chip a hole in it.
Yeah.
Then I didn't need to chip it.
They uh,
they have a whole like add water spouts
so the water keeps moving.
So
uh,
and uh,
I made,
maybe they stopped by chipping it,
but it's basically like a bubbling cold
pool.
And you sit in the sauna,
which is,
you know,
it's,
it's nudging 100 degrees Celsius.
I don't know what that is.
200,
200 degrees Fahrenheit or something.
And then you come out through the air,
which is minus 20 Fahrenheit,
I think it crosses Fahrenheit and
Celsius crossover around it in the low
minus twenties.
And then you get in the water,
you can't put your head under
[inaudible].
You can go into this condition where
you,
your brain essentially shuts down and
goes into phrase.
But uh,
yeah,
there,
the people in Finland,
they love it so that it looks like they
cut a hole in the ice.
Yeah.
That looks like they got a hole in
layoffs.
But that's not me.
If you got to my facebook and probably
find it back there somewhere in the
deep,
dark and distant.
Pam.
Yeah.
Well people loved that.
That ice cold ice cold going back and
forth between the two of them is
amazing.
It gives you a high.
The does well,
it actually really does actually
produces certain chemicals in your
brain.
Epinephrin.
So what is norepinephrine?
Norepinephrine?
I'll believe you.
I'm Dr Rhonda.
Patrick was on.
She was talking about,
um,
cold shock therapy,
cold shock proteins and heat shock
proteins and that there's a different,
um,
there's different proteins that we
produce in the sauna and the sauna is
really beneficial for hormone
production,
for sleep,
Melatonin production,
all sorts of different things.
Things Melatonin might not have been,
but all sorts of growth hormone for
sure.
That was one of them.
But things that rejuvenate the body
produced by these heat shock protein.
I mean,
just look at the nordic,
paypal and paypal in northern Germany.
They will swear by soreness I mean the
Swedes and the Norwegians and the Finns
and the Danes.
I mean,
it's not like these are not people who
you'd want to emulate.
These
are very attractive,
healthy,
long living people.
Yeah,
they're robust yet,
but I think there's definitely something
to it,
to both sauna and cold baths.
Like you know,
when Hoff know Wim Hof,
Wim Hoff method of breathing and he's
got something like 26 world records.
She's been on the podcast for 2:26 world
records,
but like dealing with climate and cold,
he summited everest in his shorts with
ice sandals on.
I'm not even kidding.
No,
no oxygen.
Didn't bring any oxygen with them is a
maniac.
Crazy.
But he's developed ability to
tolerate extreme temperature distance or
a temperature changes and he swears by
it.
He thinks it's a great teacher about
life and who you are and what you are
and just invigorates you in some strange
way that.
I mean,
when you meet the guy,
you believe it because he's like
radiating energy.
Yeah.
It's funny what people.
I mean it's like Tim,
Tim Ferris as well,
right?
Where he,
he,
he'll go through periods where he's
taken my spots and doing all this crazy
shit and measuring the impact that it
has on his physiology.
And I'm just too lazy,
man.
I think.
Wow.
I can't talk to you anymore.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Yeah,
I understand man.
Did you say the,
um,
just say the Philadelphia conference
that I,
that I sent you,
which was about,
uh,
about what people's guilt.
I'm guilty.
What did I do?
It was a,
it was white.
There was a white privileged conference.
Oh,
that's right.
I love that article at that because we
did this.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
Yeah,
you did.
I was like,
why is my twitter blowing up?
Oh,
Joe retweeted me.
So there was this white privileged
conference,
which was a kind of politically correct
talk fast.
Right.
And it basically ended up consuming
itself entirely because the people who
were attending it decided that the
conference itself had become too white.
So they were getting,
they were all there.
So they had this Hashtag.
I'm white privileged conference,
so white WPC,
so white.
Uh,
and it started after one of the speakers
there who was a white historian,
uh,
went overtime and won an Asian American,
attend a,
a woman tweeted out great keynote,
but going over time allotted is another
example of white supremacy,
Hashtag white privilege conference so
wise.
And he also made the mistake of using
the
inward in his speech.
I mean he obviously was using it in a
historical context because he was
talking about race in America.
But once that happened,
I mean,
what could possibly go wrong using the
inward at a conference about white
guilt,
right?
Then everyone starts tweeting
would never acceptable from Hashtag
white folks lips deeply offensive and
traumatizing.
Hashtag white privilege conference.
So white.
And that was from a white Tweeta.
So then it's like a snake eating its
fucking title.
Right?
All these white people just accusing one
another of being too white.
You're all whites.
We get it.
It's would Michael Shermer calls virtue
signaling,
right?
Yeah.
Right.
That's there.
They're letting the perfect term there.
They're trying to find someone who's
made some sort of an error.
They're attacking them with full force.
Yep.
And it's also like they're ignoring
context on purpose.
It's like by saying that the word is,
it's never acceptable to say the n word.
By saying that and putting that in a
tweet,
that's not true.
It's just not true.
Like if there is a reason to say it,
if you were explaining something that
happened,
what someone said,
how they said it,
you are allowed to repeat word.
The idea that you're not allowed to
repeat the word around grown adults is
to pretend that word is magic to where
that going to conjure demon,
but it also empowers the word I,
in fact,
I feel stupid for even having used the
phrase the anyway because ordinarily I'd
just say,
Nigga,
if I'm talking about the existence of
that would shock the podcast on
Australian so I don't understand
context.
Right?
But I mean,
I was talking about this on my podcast
about.
I do think that we,
we've gotten away from like where is the
other person's heart and what is their
intention?
So like if you ever use that word in
anger,
add another person.
I think your total count and you should
not do that or you're running a nigger.
That's true.
Mean that gentleman,
I couldn't help it as a stand up
comedian in me,
but uh,
but,
but if you're just using it in
conversation in order to talk about the
existence of the wood,
we know that though everyone knows that.
And I think it's a tough thing.
Here's the problem with a lot of these,
these things where you attack someone's
use of a word,
it's Duh.
It becomes one of those things like if
someone says sexism is bad,
racism is system is bad,
we need to be a more integrated and
complete and whole culture and society
and we need to look at each other for
like Martin Luther King said,
the content of their character,
not the color of their skin.
Isn't that Dha at a certain point in
time,
some people think that it's not dark
enough in enough places with enough
people,
but we're going to educate racists or we
just gonna toot our own horn as to how
non racist we are.
Right?
The latter.
Because another one of the tweets that
happened at this conference.
What red?
A white woman telling a black woman to
close the door at a workshop session.
Another example of Hashtag white
privileged conference.
So what?
You're not allowed to tell a person of
color to do anything.
No charges eps.
That's right.
Even gentle little flowers to just leave
the water running.
Just whatever you're allowed to say,
hey,
can you shut that water off?
No,
that's racist.
Oh,
okay.
Um,
what if they just throw lit cigarettes
on the ground outside?
Are you allowed to correct them or.
No?
That's racist.
Racist.
Okay.
What if,
um,
let's just spend the whole rest of the
Puc house going through hypothetical
anecdotes about what would be,
what would very strange that there is a
word that certain people are allowed to
use.
Like the black people can use it and
they can even use it as a form of
empowerment,
but I think that's okay,
isn't it?
Do you think that's hypocritical?
I reckon if you,
I reckon if you will,
people in your ancestors have been
fucked over completely full hundred
years,
then it's a little bit rich when the,
when the people who belong to the
ethnicity that's been fucking you over,
don't let you reclaim the wood that was
previously oppressive.
Oh,
100 percent.
Not only that,
it in practice it seems correct when
it's being done.
Yeah.
Like if a white person uses the word and
they use it for me,
even me just using it in that joke,
just joking around and what have you
done?
Yeah.
It,
you know,
it's a joke and it still impacts and
some sort of a very bizarre way.
But if a rapper is using it,
it seems like,
like,
like someone saying,
you know,
like,
you know what I'm saying man,
you know,
it's become that.
But it was subversive when black people
started saying.
Right,
right,
right.
But my point being a white person saying
the exact same things as horrific and
shocking that stitches guy,
stitches guy likes that word.
He throws the word around all the time.
I'll bet he does.
Doesn't surprise me at all.
Yeah,
no nuts on him.
That's not him.
Stitches to run with the joker.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You gotta get your white people straight
out of the birds.
The Black Guy,
that's Gucci Mane.
He uses it to assist.
I just mistook a white person for black
fests are amazing.
I don't even see color president too
bad.
You were born and some other shit hole
and you were born here.
You could have a fucking real good run
at it.
I'm just not good enough.
I can't do that.
Can't do what trump does.
I look at that admiringly.
I'm like,
how does he have the Bulls?
The audacity,
which you wouldn't do it that way.
No.
One of the things that I think is
fascinating about trump and really
problematic is that human beings love to
be united in tribes and not necessarily
always good tribes.
We love to be united in tribes and
whether it's tribes of people who use
Mac over windows,
whether it's tribes of android users or
it's tribes of people from Wisconsin
versus tribes from people from Texas.
We love to be in a fucking collective
group of people,
even if it's not a good group,
even if it's not good ideas,
and one of the things that I get
disturbed about what this trump thing
is,
how many annoying goofy white dudes are
really into him.
There's like there's an anti
intellectual aspect that got shut down,
debate aspect about this.
Yeah.
I think there's a lot of that being
sarcastic because it goes cultural
Australian to trump's support.
Not all of us.
It's not a,
there's intelligent people that support
them to totally but then not supporting
him because he,
his ideas are intelligent.
They're supporting him in spite of the
fact that they're intelligent because
there's something about his vibe that
appeals.
I feel like there's a bunch of people
supporting him cause he's winning and
they want to see him win and they want
to get in on some of that winning and
there's a bunch of dumb white dudes that
are hopping aboard that,
that are just letting you know who's
winning.
He's winning,
I think it's partly that.
I think it's partly exhaustion with the
political correctness that we've just
been talking about.
I just think that they feel like they
can't say anything about the threat of
Islamist terrorism or about the changing
demographics of America or illegal
immigration without being branded as a
bigot.
And I think it's also just what I was
saying before about him seeming
refreshing.
Like it's the same back in Australia.
I was back in Australia,
uh,
about six weeks ago and I was on a panel
there and they were asking me about
trump,
like the audience asks questions and
stuff and I was trying to explain it by
reference to the fact that even in
Australia,
people don't feel like politicians are
speaking their language,
like actual human beings and are like,
take for example,
gay marriage in Australia.
Australia still doesn't have gay
marriage.
You should be psyched about that.
You don't have to give away half your
money.
Sorry honey.
Can't do it.
I'd love to marry you.
Shit ain't happening.
I'd be fucking pumped.
Tax Laws are different though.
It's actually better to be married in
Australia than it is not to be married.
It's not like here where they screw you.
How's that?
Not An understanding that someone's
going to take care of your shit.
No,
it's not good.
If you get divorced,
they're going to take off.
You don't want.
That's what I'm saying.
Fuck taxes.
Don't worry about that.
So,
uh,
the,
the Australia is one of the most pro gay
marriage places in the world when you
actually poll people 70 slash 80 percent
of the population wants gay marriage.
Uh,
it's one of the least religious
countries in the world when you poll
people and more than 60 percent of the
population don't believe in God or go to
church regularly.
The last prime minister,
the prime minister before last was an
unmarried atheist woman.
So it's not like this is a place where
you would expect people to be opposed to
gay marriage.
I bet what's going on?
I Bet I get it.
I bet gay dudes are secretly going and
voting against gay marriage so they
don't have to get married.
That's it.
I think that's what it is.
I think it's like these pot dealers up
in northern California that secretly
voted against marijuana legalization
because he wanted to keep it illegal so
they can make more money and they
wouldn't have to turn in the taxes.
That's shrewd.
It's dirty,
it's dirty and it's prevalent.
I talked to some growers that were
telling me they were going to vote
against it,
that we're going to vote against
legalization because legalization would
fuck them over economically,
and I know I'm being selfish,
but hey man,
it's so we do it up here.
I mean,
do you think the Mexican drug cartels
one end to the war on drugs Helena
course them.
It's good.
Why would you?
But my point is simply that the prime
minister of Australia currently favors
gay marriage.
The palate,
there's a majority in parliament for it
and instead because he had to do some
shady backroom deal to get into power
with his fellow party hacks,
there's gonna.
They're not doing it now.
There's going to be like a plebiscite,
which is like a nonbinding referendum
about it or something and all my only
point was it's so obvious that
politicians are so full of shit and that
they are beholden to people other than
the people who elected them.
That whether,
whether you're listening to Ted Cruz or
Hillary Clinton,
people just have a sense that they're
being fed lines.
Did you hear Hillary talking about after
trump,
huge group playing the Women's card?
She goes,
you know,
fat playing the Woman's Card,
Dubbo,
lame and weak while pay and
what?
Nobody speaks like that.
Why are you speaking like that?
Why you sound like like that so I can
understand.
I can imagine people going,
we'll get lists.
It's
so gross hearing that it's so gross.
First of all,
she was a person who said that marriage
should be between a man and a woman
until 2013.
Okay.
Two thousand and 13.
She was still saying that that is just
retarded.
Isn't it?
Convenient how her views on everything
just happened to evolve at exactly the
same point so that when they win,
51 percent of the American population
comes around to them.
She has an awakening.
It's just so mysterious that I had.
I just don't understand,
and this is a key clue me in this who is
trying to keep gay marriage illegal in
Australia because if there's all those
people,
you would think that if the majority of
the people wanted it,
if the prime minister wanted,
have all these people wanted it,
why?
Who is,
who's working in,
what benefit is there of keeping it
illegal?
So think about,
I think everyone knows it's going to
happen.
It's just a matter of trying to postpone
it,
but it's what's basically happened is
that there is a rift between within the
Conservative Party between conservative
conservatives and progressive and like
socially liberal conservatives.
I think about the Republican Party here
where you've got like Christian
evangelicals as a component of it,
but you've also got the rand poll slash
maybe Donald Trump kind of contingent
people who aren't,
who don't want it,
don't really care what people do in the
privacy of their own homes,
but they're fiscally conservative.
Uh,
those people.
That faction had previously nominated a
leader to be the prime minister and that
was the prime minister.
He got stabbed in the back by one of his
colleagues who's socially liberal and
the only way that he could get the
support of the faction that he needed to
become prime minister was by
guaranteeing them that he wouldn't move
too fast on gay marriage.
So it's a minority of a minority,
of concern of like culturally
conservative conservatives who represent
rural districts with a bunch of farmers
in them.
Uh,
the farmers,
you know,
it's always the God damn farmers.
I had a joke,
one of my old specials,
there's only two types of people that
care about gay marriage.
People were really dumb,
or people that are secretly worried that
dicks are delicious.
Think that makes sense.
That's right.
Fucking farmers.
Someone's got to get them to suck a
dick.
And he exactly could realize what's the,
all the Hoopla about what about
just go ahead and suck it.
You probably wouldn't even like it.
And then you'd be like,
yeah,
this guy,
I don't give a fuck.
What about the guy who was sucking all
those whole sticks and um,
and a claw is that Seattle was,
he was dressed up
and like leather and he'd go out in the
farm in the middle of the night and he'd
like give.
Oh,
you're talking about the guy who got
arrested several times talking about the
guy who died.
He died from getting fired,
but his name was.
They used to call him Mr Hands.
I love that you know his name.
Yeah.
There was a documentary called zoo and
it was all about zoophilia,
which is a real sexual attraction that
people have to farm animals.
Always white people by the way.
Hollow white people.
Yeah.
Actually,
I think the guy who got arrested was
black,
I think just covered in leather,
black leather bro.
He's from Australia.
It's also kind of adding insult to
injury for the animal that you're
actually wearing.
Leather.
You,
I'm wearing your hat.
I'm wearing your skin at the same time
as I.
Fuck you.
He's not wearing a horse here.
Maybe not.
Yeah,
it's different.
It's different species,
but I'm this guy who lived in Itam claw.
They had found each other online on a
him in divorce,
him and all these people,
they develop this relationship
online with these people that were
really into horses and getting fucked by
farm animals and so they invested in
this property and they got this farm and
they had these horses.
There was over a hundred hours of
footage of these people getting fucked
by animals and one guy,
they type it.
Oh,
there's a video of it.
You can watch it.
You want to see.
Absolutely.
What else am I doing this afternoon and
folks who are listening only I urge you
to go to youtube just to watch the
subtle twist of his head.
Absolutely.
I'm going to wake in Los Angeles.
I got a lot of time on my hands between
meetings.
There'll be.
Do you want to win the lottery?
Absolutely.
Abandoned and famous enough.
Claw horse sex faces,
new charges in Tennessee.
Um,
was a different guy.
What year is this?
Two thousand nine.
It's after I'm.
That guy was dead.
It says.
Okay.
Here it is.
A former Washington state man who was
convicted of trespassing at an Itam
cloth farm where a man was fatally
injured while having sex with a horse in
2005.
Right.
Is accused of having sex with animals on
a Tennessee farm.
So one of the same people that was in
that group,
the guy.
What did they grow out of it?
Of course.
I mean,
the way you're hardwired is the way
you're hardwired.
It's like,
I don't know about all that.
I would think the ones that my friend
got fucked to death.
I might want to reconsider it.
So yeah,
you would think that sensible,
but it's.
I mean the thing is like being gay or
something.
I always get in trouble because when we
talk about pedophilia and stuff like
that,
I sort of make the same analogy,
which is I have.
I mean whilst it's the worst conceivable
thing that I can imagine anyone doing
morally,
I have some sympathy for people who are
hard wired in such a way that they get a
hard on from infants or animals or
something.
Right?
I mean,
the reason I'm not a pedophile is not
because I'm morally superior is because
I've never been attracted to a,
to anyone who's not post pubescent,
most likely you're right.
Most likely you're right.
The real problem becomes in trying to
decipher what is causing some person to
have these feelings.
Like is it an instance of them being
molested themselves and they were
younger.
Yeah.
Which is Mary.
It's disproportionately.
Yeah.
Is it just an error in the way the brain
works was that
some people have epilepsy.
Yeah,
but this is very different.
This is like clear victimization.
Gayness is to people choosing to be
attracted to the same sex or being
attracted the same sex and choosing to
be with each other rather.
Yeah.
This is different.
I'm just talking about what,
what,
uh,
what you're attracted to.
Right.
If you separate the actual act,
obviously,
obviously it's very,
very different because you're abusing
someone who ha,
who doesn't,
who isn't old enough to be able to
consent.
Uh,
but the act of feeling like you're
attracted a radically to a baby,
right?
Regardless of whether you act on it,
that is something that's subjectively
must just be a horrible prison.
I mean,
imagine if you could never get your
rocks off without torturing and other
person wouldn't be a pretty place to be.
It would be horrific.
Just wonder,
you know,
I,
I would
like to agree with you,
but when I think about it,
I wonder what is the actual process that
leads someone who's.
I mean,
what is going on in their mind?
I can't grasp it.
I can't understand it,
so may I just got to be multifactorial,
right?
It's got a bunch of shit.
It's probably childhood abuse.
It's probably a combination of who
knows,
but that doesn't change the fact that
they're presumably not capable of,
of,
of changing it.
I don't know if that's the case,
but it seems to be true.
The recidivism rate amongst people who
molest children is insanely high.
Absolutely.
Give them the option of chemical
castration as much additive to jail and
then just have them with low libido
goes.
The problem becomes whether or not it's
actually sexual or whether it's
psychological and if it's uniform,
like some people might be sexually
attracted to children in some way that
you could cure with chemical castration,
whereas some of them might be
psychologically attracted to the
dominance and to like what they say
about rape,
right?
That rape isn't really about sex and a
lot of the cases,
obviously in some cases it's about sex,
but in some cases it's not.
It's about power and dominance and how
many people.
It's not a sexual thing.
What if they wound up because they
couldn't get it up.
They wound up just doing things to kids
in a fucked up way because they wanted
to control them and dominate them.
Well then they're just being dicks,
but I mean it might be the origin of it
all.
I mean there,
there might be a bunch of different
versions of this and that's for them.
That might be the origin of it at all.
They might be just they want to torture
people.
Yep.
I mean there's associate pass out there,
the psychopaths.
There's people that are just fucked.
Their brain is fucked.
When you hear about a serial killer,
I mean,
is there a chemical castration for a
serial killer to stop them from enjoying
killing people?
No,
but I've spoken to experts about
pedophilia who say like,
what you want to do,
we're making a mistake at the moment by
demonizing the condition rather than
demonizing the act.
Right,
so what do you want to do is set up a
scenario in which it's possible for a 15
year old kid who realizes that he's
attracted to infants to go to a
psychiatrist and get help and talk about
his options without feeling like he is a
total monster just because he's having
those feelings.
It's hard for us to think that way
because if he acted on those feelings,
he would be a monster,
but you want to find.
You want him to be able to avail himself
of whatever kind of medical treatment is
available rather than just going out and
hiding in the shadows and doing and
committing monstrous acts.
I don't know how to get around that.
I don't need.
I don't think anybody does.
I mean think,
think,
think.
It's one of the reasons why this is such
a compelling subject is because it's one
of the most horrific things,
like there's some horrific,
like undeniably horrific things that
people are capable of doing.
Murders,
one of them,
red is one of them.
Torture,
torture.
This is right up there.
It's right up there with torture with
Isis beheadings and shit.
There was a guy on a talk show once that
was talking about his.
He's compelled to have sex with children
and he's been sexually attracted to
children all of his life,
but he fights it off and he doesn't
do anything about it.
He wanted people to understand it and he
was talking about it openly and I was
like,
first of all,
how brave is this guy that he's willing
to go on television and do these
interviews and talk about his compulsion
even though he says he's innocent of the
actual act itself.
He has this compulsion and I think the
spectrum of a different ways that the
mind functions is so complex and so
confusing as to what's the origin of
these behavior patterns.
Is it because of abuse is because of a
malfunction?
Is it a,
is there a tumor like what the fuck is
going on in someone's brain that leads
them down these paths and I don't think
that's been answered.
No,
I mean what?
Look at the take it back to be best
reality and like having a,
giving a horse a blow job.
Like is there anything necessarily
unethical about giving a host of blow
job?
Is the horses pushing back?
I say no.
What if?
Yeah,
exactly.
So yeah,
if you offer up your butt to a horse and
he's.
And he's just digging in there.
I'm telling you though,
like what is morally,
what is actually morally wrong with
fucking a horse?
If the horse is into it,
well the horse fucks you.
First of all the horses atop
the video of the guy getting fucked to
death by the horse though is horrific.
Of course available.
How is he not able to get out of the
situation with the horse out and pin?
Those are the video starts out with a
buddy of mine sent this to me.
I watched it 100 times to my computer
right now,
the screensaver.
It's in there.
I just copy and I put it on.
Little flash drives leaving around my
house just in case somebody decided to
delete it off the Internet.
I'm the guy.
It's the video starts out and the guy is
naked and he's bent over bale of Hay and
then his friend,
I use air quotes,
grabs a horse his penis and leaves it up
to his butt.
And you're like,
there is no fucking way.
And then what does that even happen?
How?
Like what kind of what?
No,
he's up in his laptop.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Here we go.
Don't be scared.
Homey.com.
What do you mean how,
I mean,
the guy's just got a giant,
but it's really that simple.
I know that like,
you gotta like you gotTa Lube up a
little bit beforehand,
you're going to make sure that you're
available,
but
that's a lot.
That's a lot of fingers.
You got to put it in before the horse
can go.
Yeah,
there's a lot going on there.
It's not that simple.
Um,
it's just,
it's again,
it's one of those things like,
what the fuck is it about a person's
mind that allows that in there?
Yeah.
What and how do you get from A.
I think this would be an amazing thing
to try to actually being there in the
bond,
like straddled over the bale of Hay.
I don't know how you.
I'd be too.
I'd be too bashful.
Even if I wanted to do it,
I'll be too.
It's adorable.
I wouldn't have the guts
I think.
I mean I'm obviously,
I'm just thinking what the fuck do I
know?
But,
but I'm pretending to have a horse
walker.
I think there's,
there's just.
Look,
there's a reason why some people love
jazz music and there's some people that
love basketball and some people like
sailing,
some people hate the water and some
people want to sunbathe all day and some
people want to only go out at night and
we're plucking people vary a lot.
And in this gigantic broad variance of
human beings every now and then put one
pressure cooker spits out a doodle x get
fucked by a horse.
Yeah,
I totally take that,
but what I mean is I'm amazed at the,
at the people who can,
who can translate their latent mental
desires into actual real world
experiences,
whether that's climbing Mount Everest.
I mean there's all kinds of things I'd
like to do.
Joe's eyes just getting real life as he
looks at something on his laptop.
I'm trying try to find Mr. I found it,
Mr. like whether it's a,
I'd like to go scuba diving with sharks.
I'd like to go,
uh,
you know,
I'd like to go scuba diving under
Antarctic ice,
but I haven't done it because I'm too
much of a pussy and I'm too much of a
pussy to get raped by a horse.
That's what I'm saying,
dude.
It's not my thing.
I don't get it.
Why is it in the meantime I'm going to
plug my podcast,
which is which people should go and
check out way the people alive.
We have paypal as well.
One word,
uh,
and you can find it on the.
We basically get three interesting
people in a bar and we all talk about
about what's going on in the world.
Jim Norton,
Artie Lange,
beautiful.
Looks like that.
Great.
Well New York's a good spot to do that.
A lot of opinionated people.
Yeah,
it's fantastic.
We did one here as well with Greg
Fitzsimmons and uh,
Fred's dollar and Zach Craig are funny
people and uh,
Joe was on it as well.
If you want to check out episode 30,
episode 30 Joe Rogan bars that,
uh,
that particular one is pine box rock
shop,
which is where we used to do it.
That was in,
it was great.
That place looks awesome.
And now we do it in Williamsburg.
Oh,
of course you do.
How dare Bushwick.
Do you have to roll up the,
the cops of your pants?
No,
it wouldn't be a tide.
It'd be like a bow tie,
like done Sinatra Style and talked or.
Exactly around my neck.
And he found the video.
I want to say some fucking.
Here it is.
I don't.
Do I want to say this?
Able to undo this.
Am I going to able to unsee this?
Will make sure that he doesn't.
It doesn't get shown on screen.
Jamie,
starring Mr Han's.
So here's the gentlemen.
There's a little dark,
it looks like a night vision type thing
because the guys lifting the horse's
front,
legs are on his shoulders or another
horse.
His front legs are on the Hay and the
Horse is dick and it's a Holla.
Look at this.
No,
I don't want to be seeing this.
Dare he cued up and the guy's having a
hard time getting it in at first.
Right?
And then
it goes all the way.
And is that one?
It was just on the son.
Yeah,
he died.
Sounds.
Do you hear the sound?
Yes.
And now the Dick comes out and it's got
liquid all over like,
oh,
is that what it was?
Yeah.
Can't look anymore.
Wonder if I can go to jail for having
that.
Like it's totally illegal.
I'm like,
I'm feeling I'm feeling a little
violated.
Right?
Should a guy died that way.
I just saw him in dying from a Dick
Eighty minutes ago.
I pulled into the car park here on a
beautiful California day and if you'd
told me then that in 80 minutes time I
would have just watched a man die from
being anal.
He raped by a horse.
How about the sound he makes?
I wouldn't have believed you when you
hear the sound again.
No,
I don't want to hear the sound again.
Joe.
This is a sound pleasant conversation is
pleasant.
What about doesn't happen to us.
We should be happy.
Be Happy.
We figured out a way to not have this
happen to us.
Yeah.
It's pretty easy to not have that happen
to you.
There are.
There are so many things that have to
happen in order for that to happen.
Okay.
I hear that.
That's the moment in which is which
horses.
Penis goes through his intestine and
into his head.
That's called.
That's a wrap.
That's a wrap for this life.
Folks.
Take care of.
See the next dimension.
Gilis fucking way to die.
The Darwin awards.
There's one who maybe lost.
Awesome.
Maybe it's better than being in a
nursing home and having some guy kick
you.
Isn't there anything in between that
allows my only two options?
Either they get to be in a nursing home
and said,
somebody kicked me.
I get to get mainly raped to death by a
horse.
That's it,
we're options,
but I mean,
listen,
my point of view is that this guy in
getting fucked to death by a horse
created this video and this video has
provided me with hundreds of hours of
entertainment that I would have never
gotten without this guide of videos.
Only one minute long.
If you have 100 times.
I've watched it so many times,
I'm exaggerating,
but think about all the people
throughout the world who will now Google
Mr Han's find that video.
I'm sure it's up there somewhere.
[inaudible] laugh their fucking ass off.
Like that guy probably gave all those
people a burst of happiness like through
his death.
Like do you think about like what you've
done in life and what having those
experiences and showing them to other
people,
what impact it has on them.
How many people have watched people like
do those,
those bird suits,
the squirrel suits where they jump off
buildings and shit and they fly around
and you watch me get a thrill out of it.
Like,
whoa.
You watch those videos.
You get a thrill out of that,
right?
Yeah.
Gotcha guy.
Bungee jumping and get a thrill.
Yeah.
Watch this and millions of people.
Sure.
I think.
I think it.
Does that make you happy?
The same way that the birdman videos
make you happy?
Yes.
There's a difference here at dude dies
getting anal.
He raped by a horse.
Bird guys die all the time.
Yeah.
I wouldn't want to save trees and shit.
These motherfuckers.
See that's what I'm talking about.
This is a humble bored on the road,
on the edge of the top of a skyscraper.
These guys are spinning around one of
these.
First of all,
you're counting on these Chinese lithium
ion batteries.
They were put together by slaves.
Who knows if they're going to burst into
flames.
This guy's doing handstands.
He's doing fucking handstands on top of
a skyscraper.
What
does that Dubai's?
Yes.
Where is he?
It looks like I can't watch this.
No,
he's perfect example.
If you saw that like that gives you a
thrill,
but if one of those guys did that and
then when flying off the building like
what did.
I wouldn't like what if Mr. Hands.
That was a video where he lived because
he got fucked to death.
A gang.
I mean,
you got fucked a gang at times where you
get fucked to death.
I'd be,
I'd be happier.
I'd be happier if he lived,
but then I wouldn't know.
I also wouldn't be happy about that.
I'm just enjoying the entire Mr Han's
experienced Joe Rogan.
What if you met him and then he was
annoying you?
I wish that guy got fucked to death.
He probably would be.
Did you hear,
did you hear that Oklahoma has had to
change there.
I was just looking this up.
But when we were talking about
pedophilia that uh,
there was a rape case in.
This is not something to laugh about,
but it is interesting about how we
define rape were a 17 year old kid.
This was last month.
Uh,
and a 16 year old.
He made her.
Well,
here's what happened.
She was really drunk.
They'd been drinking in the park with
some friends.
He gave her a ride home.
She woke up,
I think in the middle of the night,
completely deliriously drunk,
and her mother or grandmother took her
to the hospital because she was so
drunk.
She woke up in hospital.
First thing she kind of really
remembered was the doctor's asking her
what kind of sexual activity she had
happened because they'd found a some of
the 17 year old's DNA around her mouth
and on her legs.
She said,
I've got no recollection.
They went to the guy and he said,
yes,
you want it to give me a blow job,
and she gave me a blow job when she was
like,
blackout drunk.
So she charges him for rape and the
Oklahoma court found that it wasn't
forcible rape,
so now they're having to change
Oklahoma's laws because the only thing
that it would have been that would have
like,
it basically has to be forcible.
It's called forceable sodomy.
Right.
And if the judge was saying if a victim
is so intoxicated that they are
completely unconscious,
then it's not actually forcible because
there's nothing like.
They weren't forced to do it.
They didn't even know that they were or
weren't doing it.
Jesus.
Well,
how do you define that then?
exactly.
I don't know,
but I mean clearly you should not be
going around putting your Dick in
unconscious sixteen-year-olds mouths
clearly,
but at the same time I can sort of
understand that maybe it's not the same
level of horribleness as like just flat
out raping somebody.
There's
also the problem with the girl possibly
consenting at the time just being so
fucked up.
She doesn't remember consenting.
Right?
Especially she's 16 and it's one of her
first ever sexual experiences or first
ever drunk sexual experiences we should
assume.
Yes.
So it is entirely possible that this boy
who was only a few months older than her
didn't have the wherewithal to
understand that she was compromised to
the point where she couldn't consent.
So who,
who are both drunk,
that gets real weird.
It gets real weird and we don't know
exactly what words were exchanged.
What actually did happen,
what the history of these two together
was like.
We don't know.
I mean,
if I had to,
if I had a son,
I would have to say now,
just never ever have any sexual
relations with anybody who's
drunk because that's frankly,
it's like getting fucked when they're
drunk.
Guys like fucking their girlfriends when
they're drunk.
What do you mean?
Some everybody who like who didn't.
Who's early sexual experiences with,
with done sober what,
what have you.
You're both drunk like that's.
There was a big thing that feminists
were trying to push for a while and they
kind of abandoned it because they
realized that it literally makes 90
percent of the population a rapist and
they were saying you shouldn't have sex.
Even with your husband.
If your husband is drunk and you're
sober,
don't have sex with them.
Yeah.
Logistically saying that old drunk sex
is non consensual sex with because it's
full.
Makes it ripe.
You can't consent.
But then the argument becomes,
well,
how come you're responsible for driving
your car when you're drunk?
You're responsible for that.
If you get caught,
you're know you're not supposed to drive
your car when you're drunk.
It's not like,
oh,
I was too drunk.
I couldn't consent to drive my car.
No,
you're responsible.
You're a fucking adult.
You responsible for violence.
You can't beat somebody up and say,
well,
I didn't know I was drunk,
but when it comes to sexuality for
whatever reason,
you're not responsible for your actions.
If you're intoxicated,
well you are.
If you.
If you have the right pissed,
not just not the right p,
know that women were saying this is part
of the argument that of man fucks you
and he's drunk and you're sober.
Even though he's the.
He's the proactive one,
right?
That he's being.
He's being raped.
Yes.
That sex with a drunk person is rape
because they cannot consent.
Well then you might as well just as you
say,
make every single activity that you do
while drunk,
but the real problem becomes it becomes
an attack on men because it's very,
very rare that any woman ever gets in
trouble for having sex with a man that's
drunk,
but women and men have both been drunk
and the men have been accused of being
rapist.
Whereas a woman wasn't.
That was the Occidental University then.
Yeah,
that's right.
College or university?
What is it?
College College,
I think.
Yeah,
I think so.
Uh,
I mean that was the guy suing and
frustrated.
Let me so much because this is one of
those areas where like Islam or like
political correctness or like black
lives matter.
I feel like the moment you try to
introduce nuance you can be very quickly
taken out of context and accused of
being pro that thing like 100 percent,
you know,
because I'll say something like this and
then peer supporters of mine on twitter
will be like,
yeah,
like fuck her.
Or like,
you know,
let's.
Right,
but the day that is not what I'm saying
that whatsoever.
That's why it's horrific that they can
take what you're doing right now and
take it and make a little youtube clip
out of it.
Take that clip and put a title on it.
Josh Zap thinks rapes.
Okay.
Exactly.
That's right.
It's really not.
I do think it's okay.
In fact,
I encourage everybody to go out and
write
a
funny,
no place for jokes.
No,
no,
no more.
No more jokes.
But a Dojo.
Yeah.
If like if,
if I were to say for example that a
preying upon somebody,
praying upon a woman with like a knife
and forcing her against her will to have
sex with you is a class of behavior then
coming in an unconscious in your
unconscious girlfriend's mouth.
Would that like is that,
is it.
Have we gotten to a stage where it's
just not possible to even talk about
that because we just have to keep
mouthing the slogan of sexual violence
is unacceptable all the time.
Therefore there's no way of even
distinguishing in the law between
different levels.
You know,
someone who had a boyfriend,
a 17 year old boyfriend who makes a
mistake,
should go to jail for just the same
length of time as a repeat serial
Predator who preys upon women.
Well,
we don't want to admit that there is any
difference and that all these things are
exactly the same and one of the reasons
why,
because because what you just said,
just even introducing it as a
possibility.
Like there might be a variation.
There might be a there,
there might be a grade of like,
this is a level 10 rate,
but this is a level nine rape.
This is level eight.
Like,
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
As soon as you start getting into that,
it's almost like you're a rape apologist
or you a rape supporter,
or we want to be able to boil things
until fucking headline a clickbait
headline and spit it out there.
Here's my thoughts on rape,
you know,
and that's why the idea of everyone
who's drunk is getting raped is so
ridiculous because it's like we've all
been with someone that we love and we
got drunk and we wanted to have sex with
them when we did.
No one got raped.
Well,
and it's not only ridiculous,
it's also demeaning to the victims of
really terrible,
right?
Yes.
Right.
I mean,
it's also diminishes.
They have their legitimate concern.
It's also insanely sexist because it
shows women as being these people that
can't make good decisions while they're
intoxicated.
Whereas the men know exactly what
they're doing,
so they raped the woman.
So the man and the women,
even though they're both engaging in the
exact same,
the exact same act,
they're both saying they want to do it.
The man is the,
he's the attacker.
Whereas the woman is an innocent person
who doesn't know any better because
she's drunk.
There was a pace on the other.
I was waiting on the plane in the Sunday
Times,
uh,
yesterday about the woods survivor.
How the woods survivor has been,
has,
is getting used now.
It was really interesting patients in
the New York Times magazine almost with
survivor.
I am.
I had the flu and they were making the
point that like when everything,
when every act of sexual violence gets,
gets labeled with,
I'm a survivor of sexual violence.
Even if that was just unwanted touching
on the subway,
then like,
what does it mean to be.
What do you mean you survived it?
Were you ever.
Were you ever going to die because
someone likes slapped you on the ass in
the workplace?
Not to,
not to say that it's okay to do that,
but again,
you're just compressing all of the
actual real horrifying survival stories
down to the level of someone looked at
me funny and
yeah,
you can't call it survival,
but you're a victim.
Yeah.
Bit survivor sounds better.
It sounds much use.
You're barely made it.
Survivor of bullying.
I saw that someone someone wrote were a
survivor of high school bullying.
Yeah.
What the fuck happened to you?
What?
What was so bad?
What did someone try to stab you?
Did somebody beat you up to the point of
view almost dying or did someone just
annoy you all the time and make you feel
bad?
Is that what happened?
There are a few.
There are only a few scenarios in which
I think you should legitimately be
called a survivor.
A bear attack wouldn't be one of them.
Shark attack,
shark attack.
Another one.
Basically any kind of large carnivorous
animal attacking you online.
You man done.
You go through it,
but through them all tiger or leopard,
monkey.
Mayor Killed by monkeys.
Really?
She here that maybe we'll the olive
African,
African elephants are going to be dead
in 20 years.
What?
That's what I was reading an article.
They were saying there's places in
Africa that have so many elephants.
They have to kill them.
Yeah,
I know.
But there is enormous.
This is one of the things that people
don't understand.
Why is he in an area of Africa?
Africa itself is fucking huge.
Yes.
And there's a conference with all of the
people who are.
There we go.
No magazine.
African Americans could be extinct
within 20 days
if poaching maybe
because all of the,
uh,
there's a conference of African leaders
at the moment going on to figure out how
they can,
uh,
they can tackle poaching.
Wow.
But Africa is a continent.
It's fun.
Enormous city.
It's bigger than almost all the
continents combined.
I know.
But if you keep killing them at a much
larger rate than they procreate,
so over time you're going to wipe them
all out.
What's scary is people are still hunting
them.
Yeah.
On top of the poaching.
So there's,
there's these places that develop
African hunting safaris for elephants.
So they raise elephants in these high
fence operations just so people can go
over there and hunt them and that's one
of the ways that they ensure that their
population stay high.
It's very fucking twisted.
Right?
Trump's kids,
you've seen those photos of trump's sons
holding our son Shit.
Holding up Jaguars and yeah,
that whole African hunting thing.
I.
I tell people if you think it's bizarre
with from a cursory glance,
you gotta look at Luther's documentary
about these
good honey.
We mentioned this before because I've
been a fan since day since day one,
but that,
that episode is just
killer.
That one's nuts.
I love the end of it.
When the guy's going crazy,
you need to ask him all the questions
was like Africa,
he's fucked,
fucked.
He's fit.
You don't understand content.
It is fucked.
And when he was saying that,
really kind of get it.
I hate that term.
Poacher two poachers that dark term
because a lot of those people that are
poaching or just fucking starving,
they're poor as fuck.
We have this idea that these are like
these mercenaries that come over to
steal ivory so they can make money off
of it.
There's a lot of people that are killing
these animals that are homeless,
have no way out.
There's nothing there for them.
They don't know any better.
They're not educated.
They're just starving and someone says,
Hey,
you give me that Rhino Horn.
I'll give you 500 bucks,
and they're like,
Holy Shit,
500 bucks,
and then they'll kill as many rhinos as
they can before they get killed.
It's so dark.
I have a friend who went over there.
You went over there to Africa and he
said he was on a hunting safari where
they have these enormous places where
they have these hunting camps where
there it's a 10 hour drive to the other
side of the ranch.
I mean enormous,
enormous territory and while they were
there,
they encountered these quote unquote
poachers and he said,
the people from the honey cam just shoot
it.
The poachers,
they just shoot at them like the
coyotes.
They shoot it.
These people like,
I mean they don't even give them a
chance,
they just shoot at them and they're
allowed to.
It's illegal and when they shoot
someone,
he asked him like,
what do you do if you kill someone?
And he's like,
most of the time we let the hyenas
sorted out.
Most of the time we let the hyenas
short.
Let me just think about how fucking
crazy life is in that part of the world
that this guy is actually saying that
we're pretty fucking lucky and I'm
guessing that trump's kids are probably
not that poor that they need to be
hunting that way.
They're over there doing those.
Um,
big game so far.
Yeah.
There's one is a photo of one of them
holding up an elephant's trunk.
Just the,
just the dismembered trunk.
Just a big old nose just hanging in
there because little shit.
What?
Trump couldn't
pull that up.
I want to see it.
Yeah,
I do.
I do know that they've had to kill
elephants,
certain areas that have infiltrated
these villages and start killing people.
But the question is what,
how,
how fucked with did they get before they
started killing people?
Like what's the actual reality?
Well,
I mean as you,
as you say,
like what's the reality of the human
beings line?
So we're doing this as well.
I was just in a,
I would,
when I was coming back from Australia,
I spent a week in India and uh,
in Mumbai did,
there's this company that does a tools
of the biggest slum in Asia,
like the kind of slumdog millionaire
slum.
And they,
and they work in development there with
some of the poorest people in the world.
There's an area,
it's an area of the site,
it's called Dharavi and it's in Mumbai,
it's the,
it's one of the biggest slums in the
world and it's an area the size of half
the size of central park and it's got
like 2 million people living in it.
Jesus.
And they do development stuff there.
And you can walk through and these,
I mean you feel a little bit weird like
going through this place,
like it's almost like disaster porn or
something like huge canals which just
smell.
It's just shit and like dead dogs and
peace and just just,
I mean,
but you know,
what people are getting on with life,
the law firm,
there are,
there are soccer balls that plan with
like,
you know,
kids are scrounging around in the dust
and the dirt and the grime people.
People are fucking resilient in amazing
ways.
Well they weren't.
We wouldn't be here because it's 2016
shit where you go to the supermarket and
you buy a chicken breast.
A wish.
So out of touch touch the most recent of
recent.
I mean that's one of the more amazing
things about how upset people are about
how life is today.
Like God damn it,
it's the easiest it's ever been ever.
This is the greatest time in the history
of the world.
Yeah.
And everyone's.
The Sky's falling
when we don't.
And as our lives get better and better,
we don't.
We fail to accurately calibrate like
any,
any benchmark.
Like you always.
It's like there was a study that came
out that 47 percent of Americans could
not come up with $400 if they needed to.
If they suddenly got an unexpected bill,
right?
Almost half of Americans in other words
are right on the brink of the poverty
line,
but in terms of just being able to come
up with cash,
but how do we get into and get ourselves
into that scenario?
We,
we fail to recognize how prosperous we
are.
I mean,
if most of the people who are listening
to this podcast are in the top five
percent of income earners globally,
more than a lot of them will be in the
top one percent and the top one percent,
20,
34 grand a year of global global
incomes.
Is it?
Okay.
So there you go.
And even even within the United States,
I mean the top five percent is,
is surprisingly low.
It's like 50 grand or something.
Well,
I think it's more than that,
but I think it's like mm.
I thought it was either way.
Either way.
We are incredibly blessed and amazingly
fortunate and it's so hard to snip
hassles out of our complacency and
realize fuck.
Things actually are surprisingly
convenient and easy for us.
Yeah,
I'm gonna stop whining overall,
but if you're.
One of those people that can't come up
with that 400 bucks and the $400 bill
comes,
it seems daunting.
Yes.
And I'm not blaming,
blaming people for it.
I've been in,
I've had times in my life where I've
been below,
you know,
wellwell onto water.
Sure.
We all have.
But I think that's also probably one of
the reasons why you became ambitious and
why you worked hard and why you're in a
position right now where you don't have
to worry about that.
Yeah.
Because you worked your way through it
and you figure your way through
adversity,
you know,
has an interesting subject because,
um,
I had uh,
Eddie Wong in really recently and he
brought up something that I thought was
preposterous.
He brought up the idea of what do they
call it,
basic income where you give people
$35,000 a year to live.
And I was like,
get the fuck Outta here.
But then I started looking into it and
when I started looking into it,
one of the things that I was intrigued
by was like,
okay,
how much of crime and how much of
people's aberrant behavior could be.
You could write it off to them being
desperate and needy and poor and feeling
hopeless and how much of that crime
would not take place if they got $35,000
a year and if these are people that are
just going to fuck off anyway,
but this way they're gonna fuck off,
but they won't be committing crime
because they're going to have a steady
income for the rest of their life.
Is that feasible?
Like how much money is there out there?
Could you give everybody in America
$35,000 a year up to a certain number,
right?
Once you hit a cutoff,
like you hit like I would say like a
quarter million dollars a year,
you don't get the 35 grand anymore.
Like you have plenty of money.
Here's the.
Here's the thing that the great utility
of a basic income is that you don't have
to fill out forms and prove that you
deserve it,
that everybody gets it because it's so.
It's super,
super simple.
Where's it coming from?
Well,
yes.
You can't start with $35,000 a year,
but you can.
I've heard proposals,
look,
Alaska has this already.
They just call it an oil revenue.
Everyone in Alaska gets a check from the
government,
which is a cut of Alaska's oil revenue.
They basically get a universal basic
income.
It's not nearly enough to live on.
It might be a thousand dollars a year or
something.
I'll be corrected on this,
but there are all kinds of experiments.
I had Felix Salmon on my podcast.
Who's at?
Who's over at slate?
I don't know if you know him.
He's a.
he's a money.
A big,
very interesting money guy.
He has a podcast called the money put
the slate money podcast and he's a big
advocate of this idea and there's a.
yeah,
you should.
You should get him on and he's great.
He's based out of New York,
but he's Felix Salmon.
Like the fish,
I'll,
I'll send you his.
I'll text you his details after,
after the show.
Um,
I'm making a note to myself right now.
Uh,
and that he was basically saying there's
a place in like there's a jurisdiction
and I think Finland or Sweden,
which has actually trying this out just
to test the proposition of like how much
less will people actually work.
If everyone gets a basic income,
how much of a deterrent will it be
bothering to get a job?
How much will it cost?
Well,
$35,000 a year would be would be a lot
of money.
Well,
30,000 times 300 million
is the thing you would start.
It are a lot of savings,
right?
So here's the weird thing about this
idea is that libertarians like it as
well as progressives because for
Libertarians,
this is a way of getting rid of social
security,
getting rid of Medicare,
getting rid of food stamps,
getting rid of all of these different
programs and streamlining everything.
I mean,
think of how hard it is to do your taxes
and to like to fill in the forms and to
figure out what you're supposed to get.
This would just be a check from the
government.
Everybody gets it,
no questions asked.
You go out and you buy what you need to
buy.
Now with healthcare is expensive as it
is in the United States.
That's not going to work for old people.
They're going to be able to pay for our
healthcare and health insurance and also
social security and also survive on
$35,000 a year,
but if you just thinking in terms of the
budget,
if you got rid of those massive line
items in the budget,
medicare and social security and so on,
then you will be able to start to think
about affording things like that.
So you might start with just $10,000 a
year for everybody and work your way up
from there and just test it.
I think a stat,
I think one of the states should start
to do it on a.
on a more aggressive level,
just like Colorado is going to be
playing around with universal healthcare
at the November election because we'd
baby,
we'd money.
Come on son.
I love it.
I think it's an interesting idea of
Colorado decided to do that and decided
to give every state resident $35,000 a
year.
The problem would be everybody moved.
Everybody moved there,
right?
Yeah.
But,
but I
think this is a possible solution to the
rise of robots
that's not as crazy as crazy as
it sounds like.
I've just been smoking weed at the time.
Um,
I,
I think that they were going to be fewer
and fewer jobs for individual human
beings as robots get better and better
at making shit.
No,
I think everybody believes that and also
that they're going to be cheaper and
cheaper to get robots.
Yeah.
And so what happens when you've got a,
you know,
silicon valley and Hollywood pumping out
huge amounts of stuff which,
which give us a massive GDP.
A larger GDP growth is still happening,
but it takes fewer and fewer people.
I mean,
Uber is a transportation company that
doesn't employ anybody.
Facebook doesn't employ very many
people.
Uber's been challenged on that.
That gets really problematic when you
deal without the actual labor laws and
things.
One.
But that's one particular scenario.
I think one thing that's happening
that's interesting is that people are
gravitating more towards craftsmanship
and crafts and people are gravitating
towards handmade things and they're
gravitating towards things that actually
have.
Like if somebody.
Like if I go to a store and I buy a
knife,
okay,
I buy a kitchen knife,
um,
you know,
it's nice,
it cuts my vegetables.
But if I know a guy who's a blacksmith
and he actually makes a knife and he and
he does all this craftsmanship and puts
together the handle.
And that to me is like there's a feeling
that you get from this object when
you're using it.
Like this is someone's craftsmanship.
This is someone's creation.
Someone learned a trade.
They learned the art form of making a,
a functional piece of kitchen ware.
And I'm using it here.
But speaking of the 47 percent of people
who kind of come up with $400,
I mean you,
you can afford to care about such
things,
but the majority of people are just
going to buy a pack of steak knives for
1499 at Walmart.
Right?
That's true.
But that's also the case with
everything,
with clothes and with all sorts of
different things.
But for the person themselves,
someone who learns a trade and someone
who learns a crap,
someone that learns how to make
furniture,
I hopefully go more that way and become
less of a disposable.
Just China fueled like commodity
consuming country and becoming cameron
about the quality of stuff.
In some ways I think we are for people
who can afford it.
I think it's becoming for the people
that are looking for something to do
like the that has meaning in their life.
There's like extreme meaning and hand
produced.
Things like when you buy something from
someone like a,
a piece of office furniture and you
know,
this guy made it like someone made my
friend Eric made this table.
Yeah.
Unless table.
We hired them to do it.
Yeah.
He got on your mind.
Not only that,
look at the fucking welding and all the
different shit to it.
I mean this guy,
he did an awesome job in,
in creating this and there's.
There's like something to someone making
something.
You're always going to remember
where it came from.
Yeah,
that's right.
It's a cutting board.
Somebody puts together a nice hard wood
cutting board,
you know,
like you like,
oh,
this is a guy made this.
Well maybe,
and then in terms of the question of
whether or not people can afford to buy
such things,
maybe the universal basic income means
that we don't necessarily have to all be
buying those things because the people
who make them are going to be getting
the universal income.
This is the theory which is that the.
If the overall pie is bigger every year,
then you just have to figure out how to
allocate the tax.
That Pie.
Maybe that means that you have to have
super huge taxes on silicon valley in
some way in order to fund the universal
basic income,
but if there aren't enough people being
employed to fund what the government
needs to do on the basis of a
conventional income tax,
but there's more stuff being produced
going around,
there's more wealth,
you should still be able to extract that
well somehow and maybe people can.
More people can if everyone got a
universal basic income and people can
become a poet or an autism,
all knife maker or a table maker and
they don't need to necessarily be able
to sustain their living doing that.
There are more opportunities for
creative
output.
What's interesting to me is that it
might relax.
People I think will certainly.
Yeah.
I mean imagine not having to worry about
where the next meal comes from.
Well,
that's where it started ringing true to
me.
Like I was making fun of Eddie talking
about it,
but then I thought about it for quite a
while afterwards and then I started
reading some things on it that sort of
reinforced these new ideas that I was
starting to play around with and one of
the things that I was thinking is how
much of what people do that's fucked up
they're doing out of desperation or out
of frustration and how much could that
be eliminated and how much would that
change society and are ambitious people
just.
I mean you're not talking about anything
where you could fucking go ball and on
35 grand a year or 12 grand a year,
whatever you,
whatever you give them 12 grand a year.
Let's say that you're barely going to
live off that,
but you have enough money for food.
You have enough money for food.
Hopefully you got enough money for rent.
If you get some part time jobs here are
there.
Hopefully you can survive,
but you're less desperate and more
dependent upon society.
You're more dependent upon the rules of
society.
Well,
I mean to see what countries look like
when that sort of thing happens,
even though it's not a perfect analogy,
just look at the countries of northern
Europe or even you were talking about
Melbourne,
you know,
a country like Australia where it's by
no means perfect.
There are still poor people,
but gee,
the levels of poverty are a lot less
than they are here and the number of
people in grinding abject,
absolute poverty is almost nonexistent
in comparison to the way that you see it
here in the states because we have
social,
we have social safety nets that are just
much more robust,
but you only have 20 million people,
but even so,
I never buy that argument.
It everything is scalable.
Joe.
The fact that we.
Yeah,
because we only have 20 million people,
but we also have a proportionately fewer
number of taxpayers.
You have.
You have tons more people and tons more
taxpayers.
Like look at Germany.
Germany's a big country that's.
They've got 80 million people and they
manage to have very,
very few people basically know people in
abject poverty.
That might be a bad example because
they're a mess right now.
Like you know,
Germany is a mess with the immigration
issue.
That is separate,
but they're economy is not a mess.
Yeah,
but they're socially a massive scale.
I mean that's because of Syria.
Well,
yeah.
Well there's.
That whole thing is so bizarre where the
mayor of Munich was telling girls to
keep to themselves and not look at
anybody and it's crazy.
You know,
I'm not advocating that America should
invite a 10 million on stream into
documented Syrians.
Fucking insane.
But you could certainly.
It could certainly imagine a system in
which it was a lot easier for people to
wait.
You did just didn't have entrenched
levels of,
of grinding poverty.
I just wonder what the cost would be and
what could.
Is there a mathematical equation that
can be worked out where that makes
sense.
I wonder,
you know,
not doing the math.
Felix Felix will know who's Felix?
Felix Salmon,
the English guy who does.
I thought it was like Siri.
I'm like,
what are you using a windows phone.
You asked Felix.
It sounds like that sounds like
something wholesale Felix's hasn't
really posh English accent,
so it sounds like the kind of person who
you who you would expect to voice one of
those things.
Do you remember ask Jeeves?
Was everybody used to go to that before
Google was around?
I know to ask jeeves.
I mean I didn't have a really useful.
Maybe it was.
Maybe I'm too young or something.
Was it was you typed in [inaudible] dot
com?
Don't remember.
Did you have to phrase things as a
question?
Sounds stupid now.
I don't know.
I don't remember.
I know.
I'm sure I asked jeeves a few things.
I just don't remember what they were.
Now that I'm thinking about it,
James,
show me boobs.
I'll james.
Show me a guy getting raped by a horse.
What's this?
Ask Dot com now.
Oh,
just not asked her a question and it
would tell you the answer.
Where's the tallest waterfall in the.
Okay.
Ask this.
How much would it cost to give all
Americans?
I love saying in dollars.
When you're typing then
okay,
Bam.
Dot Com is not going to help you with
us.
Hey,
you don't look it up.
It would cost 3 trillion to give
everyone $10,000 a year by that time,
the extra two point five and Jesus
Christ.
God.
Damn,
that's great.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Three more than 3 trillion to get to
give him 10 grand a.
okay,
so gs.
9 trillion plus to give everybody
authority,
but you wouldn't give everybody because
everybody who makes over a certain
amount should have to fucking work it
out.
But people are so gross.
They would just stay under $250,000.
I'll make $240.
Not Give Up,
you know,
because if you let over $1 you would.
You would have to.
But I think if you were gonna start
means testing it,
then you didn't have to be a sliding
scale so that you didn't encounter that
problem.
Right?
So if you hit it to 50 then you only get
30.
If you hit two 60 and they get 25,
but then it becomes complicated and that
that negates a lot of the benefit when
you're talking about what you really
want is just a wife desperately poor
people to not be desperately poor.
And there are simpler ways than giving
everybody a universal basic income.
There are simpler ways,
but I think the real work,
the real important thing is figuring out
a way to stop children from growing up
in desperation to stop children from
growing up in an environment like a.
I,
this guy on Michael would,
I got to get back to him this week
because we're working on a new date,
but he was a Baltimore police officer
and he talked in great detail about real
institutional racism in Baltimore where
they,
you know,
they had literally areas where you
couldn't sell black people homes and
this had been established in the 19
sixties.
And because of that,
those areas are still fucked.
Those areas like there,
they're still to this day,
he found something from the 19
seventies,
the,
uh,
the police officers in his district did
where it was like a mandate,
like what they were supposed to do and
where the crime was and he's like,
it was exactly the same place is exactly
the same crimes as they were dealing
with in the 2000.
And he's like,
how few tile and fucking crazy is this
that you're dealing with this pattern
that never gets fixed,
never gets corrected.
And just,
they just,
cops keep arresting the same people in
the same areas for the same problems.
And it's like,
Whoa,
you know,
they've done studies about what the most
effective way to,
uh,
to help poor people is because
oftentimes people on the left will be,
will be in favor of food stamps or like
a bit of public schools and so on.
All of those things are great,
but a lot of recent research suggests
that just giving people money is more
effective than trying to figure out all
of these tweaks because we don't like
giving poor people money because we
think,
well,
they're just gonna spend it on drugs or
they gonna spend it on booze or
something like that with cigarettes,
cigarettes,
or food up here,
but it turns out,
and this applies whether you're talking
about desperately poor people in Africa
or desperately poor people in downtown
Baltimore.
If you give them money,
most people use it for good ends.
The the,
the thing they really want the most is
to eat and be able to pay their bills
and to get out of the situation they're
in.
A minority of people will spend,
will blow it on booze and cigarettes,
but they are a small minority.
Yeah,
I know what their needs are more better
than we know what their needs are.
There's this paternalistic idea that we
always have,
like we have to figure out how to get
people out of poverty.
People know how to get themselves out of
poverty if they just had the resources
to do so,
so just give them a bit of money.
Yeah.
It's also this absolute realization that
this is not a level playing field and
that someone corn in the slums of
Inglewood is not the same as someone who
was born in
so crazy about libertarians when they,
when they go on about how everyone
should be free.
Yeah,
of course.
Everyone should be free.
I am as libertarian as you can get,
but within within the understanding that
it's crazy to say that people are
equally for the person in beverly who's
born in Beverly hills to a white middle
class.
Upper class family is only as free as
the baby born in the slums of Baltimore.
This is crazy.
Of course you should use the,
the,
I think,
the power of the state to be able to
level the playing field a little bit.
Just to skim a little bit off the
Beverly Hills family and give a little
bit to the Baltimore family.
I don't see what's so tyrannical about
that.
Well yeah,
because you're not coming from an even
start point,
right?
So,
and then there's also this notion that
as a country we were only as strong as
the weakest link.
Right?
So if we created a system where we had
less people in desperation,
less people in despair,
less less losers,
we would be more winners will get our
shit together,
we would,
we would produce more,
we'd be more effective.
I wonder.
I just wonder what the actual numbers
are because like how much money is being
spent every year on things that we don't
need,
how much,
how much money from our taxes goes to
bureaucracy and bullshit and it's really
distorted representative government that
most people don't agree with.
How much of that,
how much of it is just fucking cronyism
and handing money back and forth?
Well,
each other,
I'll tell you what,
we don't spend a lot of money and we
don't spend a lot of money on
bureaucracy and waste in your like
people.
People who want to cut government
spending will often say like,
you know,
first thing I'm going to do when I get
into,
when I get to Congress,
as I'm going to repaint,
you know,
my congressional office or something,
or I'm gonna,
you know,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna.
Throw out the fancy stuff and I'm going
to get an old couch like these.
This is not what we're spending our
money on.
What we're spending our money on is the
military and Medicare and social
security basically.
So right in healthcare costs and stopped
and cut the military and you would.
And that's where the big,
the big,
the military.
But then what happened,
son,
let me tell you something.
Freedom Ain't free.
They're going to come over here and take
our jobs and kick our women into the
curb or something.
I've been,
I've been having a twitter argument with
a person who's been saying that,
uh,
that the reason why America's roads are
so bad.
It's because we spend too much on
foreign aid.
That's may do.
I'm sorry.
Fuck.
When am I?
Just say it because I know Britain,
Britain spends three or four times more
per capita on foreign aid.
Sweden spend six times more per capita
if you've seen the road in Sweden.
It really quite nice.
Yeah.
We have more roads,
don't we?
Of course,
but again,
you also have been more mindful.
You have more tax payers to pay for
them.
Just looking at overall numbers.
We spend more money because we have more
roads.
Yeah,
and you spend more money on foreign aid
as well,
but there were more likely to share it.
I'm a petroleum trader.
I'm going to get.
I'm going to be an egg with the opinion.
Here's something.
Here's a players,
a reform which you could support,
which would really help you figure out
where you.
Where the money goes.
When you get your tax bill at the end of
the year,
your tax statement from the irs,
they could as they do in Australia and a
bunch of other countries have a little
bar graph,
a colorful little graph with lines
showing how much you've spent on
everything.
So in Australia,
if you,
if you paid $18,000 in tax that year,
then there's a little bit,
a little purple line on the graph which
says,
you know,
you spent four,
$782 and sixteen cents on Medicare,
spent this much on security,
spend this much on foreign aid and then
you can actually see it there.
That's great.
There's a proposal in front of Congress
which some Democrats are pushing to
bring this in here.
And also to streamline the way that you
do your taxes because in a lot of other
countries,
apart from the states,
you don't have to go through the
rigmarole of filling out all of your
taxes,
the government.
Because when,
when you do a job and you get a,
you have to supply the irs with a 10,
99 or a w two at the end of the year.
Remember that the person who gave you
the 10,
99 or the w two also sent a copy to the
irs.
The irs already has it.
They could just fill it out themselves.
Instead.
They make you do it and it's difficult
and cumbersome.
But in a lot of other countries like the
UK and Australia,
they have the option of just signing off
on it and saying,
yeah,
okay,
this looks good.
You can just do my taxes for me and the
and the proposals to make to simplify
doing your taxes are being pushed by
Democrats.
And I find it wildly ironic that the
people who oppose these policies are
Republicans and Grover Norquist,
the anti tax crusader who you would
think would want to make it easier,
but it's in their interest to make taxes
as difficult to do and as difficult to
understand as possible because they want
you to continue hating taxes as much as
possible.
Also,
the republic,
the military industrial complex that the
Republicans essentially work for.
Don't want you to know how much we spend
on the Pentagon so that they oppose this
bar graph idea because they know that
the biggest line item would be this
massive thing and you'd be like,
do we really need to be spending that
much on the military?
Or is this really a jobs program where
we're building nuclear submarines that
depending on doesn't want important
districts in Delaware,
Delaware,
just so that the,
the we,
we can keep some,
some jobs.
They're in a factory that's producing
munitions that it doesn't,
does it no longer needs to be?
Well,
I think one of the good things about
someone proposing something like that as
you get to look at who's opposing it and
when someone's proposing something that
make sense and it makes it,
unless there's some sort of exorbitant
fee that's involved in giving people a
detailed rundown of where their money
goes,
then you would say,
well,
someone's against transparency and if
you're against transparency or against
freedom,
you fuck your against America.
Play the music,
Jimmy Man,
the free home of the brave.
Goddammit.
I want to know where my fucking taxes
go.
Yes.
If you're anti tax,
then you should be pro transparency and
text.
We found out my taxes.
I went to welfare cigarettes.
That's where they didn't go booze on
pills for the kids.
Yeah.
Imagine we should spend more on.
I just wonder what the number would be
like,
what to do,
the universal basic income.
Yeah.
I wonder what would the number would be
and what would be.
Just try to keep it up.
I'll tell you if I got a rant coming on.
I'll tell you if I got a rant coming on
me right now.
I'm not feeling that America even better
when I do an Australian accent and you
play the US national anthem and it
sounds really weird.
Cognitive dissonance.
I
play at Jamie.
Play the anthem.
Liliana,
let's just get a little of a bit of
patriotism going here.
Mate.
I want to tell you a thing or two about
this,
about the United States,
but talking to you.
I don't know.
Overdo it.
Can't fake it.
All right.
Okay.
What is country?
A Nation of brave,
courageous men and women who fought for
years now.
Centuries.
Okay.
Hold on.
Stop.
What about non binary sexual people,
men or women?
You being transphobic?
Yes.
You're very transphobic.
Sit on my podcast the other day that
people who vote for Hillary because they
voted because they.
Because she's a woman only voting for
her because she's got a vagina.
Someone on twitter said that that was
transferred it because there are women
who don't have vaginas.
Yeah,
I disagree.
Yeah.
There's an x and a y chromosome.
There's a lot of genetics you might
identify with being a woman.
If you've got a dick though,
we have a real problem.
I'm happy to call them limit if they
want to be called women.
I really don't have a problem with it,
but don't cut.
Don't call me.
It's not transphobic for me to make a
generalization that most women have
vaginas.
Um,
I saw an opening to call you transphobic
and I jumped on it because it's there.
So I sank your battleship.
I got 12.
I saw it as they're playing games.
You don't have to have a vagina to be a
woman.
Yeah.
You.
How about fuck you?
Jesus Christ.
What do you think about this North
Carolina law though?
About this?
Is Mrs the bathroom.
I'm so conflicted about this because I
also,
I also got into trouble on my podcast
was talking about this.
So I think it's obviously a silly beat
up and I think that trans people have
been and will continue to use bathrooms,
uh,
and we shouldn't worry about it and I
don't think that people should be
passing laws against it,
but I also think it's disingenuous of
Pro Trans people and I regard myself as
broadly pro trans,
just in the same sense that I'm broadly
pro,
hey,
whatever floats your boat,
just live the life that you want to
live.
Whoever you as do our.
Um,
I do think it's disingenuous when they
start saying that people who have the
outward appearance of the gender on
their birth certificate should be able
to use the opposite a restroom and that
nobody should have a problem with that
because they declare themselves to be
trans.
So I'm talking,
for example about there was,
I saw a facebook argument about this
where a friend of a friend of mine on
facebook is a trans woman who was
assigned male at birth and has no
intention of transitioning at all.
Right?
So she has a beach,
she's a fat guy with a beard who plays
guitar.
And that's what all of her photos are
and she doesn't want to have her dick
cut off and she doesn't want to grow
breasts and she doesn't want to lose her
beard and she's arguing that it's
transphobic to say that she shouldn't be
able to use the women's restroom.
And other people were saying,
you can understand how like a parent
might be concerned if their daughter
went into the girls' restroom and then
what appears to be a large be added fat
man walks in after her,
you know,
that is not necessarily transphobic.
And then all of a sudden she's like,
how dare you say that?
There has not been a single instance of
a trans person abusing this is just like
the gay fear back in the 1970.
If you're claiming that trans people are
more likely to be pedophiles and blah,
blah,
blah.
No,
no,
no.
We're not saying that.
We're just saying,
how do you expect us to know the
difference between you a trans woman who
looks like a man and a man when you're
being reasonable?
And that's the problem.
This is not a reasonable discussion.
Now,
here's what's really ironic,
what we really should be concerned with
is not the trans people we should really
be concerned with is heterosexual people
pretending to be transpeople
heterosexual people who are in fact
sexual predators,
who all they have to do to have to
pretend to be trans.
I mean they would do.
Oh,
I see what you mean.
Like all they will have to do is to wear
a dress and go to the woman's room and
say they're trans and they could do
whatever the fuck they want once they're
in there and that's the real issue is
not the actual trans people.
That's rice people that are using this
very ambiguous law there.
I mean this is a very ambiguous
distinction.
If someone identifies with the opposite
sex without having any outward
appearance of being that opposite sex,
all guy would have to do is say I'm
trans and you can go into a female
restroom.
I think the likely it's not going to
happen.
Yeah.
I don't recognize it's exactly.
It's a possibility,
but again,
it comes back to the conversation about
rape or about Islam or about what about
like black lives matter or whatever.
This is a new what we're trying to have
a nuanced conversation and it's
impossible to have because all you're
allowed to be is either pro trans or
you're a religious evangelical bigot,
right?
Yes.
You're not allowed.
There's no.
There's no middle ground.
We just have to hunker down joe into a
little trenches just and have a war of
attrition.
When I'm on one side and you're on the
other side and the last man fucking
stands,
it's like,
whoa,
Whoa,
one.
We don't passion dial all over again.
Just firing at each other on twitter.
You're not allowed to have a nuanced
perspective.
Don't you think this is a direct result
of the Bush administration like we were
talking about?
I really do think that that's what it
is.
I think everybody was so scared and
conservativism was at at such a high
point that the rebound from that,
the rebound from all the anti gay
hysterica.
I mean that administration was right
with homophobia,
ripe with all sorts of different types
of discrimination.
It was a fucking weird,
weird time dissolves the lift too much
and I think it also fails to recognize
the changes that social media has
brought.
I don't think this would be as bad
altogether.
Yeah.
Twenty four hour media.
Yes.
Social media.
Like Stephen Fry quit in February.
He was one of the first adopters and he
was like,
it used to be this like this,
this lake in the forest where you could
run and jump and play and now it's a
fitted swamp with everyone pissing in
the pool.
I'm a Stephen Fry fan,
but I got to say,
I think he went out like a bitch.
He should have hung in there.
Fuck yeah.
Come on.
That's small group of people can chase
you out of one of the most fucking
easily used forms of free expression the
world has ever known,
but he takes.
Is him making a joke about a dress?
Yeah.
And people shitting on him for making a
joke,
but what?
What,
what?
Why would you even care about the
opinion of people who get upset at you
for making fun of address in his blog
where he was talking about quitting
twitter,
he did begin by saying,
this is not a big deal.
I don't know if this is forever.
I'm not doing this as a stand.
I just feel so much more liberated.
Not going there because you're right.
He is at the pinnacle of his industry.
He was hosting the bloody baptist.
I mean that's like posting the Academy
Awards in the UK,
so he should be big enough to have
people sniping at him.
If you're hosting the Academy Awards.
He's a sniper.
Yeah.
That's what does this whole thing is.
I can understand.
His whole thing is marketing.
People say they're offended,
so he's getting offended by people
mocking him for being offended.
I'm not sure he's offended.
I think he just doesn't want to play
that game.
Okay.
What does that word then?
What?
Where do we looking for upset board?
No upset board and exhausted.
I don't believe you write a whole blog
because you're bored.
I think you're right.
A blog because you're upset.
He was angry,
he was visibly angry or at least
appeared to be through his tweets and
his reactions to people being upset with
him.
I'm making fun of that dress.
I mean,
I just think it's hard sometimes.
Who knows what was going on in his life
when that was going on.
He made that decision as well.
It could have been like a down point in
him in his life.
Emotionally.
You might have realized that might be an
up point because I think he just got
married.
He's getting married.
He's,
you know,
he's dating this guy who's like 50 years
younger than him or something,
so I was getting a lot of us and he's
probably,
he's probably having a great time.
He's like,
I don't need this shit anymore.
They can don't fuck off.
I don't have time for 140 characters
pitch.
Exactly.
But then why does he have time to write
about it?
Then I have to step away.
Why?
It's like when someone would notice it
and then they'd be like,
oh,
well we're Stephen Fry.
Why isn't he responding to things?
It's easy.
You just say,
Hey,
here I am,
I'm going.
I wouldn't be here for awhile,
but what?
Why,
why?
Even if you can't,
if you don't care,
you're gonna leave.
Why even make an announcement?
It's like if someone said to you,
you know,
hey man,
I just thought that your jokes you made
about rape and the Joe Rogan podcast.
We're totally uncalled for,
followed,
followed through the unfollowed dance.
See what I wrote,
but I'm pretty sure I read it.
I wish the audio podcast listeners could
see the Joe Rogan dance that just
happened of like halfway between a down
syndrome child and then
I unfollowed you.
I win in
a day.
This is the national anthem.
It's that thing that they do.
They just want to get your what,
how many people are talking about?
I mean one or two or three people got
mad at him.
No,
no,
no.
I mean,
I,
I take your point.
Sure.
Maybe it's a pussy move,
but it's his life.
He doesn't have to be on twitter if you
don't want to be on twitter.
The problem is he's so great.
Upsets me that he would have that.
That reaction too,
by the way.
I've read the things that people wrote
to him.
It wasn't really that big of a deal.
He made fun of a woman's dress and said
it looked like a garbage bag.
One of his friends.
It's kind of funny,
but of course people are gonna.
React.
Here's what.
Here's what he wrote.
He said,
let us grieve what twitter has become a
stalking ground for the sanctimoniously
self righteous who loved to second guess
to leap to conclusions and be offended.
Worse to be offended on behalf of others
they don't even know.
And then he says,
it doesn't matter whether are defending
women,
men,
transgender people,
Muslims,
humanists.
The ghastliness is absolutely the same.
Okay.
What's a pram?
The stroller.
Oh,
out of a pram as I go.
Well,
I thought it was like a boat,
a pram.
That's my.
That's what way in the British Cola
Cola.
Jamie,
Google the word Pram.
Why don't I think the pram was a type of
boat and a pram,
Pram.
You got a bunch of,
uh,
what the fuck it had a reset your
computer.
It's a stroller.
I just told you that three times.
John,
trust me.
How do you not trust me?
But I wanted him to google boat boat
because why do I think?
Oh yeah.
It says boat.
That's one of the.
Yeah,
it was a boat.
It's type of boat.
Is it a,
is it a,
a sort of brand of both
small utility,
Dinky transom bow rather than a pointed
bow?
Don't make fun of me Bro.
I got knowledge.
Deep knowledge about shitty boats,
small utility biggies.
That's what I knew was like why is he
throwing this idea that of a small
utility data,
but what he said was eloquent.
I mean he's,
he's dead on about the sanctimonious
recreational outrage and also he lives
in a country.
Remember where you can actually be,
be prosecuted for saying things that
people find offensive like in the UK.
Did you,
did you hear about the mealy mouth a
tweet this guy.
So after the Brussels attack,
there was a guy,
just a regular dude who tweeted,
I confronted a Muslim woman yesterday.
I asked her to explain Brussels,
she said nothing to do with me.
Immediately.
Mouth reply that cools the media storm
because they were like,
well yeah,
there were lots of like funny reactions
to that.
What people will like,
you know,
I asked an IRA,
I've met an Irish person and asked them
to explain the IRA.
He said nothing to do with me.
I'm mainly math reply.
Oh,
you know,
I,
I asked a dog why I was bitten by a dog
when I was four.
He said,
woof,
mainly math reply.
But this guy was arrested.
He was arrested on suspicion of inciting
racial hatred.
Wow.
And in the UK,
that's what can happen,
like in the UK,
simply saying that Islam is a problem
and or Islamic stupid can get you
potentially arrested.
Wow.
Under blasphemy laws.
Look at this.
He subsequently expressed concerns for
his health,
was taken to a nearby hospital.
He's probably having a fucking heart
attack.
Doyle's tweet,
which has since been deleted.
Read.
I confronted a one.
Okay.
Mealy mouth or par.
Wow.
That is quite a few offensive things.
He was like,
in response to people getting angry with
him,
he was like,
oh,
so I offended a towel,
head,
big deal.
So you know,
he's not maybe the nicest guy in the
world,
but when you come,
when you live in a country.
Yeah,
when you live in a country with the
first amendment,
it's pretty fucking crazy that a person
can say something,
can tweet something like that and then
get arrested.
So tamid has got some issues to camera.
Has issues with comedians.
Yup.
There was
one comedian,
I'm in Montreal that made a joke about
some kid that was dying and he,
the kid survived and all these people
had donated money apparently.
So he made some joke about,
you know,
how the fuck is this kid still alive?
Something along those lines and I'm just
trying to be funny.
And he's been fighting it in court and
they're trying to put him in jail.
And this other kid in Vancouver,
the guy who was on stage and some women
were heckling and uh,
he said something about them being ugly,
lesbians and some mean shit to them.
He got sued last.
I mean,
they're heckling at a comedy club and
you know what he said,
whether it was skillful or not,
whether it's,
I mean,
it's not like someone just yelling
something to someone out randomly.
This is someone trying to handle a
heckler ad libbing in a comedy club with
a bunch of drunk people and these
hecklers who had been fucking up the
show up until the time he got there.
So he's trying to wreck them and make
them feel bad.
They sued him and won unbelievable force
comic to pay $15,000 for tirade of ugly
words against lesbian patron after
appeals falls flat.
Like why pay 15,000 comedy show?
Because he insulted somebody.
Yeah.
I got to tell you,
I haven't seen anything that bad in
Australia,
but it is also bad in Australia in terms
of like what frustrates me the most is
that people from certain ethnic groups
or religions,
uh,
claiming that you can be,
you can bless fame.
You can,
what do you call it?
When you defend that,
right?
You can defame like a religion or
ethnicity.
Hold on,
look at that.
Jamie.
Scientists say they've developed a
second skin you can wear for more than a
day to look younger.
What?
What the fuck,
dude,
you're going to go out some old lady or
old man,
whatever,
and you're going to think I found the
perfect guy.
Wow.
Get beautiful skin.
Smells like an old guy,
but
the idea sounds like fantasy and
invisible film that can be painted on
your skin and give it the elasticity of
youth bags under the eyes and finish and
seconds wrinkles disappear and this is
from the national post,
which is an actual publication.
This isn't bullshit.
Hundred 70 people have tried it under
eye bags.
No reported an irritation or reactions.
Whoa.
Bags are just to start.
You can soak the film was sunscreen and
protect yourself without worrying about
sweat or water washing it away.
The researchers say they expect it can
be used to treat Eczema,
psoriasis and other skin conditions by
covering dry,
itchy patches with a film that
moisturizes and soothes.
Whoa,
I'm going to get me some of that,
but you know,
that's one of those weird things where I
would have never even thought that
someone would come up with this idea.
It's clever though,
right?
It's amazing.
They developed a two step process.
A polymer,
a clear liquid is applied it.
It's chains are not very strong though,
so the next step is applying a product
that links them together.
By modifying the chemistry of the
chains.
The researchers can alter the properties
of the second skin depending on how it
will be used,
making it more or less permeable.
For example,
a more permeable second skin might be
used for under eye bags were a less
permeable one might hold a medication in
place.
It can be removed with a solution that
dissolves the Palmer.
Whoa.
We're plastic people.
The love of Jesus Christ.
Well as if the fucking Kardashians more
on plastic enough,
they're going to have plastic faces.
By the time it is going to look 20
again,
by the time I need to get botox or any
kind of facial surgery,
I'm not going to need it anymore.
There you go.
Spray some polymer on my face to a lag
by you.
You make lemonade.
Exactly.
I see something and you go,
this is a positive on this.
Fuck.
Having plastic people.
I wonder if they feel like rubbers
though.
Like you know like he touched people.
It feels good like skin touching skin.
I wonder if all the sudden it's like
touching a rubber.
Well especially if you're wearing it
right?
Like if someone caresses your,
your cheek.
Does it just feel like why don't worry
about what they feel like.
Because your hands I'm assuming won't be
covered by this shit.
No,
you wouldn't cover the.
Unless you really.
Unless you're like my fingertips give
away my age.
I don't like when I take baths in my
skin.
Prunes so he can do something.
A really hot bath and then spray some
polar moment.
My fingertips.
What the fuck man.
That's great.
We're going to cover ourselves with
rubber.
We're gonna.
See,
I mean the fact that we've got enough
money to be thinking about this.
Like coming back to the question about
like poaching elephants in Africa or
Megan to the Mumbai slum.
Like what the fuck is the world on about
when you talk about the inequality
between Beverly Hills and Baltimore,
what about the inequality between people
who are inventing polymers so that we
can spray them on our bet,
our eye bags so that we look a little
bit less old at the same time as there
are people living on a penny a day in
Mumbai?
Yes.
And Naughty.
Like if you were an alien and came down
to the earth right now,
you'd be like,
what are these guys doing?
They got plenty to go around.
They got tons of shit.
That's a super good point.
And there's something that I was reading
about today about a type of polymer that
they've used on.
Um,
God,
what was it on?
It was on certain,
you know,
let me find the history here.
It was on certain,
um,
certain types of,
uh,
it's like a plastic that could spray on
things and when they spray this shit on
things it um,
it actually,
uh,
you could,
you could throw like cinder blocks off
of buildings and shit because of it.
Wait in the cinder block is okay or.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The cinder block stays together.
It's fucking madness pool.
It's really weird.
Let me guess.
The military developed.
It sounds like something like that
probably let
me find this stuff because it's some
shit that they spray on things and
they're using an uncertain automobiles.
Uh,
it's like,
hold on,
let me find it real quick.
It's,
um,
in the meantime,
you can open your podcast app and
subscribe to the way the people live.
There you go,
hold on one line and you can get more
delightful conversations with the likes
of myself.
It's called finance.
Thanks Jamie.
Google line x polymer coating because
this stuff,
they put it on,
um,
on plates and they throw it off a
buildings like,
look,
they threw this does on the history
channel.
They threw these cinderblocks off of,
uh,
off of a building and then they cover
the cinder block with paint and then
they throw the same cinderblock,
same size cinder block off a building
that's covered in this protective
coating.
And watch what happens.
It just found sentences.
Now they did it with eggs,
man,
they did it with plates,
they did it with eggs.
And then on top of that,
they did it with plastic cups where they
had a sumo wrestler stand on plastic
cups,
like look at the egg.
So they're spraying the egg.
And by the way this is like less than a
quarter inch coating that they put on
these eggs.
Boom,
bounces off the ground.
Wow.
This is crazy shit.
But look at the cups is the really weird
stuff.
They took this gigantic sumo wrestler
and they had him stand on these plastic
cups.
Of course he crushes them.
Then they take the same kind of cup and
they cover it with this line x shit.
Go Way,
way back.
Wait,
wait.
There's a sumo wrestler dude you can see
easily.
Obviously you can just a little sippy
cup.
It's a red like Red Cup from a frat
party or something.
Go way further ahead.
Jamie [inaudible].
He crushes you,
but go away for it.
No Watch.
Look at this.
He's standing on to read like be a cops
and they're not much big.
You look,
they're not much bigger.
It's not like daily became super thick
because of this stuff.
So this must just.
What does it do?
I guess it just disperses the energy of
the.
I don't know,
the full all across the.
The product.
I don't know man.
It's some super fucking polymer.
I mean,
what would you use it for?
You just use it to make everything
strong I guess.
Yeah.
I guess our cover your fucking whole
body with bro become iron man.
Become like a thing from fantastic for,
you know?
Yeah.
Put a little bit of a.
put the old,
put the anti aging polymer on first.
Then put this shit on jumping off a
building and bounce.
Dude.
That's what I'm looking at.
Just run right through walls.
Shit you recommend when you're going to
do that.
I think in 100 years from now,
science and technology will have
achieved results that are unfathomable.
Yeah.
I think we are just in the infancy.
I mean go back to 1916.
People lived like fucking cave people
there.
There were barely human monkeys.
Yeah.
And think about what,
what we're experiencing now in 2016 now
imagine what 2000,
116 is going to be like.
Well also think about it.
Think about if we can ever do like what
Ray Kurzweil wants us to do and be able
to unite like artificial intelligence
with our our intelligence.
I think it's inevitable.
If that happens,
then that's going to be a big game
changer.
That all of the physiological things
that we've been able to do in terms of
the evolution since the industrial
revolution where it's going to be like
an information revolution and we're
going to become cosmic gods in some sort
of a weird way.
I think it's inevitable because I just
think it.
As long as we don't blow ourselves up or
get hit by a meteor or a supervolcano
wipes out the planet,
I think it's inevitable.
We're going to continue.
Not We,
not you and I.
We're not going to do shit.
Where's it going to be talking?
Speak for yourself.
Don't be the first one.
We're just going to be talking,
but there's gonna be other people out
there that are really fucking smart.
They're going to come together with some
other really smart people and they're
going to figure out some amazing things
and we were just watching it that I'd
love to make skin shit when we.
When people wonder about why we haven't
found extraterrestrial civilizations yet
and we haven't heard their radio waves.
I'm so hopeful that the reason is that
like we just evolve out of that.
We've only had them for less than 100
years.
Right,
and we don't have been pumping them out
for Henri is maybe a.
maybe we're just about to find something
else and we'll realize that the universe
is actually teeming with all these
conversations between different
civilizations that we are just
completely oblivious to and they don't
care about reaching out to us because
we're just little ants on a.
on a little rock floating around,
a star on an outer spiral arm of an
insignificant galaxy called Milky Way
and they're like,
some of these guys will grow up and
they'll join the conversation when
they're ready.
It's probably exactly what's going on.
Or it gets to the point where it's no
longer necessary because intelligence
and artificial intelligence become
exactly the same thing and we create a
different kind of life with technology
in our pursuit.
Like this fucking this ibm machine
that's beating people that go game,
you know,
killing chess champions at their fucking
preferred game that one day they're
going to,
it's going to reach some sort of a state
where we have to accept it as a life
form and it has rights because it has a
conception of itself.
Can it go in any bathroom at once he
comes to computers walking to the
bathroom.
I was talking to someone who is,
who was saying that,
uh,
when we can grow artificial meat because
they're working on artificial meat in a
lab.
And then will it be the case that the
only ethical meat to eight,
uh,
that isn't artificial would be human
mate because we're the only people
capable of giving informed consent to
have ourselves be eaten by ourselves.
It would be,
maybe we can take all these fat people
and we could like suck body meet off of
them.
They'd be like,
I really wish I was thinner when you go
to a place and with no scars,
with 30 percent of your body weight
polymer that I can spray on you,
which just extract some of your,
uh,
your fat and calories and into a
smoothie for me to sell it as protein
bars that you mentioned,
the Gauguin,
the computer that,
that Bates people that go.
The thing that I find really fascinating
about that is the computer that Bates
people at chess is basically just a
brute number cruncher,
right?
So
deep blue and deep blue won whatever was
it Kasparov.
Um,
what that basically does is just looks
at all the different possible outcomes
that you might be about to play and then
rapidly calculates the probability that
any particular move is going to yield a
good result.
Right?
We can all imagine how that,
how that functions.
It's basically just lots and lots of
numbers,
but go is so complicated.
There are so many different options at
any particular point in the game that no
computer can even remotely and probably
ever will be able to calculate the game
itself.
The way that the chess computer does
there.
There are more options I think in a game
of go then there are like atoms in the
universe at some crazy stat like that.
So what the go compete,
I know went fuck that.
It's the power of exponential.
Right?
So like if there's,
if there are two options and then those
two options each lead to another two
options which include to another two
options which actually not have the two
options very quickly you get up to
numbers that are those thought
experiments of how many times would you
have to fold a piece of paper for it to
reach the moon and it's only like 30 or
40 times or something ridiculous like
that because it's doubling all the time.
Can you look that up Jamie?
How many times do you need to fold a
piece of paper for tuition to the moon?
But anyway,
so the point about the go computer is it
doesn't crunch numbers,
it learns from other go games,
so they load into it all of the go game
like thousands or millions of games that
have happened and it then looks at all
of those games and tries to find
patterns between the way the,
the,
the particular moves that humans have
done in past games and then uses its own
intuition to run billions of possible
games in its own head.
And it gradually learns from its own
mistakes.
So it's not just a computer,
it's not just like a gigantic calculator
like the chess computer is,
is a form of artificial intelligence in
that it is making calculations.
I mean obviously it doesn't know
anything we don't think but it.
But for me it's really super exciting
because I do think that it's really
interesting to ask the cheering test
question of like when is the computer
actually self aware?
And this is the beginning glimmers of
that.
I think within our lifetime there will
be computers that it's just meaningless
to say they're not self aware because
they claimed to be self aware.
They they behave as if they're self
aware,
they tell us that they feel pain,
they tell us that they have an interest
in their own,
continued existence in a way that's so
authentic and that learns that to say
that they're not self aware,
but like a chimp is would be
meaningless.
Do you think that they're going to say
start
by just trolling people on twitter with
like fake intelligence,
like imagine this guy that you're
arguing with on twitter.
He to be a person and they just realize
what,
what riles people up with spins their
gears and they just start sending these
troll twitter things out and they just
started having debates with people like
literally having debates and breaking
people down and then being passive
aggressive,
being shitty,
being inquisitive.
Like they try a bunch of different
approaches and they treat it the same
way.
They treat go games.
They just learned behavior
patterns.
That would be the worst people in the
world and if they learned their behavior
patterns off the way that we communicate
on social media,
you'd just be creating a monster.
Well,
it makes you wonder.
I mean,
if go games are that complicated,
yet they're able to master that.
What about human personality?
What do we do?
We kid ourselves in that we're so
complex and amazing that nothing could
copy us mean what if some fucking
computer figures out a way to bypass
personality?
Personality is overrated.
We figured out a way to make the perfect
personality.
This is the formula.
Run with it.
Everyone's going to love you.
Did you see that movie about I'm a x
Mokena.
See that?
Amazing.
No,
that's Kinda the conceit of that.
Right?
So there's this sort of the billionaire
kind of leader,
the Mark Zuckerberg type in that the way
that he builds the artificial
intelligence is by hoovering up all of
the.
All of your social media information
from his facebook style thing,
and I think you're right,
that that could be one way of creating
an artificial intelligence to collect
all of the communal inputs that we're
putting in every single day on social
media.
One hundred percent,
100 percent possible to learn those
patterns.
Yeah.
Jamie,
how many,
how many times?
I was just gonna say there's a specific
episode of that show,
Black Mirror I've been trying to tell
you about that deals with this exact
topic where there's some sort of like
android created thing and they take this
guy,
this whole social media presence and
recruit.
That's what his new being.
He died.
I don't want to ruin all of the.
Yeah,
it's Donald.
Yeah.
Same Guy.
The actor that's in next Maki now,
so it's a little bit.
Which guy?
The millionaire guy.
No,
the guy fucked over.
Yeah,
he's a good actor.
I gotta get Outta here,
man.
I'm sorry.
We're out of time.
Anytime time flew by.
Does it always does.
Always.
Does so much fun.
Yeah.
No,
I love it when you're back in town.
A denier,
but I'll give you a Holler at me.
My friends will be back tomorrow way
that people live and just apps on
twitter.
We the people live.
Just to pull myself out yet further.
Yeah,
it up,
baby.
Thanks man.
Tomorrow we'll be back with Alex grey.
A famed visionary artists should be a
goddamn blast.
See,
then you fucks.