Hello,
freak bitches.
Yeah.
I'm going to quote Sinbad.
Say that you got.
I love the.
I love this quote.
He goes,
he's a very nice guy.
He was great.
He did my podcast.
Tony Hands Club says he's awesome.
Talk about leaving your body.
Astral projection.
Same bad.
Does it?
He asked truly projects,
astral project.
How's he do that?
He stopped doing well.
There's all these techniques.
There's there's books and stuff about
it.
The long and the short is you get into a
trance and you imagine a rope above you.
Then pull yourself down or what he did
actually remember,
he was like,
I put something just out of my reach and
then you're trying,
as you're laying there with your eyes
closed,
kind of meditating,
you're trying to reach the thing,
and then he said he felt his hand
wrapped around and that's how he knew he
had left his body and he did it for
months and months and months and months,
and then one day he said he was like in
this weird place.
It was in the cave.
Some shadow creature came up and hit him
in the chest.
I know this is sinbad,
remember,
and he goes and it felt like someone had
cracked me in the chest with a sledge
hammer and he was like,
I never did it again.
Whoa.
And I was like,
really?
You got to go back,
try and find like booby island or
something.
He's right though.
Maybe he's ready to be snatched up by
the demons in stranger things.
It is next dimension demon that lives in
the wall.
It is scary if you read a journey's out
of the body are far.
Journey is a Robert Monroe in the
fifties.
It's like you read this book and he
still calls black people negros and
stuff like you can tell it's an old old
book,
but he's telling that's how old this
stuff is.
It's because way back he would tell
stories about like seeing something fly
by and being very concerned that that
thing was trying to get into his body
before he did.
So it's kind of a scary thing,
but it's one of those things.
So I was under the impression that
people did die when most people are
under that impression.
I've,
I've had,
I've spoken,
given talks at medical schools and stuff
and all these doctors think that
everyone died at 35 or 35 year old
results and they're like,
and it works its way into medicine where
they're like,
okay,
look,
the reason you have chronic back pain is
that the human body was not evolved to
live beyond 35,
and so of course you have wear and tear
and things like that's totally false.
The human bodies evolved to live into
the seventies,
so it's a statistical thing.
It's like if Bill Gates moves into your
neighborhood,
suddenly everyone's average annual
salary is hundreds of millions of
dollars,
right?
So if you count all these infants who
died in prehistory,
many of whom by the way died from
infanticide,
like twins normally are not allowed to
survive.
The,
the weaker one is left in the woods to
die.
What?
Yeah,
and any sort of deform and mal
formality,
we just leave them in the woods by
themselves.
What a cruel way to handle it.
Yeah.
Whew.
That's dark man.
They would leave him to wolves.
That's fucked up,
man.
Leave your baby in a basket and runaway.
Ooh,
yeah.
There's a lot of,
a lot of infanticide,
but you know,
in our world,
a lot of it,
huh?
Yeah.
Well,
just because the times were harder than.
And it was more accepted that you were
going to have to do some terrible things
that you didn't want to do.
Well,
it's just that,
you know,
if a kid's born physically fucked up in
some way,
you know,
you're not gonna,
you're not gonna have the resources and
that kid's not going to.
The person's not going to grow up to
contribute to the group.
And so generally,
and also there's a different sense of
life and death,
right?
You know,
I think we're death is much more a daily
presence.
It's not that big a deal.
So we're all gonna die there.
I was reading about a tribe in the
Amazon.
Uh,
I can't remember the name of the tribe,
but when someone gets too old to keep up
with the group,
someone is chosen randomly,
like they have a lottery or pick the
shortest straw or whatever it is.
And their job is to come up behind this
old person and hit him in the back of
the head with a hatchet.
Oh boy.
Right.
And no one wants to do it.
It really sucks,
but everyone agrees it has to be done.
And it's the least cruel option that
they've come up.
Be careful to do to keep signing up for
that job.
Exactly.
Got
Papa Joe.
You've killed nine old ladies.
This lady.
This bitches gone over.
Okay.
We'll just let her stop.
It's weird,
man.
It's a weird gig.
Kenton's wife tends to look at me like
that is the source of looseness right
there.
That's single man with a mustache.
This man got cut loose to spend too much
time with him.
It could all go down a feral.
Yeah.
What's why.
Like no one tells Ryan were to go.
Ryan can just go into the woods anytime
he wants.
I don't think that's right.
Yeah.
What about d?
Doesn't have a leash on how many times
did he call and check in,
but I was just out there with no leash
collar.
I get a long leash.
I get along,
especially during hunting season,
but mark might have a leash.
Brian doesn't have a leash.
He just asked him.
He doesn't have to call anybody.
He just goes where he wants it.
It is what it is.
Joe,
if he just decides to take that mustache
and go for a hike,
nobody can tell him that.
That,
that pisses women off because then when
demand goes,
yeah,
Hey,
Ryan says out there with no leash,
just do whatever he wants.
I wish I was like that.
Like I love being married.
I love having kids.
I loved the whole deal.
I love having a family,
but I got a buddy,
my friend Ari.
You know what he did?
He just went off the grid,
shut his fucking phone off.
He won't answer his emails.
He just disappeared.
He went to Pacific for so long.
I just want to do it for a few months.
He's just.
He's a standup comic.
Hilarious guy.
Successful show on comedy central is
doing great.
Kicking ass.
He just decided,
you know what?
I need some experiences in my life to
write about,
to talk about,
so I'm just going to fucking stop
talking to people and disappear for a
few months ago.
I talked to him in two months.
I haven't talked to him.
I don't know where the fuck is.
You call his voicemail.
It just says the subscriber.
You have reached to shut off incoming
call or I'll play it for you.
That's amazing dude.
This thing is just the most devious
creation on
it is it is
subscribers request.
This phone does not accept incoming
calls.
Message in V one.
Gotcha.
Phares.
Rockin message [inaudible].
You don't give a fuck straight in the
eye.
So if my wife heard that,
well he's out there.
You think that's good?
He's got no one to call in to check in,
but he can check in and do whatever he
wants,
but he wouldn't call and say everything.
Cool.
Yeah.
How late she can call me up.
Hey faggot.
I'm still alive and then hang up the
phone.
That's it.
I'm like,
God damn the to checkout and we can.
I mean,
where we are,
it is narrow valley public land
everywhere.
As soon as you get off the valley floor,
you're on public land like we talked
about.
I can hate.
I can hate to the fricking Yukon,
man.
That's crazy and you can be
disconnected,
as disconnected as you want to be,
and man,
there is no price tag on that.
That's the thing and I need it.