The Joe Rogan experience,
Joe Rogan podcast.
Joshua,
thanks for being here,
man.
I appreciate it.
I really enjoy your show.
Oh,
thank you.
You're,
you're huff post show.
I've seen it many,
many times and we were just discussing
the excellent recent one that you did
with Mark Marin,
which I really loved,
but I had him on Friday.
I came to know you because of the,
the whole,
uh,
how should we say this canceled core
Baer report thing.
This,
this ill advised a jump at racism or the
idea of racism.
Yeah.
Someone that's comedy central tweeted
something that Kobe had said out of
context,
out of context.
And it was taken up as being a racist
quip by an Internet activist.
And I had not really,
I wasn't really familiar with her.
I'd never heard of or anything.
And I had her on huff post live briefly
and she,
she didn't like the fact that I was a
white man,
that I got myself into all kinds of
trouble.
I'll just explain exploded into one of
those twitter storms.
I mean,
I think that was partly the
precipitating event that and then
actually forced cold beer to address it.
He did a whole segment on his show about
her and about the whole twitter storm on
Monday,
but it really kind of got traction when
I had her on huff post live on.
I think it was the Friday morning and
um,
yeah,
we shouldn't go into,
I should say what the joke was so that
people know because it was,
it was really unbelievably ridiculous.
It was unfortunate because if she had
seen the actual joke in context,
it would not have been offensive.
Oh,
I don't agree with that really.
I think she just takes umbrage at
things,
but figure biggest she likes to.
I think there was a,
there was a type of twitter reaction
that is just a project predictable knee
jerk.
It's a choice to take things out of
context.
I agree with that,
but I think that it would've been almost
impossible if she'd actually seen the
full clip.
Like she would have had to be on the
starting line wanting to launch,
but go,
fuck,
I can't go after them.
This is the,
what the context was that he's willing
to show the Asian community how much I
care by introducing the Ching Chong Ding
Dong Foundation for sensitivity to
orientals or whatever,
and it was meant to be a,
it was a satire of the Washington
redskins original Americans Foundation.
So they come up with this original
Americans Foundation.
So Dan Snyder was trying to,
it was trying to say,
instead of changing the name of the
redskins a,
I'm going to give money to like this
African American charity.
I mean,
sorry,
native American charity and call bear
satirized the redskins by saying because
he had been accused of doing some anti
Asian things in the past like bits where
he just kind of impersonal.
It's an Asian or something.
So he was like,
well,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna.
Uh,
make that right by setting up this Chin
Chung Ding Dong charity for orientals or
whatever.
Right.
That was the gag rose.
The Gag.
Well,
it's,
his thing is character.
I mean,
core Cole bear is a,
it's like an archie bunker of course.
I mean,
he's,
he's not a real guy.
This is a role that he plays a
ridiculous,
ignorant Republican and that that is,
that's,
that's the satire,
and to miss that and to do this cancel
core bear thing.
Colbert,
same as name,
wrong every time,
but I never say it.
I watch it.
I don't say his name,
but to do that it just,
it,
it highlights in the support that he
got,
but the social justice warriors or the
support that she got rather than this by
the social justice warriors on this was.
It was so maddening.
People who should know better joe,
they shouldn't fight.
I had people,
I had twitter hate campaigns coming at
me from left right and center from like
from black comics who I had known like
who should know better because they're
comics that it's baffling to me when
people engage with one another purely on
the basis of their identity and not on
the basis of the actual intellectual
point at hand,
like weird does set high go too far or
whatever.
Like I was just roundly prevented from
having any opinion about what satire is
on the basis of the fact that I'm a
white man.
Yeah,
you got to check your privilege son.
Check your privilege.
Did you check it?
I didn't check it.
Check it happen.
I need to check my privilege APP.
I never know what I would sell that is
to create an app where you can just
click on it and gives you a score from
one to 10 about what your privileges.
Well,
it's an interesting thing
because it it.
It immediately allow someone to
marginalize your opinion by virtue of
the fact that you are European or in
your case Australian or whatever your
whatever your roots are like you can
instantly discount
any credible point that you might have
had.
Just to clarify,
for people who haven't seen the way that
the interview with this Hashtag activist
twitter person went,
I was basically she was buying.
She basically literally said that I.
my opinion is completely worthless
because I as a white man,
I would not be expected to understand
the lived experience of women of color.
Now she's a 23 year old Korean American
middle class.
It was a lot,
so I don't know what,
but what's incredible to me,
the struggle is real.
Josh,
what's incredible to me is that,
you know,
when you meet somebody and you just get
a real sense of like,
wow,
this person is interesting.
They're original or authentic,
like this is,
this person is a,
is a snowflake.
I want to,
you know,
they're a fingerprint.
They're like something unique.
That's what we should all be hoping for.
Right,
and we should all be hoping to engage
with one another on,
on levels that enable us to bring that
out in each other.
She was the exact opposite of that.
Like it was basically an identity
talking to another identity.
It was a generic.
It was a label talking to a label.
Yeah.
There's an issue with this.
This need to correct people that to
define yourself by correcting people
that I think people are.
They're looking for people to step out
of line so they can check them and
instead of looking at this subtle
nuanced life that we live where there's,
there's,
there's so many different variables when
it comes to human interaction and
communication.
There's so much when you.
You're throwing in satire as well,
and it's a satire television show.
The fact that this is an all put through
some sort of a observational filter
before you immediately knee jerk react
and and,
and attack.
It just shows that there's a real issue
with the ability to communicate.
The ability to communicate is a
wonderful thing.
The fact that we all have it,
that you know,
you can do your show.
I can do my show,
we can all tweet,
anybody can tweet,
anybody can go crazy and just write
whatever they want on their blog.
It's great.
It a lot of ways,
but it's also ridiculous because people
who have not considered that they do
possess the English language,
they have the ability to communicate,
but what they're essentially doing is
just piecing together what they think is
like an argument based on these
predetermined patterns that they've
picked up.
Exactly.
You know,
as you as a white male wouldn't
understand a woman of color.
What fucking color you.
Well,
like what,
what,
how your white.
I mean you're,
you're Asian,
but I mean when you're talking about the
color of your skin,
you can't say color.
You just can't.
You might want to say ethnicity.
You might want to say,
you know,
uh,
whatever,
background,
let me clarify that there is.
I completely concede that there is a
lived experience of being a certain
being a minority ethnicity,
especially in America or in Australia,
new countries that is different from
being a white man and I'm rushed.
I absolutely concede that.
The thing is why can't we talk about the
actual details of the experience without
assuming that there's a homogeneity
between that experience as well.
Like not every Asian experience in
America is the same.
They have certain commonalities in that
they're subject to racism in a way that
you and I aren't,
but they are so wildly different.
Let's talk about the details of the
experience and what's acceptable and how
we,
how we want to converse with one
another.
Let's not assume that because a person
has a particular set bunch of labels
attached to them,
gay,
straight,
Asian,
white man,
woman,
whatever,
that that immediately disqualifies them
from having a conversation about these
things.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And also
this idea of check your privilege.
What you're doing is just discounting
someone's opinion immediately.
You're,
you're using it as a tool and it's a
lazy tool.
It's a lazy tool to look.
There's some people that you want to
just be able to say,
check your privilege.
You.
You basically want to say shut the fuck
up because you don't have the time to go
through all the things that are wrong
with their arguments,
but there are other people like
yourself.
You're a very complex dude.
You talk very well.
You're very well spoken,
you're very measured and the things that
you say,
I've watched your show many,
many times.
You're not a knee jerk reactionary guy.
You're not an asshole.
So for someone to say that to you,
it just shows that this is something
that just gets used.
It just gets thrown out there like,
here's a weapon that I have.
We're in the middle of a conversation.
Instead of having this dialogue where
we're considering each other's points of
view and different lives that we've led,
he just boom,
throw the snow,
smoke bomb on the ground,
check your privilege.
Well,
it's also,
it's the easiest way to lose
good friends too,
like privileged checker APP.
It exists.
That's the need to check it.
That's great.
I'm going to download it.
I'll download it and check my privilege.
It's also the,
it's the clearest way to,
to lose allies in the fight against
racism as well for these self appointed
kind of,
um,
people who,
who do these kinds of twitter campaigns
and online stuff.
And the WHO's who the check your
privilege brigade,
you know,
I am the most obvious ally for
antiracist.
So I'm like the least racist guy.
I should be.
I should be,
it should be a no brainer for me to
release racist non,
the less racist guy,
the second least racist guy won the race
and it's made me what I have to keep
reminding myself is this the self
appointed spokespeople who uh,
you know,
for race like this person then not the
people who I need to be defending when
I'm,
when I'm trying to defend minorities.
These are,
they are,
they are doing active harm to the cause.
Like the poor black working mom doesn't
have time to get angry on twitter.
Like I should be defending her.
Not a 23 year old Korean American Middle
Classico who's making me,
who's basically alienating me and all
the likeminded people from the
legitimate worthwhile pursuit of
fighting racism because it makes me feel
like,
well,
if I'm,
if I'm going to be rejected out of hand,
regardless of what I do,
simply on the basis of the fact that I'm
a white man.
Fuck you.
All right,
cool.
You've just lost an ally.
Yeah,
that is true.
I mean that is a very good point.
Um,
and another good point is when you're
23,
fuck look,
she's probably smarter than me.
When I was 23,
I was retarded when I was 23.
I was really fucking dumb and that's
just something I'm willing to concede.
And if,
if you had a video of me explaining my
position on anything at 23,
at 47,
I would have to go,
fuck,
I'm so sorry.
I don't know.
I just didn't know anything
and stupid.
I have some.
I have a certain level of empathy for
that.
I mean,
I don't know that girl.
So this really isn't,
for me,
that whole affair was much less about
her than about the easy way in which
people jump onto jingoistic bandwagons
about things
and also that they demand cancellation.
They demand people getting fired
censorious.
So it's so dictatorial.
It's so.
It's so antithetical to everything that
we should value about the kind of the
great rumbling dialogue of debate.
You know,
the,
the first amendment.
One of the great things about this
country is a whole bunch of crazy people
shouting at each other
and you know,
hopefully the best idea wins in the end.
You don't shut people down without a
doubt.
And I think a lot of these people,
they respond.
I think a lot of people were very
sympathetic to someone who's been
bullied and they look at marginalized
people,
whether it's a certain races or genders
or sexual orientation,
and they,
they immediately stand up for those
people because they think those people
had been bullied and marginalized.
But in doing so,
they often resort to the very same
tactics that are often used against
these people that are marginalized.
They become bullies and they rally the
troops and that's why this term social
justice warrior is so apt because
they're attacking.
This is like this aggressive campaign.
It's not a campaign of psychedelic love
where they say like,
you,
your,
your perspective is wrong man.
We have to look at this from a different
way.
And like,
you know,
there's no,
there's no sympathy.
This is like a very aggressive sort of
movement and you know,
you could say that I think it's possible
to make the argument that there's a
necessity to some of that because I
think that the aggression against people
that are,
have been marginalized,
the aggression against certain races and
sexual orientations and certain genders,
and you could say that it's necessary to
have something equally aggressive in the
opposite direction to sort of achieve
some type of balance.
I could see that but,
but make sure that what you're targeting
is the actual offense.
Like don't just.
Yes,
that's the thing.
I mean if we want to have an actual
conversation about the boundaries of
satire and let's have that conversation,
right.
It's not canceled core bear and,
and you know,
that I can't have.
Yeah,
you're really having trouble with that.
And I met.
I'm an idiot.
You next time you want to say Kobe just
in of um,
you know,
it's,
it's so stupid and complicated and it,
what also frustrates me is the fact that
if someone transgressed as a certain
boundary,
you,
there are certain words that you can say
that immediately give the other person
the right to disqualify everything
you're talking about.
There are,
there are,
there are ways.
Like,
I'll give you an example.
Uh,
I'm,
I'm constantly dealing with the
immigration department.
Obviously you can probably tell by my
accent that I wasn't born here.
Uh,
and as far as bureaucracy is go,
I mean it's like,
it's as if the DMV had control of your
entire existence.
It is just nightmarish.
It's like pulling fingernails just to
get to do the most basic stuff.
Like what kind of stuff like,
oh,
it's just really renewing your visa
visa.
Um,
yeah.
I mean,
when you are not American and you're
here and you have to have the right to
work here,
there are certain hoops that you have to
jump through and that the regulations
are so arcane and so it's so difficult
to comply with and you know,
you fill in a form in triplicate and
then it goes through a bazillion
different things.
Then it comes back as a different,
one line was wrong.
So then you have to go in and you have
to wait for ages to get a ticket to say
somebody and then you wait for another
three hours and then they tell you that
you're at the wrong booth.
So you have to go back.
And I mean it's just,
you know,
dealing with bureaucracy is like,
it's just a horrible thing to deal with.
Um,
but I have no recourse against any of
that because that's just the power of
the state and if,
if I want,
want to be able to be here than I have
to have to cop that.
But last time I came into the country I
was at wit's end.
The battle with stuff.
And the immigration officer at the
airport,
uh,
made a joke.
He said,
I live on A.
Actually,
I can't really tell the story without
giving away my address,
but that's where I just don't come and
don't hunt me down on people.
I live on a strong do it.
That won't give you the.
I look at the fucking show listening to
St Huff Post live man.
Alright.
Alright,
I'll beat around the bush,
please do.
Um,
I live on it
on a street that has the name of a fruit
that is named after a fruit.
Okay.
Uh,
and he and this,
this guy,
these immigration,
he was like,
oh,
I guess I guess you got a lot of fruits
there,
Huh?
Oh No.
Right.
So okay.
Stupid like kind of anti gay quip or
something.
Obviously I don't come across as Super
Gay.
So he obviously didn't know that I was
gay and he was like,
okay,
that's fine.
I didn't find that particularly
offensive.
I came out and as I was standing at the
baggage claim,
I was like,
oh,
all the indignities that the immigration
department has put me through,
which is so much worse than that.
If I wanted to like get this guy
sanctioned,
I could complain about that and that
little thing which was completely
harmless and stupid would be the one
thing that they would,
that he would actually get censored for.
Whereas all the other bullshit that I've
been put through because it doesn't fit
into the box of having been
discriminatory like people can get away
with,
you know,
so if you,
if you make a joke that can be perceived
as being racist,
homophobic,
anything like that,
all of a sudden it's the worst fucking
thing in the world.
But you can do anything else and you
don't kind of trip the trip wire.
No,
you're not supposed to make any jokes
when you're in those situations.
Especially not job.
I'm not,
but he can kenny though if you
complained.
I don't think he can,
but why?
Yeah.
But it,
it frustrates me that that is such a bad
thing.
I don't know.
Like when did we all get together and
decide that some stupid guy,
he's probably,
you know,
he,
he grew up in a neighborhood where you
make a joke about fruits.
It's not like,
I mean,
yes,
it's a stupid thing to do,
we shouldn't do it.
But why is that the worst thing that has
been,
that has been for foisted upon me by the
Immigration Department in the past three
years.
Well,
and what if you were both gay and you
were making jokes about straight people
like breeders,
you know,
or he thought you were gay and it turned
out you were straight and you know,
he assumed that he could make a joke
about heterosexual people and then you
like,
this guy's a fucking asshole.
He thought I was heterosexual.
I think everyone just has to take a
chill pill as saying Australia.
Just say that.
Here we have,
we invented it and we sent it over
there.
You recycled it back here.
It's pretty new for you.
I'm sure.
We kind of abandoned that in the
eighties and we abandoned that once
we've invented cars.
I was saying you invented cars in the.
We did 18.
Eighties.
All right.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure it was pretty funny.
I still don't know minute which
vernacular is Australia in which been
accurate roads of American and because
you don't like,
I'll often say things and people like
and I have no idea.
What did I say that a day.
Oh,
that's right.
Uh,
we will,
we will be able to leave work early.
And I was like,
oh,
we get an early mark.
Everyone was like,
what an early mark.
Oh Wow.
I've never heard of that.
But I like,
I've,
I've basically been in the states for
like 10 years and I still,
because you don't notice what you're not
hearing.
Right,
right.
You don't notice that people aren't
saying early.
Mark.
My English friends always say taking the
piss.
Yeah,
sure.
You're taking the piss.
Yeah.
Like what the fuck that means that you
fucking with somebody.
Like if you say are you fucking with
them?
You make making a joke.
Yeah.
I think we just have to take a chill
pill and just let ourselves joke about
like when Greg Fitz was on,
he made some joke that was could have
been construed as being homophobic or
something.
He was.
Oh,
that's right.
It's saying I'm the first guy who asks
another guy out,
get to fuck him,
and then he was like,
oh,
that's terrible.
I shouldn't have said that.
And I was like,
I was screaming into my podcast.
Go,
no,
that's fine.
That is a.
That is a joke,
right?
It's obviously a joke.
It's obviously a.
it's kind of a parody of the sort of
stupid thing that a straight person who
doesn't know.
People would say like,
yeah,
well people are people worried even
about a joke that is not mean like a
joke about like a Joe.
You can make a joke about black guys
having big dicks and someone could say
that's racist like,
but isn't it a good thing to have a big
like it's racist in a positive way.
Even racist in a pot and it's what we
were talking about earlier.
People are just at the starting block
looking to get upset,
but Sarah Silverman has a bit about
that.
She was on the.
Yeah,
I think she was on Conan years ago and
she was like,
um,
is it racist to say like,
I love chinks and she had the bitch he
had wanted to do.
She nixed it was she wanted to be like,
I love the n word.
I love like,
and she would have actually said it on
the air.
So yeah,
Nigga.
Oh,
can't believe you said it.
Yeah,
you can get in trouble just for that.
I know.
Then I hate saying the n word.
I think it's so stupid and facile,
but it's great if you're black and you
can just call your friends at.
Well I listen,
I,
I do have some empathy for minorities
being able to reclaim terminology and I
do think that a black person that has
the right to say it,
like we've screwed it for 400 years.
The least we can do is let you say the
word that we can't say.
Well,
it wasn't we,
but I agree with you mean you say we,
but I mean really,
I had nothing to do with it.
You had nothing to do with it.
I'm pretty sure Jamie's never owned any
slaves.
Yeah.
But we still have the benefit.
We benefit from an institutional system
that had,
that took advantage of that.
So check your white privilege,
right?
Josh steps.
Do we have the APP yet?
Can I get a check?
They come around,
uh,
for,
as far as,
yeah.
Who's at 10?
Like Dick Cheney?
Yeah.
I'm Sean Hannity,
Rockefeller's,
Sean Hannity,
you know,
those guys were there just like they
complete this so privileged that they
don't even,
they're not even aware of how privileged
they are.
I would love to get Sean Hannity fucked
up on mushrooms.
What would come out?
Crying tears.
A lot of tears.
Lot of sadness.
A lot of reality.
Yeah.
More.
Or would he just dessert?
Would he just peel away like an
invisible onion and there's nothing
underneath the shell.
Most likely.
I mean,
essentially he's cold bear in a real
life for them.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
That's what he is.
I said it right.
Yeah,
that's good.
Good.
Good boy.
Thank you.
Um,
he's a parody.
It's a parody without knowing that he's
a parody and it's a lot of the way bill
o'reilly is.
It's like they play to these people with
nine volt brains.
They have these people that live in is
very small box of ideology and this box
only contains a few support our troops
and Falcon the need to keep my guns and
gays are trying to fucking marry and
that's going to ruin the and Obama's a
fucking Muslim.
It's like this box these people live in
and if you can fit into that box
project,
that frequency,
you can make a lot of money.
It's the same as what we're talking
about,
about the labels,
you know,
they basically,
they live in a world of labels and
order.
Yeah.
Um,
and you know,
people,
especially Sean Hannity,
I think Bill O'reilly is a smarter Guy
Than Shawn Hannity and sometimes
diverges from the orthodoxy,
but Hannity is literally a puppet for a
grab bag of,
of pre packaged ideas that come from
Roger ailes.
And that's it.
He's a spokes means just a spokesperson.
There's no independent thinking going on
there and profits from that and I mean,
I think that happens on the other side
as well.
Going back to the whole canceled Kobe.
I think the people who are,
who are doing that are also just
plucking out of a preset,
um,
you know,
it's a jigsaw puzzle box when they've
got all the little pieces of things that
they believe and they're not open to
listening to other people or considering
new ideas.
What is this something that's Suey Park
tweeted during that time
period.
Racism and whiteness go together.
Only white people can be racist.
I mean,
that's just a product that is so
awesome.
What is the question?
You're assuming that whites are more
racist than others and that racism by
whites is worse than racism by first
versus whites.
Dumb question.
Racism and whiteness go together.
Only white people can be racist.
That is awesome.
I,
it just depends on you.
Then she's just not using the term
racist.
She's in the bears,
which he is.
Yeah,
she's at Cole bear on the other side.
She's Sean Hannity,
you mean?
Well,
both.
She's a female parody.
Yeah.
Kobe.
The character without willing to do
willing fully doing it.
Yeah.
Without consciously doing it.
She's doing that.
Yeah.
That's what that was saying,
that only white people can be racist.
Jesus Christ.
That's so crazy.
Did you.
I mean any.
Anybody that has seen the.
The riots in La when they pulled white
people out of cars and hit him in the
head with bricks,
I'm pretty sure that's kind of racist
about what they did to the Korean
community and so fucking Korean.
Exactly.
Absolutely.
No racism.
Exactly.
I mean just a child.
It's a child with ideas that don't
really vet out under scrutiny.
What offends me more frankly about that
particular tweet than the house been how
stupid it is.
Just the mangling of the English
language in abusing the word racism.
So much like I'm an English major.
She's just not using the word racism in
the meaning of the word.
If racism means that you judge people on
the basis of their rights rather than on
the basis of their individual
attributes,
then of course just definitionally
anyone can be racist,
have any rights.
Of course,
not only that,
there's many people inside of a race
that are racist towards others that vary
in that race.
There are many black people that are
racist against darker black people.
Right.
That is a fact.
That's a fact.
Often discussed in the African American
community and it happens in Asian
communities.
That happens in India a lot.
There are,
you know,
there are seven eleven's in India that
have full of face creams that make your
skin water.
Yes,
absolutely.
Well,
in the Philippines Gludethyon,
which is a,
an amino acid or an antioxidant,
rather.
They inject glutathione and they,
they,
they use it as a way of bleaching the
skin.
It's like a very common practice.
It's bizarre and it's roots are not just
in,
it's not a cosmetic thing.
It's a race thing because look,
there's a lot of white people that are
fucking tanning themselves,
so they look like orange,
you know?
I mean,
what is that?
That's an aesthetic,
right?
They're trying to look different.
These people are there.
They're trying to be wider.
Yeah.
It's,
it's a really creepy thing.
Yeah.
And if you want to end up with a world,
I mean,
something that I'm passionate about
working towards and I hope will
eventually happen is a world in which we
have basically ignored rice to the
greatest possible extent where we are
all just treating each other as
individual human beings.
Trying to find what's special about one
another,
giving people,
giving each other the benefit of the
doubt and not teaming up against each
other.
How do you best foster that?
How do you best bring about that?
You don't do it,
I don't think by hunkering down into
your tribe and throwing pot shots at
other people because of their race or
agenda.
I mean,
give me a break.
Yeah,
I agree.
I think it's actually happening now and
I think that what we're seeing in this
cancel Colbert thing and what we're
seeing with these social justice
warriors,
although I think it's ill advised,
I think what it is is the adolescent
stage of this growth,
this social growth that we're undergoing
right now,
and I think that we're in this process
of understanding each other that is
unprecedented as process of exchanging
information that is unprecedented.
And I think that the negative aspects of
it is that,
yeah,
you know,
you have to deal with some people that
do have limited patterns of thinking and
they'll just,
you know,
Hashtag cancel Colbert and Suny Park's
my hero and you get all that kind of
shit.
But I think this is a long process of
hundreds of years.
But in this process,
and this,
this,
the time that I've been alive,
I was born in 1967,
so between 67 and 2014,
where we're at right now has been in
epic change in culture.
I mean,
unbelievable.
When I was a child.
Um,
I,
I was born in New Jersey and I moved to
San Francisco when I was seven and I
grew up around a lot of different
people,
so I didn't,
I did.
There's a lot of things that I didn't
understand about like racism and
homophobia.
I,
when I moved to Florida,
I was 11 years old when I moved to
Florida and um,
my um,
my neighbor,
this kid that I used to hang out with
his,
his dad was getting super angry that
black people or that gay people rather
we're allowed to get married and he
through this fucking newspaper down
because you can't fucking believe this
shit.
They're trying to get married.
And I remember it was 11,
a fucking silly bitch.
This guy is like,
what do you give a fuck?
My neighbors were gay in San Francisco.
I grew up next to gay people.
They were always there.
I did.
I totally didn't understand it.
And between that and today it is very
rare that you come across someone who
actually gets angry in any urban
environment.
Yep.
The gay people were going to get
married.
It's pretty much accepted like hook me.
There's the,
the.
There was always this economic argument
about fucking insurance and some,
but I always felt like those were
bullshit arguments because how is that
affecting.
You don't really raising your insurance
rates
and understand all that stuff.
It's like when jared did you,
did you notice my interview with Jeremy
on it by any chance last year?
It blew up momentarily when he said that
for a minute.
What's his word?
And he basically said if you have gay
marriage than a father could marry his
son to avoid death taxes because if you
want it to pass on his estate,
then then you could marry your son and
then you'd be transferring the property
to your spouse instead of to a kid.
I guess you could.
This is Jeremy Irons and actor,
the actor Academy Academy Award winning
actor,
but it was probably just pointing
something out.
That's right.
And then the British,
because he's very,
very famous in the UK.
The British press picked this up and you
know,
how crazy the British tabloids can be
and it was like a huge,
huge firestorm over there.
Um,
and I felt bad.
I felt sorry for him because it was a,
you know what it's like when you do a
long interview and you just say
something,
you know,
it was a 33 minute interview and he's,
he,
he mused on that in like the 31st minute
of the interview and if you know,
you just chatting on a couch feels
casual.
He just thinks he's rising a kind of
thought experiment and then the British
press will go crazy about Jeremy Irons
speaks out against gay marriage in a
slightly unfair way,
but that's the kind of like stupid us
thought experiment that obviously.
So if that ever happened then you would
just change the law about incest,
right?
Right.
It's a nonissue.
Is it legal to marry your son?
No,
not even legal.
No.
No,
I don't think so,
but maybe it is.
I don't know.
It's hard to imagine whether or not they
would ever actually bothered to write
that law because what if a son,
I mean,
let's throw this out there.
It's even more offensive would.
If a son and a father,
they're both consenting adults and they
decide they love each other.
No one have sex all the time.
Who's to say that that's bad?
If they like it,
they both like it.
If the sun's 30 and the father is 50 and
they said,
Look Dad,
I think you fucking hot.
Let's.
If they both agree.
I mean if you're not talking about
children you're talking about and
there's no history of sex between them
whatsoever.
There's no slow indoctrination by the
dad.
Look,
I basically think that we should have
the largest amount of freedom.
Yes.
It's consistent with a society that in a
culture that function,
so I wouldn't say that that should be
against the law,
but it's hard to disentangle that from
the power differential there is between
a father and a son.
It's to imagine dirty.
My Dad.
No,
no fucking power over me when I was 30.
Yeah.
I think that certain point in time,
I mean 40 and 60,
you know,
you're really older men and if it was
like 120 140,
then now we're talking.
But that's hard to fuck a hundred 20
year old man they break.
Yeah.
You know,
I just don't.
I just don't think there's anything
wrong with two people that consent to do
what they both enjoyed doing.
And I know this is a weird example,
but I think that as long as they both
enjoy it,
like why do we care?
And we care because of the confines of
culture.
It's one of the interesting things about
animals.
Bonobo monkeys will have sex with
everybody except the mother will not
have sex with,
with the sun.
That's interesting.
The father has sex with the sons,
the father of sex of the daughters.
The brothers and sisters have sex.
Brothers have sex with each other.
Everybody has sex with everybody.
Everyone's gay.
They're all bisexual except the mothers.
I get out of here,
bitch.
No Dick from you.
Interesting.
Yeah.
That's the only the only boundary that
they will not cross,
which is fascinating.
I should emphasize that if people are
watching this and I look horribly
claiming it's because I'm sick.
You don't look clammy,
you look fine to do by.
Um.
Yeah.
And I appreciate you getting in here and
doing this.
I really do.
No problem.
I,
I'm allowed to pollute you.
I didn't want to pollute anyone else in
the house was fine.
I take antibiotics.
You'll be okay.
And there's only two of you in here.
I didn't want to never get sick.
The kids,
a fucking soldier really?
He'll be fine.
Good for him.
Um,
but again,
it's sort of the same thing that Jeremy
Irons thing.
It's this desire to be offended or this
green light to be offended.
You see the green light go hit the gas.
We got one.
We got an opening time to be pissed.
I do think that this is a part of a
process.
I think this is a part of a process of
along with the erosion of privacy,
along with the,
the symbiotic connection that we have to
technology which is connecting us and
some sort of very strange way and this
erosion of privacy,
symbiotic nature.
Of the,
the technological world that we live in,
and then on top of that,
all these opinions that are coming in
like this distribution method of twitter
and social media and facebook.
You could just,
you could make a facebook post that
resonates and within a couple days
fucking millions of people can see it.
Hey,
alex from target.
Who's Alex from target.
Oh,
you've been up in the woods.
I have.
There's been a viral meme last week.
What happened?
I want to talk about,
you know,
Canada holidays.
Well,
um,
uh,
there was this photo of this,
of this 15 year old checkout guy at
target who was cute and a girl tweeted
it and twitter blew up with just
retweets of this picture of this kid who
suddenly begun.
He went from 144 twitter followers to
600,000
twitter followers in like 24 hours.
Holy Shit.
Just because teenage girls thought he
was adorable.
He ended up on Ellen.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Alex from twitter.
Hashtag Alex from twitter.
Blew up the world,
blew up,
blew up the incident.
He is a little cutie pie.
Let's look at Alan.
Good for her.
She's the best.
She's awesome at that.
Um,
so yeah,
I mean when you're talking about how
things can just spiral out of control,
this connectedness is insane.
The spontaneity I'm a little bit worried
about whether it's getting too crazy.
Like,
I mean it reminds me like Nuremberg or
something.
It's like what happens if you get a
bunch of crazy bigots?
What,
what happens if you multiply the thing
that happened with,
to me with cancel callback by a million
times.
Like he could just overwhelm your
consciousness,
can overwhelm your life.
You can,
but,
but your life is going to be different.
I mean,
it's changed Alex's life,
that's for sure.
For sure.
Damn sure.
Do you know what that kid's father must
be like all day,
but he's had winning propositions.
I'm sure it's probably just the amount
of sheer photos of vaginas sent his way.
His iphone going to need one of these
big 128 gigs and so,
oh Labia.
Although I just is just getting bombed.
Or imagine if he becomes like a famous
person,
like he gets a reality show or something
like that.
And why not?
I mean if honey booboo can get one,
how about,
you know Alex from target when you're
talking about the Bonobos as well,
like that's a whole other element of
human sexuality that you can open up in
terms of terms of overcoming labels and
overcoming the way that we think about
each other and the boxes that society
wants to sort of fill us in.
There been a lot of societies where
people were a lot more bisexual than
they are in this society right now.
Almost all of them in ancient Rome and
Paris in the 19th century and a lot of
Polynesian islands and things like that.
So in the great kind of sweep of trying
to become a culture that's more
accepting of individuals and
individuality.
That's something that I hope happens
that you,
that we do where we are less sort of
judgmental about the way that we think
about each other's sexuality.
And I think that sometimes the gay.
I'm kind of going off on a bit of a
tangent here,
but just while it occurs to me sometimes
the gay community or the gay lobby,
the extremely,
you know,
pro gay lobby can do a disservice to the
sort of mission of sexual fulfillment by
requiring you to pick a team by
requiring you to buy,
but making it seem like gayness has a
certain politics and has a certain
fashion style and has a certain way of
speaking and way of behaving and that
you have to defend that and,
and fight for it.
Why can't you just Shag who you want and
love anymore,
you know,
by picking a team.
Is that an issue in the gay community?
Like if someone is gay,
then they decided to be straight for a
little while.
They get criticism.
Yeah.
That's funny.
Well,
I mean imagine if.
Yeah,
that's like the opposite of what they
should be promoting.
I mean,
the whole idea about the ability to be
gay was like,
leave me alone.
Let me do what I want to.
If I'm not,
you know,
if I'm not hurting anybody,
if it's consensual,
if this is what we both enjoy doing,
why do you care?
Why do you care?
Because you have to care.
Because this is,
this is a fight that we have to fight,
you know,
can,
can a person also like this.
If you're a meat eater,
can you have a salad?
I mean,
if you're a vegetarian,
you're right,
you don't eat meat.
But if you're a person who eats meat,
can you have a fucking salad?
If I see you eating a salad like we do
with that salad,
pussy
and like,
then that's great.
But it's also not like a.
If something,
if like a tiny flick of animal blood has
like been on one of the pieces that one
of the billions of pieces of lettuce
that you ate,
like that's not a sin.
You know what I mean?
Like their,
uh,
their uh,
their,
uh,
now at some whole foods different,
um,
uh,
what do you call them?
Bread cutting machines for the organic
bread and the nonorganic bread because
people are so crazy about their organic
bread that they don't want to crumb of
non organic bread to touch the organic
bread.
That is a religion.
Just cry,
cry.
They don't understand what organic even
means and then when you're having bread,
okay,
this is the reality of food.
If you are having bread,
it is changed from the wheat that used
to exist in the early 19 hundreds from
the early 19 hundreds to today.
The wheat that you have has been
modified and genetically modified.
It's not genetically modified in a
laboratory where they're splicing genes,
but it is the sense of natural
selection.
They've they've.
They've selected on natural manmade
splicing plants together with scalpels
and shit.
What they've done is creating.
They've created a heartier plant that
can survive better,
has better yields,
and it's.
I mean,
what is organic?
It just means it doesn't have
pesticides.
That's right.
I think that's the main thing they care
about when you're slicing and you're not
getting in front on pesticide stupid
because it becomes a kind of a spiritual
thing almost.
It's like a,
it's like you have to pray to the gods
of the organic.
God's.
Yeah.
Well the vegetarian option,
you know the whole thing.
My favorite is the vegans who have cats.
Yeah,
because guess what?
Fuck face.
You're not a Vegan.
If you're fucking buyin murdered animals
that are stuffed into cans for little
tabby and you see all these people,
they have their cats and they don't
believe in animal cruelty,
but yet the fucking cats.
Those cats are cool as shit.
I have this,
I have two cats,
but I have one cat.
She's this big fluff ball.
She's 18 years old.
I've had it forever.
She's a sweetheart.
She Meat Company come near me.
I was at Yale.
You pick her up.
She starts purring immediately.
She's the best cat.
She's a fucking murderer.
If I leave her outside in the courtyard
and a bird is stupid enough to come near
her,
she will snatch that fucker.
I have a sky,
snap it's neck and bring it in and drop
it at my feet.
Yeah,
and she thinks it's fun.
I mean,
she's not hungry.
She's not starving to death.
She does that shift for a goof.
She's a fucking bowl of food.
They're full all the time.
She wants.
She can eat.
She's a fucking murderer and that's what
you have.
If you are a Vegan with a cat,
you are harboring murderers and if
you're not,
if you're not,
if you're one of those crazy fucks that
tries to feed your cat some sort of
vegetable based food,
you're killing your fucking cat.
Okay?
That cat's going to have organ failure.
They're going to go blind is also too
crazy shit that happens to cats when you
try to feed them vegetables.
There's this weird sense in which the
kind of Vegan movement,
and I have to say I have a fair bit of
sympathy for them because I do think
that the way that we.
What we've done to industrialize
agriculture is a travesty.
Horrible,
so we will look back in 100 years that
the way that we simply treat animals
purely on the basis of,
of minimizing the cost,
the number of pennies that we have to
say Scott's down of their flesh and we
will.
I think we will regard that as almost
being like a slight,
a form of slavery.
I think it will be so morally abhorrent,
but the response to that,
my response to that is similar to your
response to that which is alright,
let's try to feel more like we're part
of an ecosystem in which we actually a
more related to the food that we're
eating into the animals whose lives were
taking and let's have some comic
responsibility for that rather than just
buying,
you know,
chicken breast in Styrofoam and trying
not to think about the chicken that it
actually came from.
I don't think the correct response is
the Vegan response,
which is to sort of imagine that
humankind is distinct and disjointed and
detached from the rest of the ecosystem
and the like.
The what the cat does to the bird is
fine because that's natural.
But for us to eat meat is not natural
because what we're morally conscious
creatures who aren't part of the
ecosystem.
We are out of the ecosystem.
Like you can have a problem with the way
that certain types of food are raised,
but I don't think it's kind of morally
consistent to think that we,
we,
that it's wrong for us to partake in the
same kind of cycle of life,
that the rest of that all other species
do.
The idea is that we are
the highest form of animal on this
planet because unlike dolphins,
we can actually alter our environment
and I think dolphins are probably in the
same range as far as intelligence goes.
If human beings,
they have incredible minds,
they have dialects,
they have the ability to communicate,
they formed bonds and packs.
They play with people and also they
don't show any violence whatsoever
towards human beings,
but human being show violence towards
dolphins.
So there's a lot of like really super
positive characteristics about wild
dolphins that quite quite fascinating.
More so than even monkeys or chimps.
Chimps don't eat babies.
Chimps will steal human babies and eat
them.
They'll rip your face off their fucking
horrible monsters.
That's our closest relatives,
so it could be argued that in some way,
even though dolphins can alter their
environment,
they have a,
a very commensurate level of
intelligence that human beings have,
but we consider ourselves the highest
because we can alter our environment
because we have opposable thumbs and the
whole deal.
Um,
but if,
if you are the highest form,
you should set the highest standards.
Our understanding and our ability to
communicate these ideas lead us to this
thing where we say,
okay,
we are causing animal suffering and
cruelty that is unnecessary and I want
to leave the smallest footprint
possible.
I want to grow my own vegetables,
eating them.
And that's it.
Yeah,
sure.
But they also won't even eat eggs,
which is ridiculous.
I have chickens,
I have 24 chickens.
They lay eggs every day and they don't
care if you take them.
Chickens never become a chicken because
there's no rooster,
so they just lay an egg and you can eat
that egg and it's super healthy.
Would they have a problem with eating
human eggs?
I don't know.
I have a joke about that,
about if your wife was in the period
every,
every month,
once a year or once a month,
rather,
they had an egg,
dropped an egg,
which,
what would you do if it can't become a
person?
We just let it go to waste.
You ate it,
throw it in the backyard.
Let it fucking go.
Finalize your food.
That's the other thing.
Like why do it,
why are we so speciesist about what
species where we.
I mean I've,
I have,
I've eaten dog in Vietnam.
And did you eat dog?
Yeah,
I mean,
what was that like?
Not Great.
That weird you out?
Um,
I kind of felt like,
again,
I almost felt like it was a moral
responsibility to do so because I eat
pigs which are at least as intelligent
as jugs and show as much empathy as
Doug's.
So why?
Where is it morally consistent for me to
be okayed and bacon and not.
Okay.
Eating dog.
That's just bias.
My friend.
Ada Coyote.
Cool.
Yeah.
It was for a mediator.
My friend Steve Rinella,
because he was tired of people asking
them.
He's a,
it's a hunting show and he's very
unusual for hunter,
very educated,
very well read,
and very articulate,
and he was tired of people asking him,
have you ever eaten a coyote?
So fucking shot a coyote and ate it.
It cooked,
cooked it on the show.
That's great.
Yeah,
and you know it wasn't bad.
I guess mates mate.
I don't know about that.
It varies.
I mean certainly varies.
There's a big difference between some
forms of meat.
I mean,
I don't mean to say that all that.
However you rise,
mate,
it's all the same thing,
but I think a wild
species of wild species,
it's going to have flesh that is edible.
Most likely edible.
I've never heard of anybody eating a
wolf except for that movie.
The gray thing on that,
but it tastes like shit.
Apparently there's certain animals to
just tastes really bad.
Like a friend just got back from Africa
and he said the one thing that the local
villagers will not eat.
His hyena.
Oh yeah,
they'll even eat lion.
I can imagine that they'll eat lion.
Apparently Mountain Lion is delicious.
Yeah.
I've talked to all these hunters that
say that mountain lion and there's all
these mountain lion rest.
I googled it.
There's mountain lion recipes online.
Yeah.
They say it tastes like pork.
Well,
yeah.
I mean why you say kangaroo a lot.
Back in Australia,
that's an increasingly popular
maintenance.
Australia is a real great.
Like Venice.
It's very gamey and lean.
Really delicious.
They are.
I didn't know how fucking muscular
Kangaroos.
Jesus Christ.
You ever seen the video of the kangaroo
choking the other kangaroo unconscious?
No.
Oh my God.
I probably opposed to see this as.
As an Australian.
Yes.
It's fairly recent.
These two kangaroos are involved in a
fight and this one kangaroo gets this
other kangaroo and a fucking choke hold
with his arms and clamps down on the
Kangaroos neck and literally gets into a
Jujitsu position and puts this fucking
kangaroo and the kangaroo just
collapses.
Meet good.
Chokes the blood out of it has to have
some sort of a thought process behind
doing that.
Yeah,
sure.
I mean,
they're an interesting.
It's such an interesting species in
Australia and flowing.
The reason why Australia has all these
weird animals is because it broke off
from the rest of the continents in the
company before,
only the other students.
That was our logo one hundreds of
millions of years,
so there's a parallel evolution
essentially,
and if you look at the face of a
kangaroo and you look at the face of a
deer,
very similar,
very similar.
They occupy basically the same
ecological niche,
but because Australia was a here at his
video will say,
well,
check the.
Because Australia broke off so early.
They would just get these random like
this.
The beauty of I love evolution.
I think it's just so interesting because
I guess they've got longer distances to
cross in Australia and they did
elsewhere and it's dry and arid.
For some reason.
They just stopped bouncing it basically
bouncing,
dear wow.
And on two legs.
The other weird that.
Well there's a.
there's an animal called the diker,
which is a type of antelope that lives
in the Congo that can actually swim
underwater as much as a hundred yards
and eat fish.
It's a fucking carnivorous antelope.
They've all evolved,
apparently with the Congo used to be was
grasslands and as the climate changed,
it became a rain forest and as it became
a rain forest,
a lot of these animals that are
traditionally grassland animals became
trapped like rhinos.
There's rhinos that are trapped in the
rain forest of the Congo and all these
antelope and deer that are running
through these swamps and the swampy like
forest thick,
thick,
thick wooded areas and this one animal
figured out a way to get smaller
and actually swim under one.
Are these short little legs good for
him.
Fucking crazy though,
and this all happened over a period of
like 2000 years.
It wasn't like a long time.
Yes.
The very short amount of time.
It is true.
Yeah.
It's a fascinating thing about the
Congo.
Wow.
Yeah.
This area where these natural selection,
it's got to be some other force at work.
No natural selection
full of jeans that quickly and just a
couple of thousand years,
but maybe you.
I'm talking about school,
obviously I'm not a geneticist,
but I think there's been some evidence
of extreme changes in evolution over a
very short period of time.
Like for instance,
people that live in Hewitt,
people that live in the extreme northern
areas,
they've developed this ability to not
get frostbite and to also keep their
hands warm and extreme cold conditions
and they believe that this has happened
between a 10,000
plus years ago when the ice bridge
between the,
uh,
the bering strait between the Asian
continent and the North American
continent existed,
but they could travel back and forth.
And the people that still live there,
they have literally changed.
They've changed to absorb.
Look,
I guess if someone,
you know,
you can imagine that if someone,
if a kid is born with a propensity to
not get frostbite in his fingers,
then he's more likely to survive,
to procreate than someone who doesn't.
And that can shake itself out over the
course of general.
There's certainly that.
There's certainly that,
but I think there's also,
there's something I believe,
and this is just me talking,
there's something that I believe about
life where it finds a way life finds a
way just like these,
when they first discovered that there's
life at the bottom of the ocean and
these crazy volcanic dream of files and
it's like,
what the fuck is that?
Some of these tiny little animals that
just aren't incredibly hot volcanic
vents in temperature.
Yeah.
So that's why when they look at like the
Moon Europa,
one of Jupiter's moons and it's covered
in ice,
but there's water underneath it.
Like what the fuck is going on in her?
That's so exciting.
Yeah.
I mean,
there might be some lifeforms that
reminds,
reminds
me when you said something,
you said something a moment ago about
the moral,
uh,
about morality and dod.
That's right.
Dolphins and stuff.
I was interviewing Neil degrasse Tyson
about extraterrestrial life and I was
saying like one,
there is a fear that maybe as
civilizations become as intelligent as
we are,
that they kind of extinguish themselves
once they,
once they get the capacity to destroy
themselves,
that within a few centuries or millennia
they sort of do and that that's why the
universe doesn't seem to be teeming with
life and he was like,
you know what?
I think that if,
if you evolve to a position where you're
able to destroy yourself,
then there's another type and those
basically saying like if what if
extraterrestrial civilizations did come
and visit us,
you know,
Stephen Hawking says that would be the
worst possible scenario there where
there are no instances of advanced
civilizations meeting less civilized
civilizations and it going well for the
less developed civilization.
Right?
I mean,
just look at what happens on our planet.
Why would that if an extraterrestrial
civilization came and visited us,
would they just exterminate us or use us
as their slaves and Neil degrasse Tyson
and saying if they had gotten so
advanced that they were capable of
traveling across the cosmos then and
they hadn't destroyed themselves,
then you would like to think that they'd
been a moral evolution as well as just a
natural physical,
biological evolution and that they would
not do that because otherwise they would
have killed themselves before they got
here.
Right,
but the counter that would be obviously
that if they did develop this and they
came over here and they realize how
fucking scary we are with nuclear
weapons and sucking every fish out of
the ocean and polluting every fucking
place we get a chance to set up shop.
Wouldn't they see us as a threat to the
entire ecosystem of the planet if we
were just leaving nuclear waste as we've
done in holes in the ground in Nevada
and polluting Fukushima to the point
where they're trying to figure out how
to dig a hole and freeze the outside of
the hole so they could fill the hole up
with nuclear waste that will be toxic
for longer than there have been humans
in this particular shape that we find
ourselves in now.
I mean,
if you go back to 200,000
years ago,
you're dealing with essentially a
different kind of human,
right?
I mean if you go to Australia,
I mean,
what does that like a million years ago
and then whatever the lower hominids
were before that,
you get to take 200,000
years ago.
That's kind of like a monkey person.
Yeah.
Basically.
And that's what we're talking about with
this fucking toxic waste.
Yeah.
We're talking like hundreds of thousands
of years of toxicity.
It's horrifyingly are responsible.
I cannot believe.
I mean.
Right.
And if you were an alien,
yes,
you would look at that.
Look at these crazy pink monkeys with
their fucking bang sticks and their
nuclear waste.
You guys are assholes that you would
just look at the history of how we treat
other species on this planet and how we
treat each other.
This is a very undeveloped,
like this is the.
This is as undeveloped as you can be and
still be civilized.
I use that term is sort of in quotation
marks,
civilizing comparison to chimps that eat
your face off.
Yeah.
Well I just made civilized in that you
can build spacecraft and conk up
arithmetic and stuff.
Yeah,
and send video through the sky and into
someone else's phone.
It's all.
I mean,
we're obviously super fucking advanced
for what we know of in the past.
Yes,
we're good toolmakers,
but we're about as undeveloped like
morally and intellectually as you could
be and still be a toolmaker this good,
but is it possible that that is a part
of why we develop things in the first
place,
that we're trying to do battle with our
instincts and that we're trying to in
our,
in our desire to innovate and our desire
to create new technology and expand our
capabilities that we're also doing this
to sort of combat what we really are
primarily this,
this deep urge that we have to fuck and
to kill and to feed ourselves and to
sleep and all these biological urges.
We're trying to fight against that and
try to.
That's the of civilization.
When you look at every space movie that
talks about like the future and the
future,
everyone is super calm.
They're all like reading minds or
they're doing things with their hands
and no one's physical because no one
doing crossfit in the future.
You know what I mean?
If you look at this fucking movies about
the future,
no one said yoked.
There's no dudes that are fuck who's
pushing?
Come on,
10 more pushups.
There's none of that in the future.
The future is not a physical thing.
The future is we've evolved past the
physical.
We're communicating with our minds were
levitating things.
We're not using kinetic energy,
we're not using muscle and
bone and blood and maybe that will be
true.
I mean,
the other thing that fascinates me is
what's going to happen with artificial
intelligence and you know,
there are guys like Ray Kurzweil who
thinks that within the lifetimes we're
gonna be able to upload our intelligence
into computers.
And I was actually speaking to an.
I was interviewing,
I do another podcast called point of
inquiry,
which is for the center for inquiry.
It's that it's a nonprofit that spreads
science and reason and secularism.
Atheism.
And I was speaking to one of these guys
who works in the field of
extraterrestrial life,
like what he,
he literally gets paid to,
to plan for what we will have to do if
we discover civilizations in other parts
of the galaxy.
And um,
I just lost my train of thought about
how I got onto that.
But,
um,
eh.
Oh,
that's right.
So I was like,
why haven't we found an extraterrestrial
civilization?
Yet?
He was like,
well,
maybe the reality is that biological
intelligence as biological civilizations
quickly find a way to turn themselves
artificial and we're looking for the
wrong thing we're looking for.
We're looking for biological
civilizations,
but it may well be the case that within
a few centuries we will all be in.
We will all be intelligences living
inside of kind of computers and the the
need for biological human beings will
have passed.
I think that's very possible.
Not only that,
if we do develop something that is
artificial that is far better than what
we are,
the argument of why we keep the
biological life alive,
kind of a road map.
What?
Why do we need to shit and piss and eat
and what?
Why do we need to do that?
I mean,
we only need to do that because that's
the best option.
But if we come up with something in a
laboratory,
if they slowly they've combined spider
silk and human cells and created an
artificial skin that is bulletproof.
I mean,
this is all proof of concept right now,
but they believe they will be able to
develop artificial human skin.
That's fucking,
I want to be bulletproof.
Make it happen.
Yeah.
But then people would be shooting
everybody and fuck you worry about it.
They're already a sort of,
um,
I'm agnostic as to whether or not,
I mean it's,
it's a big philosophical question rather
than a scientific question as to whether
or not a computer could feel the way
that I do,
whether I like this.
This is taking for granted this,
this,
this assumption that Ray Kurzweil style,
singularity assumption takes,
takes for granted a fundamental premise
that I have trouble taking for granted,
which is that if you added up all of the
data that's in my head right now and you
put that into a computer,
it would have to be obviously a much
more sophisticated computer than
anything we have right now,
but assuming that you could,
that that computer essentially would be
me.
It would feel like me.
I would be in the computer.
Now that's a.
that's a question for philosophy of
mind.
That's not a question for science
because what we really don't know is
what it is.
What under under goods.
My experience of being myself.
I also think there's an issue with why's
it so important to be you?
Why is it so important to be a person
but you do like you but you like you
because it's the only thing you have
ever known and this is the highest form
of life that we know currently,
but if you think about how many people
are fucking depressed and saddled down
with emotions and relationships and just
the stuff we're talking about today
involving racism and homophobia and all
these issues and social justice warriors
and fucking Uber Conservative shitheads
and if you look at all of this stuff
that we have to deal with just because
of the fact that we're biological
lifeforms,
existing and cultures and all these
different emotions that we have to
struggle with on daily basis.
If we could figure out a way to just
shut that off with a switch and be the
enlightened robot.
Things who are far better don't get
disease and figure out a way to
experience pleasure and it's in a level
that is just unprecedented body.
Last week I have
being,
to me the part of the messiness of being
human being is the complexity part of,
part of the beauty of creativity,
uh,
for me is being fucked up a bit like
the,
you know,
perfection would be a boring state
if you could create wormholes and travel
to distant galaxies and all sorts of
forms with zero emotion and just pure
love because it's been created and
silicone fucking plates and you could
fly through the galaxy with no worry
about not being able to breathe.
Okay.
My,
I believe in my personal experience that
without the troughs,
the peaks and meaningless,
I believe that we should have stayed
single celled organisms because all this
fucking splitting.
It's just been super complicated.
If we were single celled organisms,
we have no racism,
we'd have no murder.
Single celled organisms don't have gun
rights.
They,
they,
they don't fucking,
they don't eat anything.
So fucking boring job that boy,
are we in comparison to these artificial
life forms that can travel to different
galaxies.
I mean,
part of the beauty of Shakespeare and
colleridge and shelly and like the great
art that we've ever produced is the,
is the fact that it touches something
inside of us that is,
that can be contrasted against the
fucked up nurse of the rest of our,
of the human condition.
I think the human condition is an
interesting thing with preserving maybe,
or I like the West speaking as if we
have the option not to.
Like we will just kind of figuring out
whether or not we should flip the switch
on this.
It's,
we're still a long way from that switch.
Well
think go back to when we were,
uh,
you know,
200,000
years ago when we were the weird monkey
people,
if someone along and said,
hey,
I know we haven't figured out language
yet,
but I'm gonna I'm just explained to you
the idea of twitter,
you know,
fucking a monkey.
You'd be like,
no,
no.
Listen man,
I've got to find food in my area.
There's a beauty to starving is a,
there's a meter running from leopards
and climbing up trees to avoid
predators.
I mean,
this is a beautiful thing to have a
seven year lifespan if you're fucking
lucky.
I mean,
I guess it depends what we're talking
about,
about the fucked up most of the human
condition.
I would agree with you that if you could
get rid of mental illness,
if you could get rid of unnecessary,
a self doubt and self criticism,
then that would probably be a positive
thing,
but that wouldn't be left with purely
positive emotions that I don't think
he'd want to be.
Who wants to be on an ecstasy trip their
entire life?
Me,
I'll take it.
I'm not saying that it would be that
even.
I'm just saying that we,
we,
we live as if this idea of emotional
struggle is a necessity to happiness and
that happiness isn't a necessity to a
meaningful life and what is a meaningful
life if it is all just temporary.
You know,
life is finite and there's no.
There's no arguing that right now at
least.
Well,
what is meaning?
What are all these things other than
these,
these quantities that we attach to our
life,
you know,
I'm more happy now.
I'm less happy when I do this.
I'm more fulfilled when I do that.
I mean all these things are a part of
the biological reality that we live in
and we equate the significance of our
existence to these biological reality,
but at the end of the day,
we're just fucking and breeding and
continuing to make new TV sets.
I mean,
at the end of the day,
when you look at the human race as a
whole,
this gigantic super organism that
continues to make smaller cell phones
and fucking faster cars.
What?
What exactly is the significance?
What exactly is the meaning?
If ultimately what we're doing is
polluting the ocean and pulling out all
the fish and damaging the atmosphere and
changing the fucking the Gulf stream and
all those nutty shit that we're a part
of as a byproduct of all these emotions
and desire from materialism and all
these different things.
If we can avoid all that,
if we could live as solar powered
creatures that are made a carbon fiber.
Sure,
sure it was,
you know,
we say no because we are this,
but we can't stay this.
We're not going to have 10 million years
go by and we come back to 2014.
We look how fucking goofy this argument
is.
These dumb motherfuckers wanted to stay
people.
No,
I,
I take your point and I,
but I think that,
uh,
I think the kernel of insight there
that's,
that's precious is the,
is the fact that we've essentially got
it ass backwards about how you find
meaning and happiness,
right?
I don't think we necessarily.
I think even as biological human beings,
we can still do a hell of a lot better
job than we currently do about
contextualizing what happiness is like.
It always frustrates me when people
whine about not being happy.
Happiness for me is a byproduct have
made doing things that I'm good at and
that contribute in some way.
Right?
Like,
don't sit around like chasing.
The more you chase happiness,
it's like squeezing the soap in your
hand too hard and it just slips right
out.
The more you specifically try to focus
on chasing happiness,
the less happy you are.
Just get on with your life and do stuff
that's good and happiness will just be a
byproduct of that.
That's a very good point as a person and
I think another thing that makes you
happy is to be around happy people and
to give each other things like as far as
like friendship and love and
companionship and and laughter and like
you,
you give and you know you experienced
from each other and you know you bond
together by yourself sucks.
You know by yourself is okay in small
doses,
but find some of the most miserable,
angry people and you find a lot of times
those people have no love in their
lives.
Yeah,
that's the big issue.
Sean Hannity fucking shot love,
but it's all from retards.
He's got those nine volt batteries out
there.
We're going to close up our borders.
Sean,
once they invent jetpacks,
all those borders are going to be
fucking meaningless.
People just gonna be flying through the
air and you're gonna have to scoop
Mexicans out of the sky with nets.
Is nobody going to be able to stop them
and then we're going to have to just
assimilate and deal with the fact that
we,
you know,
we're all sharing this planet together
and this idea of borders is fucking
preposterous.
This idea that you were born in that
patch of dirt so you don't have
healthcare,
but I'm born on this patch of dirt so I
got fucking gun rights flow can freedom
and American Eagle tattooed on my back.
Everyone's going to get a shit ton more
rich though before we can get rid of
borders.
Do you think so?
Yeah.
Because otherwise,
I mean,
I'm not saying that that's a good thing.
I'm just saying that that's a fact.
A fact on the ground.
If,
if every Indian and Chinese person who
was able to move to the United States,
then a large proportion of them would.
And then you kind of get you free
healthcare because you afraid you can
afford you a free healthcare.
Not that America has free healthcare,
but you know,
you couldn't,
you can't have.
There's an old saying that you can
either have a welfare state or you can
have open borders,
be kind of both,
or you can have utopia when we all
become carbon based life forms that are
made out of
lot of libertarians would say,
just get rid of the welfare state and
get rid of the borders and let every man
sort of fend for himself.
But I'm a big believer that the,
one of the great humanizing,
socializing forces of the 20th century
was the development of the welfare
state.
That the new deal and the idea that we
have a sort of societal obligation to
take care of one another.
I think it works well in a lot of
countries,
especially in Scandinavian countries
with willow and Denmark and works well
in Australia and New Zealand.
Um,
and open borders will put an end to
that.
Well,
I think there's a good thing that the
welfare state does if it's attached to
strong ideas and a strong philosophy of
self improvement.
The problem with the welfare state is
that Unsung folks with given some
backgrounds and given some behavior
patterns that people have fallen into
that it can lead to complacency.
Yeah.
Let me just clarify what I mean by
welfare state.
That might be a slightly American term.
Uh,
I,
I just mean providing unified universal
healthcare for everyone,
providing free tertiary education or
discounted education and not burning
people with student loans,
uh,
taking care of old people to do
globally.
Um,
certainly healthcare is expensive.
Expensive in this country already spends
like 14 or 17 percent of.
It's an entire GDP on healthcare.
What we would only need to double that
or triple that to bankrupt it.
And you would certainly do more than
triple that.
You're doing 100 fold if you will.
You can do it 20 fold if you expanded it
to the world because the United States
is wildly one 20th of the world's
population.
Right.
But if you take out the amount of money
that we spend on military,
the amount of money we sent it.
I mean,
if the whole world was assimilated and
that sort of sense would still not still
not close.
No.
I mean,
mark,
you know,
we spend like a sixth of the GDP on
healthcare.
That's insane.
It's so insane.
And,
and,
and we get outcomes in this country that
are inferior to,
to other countries that have socialized
what we spend on military.
I don't know how we should look that up
because if we could spend.
Oh,
I'm,
you know,
obviously,
that's the argument.
We don't need war.
We need doctors and gun food.
I mean,
don't get me wrong,
we spend way too much on the military
way more than we need to.
I mean,
America spends more than the next.
What is it,
nine or 10 nations combined.
Those nations are friendly nations.
So who are you?
Well,
apart from depending on pay to find
China,
but you know what,
uh,
what is this for?
It's a jobs if fucking jobs programs to
keep everybody down.
Flex,
flex on motherfuckers,
make sure nobody gets crazy.
We have,
that's why we have military bases and
over a hundred different countries.
I mean,
the real expense though is when I say
it's a job program,
literally every the lowliest have made
sure that every state of America
essentially has a vested interest in
keeping their Faq,
their munitions factory going like one
state.
It'll be they build nuclear submarines
and another state.
It'll be this instead of.
Instead of having it concentrated,
they very explicitly made a political
case to make sure that all political
constituencies across the country have a
local vested interest in maintaining
their mill,
their little piece of the military
industrial complex,
which means we're producing know fighter
jets that the Pentagon says they don't
want.
They don't need simply because the local
representative will say,
well,
we're not going to cancel.
Listen,
you know,
lose certain jobs in my district.
Okay,
well,
if it's a jobs program,
just let's admit that it's a jobs
program and just say,
okay,
that's.
That is the way that we've chosen to
deliver welfare in this country by
giving people jobs in the,
in the military that,
that,
that we don't need them to do.
So in that case,
what we really need to do is declare war
on poverty.
If we declare war on poverty,
then we'll make money out of eliminating
poverty.
The same way we have the war on drugs.
The war on drugs is essentially a war
against.
I mean it's,
it's a job factory the same way.
I mean it's a,
it's a,
it's a job hustle the same way military
is,
I mean the military.
There's certain places where the
military is a viable option for people
that are in poor neighborhoods that need
some form of income.
Yeah,
that's right.
It's right.
It's a constant and oftentimes,
I mean if you're,
if you're poor,
especially if you're a minority then.
And so you kind of have the same
opportunities that other people do.
Yeah.
The military is a great option.
And another option would be to become a
drug dealer.
So the military is a good option.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
Right.
I have to fix this josh steps.
That's why I'm here.
Joe.
I don't think we're doing a goddamn
thing.
You and I think we're on.
We're on the way,
I think.
I think we've got it.
I think we've fixed about 30 percent of
the world's problems so far today.
I really don't think that this pace.
I think we'll,
I think we'll get it done a couple of
years of this conversation.
How often are you in La,
man?
We only have about 10 minutes left.
Okay,
got it.
We got to do this again.
Um,
yeah.
I'm,
uh,
I'm here.
I'm in,
I'm in and out sometimes.
I also want to plug a minute,
my new venture,
which is I'm doing alive,
someone launching a live show in.
I'm in New York in front of a live
studio audience and we're going to
podcast that.
So I want people to like send an email
to the show and get on our mailing list
so that you can get free tickets and
swag and all that sort of stuff.
Uh,
it's called we the people and it's like
a panel show me like hosting with,
uh,
with,
for guests and we talk about the news
and the audience votes on whose opinion
they liked the best.
That's great.
Uh,
as we will be really fun.
So go to send an email to info at we the
people pod.
You're going to pick the audience or you
just gotTa let Sean Hannity fans come in
showing that any fans fucking drooling
and slipping all over the floor,
you're going to let them in.
Welcome.
Welcome everybody including defense.
What about Sean Hannity?
Would you have them on the show?
No,
no worries.
Of course.
I would realize that'd be.
Wouldn't it be fascinating?
Wouldn't be facing as long as you had a
lot of time.
Really get deep with them and break it
down because a guy like that can keep up
the fucking hustle and shuffle for like
20,
30 minutes.
It would either be interesting or it
wouldn't be interesting at all.
You know?
It was like I was talking to mark Marin
in that interview on Friday about
whether or not he'd want to interview a
rush limbaugh on his show.
And he was like,
not really.
He was like,
I didn't think I'd ever get through the
the charade.
I've never really had a nice little bug
or oxycontins on murder for you.
Come on son.
Let's shake it.
Shake it.
Shake it,
listen to this.
Wouldn't it be amazing if you could get
one of those guys on drugs and just take
them down the rabbit hole and really get
like you do Iowaska.
Wouldn't rush limbal see what happens.
Oh,
a lot of crying.
Lot of screaming.
Fucking being pulled apart by a lot of
vomiting,
a lot of shooting just to load.
There'd be a lot of lot of bodily
fluids.
It wouldn't be pretty.
I take it back.
I don't want that thought experiment
would be willing to be around him
shooting his.
I could see all the other stuff.
I mean I just think of a lot of these
people that have been incredibly
supportive of war and the military
industrial complex.
Just seeing the repercussions,
the possible repercussions of that
support in,
in some sort of manifested in some sort
of a spiritual form that would be very,
very terrifying.
Advocate presence to the impact of.
Of what their part of.
I don't know.
I mean the drugs that that guy is into
the disassociative drugs.
I mean,
someone who's into like the oxys and
someone who's into like something just
like the narcotics that Zonk you out,
but even not even a hannity like,
uh,
you know,
I saw one thing that I'm pretty
passionate is,
is the,
is the push to get rid of nuclear
weapons,
right?
This is a perfectly achievable thing.
It's something that Ronald Reagan was
passionate about as well,
so it's not a right wing or left wing
thing.
It's just a recognition that if we have
thousands and thousands and thousands of
nukes in the world at some point,
eventually we're gonna use them.
Someone's going to get them.
Someone's,
you know,
we can't as they say in,
in the nuclear security guy and you can
be right.
90 nine point nine,
nine,
nine percent of the time.
And that instilled destroy the world
when you've got thousands of nukes and
social on Hannity saying like railing
against this and saying you the white
stop nuclear weapons is to have more
nuclear weapons in the United States so
that bad guys won't use them.
And I'm like,
what are you even like?
Are you even close to being present to
the impact of what you're saying,
like it's so fucking wildly out of touch
with any grand,
a big attempt to to think beyond just
the momentary immediate talking point in
the most obvious reflexive knee jerk
bullshit,
like step back for a second and look at
where you are in the world.
Well,
it's also not supported by the history
of suicide bombings,
right?
The history of suicide bombings in this
world is pretty fucking extensive.
There's a lot of people that have taken
their own life and a bunch of other
people's lives with them because they
thought they were doing it for some holy
purpose or some martyrdom or whatever.
Someone can do that with a nuclear
weapon and that is a reality of nuclear
weapons.
Absolutely.
The real question though is,
is it too late?
Is can you take the salt out of the
ocean?
Is it possible to extract all the
nuclear weapons and figure out a way to
make some sort of a deal?
At the moment,
it does seem to be.
I mean,
well with the exception of North Korea,
you could do.
You could do a deal,
I mean,
I think,
I think everyone could get on board and
look if you want to have one,
if you want to keep one nuclear weapon,
then then do it.
That is,
what is this going up?
Defense Budgets from 2012 of all the
different countries and then the US.
Yeah.
So you've got a bit.
You've got one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine at the.
So that's the next 10 countries and it's
less than the US.
Six hundred and 82 billion.
And so looking at those countries,
the only country there that say that's a
of a rival really is Russia.
China is a,
I'm not worried about China and I think
we'll uh,
we'll,
I think we'll have a peaceful
coexistence with them.
And then the UK,
Japan,
France,
Saudi Arabia,
I mean this shit holes,
but uh,
they're not going to use a tiny amount
so small in comparison.
It's hilarious ball.
That's a shit textile with go.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's,
it's a weird situation when you think
about a thousand years from now,
will we still have this whole,
this whole mutually assured destruction
thing hanging over our heads a thousand
years from now.
I can't see it.
Will we have figured out a way past
this?
I think we have to.
Well,
isn't it all about the emotions and the
greed and all the stuff that comes along
being a biological life
form,
isn't it all about all the stuff that
comes from being this troubled monkey
that's trying to assimilate with cell
phones?
And she asked him
ability to triumph over that.
I mean,
one of the most touching things this,
this past weekend was the 25th
anniversary of the fall of the Berlin
Wall.
You don't want the great triumphs of,
of human civilization is the fact that
the 20th century,
as nasty as it was,
as brutal as it was,
it didn't end in mutually assured
destruction.
These,
these monkeys managed to rise above
their,
their worst selves and come to their
better nature.
And on several occasions came really,
really close to destroying themselves
like the Cuban missile crisis.
And didn't good for us.
Good for its pilot complexity.
Pat Yourself on your back.
Humankind.
Yeah.
Well we figured out when we watched
Hiroshima and Nagasaki that this could
be a fucking mess globally and somehow
or another we managed to stumble to 2014
and kill a lot of fucking people,
but not with nuclear weapons.
That's right.
You know,
there was a single nuclear weapon.
I think it's the tightened to which we
have loads of either hundreds or
thousands,
which has the explosive power,
more explosive power,
much more explosive power.
Then every single bomb dropped in World
War II by all parties,
including Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
Whoa.
That's on renamed my deck.
Tightened to
rename.
Know that they had all these other names
called Titan one a column.
And what is it?
Enola Gay.
The plane.
I think that
it's nice to see that we haven't done
that.
It's nice to see that we haven't blowing
each other up since 1945 or whatever it
was.
What was it?
40th five when we dropped the bombs.
It's nice to see that.
We have not done that since then,
but it's such a small amount of time in
perspective.
That's why we have to get rid of him,
I think.
I think we've.
We've stumbled onto something that is
far more advanced technologically than
our emotional capability has to handle.
It's like it's like you've been given.
You've given a monkey the,
you know the keys to a car,
you just gotTa.
You just gotTa take the keys back.
Well,
it's also the people that have this are
not the people that built it and created
it and engineered it and understand it,
and so the discipline involved in doing
all those things in the accomplishment
of creating it.
The people that did create it were
absolutely horrified at it being used.
The oppenheimer quote,
I don't know if you've ever seen it,
but it's fucking terrifying.
We can end on this.
We like Oppenheimer quoting the Bhagavad
Gita and seen that.
I haven't seen it.
I've read the quote.
It's fucking amazing because you see the
pain in this guys face like the als is
the face of death or whatever that is.
I am because I am damn death destroyer
of worlds and he,
he.
Well,
we'll play it and we'll,
we'll end on this.
Please tell people how they get ahold of
your show and how they get ahold of you.
So huff,
post live,
you can just go to www dot huff post
live.
We ere seven or eight hours of original
content every single day.
You could probably see stuff posted in
terms of clips all over the Huffington
post or you can also go to having a
post.com/live
and the.
So that's my main gig and then this,
but subscribed to this live show and
you'll get lots of cool swag and stuff
because I'm going to podcast it and that
is info at we the pod.
We got another hour.com.
My fucking clock.
Oh,
we're good.
let's play the Bhagavad Gita thing too,
right?
Cool.
I was like,
how did that go by two and a half hours.
Go by so quick.
It was one and a half hours.
Okay.
I'm fucking stupid.
I can't say cold bear and I don't know
about time.
Change is.
I have this little clock here and
daylight savings.
It's an old school,
Clark Davidson,
so let's play this Bhagavad Gita thing
because it is good.
I'm glad we do this because I love
talking to you,
man.
Alright,
five,
four,
three,
two,
one
in the dead.
Silence of the morning at five,
29,
45 mountain war time.
The Wester was bathed in an intense
flash of light that man had only seen
from the stars.
Just cut the fucking oppenheimer.
Man.
You know this drama bullshit.
There it is.
Okay.
Here it goes.
The world would not be the same.
Look at his face,
man.
Kill people.
Shoot.
People cried.
Both people were silent.
I remembered the line from the Hindu
scripture,
the Bhagavad Gita.
No,
trying to persuade the prince that he
should do his duty to impress him.
Takes on multi armed form,
says,
now I am become death.
The destroyer of worlds.
I suppose we all put that on way or
another.
Oh my God.
Chills up my fucking.
That's
fine.
When you see his face and you realize
that this is a scientist that
essentially was given the task of
creating this incredibly destructive
device and if he didn't,
if they didn't,
then the enemy would have and they saw
what was going on with Nazi Germany,
the Third Reich was taking over Europe
and killing everybody and what was going
on in the Holocaust,
and they just realized that we're in
this unwinnable situation,
someone to do something.
It's completely bombed,
completely understandable.
The scientists like to blame the
scientists for doing it,
and they were,
as you can see,
morally conflicted about it.
Richard Fineman,
one of the greatest physicists of the
20th century,
worked on it and then campaign for the
rest of his life for denuclearization
and he died of cancer because he kept
going to these nuclear testing zones and
dumb and protesting.
That's how firemen died.
Oh No,
hang on.
That was Carl Sagan.
Sagan died from cancer because of his
anti nuclear protests,
but fireman was also very conflicted
about his role in in,
in all of that.
It's tricky.
I mean,
you had to do it at the time,
but in hindsight,
just imagine,
I mean,
think of a world where there is no nukes
and it's just another like the idea of a
single bomb wiping out an entire city.
You used to have to fly sorties over
Dresden,
24 slash seven,
just raining bombs on something just to,
you know,
to destroy.
So you may one bomb killing thousands,
hundreds of thousands of people
potentially nowadays.
Millions of people from one bomb one
moment,
one instant,
and we got up to,
you know,
when we're in the height of the Cold
War,
we were producing hundreds of these,
I think was hundreds a day at the peak.
What was it?
No,
it was no,
we were producing more than one an hour.
It was like,
yeah,
we will produce.
Will produce what we ended up with over
10.
No,
again,
remember it's like in the tens of
thousands of nukes that we had
stockpiled.
We've now brought that considerably
down,
but we still have thousands,
thousands of nukes for everyone.
Many times over.
We could kill everyone on earth many
times over.
Totally.
We could kill not only every one,
but like everything we could blanket the
planet.
Well,
when you look back at history and the
horrible things that human beings have
done to each other without bombs,
I mean if you look at the amount of like
the Mongols regularly killed.
I mean the estimation is between 20 and
$50.
Million people during Genghis Khan's
life and they did that with horses,
horseback and arrows and catapults and
shit.
And they killed cities with a million
people.
They wiped the entire city out.
They did that with no weapons other than
standard shit.
Yeah.
It was a lot more work.
Not more work,
but it's the idea behind it that's so
terrifying that people can be so fucking
brutal.
And the idea that you give the same
animals,
this ability to do the same thing with a
press of a button.
Yeah.
It's the ease of it that is so kind of
bone chilling about nukes.
It's similar to people who,
who are big guns,
guns,
rights defenders will.
Uh,
we're so lucky.
The Hutus and Tutsis had each other to
death with machetes.
They didn't need guns.
No.
That's true,
but it's just you have to really care
about it more to kill someone with a
machete than we've been by pulling a
trigger.
It's just a lot easier and that's,
that's true.
If nukes you have really you,
you are able to achieve spontaneously
with almost no effort,
something that would otherwise take a
tremendous amount of effort and
forethought.
What scares me the most about the gun
debate is not the concept of whether or
not people should have checks whether or
not people should have access to
automatic weapons.
It's the ignoring of the psychotropic
drugs that people are on.
It's the ignoring of human,
illegal.
One's legal.
One's the ignoring of all the different
instances of people either being on
antidepressants,
withdrawing from antidepressants,
getting off their medication,
and having unbelievably erratic
behavior.
The,
if you ever looked at like the
statistics for massive mass shootings
and how many of those people were on
psychotropic drugs are coming off of
them or,
or withdrawing from them.
It's almost all of them.
Right?
But there's a,
there's a,
um,
there's an ambiguous causation chain
there,
right?
That's right.
Is it the drugs or is it because they're
crazy and that's why they are taking the
drugs?
It's a very good question and that's
where,
uh,
I deviate from a lot of guns rights
advocates.
I don't think that we should have some
sort of background checks or don't think
we should have stability checks or the
very least.
How come you don't have to have a
license?
How come you have to take a test to
drive a fucking car?
Someone stands over you and looks at you
and everybody knows.
It's that weird feeling of being in the
nervousness of being in the car with a
driving instructor that's asking her a
tester that's asking you a few questions
and seeing if you stop perfectly at a
stop sign and whether or not you look
both ways before you make a turn,
but you could just go buy a gun and no
one has to look at you.
No one has to ask you if you know how to
fucking load that.
Honestly done understanding the gun
debate in this,
in this country.
I don't.
It does not even compute for me because,
uh,
I don't understand why the gun lobbies
against all of that sort of stuff.
Like I don't have,
I'm not,
I don't have a huge issue with people
having firearms.
I do basically think that that in dense
urban areas,
you should not be packing a gun unless
you're like a unique one because you're
a celebrity or something.
Um,
but I don't understand why the NRA
thinks that background checks and
licensing and stuff.
Is,
is a paranoid and they think that that's
a slippery slope and that that's going
to lead to guns being taken away in the
future.
Or is it actually those simple
precautions that they,
that they on principle objective,
I can't figure it out because it doesn't
make any sense to me.
If you could massively reduce the number
of people who are being slaughtered in
this country constantly every day,
why wouldn't you?
I think it's the slope thing.
I really do.
I think it's a slippery slope argument.
I think that,
uh,
it's like we were talking about with a
social justice warriors,
you know,
that there,
there's the extreme reaction towards
doing something that I believe is
morally correct and,
and fighting for objectified people are
fighting for marginalized people.
That this is in reaction to the racism
or sexual exploitation and all the
different things that have occurred on
the other side of the spectrum.
And this is what in,
in,
uh,
in sort of an analogous way they're to
do with gun control.
What they're trying to do is fight off
any form of possible gun control,
fight off any background checks,
fight off any waiting periods,
holding periods,
fight off magazine size restrictions or,
and yet like,
like I was saying about,
um,
about the,
the Sui pox of the world,
the cancel Kobe is of the world.
I'm losing potential allies in people
like me.
That just completely alienates me from
the gun rights movement,
right?
Because if,
if the,
if the conversation was around,
should it be legal or illegal for a
person who is saying who is provably
sane and who undergoes a test to make
sure that they know how to,
how to safely use a firearm and is
responsible and can keep it locked up
at,
at home,
should they be able to have a basic
firearm,
then you're not going to get a lot of
dispute from almost anyone apart from
the most extreme people on the anti gun
sight and there are very few people like
that.
So you alienate,
you lose an ally,
you lose a potential ally and someone
like me by being so rabidly against what
I regard as being simple precautions for
the responsible use of something that
could kill people.
I,
I agree with you,
but I think that this is what we're
dealing with.
We're dealing with.
There are,
there are many groups that,
I mean there was a famous obama quote
where he was talking about how people
are just resistant.
They don't just,
you know,
whatever.
Whatever it is,
they don't want us to come and take
their guns and these people were furious
that Obama would think that he has the
right to come and take their guns.
Like who are you as a person to tell
another person they cannot have this gun
and there's a lot of people that fucking
love guns in this country.
I have friends that are gun nuts.
My friend Justin is a fucking gun nut
everyday that dudes at the range
shooting targets like a 900 yard
distance and fucking pinging metal and
you know,
it's like bang.
Think because you shooting that fucking
far away.
Like you can actually hear it after the
gunshot goes off.
I think that's fun.
Good fat.
He's got a hobby.
Okay.
No one's known.
Taken his guns.
He,
it's there in the constitution amendment
to the constitution.
The.
Whereas about things changing,
we'll think about the privacy
amendments.
I mean think about what's,
what's happening right now with the NSA.
This is unconstitutional.
What's happening that didn't do any good
anyway,
what they're doing as far as like spying
on everyone cell phone,
being able to record.
Everyone's messaged as data center that
did developing in Utah is going because
the supreme court is stacked with a very
tough types of people who gun nuts vote
for.
That's true,
but they're worried that the Thai could
shift with a president like Obama was
somewhat.
Yes.
If you had a rabidly left wings,
if you had a supreme court that was
eventually as rapidly lift wing as the
current supreme court is right wing,
then it's conceivable of course that you
could just rip up a portion of the
constitution and ignore it and
reinterpret it some way.
Worried
about it.
I mean if you see this far fetched,
it's so far down the road,
I would think it's so far fetched that
they'll be able to record.
When Alex Jones,
who's a friend of mine who's arguably
very crazy,
but he used to tell me,
Joe Rogan,
they're going to take every single phone
call that everyone makes cross the
country.
They're going to record it in a database
and you're going to have everything
you've ever said.
If you ever get in trouble,
they pull you over for some reason.
Some guy wants to fuck your wife,
wants to put you in jail.
They're going to go to your [inaudible]
database and pull something out and
taken out of context and lock you up in
a cage and I would go to.
This guy's so fucking out of his mind,
but then you look at what's going on
today.
When this Edward snowden revelations
came out that literally they can go to
your email,
the employees.
It's not just metadata,
all this horseshit that Obama said,
it's not true.
The employees can go to your email and
record and take anything they would
like.
That is unbelievable.
It's an absolute outrage that this is
the.
This is the show in which I'm most
furious at Obama along with like
hounding whistleblowers and leakers and
prosecuting these,
these people.
But I mean in terms of,
you know,
Alex Jones being right on that.
Y'All a stopped clock is right twice a
day as well.
You know,
just because someone gets something
coming from Josh,
that doesn't mean that you can get to
the rest of charge.
That's a good.
Alex Jones.
Thank you very much.
He's my friend.
Um,
you know,
uh,
I think there are,
if we have to,
it's useful to sort of allocate our
concern to the fields that most deserve
it.
And at the moment the big concern for
people who like freedom is.
No,
I don't,
I just don't think that's a big concern.
That's not my concern.
This is not going to happen.
Take umbrage and issue with something
you said earlier about someone living in
a city not being able to have a gun.
Why?
Why not?
I mean,
isn't that like one of the most.
If you live in densely populated area,
the possibility of you being robbed is
much higher.
You know,
if you live in certain areas like
Detroit or Chicago where I think guns
should be a way of resolving disputes
between individuals even.
That's true.
What about defending yourself?
It'll take it.
Yeah.
Be able to use someone breaks into your
house and they have a gun and they're
looking to kill your family.
You don't think you should be able to
defend yourself.
Uh,
you should be able to defend yourself.
The,
the flip side of that is that if
everyone is,
um,
you end up with,
with far more violent cities,
then if everyone.
Isn't it so true,
sir?
Look at the statistics of the society is
a polite society.
I have this assistant in,
in defense against this concept.
Chicago has one of the strictest gun
control laws in the country.
Everyone has the highest level.
It's a good example.
That's why,
because it also has an extremely high
level of gun violence because you're not
going to ever get the criminals to stop
using guns because they're illegal
because they're doing illegal shit.
Anyway.
One of the things which were I agree
with with you on that is that there are
so many guns in the states already.
We're like,
we're so.
We're so far the horse has bolted so far
that that closing the gate now is kind
of pointless.
There are more guns in there.
Are People out there?
Yes.
So my house are.
I do think that that,
that's the explanation for why places
like Chicago is so violent because you
see,
I mean,
what is the point in putting in a gum,
a strict gun law now everyone's already
got guns.
Well actually in defense of the reality
of the Chicago situation is it has to do
with organized crime Chicago.
Um,
it has to do with the war on drugs and
it has to do with gangs being control of
drug dealing.
What happened in Chicago,
they,
they sort of destabilize the environment
by locking up key gang members.
I have a friend in Chicago cop and he
explained the whole situation to me what
an unbelievable clusterfuck it became
when they locked up certain they,
they,
they went on these rates,
locked up certain gang members and drug
leaders,
drug drug gang leaders.
And when they did that,
a power struggle ensued.
And then it's sort of like what's going
on in Mexico.
It's like once you,
once you have this power,
this power struggle,
you have this vacuum.
People try to fill the position and
there's just unbelievable violence.
I mean,
he was describing to me things that they
find on a daily basis,
the amount of murder that they,
that they encounter in Chicago.
And it was,
it's not just disheartening,
but I was like,
why do you stay last days?
Like,
Hey,
this is my job,
is what I do.
Uh,
you know,
I'm not happy about it,
but uh,
it's,
uh,
I,
I hope we can get a handle on it
eventually.
But he,
but he was outlining all the different
issues with it.
He's like,
this has nothing to do with gun control.
He goes,
if you,
you change the laws,
you would have the exact same results.
This has to do with profit,
nasty with drugs and that's due at the
war on drugs.
Yep.
It has to do with the fact that these
people can make insane amounts of money
and then they have this insane
resources.
Exactly,
exactly what we're seeing in Mexico.
Mexico.
Mexico is one of the great tragedies of
the world at the moment.
Also,
it also provides a good counter if you
want to be more original next time,
then use Mexico as the gun them because
they actually have really strict gun
laws to look at how a wash with gun
violence there.
So I take that.
I take that point.
I take that critique.
I think in.
I think in other societies I was a big.
I was a big fan of the fact that
Australia,
after it had its last mass massacre mass
shooting in the late nineties,
a conservative prime minister took on
the gun lobby and basically outlawed
guns,
did a gun buy back with the government,
paid to collect guns and there's a huge
amount of misinformation on the web
about the consequences of that.
Buy a gun rights folks,
100 people and the whole continent.
That's kind of my point is not going to
work.
It's kind of my point a.
and you didn't have this preexisting gun
culture,
real movies.
That's right.
It's,
you know,
a lot of Americans who don't,
who haven't been to Australia,
kind of assume that Australia is real
rugged outdoors.
He kind of a wild outback Steva when
Crocodile Hunter Crocodile Dundee.
In reality,
we're a bunch of pussies where we all
live on the coasts in,
in several big cities,
you know,
like three cities have almost half of
the entire population of the country and
we all sit around going sailing and
drinking chardonnay and drinking and
sipping lattes.
So we didn't really need it.
Guns I fucking love.
Sydney is one of the time.
I've only been there.
This is the only place I've ever been in
Australia,
but I'd fucking move there in a
heartbeat is shit.
Hit the fan.
If somebody decided to blow up America
or if yellowstone exploded and needed a
place to live,
I fucking moved to Sydney and a God damn
heartbeat.
Hard to think of another city that has
just just in terms of the sheer day to
day standard of living as,
as nice as pleasant place to be.
You know,
the sunshine,
the hub of the food,
the friendly people,
everything.
The Asian communities,
the Middle Eastern communities.
The problem is you guys drive on the
wrong side of the road to switch over.
I'll move.
Well,
Americans are like,
listen,
we invented the fucking car.
Why are you guys driving on the wrong
side of the Goddamn Road?
You know what that is?
Yes.
I tell me,
remind me swords.
It's an ancient ancient thing from
England and that when you would pass on,
the horses were passing the road.
If you were fighting in combat,
you would fight with your right hand.
So most people are right handed.
That's the hand you would carry your
sword,
so you really want to be on the left
side,
so that way if someone was on your right
you can hack at them.
If you are on the right side and
someone's over on your left side and you
have a sword,
it's fucking very difficult to reach
across the horse or you'd have to hack
on
do with there being two horses on put to
pulling coaches.
I mean,
I think you're right,
but why?
But that doesn't explain why it was
different here in the states.
Why will people already using wholesome
cots on the righthand side here?
They also use a right handed
because when we were.
By the time we got to America,
by the time European travelers came to
America,
we were already like,
fuck England,
fuck your up.
We're going to do shit our way over
here.
Let's just go on the other side of the
road and then we invented cars and so we
like,
we don't have guns.
They're like,
it doesn't matter.
I'd rather be further away from the
fucking guy shooting.
I'll fucking go on the right side.
I read
that.
In addition to that,
there was.
They will wider roads here so you would
have two horses side by side or like for
horses or something.
Pulling Lodge at cots than you than they
had back in England and that it had
something to do with being in the right
position to whip the horses.
So you didn't have to cross over your
body to with the whip.
[inaudible] could be.
Who knows?
I don't know.
I'm talking out of my ass clearly.
Yeah,
me too.
But I would.
I talked to my friends in England.
They were explaining to me that it was
actually literally went back to the time
of sword fighting,
that you would be on the lefthand side
that I just don't buy.
Why Americans would have changed because
we're better when you're smarter.
We have guns,
we have jets,
we go to the moon.
This is a lot,
lot better here.
It's a lot better.
This is why people don't love me or
America.
Both.
Yeah.
I don't mean it folks.
Relax.
Everybody please.
There was a thing that.
It is interesting though,
isn't it?
How different different cultures kind of
conceive of or different nationalities
conceive of themselves.
More Koreans are very proud and uh,
the North Koreans particularly
nationalistic,
so much so that you know,
it's a crazy basket case of a
dictatorship and it's the best example
of the bullshit that America tries to
shove down everyone's throats about
protecting people from bad people like
Jesus Christ.
If we're really worried about protecting
people,
is that what really why we're in
Afghanistan because we want to protect
those folks.
Why the fuck have we not invaded North
Korea chartwells to logistics about
China nuclear weapons and the proximity
to South Korea who are allies and all
this blah,
blah blah,
but there's not even a discussion about
mitigating the situation.
There's zero discussion.
No.
Why?
No natural resources.
It's so fucking poor.
They have to keep the lights off it.
They're not even strategically important
in any way.
Like the.
They're basically a vessel of China and
that didn't matter to us.
I just it
back from Canada.
I was gone for a week.
I was offline essentially for a week.
Pretty much.
Did fucking Dennis Rodman get Kenneth
Bay released?
He thinks he said he did.
He wrote a letter right after you got
back from one trip there.
And he's claiming that I have not seen
that reported.
That was the uh.
So he's reporting well,
he does have a relationship with Kim
Jong.
Ooh.
What's that all about?
Dude loves basketball.
It's fucking great thing.
No,
I understand why he wants to be,
you know,
hub.
And with Dennis,
what's enough?
Dentists?
Dennis is broke as fuck.
I mean,
you think about what is not in it for
dentists.
What does Dennis have going on?
Man?
It's not about.
I'm not baffled by like,
uh,
why he does it.
I'm baffled that he's so bought into
that.
He seemingly so bought into the
propaganda of that regime.
He's,
he keeps,
he has this stupid moral equivalency.
This is something that also frustrates
me when people are like,
oh,
because of the U.
S does bad stuff.
That basically means that we're not in a
position to criticize anybody else
because you say that.
Yeah.
He's like,
Hey,
robin says he helped secure.
Kenneth pays really well.
It's nice and Kenneth Bay got released.
He's like,
I've heard him say,
look,
Kim Jong Kim gentlemen,
you know,
we here we're hear all this propaganda
about what a bad guy he is.
But Hey,
you know,
Clinton Clinton screwed Lewinsky.
So you know,
stuff happens.
Bad stuff happens here as well.
That's like the dumbest fucking.
Not exactly parallel dude.
I think that
what he's probably doing is trying in
some way to.
If he goes over there on a regular
basis,
he has to play politics.
He has to,
he has to say something positive about
it.
I mean he has to,
he says negative things is going to get
back to that.
I just don't think.
He doesn't strike me as a very smart
guy.
He's definitely not that.
I mean,
do you ever see him on celebrity rehab
with Dr.
drew knew he was terrible.
It was awful.
I mean,
he's not a bright guy and it's,
you know,
he's,
he's also in a weird situation where he
doesn't have a whole lot of job options.
I was at the k one k one is um,
it's one of the biggest kickboxing
organizations in the world and they had
a big mixed martial arts event in Los
Angeles many,
many years ago was the,
not many,
many,
but it was the debut of Brock Lesnar in
mixed martial arts and Dennis Rodman for
whatever reason,
got hired by k one to be there and like
pump it up.
And like it was very strange.
It was very Japanese because Japanese,
they're there.
They have their big fans of pageantry at
these events.
And the events are often filled with
like huge,
like gigantic crowds and big,
big walkthroughs and big productions and
explosions and fire and like,
so Dennis Rodman is like standing at the
top of this things,
you know,
and he gave the speech and it was just
so dumb and awkward and he was saying
fuck the UFC k one is here and all these
different crazy shit.
But my point is like he doesn't have a
lot of money.
Like he has to do things like this.
He doesn't have a lot of options.
So then just don't talk about it.
I will stop or something.
It just frustrates me when,
when stupid people talk about shit that
unless that.
And it's usually,
it's so fast,
it's so easy and fashionable also to be
like anti American and to be anti.
Yes,
America's foreign policy is a basket
case.
America has done a lot of shitty stuff
but you know,
you get this also with conversations
around Islam and you know,
I know you've spoken to Sam Harris and
stuff about this,
about the,
the oldest old things are not equal.
I just interviewed an Iraqi human rights
campaigner who,
who has come to the US as refugee.
He's in his early twenties.
He grew up under Saddam Hussein.
He,
he grew up during the American
occupation and he is.
He'll basically frustratedly saying,
stop saying that there isn't a problem
in Islam and stop saying that the US is,
is to blame for everything that's going
on in the region.
We have our own problems and by and when
leftwing people think that they're doing
the right thing by being old fashioned,
oblique kind of anti American.
You're not siding with the people who
actually need help over there.
You're not siding with the secularists
over there and the and the people who
care about human rights.
There's also this weird thing,
and this goes back to the social justice
warrior thing,
where people are allowed to criticize
Christianity openly,
but if you criticize Islam,
you become Islamophobic.
Oh Shit.
That's such an overused term.
It is.
Which is not to say that there aren't
Islamophobes like the preacher who
wanted to burn the Koran.
Well,
there's,
there's people are phobic in many,
many ways.
You know,
there's Christian have hopes,
you know,
you want to look at it that way.
I've had Christians on my podcast that I
deeply enjoy rupert sheldrake,
who's a scientist who's also a
Christian,
but his version of Christianity is more
of a philosophy and it's like
psychedelically based.
Then I mean it was very,
very interesting guy and openly
Christian and he derives or he.
He gets a lot of comfort from that and I
know he does it in a very,
very intelligent and well thought out
way and it's.
It's an interesting point to discuss
with a guy like that,
but this Islamophobic thing like this
idea that if you criticize like Sam
Harris has been accused of it on a
multiple times,
it's just Islamophobia.
His Islamophobic stance.
Listen,
all religions are fucking terrible.
All of them.
They're terrible.
They're terrible for I.
ideologies are bad for thinking they are
bad because they lock you into a
strategy or they lock you into a pattern
rather.
And if you,
you aspire to be divine inside that
ideology,
especially in ancient one,
it's extremely difficult to think
outside the box.
Well,
they are the oldest and most original
incarnation of what I was talking about
at the beginning of the,
of the show,
which is thinking in terms of labels and
preset,
uh,
you know,
things that you can just pull out of a
box and take with you rather than
actually communicating or thinking
originally or being authentic.
Right.
I mean,
you know,
the,
the tribes that we belong to an hour be
they,
the pro gay tribe or the suit or the
cancel Kobe tribe or any of those things
are really just new small cultural
versions of the old biggest tribes which
are religion.
It's religion is just the easy preset
way for people to inherit assumptions
about the meaning of life and the
history of the world without having to
do any intellectual lifting of their
own.
I also think it's,
when you look at religions,
I'm absolutely fascinated by religious
and I find them amazing and one of the
things that I find amazing about them
just from a historical historical
perspective of thinking about people
that lived in a time where there were no
answers.
I mean,
it is really truly amazing.
We started coming up with mouth noises
to indicate where to go and what to do
and what foods to eat and what's known
and what's yes,
and then slowly but surely after fucking
eons of staring at the stars and seeing
people die and experiencing loss,
they tried to find meaning to it all and
they slowly but surely created these,
these fables and these parables and
these things that eventually were
written down and translated from
language to language.
I find it absolutely fascinating when
you look at it from a historical
perspective of this,
this being this organism trying to
understand its place in the cosmos and
that's what I think is beautiful about
religion.
I think from a historical perspective,
it's beautiful.
The problematic aspects of it when you
try to apply it in 2014 with all the
goddamn information that we know,
and I didn't mean to say God damn,
but I said it because it's appropriate
accidentally.
The information that we have now that
refutes virtually everything.
That's right.
I mean he's.
Look what you say is very nice and
poetic about the historical origins of
religion,
but as soon as the enlightenment came
along,
as soon as the scientific method was
developed,
as soon,
certainly by the time Charles Darwin
provided an explanation with how
naturalistic processes could give rise
to intelligent life,
you don't need those original myths
anymore.
I mean we should long ago have been able
to dispense with them and the fact that
we're,
we're unable to talk openly and frankly
about how concerned we are to be about
people who take their religions
literally is a problem.
It's a huge problem.
And I also.
I also have a problem.
I agree with Sam Harris also in the
point that you know,
moderate.
You say you,
you,
you enjoy talking about Christianity
with this Christian who you had on.
I do have a problem with people who give
cover essentially to religious
extremists by presenting religion as if
it can be my reasonable thing because to
the extent that moderate or moderate
Muslims are moderate is the extent to
which they don't really follow the
letter of their faith.
Right?
And then you have to reinterpret and
kind of squint and peer at your holy
book through a particular prism,
and then do a lot of juggling and
reinterpreting in order to come out with
a conclusion that is kind of morally
tenable in 2014 to secular people.
Yeah.
That is extremely important point.
Right?
And that's,
that's a big issue when it comes to the
leaving of the Islamic tradition.
If you leave,
you're supposed to be killed the
fastest.
Yeah.
Apostasy in Islam is punishable by
death.
Homosexuality is punishable by death.
Um,
I watched a fucking horrible video last
week,
absolutely horrible of a woman who was
accused of adultery and she was stoned
to death.
And this was,
uh,
this was all carried out by these isis
guys apparently.
Supposedly,
you know,
whether or not that's true.
I don't know.
I just watched this video and it's being
translated.
But this woman,
she tried to apologize to her father.
Her father wouldn't even touch his hair.
Touch her hand.
He wouldn't shake her hand.
He says,
you're not my daughter anymore.
And then he threw the first rock.
It was fucking horrible.
And that is all done under the guise of
religion,
all of it.
And you constantly hear apologists like
Reza Aslan is an obvious example saying,
look,
this is a gross or Ben Affleck on Bill
Maher's show.
This is a gross Caribbean.
Ben Affleck,
he's gonna fuck up Batman.
I know that son of a bitch.
We need a jihad.
I don't mean that.
Come on,
you're a good guy.
Uh,
the refrain is always,
this is a generalization.
Most Muslims are good people and that is
absolutely true.
The vast,
vast,
vast majority of Muslims are good people
and just like you and me.
But the,
the kind of the software that they're
running on is problematic.
And this rocky and human rights activist
I was talking to was saying,
look,
one thing that raises Aslan will always
say is like,
what about Indonesia?
For example?
Indonesia is the most populous Muslim
country in the world.
Apologists for Islam,
uh,
constantly pointing at it and saying
it's,
it's fairly progressive.
It's had a female leader,
you know,
it's democratic.
It's not.
This is not Saudi Arabia,
you know,
to to think that all of Islam is about
not letting,
not letting women drive is a
misrepresentation of the way that most
Muslims live,
but you would hardly say that a country
like Indonesia or even Jordan or any one
of the other sort of good Muslim
countries is particularly progressive by
the standards that we should expect as
liberals as smaller.
I don't mean in the political sense
within the United States,
but as people who believe in freedom,
yes,
that you know he.
This is rocky was saying,
this is the.
This is the bigotry of low expectations
that if someone in the United States
were to say the things about women and
gays that are routinely said,
even in Indonesia and the most moderate
Muslim countries,
liberals would be absolutely outraged.
Why are we holding them to such a
different standard?
It's very good.
Very
good point,
and I that one of the resist the
resistance.
One of the big points of resistance when
people in these countries get upset at
people criticizing religion is you're
essentially criticizing their way of
life and their culture and it's tied in
together and that this is almost an
extra bowl from their,
their,
their daily existence that Islam,
whether or not they believe in death for
adultery or homosexual or any of the
things that we find completely
offensive.
What you're saying by criticizing their
religion is you're criticizing their
very way of life.
That's right,
and that's what you're dealing with when
you're dealing with these fundamental,
these fundamentalist societies
and not even fundamental societies.
I mean I can understand that if,
if all of your being and your culture
and your family and your community are
woven up in a certain set of traditions,
even if that's just,
you know,
a,
a Catholic Catholicism because you grew
up in a suburb of Boston and you know
that's the way you do things and then
someone confronts you and says that that
is just a tissue of fabrications and
lies that have been handed down for
generations and it's wholly worthless.
That's going to be an affront to to,
you know,
I mean it's not because it's not an,
we're not intellectual beings.
We can't like unpack and disentangle the
sort of factual claims of our faith from
the lived experience of being a human
being who lives in a community and goes
to church and has a nice posture and all
of that sort of stuff.
We have to find a way to do that though.
Like we have to find a way to
disentangle when people do identity from
our,
from the intellectual claims of
religion.
Yeah.
It's a lot of people do it very slowly.
They do it over the course of their
lives.
Like I have some friends that,
um,
when I met them probably a decade ago,
they were pretty hardcore Mormons.
They're really nice folks and they're
friends with my wife first and then we'd
go to dinner with them and then we'd
have these bizarre fucking
conversations.
Like you don't believe in a higher power
I go to.
It's not that I don't believe,
I just don't see any evidence.
Like show me some evidence of a higher
power.
And then I'll say,
well,
that makes a lot of sense,
but it she's like,
well,
I wouldn't be able to live with.
I wouldn't be able to get up every day
if I didn't think that something's going
to happen after I die.
I go,
don't you enjoy going out to dinner?
We're out at dinner.
We had a nice dinner at a nice
restaurant.
We're having fun having a glass of wine.
You are enjoying this.
Like why does this have to lead to some
magic fairy land where people have
wings?
Why does that have to,
why can't you just enjoy this life?
Well,
I don't know.
I don't know what happens when I die.
I mean,
if I didn't know what happens when I
die,
I wouldn't be able to go on.
I'm like,
well,
that's pretty ridiculous.
That's pretty ridiculous.
But for a lot of people it becomes,
um,
scaffolding for your thoughts,
scaffolding for your emotions.
Like you have this structure that allows
you to get by.
It allows you to get through every day.
And if someone pulls that structure and
you're forced to sort of create a
structure on your own,
it's extremely problematic and these
people that I'm friends with,
they abandoned their church and they
abandoned their church and now they're
in this very weird limbo place where
it's fairly interesting because they're
very insightful.
And the woman we had this weird
conversation which she was talking about
how she feels like she's very open to
being scammed because she's so trusting
because she grew up in a fundamentalist
mormon background and that she's just so
open to suggestion because she was
buying into horseshit her whole life and
she,
she just didn't question and this
becomes sort of a pattern of thinking
and it's,
it's hard for people to just all of a
sudden reestablish their,
their ideology would establish their
position and religion is an excellent
scaffolding for sort of establishing
your,
your place in the world.
Yeah.
And it's very comforting to have a sense
of authority of as well,
right?
I mean there's something like being,
having,
having a loving.
Yes.
Having the creator of the universe like
personally taken interest in your
wellbeing must be an incredible sort of
ego boost and Monday incredible security
blanket.
I mean,
there's a reason why religions strokes
us in certain ways that 98 percent of
the world is religious.
You know,
it,
it provides,
it must provide some kind of sanctuary
that's hard to,
to,
to shake off.
I think it's an enlightenment bridge.
I think it's a,
it's almost like a,
a construct that we've created to sort
of get our way out of the monkey body to
get our way through to some next stage
and as we're rejecting it now,
pretty much for the first time in human
history,
it's culturally acceptable to reject it
and it's almost more prevalent amongst
youth than it is to accept it.
If you talk to people in the,
you know,
the early 19 hundreds about rejecting
God and atheism,
but you would get a small percentage of
highly educated people that would accept
that idea.
Whereas if you go to universities today
and you promote atheism,
you're gonna get a massive following.
Yeah.
There's a massive amount of people that
are with you on this.
I'm,
I'm not even following Shinsei following
a massive amount of people in agreement
with you on these concepts that they.
Yeah,
we are dealing with a new era when new
era of understanding and for a lot of
people that's absolutely terrifying.
Yeah.
It's less terrifying to me than the
possibility of people,
of people with religious delusions
getting access to weapons of mass
destruction,
which is why I keep fighting,
fighting the atheist fight.
I think this is.
This has the potential to be absolutely
calamitous and whatever we can do to to
minimize religious thinking and
basically just hold people to account
for what they claim to believe.
I mean if,
if,
if you were interviewing someone for a
job and you were considering hiring them
and they started talking about how Elvis
is still alive and he communicates with
them through by leaving messages in
their toast or something,
I when you would just immediately
disqualify that person from you,
you would think,
this is a crazy person.
It would be nice to me if you similarly
judged people who claim that the creator
of the universe speaks to them on a
daily basis and listening to what they
say and listen to their prayers and,
and intervenes in worldly affairs to
cause,
make natural disasters like destroy
their neighbor's house but not their
house.
I mean like for so many things on your
mental arrogance.
Like I saw her on the TV,
there was like a,
you know,
a wildfire that went through an
Australian suburb and the lady standing
there in front of her house,
she's like,
ah,
you know,
God saved my house.
Like what?
God hated good neighbors so much.
He wanted to burn down their house.
That's a pretty fucked up thing for God
to do.
Like just to judge people on these
beliefs the same way we would judge them
if you,
if they weren't religious beliefs,
if they were equally silly but,
but not protected by the fact that they,
they,
they fold into a formal role.
Well,
the legacy thought patterns or thought
patterns that existed before the
Internet.
And I think that the Internet is the new
religion in the sense that it's not a
religion,
but it's a,
it's a way to establish cultures and
communities.
It's a way to exchange information.
It's a way to to live and think that
never existed before when you were
alone,
when you were by yourself,
when you were in these small tribes and
all you had with this stupid old book of
nonsense stories about,
you know,
the original two people that existed in
fucking earth being created in seven
days by an old man who lives in the
clouds.
That was all you had saw your hat and we
have so much more now.
And the,
the,
the landscape that you're surveying is
so much larger.
The landscape of information is just not
just,
it's almost inconceivably larger and
inconceivably larger than when I was a
boy.
I mean I,
I was,
I went to Catholic school for only one
year and I was very fortunate that I
didn't have very religious parents and
they just sent me to Catholic school
because it was a good option.
I mean everyone was sort of religion,
religious,
but only casually,
but it was so bad that I abandoned all
my ideas of religion and I can really
clearly remember this because it was an
important part of my life because my
parents had broken up when I was five
years old and I was really insecure and
scared and I just.
My Dad wasn't around anymore.
I was with my mom and I was,
for whatever reason,
I was seeking some sort of comfort in
religion,
what God says you should do this and God
says,
I don't even know who the fuck I heard
it from,
but I went to one year of Catholic
school and these people were so horrible
that I abandoned everything.
I had given it all up by the time.
Okay.
They're the,
they're the cancel,
Colbert religion they could have.
Had you had.
You just been a little sweeter.
I so I understand it.
Even though I was only five years old,
I can remember it.
I mean,
I remember in vague sort of snapshots
and some weird,
weird images in our mind and we are
concepts that I've sort of like held
onto.
I've never experienced it.
I've never,
I've never.
It's a,
it's a,
an aspect of human,
human kind and human civilization and
human psychology that is totally opaque
and ineffable to me.
I'd done,
I'd done it under.
I can't quite understand how.
I'm almost one of the very,
very few people in the world who doesn't
have that Jane Breed,
I guess I've me to a computer.
Well you're one of the very few people
in the world,
but I think the children that are
growing up today,
kids that are born
in 2014,
there's going to be a less and less of
that it's going to be.
And also I should carve out here.
There are certain civilized societies.
And again,
I use the word civilized advisedly,
not to,
not to shit on,
you know,
developing countries,
but there are educated rich countries
where the populations have basically
gotten rid of religion altogether.
Really?
Cultures in Denmark.
Um,
I mean Australia and New Zealand,
a pretty secular,
like paypal will normal nominally tick
Catholic on a,
on a box,
but when you actually stopped to ask
them whether or not they believe any of
the tenants,
you've got 60 or 70 percent of the
population who never go to church and
don't think of themselves as being,
as being religious.
We'll look about gluggy Canada,
less religious than America.
America is less religious than Mexico,
right?
America is the most religious rich
country,
and that's all by the Reagan
administration.
Those cocksuckers.
Why?
Because they courted it.
They courted the,
the,
the rat model of Christian religious
people from the 19 eighties were courted
by the Reagan administration because
they recognize them as being a source
of.
If you could get those people on your
side,
you had a guaranteed base.
That's where they get their political
clout from.
But it goes back a long way in American
history,
the strain of puritanical evangelic
event,
evangelical protestantism,
uh,
in Australia,
we have a saying that whenever there's a
moral outrage and America and America
gets it's tits in a tangle about,
you know,
Janet Jackson's Boob or something,
we say,
thank God we were founded by criminals
and.
No,
but it's true though.
I mean Australia has legalized
prostitution.
Yeah.
Australia has a lot of things that
America doesn't have in that sense.
And I think the,
the,
the foundation,
the original echoes of ignorance that
started this whole thing off.
They still reverberate in 2014 and I was
really ridiculous ideas about sex in
this country.
Oh God.
Don't even get me started.
It's crazy.
I'm trying to get you started.
It is.
That's why we're here.
The dysfunction that religion puts into
people's sex lives,
I think is just.
Well for a start,
it's criminal because it leads to so
much suffering,
especially in the gay community.
I mean,
you know,
the,
the level of teens,
teenage suicide among Quia kids in
religious areas is shocking.
Is a national disgrace that we should be
doing a lot more about and we should be
much more vocal about not tolerating,
you know,
preachers preaching of hate,
the preaching of hate and also this idea
that it's a choice.
That's maddening to me.
What always makes me feel like I was
reading a,
an opinion by Scalia about this and it
almost sounded like these people are
bisexual because if he believes it's a
choice,
he's implying that he could choose to
blow a guy.
Well,
he couldn't choose to blow a guy.
Yeah.
Why not?
He could.
I mean,
if he's just like,
fuck man.
Bowie apparently slept together.
If you want to believe.
Yeah.
I'm fucking shocked at ex wife.
Lot of crazy stuff was going on.
It was the seventies.
I get they got nutty,
but I think it is a
choice.
But here's my point.
So what if you're a straight person that
you choose to do gay shit?
What?
Who Cares?
Why does anyone care?
And if you will,
why would anyone say that?
It must be a choice.
How could you possibly know what someone
wants to or doesn't want to do,
what they feel inside,
and even if it were a choice,
let's assume for the sake of argument
that everyone is like perfectly
bisexual.
It's an absurd argument,
but this is kind of what they're saying,
what they're implying.
If they're saying that it's totally a
choice,
then you don't give up your civil rights
just because you belong to the community
you belong to as a choice.
Religion is a choice,
but it's still protected.
You still have the right to worship in
whatever faith you want.
The fact that I can choose to be a
question or choose to be a Muslim
doesn't deprive me of my right to
exercise the to the free exercise of
religion.
Similarly,
the my choice to be married to a man
should not even if even if it is
completely a choice,
the way that I'm hardwired sexually and
emotionally should not deprive me of my
civil rights.
Absolutely,
and that's one of the most offensive
ideas in when it comes to this country
where there's an argument against same
sex marriages and it's still a fucking
hot point topic of debate in 2014.
How many states are where our same sex
marriage too?
I think that's fucking crazy.
That is crazy.
Vatican propose a dramatic shift in
attitude towards gays.
Same sex couple.
This new pope.
I'm not into the pope man,
but this new new pope is a fucking and
interesting is a goodie.
He sits on a regular chair.
He doesn't ride around the pope.
Tmobile.
I mean they got rid of that evil fucker
and they went a 180 degrees.
The other director.
Yeah,
he's causing.
I mean he's a,
he's ruffling a lot of feathers in the
conservative,
you know there are a lot of people
behind the pope who are conservative
cardinals who are not happy campers at
all.
He represents a much more frankly,
Latin American strain of religion,
which is a much,
much less crazy,
much more loving,
kind of communal interpretation of
Catholicism.
So there's 18 different states.
You said 35.
I think I'm right.
Can we google it?
I think that.
I think that um,
that's fucking incredible.
That's incredible that there's still
laws.
It might actually be the other way
round.
It might be 32.
You can't get ready and I don't know.
We'll find out soon enough,
but the fact that there's that many
states where it's 32 states have legal
same sex marriage.
That's fucking crazy.
I mean frankly I'm given like,
it's like you were saying about the,
the moral evolution of racism though,
like from when you were growing up,
born in 1967,
that that half century there has just
been a massive,
massive period of advance.
And it is true.
I mean you've got to give people time.
I do.
I am impressed that 32 states now you
can get married,
same sex couples can get married and
because just 10 years ago,
let alone 20 years ago it was kind of
inconceivable.
Well,
this is why I'm not impressed because
there's no logical reason other than
religion,
but there never is.
It's never logical.
There's not a logical reason for racism.
There's not a logical reason for
homophobia.
There's no logical reason to cancel a
call back.
I mean people
in a completely free society.
There should be no reason to restrict
people because you don't like it.
There should be no reason why anyone
should be able to say you can't get
married to a man because I don't like
it.
I hope that that sentiment is becoming,
and I think it is becoming more and more
prevalent across the board,
100 percent that the libertarian wing of
the Republican Party and the progressive
wing of the Democratic Party,
a kind of whole showing together.
They're kind of opposite extremes,
but they're actually quite close on this
stuff.
Also on NSA stuff and civil liberties.
Like I really wish we could galvanize a
community of likeminded people who have
basically broadly socially libertarian
and kind of culturally sophisticated
people to enact policies like this.
And I think that.
I think that that group,
that core is growing.
The trend is definitely moving in that
direction and I think the only thing
that would stop it as some sort of
cataclysmic disaster sends us back to
this really difficult struggle and
removes our access to information.
Well actually I think what he always
does,
it is like an attack.
If we get hit again in,
you know,
in a,
on a scale of nine slash 11 or heaven
forbid worse,
which probably would be,
if it were another example of mega
terrorism,
um,
then you will get people clinging to
their religion more and gun,
going back and being less tolerant and
being much,
much more okay with their civil
liberties being infringed that we more
antagonistic.
That's the really corrosive effective.
But don't you think things come in
waves.
I mean there are,
there are like a heightened
civilizations that fall apart and then
they come back and go and forth and it's
like if you look at history,
we like to think of history as being
some straight linear path to 2014 with
progress from day one to day.
You know,
but it's not.
I mean,
there's ages of enlightenment and
there's is decreases and there's
cataclysmic disasters,
natural disasters,
horrific things that happened that throw
people back.
I mean,
there's people that argue that Iraq and
especially Baghdad,
I've never recovered from the Mongol
invasion of the 12 hundreds.
They killed everyone in the city,
turned the river red with blood and
black with ink,
literally slaughtered all the scholars,
threw away all the.
I mean,
the one thing that people in this day
and age don't realize is that Islam used
to be the center of Science of
philosophy.
I mean,
that was the original advanced course.
Sure.
Yeah.
They were onto,
onto the enlightenment along time before
we were.
That's the.
That's the odd thing about the way that
the tables have turned.
I mean,
look at the.
Yeah,
the library of Alexandria,
Alexandria burned down and we lost
massive resources of human civilization.
Yet as we say in Australia,
it's swings and roundabouts,
meaning,
you know,
it comes and goes.
Well,
I think we're looking at things on an
unbelievably large scale and we're
looking at these little blips and these
blips are very important to us because
our lives are so short in perspective.
You know,
if you.
If you look at the concept of a human
life being only 100 years at the very
best and look at a 100 years in to the
10,000
years of human history.
It's a fucking blink of an eye
and the 10,000
years of human history is a blink is a
blip in comparison to the age of the,
of the earth and the age of the earth is
a blip.
And on the age of the universe and
talk to folks like.
There's a guy named Randall Carlson who
have had on the podcast who's an expert
in Astro asteroidal impacts and he
believes that the whole reason for this
10,000
year like our idea of human civilization
being 10,000
years.
He thinks that goes back way further
than that.
And he points to all these meteor
impacts.
And especially in Asia and in Europe.
In a $12,000.
When they go to these core samples of
the earth,
you go back to about 12,000
years ago,
there's all this evidence of what's
called nuclear glass try thing.
It's called Triton night.
That means that the earth was pelted by
meteors,
human civilizations prior to that.
Most certainly he's.
He's absolutely there any fossil
evidence.
There's evidence in far as far as
construction that we're starting to
uncover now let go.
Beckley,
Tapi is this massive stone structure
that existed back when they thought that
people were just hunters and gatherers
and it's a recently on earth and to this
day they've only gotten about five
percent of it on earth,
but it's these massive stone columns,
19 feet high that are between 12 and
14,000
years old at a time where they didn't
think anyone was
building as scientifically minded guy on
on issues where I don't really know what
I'm talking about.
I usually just get gail to the majority
of expert opinion and that's so far
outside of what we most archeologists
claim more.
Just go with them.
No,
it's not anymore,
right?
Yeah.
Go back to the tap,
but you need to look at this because
this is,
well 100 percent established science
would.
The reason why it's established is go
beckley.
Tappy was somehow or another covered up
on purpose,
so they were most likely conquered by
someone else and these structures were
covered.
So when they do these,
uh,
these carbon samples of the soil,
it's uniform from the top to the bottom,
which means that somewhere around 12,000
years ago these things were covered up.
That means it could be far older than
that because you're dealing with stone
structures and meaning it could be
13,000.
Who knows how old it could be,
but
these are huge structures that were
created.
Jamie,
pull it up if you get a chance.
Also,
it depends on how you define
civilization,
right?
I mean,
this is really advanced stuff.
Look,
I don't mean to be old pc about this,
but the Australian aborigines,
they are 80 to 120,000
years old.
The oldest surviving civilization now,
they don't build big,
you know,
big structures.
But to survive for 100,000
years in a stable form,
to have language,
to have a certain culture to,
you know,
to know how to,
how to use the land and to know how to
hunt and to build tools and all that
sort of stuff.
Like that's a,
that's a long time that makes our sort
of 5,000
years of,
you know,
modern civilization look like just
nothing.
I think like sue was about 6,000
years ago.
That was what we considered to be the
first written language and cuny
cuneiform.
Yeah.
I'm sort of just counting it from the of
Judaism,
I suppose in the Iliad and the Odyssey
and the Talmud.
This,
um,
go back.
The tappy discovery is just one of many
that they're slowly starting to uncover.
Because when you look at these
structures,
a lot of them are there,
they're covered up with dirt.
The Amazon,
they're constantly finding these ancient
civilizations.
They have no explanation for the Amazon
ancient structures that have actually
become like hills and they find these
hills and they go,
I think this might've been a building.
And then they start hacking through it.
And then they bring in a radar and they
just,
they,
they pound the earth with radar to try
to understand what's underneath it and
they find these builders
things that amazing how quickly we can
forget our history such that we don't
even know that.
Like I would have thought that there'd
be a continuity of human experience and
human record keeping in some way that we
would.
We would know that we wouldn't have to
be making this stuff up.
Well,
that's what Randall Carlson comes in
because Randall Carlson,
who's an expert in these asteroidal
impacts,
says that human beings have had to reset
that.
There's been several resets over the
course of many,
many millions of years,
or in many hundreds of thousands of
years of life.
There's also a super volcano in
Indonesia that they've attributed to be
one of the main reasons why all human
beings come from one individual genetic
source.
They think that 75,000
years ago,
the Super Volcano,
that glue,
it's much larger than yellowstone and
yellowstone blows.
We are all fucked.
Like it's going to kill almost everyone
in this continent eventually and
globally.
It's going to have a massive effect to
nuclear winter,
a massive climate change,
and every six to 800,000
years,
this fucking goes off.
It's a called volcano.
That's,
I believe it's 600 kilometers wide,
which is 300 miles and they only
discovered this,
that this used to be a volcano in the
beginning of the 20th century when they
started using satellite imagery when
they started looking at yellow stone
from space and they were like,
um,
it's kind of fucking cap that blew off
and left a crater.
Like,
it's like we're just going about our
lives,
you know,
the best laid plans of mice and men.
I mean,
it'll all go to hell at some point.
Some point,
and this is at yellowstone,
that's the Caldera fucking terrifying.
And they figured that out from space
where they looked at it and so that used
to be a mountain and that mountain
exploded and left behind this sort of
crater looking.
It's amazing in terms of the continuity
of civilizations and how we.
And that,
that reset that.
I was reading a fascinating pace about.
There was a a commission to figure out
how to.
We were talking about radioactive waste
earlier on how long this lasts,
right?
The radioactive waste from nuclear
stockpiles.
How do you build signs for future
civilization?
To tell them not to touch the weights
don't go.
There is an act.
There is a fascinating.
I think it's in slate.
A fascinating article about the
commission which was which had the
commission which has been commissioned
to figure out.
Let's assume that there's a
civilizational reset,
which there probably will be right at
some point while this stuff is still
bad,
so these people aren't going to know our
language.
They're not gonna understand that a
skull and crossbones means this is bad.
They're not going to.
They may not even understand the concept
that we may lose the technology to
nuclear and understand what nuclear is.
They May.
That happens.
Surprisingly often.
We know it's already already.
I'm losing where my photos are from hard
drives that are just three.
How drives it go,
right?
You know,
multiply that by a million and suddenly
they're designing like these,
these huge landscapes of like
interlocking sticks that are like,
you know,
hundreds of feet high to try to imply
that this is a bad,
this is a bad thing and that you
shouldn't dig it up.
But I mean at the end of the day what
the conclusion was,
you probably just shouldn't put anything
there because people were always going
to be curious and you never going to
convince them like,
you know,
we go into the,
we go into the tombs of the Pharaoh in,
you know,
in Egypt because we just think that
their beliefs about,
about,
uh,
you know,
the,
the bad that will come to us from going
in.
There are silly fantasies.
What a future civilizations think that
we're full of silly fantasies when we
tell them not to go into nuclear waste.
That's absolutely possible.
And I think we would need something like
Georgia guidestones or like some giant
Rosetta stone in several different
languages to sort of let them decode it.
And if we do have a civilizational
reset,
like a barbaric type civilization is all
that's left and we literally like
walking dead,
running around,
scavenging for food and everyone forgets
how to count.
I mean fuck man,
people are.
A lot of people are going to die of
cancer and if it's the only people that
are left on earth are people that live
in Nevada,
they might all die.
I mean that's very possible.
If you're talking about 75,000
people,
which is low or 75,000
years ago,
which they think a few thousand people
were leftover.
That's right.
Isn't that amazing?
That's it.
Yeah.
This Indonesia.
Okay.
And when we are all much more closely
related than you would ever assume from
that bottle necking period,
where,
where humanity dwindled down to just a
few a few pipes.
So where their thinking is 75,000
years ago,
giant sums of people were wiped out.
And then 10 to 12,000
years ago again,
giant amounts of people were wiped out.
And that's where civilization had it's
reset.
That's also the end of the ice age.
That's also the almost instantaneous
death of woolly mammoths,
Saber Tooth Tigers,
and it's this moment,
this event that they're showing in
geological evidence.
It's indisputable.
There was absolutely some sort of huge
meteorological event,
some sort or media event asteroidal
event where we were pelted were pelted
with and it's not like it's unusual.
It's like something like 900,000
near Earth objects had been mapped out.
Yeah,
we,
this is actually a really easy thing to
solve,
but we don't put the money into solving
it yet.
If you identify it far enough out,
it's a simple calculation to be able to
do the math and go,
oh well that one's going to hit us.
And then you just got to send up a bunch
of nukes to nudge it off course if you
catch it early.
But if you don't catch it until it's
almost here rude,
they don't think they think that
anymore.
I don't think they think nukes.
I think the idea's to nudge it out of
the way,
but with changing the,
um,
the um,
what,
what is it called?
The aerodynamics of the,
uh,
of the,
the asteroids idea.
It's interesting putting a web on it
somehow or another will affect how a.
I mean,
I'm sure there are a bunch of things,
but it's difficult engineering thing to
come up with a figure to figure out a
way to nudge an asteroid.
I don't know if that's true and I also
think there's also an issue with space
because of the gravity of the sun.
There's a lot of things that come from
behind the sun that we don't even see
coming because the gravity of the sun
altar space,
it alters the way we view things,
but kind you factor that in.
I mean we spent around the sun so we get
to see all four corners of the of the
universe as we go around,
but to this day constantly there's
things that come very close to us that
we don't see coming because we.
Because Republicans cut funding to NASA
and stuff like that.
Well,
I would like to think that that's the
case,
but I think it might be slightly beyond
our grasp right now.
To see all of them coming.
Things that are coming from the North
Pole and the South Pole.
They're coming from places where we're
not really observing the sky,
very vigilantly and you know,
a lot of what we find is actually
discovered by amateur astronomers.
They find asteroids and they named them
and measure them and then they send in
their data and how many of those fuckers
are out there.
I mean,
I don't know how many people are out
there actively searching for asteroids.
I don't think it's very many and I think
it's shocking.
But you're talking about the policy
concern,
which I agree with.
I'm talking about there are two
concerns,
right?
One is,
would it be,
do we have the scientific and
engineering know how to be able to nudge
a,
an asteroid out of the way if we catch
it early enough.
And then the other question is,
are we bothering to look?
And it's the question that I'm,
that I'm more concerned about.
I think we're getting close,
but I also think there's the issue of
collisions when asteroids collide with
each other and then send one hurling
towards us that we didn't expect that
can happen too.
We're fucked.
Fuck.
We're all fucked.
So,
uh,
we did another hour.
That's good.
So I'm gonna go take a chill pill,
take a chill pill.
Tell everybody one more time.
How do we get to your show Josh steps on
twitter.
You can either go to buy.
Well actually my website stand on the
web,
so don't worry about that.
It's just steps on twitter.
J O s h Z,
z e PPS.
I always want to say it's dead because
that's what you're saying.
Um,
but uh,
but shoot an email.
Just open your email address.
Please don't know.
I want them to because they that can
subscribe.
It's just info.
It's not my personal address info at we
the people pod because we,
the people are going to be the night of
the live show info.
That way the people pod.com.
And tell us what part of this
conversation you liked the most and then
you'll get free stuff.
When I launched.
I'm going to read that much on employee,
so I'll find something.
Josh steps.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you sir.
This a beautiful conversation.
I really enjoyed it.
I'd love to.
When are you gonna?
Be In la again.
I don't know.
Whenever you invite me back,
we'll work it out.
Great.
Thank you.