Good.
Four,
three,
two,
one.
Live Brian Red Ban.
Feeling Buddy.
Great.
Feeling it in here.
Angry.
Alright.
Sore.
But I got it.
I love this new studio.
It's so amazing.
It's crazy how much stuff you're going
to have in here.
It's going to be bad ass.
Yeah,
we're working on it.
We're making it happen.
Before we do this,
I have to apologize.
I have to apologize for something I said
last week,
last Tuesday in passing,
we were watching a corey feldman clip
and uh,
corey feldman was doing this crazy dance
and Greg Fitzsimmons was in and Corey
Feldman had some little tight jacket and
it's just weird song he was saying and I
said that jacket was wearing that jacket
when he was young and he got diddled
his.
I was trying to make Greg left,
right?
You're trying to say fucked up things to
make comedians laugh,
which is what we do and we get together.
We say the most heinous shit,
but I felt terrible after somebody
pointed it out.
Like I didn't even remember saying it.
Some pointed out.
And then Saturday I watched it and I
felt so terrible because the especially
like out of context,
like it's just me laughing about him
getting detailed.
Right.
And it just,
it's horrible.
Anything that's taken out of context,
like that's going to make you feel weird
if you don't see that,
but there's no excuse like what it is.
It was,
you swing it a lot of pitches when you
do an live podcasts and sometimes you
hit yourself in the Dick with a bat.
And that's what I did.
It was,
it was totally wrong.
It wasn't,
it wasn't funny.
I took a swing at it was,
it was the wrong thing to do.
It was what the best way to describe it
is.
It was thoughtless because I didn't
really didn't think I was just trying to
say something fucked up to make greg
lap.
I wasn't thinking like this is a real
person.
And I've watched him the other day in a
movie man.
I saw him in Gremlins.
I was watching gremlins with my kids
after.
Actually we did the podcast before.
I watched the clip though,
because I didn't,
I hadn't seen,
you know,
I do it and then I'm done with it,
but I didn't think about it.
I said,
you know,
first of all,
he was doing the Michael Jackson thing,
you know,
he wears a Michael Jackson jacket and
dance like Michael Jackson.
He didn't.
He said Michael Jackson didn't even do
anything to them,
so it didn't even make sense.
It was just a stupid line to say,
but I felt terrible.
I couldn't sleep Saturday night.
I felt really bad.
I felt bad for a bunch of reasons.
One,
I felt bad because it's a mean thing to
say and I didn't.
I didn't mean it to be.
Even though it was just,
I was just trying to be funny.
You know patrice o Neal said something
once when he was defending opie and
Anthony,
he was saying,
when someone says something really funny
or the same person says something really
fucked up,
it all comes from the same place.
Like they're trying to do the same
thing.
They just miss you know.
But that was without a doubt,
the worst miss,
the most embarrassing to me.
I'm the most depressing the most.
Uh,
what's the best way to describe it?
Just so disappointed that I did that
because he is a,
he was a kid,
you know,
I don't even think he actually got
molested.
I think he was actually saying that
Corey Haim got molested and he didn't.
Well,
that would make sense where I,
Corey Haim did so much drugs,
you know,
if he did get molested.
But.
Well,
I started looking into this shit more
and more recently like Hollywood
molestation with children.
It's,
it's no joke,
man,
like just as.
It's no joke with sexual harassment and
assault with women.
When you see me,
this Harvey Weinstein thing and these
other directors now are getting in
trouble for the same thing.
The same kind of shit happened to a lot
of kids that were involved in,
in these child movies.
You don't think about that when you're
just trying to crack a joke.
And I just want everybody know if,
if you were disappointed,
there's no.
If you were disappointed in me,
there's no way.
You were more disappointed in me than I
am disappointed in me.
I didn't sleep Saturday.
I had a hard time sleeping last night.
I felt bad about it all day.
I felt terrible and I went to underwood
farms.
You know what an underwear ad farms is a
great family.
Time.
Had a good time with the kids.
You know,
we're picking out pumpkin's and doing
all this stuff,
but the entire time I was there there's
like this blanket of like,
how did I say that?
Why did I say that?
Like sometimes you'll say something
fucked up and then after you did it,
like you can't believe you said it like
it.
Especially when we're doing this live.
Right.
If you and me were just out at a diner,
we would probably say that and laugh to
each other because no one's getting hurt
by it.
We're just making each other laugh and
we do that all the time.
Right.
We say started shit to each other all
the time,
but when other people hear it and then
the guy hears it,
like of course you heard it.
Like that's just wrong,
you know,
I didn't mean to have that impact and I
didn't think about it.
It was very thoughtless,
so I was extremely disappointed myself.
But what's interesting about it,
trying to look at it from a different
perspective,
trying to like examine it,
like the feeling of doing something that
you shouldn't have done that might have
hurt someone's feelings because you were
senseless and thoughtless.
That feeling is a terrible feeling and
it's,
it's weird.
Like it overcomes your whole day.
Like,
no,
I don't think anybody knew because I was
still having fun with the family and
everybody was laughing.
We did a lot of kid stuff.
But at the end of the day that was with
me all day.
I mean,
it was just,
it was like a fucking wet blanket that I
was carrying with me,
like a depression blanket.
And um,
there's no,
uh,
there's no other way to put it.
Then you know that I'm sorry and then I
shouldn't have done it.
But what I was thinking while it was all
happening,
I was like this feeling of letting a
bunch of people down and hurting
someone's feeling,
doing something in a mass way,
like on the Internet.
This is a new feeling like before you
could,
people could be upset at you,
maybe someone you know or people you
work with and it's a bad feeling.
But this is a different kind of bad
feeling.
It's an intensified bad feeling.
Especially like the way I did it because
it's so stupid.
And I would think that at this age I'm
50.
I would see like a don saying stupid
shit.
Obviously I'm not,
you know,
I'm,
I'm not done.
Like that's the fucked up thing about
being a person.
It requires constant diligence.
Like you have to constantly pay
attention to your thinking.
You have to constantly pay attention to
the way you behave and who you are.
You can't just go off the cuff.
And the other thing,
it's making me think of,
you know,
doing this sober October thing.
And um,
obviously I love pot and uh,
I've always loved pot and I've been a
regular pot smoker for 20 years,
but what,
there is a difference in my personality
when I'm not smoking pot,
grumpy,
uh,
more,
more tense,
less kind and I have to like catch
myself before I get upset about things.
Whereas when I'm high or if I even then
I'm not,
if I'm,
if I'm not even if I'm high,
but if I'm just smoking on a regular
basis,
I'm way more mellow,
way more relaxed about things and way
more.
Um,
I guess the right word is humble.
It's not like I'm cocky when I'm sober,
but I'm like really aware,
much more aware of gratitude.
And Fortunately I'm lucky and
appreciative of my friends.
I want to hug people more.
Like pod has a lot of,
for me from my fucked up brain has a lot
of really positive effects as a lot of
really positive personality effects.
But I think I might be downplaying my
dependence on it.
Like I think that might've been going
like that's nothing.
I'll just fucking quit pot.
It's nothing man.
I don't know about all that.
Um,
my dreams.
Here's another thing.
You remember him,
dude,
I don't remember them.
They're fucking crazy.
They're all wolves and bears and
drowning and falling off buildings and,
and fucking lava coming at you.
It's all primal shit.
Wow.
It's weird,
man.
I'm having all these,
uh,
these Predator dreams.
It's,
it's very strange.
Like,
um,
I had these dreams,
these,
these cart almost cartoon wolves at
these giant feet and they will like
running through the woods and uh,
somehow or another trying to get away
from them.
I had a dream that I was for some reason
I was crawling through some fucking cave
and there was an enormous bear inside
this cave and it was looking at me and I
was like,
I gotta get the fuck out of here.
And it was like trying to figure out
whether or not the bear was going to
come after me,
but I mean super vivid.
I don't,
I don't remember my dreams when I was
getting high and last I took the Alpha
brain before I went to sleep.
That,
that will fucking spark you up some
crazy lucid dreams.
But other than that,
I would just sleep good.
I never had a problem sleeping.
I'd get up in the morning and I'd be
fine.
But there is a,
there is a big difference between me
when I'm using pot and me when I'm not
using.
I'm noticing the same thing with Ari and
those are.
He gets a little more intense about
things,
a little more upset about things.
He's fucking gets really mad at people
on comments.
He fucking fights with people online.
They call them a Welsh fuck you.
I'm not a wheelchair.
He's like super intense.
Have you ever switched in it?
They.
Have you done anything more since you've
done this?
Like are you drinking more coffee
everyday,
are you?
No.
Well I'm doing so much goddamn yoga that
because we have this hot yoga challenge
and the hot yoga challenges,
you have to do 15 in a month.
Well my dumb ass did one the first week
and two the second week.
So yeah,
so I've been on a rampage where,
um,
I've done eight straight days of yoga in
a row as of today.
Wow.
Yeah.
And I have four more to go.
Um,
so the Thomas biggest problem.
Tom?
A week?
Yeah.
Black Ford to do though.
I mean I have until next Tuesday so I
could kill it on,
on Thanksgiving.
The 31st could be my last one,
but I'm not going to do that.
I'm banging them all out this week.
We're doing it together for the first
time.
Ari?
Tom Burton.
I would do it together.
I don't want to say where.
And I don't want to say when,
because I don't want you fucking freak
showing up,
but we're going to do it together one
day this week.
You also,
that's what Tom's biggest problem is.
It's just he's so busy trying to fit in
you,
you kind of do a 90 minute hot yoga,
which I thought was insane because
they've never done it.
Right,
right.
Every 90 minutes is a long time.
Well,
I do it every week,
but I usually only do it once or twice a
week.
And now I've done eight fucking days in
a row as of today.
It's rough.
I'm shredded though.
Son.
Ken Shredded my bobby.
I'm burning off so many fucking
calories.
I actually had blood work done today,
so I'm very interested to see what my
mineral levels are live because I'm
sweating out so much and I'm not really
supplementing minerals that much.
I might have to do that.
I do that on a regular basis,
like every three months I get blood work
done.
The sealer where my nutrient levels are.
I just found this company,
I don't know if you've heard of it.
I think it's called like simply well and
it's like they have all these DNA tests
that you can do,
so I ordered the testosterone test,
but they also have our gi tests.
They have all these tests and they send
it to you.
You spit in a vial,
it takes some hair or something like
that.
And then it's kind of like 24 and me.
What words?
Like the DNA testing,
but they have it for everything.
Vitamin D deficiencies and.
And you could have it like on a
subscription where you get it done
every.
They send you a new kit every three
months to see if it's changed.
Nice.
A testosterone.
That's what I got.
I just got it yesterday.
Huh?
Um,
so to get off this corey feldman thing,
just the end of the day,
I just want to say that,
uh,
that I'm sorry,
and if I disappointed anybody,
I'm sorry to it.
Just when you,
you know,
comedians try to say fucked up things to
each other and I was talking to Colin
Quinn about this the other night.
Collin was at the comedy store and I
told Carl and I were talking.
I go,
man,
I miss tough crowd.
He goes,
oh,
I miss it so much.
He goes,
but you know what?
We could never fucking do it today.
He goes,
[inaudible].
Think of the things that Patrice and
nick depaulo would say to each other.
He's like,
if you did that today,
people would have riots.
They would be protesting.
They would,
they would try to have the show shut
down.
Comedy central would freak out.
People get fired.
I was like,
you probably right.
But that was like the best show ever on
comedy set next to the Chappelle show.
No,
next to South Park.
Okay.
South Park number one,
Chappelle show,
number two,
tough crowd number three in my opinion.
South Park still go in for it.
They,
they,
they don't give even the video.
Fuck.
They have this new video game.
It's called butt hole fractured,
but whole fractured saw that I saw that,
but it's a,
there's like a part where you're like
these little boys and you're dressed up
as strippers and you're in a strip club
getting lapped at.
You're doing lap dances for guy,
so you're on a guy's junk and rude.
It's such a good kid.
So,
so anyway,
these moments where you fuck up these
terrible feelings,
like this is how I'm looking at it.
I wish I could take it back,
but I can't.
Right?
There's nothing you can do.
And if people are mad at me now because
of that,
you're right.
You know,
I don't,
I'm not trying to make any excuses for
myself.
I shouldn't have said it.
But when you do have these moments where
you fuck up and you feel terrible,
there are an amazing opportunity to
grow.
You know?
And I think people need to look at stuff
like that this way,
or at least I've been looking at stuff
this way for the last like 10 years or
so.
And it's made a big impact in my life
because I think regular change happens
in like a regular change and growth
happens in like a grinding slow sort of
progress or progression.
But when you,
when something fucked up happens,
when you do something fucked up and you
get that terrible feeling,
you have this opportunity for these
leaps of understanding and these bad
feelings that happen.
They're just,
it's a big alarm to let you know.
And one of the things that I was
thinking about is that human beings now,
the way we interact with each other,
like there's this,
there's a lot of pressure now on people
because it's all this call out culture.
You know,
people are getting mad that people are
doing dumb shit.
Like white girls wearing braids,
you know,
cultural appropriation that going after,
white guys wearing dreadlocks and people
are mad that people are dressing up like
Geishas and they're calling them out
there.
There's a lot of silliness to all this
shit,
but what's interesting about it is
everyone is expressing their displeasure
and pleasure of things there.
They're expressing their anger with
things and their happiness with things
at a level we've never seen before.
And I think people that experienced this
like if it makes sense.
Like it's one thing if somebody gets mad
at you for something like,
you know,
you shouldn't be wearing that blue hat
man.
You know,
I'm in the crips and you know,
we,
we only support red hats or is it the
bloods?
I don't even know.
I think the bloods,
the crips or blue,
right.
If someone gets mad at you for something
that doesn't make any sense that stupid,
but if someone gets mad at you for
poking fun at someone being molested,
that that bad feeling is valid.
Right.
And I think these bad feelings that like
Donald Trump must feel 24 slash seven,
like there is probably.
I mean part of it.
I think part of the reason why he so
angry at people and bitter and barking
and fake news.
I think he feels like shit all day long
because you know,
this guy checks his twitter,
you know,
he does check,
he reads his company,
he's a fucking ego maniac,
right?
So he's paying attention to new shows to
talk shit about him.
He's paying attention to late night
comedians that make jokes about him.
He's paying attention to center.
He can't help himself.
He's constantly commenting on it and he
hears all these people laughing at him
and mocking him and he uses all these
people that think he's a terrible
person.
I read his twitter when he'll put up a
comment,
he'll put up something on twitter and
then I'll read the comments under it.
It's like,
Holy Shit.
People just go hard at him.
You know that motherfucker reads that
stuff,
you know?
He does and he's also involved in a
lawsuit,
several lawsuits now where he's blocked
people on twitter and they're
questioning the constitutionality of
someone being able to block someone from
commenting whether the president of the
United States.
I mean this is a new way to communicate.
You don't want to hear what people have
to say because it's negative.
Well that's,
you know,
we're not,
we're so people are questioning this in
court,
but I think that that feeling that's
hitting this guy,
he might be too old for it and he might
not be ready for it in his he.
So he's got so many things wrong with
them to begin with.
You know,
with his,
the way he treats the world and his,
his ego and the way he's the,
the,
the non presidential and non statesmen
like behavior that people thought was
cute when he was running for office and
the LLC is a giant problem when he's
threatening war with nuclear weapons,
with Korea and shit like that.
But this thing is a new thing.
Is this,
this swarm of bad feeling and in return,
good feeling when something good happens
is a new thing and I think that it's
going to shape the way human beings
interact with each other in a really
radical way.
Because I don't think it's ever existed
like this before.
It hasn't
really has and if you,
if you look at it is if it's a good
thing or a bad thing.
Like,
I forget what I was listening to the
other day where when you were a kid,
uh,
you used to just go outside,
say bye mom,
and then come back at night,
you know,
when it's time for dinner,
eat dinner,
then you go play some video games,
go to bed now it's like the
communication between your mom and stuff
like that is so much more intense.
Constant.
It's constant all day long.
It's like if you're not there,
you're getting texted by your daughter's
son and it's like constant communication
where it's more parenting.
So that's good.
Do you facetime with people all the
time?
Yeah.
I mean remember when we were a kid that
was some jets and shit.
Yeah.
I heard George Jetson do it on your
phone.
I do a phone call.
I was talking to my on my phone the
other day and I'm like,
I am doing Dick Tracy right now,
but better than Dick Tracy.
Right.
Dick Tracy's was bullshit to answer my.
I was in the steam room the other day
and my phone and I was like,
ah,
I can answer it.
Yeah.
Hey,
what's up?
Because it actually has a cell phone
chip.
Yeah.
This guy was at my door.
I was like,
just go in.
I'm not there,
but just go in and pop out of the
bushes.
Shaking your hand.
Right.
She's got the moon apartment building
that make yourself comfortable.
Come on in some of my package.
Oh,
you can take the concept or coming at
Fedex.
Guy should be here soon together.
Take pictures of you too.
I like Brown and I like to Fedex Elf.
It's cool too.
We don't fuck around with DHL.
Got a disease last time.
Oh Dhl on track to Dhl was like the RC
Cola of delivery services.
Totally is RC Cola.
Like if someone said,
hey,
do you want to own RC Cola?
You'd be like,
yeah,
fuck yeah,
it's a lot of money,
but you know,
it ain't Pepsi,
which is.
There's got to be some people out there
that look huge RC Cola fans that have
like RC Cola tee shirts on shit has got
to be dialed.
RC Cola.
Super underrated.
That diet.
Right?
What are,
what are all these obscure ones like
Figo Wu Tang,
au fait with Mr Pitts.
CP CP that.
What's that bad ass root beer?
IBC.
That stuff is fucking fantastic.
Yes.
God.
Damn.
That stuff's good.
I wish that she wasn't bad for you
because God damn it.
Taste delicious.
That is the best fucking root beer on
the planet that I've experienced.
I've tried to not drink sodas much
lately.
That's my Arnold Palmer honor poem or
somebody new thing like I go through.
So like,
that's like an old person thing,
right?
Arnold Palmer?
I am.
I get it.
Like it's so funny.
I get Arnold Palmer's now.
I drink them all day long.
It's like living delicious.
Yeah.
Little little lemon in there.
Now let me ask you this.
Um,
because I don't think
that I would have ever done this many
yoga.
No,
I wouldn't have done this many yogis.
And I know I wouldn't have taken a month
off weed and I know it would have taken
a month off.
Well,
the mother booze.
Not Hard.
I mean,
the only thing that I went the other day
to a Mexican restaurant and I wanted a
margarita so bad have to,
we having,
they had these delicious uh,
um,
there were rib eye tacos.
I was like,
oh,
that looks good.
They fucking with Habanero sauce on.
I'm like,
give me a fucking marguerite.
Oh Shit.
I can't have one.
It really hurt me.
He could have a fake Margarita.
Nope.
Can't have it.
I wanted a beer too.
I wanted a beer and a Margarita.
Um,
but that's not hard,
but I would have never done this.
Might take a week off or something like
that.
I would never have taken a month off if
weren't doing this challenge.
What would you do?
Like,
what kind of challenge would you do?
I tell you,
hang in there and stick with it because
a lot of people don't know,
but you lost like 70 pounds once,
over,
like a short amount of time.
You went crazy.
Brian broke up with his girlfriend.
Fiance.
Yeah.
Same thing.
It's all semantics.
Anyway.
Broke up and said,
you know what?
What am I gonna do with this?
Right.
You got a picture of a all skinny.
Look at the edge is Jesus Christ.
Jesus is still not the guy on the left
though.
Boy,
you got to 43 to 45 to one 63.
Wow.
Look how skinny legs.
Lower righthand side.
Dude,
you're a cute little bitch.
Little look at that.
We'll get the phone.
You're holding up.
It's my job to look at that phone.
Isn't that hilarious?
That back then that phone was the shit.
And if you had that,
now you would assume that you live in
like assisted housing.
I still have that phone to you.
What do you do with it?
Sits in a box in storage texts.
Isis with a burner phone.
But this.
So you,
you.
So what did you lose?
How much did you lose their two?
40th five to one 63.
Jesus Christ.
Dude.
Eighty two pounds.
More than I thought I had lost.
You lost a shitload of fucking weight,
man.
That's amazing.
That's weightwatchers right there buddy.
So you did it at one point in time.
By the way,
what the fuck is going on with your
underwear line?
Like where is it?
Is it like,
oh,
I did that.
The,
if you did it,
it's right above the peers.
That's the Deq root.
Look at the picture of you holding up
the old pants.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
That's just crazy.
And that wasn't even my biggest pants
either.
That's crazy.
Well,
okay.
What would it take?
What would,
what,
what would you be interested in doing?
What kind of challenge?
My challenge is I talk,
I've been talking to Hinchcliffe about
this and a few other people because one
of the biggest things for a lot of us is
smoking and it's cigarettes and uh,
I've been trying to get like we had nine
slash 11 last year.
It was supposed to be nine slash 11.
We had a month notice.
All of us were supposed to click on nine
slash 11.
So we went and forget the date said,
click,
let it go.
It comes out of your mind is so simple,
so easy.
You're so used to say,
but then I was the only one that did it.
I did it for two days and then everyone
else didn't do it and they're all
smoking when you're at the commissary
and all your friends are smoking around
you.
It's almost fucking.
And Tony smokes a lot.
Tony smokes a lot.
A lot of people smoke a lot at the
comedy store.
So my whole thing was like,
hey,
let's,
let's quit cigarettes and everyone
seemed down on it.
Then yesterday I was like,
Hey,
we still quitting next month cigarettes.
And I was like,
man.
So you guys are going to do in November?
Yeah.
I was going to try to quit and.
Well listen,
why don't.
Why don't we set up a chair at least
when I get back from Columbus,
Ohio.
I'll be there next month.
Let's think of a challenge that you
could do and who would you do it with?
You need like Tony Hinchcliffe for sure.
No sugar.
This is,
this is you for a month.
No sugar,
no booze,
no cigarettes.
He would lose 30 pounds just doing that
without having cigarettes.
I'd gained weight because cigarettes
actually like,
I think it's like your heartbeat and
stuff.
Like when you quit cigarettes,
you start munching more like on food.
You use again,
a lot of weight if you use it as an
appetite suppressant.
I use it for breakfast.
Isn't it also,
isn't it also a stimulant though?
It's a stimulant.
Um hmm.
I definitely need to lose weight,
but I also more importantly I want to
quit cigarettes.
Like the drinking I.
that's easy.
Like I quit drinking the other day for
like four days and I smoked while.
You mean I didn't train for four days.
I smoked weed though instead next day I
had,
I was like,
why do I have a hangover?
It was a weed hangover.
Like we'd hang on.
Yeah.
I didn't even realize that when you
first start smoking weed used to have
these.
Like the next day you're like,
man,
I smoke so much weed.
I feel like dumb or something like that.
The next morning I hadn't had.
It had been wild because usually when
I'm smoking I'm drinking.
So I was blamed on the drinking.
Like God damn,
I feel like hungover.
Well,
I've never had a weed hangover.
I don't think you're going to have one.
When you start smoking,
you're going to be a so fucking high.
You're going to smoke half a joint and
be like,
oh,
I want to be handled.
I'm legitimately nervous,
legitimately nervous about smoking pot
again.
But here's my real concern.
I'm really wondering like,
what is going on where I am dreaming so
much more vividly without pot and is
that a bad thing that I'm not dreaming
when I'm smoking pot?
Like am I somehow or another doing some
damage?
Yeah,
I think so.
I think,
I think for sure that marijuana,
if you smoke a lot of marijuana that you
don't have as good a dreams.
I don't,
I don't think you realize you are not a
neuroscientist.
Dr Brian,
Dr Brian here,
Dr Red Band.
But what exactly do you think is what's
causing the lack of dreams?
Another thing you might have,
you know,
thc in your fat and so you're getting
thc,
you know,
still,
burning off.
Especially since you're doing yoga.
It's probably like,
you know,
it's probably still fucking with you a
little.
I don't know,
maybe I don't know,
but I mean we got high before most of
the podcasts with comedians.
I got high before most comedy shows,
so that's like three,
four nights a week at least now I take a
day or two off and it was nothing super
easy to do.
It was never a problem,
but I never took a month off.
So when I would take a day or two off,
even if I go on vacation,
right,
if I went on vacation,
I would take a week off people.
People were mocking me relentlessly
online before I told everybody that I
was taking the month off when they
started doing all this.
Pray for Joe People was going,
Joe,
uh,
I don't,
in quotes,
I don't smoke weed on vacation Rogan,
like,
that's not a problem.
It's not a problem,
but it,
it was just like,
you know,
I'd be in Europe or something like that,
you can't get weed,
don't bring it with you,
you don't wanna go to jail.
So just don't smoke weed.
It was no problem.
So I was like,
I don't need pot.
It's not an issue and I don't need it.
Obviously I've gone through this whole
month,
but I'm really.
I'm stunned at
the differences in the way I'm dreaming.
Like stunned.
Like I never expected it to be so
extreme,
so vivid every night I'm having fucking
crazy dreams every night
and they're almost all primal.
They're almost all like animals and
waterfalls and fucking ocean and it's
all a lot of falling,
like a lot of like
balancing on shit.
Like Ooh.
It's interesting.
Weird.
I think I'm too busy.
I've been thinking about that lately.
I think I do too much shit and I never
thought that before.
I never thought that.
But you would think that like smoking
pot would make you think you're too busy
but not smoking pot.
It makes me think I'm too busy.
It makes me think that
you're probably thinking clear though in
some ways.
You know,
your mind's not fogged with.
Like,
you know,
you're overthinking about music instead
of like life,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
food does not taste as good.
Tell you the food's way better when
you're smoking.
Weed is good.
Movies aren't as good.
Music doesn't sound as good.
I think the key to it is using it
occasionally.
I think that's the key.
I think marijuana,
like daily,
Terence Mckenna talked about this many
years ago and he was a,
he was a daily smoker and one of the
things that he was saying he was doing
some sort of a lecture and he was saying
that the correct way to do marijuana is
to not do it for a long time and then do
as much as you can stand and then just
fucking hold on.
And that's how he would do it.
He would do,
um,
cannabis when he was doing it correctly,
when he wasn't like a,
an inveterate daily smoker.
He would do it like a psychedelic who
would do it in these big bursts where he
would,
you know,
and he was recommending like that's the
way to do it.
And that people will think they know
what cannabis is if they smoked cannabis
on a regular basis.
You don't really know like the way to
really know what it is is to take a lot
of time off
or obviously eat one of Joey's edibles.
No,
I don't do edit was anymore.
That's one thing I quit completely.
I don't fuck with edibles at all.
I would like to see what happens with
Joey.
If he took a week off,
a month off,
joey would be violent.
He would attack people.
Yeah.
It took a month off of edibles or
whatever.
Right.
Did you ever give it up for lent choice
about religious?
Give it a full month dog.
He's going to be here Friday by the way,
folks.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Um,
but if he did take a month off,
I mean he didn't take a month off weed
though.
I don't think it was smoking.
I think it was just eating it.
Yeah.
He told me that once he told me he was,
I can't do these fucking edibles
anymore.
The too much.
Too Much Joe Rogan.
I'm fuck it up.
I'm taking too much.
It's messing me up.
The next time I saw him,
next time I saw him,
he was down and stars to death.
Literally the next time I saw him,
I go,
how much?
How many milligrams was 1:25
throwing down to slash 25 milligrams
stars of death.
I'm like,
you are a monster.
You saw the episode
where he passed out right on the
microphone.
Right?
I can't even see.
He's looking at life to be like slits
like he's like barely crack in the page
of a book.
Like hilarious.
I was listening to his latest episode.
It's Felicia Michael.
So who has a new movie that I'm in
called pervs.
Uh,
where we went through this.
When those strip things,
we put the money in and the curtain
comes up and there's a woman naked
masturbating.
Well,
Felicia did this movie where she asked
me to do.
It's in north Hollywood,
deep in north Hollywood where you
shouldn't go and it's so great.
You're eating this growth sections in
north Hollywood.
Growth in this curtain comes up and
there's all these cameras.
Just this woman.
They're masturbating while asking me
questions and it's so hard to answer
when there's somebody doing that and
you're just like,
what kind of question?
Like,
uh,
just like sex questions and stuff.
I don't remember because it was so long
ago.
I forgot I even did it.
But,
uh,
Felicia was on the other day and
listening to Lee on that,
like he's leads never been to a strip
club before,
but his little voice when he chimes and
he's like,
I've never been to a strip club
authority.
Never been scared of him.
He said,
I want to take that guy to a strict so
bad.
Why is he scared?
He don't know.
He,
I think it's a money thing because he's
just like,
I just don't get it.
You pay the money.
Then they tried to get money that
someone told a story recently about
Jeremiah Watkins trying to took them to
a strip club and he freaked out and just
like ran out the back base.
Same kind of thing.
Like he,
I don't know if he's ever been to one or
doesn't want to go or.
Yeah,
he uh,
he looked at the ground and walk from
the front.
Never looking up all the way to the pack
out the back door.
Yeah,
I did.
I did get a day.
It,
it's just crazy.
I did a show with George Perez and
Compton at a strip club in Compton.
And let me tell you,
man,
that was one of the most eye opening
like,
that exist.
We walk in,
there's stripper.
The stripper just came up to me and he
goes,
hey honey,
look at this pussy ass all the babies.
You want to get it?
He wants some of this written.
I'm like,
Whoa,
what?
She look like a,
like a baby Mama.
Like I don't know,
address that's still baby hand sticking
out of her probably blue baby here and
shoot.
Attractive.
No,
there was,
there was a few,
but then every time you talked to them
you're like,
Oh,
if I fuck up,
I'm dead.
You know,
like she was like,
yeah,
it was pretty crazy for hostile.
What about the clientele?
Uh,
well they,
they,
they were mostly there for us,
like they,
George just pretty much we had the whole
club board ourselves.
I've always all people coming to see the
show.
So it was strippers too though.
And strippers to what was the idea that
you would get people in there for the
show and then the girls would dance for
them afterwards?
Yeah.
And while we're doing the show,
they were coming and sitting on table
and hey,
you want to go get him?
But sex upstairs just making that up.
Or was it was it was foreign.
Whatever you want.
Pretty much play,
but I even fucking scary.
Yeah,
if you go to a bad neighborhood,
I mean there's levels to everything,
right?
Like the,
the levels of stress and pressure that a
check has to deal with.
If she's a stripper in a really bad
neighborhood like that.
That's how diamonds get developed.
Son Diamonds in a,
in a fluffy pillow,
you know,
you're gonna,
you're not gonna make a diamond on a
tempurpedic mattress.
Fucking pressure.
Serious.
Serious pressure man.
Like when you see one of the street
hookers walking in a bad neighborhood,
it looks like that's where they all
worked with Tom and Brian Callen met his
ex girlfriend walking the streets.
That was harsh.
That is,
that's when.
That's when you just go,
whoa.
What?
He was outside of the coach and horses
on sunset,
you know,
that place where Stan hope used to love
that.
It's closed now.
But is it?
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure that's too bad.
that was a good little joint.
I remember Ralphie may rest in peace.
We,
we were supposed to meet Ralphie there
and Ralphie showed up an hour later.
I'm like,
what the fuck?
Ralphie look in the backseat and he had
like 13 boxes.
Those Jalapeno poppers from Jack in the
box.
Oh my God.
He just had gone off on holiday.
Pino poppers.
Poor Ralphie when he,
um,
he had his stomach stapled and when he
had a stomach stapled for some reason he
couldn't eat meat.
Like there's something about the
operation they did.
It made him have a real issue with meat.
But he still loved to cook it.
So used to barbecue.
We went over his house once and he,
he,
he's a fucking killer.
Cook.
Ralphie makes some barbecue sauce,
baby,
big baby barbecue sauce.
I went to his house and he cooked like
this whole thing and got to eating meat
at the time.
Oh yeah,
he,
he got his staples removed.
I mean he did himself.
He just ate right through those staples.
Yeah.
He had this idea that he was gonna lose
all this weight and then it,
it did kind of work for like a couple of
days.
Well the problem was he was so big that
like if he said he lost weight,
like,
okay,
how much you know,
he,
he'd say he lost 100 pounds and you'd be
like,
I'm about.
I believe you.
It's hard to tell.
You know,
it's like you couldn't.
But imagine like how strong his legs
must've been the strongest feet in the
business.
Like that guy I could probably kick
through a fucking building.
Think about it.
Like if he,
if he's carrying around 500 pounds,
imagine if I took you and I threw 300
pounds of weights on your back.
You,
you're just walking around with 300
pounds everywhere you go.
I wouldn't be able to do it.
Like I lift weights all the time and I
wouldn't be able to do it.
I'd be like,
what the fuck man be.
You'd walk everywhere.
Buster was giving us cool Ed.
He had those calves,
you know,
those fat dude calves.
They did a develop this model.
But if you could like,
look at the musculature in his legs,
I bet if you get through all the fat and
his arms,
his arms like normal size arms,
but I bet he had some jacked fucking Lee
Haney quads.
Yeah,
I would imagine that that's a tender
meat down there.
Like it's weird when you see people that
have those big calves,
but they're always blue like that.
Diabetes legs.
That's rough.
That diabetes blue.
Yeah.
That's super common though,
right?
Yeah.
There's a homeless homeless guy by,
by my house just hanging out at
starbucks and he hasn't so bad where
it's blistered and every time he walks a
little blood squirts often do ribs down
his leg.
It's the grossest thing ever.
He's homeless.
Uh,
yeah.
He's fat.
Yeah,
he's huge and what's weird about Burbank
is there was another guy that had like
this big nose,
like it was a,
like he looked like a,
it was some kind of weird sis nodes
where it's like the size of like a,
like a pineapple,
and he looked like Bernie Kozar,
whatever.
That old guy.
I'm Bernie coats are aware of what her
back for the Brown.
No,
no.
What's Bernie that sports?
I,
Bernie,
they go to sports accommodator the only
guy.
Howard cosell either had like a hardcore
sound.
No,
like huge though.
You're like the only guy who knows less
about sports and,
but uh,
all the people in Burbank college like,
Hey,
we'll fix your nose.
Like people are so nice.
Like I'll pay for your nose to get fixed
and he wouldn't,
uh,
yeah.
Bigger than that.
Like imagine that knows times 100.
What was the dude that was the cubs guy?
Crazy glass.
Hey Harry.
Harry.
Harry Carey.
Didn't he have like a list now?
He just,
he was like really big glasses and he
just talked to real crazy.
Will Farrell did a great impression
town.
Hi,
I'm.
Hi Carrie,
you would feel like a homeless guy would
be skinny.
I'd be like the ultimate diet.
No food,
a lot of walking.
Well the only food that we're eating
probably is like fast food,
like fast food,
so fucking cheap.
The other day.
Arby's has this new steak.
You should go to Venice,
Venison Burger or something.
I think they have elk only in a couple
places,
but they have venison and a bunch of
places.
Yeah,
Venison.
I had it yesterday.
It's like having a steak on a on too.
But,
but it was only $5 and it was great.
It was a real life.
It's venison.
They do these mass executions of deer in
some,
some places where they,
uh,
they have to eradicate these deer,
like to get a little too crazy.
I would imagine that's probably where
they're getting some of their meat from.
Yeah.
Because it's lonely for a limited time.
Only in limited places.
Well you can only hunt them for so long.
Like if it's in during hunting season,
you're not allowed to sell it
commercially.
Like hunting meat.
Like there's,
you can buy farm raised deer,
they might have that,
but I think like a,
I think it's illegal.
I'm pretty sure it's illegal to sell
wild game.
Like to actually sell it,
sell it.
I don't think you could sell the meat,
but I have some for you.
I have my,
I have elk Jerky for you.
Oh,
I went on.
I have,
I have elk Salami for you.
What was that one thing you made me that
one time.
Oh,
that was a smoked ham.
That was wild boar.
Wild pig shit.
Wild pig is so and wild pig is very
sustainable.
Those little motherfuckers,
they breed like crazy.
You,
you literally have to shoot them.
They have a big problem with them right
now in San Jose.
I was just reading this thing about San
Jose.
San Jose is trying to figure out there
they're hiring people to a set traps in
people's yards because in the middle of
the night these wild pigs come up,
but just fuck people's lawns up and at
San Jose is like tech industry,
you know?
It's like,
I don't even know.
That was a thing up there.
While oh my God.
Well what's interesting is a lot of it
came from that crazy asshole that made
weedy illegal.
William Randolph hearst,
when he built the hearst castle.
Have you ever been to the hearst castle?
It's pretty sweet.
I never put the two together.
I was like,
Oh fuck.
I've been there.
Yeah,
that's is that.
Is the hearst castle,
the one that has like the stairways that
lead to a brick wall,
like you opened up the door and there's
nothing there or is that another is a
crazy lady I think.
I think I'm thinking of a different
person,
but William Randolph hearst,
when he had the hearst castle built,
he released a bunch of wild boars,
Eurasian bores all over the backyard so
we could just hunt them and shoot them
because he was just crazy rich asshole
and those motherfuckers populated the
entire northern California region.
That's crazy.
Hunter s Thompson when he was young and
he lived in big Sur.
He used to go hunt wild boars with a
machine gun.
There's like a famous classic picture of
Hunter s Thompson holding a knife and an
AK 47 while there's a wild boar that's
hanging from his back legs and he's
cutting it open and about to cook.
And have you ever had pig's tail pig's
tail?
That pig's feet?
Pig's feet?
I hate that fixed fee.
It's good.
Is it delicious?
Yeah.
I don't remember much about my,
my real dad,
but I do remember he loved pigs feet and
I ate it when I was a little kid.
Yeah.
You can buy at the store.
Pickle it takes his feet.
He's got to go to the bad neighborhood
though.
No,
they have it.
My,
my girlfriend eats all that.
She gets.
She gets fish eyeballs.
Sheets,
fish.
Oh,
you're dating an Asian.
That's the winchester mystery house.
This is the.
That's the nowhere.
Where's that one at?
It said near San Jose.
Okay.
Yeah.
Same kind of area.
This house is a wacky house.
How'd you go to this house?
I was a little kid.
I thought it was a great.
Well,
I lived in San Francisco when I was
little fruits are age seven to 11.
We lived in San Francisco and we took a
tour of the hearst castle when I was
little.
Remember it,
and we went to this mystery house too,
but there was like doorways to nowhere.
I love these old rich houses.
Like,
like I went to the gamble house in a
procter and gamble.
It's a,
it's in Pasadena,
but that's where they filmed like back
to the future.
What was that one with the fish?
With the seagull.
What the hell is that?
All right.
It's just somebody.
Oh,
someone's blog.
So what we're saying what but like these
houses back then,
the architecture there and proctor and
gamble at the time he was like,
you know,
our billionaire.
So he would have these houses have so
many unique.
That's it,
right?
Is that the hearst castle?
And Campbell had the gamble house.
Yeah.
And so like there's like all these,
like secret rooms and the architecture
there is amazing.
That's a beautiful house.
Doc Brown.
That's duck.
Darren's the future future.
Really?
Yeah.
No Shit.
It's in Pasadena.
It's a cool.
In Pasadena that houses.
Yeah.
That's beautiful.
I love houses like that would structure
like who that lawn to the architecture
there is so amazing and just this
amazing man.
Pasedena.
Whoa.
That's the inside of it.
And you can walk through there.
You got a three 60 tour.
This house is shit.
Like look through shit on the inside.
Is this like they have tours of it?
Yeah.
Me and my mom works as a ghost.
People go look at the coast.
They have different kinds of tours,
tours where you get to go to rooms that
you can only go to if you go to this
certain tour.
Uh,
that's fucking beautiful.
That's the same house.
Yeah.
Pasa.
Dina had this Frank Lloyd Wright House
that was for sale for ever and I think
it finally sold and there was another
one that's like another Frank Lloyd
Wright House,
I believe that was for sale in Los
Filez.
And I was like,
God damn,
I don't want it.
That's the house.
Like I don't want to live in Los Filez
with all the hipsters,
but I might live there just to be in
this house.
Look at this fucking the Mallard House
that places the Shit I love though.
Yeah.
The inside of that house was incredible.
Jamie,
go to the inside when you see,
um,
there was all this crazy patterns here.
See all the crazy patterns in the stone
columns.
I mean,
it was just a gorgeous house.
Like it was literally like you're owning
whoever owns it.
You're owning a piece of historical art.
Like that one right down there.
Look at that.
That's insane.
I mean,
come on,
man.
That's,
that's like a museum or something.
There's a house in Pennsylvania,
Frank Lloyd Wright House.
I think it's in Pennsylvania where it's
the same thing where it's just
waterfalls and amazing things like this.
Like,
you know,
it's probably the dope house I've ever
seen is the,
um,
Ferris Bueller's day off house when he
drove the Ferrari of Seattle,
that houses in Seattle.
That looks like it right there though.
The Pennsylvania one because waterfall,
that looks like.
Oh,
look at that.
Click on that.
That's the one I'm talking about.
Chicago that's in Chicago.
I'd probably have to dodge bullets.
And the way the house was for sale not
too long ago,
really.
I remember calling a fuck load of money.
How much the Ferris bueller house cost.
Look at that house.
God Damn.
That's gorgeous.
Awesome man.
Laura.
No,
that's Laurel highlands.
Pennsylvania therapists do.
There's nothing better than like living
around trees.
Like there's something about like that
image of that house with all those trees
in the background and all that green
light that just makes you want to let
you know what it reminds me of the crazy
billionaire.
And uh,
uh,
ex Mokena.
Remember that guy?
The guy lived in some crazy wooded.
Oh,
I just rewatched it.
Sits there.
It is.
Ferris Bueller's Day off house that
houses the shit.
But people would watch you.
Fuck.
They'd be hide in the bushes.
Binoculars.
I see.
I just got a new movie coming out.
Ferris Bueller?
Matthew Broderick.
Oh yeah.
The x marketing guy has a good movie
coming out.
We watched the trailer off off air,
but I try to remember what it was right
now.
Yeah.
At some sort of a science fiction movie,
right?
Yeah.
That's one of my.
If I had a top 20 all time favorite
movies,
ex Makan is right in there,
so well done me to watch it.
It's perfect.
Still.
Is he doing that?
That book?
The science fiction book.
Annihilation.
Yeah.
What is it about Jeff Vendor Mirror
watch the new trailer for x and Natalie
Portman's in it.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
That they go to and like her husband
died and their journey to find her some.
Some portals will,
we'll find out.
You know,
dude,
I to stop drinking coffee when I'm on a
podcast because it's the flip thing.
Yeah.
Terrible.
Caveman coffee.
Just coffee in general.
If I drink water I'm fine.
If I drink coffee,
I started flipping up and I have to
clear my throat.
You should get a little bubbles will get
out of that Flim Oh,
you know what I like dude.
Z that Stevia soda.
Do we have any of those back then?
The Soda?
Yeah.
I don't know what flavor is and those
things are delicious.
During those months.
Where do you find them though?
I can't find them anywhere.
Amazon.
Amazon?
Yeah.
Amazon.
Some grocery stores,
but like the Soda Aisle,
so big and taken over by the big ones.
There's like one six pack and every
grocery store and get lucky.
I'm so burned out on the cry trying to
do all the Zv a water.
Yeah,
very similar.
It's so.
Stevia is still fine,
right?
Like there's nothing bad with Stevia.
I always hear like,
what was the other one night?
A aspartame.
Yeah.
That's terrible pain.
The other wall.
The clo.
The xylitol.
Um,
yeah.
What was the coconut one?
Fuck.
What was that one anyways?
Most of them like monk fruit.
Supposed to be really good.
Um,
most of that stuff,
like the chemical stuff's dangerous,
but the Stevia,
I think I'm pretty sure we should have
jamie.
Check as soon as Jamie comes back.
I don't want to tell anybody job,
bro.
You'd all.
Steve,
do you want.
Do you remember that crazy guy that was
a snort and Stevia?
Yeah,
that's his name.
Dan Quinn still alive,
man.
That guy was crazy.
He was a guy.
Yeah.
I had some awesome videos of him snort
and Stevia talking about Stevia burns
off calories and it gives you muscles
route here.
Yeah,
we got root beer,
soda.
This is zero calories and it's sweetened
with Stevia and it's like a lacroix with
that tastes better.
Grapefruit citrus.
People going to think this is some
really fucking low level,
sketchy commercial man.
If I wasn't wearing my me undies right
now.
Well if you just go to stamps.com.
Oh my God.
It tastes like root beer.
Yeah.
Legit.
Okay.
Here's the question.
Is there anything wrong with Stevia?
We need to find out.
I feel like there was something recently
that's.
Does Stevia kill you?
My Dad still on the thing where if it's
any kind of artificial sweetener and
your brain thinks it's real,
so it releases chemicals unnecessarily.
That doesn't have any where to go.
So he says it's still bad for you.
Any artificial sweeteners?
Right?
So this isn't an artificial sweetener in
it.
I just know Stevia is with the plant.
That's why that was a little green leaf.
That's what Stevie it looks like,
but isn't it your brain think like,
hey,
this is sugar though.
It tastes like sugar.
I don't know.
Maybe your brain dust.
My sleeping,
my brain smart enough to know my brain
is like,
Yo bro,
this is fake,
bro.
Isn't fake sugar bro.
Don't get crazy.
I had a real coke the other day by
accident.
Oh yeah.
I went to a drive through,
was late at night and I was fucking
starving.
And uh,
I've worked all day and I've worked out
and I was just like,
I just need to get a fucking burger king
or not.
Burger King.
Wendy's went and got a,
a baconator yeah.
And I asked for a diet coke and he
hooked me up with a regular coke.
Please do.
That shit pisses me off.
But it's still good.
It was so good.
I haven't had a regular coke and years.
I treat myself once in a while.
Get a little Mexican coke.
I went to in and out the other day.
I am not on board within an hour.
I'm not gonna get shit on this.
But what's wrong with you?
It it in and out.
Cigarettes killed your fucking teeth,
but you got to Wendy's.
It's so much better.
What if you have a group?
If you have a burger from in and out,
in a burger from Wendy's,
we have Chinese tastes a million times
better.
You are.
You definitely have fucked up.
There's a show called good mythical.
What he's saying.
I don't even know what you're saying.
There's a show.
You really think that Wendy's is better
than in and out a million times better
than it.
That's a million million.
I can't trust you with anything from now
on.
You're,
you're from California though.
So you grew up on,
in and out,
but most of your life is spent here in
California.
I just used it.
Columbus bias on Wendy's though from
where we were from,
doesn't mean it's better.
True from California.
You all getting to know I would love to
take five guys,
uh,
all the burger places that we know of
and have a taste test with blind taste
tests.
And you tell me which one's the best
night out will be nowhere close to the
guys with Bacon and Jalapenos would.
But fuck all the rest of them.
I just said it.
Five guys is good.
I liked it.
I don't like the fries as much as I see.
You got a problem with your face.
Fat Burger's really way up there and
many of them to come to compare their
taste wise.
It's just one like a mile away from
here.
I don't know.
But I mean there's just not tons of them
all around the world and country.
Pretty good.
They're pretty good.
Really good.
They give you frozen meat.
I think it's frozen meat that they cook,
but I don't think that's that big of a
deal.
I'll tell you what,
man,
that whole frozen versus
this is fresh argument.
I think the real thing is like when you
cook it,
you got to cook it like right there and
then you know like right,
like the problem with a lot of these
fast food
places that didn't have that fucking
thing.
Cook way in advance.
They just nuke them and then hand them
to your microphone.
Burger King says flame broiled,
but you know what they do?
They flame broil it.
Then they put it in a pan with all this
beef juice and they just let sit it in
this pan,
like kind of like a caterer,
like when you go to catering where they
just pull it out.
It's discussing,
uh,
the grossest burger you'll ever have in
your life is Carl's Jr.
Grassfed burger at some time.
But you'll throw it out your window made
me sick.
How disGusting it was.
Establishing lawsuits.
I know a lot of people are big fans of
water burger when we talk about in and
out,
like where they have it.
I think like Texas is a big place where
I went to burger,
but they're all Texas doubt.
They've got a fucking big belt buckle
and cow horns on their front.
Cadillac had a burger,
delicious fucking mind by the spicy
ketchup from amazon.
that's the best ever have.
But you buy water,
burger,
spicy,
ketchup.
Amazon,
I'll buy you say it's fucking the best
catch up in the rod of burgers.
Good.
maybe be wrong.
I wouldn't say no if I was hungry,
But it cannot fuck with five guys are in
and out.
Let's do a taste test,
so.
Okay.
What's wrong with steve?
You?
What is it?
Stevie is short for stevia.
Reb bod deanna,
a plant from the chrysanthemum family,
which grows in parts of Brazil and
Paraguay.
The compound that makes the stevia sugar
is extracted from the leaves.
It's used in the uae,
east asia,
Russia,
blah,
blah.
And it's about 200 to 300 times sweeter
than sugar.
Whoa.
When did the fda approve it?
In 19 nineties,
fda rejected stevia as a food ingredient
after research linked it to reproductive
problems and possible genetic mutations
in rats.
Well,
not a rat.
So,
uh,
in 2008,
the fda approved a specific formula of
pure stevia rebar.
The said,
I would say that owes side a pure via.
And truvia both contain the reb,
a version of stevia,
which is fda approved.
The fda recommended daily dose is no
more than one point three milligrams per
kilogram of body weight.
For healthy adults,
you'd have to have at least 29 truvia
packets a day to exceed that.
What do the experts say if you're stevia
isn't made from reb a,
like for example,
the whole leaf extract that's sold at
natural food markets and labeled as a
dietary supplement,
hasn't been vetted for safety by the fda
for truvia and pure via.
The fda concluded with reasonable
certainty that renee is not harmful
under its intended of use
based on studies it looked at concerning
reproductive blood pressure and toxicity
effects.
AltHough scientific studies in 1960 and
19 eighties found that stevia derived
products decreased fertility and female
rats feed at the church full of loads
and potentially lead to mutations.
The fda concluded that those problems
didn't apply to a based on additional
research that's one paid off the problem
with those fucking I don't trust any
studies from back in the day anymore.
After that sugar study got exposed where
you found out from the New York times,
did this whole expo say on how the sugar
industry bribed all these scientists to
say that sugar is not bad for you,
it's a saturated fat,
and they,
although they,
they pushed all the blame on heart
attacks and heart disease,
saturated fat.
So it's hilarious.
So this,
uh,
I can't tell what they're pretty much
saying is like the whole foods,
the pure extracted stevia plants are not
good for you or they're saying it's not
fda have to,
hasn't been vetted.
That's thE stuff that we put in coffee.
That was also a four year old article.
I was like,
oh,
they're jones.com.
Which seemed like a good place,
but it was mother jones is a good place
if you have stinky feet and you're like
wearing birkenstocks and uh,
you have wouldn't beads.
Mother jones is a good magazine,
but they're super left wing hippie.
I don't know if they're right though.
They might be right.
Makes sense.
Yeah.
I was just looking for some fda results
on that.
I mean,
there's no biological free rides.
If you talked to the doctors to say,
look,
there's something probably going on,
you know,
like I used to think that advil was
fine.
I think that advil,
there's no,
no problem with advil until dr rhonda.
Patrick explained to me about strokes
and fucking the heart attacks and all
kinds of crazy shit that you can get
from consuming advil,
advil,
the thing that you're supposed to take
though,
if you're having a heart attack.
No,
not to ask for aspIrin.
Aspirin and supposedly prevents heart
attacks,
but I wonder why like do you think it's.
Is it something in the aspirin?
If I remember correctly,
she probably googled.
I think it comes from the bark of a
tree.
I think actual aspirin is an extraction
like a plant extraction and somehow or
another aspirin,
because it does reduce inflammation is
supposed to be good for people that have
heart problems.
Aspirin blocks an enzyme called cyclo,
oxy jennay's that makes your body less
likely to produce chemicals that can
cause inflammation.
It helps prevent blood clots.
That's important because they clog the
arteries and blink bring blood to the
heart muscles in the brain,
which increases your risk of heart
attack and stroke,
so a aspirin blocks that enzyme and
makes you less likely to have heart
attacks and stroke.
That's pretty bad ass,
but what is aspirin from?
where does aspirin come from?
Is aspirin safe to take a vitamin every
day?
Actually encourage you to take aspirin,
but you know what else can be done
that could probably mimic the effects
like when you talk to people that really
understand like health ailments.
One of the big things they all seem to
bring up is inflammation.
Like inflammation is like one of the
number one sources of malaise.
How do you say that?
Malaise disease,
a massive issues.
Health health issues that people have,
inflammation,
they think is a huge factor in cancer.
Huge factor in heart attacks,
strokes,
everything.
An inflammation is just fucking bad.
Like anytime you're eating inflammatory
foods,
that's the big problem with sugar.
That's the big problem with refined
carbohydrates is that they produce
inflammation in people like a lot of
people that have like joint problems and
shit,
they go on a low carbohydrate diet and
other joint problems go away.
Like if you have pain,
your ankles and shit.
While a lot of people have found that
that just changing your diet makes that
go away because a lot of that
inflammation is just the.
Your body just not responding very well
to your diet.
Yeah.
But that's different people.
So what does it say?
Anything about it being from a tree.
Oh,
I made it up.
It seems like it's.
I,
I agree with you.
I've heard that before.
there's something that sounds familiar,
but I don't know if it was aspirin or
not.
Well,
what does it say it's comes from?
I think it's just a chemical compound.
I think acid tilak acid,
but I think it's.
What is aspirin extracted from the
plant?
Googled album because I think aspirin
was around way before they figured out
how to make like pharmaceutical drugs.
I think that shit's been around forever.
There was a dude that was a friend of
mine who was a really funny comedian who
would a willow bark,
willow,
barnes z,
how to make aspects from a willow tree
bitch contained the willow bark of a
white willow tree contains the salus in,
which is the chemical known as the sat,
a satanic whatever.
It sounds like.
Witchcraft doesn't sound like
witchcraft.
Park of a tree in the middle of the
night,
unless you'll bring it to me and I will
cut and dry it up.
I'll put it in a written.
It's a willow tree.
Willow tree.
The same as a weeping willow.
Huh?
Weeping willow.
Willow's the one that's like sex has
like Those fuzzy things on it.
Maybe felt like I had a willow tree and
go,
ooh,
yeah,
that's a pretty tree.
It's a nice treat.
Whoa.
What's that one?
It's frosted and how to make aspirin
from a willow tree.
Let's find out how to do it.
What do you got to do?
Let's make our own aspirin.
It's make toothpicks out of a willow
tree that prevent heart attacks to now
you're talking.
I wonder if that's real and if you could
do that.
Probably.
Huh?
Why not,
right.
Always sucking on a toothpick instead of
smoking a cigarette.
Yes.
So that's what you want to do,
right?
You want to quit smoking?
Quit smoking is my number one thing.
Lose weight as my number two.
What's number three?
Grow your dick.
Uh,
get rid of the damn rat at my house.
I feel like I'm diseased right now.
We played the video a couple of weeks
ago.
Of what?
Of your.
Your rat?
We showed dreaming of your ra.
Did we play with the screaming one that
found the link late to like later.
And we lived on.
Brian caught a rat in a trap and set up
cameras.
I can't tell you what happened.
The second part,
what happened?
So there's two rats were killed.
One the second one with the video with
the screaming one escaped for a week.
We didn't see it.
All my cameras.
I have like all these night vision
cameras.
I'm like,
well it must have ran away.
Uh,
so I took all my traps,
putting them underneath the sink.
What am I traps was a electrocute
electric one when they walk in and they
get electrocuted.
So I put that in underneath this thing.
Anyways,
cut to three months later.
It smelled like death in my kitchen.
You've smelled death before and you're
like,
oh,
what the fuck is that?
Sure enough,
I opened it up and I see this flashing
red light is the rat had gone into the
electricity thing.
Electrocuted himself,
had been there for three months,
went in there after after a must have.
He must have been injured in my,
underneath my sink.
He might have been injured.
It's the same rat.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because I had so many cameras that I,
I could tell there was one bigger,
the pregnant one that we killed first.
Then there was the father or the husband
and like it was like two different
sizes.
One was like,
you know,
the crazy big one was smaller,
but uh,
so I look and I see this rat tail coming
out and it smelled like death right when
I opened up the thing.
Of course,
luckily I'm dating an asian who eats
fish eyeballs.
So I was like,
no,
get that outta here.
So he made her do it.
No,
she doesn't care.
She does.
She,
she has no emotion about death fishing.
And so she takes it out and she puts it
in the trashcan.
Like I just told her to throw the whole
thing away and we're not going to reuse
that electricity thing and it fell out
into the trashcan and bust open and all
these maggots just come out like,
oh,
hundreds of maggots.
Like a burst open.
Like the skin just couldn't take it
anymore.
She'd take pictures.
No,
I did.
I think she did.
I was freaking out.
She definitely take pictures of it now.
The rats back.
New grad.
I guarantee you you probably had a ton
of rats living in your house.
Well,
what it is,
we figured we got the exterminator out
and we have one of those crawl spaces
underneath my house and the whole house
has been,
you know,
gritted up so there's no rats can get
inside.
So how they're getting in was confusing.
Everyone found out her stupid ass
neighbor.
He's like,
oh yeah,
rat chewed through my screen in the back
of my house the other a couple months
ago and he has a cat,
so they've been coming in his house,
going in his kitchen,
going underneath the house,
going out into my house.
So he just,
because he didn't tell us that he has a
big hole in his back fucking screen.
Yeah,
but it's back screen.
The rats are coming out of his house.
It's coming in his house through this,
this whole.
And then they go in his kitchen
and underneath they can go underneath
the house by goIng under the pipes under
his kitchen.
I guarantee you there's rats everywhere.
Like you can't blame this guy.
You live in an area.
There's Backyards knows horses
everywhere.
They're everywhere.
You know what?
There's a fuck load of rats.
That goddamn comedy store.
Yeah.
I saw three last night.
Every time I go to that back smoking
area,
I look for rats and you'll see them
scurrying across the top and I took
videos of them.
We were all hanging out in the back and
the parking lot area where it says
mitsis comedy.
Mitzi spot only.
It's fucking rats all over the place
over there.
I hate rats,
man.
Do you have red?
You don't have rats at your house.
You have like other crazy shit,
right?
We have routes to grants is definitely
raTs.
Yeah.
We so trenches.
I caught a big trench.
Look on my instagram.
I've never seen a tranche.
The lead just walking around.
That's real big fucker in my house.
I put my sneaker next to it so people
can see how big it is.
Big.
I just,
I just put trenches are pretty.
Pretty mellow man.
Like you scoop them up.
I put it in a box.
I got to scoop them up in a shoe box.
Put them outside.
They don't bite or anything or look at
him.
Oh my god though,
if I saw that coming out of my shoe,
are you freaked out?
He didn't come out of my shoe.
I put this shoe down next to him.
I know,
but are you scared that anytime you put
your shoe on there might be a tarantula
in it?
Trenches.
Don'T scare me.
Black widows were much smaller than that
and I see them all the time and they
will fuck you up.
Black widows are what's really scary.
Yeah.
I have a lot at my house.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's a fucking big bug,
right?
Would you ever eat that?
Yeah,
they taste good.
Apparently the tastes like crabs.
Well,
they're in the crab family.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's what I've watched.
uh,
I watched the television show where
these people were living in the amazon,
I believe,
and they were cooking.
See if you could find it.
Amazon natives cooking giant spiders.
I mean,
and they had them.
You ever see how they do need to look it
up?
I hosted a fear factor.
I could watch anything.
I could literally watch people eat
dicks.
I know when they,
they.
You ever seen those things that they
make,
it's almost like a,
a screen and they put a fish down and
then they put the screen on top of it
and they bury it and they're.
No,
no,
like you cook it over a fire,
you know,
like not a screen.
It's like a bunch of sticks and the fish
is in between the sticks,
you know,
it just,
it basically just holds the fish in
place while they cook it over the fire.
They did the same thing with these,
these giant fucking trenchless.
They cut them open,
slip a,
split them up and lay them down on this,
uh,
this fire and just put the torrential is
out there to cook.
Just like they would cook,
like a crab or a piece of fish or
something like that.
It looked good.
I bet they taste good.
Fuck nasty.
They're really bugs,
you know,
like they call,
they called lobsters,
bugs.
I think that's the thing.
Like those,
those divers,
they call them bugs.
oh.
Oh,
they're gonna kill it.
No.
Yeah.
See here,
they get these fuckers.
Is it popping or mouth?
Oh,
they get really itchy because the hairs
off of those bugs,
they um,
they're not bugs really.
They're arachnids.
But the hairs off the spiders.
So they take it like little kids,
man.
Oh,
they cook over the fire.
But the thing is,
man,
I think they taste good.
Somebody told me that aiden before.
You know what,
it might've been less.
I think less drought told me that adam,
that he ate them or girlfriend would eat
that right away.
No problem or problem with chopsticks.
Yep.
She put some of that,
a duck sauce on it.
Look at these kids' minds ready,
but it looks like crabs tastes a bit
like crap.
They're all excited.
Human planet.
Bbc.
That's cool.
But why are we afraid of is,
but we're not afraid of crab.
Like you know what?
No one has a problem Cooking like you
ever see like an alaskan king crab
alive.
Their fucking legs are like this long.
Come in your house.
That's a good point.
You don't have to put a sneaker next.
I think it's a hair thing.
That's another good point.
But roaches don't have hair and roaches
freak you out.
Ah yeah,
but that's a shell thing,
huh?
Like if roaches were yellow.
No,
that's what have you.
Well listen,
I hate him.
Roach roach on fear factor.
They taste like nothing.
It was like nothing they scored in your
mouth.
That's kind of gross.
Like a gag,
a little bit like scored it when I bit
into it because it's so juicy,
but the actual taste itself was very
bland.
What about those you guys pill bugs or
those garden bugs that you guys used to
have on fear factor?
Those big green caterpillars that were
just pop in your mouth.
Oh,
I ate one of those tomato horn worm.
I ain't one of those.
That wasn't so good.
What?
What that tastes like that it seems that
strong still,
but very mushy.
Like if I was really hungry,
I eat the shit out of a plate of those.
Oh,
those roaches.
Roaches.
Because I was in Mexico last year and we
were in cancun.
No cabo tomato.
Warm when I was fearful.
Yeah.
chewing up.
Oh god.
Damn storm man.
This is when fear factor was costing is
man,
if I met this dude right now,
today,
if I saw that dude today,
I'd be like,
nice to meet you.
Like I never.
I don't remember meeting.
That's so great.
memories such dong shit.
Wow.
My memory's pretty good for like normal
stuff,
but I think I've seen too much.
All those people.
I don't know who these people are.
This is where obviously met them.
That dude is going to town though.
Look at him.
This is when fear factor was amazing.
Ludicrous.
Man.
Call me.
I'll give you some tips here.
When did we talk about is like one of
those stones is like,
oh no,
you're gonna get your cell phone wet
time.
Like,
no,
they're on a budget.
Yeah.
Luda might've ate up that budget on that
fast and the furious gig money.
Now he's stuck in that world with tyrese
and how those guys,
when their franchise and we talk about
tyrese and rock.
Oh my god.
Did we talk about it yesterday?
We mentioned it off on it.
We didn't,
we didn't talk about it.
I have no idea.
I was,
uh,
on youtube looking at something else.
I was looking at,
uh,
some automobile thing and uh,
I saw the rock and then I saw the rock
dysentery,
reese and I was like,
this is real.
And I went to.
No,
it's real.
They apparently,
tyrese talked a bunch of shit about the
rock and the rock did a review of
[inaudible] album,
but they're Also in a movie right now.
They gather.
Doesn't matter.
He doesn't like them.
Yeah.
The things coming up because the rock
made a deal to make a a spinoff sequel
to the fast and furious franchise that's
not bringing.
Involving anyone that's in the fridge
and they're mad.
Tyrese is like,
you're splitting up the family,
which means nobody wants to go see a
goddamn tyree smoothly.
That's the real problem.
Yeah.
I'm on team rock.
Whatever he wants.
I love the rock.
He's a sweetheart of a guy.
If you meet him in person too.
Oh,
you got to meet him.
Yeah,
he's great at tate did a movie with him.
Jumanji.
He's a fucking great guy.
Like legitimately great guy and he
inspires the shit out of me.
You know,
a lot of people think that that meat
heads stuff like in the gym,
like push harder,
get it done.
You know,
all work.
All play all day.
You know,
like all that.
I,
I find him inspirational.
I don't care if it's,
I don't care if it's simple stuff.
I think he's great.
I love him.
It was pretty good.
Yeah,
we got kimmy some volume.
Am I just wrapped a phenomenal workout
here in the iron paradise.
Got after it.
Hardcore hardest workers in the room.
It's how we do it.
The number one question that I'm asked
everywhere I go around the world is
always,
how is it that I stay so motivated?
What are the motivating factors in my
life that keeps me in this psychological
space?
Um,
number one will be gratitude.
I try and find a way to be grateful for
every single thing I have.
Every single day.
Wins,
losses,
loved ones,
you name it.
My life wasn't always this way.
It was much different many moons ago.
So these days I'm grateful to the bone
for everything.
The other thing is hunger.
Uh,
you always hear people say,
well,
it's about being number one about being
at the top,
or how about this?
Um,
you always got to find somebody out
there is going to work harder.
Well,
I don't know that that might be
bullshit,
but I know no one is going to be
hungrier than I am and I try and find a
way to be grateful,
so I hope that helps.
It's 2:00
in the morning.
If you're watching this,
you better be doing something productive
and not freaky shit.
While you could go do some freaky shit.
Saturday night.
Need a little editing,
but I liked the point inspirational,
but he's.
But that.
All that saying about gratitude,
that's real.
That's legit.
And who fucking works harder than that
guy?
He's always on a new tv show.
He's got 10 movies.
Juggling at the same time.
Probably sleeps two hours a night.
Look at them.
I could do without all these pictures of
people hopping in private jets though.
I get it here.
Rich.
That the private jet thing to me is,
is just,
that's a weird form of selfie.
You know,
like the private gym photos I get,
but the private jet photos.
Who's the guy that that fake?
The private jet.
Oh,
bow.
Bow.
Wow.
That's amazing.
Now isn't it like people pretending to
little bow things.
WhaT's funny is nowadays flooded,
it's someone on the plane busted him and
now,
and it's crazy because you could get a
private jet pretty easily.
Now there's an app,
whatever that app is where you can rent.
Like if you're going to san francisco,
you can,
if you're with four people,
you can get like $200 plane tickets on a
private jet really that you can print
out private jets through an app.
Now I think it's still pretty fucking
expensive.
It's not like,
I think it's called jet smarter jet.
Set it the one here.
You can only just go to like san
francisco,
vegas and maybe like oakland,
but it's cheap.
Cheap.
It's super 200 bucks,
250 bucks,
250 bucks to go to vegas on a private
jet.
And you could,
if you could rent out the whole jet,
just your friends.
You got to reserve it in time and make
sure there's only after um,
after the vegas massacre tickets for
like 70 bucks you have to vegas.
Like how does that work?
Does the airline just decide?
No one's going to vegas.
We need to make it cheap and easy.
Right.
Where do they go in cahoots with the
casinos?
Like I just happened fast.
I don't know.
I wonder if they're in cahoots with the
casinos Because here's one thing that I
noticed.
you can't get a late night flight out of
vegas.
Like,
oh,
can we.
You want to go home?
Well,
I think that's because of noise order or
like same with burbank.
you can't fly out or las vegas.
Noisy fan.
Come on man.
what time did they stop running?
10.
Probably you can leave la at one in the
morning,
right?
You leave la anytime in the night so we
would you feel weird staying at mandalay
Bay because I mean we used to stay at
mandalay bay all the time.
All the time.
I think I stayed in that room.
I'm almost positive.
I stayed in that room probably half
because that was a corner suite.
It was always dope suite.
I think the fertittas put me up in that
room way back in the day.
I'm almost positive.
I looked at that room.
I'm like,
god,
that seems like super familiar.
Yeah.
I would stay there.
I mean fuck,
it's one guy,
one crazy guy,
now he's dead,
But if you go online and read all the
fucking rumors and all the theories,
jamie's one of them.
I was looking at facts.
I'm not going into the conspiracy stuff.
There's the chairman.
He's kind of a truther.
He's a vegas truth or there's reporters
looking into it.
I don't need to do that job for them.
They're looking into what do you think?
There's a second gunman.
No,
third,
fourth,
fourth.
The team.
I'll just say this.
Much of it.
It was happening.
I was
listening to the police scanner audio
and I was just following along the
story.
The story changed and I had questions on
why it changed.
Seems super normal.
Sitting around listening to police get
her audio.
Oh,
you mean multiple shooters from multiple
hotels.
I'm not,
I just,
that's because he was shooting towards
multiple hotels and then shooting
straight towards that,
but no,
there was some reports of people
shooting people in a New York,
New York and.
But here's the thing that you have to
take into consideration.
Whenever there's a mass shooting like
that,
there's chaos and one of this chaos.
You're going to get all sorts of bad
information.
people just like they see things that's
not there.
No one knows where the shooters were
coming from.
People thought there were shooters in
the crowd.
I hAve friends that were actually there
at the thing that dodge bullets.
One of the girls who works for the usc,
she was one of the ring card girl.
She was actually there and she said she
was running away.
People were dropping right next to her
like she's trying to run and people got
shot,
like literally like a movie balloon.
People dropping and falling down right
next to her.
One of her friends blew out her acl
because the guy got fucking shot in the
head and fell and landed on her sideways
and blew her knee out.
Dan blitz blitz ariens or said they hit
that woman next to him.
Has her head blew up.
Yeah.
He was running away making a video.
I just saw some girl got shot in the
fucking head.
He was right there at the concert.
Fuck man.
I mean that guy plan that shit for a
long time.
I mean,
I don't like to read too much into it,
but that whole family's fucking crazy.
The father was a serial bank robber who
used to do all sorts of charity work so
that people think you're a nice guy and
then he'd do this charity work and you
know,
hey,
it's just me.
Just nice mr fred and then mr fred would
go rob fucking shitload of banks.
Yeah.
He had mental health issues.
Two years they fucked up.
The father was a nun who was a real
sociopath.
Uh,
and then the brother,
the brother did like this rambling 30
plus minute interview where they were
talking to him,
uh,
after the murders and all he just kept
talking about is what a great guy.
His brother was and his brother was so
smart and my,
you know,
he was the type of guy,
but if you wanted to just fly to Japan
and have sushi.
Yeah.
Or kill 50 fucking people.
Like it's nothing like what are you
talking about?
Your brother is a fucking serial killer.
Your brother's a mass murderer or you
know,
you shouldn't be talking about what an
eccentric character,
you know,
he wasn't like us,
he would win,
win,
win when the casinos and they comped him
everywhere and it's real weird.
his brother talking is like a guy who's
crazy,
who's trying to not seem crazy.
That's what it's like.
It's like a guy who's trying to pretend
like,
hey,
I think just like you guys do.
I mean,
I'm perplexed that fucking apple does
not fall far from the tree.
When you got a dad that's a psycho like
that,
and he's raising kids like it's a.
There's a high proBability that all
those kids are fucking psychos to.
This guy didn't do anything until he did
this.
That's another thing that's fucked up.
It's not like this guy
had this history of violence.
He had planned this out and apparently
gone to several music festivals and
taking hotel rooms overlooking the
arena.
Probably plot it out in his head when
they found a note,
people would.
The notes say with the note was
ballistic calculations.
He was doinG ballistic calculations like
drop a bullets,
like you know you're shooting someone
and you're,
you know,
you're at a certain distance,
like some hunters have like a sheet of
paper that they put on their rifle sight
and the rifle site it'll say like at
this in a hold here,
you know,
at 500 yards,
turn,
turn to seven or six or whatever,
whatever they've calibrated as this guy
had those calculations written down on a
piece of paper while he was gunning
people down out the window,
straight up psycho.
Just hard to believe that that's a real
person and if you believe a people that
are quote unquote experts in these sort
of Mass killings and these psychological
outbursts,
they think that they come in clusters
that like this happens and then someone
decided that I want to be the next guy
and then they do it somewhere else.
So think about that
or not.
The day of case stuff didn't come out
yet,
right.
That's supposed to dump.
Or clInton trump.
Trump is,
I guess supporting it.
He's gonna release it all.
Of course they try to kill him.
Pardon?
The only thing they trying to kill
trump.
Do you think it's going to show
anything?
I don't know.
I think someone's trying to kill trump
though.
Do you think if you had to guess.
I just didn't anyone ever.
Every president is probably always
getting threatened,
but not just like,
do you think there's ever been a like a
meeting where they got behind closed
doors,
like some shadow government type shit
and they said,
do we do this or what do,
how do you want to do this?
I'm gonna do this.
What are we doing?
We're gonna do this.
This guy's talking about the c,
the he,
he.
There was like a recent thing where he
was blaming the fbI for something about
Russia saying the fbi was involved in
suppressing inflammation and everybody's
like,
do you understand that the president of
the United States is questioning the
integrity of the intelligence community?
Like how crazy that is.
He doesn't trust them or whatever.
Doesn't trust the three letter,
but he loves to do that though.
He loves to make everyone else seem
untrustworthy.
I mean that is his thing.
His thing is about fake news,
the failing New York times,
fake news,
cnn,
they did fake news that like word exist
two years ago and it's now like it's
the,
the.
You can't go a day without fucking
hearing.
I do not remember the term fake news
now.
I remember right before clinton or trump
became president.
I remember talking to my mom about how
horrible everything was and I remember
going,
the biggest problem I habits with this
fake news,
and that was before fake news was talked
about on tv,
but I was talking about fake news on
facebook.
I was saying like,
my sister keeps on posting this
bullshit's fake stuff that posting and I
was getting mad at my sister.
It's like fake news.
I remember my mom lives at is a lot of
fake news and then literally like up two
months later everyone's talking about
the fake news was kind of obvious
though.
That was like when they said that I
killed a mountain lion outside the ice
house.
That was like fake news.
There was another one.
There's someone said that I disarm
somebody at the comedy store,
a buddy of mine is a cop,
actually sent me a text saying,
hey,
way to go.
That's a tough situation to be in.
I was like,
what?
He's like,
you disarm somebody at the commerce to
argue disarming nobody,
but what the fuck you talking about?
I guess thinking that through what
happened next I would guess or I would
say is that people started manipulating
those websites to not be parody or
satire even,
but they would make it look like a local
news channel in some part of
Pennsylvania,
West Virginia and then make a really
salacious clickbait story but have a
bunch of google ads on there and I've
seen those.
Those got weaponized are apparentLy a
little bit and I weapon.
That's the word I would use because they
were being turned into bots.
Those kinds of nets.
What spread the quote unquote like fake
news of today
that's being spread all over.
Well,
I was reading a story thing was on dig
about a russian troll farm like that.
They have these businesses like these
trOll farms are like their businesses.
It's like this,
like do you work at t mobile?
No,
I work at the troll farm.
What a fun job.
That is so great.
Well you are one of the original trials
dude.
Pepsi spice.
Oh yeah.
We've brought it up many times.
Russian troll farm.
That weaponized facebook had american
boots on the ground.
Okay.
That article makes me annoyed.
Maya,
you're annoying me.
Weaponized is annoying me.
Like how's it?
What's.
Why is that term?
That's such a loaded term.
Weaponized.
Still go to it.
Let's understand what she said.
twitter,
ceo cher'S tweets.
Hold on a second.
Is that jack?
So I'm trying to get jack in here.
I'll be honest about conversations.
Twitter,
ceo shared tweets from russian troll
farm according a account claiming to be
a black woman.
Oh,
that's so good.
Rihanna collect.
So humanitarian award year from award
from harvard.
She kicked off women's history month
with a bang.
Reads one of the tweets.
Dorsey shared from crystal one johnson
in march,
2016.
That's hilarious.
So this woman is tweeting all this shit
pretending she's a black woman,
but really it's.
It's an account made by the russian
internet research agency with links to
the kremlin.
That is wonderful.
I know crystal.
One johnson.
Do you think they killed her account?
Go to account.
See if it's legit.
I hope it's still there.
Just to highlight it.
CrYstal.
one johnson,
please,
please be real.
Please be real.
Tell me if you think it's real.
Brian.
Yes.
Yes,
yes.
Let's see.
Go.
Oh,
she's still up now.
It's gone.
It's suspended.
Dammit.
God dammit.
Jack.
That was what she used to look like.
I know that was somebody else's account.
Hood to someone who saved it.
Oh,
that's her tweets.
That's the account here.
This is amazing.
Like you look,
she has a.
Is a picture of a beautiful black girl
laughing.
You probably didn't learn this in school
and then she has a pic.
Says amelia bassano is the lady who
wrote all of shakespeare's plays because
she was black.
They would not publish her work.
She died in poverty because she never
received a dime for work.
Shakespeare was illiterate and could
barely write his own name.
Why?
Because it's funny.
Positive black.
Well,
so people will share that look,
go,
go back up to that tweet.
That doesn't show you how many people
retweeted it.
Does it?
If it got deleted So I can.
Oh,
this is wonderful.
It's wonderful.
I mean that's like,
so obviously not true.
Like she's pretending that some black
woman wrote all of shit.
I mean,
isn't that like.
Wouldn't that be like the ultimate thing
like the white man,
the white male privilege of Shakespeare
allowed him to steal?
What is that?
And fake was actually an african
american is no way is that real.
This is the real.
And frank believed that.
Then anna queesha,
Frank Jackson,
I think it's a joke.
She was a jew fRom africa.
The real land of the chosen people.
All my god,
that is amazing.
but that's going to trick someone who
doesn't use the internet a lot.
You know,
white washed,
fake.
No.
She's like,
she's pretending to Be a crazy radical
feminists.
Someone else respondeD.
This was a response to that tweet by
some random.
Yeah.
Oh,
delirium.
Swag.
Oh,
well that guy's probably rushing to how
many people that you contact on a daily
basis or actually just russian trolls.
Half the internet.
I feel like I'm right.
Could be.
Yeah,
but they're.
What they're doing is very clever
though.
Like it seems legit.
It seems legit,
right?
Like that seems like a crazy person.
like I've,
I've seen many,
many crazy radical black activists on
twitter that say things that are,
aren't nearly as ridiculous as that or
are the more ridiculous than that's less
ridiculous than what they say.
I mean,
this is one.
If it's part of the problem,
I don't even know what's the right way
to word the phrase it,
but like this is going on all over the
internet and different forms and
variations and it's being used and not
so like nefarious ways,
but it's being used for potentially
good.
I don't know what the good would be,
but someone is probably figured out how
to use these bots.
Do you remember before retweeting was an
option on twitter?
People would write our t and then they
would write what you said.
Yeah.
I used to enCourage people to write our
tea and just make up a bunch of shit
that I said and then I would go,
this is outrageous.
I never said this.
How dare you?
And people would just say the most
ridiculous shit.
Like I love the taste of cox and they
would.
And and you know,
our ti,
joe rogan just finally coming out.
I was like,
god damn it,
but I just,
I don't remember when I did this,
but it was like the early days of
twitter because I was like,
this is.
Got it.
You could definitely do that.
And then people would believe that you
said a bunch of racist shit or a bunch
of gay shit.
We just opened that back up now.
Didn't you go crazy?
I like it.
This part of the,
what I like about the internet is like,
did you read or did you listen rather to
the radiolab podcast on shilo lebouf now
I didn't.
It's fucking great.
I sent it to jamie.
What is it called again?
Twitter.
Truth trolls,
you have to find it because they took it
down.
How do you take it down?
I just got enough.
You had it already downloaded on your
phone because you've are auto download
radiolab podcast,
so when I went to go find it,
I had to go search for it.
There was.
I sent you that link.
They had taken it down the next day or
something because people thought that
they were endorsing,
endorsing that.
Trolling.
They should be endorsing it.
It was awesome.
Yeah.
What the four chan guys did was fucking
amazing.
This is what they did.
Shilo lebouf,
so I say his name,
but move whatever that fucking crazy
assholes name.
He was doing some weird art piece where
we stood around with a bunch of other
people and so it was like he will not
divide us.
He will not divide us.
They would all say that and then all
these four chan people found out aBout
it,
so they showed up and started yelling at
a bunch of fucking trump shit still
alive right now.
The camera's still do this.
When all after that whole thing ended,
they ended up selling this to another
company or our people in.
They're handling all of it now,
so his name's not attached to any.
Okay,
so this.
He will not divide us thing.
Right?
He would go to these places and say he
will not divide us.
He will not divide us.
And people would show up and they would
show up with like keka stand shirts on
with pepe the frog.
They would wear make America great
again.
Hats on.
And they weren't even necessarily trump
supporters.
They were just people trying to have
fun.
Right?
They're trying to fuck with people.
Right.
So what they did was shiela above put up
a flag in the middle of nowhere that
said he will not divide us.
And then had a live stream where you
could go and look at the flag as it's
waving in the breeze.
Right?
They found the fucking flag.
They found out where it was.
No way they found it was genius and it's
all detailed in this radio lab.
The fact they took it down is actually
making me mad.
Why would they?
Because what these guys did was awesome.
All right.
First of all,
it was brilliant.
They found social media Posts that
showed that people had met sheil above
in some,
as I say his name,
the above,
the above.
They found out that they had met him in
some weird place in Tennessee.
So they triangulate where he would be.
Right.
So then what they did was they went
around,
they had one of their members go around
with a car and beep the horn so they
could hear the horn on the camera and
once they heard the horn on camera,
then they knew
he was there or then they knew that the
fire was there.
So Then they found out where it is by
stars.
They looked at the fucking stars and
they figured out where the area is
because when it's nighttime,
you can see the stars on the live feed
and you figured out what constellation
it was.
They went to the fucking flag,
took it down,
put a make America great again hat on,
and a pepe the frog thing up there,
and the guy walks up to the camera and
goes,
fuck shiela.
Above,
and that's the end of it.
So great.
The fact of radio lab took that down.
That's depressing.
Why did they do that?
Then?
Understanding what's happening here.
Here's a.
Here's how they did it.
So like when he was moving around,
they found the log cabin he was in and
they're like,
let's look for rental cabins that
matched the wood pattern.
There are around 3000 rental caverns in
lappin lapland.
We just need to match the wood patterns.
Easy enough.
Then you just spend time doing it,
but shit,
your animals.
I fucking love this.
I don't understand why they were mad.
Here's the others did it too,
but.
But this one,
I understand.
I don't understand why radio lab would
take that down.
Why don't you google that?
Why did radio lab take down the twitter
truth or trolls?
Troll trolls,
trolls.
Whatever the fuck.
It was so rare you listen to radio.
I haven't ever listened to radio lab.
What is it?
It's an amazing podcast.
It's like a news or it's one of my
favorite podcasts.
They have all kinds of crazy shit on the
mean.
They have stuff on all sorts of
different inch.
Oh,
radio lab removes its truth trolls
episode from podcast feed.
This was.
I was trying to find the actual because
it say why they posted the reason why
this isn't second what,
but it's saying that they removed it,
right?
That was someone reading the article.
Obviously they removed it.
Editorial radiolab is decided to take
down this episode.
Some listeners called us out saying that
in telling the capture the flag story
and the way that we did,
we essentially condone some pretty
despicable ideology and behavior.
Oh,
come on.
To all the listeners who felt that way
and everyone else,
please know that we hear you and that we
take these criticisms to heart.
I feel awful that the things we said
could be interpreted that way.
That's on us.
It was certainly not our intention and
we apologize.
Come on folks.
You guys are missing the humor of this.
These,
these aren't despicable people.
They are saying things that are
ridiculous because it's funny,
like there's a lot of people that say a
lot of fucked up shit online.
Do they actually mean this stuff or are
they saying it because they are
anonymous and because it's fun to say
fucked up things online that you're not
supposed to say?
I would say the latter.
I don't.
I think there's a bunch of people that
are really legitimately fucked up
online.
There's a bunch of other people that
think it's fun because they're stuck at
some goddamn soul sucking job and some
fucking cubicle somewhere and they have
access to the internet and so they go on
message boards and they fuck around and
they troll this asshole shiela above is
a dumb dumb,
right?
He's.
He's a fucking plagiarist.
I mean this guy has been busted for
plagiarizing like giant chunks of other
people's work.
Right?
Like what did he get busted for?
Plagiarizing.
He's,
he's,
he's in jail every couple of weeks for
being an asshole and being drunk and
silly fool.
I think that that gig,
being a fucking movie star is insane.
I think it's insanely pressure filled.
It's way harder than what we do in terms
of like dealing with all the people that
like you and managing all the
relationships and brief history of
shiela above copying the work of others.
Yeah.
It's like a ton of shit.
What does it say?
He plagiarized and apology to alec
baldwin in 2013,
roughly quit.
What would have been his first broadway
show orphans due to creative
differences.
That is he couldn't get along with alec
baldwin.
According to reports,
the decided the best way to explain his
departure would be to tweet out a photo
of his email apology to the cast and
baldwin by name.
Unfortunately,
parts of the pros sample a man owns up
dot,
ellipsis.
A man grasps his mistakes was ripped off
verbatim from a 2009 esquire article
titled.
What is a man?
People including the articles author
noticed.
Hm?
Barf.
Yeah.
That's not that bad,
but it is plagiarized a bunch of shit.
He plagiarize his directorial debut,
his short film,
howard can tour.com
premiered in 2012 cannes film festival
until it was posted online.
December 16th,
2013.
That viewers began to notice that the
film is almost an exact adaptation of a
graphic novel.
That's what the one by daniel close,
best known for ghost world,
close told,
budge buzzfeed,
which bought much of this story to
public light,
brought much,
much of the story to public light.
The first ever heard of the film was the
morning when someone sent me a link.
I've never spoken or met mr leboeuf have
never seen even one of his films that I
can recall and I was shocked to say the
least when I saw that he took the script
and even many of the visUAls from a vEry
personal story I did six or seven years
ago and pass it off as his own work.
Yeah.
Wow.
I actually can't imagine what was going
through his mind.
He then apologize for plagiarism by
plagiarizing a yahoo answers post from
four years ago.
God,
hE says,
copying is in particulArly creative
work,
being inspired by someone else's idea to
produce something new and different is
creative work.
Uh huh.
Well,
that's not totally copying what he said
fRom the,
uh,
whose answers,
but it's pretty god damn clothes,
whatever.
He's obviously got mental issues and
whether they're real or whether he's
trolling or whether he,
whether he's having a psychological
meltdown because of all the pressure of
being an
actor,
there's a shitload of pressure and being
in transformers,
it's so gross.
Some of them are great.
Don't get me wrong.
I've met a lot of cool actors a lot,
but I would say 10 percent of them are
useless.
That's a,
that's a big number.
That's a big number.
I would say three percent of comedians
are useless.
My being generous with the open
microsoft.
Microsoft professionals.
Yeah.
Three percent,
three percent,
maybe five,
30 percent of just loopy,
but at the comedy store is even less
like paid regulars at the comedy store.
I would sAy it's less than one percent.
That's totally different because when
you're including all comedians near,
you're talking about like the cruise
ship comedians,
the comedy store,
comedian or I mean a comedy class.
Comedians,
blabbers,
flappers,
the whole establishment.
Yeah.
The whole,
the whole broad spectrum of humans to
tell jokes on stage.
I ran into a buddy of mine.
He used to work on fear factor and uh,
he's now doing standup in burlington,
Vermont.
he didn't start until he was in his
forties.
Wow.
Yeah,
I just said had a fucking dream.
I've got a dream.
And he just decided to start doing
standup comedy in his forties.
Dean delray started at really young.
Really?
I think it is 38 or something like that.
I want to say dean was in his forties as
well because deans in his fifties now,
I don't think he's been doing comedy for
10 years.
No,
he hasn't.
started open mikes with him or like
seven years ago.
Man.
He's pretty fucking funny now,
man.
I'll tell you what.
Dean had a set the other night at the
improv.
He made me laugh hard.
He had some funny jokes.
I don't Want to say what the joke the
bit about,
but it was about people don't wear
condoms.
It Was fucking really well written.
he goes on stage more than anyone I
know.
He actually writes down each time he
goes onstage,
if he doesn't go up two or three times
at night,
he Freaks out like he has.
He Doesn't dAte.
He doesn't have any relationships.
He just does stand up 100 percent.
oh,
what's that about his date?
I don't know man.
That seems like not a good time.
That's he's.
He,
he.
Every time I asked him about it,
he's always just because I don't want it
to interrupt my comedy.
He's so focused on comedy.
Was data comedian.
Oh,
it's probably a bad idea.
It doesn't always go back and look at
tom and christine and natasha.
Zero is good one.
She,
she just fucking swings.
Monkey bars from one comedian to relax.
I think she's pregnant now.
No way.
Yeah,
she was awesome.
It was a joke.
She was on the side.
Phalen and choke.
I don't think so.
I think she actually is moshe kasher
fruit fertile.
Yeah.
He's got.
He's got that.
He's got that good juice.
Juice.
Yeah.
He good did.
That would be great.
Parents.
They're fucking smarter.
Shit reveals the worst parts of being
pregnant in 2017.
Oh,
she is pregnant.
Wow.
It's.
Here's a nice little belly gun.
That's interesting because she was kind
of cranky last time I saw her at the
comedy store.
That makes sense.
She didn't look pregnant though because
you had so many things on it.
Yeah.
Well,
she's a.
She's well dressed.
She's.
That's interesting there.
If you had to pick like the funniest
comedian couples,
their top three.
It's like a rich vos and bonding
mcfarland right up there.
I think I got to give the fucking title
to the mommies.
I give the title of the tom and
christina.
Absolutely.
I think they're number one as far as
funniest couple,
but moshe and natasha right up there.
They're both legit.
Real top flight standups and they
actually get along somehow.
So the water champs,
I don't know if tom and christina,
they have a champion.
They have like real competition with
each other to see who's the water.
Having a person at the personality champ
content amongst themselves.
Well,
tom is in the throes of our yoga
challenge and he's lost a shitload away.
Christina was just ranting about it,
like how great he looks.
He looks awesome,
dude.
He fucking guy.
When we did that weight loss challenge,
he was like,
what was it like 40 something pounds and
then just ran with it.
Never let up.
Never.
Never went back to his old ways of
eating and just stayed.
Fit.
Worked out constantly.
Yeah,
and he looks great.
There was a picture of him the other day
that somebody put up on instagram and I
was like,
jesus christ,
like,
look at him.
He's skinny.
He's got to go get all new pictures
again because yeah,
it doesn't look the same.
Well that was bert was talking about
that,
like his mostly stories.
Photo.
He's got this big old moon face and now
you look at it and he's a.
He's all fucking thin and sexy.
We to wrap this up,
dude,
I gotta I gotta abbreviate this one and
get this out of here quicker than most
can I recommend a show for you,
please.
There's a show that I can't get enough.
It's called good mythical morning.
Have you ever watched this,
jamie?
Uh,
so It's these two guys.
And it's really interesting how they
filmed it because it's,
it's for all the kids love it and adults
love it.
And,
and,
uh,
there these two guys and every day they
do this show and it's only like maybe 15
minutes long,
but everyday it's something diFferent.
Like we're going to taste test 10
hamburgers anD we're going to figure out
which one it is or we're going to see
if,
uh,
we're,
we're gonnA play this game where one,
uh,
one thing is a cow eyeballs.
And the other thing is gummy cow
eyeballs and whoever loses has to eat
the cow eyeballs.
And it's like they,
they take parts of fear factor,
they take parts of just like interesting
things.
Like we're going to see a taste expired
food from 40 years ago and they're
constantly eating stuff every day.
Like I'm gonna die.
Uh,
it'S really great.
I highly recommend.
It's called good mythical morning.
They also have a podcast called a ear
biscuits linker.
The guy's name is pretty hot ones.
I did a,
a form of hot ones.
It was a,
one of his officers when the in between
seasons like me and him went to the
hottest,
a chicken place in los angeles,
chicken place in raise and it's nasty.
It's,
oh,
it's the most amazing chicken every.
Where's it at?
Helen ray.
When ray and ray's downtown raise.
You should,
that's the episode.
Uh,
but how enraged it's nashville hot
chicken.
And so they have like the hottest
chicken,
uh,
and they also have chicken that's not on
the menu.
So we ate the three hottest chicken and
one that's not on the menu.
Me and him wasn't it on the menu because
it's too hot.
You had to sign papers.
Like it's,
it's,
you're not supposed to eat it.
Like what happens?
Well,
you should watch the episode,
but pretty much leave me with a
cliffhanger.
But after we did it,
he said,
shaun says that was hotter than anything
we've ever done on hot ones.
And me,
he left immediately went to his hotel
room,
me and him.
I went to my house a 45 minutes.
I'm just crawling,
like,
laying there,
like crying.
I fall asleep.
I wake up,
I'm shooting blood like it's 24 hours of
hell and be an incident like I wrote
sean,
like,
are you in the same boat?
And he's like,
yeah,
I'm dying to like,
is it that bad?
It was that bad.
So if you go to hell and raise,
I recommend getting into mild or medium
hot,
but do not get the hottest and don't ask
for the hidden menu item hot because
it's like horrible.
Unless you want to ruin your life.
But then when it was over,
did you feel good?
Sort of like a near death experience?
No,
I felt like I was who listened?
Who hallucinating?
Hallucinating jesus christ.
I mean I was eating paper towels at
parts just because it's a comedy or it
was too high.
Do you try milk?
No.
Uh,
we had ice cream afterwards that we
should supposed to help,
right?
Yeah.
Ice cream kind of helps.
Uh,
but getting the oil like that.
My,
my idea was get the oil out of my mouth
because it was uh,
my,
my lips were getting.
And what is the pepper that they use?
Like carolina?
Rhea was carolina rita ghost pepper.
It had a bunch of them in there.
A christ.
So you ate like ghost peppers?
Yeah.
And I had all,
if it's horrible dude,
a chip now you can buy.
I think it's for 99.
It's one chip that's supposedly the
hottest chip you can eat.
And it's got,
I think it's made with like two or three
of those ghost peppers or some shit like
that.
A chip one chip.
What's wrong with people?
One of the funniest episodes of good
mythical morning is watch them eat the
hottest pepper in the road.
And you'll see what I'm talking about
there.
It's scott will be back tomorrow with
the winner of the moab to 40 courtney
doe.
Walter,
she ran 238 miles and she beat everybody
by like almost a marathon length,
right?
Didn't she beat them?
I think she was 20 plus miles ahead of
the second place,
dude.
Wow.
Can I promote a show real quick?
Uh,
November 8th and rabia indianapolis at
mortise November 9th spot.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
And then November 9th,
I'll be at the funny bone hometown,
uh,
in columbus,
Ohio.
And November 10th I'll be another spurg
at the new arcade theater that just
opened up.
so our full three block comedy shows and
people where they get tickets for that
[inaudible] dot tv.
Powerful.
Okay.
We will be back tomorrow again,
like I said,
with courtney doe,
walter.
And then,
uh,
Adam Green tree.
Oh,
we got tom
delonge from blink one 82.
The dude is like somehow or another
communicating with aliens and he's doing
some stuff with like spaceships and
shit.
I'm sure he'll tell us.
And then the great matt flavor will be
here on friday.
We're kicking off the new studio with a
bang.
This is the official hark launch week.
You fucks.
We love you guys.
thank you.
Bye.