Push the sucker right up.
Close three,
two,
one.
And we're live.
What's happening man?
How are Ya?
I'm cool man.
There in La to meet you in person.
I've seen in magazines seen you since
man.
But like when,
when did you first burst onto the
bodybuilding scene?
What year was that?
Oh,
is it reminiscent today?
First Time I came out here was 1992
golds gym.
So I came from UK to do my first
professional bodybuilding contests was
called night of champions in New York
and I got second place there and made a
real big impact.
And the weeder company that used to be
based out here with a flex magazine and
muscle and fitness right down the
street.
They used to be.
I don't think they are now.
Closed down.
There's a fence around it and
everything,
but that's,
that's less than a mile away from here.
Yeah.
The,
the weeder officers are out there and
you know,
we though it was a,
it was a big name and bodybuilding,
the magazines and everything.
So they flew me out here,
did my first photo shoot at Gold's gym?
Nineteen 90.
So 27
and I remember watching you in those
magazines.
You were the first guy,
well,
you know what were the first guy,
but you were one of the first guys that
I ever saw in a magazine that it was
like,
gee,
how the fuck is that a person?
You were so big,
man Christ you were big.
That's funny.
Okay.
Because I look back at some of the
pitches now me and I say what the fuck,
you know,
it's um,
and I came into the sport and I wanted
to see what I could do.
I want it to like take it as far as it
could take it,
you know?
Well,
you represented to me as an outsider
looking in this insane determination,
you know,
like I've,
I felt like all the best guys,
whether it was arnold or you or Lee
Haney,
all the top guys,
they always represented not just like
the biggest and the most profoundly
ridiculously muscular bodybuilders,
but also this extreme dedication that
was required to reach that level.
Been around minute with martial arts and
everything.
And it kind of sport is the same thing.
What separates the guy that's first from
second,
from third or whatever,
you know,
you all got certain physical
characteristics that help you in your
sport and so on.
So you're all gifted up there.
So what can separate the guy from first
and second and third?
It's,
it's all up there.
That's,
that's the key.
How did you develop your mindset?
Was it something that you always had or
was it something that you developed as
you were training?
I think there's something already
already had and I kind of left home when
I was 16,
so it was out on my own on the street
and uh,
you know,
you're either going to get smart and,
look after yourself or you're going
gonna fall down.
There's nobody there to catch me.
So that was there from a,
from an early age I think.
And uh,
I was just very determined to,
to this thing that I will be good at in
order to change my life and change,
you know,
uh,
the projection of my life for the people
around me.
Um,
I always grew up on a housing estate in
the UK.
I no education,
I was in a jail when I was 18,
so I had all that.
That was,
you know,
the people around me.
I was like,
I didn't want part of that future.
I wanted to do something else and I got
this thing that was good at,
so I'm going to take it and run with it,
you know,
it's crazy how many people have similar
stories like that where they were in
just a terrible environment and they
realized that they had a tough enough,
they had a smart enough and they had to
get out of there and if not for those
terrible situations,
who knows if they would have ever
reached the levels of greatness that
they can tell you from our point of
view,
I don't think I would have done because
I would be too comfortable.
If you're comfortable,
you're not going to put yourself through
that extreme kind of pressure and pain.
And uh,
you know,
I wanted to improve my life,
changed my life and uh,
through the sport.
Here I am sitting talking to you on this
show.
People are listening to me.
I've been all around the world thanks to
my sport.
So it's been great for me.
You know,
when you meet current bodybuilders,
are they like,
hey man,
what the fuck?
I couldn't be.
Not a gigantic huge Mr Hawkins your
regular size athletic looking dude.
Yeah.
Not really.
Maybe some of the younger guys that are
coming into this now,
but you know,
people know me.
Um,
I was a professional bodybuilder.
That's what I did and I was the best at
doing that,
but that kind of training and that kind
of physique is not going to serve me
now.
So I do training to be more functional.
My goals are more health related now.
Whereas before I was a young guy and I
want it to be the best at this thing I
was doing.
I put everything into that.
Um,
but you know,
that kind of physique.
It's not practical for everyday usage.
You know,
how to tie my shoelaces when it was 300
pounds.
I'm sure.
Man.
And how tall are you?
Five.
10,
five,
11,
five.
11.
So like when you were that big,
you were just a ball of muscle.
Just a mass.
Yeah.
And 300 pounds.
I was 300,
3:10
in the off seasons.
Christ competing to 65,
but I mean to 65.
Lean as fuck the hydrated,
you know,
shared it.
So yeah,
that's,
that's all I did.
That was all I did.
I trained,
I eat asleep.
I studied.
That's just my mental focus was like
lasered on that thing that was doing
nothing else.
I wouldn't go to the movies,
I wouldn't go to dinner if I got home
after 11 because I got to be in a bed at
11.
That was,
that was the regime that are live for,
for many years and that's why I was able
to beat other people that maybe it could
be argued they were more gifted than me,
but they weren't willing to do that.
So that's,
that's what it's all about.
Yeah.
That's what I had always read about you.
And that's what I did.
Like I said,
there was the impression that I always
got like,
what you represented is the pinnacle of
extreme dedication.
Yeah.
And study,
you know,
um,
we had no internet then.
Everybody's got coaches now and
nutritionists.
The thing that appealed to me is this
was an individual thing.
I had to learn about the training,
had to learn about the nutrition,
how to learn all this stuff myself.
And that was,
apart from the training,
that was part of it as well,
you know,
the learning part of it I enjoyed.
Was it hard to get good information
because I'm sure there's a bunch of like
gym experts,
there's always these bro science guys
that are hanging around giving you
shitty advice,
like how hard was it to get the proper
information when it came to the
training.
I kind of sifted through it and uh,
was very influenced by a guy called
Arthur Jones.
Don't know if you've heard of him,
but off Jones he invented the Nautilus
machines.
And uh,
this guy was like a billionaire self
made billionaire who's just was
fascinated with the bodybuilding but had
no business interest in it.
So he just wanted to know.
He studied it and it was like,
what is it that causes muscle growth?
What is it?
And um,
he found it was the intensity of
exercise and then there was another
bodybuilder might men,
so went to compete in the Mr Olympia
when the Mr Universe,
he took those principles and who used
them and so I read all this stuff and it
was very logical,
it made sense.
And then I try to own the gym and it
worked in the gym and if I trained more
often or if I did more in the gym,
my progress was slow down or stop.
As soon as I cut back and I made the
workout shorter and more intense,
my progress went.
So it was for me,
it was pretty early on.
I learned how to train properly and
that's why I was competing.
I competed on a world championship after
18 months training,
which is pretty much unheard of.
That is pretty much unheard of now.
When you say shorter,
more intense workouts,
how did you regulate that?
Like that is,
that's a huge issue with martial artists
is overtraining or they want to do more
work than everybody else.
They want to work harder than everybody
else and they want a break in their body
down and showing up for the fight.
Exhausted.
Overtraining is a big thing.
Yeah,
and if you see the process for muscle
growth is you go in the gym and it put
stress on the muscle.
If you put stress that is not used to,
then it's going to react.
You're going to get growth,
but you need to recover from that first.
You don't go to the gym and grow and
then recover later.
That's the way it works.
You Go,
if you've,
you know,
you give your body some stresses not
used to,
you'll get a reaction,
but before we get the reaction,
you have to recover.
So if you're not allowing enough time to
recover,
you're just.
I use this analogy,
a seminars I do.
It's very simplistic,
but it gets the point across.
If you get a bit of sandpaper and you
rub it across the palm of your hand and
it's kind of bloody.
If you leave it and let it heal up,
what's going to happen?
The skin's gonna develop back a little
bit stronger,
a little bit thicker than before because
it wants to protect against that stress.
So that's the process,
but if you go and you might get hand
bloody and before it's healed up again,
you're going and rub it again.
What's happening?
You're not really getting any way.
Just going to have a bloody hand.
You know,
you think you're being tough,
but you're actually just being silly.
Yeah.
And it's a why are you going to the gym?
Right?
I'm going to the gym to get results,
so I'm going to do whatever it takes to
get results and if it means training 30
minutes once a week or it means training
10 hours a day every day,
whatever it takes.
I was willing to do it and I would have
done it,
but I'm training 10 hours a day is not
going to build your muscle.
It's just going to burn out.
So I was doing average 40 5:50
minute workouts probably four times
a week.
And everybody say,
oh,
that's it.
Whether I write on a piece of paper,
what the fuck is that?
That's nothing,
man.
I'm like,
okay,
well come and do it.
Come and do it and tell me if you want
to do more when we're finished and
nobody has ever said,
oh,
please come and do some more.
They're like,
that's it.
That's enough because every set by the
warmup sets you've got to warm up and,
you know,
to be safe and everything.
But the set,
the real sets,
so I call them,
we're going to go to absolute failure
and even beyond with forced reps,
with assistant as reps,
maybe extra negative reps,
which is,
um,
something that most people neglect when
they lift weights,
they think,
you know,
I've lifted it.
All right,
well let it go down.
I've lifted it,
but they're neglecting the lowering part
of the weight and the negative.
So I get people to really slow that
down.
So you're taxing that part as well.
And even at the end of the sit on some
exercises with machines where it's
practical.
So you know,
you can't curl anymore physically on the
positive,
on the contraction,
what your strength on the lowering is
greater.
So if you did curls and you failed,
I could lift the weight to the top for
you and you could lower it down for
probably another three Reps.
so if you'd just gone to failure here,
you wouldn't have exhausted the negative
part of the Rep.
so my thing is the exhaust,
everything,
it's totally fucked.
You can't live,
you can't lower it,
you can't lift it,
it's total failure if you do that once
and an exercise and then time to move on
to another exercise.
How did you develop your protocol?
Just trial and error.
Trial and error.
And you know,
I didn't invent this system of training
as I said,
people there before me,
Arthur Jones might mentor,
I just taught what they did and refined
it a little bit more for a competitive
bodybuilder because Arthur Jones wasn't
competitive bodybuilder.
People who trained weren't so his,
his routines were even briefer than
mine.
But for a bodybuilder,
you know,
you've got,
you've got to work the side,
Dell,
you've got to work different aspects.
So,
uh,
I'd probably did a little bit more than
they did.
Um,
so I adapted it to myself and my needs
now when you were at your height and
when you're 265 pounds shredded and
dehydrated and then 310 pounds in the
off season you got,
it must be like used to looking at
yourself like that.
Like was it hard to adapt to being me?
You still obviously a very fit guy,
but you're a normal size.
Like if I saw you I'd be like there's a
normal fit guy.
Yup.
That's what I want to be in A.
I'm not training for bodybuilding
because it's not what I want to do now.
Plus I got a lot of injuries from a low
super heavyweight.
So I did,
I got a torn rotator cuff which is not.
I've tried out a couple of surgeries on
that doesn't repair.
So you know,
I was trying to lift weights and
continue to do and what I do because
that's what I'm used to doing.
Right,
right.
And when you're familiar with doing
something that you're reluctant to
change to something else,
but I noticed my shoulder is getting a
bit worse and my hips were getting,
you know,
I'm like,
hold on,
is this serving me now?
Why am I doing this?
Am I doing this just to try and maintain
something for other people what they
think I should look like?
And I kind of came to the conclusion,
yeah you are because you're not,
you're not a bodybuilder in the morning,
not competing.
So if during this training is not really
benefit and humans maybe making your
injuries worse,
you know,
when,
when you're 60 or something,
you're going to like lift your arms up
or something like that.
So I'm thinking more practically.
And um,
I started doing yoga and I really fell
in love with it.
It's amazing,
isn't it?
Yeah,
it's amazing.
It's physically,
I got much more range of motion mobility
and then you've got the spiritual aspect
of as well.
So I'm actually the.
I was inspired to do yoga from a DMT
trip predator,
a dmt trip.
And I came back and I was like,
my body's all fucked up this thing,
right?
Like I gotta fix some stuff here.
What should I do?
And I didn't even,
I vaguely knew what yoga was,
but I didn't really know what it was.
And I got to do something.
Got To do yoga or Tai Chee,
I don't know what it is,
but I started looking into it and then
found a yoga teacher.
And I do that a couple times a week.
I find it's great.
Every time I do it I just think I should
do more on this morning.
And I got up this morning and did yoga
class at 8:00,
Gold's gym and you know,
on an empty stomach,
just had some water and some tea and I
fucking feel amazing or that from that.
Well,
it just,
to me it feels like it connects
everything.
It connects all the tissue from the back
to the legs to the arms and the neck and
the core.
It strengthens all the connecting stuff.
Yeah.
And you get a flow going around.
That's the thing with bodybuilding,
because bodybuilding,
you're isolating the muscles right?
So you're isolating your bicep,
you're isolating the tricep,
isolating the deltoids and putting
stress on those muscles to maximize the
muscle size of those individual muscles,
which is great for bodybuilding.
But uh,
your body's function like that,
you know,
if you throw something,
you throw a punch or you know,
you don't use one muscle,
use the sea,
you know,
sits chain affects your whole body,
works together and bodybuilding.
You don't really do that,
you don't learn to do that.
So that's what I've had to relearn,
you know.
So when you exercise today,
like what kind of stuff do you do
besides yoga?
I do yoga a do some cycling.
I live in Spain,
we've got some good hills there.
So I do because I like to push them and
I can't push the whites anymore.
I can't get in that zone,
you know,
because because of my injuries,
so I got to do something else.
Yoga is a challenge,
you know?
And it continued to be like if I do that
until I'm dropped down dead 80 years
old,
there's always more that I can do.
You know,
you can always do a bit more range or a
bit more difficult pose.
So there's no,
there's no ceiling there,
you know,
uh,
with the bodybuilding I already been on
the ceiling.
Yeah.
You know,
um,
I do cycling couple of times a week up
and down the hill,
so that's like,
you know,
it's got almost like intervals because
you do a hill,
it's intense and then you go flat and
it's a bit easier.
So I enjoy doing that.
You move to Spain?
Um,
well I lived in UK and I started
visiting Spain because in Spain,
the south coast of Spain.
He's got a very brick,
a British community there and the
weather is amazing.
It's like La Mar Bayer is like,
for me it reminds me a lot of la,
but a mini la without all the bullshit
and the traffic about the crime and all
that kind of stuff.
Uh,
so that's why,
that's why I moved there.
Oh,
that's nice.
Have you ever looked into anything for
your shoulder,
like stem cells or things on them?
No,
I had,
um,
there was a new surgery now because what
happened,
I tore my supraspinatus a couple of
times and because the end was badly
frayed there to chop off the end,
so now it doesn't really bridge the gap
to the Humerus,
so it needs a bridge and apparently
there's a new surgery that they can,
uh,
make a bridge now.
Um,
but I went to see a surgeon and he's
like,
okay,
what's three issues here?
Pain,
you have pain.
I'm like,
no,
I'm not really have range of motion.
Actually I got more range than the other
shoulder was a bit loose.
Um,
so the only issue with mine is strength
and stability and he wasn't able to give
me 100 percent on whether the surgery
would do that for me.
And I've had a bad six surgeries.
I had a tendon reattachment here about
three on the shoulder,
had the hips and I'm like,
you know what,
unless you're going to tell me a hundred
percent that going through the
inconvenience and pain of a surgery is
going to give me what I need,
then I'm not going to do it.
I'm just going to cope with this and I
can't venture risk,
but so what,
like,
you know,
it doesn't really matter that much to
me.
You can,
you do pushups or I can do some pushups
but probably like 10 where before I'd do
like 100 or something so it's very
weakened in stable.
So yeah,
if.
Sure,
if,
if I had a surgeon that says to me,
listen man,
we're going to do this and I guarantee
your shoulders going to be stronger and
more stable after it because you know,
you've got to sit with you in a sling
for like six to eight weeks.
You can't shower properly,
can't dress and in and all this stuff.
So for me to go through that again,
I would have to have like,
yeah,
this is definitely going to help.
Then I would consider it until then I'll
live with it.
You know,
they're doing some pretty amazing stuff
now with stem cells.
Yeah,
there with some tendon tissue.
So
yeah,
they can do a lot of soft tissue
regeneration.
They're also doing it now.
The most recent things.
They're combining stem cells with
platelet rich plasma that doing it
together and they found that by doing
the stem cells in the prp together,
it helps generate new tissue growth
better.
Yeah.
No,
my wife,
she had a knee surgery and she had the
PRP and the recovery was real quick.
So yeah,
it's nice it she had meniscus,
is that what it was?
Yeah.
So yeah,
if there's any surgeons out there that
repair Dorian's shortened supraspinatus,
let me know,
man.
Now is your situation very similar to
what a lot of bodybuilders face after
they retire?
They just,
they're so much stress and strain on the
joints in the back and.
Yeah.
Well I'm Ronnie Coleman,
who is the Mr Olympia after me and he
said be serious.
He did a lot of really heavy squatting,
which also when he was getting ready for
a bodybuilding competition and basically
doing power lifting,
which probably not a good idea.
Um,
so ron has a lot of problems with his
discs in his back and I'm not sure of
all the details,
but I know he's had a lot of fusions.
So his mobility and so on is going to be
limited.
And one fusion.
Yeah,
several.
So he can't turn his neck and his back
to good.
And is that both of his hips replaced?
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
He's a young guy to hold.
Was Ronnie's?
No,
no run is like almost my age is probably
early fifties.
Yeah.
Why do I think he's younger than that?
He retired.
I'm thinking should I said 4,636?
He did.
We both were known to be very strong
running more so than myself because they
did power lifting before.
So we moved some heavy weights and uh,
you know,
any sport man is that you're going to
have some consequences.
Yeah.
No To ron if you fight and play
football,
whatever and everything has its,
you know,
its downside.
But all things considering I think I'm
doing pretty good.
I'm healthy and you know,
I got a dicky shoulder.
So big deal.
It's okay.
Yeah.
I'm telling you man,
if you just hang in there,
they're on their way to figuring
something out for that.
Yeah,
that's,
that's almost what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking like don't do anything now
because a few years time there'll be
something that can really do the job.
So yeah,
I'll wait until then.
Yeah.
The last thing you want to do is get
something.
Like,
I always tell that to my friends that
are thinking about getting disks fused
and like,
you know,
they're so close.
They're shooting.
They're shooting stem cells into the
discs directly in regenerating tissue
the same way they've been regenerating
municipals,
tissue and tendon tissue and things
along those lines.
I met a guy that trained out here many
years ago in La and he told me they were
an I've seen before and after x rays of
joints that are the joints destroyed.
He's got no cartilage,
so looking at replacement and these guys
have actually regenerated the tissue
back,
but it's quite a lengthy process of
traction,
like hanging upside down and hours of
ultrasound just to push a ton of blood
into that area.
Blood Supply and then you can heal it
up.
You can actually regrow cartilage
tissue,
but it's not.
Um,
it's not quick.
It's not on the protocol of the Medical
Association.
So they basically push these guys out of
business with lawsuits.
Well,
you know,
there's a doctor that we've talked about
on the podcast before that recommends
hanging from a bars for your shoulders.
It's one of the best things ever to
alleviate pain and also to increase
range of motion and reduce impingements.
Well,
I'll have to get in touch with this guy.
Yeah.
Well just for my,
for my back,
I got the inversion table and I do that
a couple of times a week just to keep
them ability there.
I know one of my discs,
l five five's a little bit warm,
but I don't do squats or heavy overhead
stuff,
so I think it's going to be okay.
But yeah,
I still,
you know,
it's all about prevention.
Have you heard of the reverse hyper
machine?
Have you seen that?
No.
We have one in the back.
I'll show it to you,
but it's a creation of a west side
barbell.
You know Louie Simmons,
crazy bastard.
Yeah.
Louie Simmons created this machine that
when you lift your legs up,
it strengthens back and on the
down.
When it swings down,
it's active decompression,
phenomenal for disc issues.
It's like active decompression plus
strengthening together.
I have one back here.
I love it so much.
Right there is like this.
You could see it up here.
It's.
We've talked about this so many times
people would think this guy is like
hired me to endorse this product,
but it's an amazing product.
That is.
Yeah.
It's the reverse of the hyperextension
la,
so he can explain it.
Can hear the range of motion at the top.
Squeeze,
squeeze,
squeeze.
Really?
She drops her head.
Raise your hand.
Way Up.
Drops on the way down for a flagship in
extension is fine.
This will absolutely help desk.
This is traction.
Motion Traction,
and got one of those
wife very fit,
so I'm sure she does a lot of lifting as
well.
So that was a world champion as well.
Enough failed.
You know,
it's so common for anybody that puts any
strain in their body to have usually
five l and l,
four area on the.
On the bottom of the spine,
one of the things about bodybuilding is
that in isolation,
when you're,
you're constantly isolating these
things,
does that run the risk of like a
weakening certain areas?
Like you have to be?
I would imagine very cognizant about
balancing everything out.
Um,
I think,
uh,
like with bodybuilders,
a shoulder injuries is the most common
because you've got the rotator cuff
which is a small muscles and tendons
which gives you the ability.
That's why it can move it around rather
than being a hinge.
Um,
so what happens,
you know,
you get an strongly at altschool,
all these external muscles are getting
bigger and stronger,
but these guys inside I'm not.
So eventually they get overloaded and
you get some kind of issue there,
some kind of tear.
So when I'm training people now I give
them a rotation exercises to strengthen
those areas so that can avoid that.
But Hey man,
I started training.
The eight is like we didn't know
anything and when I got an injury and
are living in England as well,
there's no sports medicine doctors
dealing with strength athletes or so on.
And so I just go to your doctor and he's
like,
how do you do that?
Lifting weights,
stopped doing that shit.
Why you left their wives,
take these pills and that's,
you know,
so,
so now we have much more information,
much more,
you know,
a sports therapist and so on.
So there's a lot more things available
now and a lot more knowledge and
information that we didn't really have
back then.
You know,
that's,
that's the main thing,
you know,
collect some of the smallest supporting
muscles.
I think when you're doing major
bodybuilding exercises,
do guys now address that?
Do they do like a lot of rotation
exercises?
A lot of rotation
in the gym than like,
you know,
if it did that back in the eighties,
people like what the fuck you're doing
little wait time,
lift some weights.
But I see people doing it now and with
the bands and everything.
So yeah,
people doing more preventative stuff.
It's fascinating
because there was guys like arnold who
was kind of the original pioneers and
then guys like you who came after him,
but you were still again,
pre-internet,
figuring things out on your own,
learning from the guys that came before
you,
but taking it to another level,
that was the beauty of it for me.
I never really liked team sports because
I just felt like this I sold was letting
me down here,
you know,
and I felt like that through my life as
well.
I felt like,
like my parents didn't really,
you know,
like everyone's fucking letting me down.
Fuck this,
I'll do this myself.
And so I got to learn about the
nutrition.
I learned about the training,
I got to do it,
I've got to pull it all into action and
of course I had people supporting me,
but when I got on that stage it was win
or lose.
I'm taking full responsibility for this
and we don't really have that now.
And the guys don't learn anything
because they've got coaches.
So what should I do?
Bus Do this,
do that and eat this and eat that.
Okay,
and you know,
the beauty of it's gone,
you're not learning anything anymore.
What if you fall out with the coach like
I was going to do next contest.
So is that like a big thing now?
Like there's like a series of coaches,
is it like MMA camps?
It's the same thing and it's like,
I dunno,
I think the guys a suckers because who
is making the money here?
The coaches,
the coaches are making the money,
not the,
not the competitors.
The coaches are smart and I look at the
coaches and I say,
who the fuck are you and what have you
done?
You know,
what,
which contest if you actually want.
And most of them haven't done anything.
It's just all theory.
So I'm sort of the exercise
physiologists,
just guys from the industry that,
you know,
they're,
they've trained a few people and they've
got a few results and uh,
it's more about the,
for me it's more about the insecurity of
the guys competing.
Like why don't you learn yourself and
listen to your body.
And I used to make notes,
you know,
every week I'd write down my diet,
I'd write down every single workout that
I ever did from 1984 to 1997.
I have in a training log.
You should sell that.
I printed out all these little exercise
books,
you know,
and like you can see the first one went
on like 21 years old.
It's a bit childish with the comments,
what it's like,
you know,
I felt shit today.
This was a shitty worker.
Never fucking let this happen again,
you know,
all this stuff.
I'm talking to myself.
So I've got all this and then go back
and look at it sometimes.
And it's weird because I can go back to
1988 and I can look in my book and I
look at that workout and I was like,
I was in this gym and I was training
with this guy and I can't even remember.
Like I was like,
why do I was wearing.
And I can go back in time and remember
just from those nodes.
Yeah,
like every workout.
As soon as I've got home and I finished,
I was like,
Hey,
bench press,
I did this,
and every month I would make notes and
say,
okay,
this is what I'm doing now.
These are my goals for the next four
weeks,
you know,
whatever,
like little goals,
like I'm going to put five pounds on my
bench press,
but you do that every month.
Then the end of the month,
you've got your end of the year.
He got 60 pounds,
right?
So,
uh,
did all these things like,
you know,
a mental rehearsal,
visualization,
all this stuff.
I did it,
I just,
I kind of learned it.
Nobody,
nobody taught me.
So,
um,
that was one of the things,
goal setting,
writing and writing it down on a piece
of paper just.
And that you can do this with anything,
your business,
whatever.
You're writing it down on a piece of
paper,
you make a commitment,
it's fucking,
they're on a piece of paper everyday.
You can look at that and it just gives
you a stronger mental vision.
And instead of saying,
right,
I'm going to win this contest in 18
months time.
Yeah,
that's cool you're going to win that
contest,
but how are you going to get the.
It's like saying I'm going to sail to
Australia.
Yeah,
it's a good idea.
That's cool,
but how are you going to get there?
If you've got a plan,
have you've got a map of like,
fuck,
you're going to go with no map,
you're just going to get lost,
you know?
So I found that very helpful and that's
what I try to teach people as well,
you know?
Yeah.
I think writing down goals is huge and
it's something that most people don't
do.
Yeah,
I still do it now.
Like a daily thing.
This is what I got to do today.
Sometimes I won't get through it all,
but you know,
at least it's there.
I might put a couple of things off for
tomorrow,
but I find it very,
very helpful.
Yeah.
And which I've written it down like,
you know,
like let's say a,
I don't know,
you want to stop drinking or something,
write it down.
I'm going to stop drinking alcohol,
sign it if I can put it there on your
table.
It don't just have said that you've said
that you've made the commitment to put
on a paper,
so you're gonna,
you're gonna let yourself down.
You're going to be a pussy,
you're going to be weak and you're going
to break that.
You made that commitment,
man,
you know,
it's there on a piece of paper.
So,
uh,
that's that strong.
Especially for the type of person like
you dedicated focused guy.
Like something like that is just extra
motivation in,
in a,
like a,
you know,
it's a scaffolding.
Yeah,
exactly.
Is there,
it's solid,
you know,
something.
Just say it casually.
I fucking committed to this.
I wrote it down,
you know?
Yeah.
I'm a firm believer.
I think you should,
at least for a week,
you know,
at least for your week,
set it down and have a little checkbox
next to it and make sure you can look at
that.
Like,
I did this,
I got my workout in,
I got my,
my,
whatever.
Whatever you need to get done,
whatever you trying to slack off.
It's five things to do that I did for
them.
I didn't do the fifth one because I
smoked a joint with four to five.
Still that four out of five.
I would reward myself.
If you do write things down,
no,
you'll just get more done.
Even if you don't fulfill the entire
even to get more done than than if you
didn't do it 100 percent.
It's having a plan man and everything
needs a plan.
If you want to get somewhere,
I'll use that analogy.
if you're a captain on a ship,
you don't just get on the ship and say,
Hey Ho,
let's go silent and we're going to get
there.
No,
you're probably not.
You need to.
You know,
you need a route to get there and you
need to know what it takes to get there.
I'm going to do this.
I'm going to do this fight competition.
Yeah.
Cool.
But do you know what it takes to get
there?
Right.
First of all,
this is what it takes.
Okay.
Are you prepared to do this?
Are you going to do this?
Yes or no,
and if it's yes,
go for it.
You.
If it's too much to
be honest,
I just don't fucking do it.
You know,
there was a time when you were a,
at the top of the heap where there was,
there was debate as to like what a
bodybuilder should look like.
There was like the Frank Zane look,
which was like a strong obviously fit
guy,
but much smaller and just symmetrical.
And then there was you that just came
out like the fucking Hulk,
you then,
and then it was almost like overwhelming
for a lot of people.
And then there was this debate to try to
figure out.
Absolutely.
Because when I look at a bunch of
bodybuilders on a stage and they're
trying to pick out who's number one,
who's number two,
I'm like,
I can't.
I mean,
I always assumed that it's like a lot of
other things,
like the deeper you are into it,
the more you can see the intricacies of
it.
Whereas for me,
a person is not a bodybuilder.
I'm like,
they're all fucking huge.
Like how can you tell who's the best?
Oh,
so it's a matter of um,
you know,
it's bodybuilding,
right?
Yeah.
So it's,
it's muscle size is a big factor.
It's not the only factor,
but it was a big factor.
If you look at the Mr Olympia is,
for instance,
in the era of Frank Zane and Frank Zane
is a body that probably most people
would look at and say,
fuck it.
Now that's,
that's it.
That's great.
And you know,
probably look at me and say it's too
extreme.
Um,
but in the era of Frank Zane,
who was Mr Olympia was Arnold Arnold was
Mr Olympia.
You could,
you could argue that Frank Zane,
his buddy his is more aesthetic and
nicer and prettier than Arnold,
but Arnold beach and why it just was
bigger,
more freakishly impressed,
his bigger.
And uh,
Lee Haney was eight times Mr Olympia,
you could argue maybe Lila abroad or,
or somebody like that was better
proportion and put together,
but he was much smaller.
So,
you know,
Frank Guy,
you would see the gym today like a
regular dude.
There's a lot of regular duties under
the,
a category now.
So you've got bodybuilding.
Um,
but you've got other categories now that
you didn't have.
So you've got men's physique,
which is more of this a type of
physique,
they're looking for various theoretic
tight waist,
everything like that.
And you've even got classic
bodybuilding,
which is height over weight ratio.
So you know,
the guys are not that big.
So you've got different categories as a
reaction to people not really liking the
direction that bodybuilding went and,
and uh,
yeah,
I'll take responsibility for it going
the size root and um,
I had a nice physique when I started,
you know,
I had a nice physique,
had nice abs and everything,
but I'm like,
if I'm going to do this,
I'm going to do this to the Max and I'm
going to see how far,
you know,
how big can I get,
how can I get,
how strong can I get?
I want to go to the Max and I don't want
people to say,
oh,
that's,
wow,
that's a nice physique.
I want people to say what the
fuck?
That's what I want it to do.
Well,
you succeeded in that.
You definitely succeeded.
Yeah.
The guy that inspired me to before that,
that
was Tom Platz.
I don't know if you're not with the
fucking
freaky legs and you know,
he was the guy,
um,
when I started,
it wasn't Mr Olympia,
but he was very inspirational and um,
when he talked it was just full of
energy and enthusiasm for the training
and pushing the body to its absolute
maximum.
And I remember Tom Platz saying,
you know,
when I walk out on stage in a
bodybuilding competition,
I want to see those judges there with a
pencil and the paper.
And I was just wanting to fucking drop
that pencil and just say what the fuck
is that?
We're so big.
His legs were so freakishly big like
that guy had,
like,
nobody has really surpassed Tom Platz
his leg.
I don't think to this day.
It's fair to say
now is that just,
it's weird because it's very rare that
someone's known very specifically for a
body part that we plats is known for his
legs.
What plats made a whole career on,
on the legs.
And uh,
not only the legs,
the passion he had for like pushing
himself into the gym for the,
to the absolute maximum.
And that inspired me to do that and try
and take it even further and that now is
missing.
That's not here anymore.
Now for me,
the bodybuilding and the fitness
industry,
people are just really more concerned
with the cosmetic,
the look and you know,
taking their pictures and putting them
instagram and all this kind of stuff.
They're not really into as almost a
spiritual side of it.
You know,
where you want to push yourself to that
maximum and see how far you can go and
how,
you know,
how far your mind can go into the pain
and all that kind of stuff.
That's not really there anymore.
Well,
what's,
what's missing?
Like,
what's the element that's missing?
Like why isn't that near?
Um,
I dunno man.
I mean a collection of society in
general.
People just want stuff like,
you know,
they want stuff easy.
Now.
You know,
everyone wants to be famous,
but the picture on Instagram,
you don't need to do shit.
Just be famous.
Go on.
Big Brother.
Be famous for nothing.
Nothing.
Yeah.
That's,
I don't know.
I think that's a reflection of the way
things are perhaps in everything.
But what's the difference in the way the
bodybuilders approach it today?
I mean,
they're obviously doing something
because there's still huge on.
They're still,
you know,
these giant guys that are lifting
weights.
So what element,
if you look at the giant guys that have
whites now that don't look quite like
myself and the guys from the nineties
now the guys are just big everywhere.
The waste.
So huge.
Everything huge.
Um,
and it's 20 years since I competed in a
contest,
so I don't exactly know what the guys
are using a lot more different to drugs
and we use a lot more insulin and igf,
things like that.
So,
um,
I think what you're seeing in the big
guys is somewhat systemic growth.
It's like they just got bit bigger
everywhere and that doesn't look,
uh,
so appealing I think,
right,
when their guts extent.
Yeah.
So maybe the relying more on the
chemicals and they don't really,
you know,
I haven't really heard anything from any
of the bodybuilding champions in the
last 10 or 15 years.
I don't think I'm interesting or new or
revolutionary in the training methods.
It just,
you know,
I don't really even talk about it that
much now.
Everyone just does the same stuff.
Know.
Well,
it was at one point in time where no one
talked about it at all.
Right.
Like it was.
You would get the magazines and they
would tell you to take creatine and you
could look like me,
but everybody kind of knew who.
Everybody who knew.
People who knew people was somewhat
Vienna circle.
Yeah.
I remember I started in the eighties and
I read the magazines and a few things by
Arnold and Mike Mansa where they kind of
admitted that use something,
but they've downplayed it.
Oh,
it's only for the last six weeks before
a competition just to give us that last
Polish and stuff like that and ask a few
guys in the gym.
And when I first started they were a bit
cagey,
like,
no,
don't,
I don't do that.
And later on I found out they're all,
they're all doing it,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
and it was very much an inner circle in
the gym.
Bodybuilders now everybody knows about
steroids and now it's mainstream.
And guys take steroids now just for
cosmetic reasons because they want to
look bigger and harder and quicker.
Uh,
I just equate it to women having a
botox.
So having some implants,
the guys want to look bigger.
I don't want to work so hard.
They don't want to,
you know,
they just want to quick,
right?
So you get guys coming to the gym and
that just takes steroids pretty much
straight away.
Um,
I don't necessarily learn how to train
really properly.
Um,
and uh,
it's not just competitive bodybuilders
now.
I mean,
it's everywhere.
It's everywhere.
It's mainstream.
You look at Hollywood,
you look at hip hop artists.
I mean,
come on,
they're all,
they're all doing a bit of juice,
man.
Look,
look at nearly 10 years ago and look at
him now,
man.
He was just,
I haven't really been interested in La.
There's a,
there's a lot of them.
Nearly a cool J.
I mean,
you know,
they all,
they're all jack man.
I'm know it's not fully me.
I can see what's going on guys from
Hollywood,
they want to get in shape quickly for a
movie.
You know,
guys just want to look good on the
beach.
Um,
it's,
it's everywhere now.
It's main course.
There's nearly damp.
No,
he's checked.
Yeah.
We saw a picture of a huge Jackman when
he was preparing for Wolverine was doing
dead lifts and uh,
he was in his forties and someone was
asking me,
do you think he's,
I guess,
yeah.
Well,
I mean,
how much did it get paid for the movie
as well?
Fuck yeah.
Well No,
not only that,
like tip for a guy that is not really
that kind of an athlete to all of a
sudden look like that.
Like you got to make some radical
physiological changes and a couple of
months like that was,
that's not even a good picture of man.
It's real good pictures of them checked.
But um,
I mean there's pictures of him from the
movie too,
which just,
he's enormous.
Like he just became an enormous guy.
What I'm saying is like how much did he
get paid for the movie?
And my point is,
you know,
he got paid for that.
So maybe he took her little health risk
or whatever.
You can debate that,
but he's getting paid for it,
but is it worth it if you're just doing
it?
Just fucking look good on the beach and
all look good for the girls or
something.
Yeah,
I'm trying to put it in.
But here's the.
Here's the thing,
man.
Once you get on that merry go round,
you don't want to get off.
That's the problem.
Right?
And you don't want to get off because
you took some stuff.
You know,
you got bigger,
you getting more attention from the
girls.
Now guys got more respect for you.
Your self confidence is up.
You don't,
you don't lose all that man.
Well,
speaking personally because what I took
it for a competitive sport.
I'm going to stop that.
Stop.
That was it.
But that was my,
that's my question.
Like how did you just accept the fact
that you were no longer a superhuman
looking freak show of a man?
Now you became a regular man.
Was there a lot?
My whole thing was see if with
bodybuilding competition,
uh,
I never showed my physique even in the
gym with the guys that are trained with.
I was covered up all the time if I want
to look at my physique and practice my
poses and stuff,
I did it at home.
So on the street I always wore long
sleeve.
I don't give a shit about anybody else.
Why is that?
Because I did it purely for competition.
But why did you cover it?
Why don't you just dress like with a.
because it's freaking wanted attention
all the fucking time and I'm not
interested in it,
you know,
I'm a quiet guy and I just wanted to go
about my business and reveal this thing.
I've been working on [inaudible].
I didn't see it as being.
It's almost removed.
It's like a statue I'm working on so I
wasn't tied up in like I was tied up in
being Mr Olympia because that's who I
was and that,
you know,
somewhat a,
a plane.
Um,
what the whole huge body and I didn't,
I didn't need that for,
for everyday use.
Well,
that sort of fits with this whole
Spartan image that people had a view
that you are the image of you was like
this guy that was just doing work that
other people weren't willing to do and
some sort of quiet isolation somewhere.
So literally we're not as deep basement
a basement in Birmingham,
England where,
you know,
it's not exactly a hotbed of
bodybuilding activity,
no beaches or nothing.
It's an industrial city.
Um,
so I just locked myself away there and
worked on this project and I love doing
it.
I love just being in that tunnel,
you know,
seeing what I can do and obviously the
further you get along,
the more difficult it is to make any
kind of improvements.
But I was trying,
you know,
that's fascinating to look at it that
way is almost like an art project.
There was a statue I was removed.
It was not my,
I wasn't like building this body so I
could get,
you know,
admiring from the girls or the guys
going to be.
I was already like a fit strong guy
before I started.
So I didn't come from that place of
like,
I need to do this to make myself feel
better,
I need to do this because I have some
talent for it and I can change my life
with this.
Maybe I didn't know it was going to be
Mr Olympia,
but I just knew that if I put my energy
into this,
something positive was going to come
from it.
And after a few years I won the British
Championship.
And because of that,
you know,
I was British champion.
I didn't have a car.
I went home to a one bedroom apartment
with no furniture.
I didn't even have a proper bed.
I had a mattress on the floor,
I didn't have shit,
but I wasn't the British championship.
And because of that somebody put up the
money for me to open a gym.
Then I had a gym,
then it was making an income from my
sport.
So even if it went that far,
it would have been worth it,
you know?
Wow.
Well,
I think that attitude is probably what's
made you like very healthy mentally
afterwards,
what are separate from your body and
that it was a project,
there was a paragraph
the way it was very tough because I was
a sky or was Mr Olympia and this is
solely been doing since I was 21 years
old.
And then I got an injury.
So my exit from the sport was not
calculated.
I told my tricep tendon on the left
elbow and this had already won injury,
a bicep tear.
But I kind of handled that and it didn't
affect my training too much,
but this was almost a complete
detachment that I have to repair.
And after that I just knew I couldn't,
I couldn't lift properly and like,
you know,
you can't compete with the rest of the
world if you can't lift properly.
Um,
so I had to retire and then I was lucky
in limbo as know who the fuck am I and
what am,
what am I going to do with my life?
So it took me a few years to kind of
slowly get back,
but it wasn't about,
Oh,
I've lost my muscles when I'm going to
do.
Like it was more about,
you know,
I don't know what my role is in life.
I don't know who I am.
It took me a long time to find that.
And I think a lot of athletes that
retired from sport,
they have the same same issues.
It's a giant issue with fighters.
You,
you know,
you've got this fucking tunnel that
you're in,
right?
It's almost like being at war like
stressful,
but you know,
you've got this role and this,
this thing that you just aim and for all
of them
time and now it's gone.
Like what the fuck you going to do?
Who are you,
what it's all about,
you know?
So it took me years to kind of come to
peace with that.
But it wasn't about losing the muscles.
It was about losing my goal and my focus
in my role in life.
I think.
Yeah,
the,
for a lot of athletes it's the intensity
of life is all of a sudden reduce down
to a mundane normal guy and lows and
mediums the time.
Um,
but I turned it around because when I
was doing bodybuilding,
my life was very restrictive,
like a fucking monk,
you know,
I just had this regime and I didn't want
to socialize.
I didn't want to do anything outside of
that.
So after some time I came like,
hey man,
so you can't do that anymore.
What about,
how about the thousand and one things
you didn't do when you were doing that
because you couldn't.
Now you couldn't do all those things.
You can go a do you know,
not eat all day if you don't want to eat
six meals a day,
you can do what you want,
you know.
So I started looking into some other
things was interested in,
I was always been interested in
wildlife.
So I started going a few safaris and
things like that and yeah,
slowly I realized like,
Hey,
there's a million and one things you can
do in life like this,
you know,
get over this.
So it's just a transitionary
transitional period.
Yeah.
But,
um,
I can absolutely see why many athletes
struggle.
Uh,
Frank Bruno,
who was,
you know,
a boxer,
well boxing champion from Uk.
I know he had a really hard time and
almost like he was world champion when I
was Mr Olympian.
We've tried at the same time.
We both got divorced like everything
falls apart,
man,
like,
you know.
Um,
and then you hopefully rebuild back to
something else.
Yeah.
It seems that very few athletes have a
smooth process into retirement and
fighters in particular,
they always come back when they
shouldn't.
Yeah.
Well I know why they do that.
When I was a kid,
I was always,
why is Ali coming back,
man?
Like just,
you know,
he's the greatest and now he's going to
get beat by some guy cause it's coming
back.
What do you miss the fucking adrenaline
or whatever it is,
if that,
you know,
that all your focus,
all your soul,
everything is going into that one point.
And like it's,
it's tough to replace,
but you've got to know when it's time to
step down.
I think now when you did decide,
did you have a plan,
did you write out a plan,
like how to step down because he wrote
out a plan for the rest of your life?
No,
because it was,
it was like new.
Tara was like that,
you know,
it was like I didn't have a plan for the
injury.
Yeah,
vaguely.
I had an idea in my mind that I would
like to open more germs when I finished
bodybuilding.
I'm actually,
I didn't happen,
but um,
I started my own nutrition company which
is still doing sports nutrition during
unites a sports nutrition.
So,
um,
put a lot of energy into that and a
different things and being able to
experience things in life that I shut
myself off with.
So that's how I dealt with it and now I
feel I felt great about it and I kind of
look back and I can sit back and say,
you know what,
I couldn't give any more to that thing.
I couldn't have given any more.
So there's no regrets.
Like a lot of athletes,
you know when you're young and you're
there,
maybe you don't really appreciate it so
much and then when it's gone you're
like,
shit man,
what if I'd done this?
What if,
what if,
you know,
I don't have those.
What ifs?
Man,
I did 100 percent even too much to the
point where I got injured,
so I'm,
you know,
I'm happy with that.
I can put that to rest.
That's a great lesson.
That's a great lesson for young people
coming up.
If you just do all the work when it's
over,
it's so what you can do it man,
win or lose,
you do what you can do and then you have
the self satisfaction,
the pride to look back and say,
you know what,
I fucking give it everything I had and
no regrets.
And that's the way I feel about it.
And I know there's a lot of my
contemporaries that compete against me.
I don't really feel like that.
That's why a few of them are still there
in the fifties and the making comebacks.
That's one of the most horrible things
to see someone who's lived a life of
regret.
Yeah.
This has
just narrative and I don't like to see
athletes coming back when they're not as
you remember them at their best and
they're coming back and the not so good,
which I'm sorry,
but inevitably at 50 years old is going
to be the case.
Is there any body builders are doing
that now at 50?
Uh,
yeah.
Kevin Love Ron who came second to me and
Mr Olympia.
He made a comeback last year.
Really?
Yeah.
How do you look?
Uh,
well,
it depends how I answered that question.
How did,
how did it look compared to previously
not good at all?
How to look for a guy that's making a
comeback at 50 years old?
Yeah.
Great.
But it's not a 50 year old guy looking
good contest.
This Mr Olympia as well.
So,
um,
you know,
just tried to make it come back within a
year.
It doesn't take many,
many years to get to that kind of shape.
So I was the thing with bodybuilding,
you,
you've got a thing called muscle memory,
so maybe it took me 10 years to get to
be 260 pounds ripped,
but now that information is in my DNA.
It's there so I could theoretically not
trained for 10 years.
Lewis,
all that muscle,
I'm probably get that back in six to 12
months.
Really?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Well I've heard of muscle memory and I
know that it's a thing but it hasn't
been physically isolated.
What causes that or how it is in your
DNA?
I'm not really sure if they have or if
they're interested enough to do to the
studies that's necessary,
but those of us that are in the sport,
we know it happens.
I mean arnold did it like a 1974.
I think Arnold was gonna retire,
but then it got this pumping iron movie
that everyone's familiar with.
Um,
so the 1975 Mr Olympia,
which the pumping iron and runs around,
he basically made a comeback for that
just just for the movie.
And previous to that he did a movie
called stay hungry with Sally Field and
Jeff Bridges and I think he had to get
down to like 200,
200,
10 pounds because the director didn't
want them to be too big for that.
So he came off the back of that and they
just put all the sides back on for the
Mr Olympia for pumping it.
Really?
There's.
So the director made him sort of a
macy's himself.
Well,
he still looked pretty big,
I guess for the average person.
Yeah.
Oh Man.
That's nothing compared to how he looks.
But next to Jeff Bridges.
Yeah.
I mean he looks like a really big fit
guy that you'd see at the gym.
Look at Jeff Bridges.
The dude abides.
I liked to do.
I love that guy.
He's still around,
man.
Still banging out great movies and
talking about how many great movies that
guy's been in.
Absolutely.
What's the one where he's a country
singer.
That was great.
Oh,
like,
yeah.
Yeah.
That was recent.
God Damn it.
I saw that.
That was a good movie.
Yeah,
he,
he's,
he's good at choosing roles.
So when,
when a guy does get down to something
like that,
is it a matter of taking less steroids
working out last,
like your body just naturally starts to
shrink
pure.
Uh,
if you're taking steroids and you're
stopped and you're going to lose a lot
of weight pretty quick and maybe just
don't lift weights,
play tennis,
do swim into something else,
and your muscle mass,
it's going to go down.
So I'm guessing that's what it is.
Now.
When you first started bodybuilding,
how long did it take before you did take
something?
After about 18 months I decided I want
to do a contest and I knew the guys in
the contest.
We're taking stuff.
So I just want to be on a level playing
field with them.
Um,
so like two months before my first
contest in which take a little ballot,
Debo,
20 milligrams a day,
a day.
That was the first thing I ever had.
And then narrowed to the contest,
I switched to some Var and Prima Bolin,
but I mean 20 milligrams a day is like
fitness chicks take that.
No.
Do they do,
do take steroids,
right?
Means paying hundred percent,
100 percent,
even bikini chicks like skinny,
but because they want to look harder,
they went a leaner and it's uh,
you know,
I got girls that are fucking strippers
and all kinds of chicks asking me,
Oh,
I'm,
I want to take this [inaudible] stuff.
You,
you know,
anything about that.
I'm like,
I do to you.
Oh yeah.
The guy just told me it's gonna.
Make me lean.
And everything
said,
all right,
let me explain what this is.
This is an anabolic steroid and anabolic
steroid is a derivative of testosterone,
which is a male hormone.
So what they try to do is minimize the
androgenic part of the testosterone,
the male like and so you're left with
more of the anabolic,
the building part,
but they can't completely minimize the
androgenic part.
So even though stuff like winstrol Lavar
is less androgenic men,
testosterone is still derived from a
male hormone and if you take off,
you're still going to get the male side
effects,
which is pretty common in women's
bodybuilding and fitness and so on.
It's common in athletics across the
board.
We see it in mma.
We see it in women in MMA as well.
Look,
man,
if you're a competitive sport,
a competitive athlete,
you're going to do whatever you can do.
You know,
so when I'm.
There was a study was done by a guy
called Dr Goldman and it's called
Goldman's dilemma and he asked a bunch
of athletes.
I'm including the Olympic level
athletes,
so if I could give you a pill that would
guarantee you would win the gold medal
or whatever the equivalent is in your
sport,
but you would die at like 40,
45,
would you take it?
The vast majority of people said yes,
they would take it.
That's the mentality you're dealing
with,
especially when when you're young man.
Yeah.
You feel indestructable like nothing's
gonna,
you know?
Yeah.
It doesn't seem real to write.
It's like global warming will one day
make the seas rise.
Yeah,
but not right now.
So fire up the fucking.
Now I want to fucking gold medal.
That's all I'm interested
in.
I'm not even.
That doesn't even exist.
I'm here now on the fucking gold medal
and this is the mentality of the,
you know,
the successful athlete and you know,
maybe it applies to everything or maybe
it was a fucking businessman if you said
you take this pill and you'll fucking
make billions,
like would you do it,
you know,
driven businessman of probably say fuck
it,
I'll do it if it's a solution that allow
you to win.
Yeah.
So that's what I did.
I,
I consider that I did a calculated risk,
you know,
as far as taking steroids with the
possible negative health effects,
which I tried to monitor.
I had doctor's,
you know,
blood test and everything like that.
So if something was going wrong,
at least out of the,
you know,
did you ever find anything wrong?
Now,
some things were a little bit out of the
normal range when I was heavy and my
blood pressure went up,
like not sky high,
but it was,
you know,
40 over 90 1:50
over 90.
So it was,
was edging up there but it was 300
pounds.
So,
you know,
and um,
couple of other readings were a little
bit but nothing of great concern,
you know?
Um,
but that doesn't mean to say that the
harmless because it's over a period of
time.
Right.
And I equate it to smoking,
you know,
um,
if you smoke for 10 years and then you
stop apparently after 15 or 20 years,
you're back to like,
you know,
a guy that didn't smoke if you smoke for
20 years,
25 years,
and maybe it's a different story.
Have you ever seen Chris Bells
documentary bigger,
stronger,
faster?
I haven't,
no.
I'm,
I think I'm due to speak with those are
the brothers,
right?
Yeah.
Chris and I think I'll be going on the
podcast at one point,
but I actually haven't watched it.
No.
Great guys,
really great guys.
They both been on here a couple times
and very knowledgeable and Chris is a,
just did a great documentary called
prescription thugs to about the
prescription drug industry and you know,
getting people hooked on these pain
pills but in bigger,
stronger,
faster.
One of the things that was fascinating
about it was that he was going over,
like we were told that this is going to
kill.
You were told that all these health
negative health effects,
he's like,
but where's the bodies?
Where are the bodies like,
can you think about all the things that
kill people,
obesity,
crushes,
human beings.
I mean,
it is one of the number one causes of
death in America,
but yet it's looked at
like smoking alcohol,
prescription drugs.
Oh,
all those things.
All these things that have been some
deaths in bodybuilding,
um,
uh,
that may be attributed to steroids and
there's been a couple that definitely
attributed to diuretics,
which is,
you know,
diuretics,
you lose a lot of water,
you,
you can lose electrolytes,
potassium and sodium,
which regulates your heartbeat.
So then you're playing Russian roulette
with a bit on.
A couple of people played that game and
lost.
So
yeah,
that's an interesting thing to point out
because the diuretic aspect is,
is critical.
When you see someone on stage and you
see them shredded,
those guys are basically almost dead,
right?
I mean,
you know,
like probably the least healthiest
fucking point you've been all year is,
is when you're looking like that on the
stove.
Amazing.
You look amazing.
But I can tell you,
you know,
you feel weak as a kitten.
You don't feel real good at that point,
but you know,
you do whatever you got to do what's
required.
Um,
996 when I was competing,
they had actually a testing for
diuretics because there was a couple of
deaths and the people in charge started
getting concerned,
you know,
this doesn't look good and that affects
your revenue.
And so,
um,
they don't attempt.
They attempted steroid testing in 1990
but it affected the guys look so much
that,
you know,
once you've seen a guy like this,
so once you've seen a guy fight like
this or once you've seen a guy run this
fast,
nobody fucking wants to see anything
slower than that or less than that.
Right?
They want,
it's just not interested.
So they realize that real quick like
fuck list with just forget about the
steroid testing.
And anyway,
steroid testing is like,
it probably just makes it more unfair
because the guy that's got more
information and like the clearance times
and all that stuff,
they don't want to stop people from
taking it,
they're just going to take it and try to
avoid,
get round the test and it's the same in
all sports and I don't care if it's
fucking running,
riding Tour de France,
whatever it is,
it's going on to some degree.
What would the UFC has done and they've
self imposed.
This is,
they've hired Jeff Novitsky,
the guy who went after Lance Armstrong
and he's had to Usada and they just do
random tests on our ended.
The punishments are terrible,
like two year suspension.
I mean,
I think first time you get pop,
first time for steroids.
I think it's a two year suspension now
for the UFC.
And this is again,
this is self imposed.
It's not even in Nevada state athletic
commission or any other athletic
commissions in positions.
And uh,
they've radically cut back on the amount
of people that are first of all caught
in second of all doing steroids.
They're just not doing it,
but if you do real random testing you
around.
Yeah.
Then you have a better chance of
eliminating something.
It pisses athletes off because you
awaken these fighters up at 6:00
in the morning and they need the rest,
but they take the blood,
they take the urine,
see you go back to sleep and you know,
that way nobody can be safe and you've
seen a radical change and performances
and some athletes have.
People were suspecting of doing
steroids.
They changed the way they look like
there's so many pre and Post Usada
pictures of people that post them on
like twitter and facebook and stuff like
that where they,
you know,
in these groups where they talk about
fights and like who's.
You know what chaff cleats had been hurt
most by Usada.
Yeah.
It's like,
it's.
It's interesting because the more of the
bigger guys or it's across the board,
it's bigger guys,
but it's also epo,
like a lot of guys have been popped for
epo.
They've been popped for.
What does that other side?
Mel Melatonin.
There's another one,
God dammit,
I'm trying to remember it,
but it's a similar thing to epo,
EPO,
increase red blood cell count,
so you get more oxygen,
which would give you more endurance.
Yeah,
but that's,
I mean that's giant in the sport.
Yeah.
I mean physical size is not really that
much of a consideration is very few guys
that are really big and muscular.
Well here's the thing with steroids.
I mean that can give you muscle size but
it depends on your training,
but the training you're doing so it can
also help with their insurance.
So just because the guy is not big and
muscular doesn't mean there's not
benefit from steroids.
You get runners and cyclists and like
Lance Armstrong,
Armstrong is like,
you know,
he was on a pedestal and then is
demonized and is down here like let's
say the owner guy using a bit of
testosterone or you know.
No,
he was a,
you know,
Bill Burr was a good friend of mine and
stand up comedian had a hilarious bit
about it and he's like,
are psychopath was better than you're a
psychopath.
You got a dirty sport.
He's like,
we just have one psycho that was more
psycho.
You're psycho.
And uh,
he had testicular cancer,
right?
Yeah.
So I'm assuming then you're not
producing any testosterone,
so you've got to have to put it in from
outside.
How much?
I don't know.
Well,
they had it in the used to allow
testosterone replacement therapy for
fighters.
They don't allow that anymore because
guys are abusing it.
And also there was a questions of why
they were losing testosterone in the
first place and one of the thoughts was
damaged to pituitary gland because
that's apparently a big factor with
fighters.
Once they developed damage to the
pituitary gland from head trauma,
they start decreasing the amount of
testosterone in their body produces.
And so the thought was put it back in,
but other doctors are saying,
well maybe you shouldn't be competing
anymore.
Maybe put it back in for general health
and wellness,
but you probably shouldn't be competing
anymore if this is the way your body's
responding to head trauma.
Yeah.
And it shouldn't really need replacement
testosterone until you're like 40 or
thereabouts,
you know,
because it shouldn't be producing still.
And there's ways to up it,
right?
Even natural supplements to up it.
A despotic asset as long as,
what is d aspartic acid despotic I said
as a compound,
I think it's from amino acids,
but anyway,
they've done studies on it that shows
that it can raise your own natural
testosterone.
Some herbs,
Tribulus Terrestris also has some,
uh,
you know,
some studies to back that up.
Also exercise,
right?
Like high intensity exercise,
sprint,
certain kinds of squats.
So how much it's going to make a
difference.
I don't really know.
But yeah,
heavy,
heavy exercise would raise the
testosterone over normal baseline.
But once it gets to a certain age,
it starts declining.
In any case,
you know.
Now when you started taking stuff and
you started off with d ball,
what?
Like at the height,
what was the craziest amount of shit you
were taken?
The most stuff I took was in the off
season when I was trying to real heavy,
trying to build sized because I had to
raise him that used to get ready for
contests and I was always known for,
like really coming in in shape.
Um,
so I don't use so much stuff getting
ready for a contest you use more in the
off season,
so like a thousand milligrams of
testosterone a week.
Um,
some decker to rebel and maybe 500
milligrams and Debo maybe 40,
50 milligrams is average and growth
hormone in the off season I saw a lot of
shit.
It's probably about 30 percent of what
guys are taken now.
I think so based on what people are
telling me,
I mean I have people come to train with
me that haven't even done a competition,
let alone the Mr Olympia and they,
their stack is more than that because
they found it on the Internet.
I'm like,
what the fuck?
You know why I just saw it on the
internet somewhere.
This,
I mean you go on the Internet and have a
look for Dorian yates stack.
I mean I've been on there and it's,
I'm like,
first of all,
50 percent of this stuff,
I don't even know what it is.
Right?
So I don't even know what it is.
And the rest of the stuff that I do
recognize,
like if you take this,
you're going to get real health
problems.
So like is an issue,
right?
I mean instantly taken too much insulin
and you fucking kill over in a coma.
Um,
I tried incident in the last couple of
years.
I was competing because there's a few
guys started using it and so on.
And I don't feel that I've benefited
from it.
I got a bit bigger,
I got more bloated,
the conditioning was harder to get.
Um,
so for me,
I didn't feel I get any benefit from it.
You can get bigger,
but it's not the quality,
you know,
it wasn't.
I was known for like Super Hot,
grainy quality and I was,
I was losing a little bit of that.
He was an insulin.
So that's my opinion.
I wouldn't recommend,
I don't recommend it to people that are
trained with because it doesn't have any
real benefits and has,
has risks go why,
you know,
that's fascinating.
Like the quality,
like what constitutes the quality of
muscle that you looking for?
Well,
I,
I think,
uh,
in my case I was known for muscle
density so you could have a 20 inch arm
that's like got good volume.
We have 20 inch on the,
it looks like a fucking block of steel.
So how do you get that look how,
what's the difference?
I think the differences in the training
that I've trained very heavy and
primarily quite low reps compared to
bodybuilders.
I was working in six to eight,
six to eight,
a little bit high on the legs,
10 to 12,
whatever.
Everything I did was like six to eight
reps where most of the guys that do
intend to 12 and they relying more on
pumping,
just getting a lot of blood volume into
the muscle rather than overloading it.
Um,
so I had a density in a powerful look to
my physique that the other guys,
when they stood next to me,
uh,
they didn't have that.
And that was just from really heavy
training I think.
So you get the density of the muscle
rather than just pumping it volume one.
How did you figure out how to make that
number like six to eight,
like why not three to five,
like you know what I'm saying?
Like how did you arrive over over many
decades.
First of all,
people in the gym and also studies as
well.
Most studies would say for muscle growth
you need to keep the muscle under
tension from about a 40 to 60 seconds,
which in most cases would be eight to 12
reps,
so I went a bit lower like six to eight
a that worked really well for me,
but not on legs.
I went higher,
10 or 12 on on the legs.
So just a bit of trial and error.
We know I'm the lower reps will give you
more strength and more power without the
hypertrophy of the growth of the muscle.
So that's ideal for fighters.
I worked with a few fighters in the UK
and I tried to explain this to them and
it's hard for them to grasp because they
think I'm in the ring.
I'm doing a lot of,
you know,
I need insurance.
Yeah,
you do,
but you're already doing that.
You're already doing that,
right?
So if you want to get more power behind
the punch,
but you don't want to build muscle
because if you build muscle,
you put on weight and then you've got
the white category.
So whatever more power you got,
it's going to be negated by the fact
that you fight fighting heavier guys.
So if you could stay the same weight but
be more powerful and stronger with that
building muscle size,
uh,
that would be the key.
And that's basically like power lifting,
low reps,
three reps,
and then have a really long rest totally
foreign to mma training.
You're going to do a bom,
Bom,
bom,
put it back and wait for three or four
minutes.
Yeah,
do it again.
So you get that bar,
the power behind a punch,
but without rest,
but without increasing your muscle size,
you know,
because that would,
if you,
if you get more power behind your punch,
but you're going up a weight class,
like so what,
you know,
you want to stay in the same weight but
be stronger.
That would be ideal for a fighter.
So that seems counterintuitive for a lot
of people because they assume that
bigger muscles mean more power.
Not necessarily.
I mean,
bodybuilders have got a bigger muscles
and power lifters.
How lyft is going to lift more weight at
least for one or two reps,
you know?
Yeah.
They're training for that power boom.
Right.
Same thing with weightlifting is a
couple of reps,
but very explosive and powerful.
That's hard for people understand
kettlebells as well.
Like,
yeah,
throw it up,
you know?
Oh,
well that's the thing about kettlebell
competitors.
They'd not the biggest guys like they,
the internal musculature,
the call.
There's a lot of the lifting,
right?
Yeah.
You know,
uh,
if you're throwing a punch,
I mean who cares if you got huge biceps,
it's like the internal,
right?
It's terrible all the way up through the
call that's going to give you that
power.
So you've got to go.
He's like feed or I mean Elanco who?
I'm a huge fan of him.
I like his fighting style as well,
you know?
Uh,
I mean the guy looks like he's got arms
like sticks is it looks like he's got a
pot belly,
it looks out of shape,
but if I can hit like a baseball bat man
early in his career,
he was bigger.
Yeah.
You and he stopped training weights and
started training only sports specific,
which is,
it's a very controversial subject
because if you talked to modern strength
and conditioning coaches,
they said it's absolutely the wrong
approach.
And if a door continued to do strength
and conditioning along with his martial
arts training,
he probably would have been able to
prolong his career.
But who the fuck knows if that's true?
That seems like a very,
it's very hard to say what would have
happened,
but the modern approach seems to be,
do you have to consider strength and
conditioning as a huge part of any
regimen in terms of like some of the
elite athletes focus primarily on
strength and conditioning and camp and
not really unskilled work because they
feel like they already know how to fight
as well.
It's already the conditioning.
It's all about,
um,
I mean as far as the,
you know,
the conditioning of their emotions and
their ability to react is already there.
It's just a matter of building the
ultimate gas tank and having the body
that can perform and react as quickly
and as fast and recover as fast as
possible.
Well,
they've got the guys that hit the
hottest that not necessarily the most
muscular though,
that's
some of them are like tyron Woodley,
who's the UFC welterweight champion.
He's one rare guy that kind of violates
the normal build of a professional mma
athletes because he's fucking jacked.
But he's also,
he's also very smart in his approach.
Whereas like he's the consequences of
engaging with him or extreme because he
has tremendous power so he can pace
himself more than like maybe some guys
can because if you get in a firefight
with him,
like one shot from him put the lights
out on you.
So he's got this ability to.
And he's developed a very,
very interesting way of fighting where
he just paces his bursts.
But it's bursts are so terrifying.
Like when he comes at you,
when he can,
when he does sprint your way so much
faster than the average fighter and so
much stronger that I guess in his mind
having all that muscle and he says it's
actually natural.
He just said he and his son.
Is it genetic?
Yeah.
My son is doing bodybuilding and uh,
you don't have a particularly good a
fried chicken and burgers and stuff and
his like shredded all the time.
It will.
Tyron son is jacked and he's a little
kid and he's parked on genetics are
real.
There's no denying.
It's like me.
When I started I had already a physique,
had the ABS,
I was laying,
I had the shape.
Everything was there.
Just that to get bigger.
So jeans are a big thing as far as your
body type.
Oh,
is it insurmountable?
Like if a guy has shit genes,
can he become like a jack?
No,
no,
no.
Whoa.
It can get better.
Get better.
But you can't be Lee Haney.
It's a rare individual that you know,
couldn't get up.
And the Mr Olympia stage is probably
hundreds of thousands,
maybe millions of guys around the world
that in the gym training and maybe it
would like to compete.
Um,
what do you know,
Kinda kinda everybody be a UFC champion.
Can everybody be a basketball player?
I know you need certain tools to start
with and then you've got to work on that
and build that.
But at least for,
for athletes and fighters in particular,
you see guys who don't have impressive
physiques had,
have incredible records and wound up
doing really well with their skill and
their tactics and their mindset and
their understanding of when to engage,
when not to engage with bodybuilding
dough.
It's a very specific look if you are
born with like slope,
shoulders and small hands and
you're fucked,
right?
You need to,
first of all,
you need the frame,
the frame.
You can't,
it's the bone structure.
You can't do anything about that with,
with the training,
right?
So you need a relatively wide shoulders
to smaller hips.
You need the limbs to be proportional
for bodybuilding.
Um,
most of the successful guys that tend to
have a little bit longer legs compared
to the torso because it just looks more
authentic and makes the upper body
looked more like that.
So that's a bone structure.
You can't do anything about it that you
need to be born with a bone structure.
Um,
and then you've got muscle bellies,
so you got the length of the muscle
belly,
which is genetic.
So if you've got a short bicep,
you know,
used to tell you I'll go to the gym and
do preacher calls and we get along.
No,
you have your muscle attachments are
genetic.
So the longer your muscle bellies are,
the more potential they have for volume.
So somebody that's got uniformly long
muscle bellies with a good frame and a
good metabolism that tends to have
naturally low body fat.
Then you're looking at somebody with
potential to be a good competitive
bodybuilder.
If they don't have all those things,
everyone can improve.
But are you going to go win contests?
No.
Have you ever had a guy come to you and
said,
and I want to be a champion,
and you like kid,
you're fucked.
Yeah.
Damn.
I mean,
why?
You know,
Dorian Yates tells you you're fucked.
I don't say I try to be a little bit
more subtle than that,
but uh,
I'm like,
you know,
I don't,
I'm not here to bullshit anybody.
So if somebody asks me,
I'm just going to tell him like,
yeah,
you can improve man.
But like,
you know,
you're just going to waste your time if
you're driven by a Mr Olympia because,
you know,
I don't be rude,
but you just,
you just don't have what it takes.
Like enjoy your training.
Shouldn't be healthy.
You have fun in the gym.
But yeah,
forgot about that because it's not going
to happen.
That's hard for people to hear though,
but it's better than me blowing smoke up
their ass and saying,
yeah,
Oh yeah,
you know,
yeah,
pay me.
And Yeah,
you can be.
You can have whatever you want,
man,
because somebody else is going to tell
him that.
Have you seen a guy that you thought,
man,
I don't think so,
and then he became a great bodybuilder?
No,
no,
no.
Jesus Christ.
I can pretty much.
I mean I've been around like,
you know,
what,
a 35 years I've been in this guy man,
so I can see people and I've seen people
probably with more potential than me.
Well they don't get anywhere because
they don't apply.
So it's,
you know,
you've got to have the physical stuff,
but the glue,
the thing that holds it all together is
this.
So I've seen freaks in a gym,
but they,
you know,
first of all,
they're not that smart.
They don't really understand everything
that's going on.
Um,
and usually when somebody gets something
real easy,
they're not,
they're not really that hungry.
Right?
So it's not necessarily always the guy
with the most potential that,
you know,
you can beat somebody with more
potential by being smarter and working
hard,
but it's,
you know,
72 degrees,
right?
Yeah.
That's what I've always said that like
you can get a guy who's the most
dedicated,
the most hungry wanted the most,
but when you're competing in basketball
against Michael Jordan,
yeah,
you're kind of fucked because he wants
it bad too and his genetics are just so
superior.
There's just no way around.
So you can't equalize that.
Well,
what are you going to do?
You know,
I saw this thing in England recently.
Guy came over from the states,
the real,
I don't know what his name was,
but it was a good martial arts.
It was a kickbox.
He was dedicated.
It was lean and fit,
and it came over to fight this gypsy
fight or over in England and this guy's
like fat out of shape.
He turned up like 45 minutes late for
the flight because it had been drunk the
night before and he came in and it's
just fat and it looked like shit and an
for like half an hour.
He's getting his ass kicked.
Well,
they're not thinking,
oh,
he woke up and it kicked the other guy's
s.
So this guy has been training,
has been dedicated as he's doing all
this stuff and this guy is the night
before is getting drunk,
but he still come in and kick the guy's
us.
So you know,
it probably just had more potential or
he had a hot head or something.
I don't know.
There's a lot of factors involved in
fighting.
I mean his experience,
his ability to take punishment that some
of it is just inherent.
Like some people just have a like a
wider face,
stronger neck.
They can take a shot better.
Yeah.
There's oral genetic characteristics,
right?
The ability to absorb punches,
it seems to be,
or at least the variables seem to be a
lot of it based on maybe you've got sick
of bones or a shorter neck so your brain
doesn't rattle as much or something.
Mark is a perfect example.
That is one of the best kick boxers of
all time.
And from New Zealand just to tank of a
man,
you know,
five foot 10,
265 pounds just built like a brick
shithouse oh dude.
Cro.
Cop had kicked him and he went down and
got right back up.
It's like nobody does a cro.
Cop had cakes you.
That's a wrap,
you know,
and he's one of the few guys that
survived it.
Well,
I got a my friend,
my business partner from New Zealand,
I don't know if it's true,
but he told me about Malcolm is I've got
a brother and the dad used to get them
in the back yard there and just like
knock the shit out of each other until
they're like immune to getting hit.
Yeah.
I don't feel it anymore.
Well,
he's been knocked out a few times
recently like,
but you know,
he's in his forties now.
It isn't it the case with fighters?
I don't know.
I noticed that.
Anyway,
you get a guy that's like seems to be
invincible,
then it gets knocked out and then after
that he it like
chocolate down for instance.
Perfect example.
Yeah.
Unquestioned.
What is that?
Well,
your brain does not want to take that
kind of punishment anymore.
And with Chuck explained to me was that
when it gets to a point where your brain
realizes that you're too tough and
you're just going to absorb this
punishment and it just shuts itself down
to protect it.
And that's how he described it now.
And obviously that's not like a
neuroscientist describing it.
There's also the connective tissue that
keeps the brain connected and inside
that it gets looser and more torn.
Have you ever seen connective tissue?
It's almost like a,
like a strong version of cotton candy
is.
It looks like it's not.
It's not the toughest stuff in the world
and it's not supposed to take that many
beatings in the wild.
If you had that many beatings over a
certain point that you'd be dead
already,
somebody would've already eaten you.
But a MMA seems to be safer than boxing
because you don't hit as many times
sorta.
Yeah,
I would say probably overall safer.
But that's like saying motorcycle racing
is safer than like going down hill and a
skateboard 60 miles an hour.
You're kind of fucked all relative,
right?
Yeah.
It's like the study that they did that
just came out this week on football
players would show they did.
They,
they did a test on 111 fighters are 111
football players.
One hundred and 10 had traumatic brain
injuries.
I saw the movie account numbers called
now with the brain damage was causing
the guys to be violent and kind of
stuff.
I mean,
they were saying that 87 percent of
football players at all levels,
high school,
college,
all,
all levels have traumatic brain injury.
80 seven percent of what you're going to
do stop exact club football and stuff.
MMA like that's the question.
Climb Kleiman like,
you know,
everything's got its uh,
its risks,
right?
Every,
every sport,
unless you do it like,
you know,
moderately.
If you do things in moderation that good
but could never be dorian yates in
moderation,
competitive sports or not,
you know,
they're not the healthiest thing in the
world right now.
No,
I mean,
you're dealing.
Well,
I mean,
I guess there's injuries involved in
basketball,
right?
But you know,
you're not,
you're going to lose your ability to
think.
But uh,
even like endurance sports,
a marathon run and stuff like that,
these guys die younger than incidental
person.
Yeah.
Because of the massive amount of free
radicals that are producing,
which is aging the cells from massive
free radical from all this oxygen like
uh,
so you know,
you,
your agent,
if Salads,
you're wearing yourself out doing all
this interference sports.
Um,
I think what's going to come out in the
future,
and I've been doing this myself and
getting great results is very short
interval training now they've done
studies with five minutes of cardio
workout and it's getting the same
results as an hour.
Well that's,
yeah,
I do 10 minutes.
I do what I do a 90 seconds,
like,
you know,
moderate.
Then I do a 32nd all out sprint,
whether it's on a cross trainer or a
rower or kettle bells or whatever,
get the heart rate right up,
like one 60 or something.
And then go back down to do that a few
times,
like 10 or 12 minutes.
And my resting heart rate was pretty
good for a bodybuilder.
I guess it was like 50 4:55
in the morning.
I had it down to like low forties,
45 in the morning and that's just from
doing a couple of times a week or 10
minute workout and once a week I do a
hard bike ride,
but yeah,
absolutely because you want to get the.
You want to get the benefits from the
cardio exercise,
which is a more efficient cardiovascular
system,
but you don't want the negatives for
that free radical.
So if you can get what you're looking
for in a 10 minute workout,
what are you going to do?
An hour or two hours.
I don't know if it would be useful for a
fighter because you're going to be in a
ring for all that long,
so you've got to condition yourself with
that.
Just talking about for,
for general health.
Wow.
I've never even heard of such a thing.
Yeah.
Interval training,
but 10 minutes,
10 minutes.
They've done studies on the four and
five minute workout.
So that's.
I think that's the future where you
know,
you want to get the benefit without the
negatives.
Do you think you could run a marathon
right now?
Could I run a marathon?
No.
No,
I running is not.
Not For me now.
Well not definitely not for you.
When you're in your prime fast walking.
That's good.
When you were in your prime,
how much endurance did you have?
Like if you had to do something,
if you had to go up a flight of stairs.
We like to
bad because I always did some cardio.
I did some cardio and stretching and so
it was a bit unusual for,
for bodybuilders because that doesn't
give you bigger muscles,
but I saw the other benefits of it
because if I got more efficient cardio,
like I'm training legs and back,
stuff like that.
That's a huge amount of oxygen and you
got to failure on squats or leg presses,
you know,
that's a huge amount of oxygen.
So for me to recover from that,
I needed a bit of a cardio so I was
doing three or four times a week off
season every day getting ready for a
contest,
but it wasn't very intense.
It was more like moderate.
I did like fast walking for an hour or
do stationary bike for 45 minutes,
sometimes twice a day.
So I was doing quite a lot of cardio
work,
getting ready for a contest rather than
starving myself.
Oh,
I see.
I was bringing the calories down a
little bit and bring the activity of a
little bit.
So it was a bit of both.
A bit of calorie restriction,
a bit of more activity,
more calorie burning
now when you do in calorie restriction,
but you also have to keep all that mass.
How did you contradictory goals?
Yeah,
uh,
you know,
training we can debate because I trained
with some mma guys in England,
a bit of Jujitsu,
but mainly conditioning stuff and it's
fucking hard man.
It's hard training,
right?
He's just a super hard cardio and then
someone's trying to punch you in the
face at the same time.
That's hard.
So we can debate about the training.
Which sport is harder?
Yeah,
because I've done a little bit of both.
Um,
but what's harder and bodybuilding is
when you leave the gym,
it's still with you and when you're
getting ready for a contest,
you're going to do more training and
you're going to eat less.
So most sports,
if you try,
you can go train hard and then you can
go home and eat with bodybuilding,
you know,
two months before a contest,
you,
you're hungry all the time because
you're trying to lose,
slowly lose the body fat and maintain
muscle.
If you're trying to lose weight too
quickly,
your body will preferentially burn a
muscle because it's like,
what is an emergency store,
right?
Your body doesn't want to give it up.
So you've got to like coax it out
slowly,
you know?
Um,
but yeah,
you're going to be hungry and you're
gonna be tired for a couple of months
ago for a,
for a contest that isn't selling fun is
not fun,
man.
It's,
it's a constant mental battle as well
because your body's telling you to eat,
you gotta eat,
you gotta eat and at night you can't
sleep properly because you got to sleep
a little bit.
And then your body's like,
internal alarm clock will wake you up if
I can stop and go eat and you're like,
nope,
I ain't doing that.
But how do you keep your body from
absorbing all that muscle because you're
carrying so much muscle?
Is there a drug that you can take that
keeps the mass?
Well,
you know you're taking steroids which
are anti,
which are anabolic and anti catabolic.
So that's going to stop you from losing
muscle.
However,
you know,
if you restrict your calories too much
or too much exercise and none of it,
you still going to burn muscle is just
going to lower the chances of it.
So you know,
you've got to stack everything in your
favor.
You've taken steroids is,
you know,
try to keep the muscle mass and stop
losing it.
But if you do restrict too much,
you're going to,
you're still gonna lose it.
So you need to like one or two pounds a
week very slowly.
Your body from going into the shock.
Yeah.
That's where a lot of fighters go wrong
because they're starved themselves for a
couple of weeks and lose muscle.
The Lou strength,
I lose glasses in front of muscle and
you know they're weaker.
Yeah,
they fight very weak.
That's,
that's a huge issue and a lot of
fighters are choosing to go up a weight
class and they're having big success.
Donald cerrone's,
great example that it's been quite a few
fighters.
Oh,
you lose it.
You lose that weight very slowly.
Not Depleting it down.
Know what kind of diet where you want
when you were competing
for a high protein,
high protein,
a off season.
There's still a lot of cops,
major and fat and then getting ready for
a contest.
The cops slowly come down,
but I was a big guy to 70 to 80.
I was still eating probably 3,500
calories a day,
which is probably more than eight now.
But you know when you're that big you,
you're starving
because what do you weigh now?
A way now to 30,
something like that.
So yeah,
all that extra mass needed to be fueled.
Yeah,
exactly.
Now what,
when you were in say like out of contest
now,
what your goals were to put on muscle
that you would eventually
like you would get bigger and bigger
every year.
That was one of the things it
so yeah,
and then maybe there's certain areas
where you want to like work on at some
point that's a bit behind so you put
more focus on that and a bit less on
something else to try and keep the
balance.
Uh,
it might sound strange now,
but when I first competed a,
my first contest I lost to a guy called
Mohammed bin Aziza and his back was just
like freaky thick.
It was like three d coming out and that
just stuck in my mind.
I'm like,
fuck that.
I got to,
I put a picture of him on my fridge at
home.
I put a picture in the gym and a funny
enough,
later on in my career I became known for
the guy with the best back kind of
thing.
So,
um,
yeah,
it was inspired by other people to do
that.
So I worked on the back for a couple of
years.
What is the difference between the way
you approach nutrition when you were
competing versus the way people do it
today?
Because so much changes in nutrition.
I mean it seems like every five or six
years like,
oh nope.
Low fats out now you go high fat,
high carbs around,
now you go low carbs and it could change
back and forth again.
I think the seven is like Arnold area,
Frank Zane,
they'd go more low carbs getting ready
for a contest,
but then you lose sizemore quickly.
Um,
why do you lose sizemore quicker that
way because you get caught that ball do,
you haven't got the energy.
So you know,
your body can use the amino acid from
muscle for energy.
So there's a balance there.
And also you lose the glycogen storage.
It muscle is a 70 percent water and the
water holds um,
carbohydrates and the muscle glycogen.
So you lose that as well.
So you lose that bit of volume when you
lose the glycerin,
you lose the water.
So shrink down a little bit.
Um,
so my approach was more,
it was high,
higher carbohydrates,
especially in the off season,
getting ready for a contest to cut them
down,
but not,
you know,
not zero and a fairly low fat.
I think people now realize that fats
more important and there's probably more
fat in the Diet than there was back
then,
uh,
which,
which I think is healthy fats just got a
bad rap and it's bullshit,
you know.
Well,
that's,
um,
we've talked about that several times in
the podcast,
but there was a New York Times article
recently about how the sugar industry
paid off scientists to fake results.
And that was done in the,
I get the fifties or sixties and that's
haunted people to this day.
They think that fats are bad for you.
They're essential.
I may be wrong with the organization,
but I think it was World Health
Organization.
They,
uh,
basically submitted a study that showed
how bad sugar was and some department of
the US government,
which is getting a lot of money from the
sugar lobby basically said,
I think you want to reconsider this,
you know,
kind of like.
So that's where the whole fats are bad,
you know,
low fat came from.
I know back then how bad sugar is.
So I found it amusing when I first came
to the states in 1990 got all these low
fat products.
I've called my friends at homeland.
How fucked up this is,
man.
They got low fat muffins.
Of course the fucking low fat.
They're full of sugar,
no fat,
low fat yogurt,
low fat muffins.
It's fucking full of sugar.
It's the worst thing you could have,
you know.
So people thought they were being
healthy but they've been misled and it
makes you fat.
Yeah.
Nothing wrong with fats as long as their
natural,
you know,
if you get the fats in baked goods and
all this shit,
you know that that's not good,
but natural fats in animal products and
coconuts and all that stuff,
it's great.
Now what would you use for
carbohydrates?
So you.
Did you have a preferred method or did
you
complex stuff like a oatmeal was a big
thing.
He was an oatmeal brown rice,
sweet potatoes and some fruit and fiber,
vegetables.
Those are the main things that I use.
Basic,
nothing fancy,
you know,
did you mix your portions up and like a
little tupperware boxes or something
like that so that you could know exactly
what to eat.
I used to weigh my food like pretty much
all the time other than nate and
restaurants.
Very rarely and yeah,
I used to pack them up in boxes because
you know,
you've got to have it all the time.
Right?
Yeah.
So that was one of the things I did Miss
Miss Mountain so relieved and I carried
on a fucking plastic boxes around with
food and just go to a restaurant and eat
whatever I want and have an ice cream if
you will do.
Exactly.
That must've been nice when you realize
you could just just eat.
Yeah,
I'm off season wasn't too bad because
I'm eaten good food,
but a lot of it.
But yeah,
getting ready for a contest.
I mean that was a real mental test,
you know,
because your whole body is telling you
you got to eat man.
Even at night I said,
you wake up,
you got to eat.
No,
no.
And I'm going to eat and when to watch
MTV for half an hour from maybe fall
back to sleep a little bit,
hopefully,
you know.
Um,
so yeah,
the Diet thing,
I don't miss that at all.
It was,
it was a tough mental challenge and I
did it.
And you know,
whenever you get through a challenge I
think it makes you stronger.
But uh,
you know,
I don't want to ever do that again.
Yeah.
I can only imagine
now when you give these seminars and he
talks to these,
uh,
young bodybuilders that are coming up,
how do you be.
You kind of have sort of a holistic
approach to life down there just about
health and wellness and.
But when you were coaching,
these kids are talking to these kids
about how to be successful and
competitive body is a multiple time.
Mr Olympia one of the greatest of all
time,
if not the greatest.
You mean you can't have a holistic
approach?
Kenya,
you
to me for bodybuilding advice,
and I don't have the body now
necessarily,
but I got all the information here that
I can put across to people for the
training for the nutrition,
but it's called specific,
you know,
you want to be a competitive
bodybuilder.
This is what you got to do.
I'm not a competitive bodybuilder now.
My Diet and
my training is geared towards what my
goals are,
which is functionality,
a health and wellbeing.
And that's,
that's what I'm into now.
That's where I'm at.
I'm not a bodybuilder anymore,
you know,
and buddy reduce or if anything and um,
I,
I feel good man.
I'll fucking get a suit from Hugo boss a
couple of months ago off the rack and
this was like so happy I could just buy
a suit off the rack before it had to
have it made and if it go for a fitting
and go for another fitting all that.
I'm sure if they looked at the
measurements of paper,
they were like,
what the flight suit suited for?
What is this,
you know,
was like this wide going down,
this is a wardrobe.
What is it,
you know,
so uh,
yeah,
I look on the other side of it,
you know,
the young guys coming up,
maybe they think less strange like,
and asked me don't you dare look at
pitches back and think wow,
look like that.
I'm like,
no,
I don't look at.
I just look at that and I think wow,
that was fucking extreme and what I did.
And that's craziness and credible,
but does it always you as far as
competition and let yourself like that.
Sometimes when I look at those black and
white pictures,
giant picture of Dorian Yates and is one
of those black and white pictures man.
And that's just like hear you saying,
there it is.
Look at that.
That's insane man.
He couldn't really fit any more muscle
onto that frame really.
You know,
like I know I went to places and I did
things that other people,
you know in the gym,
look at your fucking forearms while my,
here's the thing,
forums.
I never did any training for forums.
All that was just from gripping the ball
when I was doing back training mainly
and some bicep training and stuff.
So I had 19 inch forums and identity to
a single fucking exercise for them apart
from gripping onto that is so
ridiculous.
Well that's a good pitcher but is not
me.
I don't know how dare you Jamie,
pull up a non Dorian because somebody
put it on Google.
Put up that winches.
Keep going to your right.
No,
no,
no.
Down what you were.
Yeah.
To right.
One more.
That one.
Bam.
So I trust it.
That's from the onstage pitcher from Mr
Olympia.
So what you can see,
if you look on the legs,
you can see the thinness of the skin and
the institute with the muscle underneath
like this.
No fat.
There's no water between the skin layer
and the and the muscle layer.
Um,
what body,
but what percent of body fat did you get
down to?
Well,
I don't really know because I had
skinfold calipers used to do full
calipers.
And you're not accurate.
They used to get down to like three
point five,
probably like a month out.
But I know I got leaner after that,
but it didn't really register because
they're not that accurate after that
point.
So I don't know,
maybe three percent,
but it's,
you know,
nobody measures your body fat is what
you look like.
It's a visual thing.
It's really what you look like in the
mirror.
But how did you know like how much water
to drink and when to back off and um,
experience.
I didn't really,
uh,
your fucking legs,
dude.
I didn't restrict a water intake until
like maybe 24 hours before the contest.
Little your right leg there.
That's preposterous.
Yeah,
that's a huge media.
Alice right over the knee.
The,
that's a lot of sick work,
man.
That's like,
that's like I used to try and legs
pretty much once a week and for four or
five days of every week I had trouble
sitting on the toilet.
Trouble moving around.
I mean if I didn't,
I wouldn't be happy,
man.
That's a field that fucking pain,
pain in the ass,
pain in the leg just to sit down.
But hey,
satisfying because you know,
you fucking done some damage.
But if it's like that and the damage
repairs itself to get slightly bigger
and stronger bodybuilders,
just an adaptation to stress,
you know,
you put a certain stress,
your body's going to adapt to it.
Fuck,
I need to get bigger and stronger so I
can handle this stress next time.
That's basically what it is.
So continually trying to stress yourself
like anything you want to get better.
Katia,
go to express your cardio system so it
adapts.
Yeah.
There's no other way,
right?
To get that big.
I mean there's no shortcuts.
There's nothing you can do.
There's no easy route.
Well,
I don't know.
It looks like guys are looking for the
easy route now because I don't see them
train that hard.
But then you don't see the quality of
their physiques the guys a big now.
But you look at the quality is not the
same.
It's not the same.
Not the same.
Can you just generally accepted in
bodybuilding in the nineties was the
peak of competitive physiques as far as
the standard and the depth of the
standard.
There was like six to eight guys on that
stage that were like really,
like if you are off,
you know,
there's places could change.
Now you've got one guy,
Phil,
Phil Heath,
who was the Mr Olympia and it's pretty
like distance between him and the next
few guys.
Now what is it though that it doesn't
open the door for a current modern day?
Dorian Yates,
like some super dedicated person.
Me physiologically,
people can still do the same things that
you did.
Yeah.
But um,
things have changed since the nineties.
There's a lot more avenues that people
could choose to go down.
I was like doing a sport or in,
for instance,
UFC that doesn't exist in the early
nineties.
I remember watching the first show on a.
It was in New York.
I watched on TV the first,
the very first one,
you know,
with,
uh,
always crazy.
So you've got,
you've got mma,
you've got crossfit and it got all these
other competitions now in the,
in the bodybuilding arena,
that's not bodybuilding.
It's men's physique,
whether we're the board shorts and they
got the nice physique and abdominals,
that kind of physique that most people
aspire to have.
I guess.
A,
you've got classic bodybuilding,
so got a lot of different avenues and I
think the interest in pure bodybuilding
is a lot less than I made in the
nineties.
Everyone wanted to be a bodybuilder.
It was like hugely popular.
Yeah.
What's interesting now,
what is this Jamie?
What do you pull it up here?
This a Mr Olympia from
996 is myself,
Sean Ray in the middle and that's one of
Coleman on the end who became a an eight
time Mr Olympia
guys are on Jack also.
It's so hard to tell them like,
I'm looking at this.
I'm like,
fuck,
I'll call the guy on the end is the
best.
Well,
it's also got to be hard for that tiny
dude that's next to you decided to do
it.
It's always been unhappy because it got
been by me,
but a thing as he had a great physique,
just like frank.
Zane had a great physique,
you know,
if he was the same size as arnold,
maybe it would have beat him,
but he wasn't in the same size as
arnold.
And same goes with a gentleman up there.
Mr Shawn Ray.
He had a great physique,
but you know,
I was twice as big.
So big guy always beats a good little
guy,
right?
Yeah.
It's a crazy sport man.
Now what about the top guys today?
Like you said,
Sean Heath is the number one guy to
them.
Phil.
Hey,
I'm sorry.
Now there's so many different avenues
now and a lot of them,
a lot of people are going towards like
the Internet route because you can make
a lot of money as like a,
an internet like famous person for being
a bodybuilder.
Then you selling things and selling.
There he is.
Phil Heath pretty jacked.
Yep.
Phil Heath is,
you know,
is not very wide in the shoulders,
a weak point,
but has got huge,
um,
long muscle bellies on the most of his
body as his pecs are not great,
but the rest,
you know,
the rest is a,
it doesn't really have any weak points,
so that's why he's is ahead of everybody
else and you just think there's just
less people doing it now.
There's less
people go into to competitive
bodybuilder because there's a lot more
avenues and I think it's less popular
now because it's almost like peeked out
with myself and run in and gone down a
little bit.
It's like,
how do you know,
how do you surpass it?
Got to a peak and guys are trying to do
that so that they,
you know,
that they're trying to get big and
they're getting big,
but they're getting big with a big waste
and everything as well.
So it's not the same.
It's not the same look as not the same
quality.
That's got to be super dangerous,
isn't it?
When you see those guys,
those are enormous bloated bellies.
That's a huge debate.
And the like,
what is that?
What is it?
I don't know,
internal organs that are
initially,
uh,
that's what people thought,
right?
And um,
I,
my wife started getting little bloated
around 96,
97,
maybe [inaudible] 97 when I was using
insulin.
Right.
You got a little bloated and load
standard.
Um,
but when I retired it went down and I
actually in England because I was always
like,
oh,
I'm taking steroids for this sport
because I'm a professional when I'm not
competing,
I'm not going to take them.
So stop taking them.
And also I took growth hormone and that
was the thing.
A lot of people think hormone is going
to increase the size of internal organs
and that's why guys are getting bloated
waistline.
Uh,
so I went and had a real,
I mean a battery of tests where they
actually measure all your internal
organs and mine all totally normal.
Apart from my heart was a bit bigger and
stronger,
but that's just normal athletic hot.
Uh,
so that wasn't the case.
So I perhaps it's,
I'm a fat this building up around the
internal organs or maybe it's just a lot
of water in the intestines and it just
blows to the waste out of the short
answer is the short answer is I don't
really know who's that guy in the far
left a.
that's like a turtle shell.
There's not really a turtle shell.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
So that could be insulin.
That can be.
We only seen this kind of thing
happening since the guys are using
insulin and igf,
which is insulin like growth factor.
Wow.
Um,
so yeah,
it's not a good look.
It's not a,
you know,
a turtle show.
Look,
it's so weird.
It literally looks like.
So it's like the guys that got big but
everywhere systemic,
like growth,
you know,
when you're training with weights,
your major muscles are going to grow but
not around the waist can thicken a
little bit but not that much.
Now when you got off of everything,
when you retired,
what was the crash like?
Well,
it wasn't something I was ready for.
I had a lot of things going in my life.
I had a divorce,
I had a,
somebody close to me pass away and um,
you know,
retiring,
so you know,
they say a death in the family or
divorce or retirement is like a major
stressful event or how about an old
fucking three at the same time while
you're not while you're coming down from
steroids.
So yeah,
I definitely suffered from depression
and anxiety.
Like I don't know what's going on,
like why do I feel like this?
I didn't even like now I know,
right?
Because you fucking stopped cold Turkey
because I'm extreme unlike I'm using
them because I'm doing this.
I'm stopped now and stop and I had no
real help.
There was no real like this guy is now
and especially in the states that,
you know,
they specialized in patients that are
using steroids and all the possible side
effects and coming off and all that
stuff.
I didn't really have any of that.
So I just went cold Turkey and after
about two years my normal testosterone
was still not coming into the normal.
So then I went on the replacement
therapy,
which is like twice a month,
a testosterone replacement,
and then I felt normal again.
So the,
the come down like you,
you're taking this work.
What were you taking like right before
he stopped,
like what was the,
do you remember?
Probably about a thousand milligrams a
week total of testosterone,
a total of every.
All kinds of stuff.
Deep on everything.
But if testosterone but have a deck or
something like that and then
then stop and then,
you know,
was it a gradual effect where your
body's freaking out or was it like
almost instantaneous?
Um,
it was probably after a few months I
started like noticing I wasn't feeling
too good,
funnily enough,
like sex drive didn't totally disappear
and actually had my daughter was
conceived while I was not on anything.
So I think they did trials with
testosterone as a male contraceptive and
it was moderately effective but not
enough that they would market it.
So,
um,
yeah,
probably like six to nine months it was
really not,
not feeling good at all.
And you know,
there's a lot of factors there.
If I was still taking steroids,
but those things happened in my life
would have felt as bad,
I don't know,
probably not,
but there were definitely a lot of
traumatic stuff going on at the same
time.
Now,
was there any conventional wisdom in the
bodybuilding community of how to slowly
cycle off or what the factors would be
and how you could mitigate them?
Not at that time now.
Twenty years on.
I mean,
you can go on the Internet and find a
ton of information,
but,
but not really.
Then the only thing is guys were using
was atg,
which is like helps to Cheryl and
testosterone.
Clomid,
clomid and some natural stuff like that.
Um,
I remember going to an endocrinologist
and asking him like,
you know,
what she'll do is she'll do acg and this
and that,
and he's like,
look at me.
And he said,
you know what,
Dorian,
you probably know more than me about
this.
Thanks for that.
Now you know,
he's talking about this situation and
somebody coming off steroids,
he didn't know.
He didn't have a clue,
man.
Right.
It's a different thing,
but now you've got guys out there,
they'd have a whole.
I did a seminar and I'm in Canada and
Ben Johnson was there,
actually the guy that Olympic gold
medalist for awhile,
he was there with his doctor and has a
couple of other doctors there and one of
the doctors told me that absolutely
every guy that was in the hundred meters
race tested positive every guy.
Um,
but I think it was CBS was covering the
contest and they're like,
we can't fucking,
you know,
kind of have every guy like,
yeah,
you've got to choose one and make sure
he's not American.
Really.
That's the story they told me and I
believe that man,
there's definitely some real good
evidence that they're all doing
something
goat.
I felt felt bad for him and he was like,
fucking demonized.
I remember all the newspapers.
I remember my son went to school and
they did a whole thing at school about,
you know,
and it came home.
He must have fucking known.
His Dad was jacked up.
Like,
like,
uh,
the guy was cheating and you shouldn't
do that and all this stuff.
They told him at school and I was like,
alright,
so not explained to you when you have
it,
and he also had no recourse like Lance
Armstrong today as a podcast.
He's done a bunch of interviews.
He can tell his story and now you know,
I mean I think there was a period of
time where lance was demonized,
but over time that is greatly subsided
and people now recognize,
no,
he literally was in a sport where
everyone was cheating.
But is that cheating?
Well,
if everyone's doing it,
is it cheaper?
Then the real issue I think was
deception and lawsuits and saying that
he didn't do it in suing people who said
he did and there was a lot of stuff that
wasn't exactly the smartest thing to do,
but you're dealing with a cornered
person who's a super competitive alpha
male trying to figure his way out of
this mess that he's found himself in and
this mass that exists systematically or
systemically in this entire industry.
The entire sport that he's involved.
Yeah,
I remember the um,
there was a car that got stopped in the
board or a few years ago and the Tour de
France is going,
you know,
France to someone across the border
anyway,
and it was a team call,
right.
And they stopped the team car and it was
just full of apo and steroids and all
this stuff,
you know.
So it's how well,
uh,
when was the first Tour de France?
I don't know,
but I know environment,
one of the very early ones,
uh,
the,
the guy that was winning,
he died because it was using
amphetamines let back in whatever,
I don't know,
19,
10,
20 or something like that.
So,
um,
it's there,
it's part of the sport.
When I came into bodybuilding,
it's not like I invented steroids with
already there,
you know,
my first Mister Olympia is in 1965.
Larry Scott was the Mr Olympia and 90
65.
And he said he was using steroids and
that was 1965.
So when did this start being used?
I don't know,
but for sure in the early sixties,
1965,
they had steroids.
When did they invent steroids?
Uh,
I believe,
well,
you had testosterone.
Testosterone was used in the Second
World War.
The Germans were using that with the SS
soldiers.
Um,
so injectable testosterone was available
then steroids,
which are more refined version of
testosterone.
Um,
I think late fifties.
How is it more refined in what way?
So you got testosterone is a male
hormone,
so it's basically 50 percent androgenic
that's male,
like characteristics,
50 percent anabolic repair build.
So they want it to take this and they
want to this pot the anabolic and
minimize the androgenic because that's
what gives you side effects,
prostate growth and all that stuff.
So they try,
they refined it so that those effects
are minimized and more of the anabolic
effect.
That was the idea.
And as a guy called John Stigler I
think,
and because they found out the eastern
bloc,
they had their own at their own stuff
called to rentable.
So a siegler invented,
definable,
and I don't know,
don't quote me if I could be wrong,
but I think it was about 58 or something
like that.
He developed that for us.
Weightlifting team,
1958,
I think it was 58 years,
but before that you had testosterone,
so who knows what a.
When people started using it,
but for sure from the early sixties it's
been a part of bodybuilding and then
other sports and they used to be a
disclaimer inside the steroid thing
saying anabolic steroids do not increase
athletic performance.
That's hilarious.
Right?
So they stated this and they also told
guys if you take this,
your fucking balls are going to drop
off,
you're going to fucking die.
You're going to get liver cancer.
So guys started using them and seeing
that that's all bullshit,
right?
So then they don't want to listen to
anything.
These medical guys you've got to say
because you're aligned to us then.
So you're going to be lying to us all
the time.
Not necessarily.
So.
Yeah,
because you do have chances of side
effects,
but if you could say it's been greatly
exaggerated and certain propaganda and
deception,
right?
Yeah.
Just tell the fucking truth,
man,
and let them deal with it.
And uh,
that's what I do because I saw all this
stuff on the Internet about what I'm
supposedly doing and I thought young
guys are going to read this and maybe
they're going to do it.
So I did an article in a magazine,
muscular development and I said,
here,
this is what I did,
this is what I did in officer,
this is what a different context and
these are my opinions and you know,
my honest opinion is like,
I don't think it's worth it unless you
know,
you're competing and so on.
But ultimately it's up to you.
Let me give you the information.
What you do is up to you.
And I don't know if 70 percent of the
people like this is bullshit.
He didn't really,
you must have talked much more than this
because I'm taking this.
Actually I'm taking more than this and I
will look like,
oh,
tough shit man.
You know,
I know a lot of guys that take more
stuff than me.
Then I couldn't even compete in a
contest.
I'm not even good enough.
Is there a certain amount where it
doesn't help you?
I think it gets to like,
the cup is full,
right?
You know,
it's just a matter of hard work is the
cup is fallen more than that.
Isn't that going to help you anymore?
It's just going to increase your chances
of negative effects.
Um,
so when I was an amateur,
it might,
my policy was always take as little as
possible to get the maximum effect and
when that's not working then you can go
up a little bit more,
you know?
Um,
but if you go a day one and just
throwing everything in,
the body's going to get used to that way
you're going to go,
where would you get steroids?
Uh,
where,
where did I used to get them?
I mean when I got them in in UK was just
from the gym when I first started.
I mean people were bringing them in,
trucks loads full from Europe and there
was not,
you know,
the authorities are not even aware of it
or concerned about it or anything.
Now the policy,
at least in a UK,
and it depends on every country in
Europe,
but in uk it's perfectly legal to have
steroids for your own use,
so you going to be driving your car with
a bunch of steroids on the fucking
passenger seat and the police call you
and you're like,
what's this?
Isn't my steroids?
Okay.
For Your own personal use is selling,
making money and not paying your taxes.
That's all they care about.
No.
Well,
that's I think how it should be.
You know,
as long as his education,
as long as you're not lying,
but the problem is when you lie to
people about the effects of things,
then they think you lied to them about
pain pills.
You're find about all sorts of other
stuff that is actually deadly.
I think all fucking drugs should be
legal and it should put money into
education and treatment and that's what
they did in Portugal and the fucking
results.
Write down,
Glenn Greenwald actually post something
today about that.
Showing how it's changed over time and
gotten actually better since they have
made,
especially in particular marijuana since
they've made marijuana.
Legal and started legalizing drugs and
in Portugal they've had far less
incidences of people having like real
issues,
so literally and the money they use it
to reeducate people and get them out of
that cycle and try and get them back
into society to,
to get them a job and all that stuff is
just going to punish people for doing
it.
How the fuck they ever going to get
better?
Yeah.
Well there's also a problem with telling
people not to do something and they want
to do it.
Especially when you're young.
This is a label.
Oh yeah.
Let me do it.
Here it is.
You can fucking have it if you want,
but this is all the negative
consequences.
And what do you want to do now?
People are choosing
to do it.
The bodybuilders.
Bodybuilders that died.
Um,
did any of them die from steroids or did
they die from complications involving a
host of different issues?
Well,
that's hard to say because there's been
quite a few of bodybuilders and mainly
male and mainly the bigger guys.
Well that has been a couple of women
that have died from heart attacks.
So did steroids contribute to that?
Possibly.
What,
what,
uh,
what else were they doing?
You know,
the individual cases,
who knows with taking pain pills,
a antiinflammatories or they're doing
recreational drugs.
There's a lot of,
a lot of factors there.
Um,
but I think would be probably fair to
say that using steroids over a longterm
will probably increase your risk of
heart disease perhaps.
I think it causes some inflammation in
the lining of the arteries.
Can raise the blood pressure a little
bit and so on.
So yeah,
I,
uh,
I compare it to smoking,
you know,
probably not as bad though.
Yeah.
So the way I look at it as I smoked for
10 years and then I stopped.
So now
quit stuff.
And now speaking of smoking good stuff.
How did you get,
how did you find out about DMT and how'd
you get involved?
Because I read something about you
having these positive dmt experiences.
Wow.
How strange is it reading about,
you know,
massive bodybuilder now getting into
psychedelic drugs while I'm speaking
openly about that first time
did I asked her,
was on in Brazil.
I met,
my wife was outside,
she lived in Brazil,
so we went out to the Amazon and the,
well this was like 10 years ago,
you know,
so people weren't really not like now
people know what I'll ask her is because
so much information out there yourself
talking about I'm talking about is a ton
of stuff on the Internet.
Um,
it wasn't so much then,
but I heard about it and I heard about
this.
It's a life changing experience and all
that stuff.
So we were out in Brazil and we've got
this guide and ask him for Ios Oscar and
he's like,
bring me these two balls of brown stuff.
I don't even know to this day if it was
really Alaska,
but I just got really sick and didn't
see any great revelations apart from
I've got this thing in my head.
Stop poisoning yourself.
Well the night before I'd been out
drinking,
getting drunk and everything.
So you know,
that was my experience with that.
Then a friend of mine out out here in
California actually I knew about dmt.
I used to live in Amsterdam and I read
the DMT,
the spirit molecule and all that stuff.
So I knew about it,
but I had no idea get the stuff away you
can get it from and everything.
So a friend of mine got it.
And uh,
that was my first experience of like
leaving the room,
so to speak,
and the planet.
And then since then I had to some very
positive ios grew experiences,
but with a shaman and doing properly and
prepare in like five days of know,
restricted diet and no sex and all these
kinds of things you do to prepare and
also afterwards,
um,
so dmt is like blow the fucking doors of
your perception and realize that this
world we're in is like,
you know,
it's nothing,
it's just a little illusion,
right.
There's so much more outside of it.
Um,
so there was that.
But with the DMT,
I think it's like you've got a computer
with like so much storage space and
you've got,
it's like a thousand times more than you
can retain.
So you see all this stuff and while
you're there you're like,
I know everything.
Oh yes,
but when you come back,
how much of it can you hold onto,
you know,
uh,
so you've sent it and that's like,
makes you look at everything
differently.
What the Ios is over hours.
So I feel like from the Ios I actually
benefited more,
it was like going through therapy or
something because it was much slower and
I couldn't digest it,
you know,
so um,
but doing it with the Shaman,
uh,
I did it with a guy called Gmo,
other Railo and his,
one of the top guys in the world from
Peru comes to Spain a couple of times a
year.
So I did it with him and um,
yeah,
it's probably,
I don't know,
it's probably two or three years since I
did dmt because I sat down one day and I
said,
actually I fasted for three days before,
so I'll be like,
just in the zone.
And I said,
right,
I'm going to sit down.
I got my dmt here,
I've got my vaporizer here.
I'm going to fucking smoke as much DMT
as I possibly can to like,
like,
you know,
to like gone and pass out.
So I had that experience and since then
I just don't feel any need to do it.
I don't think there's anything more I
can take from it.
I've had many people tell me the same
thing.
They had such a profound breakthrough
experience that they're like,
okay,
I get it.
Yeah.
I had a crazy one in around 2000,
I want to say like two,
eight or nine or some point that.
And I took a long time off.
I didn't do it again till like five
years later maybe.
It was pretty intense man.
I mean the,
the Ios was nice because it comes in
Nice and subtle and you go through hours
of this thing.
But DMT is like,
last time I did feel very anxious when
you'd like,
like it's almost like you're leaving
your body and you know,
so you get that bit of anxiety,
but once you go,
oh yeah,
that's cool.
But if you've done it more than one time
in a day,
like multiple times in a night.
No,
I just,
you know,
just blasted it as far as it could go.
And that was it.
I've done it several times over the
course of a few hours and uh,
you know,
you are more comfortable letting go that
way and some sort of a strange way,
but it never gets less alien.
Oh,
he had a,
I'm not gonna mention his name,
I don't know his name,
but we had an experience,
me and my friend a few months ago,
um,
uh,
that I'd never seen before because
usually people take dmt,
they very calm and sit in the chair and
you'd go off and you might start
laughing,
but you know,
you don't move much.
Right.
And this guy,
he just like freaked out,
like it wasn't for 10 minutes or half an
hour on.
My friend was a former MMA fights used
to fight with shamrock.
So we're hitting in a wrestling
techniques.
So we had to hold this guy on the floor
to stop him from hurting himself because
it was totally freaking out.
So I could see the guy was going through
some,
something traumatic from the past.
So today I messaged them,
I say,
hey,
did you ever find out what the guy,
what,
what was that?
You know,
because it was,
he said,
yeah,
it was from his birth.
What's his,
from his birth when he was born,
he had the cord around his neck.
Oh Geez.
And then he went back and relive this
and so that had been in the back of his
mind all his life,
subconscious,
subconscious as a huge effect on us,
but we don't know it's there.
So now he opened that box and let it out
and that's gone now,
you
know,
so it can be therapeutic.
A,
I thought this guy's like,
oh,
he's going to be.
But when it came back,
it was like,
Hey,
I'm like,
you're good.
He's like,
yeah,
I'm good.
I'm like,
do you know what just happened?
He's like,
no.
I said,
good thing.
We filmed at them and go home and watch
this.
I had a friend of freaked out too.
He freaked out.
He threw up,
took his shirt off.
I was running around saying a bunch of
crazy shit.
And then,
uh,
after he came down,
you know,
we calmed him down and took like 10,
15 minutes.
He goes,
okay,
well obviously I'm a work in progress,
but never forget that,
but did he know what it was that was
troubling him so much?
Well,
he had a bad childhood for sure.
Everything is like most of our shit is
from that,
right from the developing years?
No,
for sure.
Yeah.
I mean in especially like real traumatic
ones,
abuse being beaten by his Stepdad and
the punches fucked up shit that was just
haunting him,
but he,
you know,
helps you to come to terms with that.
Especially the Ios because it's longer.
I felt like the first time I did Iowaska
properly with Shaman,
I felt like
I was a different person.
The next day I felt it was done 20 years
of fucking therapy or something and just
a lot of stuff I'd worked out in my
mind.
I could even see other people's point of
view on things and that I couldn't see
before.
That's huge.
Right.
Seeing other people's point of view,
especially a guy like you who's so
determined and goal oriented and just
cut out all the bullshit and get it
done.
Yeah.
It can be a little insensitive to other
people's feelings around it because it's
just like
nothing keep up my way.
That's a male thing in particular.
Right.
And then,
and it's like,
and bodybuilding and intensity and
competition and then being the best,
arguably the best ever and just fucking
finding every day.
A couple of weeks ago it was like that.
You don't see yourself as other people
see you.
So what do you mean?
He said like,
I remember when I was a kid,
first of all the size,
you know,
it was fucking huge,
but it's your persona.
You might've said to me something very
like normal,
like a,
you know,
whatever.
What are you doing with a dog?
Like,
just something normal.
I said,
no,
I'll be like,
because just your,
your presence made me feel like the
inner
right.
That's got to be weird when you're a
little tiny kid and your dad's a
gorilla.
Yeah,
I remember he did a
it.
It's a kickbox and right.
So he got his black belt when I was
about 11 or something like that and that
was my thing.
I used to take into kickboxing and pick
him up and he's like,
Dad,
can you just,
can you wait outside?
I'm like,
what do you mean you want me to come in
and like,
just wait outside,
like,
you don't want to come.
It's like,
yeah,
but everyone's like freaking out and
looking at you and it's got to be nice
to have like know I'm fucking coming
inside man.
Semi anonymous and crowds now.
Yeah.
Unless someone's a hardcore bodybuilding
fan.
Well that's the thing,
uh,
not necessarily slow because uh,
because of the interviews I did on
London Real,
um,
and I've talked about ios gear and dmt
and spirituality and reality and all
this stuff.
I get so many people coming up to me
like they're not from the gym.
I get housewives that young kids.
Like it's almost like you're the guy
from London Real,
you're the guy that,
you know.
So I got a whole bunch of other people
that appreciate what I'm saying about
spirituality about reality and life.
And they're like,
fuck man,
what'd you said?
That really helped me and I got so many
letters and emails and stuff,
people,
you know,
like they just took something away from
what I was saying.
So I mean that's,
that's really why I do these interviews.
It's just trying to help the whole
general vibe and the,
you know,
put it out there and um,
there's a whole consciousness awakening
revolution going on now and I'm just
want to push some dominoes,
you know,
like create that effect.
And then,
you know,
if you touch one person,
they touch somebody else and it's like
the butterfly wings flap here and the
other side of the as a,
you know.
Yeah.
It really or something.
It does seem to be working in that,
in that regard,
right?
It is,
it is the time,
man.
It's the time is so many people that are
more aware now than like 20 years ago,
isn't it?
Kind of like,
I mean,
there's parallels to bodybuilding,
right?
It net.
When Arnold first started doing it,
there was very little information for
Harley and you guys got to see what they
did and build upon that and more
information came out and now because of
the Internet,
there's so much information,
too much information.
People are aware more of what it's all
about.
Well,
with Psychedelics,
I mean 20,
30 years ago,
there's so much ignorance and so little
understanding of and also so little
understanding,
especially when it comes to something as
extreme as dmt.
There's still a giant percentage of our
population doesn't even know what it is.
Yeah.
They should all take it.
Especially the fucking politicians.
I'd like to get those politicians,
man,
I'm fucking get them in a room and force
them to take dmt and then see how
they're going to behave afterwards,
how they're going to look at the world
and treat people after they've had that
experience.
I don't.
I don't think it can be a,
you know,
so self centered and unfeeling as most
of them are.
After you've had that experience.
I think that any breakthrough
psychedelic experience,
whether it's silicide been or LSD or
DMT,
they all pretty much,
you know,
ego dissolving roads to the same place.
Terence Mckenna used to say that DMT is
the center of the Mandala.
The way I describe DMT is it's like
mushrooms times a million plus amens and
then it just seemed so titanic.
Lee Bizarre that there's like,
I've tried to describe it to people,
but I always say,
look,
I'm going to tell them what to do it.
I'm going to give you some bullshit
or because you can't.
It's no,
we don't have the words to put it into
words,
you know,
you can attempt to.
I went to this place was not a place,
but I don't have the word for it.
The places everywhere is like.
And there's colors,
there's numbers,
the shapes and people think things and
this is like everything is all one
fucking thing.
And what I noticed is like my breath was
connected to it.
I don't know how it happened,
but I was in the trip and I went like
that.
And the whole thing moved.
I really let me try this then and then
the whole thing moved and then there was
music playing and the music was part of
the thing as well.
Like the thing,
I don't even know what to call it,
the thing that place,
I don't have a word,
you know,
we played a bunch of these shaman and
the Shaman who grids is the last time I
did it and the Shaman [inaudible] like
literally made the DMT images dance like
they had figured out a way with these
sounds and songs to integrate these
beats into dmt trips.
And as you would take these trips,
these shamans had figured out the right
sounds and songs how to make
the trip more intense and sort of guided
in a strange way.
What I had with um,
with a shaman,
with the Ios guy.
He comes around and sings these arrows
and like changes tone and then it goes
deeper base in his chest and it's like,
it's,
it becomes part of it,
you know.
And I was even moving in voluntarily.
I was my arms going up,
my body was moving and it's like I'm not
doing this.
I don't know even know how it's
happening.
It's like somebody picking my arms up in
a move and I was,
you know,
started dancing around with this
becoming part of this rhythm.
Wow.
I had an experience once one of the
first times ever did dmt where I saw the
difference between negative and positive
thinking.
Like I started thinking negative and
there was all this like black and dark
green and like these,
uh,
threatening shapes and colors and then
something recognized what was going on
in my brain that the shapes and images
were connected to negative thinking.
And I relaxed in the shapes kind of like
settled down.
And then I started thinking positive.
Like I heard all these expressions of
love,
but like you're hearing it but you're
not really hearing it.
It's like the thoughts are getting into
your head.
Like someone's trying to say it without
using words.
And then I started thinking positive and
from those dark images blossom these
like beautiful,
like geometric flowers and colors and
impossibly spectacularly beautiful
images.
And I was like,
oh.
And I,
I,
I recognized in my mind there is an
actual thing that happens when you think
negatively and an actual,
it's not just some sort of affect the
program,
they're in a program,
your thoughts,
the program's coming towards you and
your thoughts and it's interacting with
the program.
Yeah.
And that's why conflict,
interpersonal conflict between people
can be so negative.
It's not just as simple as you and some
person getting into an argument.
It's those dark images and those
negative forces becomes a part of your
system.
I had exactly the same thing,
so,
but it was almost like a tunnel.
I was in this tunnel and it was the same
thing.
Yeah.
Oldest
images around and scary and everything.
And I was like,
I instinctively I knew to be very
relaxed and I started laughing like,
fuck you.
And not even real.
You're not even real.
And when I said that
it went away and I just got this thing
that came into my head.
You have just been in the valley,
um,
was a cold.
The Valley of the shadow of death is
sin.
And the Lord's prayer,
I think though we walk through the
Valley of the shadow of death,
I fear no evil because God's bought
aside.
I vaguely remember from school or
something,
but I got this thing that you were there
and you're in the valley of the shadow
of death and because you like,
fuck you would like,
ah,
it's not even,
it just,
it just disappeared.
And then it went to somewhere really
nice.
Wow.
Yeah.
I just wonder how much his real,
you know,
it's,
it's such a hippie thing to say like,
how much is real?
I don't know.
You know,
I've been having these thoughts a lot
lately about how much of how much of
live do you manifest,
how much of life is real?
Because it's such a bullshit thing to
think it's such a hippie thing to think
and so many people that say that are so
annoying.
Yeah.
But scientists are saying the same thing
now.
Quantum physicists saying,
uh,
it was a fingerstick names.
Profess at guides know if you're
familiar with him.
Professor Gates.
And uh,
he said that they've broken down reality
into the smallest level and it's a
computer code.
Yes.
I've seen that gun code.
It's a specific computer code of Zeros
and ones.
And it was invented in the 19 forties by
something.
Yeah,
I've seen that guy being interviewed.
We actually talked about it with Neil
degrasse Tyson and he,
I tried to get him to sort of break it
down and explain.
But what it is is essentially that when
you break reality down to the smallest
level,
it mimics a self-correcting computer
code.
Not just not just a computer code,
but a computer code.
That self correcting,
which is right there.
I just said a bunch of noises that I
don't even understand.
You know,
it's just,
it's gone beyond
now you're getting a spirituality and
science coming together because the
scientists are saying what spiritual
masters,
they're already telling us that we live
in an illusion and everything is inside.
Not outside.
That was saying that thousands of years
ago.
But some of it is real,
like you have to work hard or you don't
get results,
right?
Like your,
your hard fast,
pragmatic reality of being the best
bodybuilder in the world revolves around
actual work,
real results
in this,
in this reality and this program,
but also to do physical stuff.
Yeah,
probably there was a lot of mental shit
going on there too.
Absolutely.
The work was being done,
but also there was probably a lot.
It's
all day.
I mean that's all I thought about like
literally all fucking day.
So you know,
I had to have the physical goods to make
it happen.
I could dream about being basketball
player all day.
It probably wouldn't help me because I'm
not built to be a basketball player,
but those thoughts were just going out
all the time.
And I was a kid in Birmingham,
industrial city in England and I was
thinking I'm going to go to America and
I'm going to be a bodybuilder.
And everyone around me was like the fuck
you took.
Um,
so yeah,
that was those thoughts all the time.
So I think it's like a holographic
program.
We're in what we influenced it,
we interact with it,
with our thoughts.
That's kind of where I'm getting at now
in some way,
and the guys that were spiritual masters
like Buddha or the guy that called Jesus
and all that know that apparently did
things that were called miracles because
they were outside the box,
outside the physical reality we live in.
How can they walk on water that's not
possible,
but if you are so advanced that you
really knew it was a program,
then you can like heck the program and
that's how they able to do it.
They're kind of remove themselves out of
the program.
Yeah.
How can you.
How can you,
you know,
how can guys levitate or.
Well,
yeah.
I don't know.
I wasn't there.
See that's the thing.
There's no evidence whatsoever that
anybody actually can levitate.
Well,
people have witnessed people doing it,
but I have witnessed is a lot of.
We'll set some weird shit.
The problem with people saying things as
they might have literally seen that,
but it doesn't mean it wasn't a
hallucination.
And then again,
it doesn't mean that a hallucination
isn't an alternative
reality.
What is it,
you know,
people say you elucidate when you take
lsd or dmt or just elucidating hio or
you're just seeing more stuff
that you can't normally see because now
you've shifted your,
your,
uh,
your vibration,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
one of the things that I tried to
explain to someone about dmt that have
kind of used over and over again since
then is that I felt like I met with the
divine force of the universe,
like have or he divined forest,
maybe my puny little brain can only
comprehend this level of divinity and
that maybe perhaps it was something even
more profoundly more powerful and
knowledgeable and wise past that,
but I wasn't ready to perceive it.
Then maybe there's levels to that,
that it's fractal just like everything
else.
And someone said like,
well,
you know,
how do you know that wasn't a
hallucination like a.
well,
it could have been,
but here's the deal.
Whether or not it was or wasn't the
experiences the same.
Like if you really go into some other
dimension in God or you take a drug in
which you experience going to another
dimension and meeting God,
it's still the same experience,
the exact same experience.
And why?
Why is everybody's experience kind of
similar,
right.
To have a whole totally different
fucking illusion.
No one seems to think it's no big deal.
No one that I know who's ever done dmt
is like,
hey,
it's no big deal.
You're not going to be the same
afterwards.
You know,
you get your,
your perspective.
Is it going to a different point of view
is going to be different.
And uh,
it can only put.
I've never,
I don't know anybody that's done dmt.
And then they've said that was not a
positive experience.
I didn't get anything from that.
Every fucking body.
I know it was said that lot.
Wow,
the fuck,
where am I?
That's like,
what are noises that come from my mouth?
And nobody's like,
nobody's ever said to me that even the
guy that I saw that looked like he was
getting raped by the devil because
that's that guy getting raped by the
download.
I didn't see that,
but I saw his eyes and that's how I
imagined somebodies eyes with
like that was happening.
So he looked like
an absolute terror is all I can say,
absolute terror.
So in this guy's eyes for like 20
minutes,
but when it came back it was like,
oh,
this is the guy that was.
He didn't even know.
I'm like,
you okay dude.
Yeah man,
that was fucking great.
Like,
do you know what happened?
It was great.
Okay,
you need to watch this video when you go
home because we fell into man.
I had a friend,
my friend Doug Stan hope and he's talked
about this many times on stage.
I got him high on Dmt at my house and
uh,
he's the only guy that I've ever got
high on dmt that I worried about because
he fell over on the couch and started
moaning and like foam was coming out of
his mouth.
He was,
but he's so unhealthy.
He smoked cigarettes.
He drinks constantly.
And I was like,
oh my God,
did I break my friend that I was really
worried.
I was like,
maybe I should have considered the fact
this fucking guy doesn't really
take care of things.
Uh,
I think when your system's kind of
toxic,
you don't get the best.
Oh,
he came out of it.
He got great results.
He came out of it.
It was a fantastic experience for him.
He came out of it with all these
revelations.
We had great conversation about it,
but in the moment he was like,
and I was like,
oh no,
I've killed him.
Oh,
this guy was like spasm him and kicking
him.
And my friend had to hold him on the
floor to stop him smashing the furniture
in the south.
So.
Wow.
And it was like thinking he was being
chosen 10 minutes.
Oh Gosh.
15,
20.
Oh God.
I was like,
I was starting to get concerned.
Like Jesus Christ,
half an hour later he came out of it,
but he's glad he did it.
Now that he couldn't see himself at the
time.
Know.
Do you ever a float a flotation tank?
Yeah,
I did it once.
And you know,
funny enough,
when I was a kid,
I read Frank Zane,
Frank Zane was doing flotation tanks
back in the seventies.
Yeah,
those Samati tanks.
So I always wanted to do it and I saw
this place when I was over in England.
So I went in there and I said to the
guy,
like talking about it,
I said,
listen man,
let me ask you a question.
I said,
is it good to smoke weed before you go
in there?
And he's like,
I'll tell you the truth.
He said,
a lot of people come here,
they smoke weed outside before they come
in.
He said,
but the first time I think it should
just go with nothing and see how it
goes.
And I'll be honest,
I was in there for like an hour thing
after 40 minutes,
I just got really fucking bored.
I thought to myself,
I meditate every day,
every day.
Uh,
so I was like,
this is like,
don't fail.
This is any better than major in my
meditation.
I just getting kind of the same thing.
So really I wasn't,
I wasn't blown away by it.
Like I expected to be to be honest,
but then,
you know,
done dmt
and I'll ask her and asset and
everything.
So maybe my expectations were too high.
Um,
I always give the same advice I give.
I say don't smoke weed the first time,
just go in and experience it,
but my thoughts are that isolation tanks
and the isolation tank experience is
something that it takes time to really
fully relax and settle in and there's
layers to the onion and you got to go
deeper and deeper and peel those layers
away.
And I've done it so many times.
I have one in my basement and so I've
done it so many times now that when I go
in,
I can slide right in almost immediately.
But I'll tell you this,
I rarely go in sober.
I almost always go in high as a kite and
edibles preferably or the best way to
really.
I can have full blown psychedelic
experiences in the tank on edibles,
full blown visuals.
Well,
going into the jungle,
experiencing the center of the universe,
like intense,
intense stuff because the relaxation,
the,
the fact that you are the only
information you're taking in is there's
a mild feeling of the water on your
body,
very mild that you have to think about
to be aware of and occasionally you'll
touch the sides of the tank and you have
to kind of write yourself.
There's no some water gets in there or
something,
but other than that,
I don't rub your eyes,
get salt dries as a bad one,
but other than that,
you're,
you're experiencing no sound,
no,
no visual input,
and in the absence of that visual input,
I think all those other thoughts become
more powerful.
So whatever the effect of marijuana is
an irregular body when you're just
hanging out,
sitting around.
That effect is intensified in a big way
when you're in the back and try that
next time,
but when you're in town I can hook it
up.
Alright,
cool.
If you want,
how many,
how many times are you in town for?
How long you in town?
For a we're on a hips so Thursday
evening and go to vegas to do a
competition that.
Well they have them in Vegas too now.
They have everywhere to make.
When I first started doing the tank,
I first.
My first experience I think was in the
early,
early two thousands and I got my first
tank in 2003 because when I bought my
house,
one of the reasons why I bought it is it
had a basement and I was like,
I want a place to put the tank.
And because I had done the tank a couple
of times at this place called soothing
solutions in Burbank.
Yeah.
If you've got it there and you can do it
every day then oh it's the best.
I'll do it at night and I get home from
a comedy show and I'll say I need to
process my thoughts and go over my
material and I'll climb in that tank and
just take off to the center of the
universe and figure things out and also
makes me reconsider like how my thoughts
are.
Be like one of the things about comedy
is you know,
you have an idea and you've got to try
to figure out a way to get that idea
into people's minds and sometimes it's
the wrong way.
Like sometimes it's too abrupt or too
corrosive or it's too,
it's just not,
it's not,
it's not smoothly getting into people's
minds,
so you have to like really consider it.
So that idea of seeing other people's
perspectives like that we were talking
about earlier,
that's huge with standup comedy and one
of the best ways to kind of get out of
your own way for me is to explore things
in the tank because in the absence of
any physical input,
he kind of stopped thinking of your body
and your brain and you as an individual
as like the captain of the ship and all
the other things start to become more
and more.
You've got more room to us.
Well that's the idea is like you and I
are having this conversation,
but one of the reasons why I like to do
it in this room with no one else here
but us.
So there's no distractions,
right?
But if there was a guy in the other room
with a Jackhammer,
it would fuck us up.
We'd want to get out of there.
Right?
We want to it go over here so we can
talk more quietly in the gym.
You want to go to the gym?
You want to be sure.
That's why a lot of guys put headphones
on,
right?
You just want to fucking grind and get
in your own head.
Well,
in life itself,
like while we're sitting here,
your chair is sending signals to your
ass.
You don't have your hands on the table.
It's all data in the tank.
There's nothing.
And in the absence of sensory input,
I believe that your brain become
supercharged and I think you can
consider things in a much more clear
way.
I think you have more resources.
As I said,
I find the same with meditation.
It's like when I've tried to explain to
people,
as I said,
it's almost like I feel like it's slowed
down my thought process.
So now when I have thoughts,
I see them coming in and I'm like,
don't wanna act on this thought or not.
Whereas before I already acted on it
before it was,
you know,
I recognize that that's a huge problem
as being a reactionary person and
constantly dealing with input coming in
and the like instinctively batting it
away or stay stressed and anxious.
You are always going to react like that.
So you need to get rid of all that and
people know that.
I think that's one of the reasons why
people have a real problem with
president trump.
One of the real problems we have with
them like this,
the guy that argues with people on
twitter gets mad and it was nail on the
wwe.
Wasn't that perfect training to be the
president.
But that's fun.
That's silly to me.
I mean that's the same thing,
man.
You're performing familiar.
That's just what,
uh,
you know,
the president,
how much power does it really have?
How much influence or is it just a,
just a pantomime that destruction for
people.
But that was before he was president
when I'm reacting to is like him
tweeting things today,
like shitting on people,
insulting people.
Like when you're the fucking president
of the United States,
he the leader of the free world.
You can't be going on twitter and just
insulting people,
putting out that conflict energy that we
were talking about for what reason?
If people recognize whether they know it
or not,
inherently they know that this is not
the way to lead.
This is not the way to be above it all.
This is not the wise person that we want
at the top of the hill.
Setting the standards for all the people
who have a.
which was your alternative.
There's no alternative,
but you go,
I don't think there should be a
president and I've said this a million
times.
I just think there's too much power.
Does
the president really have.
I mean you had to Obama,
right?
He said it was going to close down
Guantanamo Bay.
Yeah.
Great.
But it didn't happen.
I don't want to know why did he want to
do it,
but he couldn't because other people are
really in control or maybe they want to
do
bullshit.
I'm like,
why?
They shouldn't do it.
There couldn't be a bunch of factors.
I don't know,
but I think maybe you go there with good
intentions,
but there's other people that pull us,
pull the strings and you know,
presidents,
just a front guy
in that sense.
One of the things about trump being so
bold and so egotistical,
I think that's probably a positive,
is that he's resisting the deep state.
He's resisting all of these other
outside influences.
Any so wealthy that he has the financial
power to insulate himself from these
other people that are like him.
Well,
I,
you know,
I got friends in the states and that was
the feedback that I got.
The,
the guys that liked trump,
they liked him because I felt that it
wasn't gonna be controlled by the,
you know,
the big money,
uh,
the,
the guys that own the Federal Reserve
and,
or pulling the strings on the military
and all that stuff.
But I don't,
I don't think you can have,
I don't think you can beat those guys,
you know,
control the money system,
the control,
everything.
It's a mess.
I think I like your idea.
We need to get them all fucked up.
So let's get hillary stoned and make a
real nice,
cool lady.
And she would just go,
I have cancer.
I confess is a picture of a deer that
was on the side of the road that was
dead.
And you know,
those one of those comic memes.
And it said,
what did this deer know about?
Hillary Clinton seems to be dangerous to
know too much about Hillary and Bill
Clinton.
People were killed just in the last
couple of weeks that committed suicide.
A lot of people know this shit,
right?
So like,
we've got this fucking psychopath.
Well we've got this idiot guy that but
maybe is a better alternative than the
psychopath.
So let's go with the orange guy with the
orange guy because he's,
you know,
his not part of this cabal.
And maybe he's gonna he's gonna change
things for the better.
So that's why people went with him.
I believe because he was seen to be not
controlled by the same forces,
if you like the,
you know,
the Clintons,
the bushes,
the fucking,
all these people,
they're on the same club.
Right.
Well,
it just seems that change,
especially change over our culture,
you know,
over a civilization happens in these
like slow ticks to the right or ticks to
the left,
moving in a good direction or a bad
direction is so.
It's so slow to change and like,
so when something like this comes around
that is perceived to be a negative thing
and it's perceived to be a negative
thing moving in a terrible direction and
quite rapidly.
It scares the shit out of people.
Well,
that's the feedback I get now.
If people over here,
they,
they're concerned,
you know?
Well of course not.
I don't think it makes that much who is
president.
So it's just a,
it's just a fucking side show to
entertain people came distracted.
Do you think that's on purpose?
I got all.
Yeah,
that old emotional like,
oh,
trump is a,
uh,
it's like it's just bullshit is a
pantone.
Mine is just to keep you distracted and
I keep you entertained,
just like football and everything else,
like don't look over here,
look over here.
So magicians trick in.
Wow.
I like to think that way sometimes.
Then other times I think it's probably
just too complicated for anybody to
really orchestrate and we're just
reacting to these wants and needs and
human instincts and all a variety of
factors that have been set in motion,
like the momentum of these things that
have been set in motion forever and
people trying to profit and people
trying to figure out how to control
various factions of it,
but the idea of like one person or one
group pulling the strings,
it's not as clear cut as that,
but I find it less and less plausible.
Yeah.
This is a small group that controls
that.
The debt.
It's not even money instead.
So if your control that then it can
control pretty much everything,
right?
Isn't everybody in debt is every country
in debt is in China in debt to.
So who.
Exactly.
That's fair.
If everybody is in debt to everybody,
like,
is that really dead fucking front money
and put a number on a thing and you
know,
you owe us x amount,
let's just cancel a debt.
Yeah,
no,
that's why they distracted with things
like we've got to go after medical
marijuana like that jeff sessions guy.
He's,
he's the ultimate distraction.
It's going to start crying,
kind of versus like,
that's a huge thing in the evolution of
consciousness and it's getting more
available and more accepted and uh,
the so many layers to it,
man.
It's like medically,
it's amazing.
Spiritually.
It's amazing.
It's a hemp plant.
Can fucking supply what you know.
Henry Ford built the model t ford out of
Hamp Hempcrete,
right?
Not only that,
it's way stronger.
So why is it with a hammer?
He hits the fenders and rust.
It's lighter,
you know,
everything.
He filled it with ethanol as well.
So did you ever see you see
them make that a video where they have
him hit the hammer against the offender?
It's like the first model t they had met
fenders.
They had made them out of hemp and he's
whacking it with a fucking hammer and
hammer.
The people don't understand if you've
never experienced it,
the hemp stalk the actual stock of the
tree itself.
It'll get very big and thick and it's
extremely hard,
but extremely light.
It's not like any other wood is light
light wiring.
It's fucking hard like oak,
but light like Balsa Wood.
Look at this.
That is hemp.
So he's banging his hammer against this
fucking car and it's not even making a
dent.
So tell me why it didn't build the car
out of because of William Randolph
hearst.
That fucking cunt.
William Randolph was the guy who owned
hearst publications.
He also owned a bunch of paper mills and
he's the guy who demonized him.
He's also the guy that was the
motivation for Orson Wells to make the
movie Rosebud.
You are the movie citizen Kane Rather.
He was in the oil and steel industries
as well.
It has to do with a lot of things,
but a big part of it was William
Randolph hearst because they had a cover
of popular science magazine that was
like hemp.
The new billion dollar crop and they
made that because there was a.
There was a device that was invented
called the decorticator and what a
decorticator was.
It was a machine that allowed you to
effectively process the hemp fiber
without the use of slavery.
See,
for years and years they had used
slavery to process hemp and hemp was
what they used for canvas.
That's why I can have the name canvas
comes from the word cannabis.
That's.
That's literally Lamont.
He wrote the declaration of independence
on him,
so the first drafts on hemp paper,
it's a far superior paper.
Then wood pulp paper.
Well,
when they had come out with this article
in popular science magazine,
hemp,
the new billion dollar crop,
they were essentially saying that hemp,
because of the decorticator now hemp
would replace Wood for paper for all
these other things,
so I don't need to destroy the forest
animal.
William Randolf hearst not only owned
these newspapers,
but he also owned these paper mills and
he owned these forests and he decided to
combat this competing industry with
propaganda.
So they started printing these stories
about how these black people and
Mexicans were taking this wild drug.
Marijuana women.
Exactly.
And then everybody was like Jesus.
So when the.
When Congress first made marijuana,
first of all,
marijuana was not even the word for
cannabis.
Marijuana was a word for a wild Mexican
tobacco that had nothing to do with it.
As Mexican.
It was the exactly careful danger,
danger to the cross,
the border around ones.
And so they people responded to this and
they,
when they made it illegal,
they didn't even understand that they
were making cannabis.
They didn't notice to understand.
They were making the,
the commodity hemp illegal like to this
day until recently on it.
We sell hemp protein.
When we first started on it several
years ago,
we had to buy all of our hemp from
Canada because even though it's not
psychoactive,
it was illegal still to grow in America.
It's so stupid.
It's just so tied,
technically stupid.
But the,
you know,
there's a,
there's a crack in the dam now that you
kind of stop it,
man.
That bowl was rolling now and people are
waking up to the benefits,
you know,
how many states you're gotten in us now
that's legal is quite a few medical and
I think there's something like,
what is it like nine recreational,
Nevada,
Massachusetts,
California,
Oregon,
Washington state,
Washington,
DC that I say that already.
Um,
I don't know.
I mean the other ones there are main
Alaska,
Colorado,
of course.
Yeah.
So how many of them legalized canvas?
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
legalized.
And then jurisdiction with medical
decriminalization that there's a lot of
funky,
weird shades too,
that there's more than three shades
there.
You just make it illegal across the
board.
Well,
it takes time,
man.
The amount of money.
What's fascinating is the amount of
money that is coming in and that's
affecting it because these people are
getting into Colorado.
The was massive.
Put it back into the school systems and
the metal giving people tax refunds.
Sorry,
we made too much money tax at 39
percent.
And everybody's like,
okay,
nobody gives a shit.
I read that in,
in Nevada,
in vegas that literally running out.
Oh yeah.
Urgency.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
Well I hope not because I'm going there
Saturday.
Oh,
they'll get you some.
I'll hook it up.
I know people,
Nevada declares marijuana state of
emergency to avoid $100,000,000
tax shortfall because they wanted the
money from the marijuana because they
were making so much money in taxes
because I think,
I think Nevada has 39 percent as well,
right?
They had a 39 percent tax rate.
If it's 15 for recreational,
only 15.
Really think so.
Well,
they fucked up.
They should've went 39.
Nobody gives a shit.
It's still five bucks for when you're
buying it.
I don't know if this,
the works are getting texts too for what
they sell.
Recreational marijuana tax
fingers.
The bowl was all in as not going to stop
now.
And uh,
so many people out there have cured
cancer as well about using the
concentrated oil and stuff.
I got a couple of friends that have
cured their own concept from changing
the Diet,
uh,
go into a plant based alkaline diet and
taking the cannabis oil.
And the doctors are like baffled.
Yeah.
So there's that.
And that's a powerful thing.
If somebody kills a concert,
they're going to tell everybody.
I tell everybody they know all their
family and it's just a matter of time.
Yeah.
They just had something on the,
on a mainstream,
which I was surprised a mainstream a
news show in England where they had this
case of this kid who was in hospital is
dying from.
Can't remember what it was.
But anyway,
just the point is his mother was
sneaking in the cannabis oil and he got
cured for that.
And then they did this whole thing on
the breakfast tv about how the,
you know,
the kitchen was got rid of his constant.
Now what I noticed,
they still,
you know,
the obviously told to say this or that,
there's told this whole story about the
kid is like,
you know,
it's kind of gone now because his mom
was sneaking in the cannabis oil and
wow,
we need to look into this.
But,
but we must state everybody.
People,
we must tell you that we must,
you know,
it's not a cure.
Right?
What the fuck you're talking about?
The kids killed while you're talking
about,
it's not a cure,
but it's obviously something they've got
to state,
you know,
because it's actually illegal to
claim that you can cure cancer.
Well,
it's illegal to possess the marijuana,
so it's illegal probably to use it as a
treatment even though it's effective,
you have to say it's not a cure.
Exactly.
Under the influence of the
pharmaceutical drug companies that will
come down.
I mean there's pharmaceutical drug
companies that advertise on these
networks,
which becomes a huge problem because of
their advertising abilify and fucking
Welbutrin and all this different shit
that they're selling.
They're not going to be interested in
you telling positive stories about
abandoning all pharmaceutical drugs.
Then taking natural remedies,
of course not as competent it.
So what they're trying to do now is make
you know,
slightly different versions of it that
the complaintant a swan company,
I think at Gw pharmaceuticals and UK.
What?
Guess what?
It doesn't fucking work when you do
that.
No,
so I'm laughing at them and waste all
your fucking money.
The plant is perfect as it is,
as a perfect balance is it's.
It works as it is,
so,
but they can't trademark you trademark
it,
so you want to change it a little bit to
create something can trademark and make
tons of profit off.
But guess what?
Because it ain't working.
Yeah.
Once you.
Once you change it,
it doesn't work the way it's supposed to
work.
It's all people trying to control shit.
You know,
it's people that are trying to control
how much agriculture you could sell.
I mean that's what it is.
It's agriculture with marijuana really
is a psychoactive agriculture.
It's plants like the idea that you tell
someone they can't grow tomatoes
in their backyard.
It's fucking bananas close.
It's a plant that grows from the ground
exactly as it is.
God fucking made plant grows from the
ground.
How?
How can that be illegal?
Right?
So if you have tomatoes in your
backyard,
everyone knows tomatoes have lots of
vitamins are healthy for you and you
know one who would say,
oh,
you can't do that.
I go to the Chinese have been using hubs
so thousands of years.
Sure.
Marijuana is just the same thing.
It's just,
it's the mother of all
the fucking top,
uh,
you know,
sometimes people get confused about
like,
Oh,
you know,
you're supposed to be healthy.
Is supposed to be an athlete.
What'd you doing?
Smoking marijuana.
I'm like,
this is the fucking healthiest thing I
do every day.
I got like 40 tablets here.
Yeah,
I got fischels.
They got vitamin C,
got resveratrol,
I got her herbs,
I got everything in know.
Well,
guess what?
More powerful than all those fucking
things together,
although they're beneficial is my
cannabis oil I take every day.
This is like,
I don't know if you're familiar with a
guy called Bob Melamede.
Dr Bob Melamede,
his,
uh,
studies a free radical is a human
biologist,
I think.
And he states that a cannabis is the
most powerful antioxidant,
most powerful anti aging substance on
the planet.
Period.
That's it.
So I,
I consider it a health supplement and
yeah,
I get high enough.
It's a health club too.
And there's also ways you could take
that are non psychoactive.
You know,
people that take cbds or I take this
stuff.
Charlotte's web,
hemp oil.
Take this everyday.
That's a high cbd.
It's
fantastic.
That makes you feel good.
It alleviates aches and pains is good
for anxiety.
It's good for mental clarity.
It's just great for your body.
It's just some.
It's an essential oil for your body.
I got my left knee.
The cartilage is gone.
Uh,
the shoulders,
you know,
not only the supraspinous that's gone
the,
you know,
when I go for a scan,
they're like,
oh,
didn't know you had your shoulder is the
arthritis is really bad.
You must spend a ton of pain.
I'm like,
nothing.
I don't have any pain.
I don't know if that's down to my kind
of issues,
but it definitely,
definitely a factor in the,
you know,
I'm sure it's a factor.
Do you think also a factor is mental
toughness because of the fact that you,
your understanding of pain is probably
way different than that.
How you perceive pain,
you know,
like you're not going to dwell on it the
way that advertising is not a big deal.
I'm,
I live with that every day from,
from training,
and actually look forward to it in a
way.
Yeah.
So probably my perception of pain is
like,
is less than everybody else's,
but for sure,
you know,
when I'm asleep,
if you had to reel arthritis,
I mean it's going to wait.
You're going to get paid.
I don't get anything.
So something I'm doing is helping.
Um,
yeah.
I consider cannabis to,
they'd be the most powerful health
supplement you can take.
I'm better than all the other stuff,
but I still take all the other stuff as
well because I'm stuck in all the odds
in my favor,
you know?
Yeah.
I mean I think it's really important
guys like you that are going against the
grain explaining your position and,
and also you as a respected professional
athlete where people will listen to you
and they go,
oh,
well this guy is such a straight shooter
about steroids and about training and
about injuries and all these other
things.
He's not going to lie about this.
Well,
the people have just been had this
misinformation for so long,
so strong in that brain is like,
it's hard to change.
So a change that you know,
especially if you don't have any
experience with a soft,
like this fucking drug.
Like I dunno if somebody put on the
instagram,
I can't believe you ate smokes weed.
I just fucking hate lazy stoners.
That's a pretty strong reaction man.
Like you hate somebody because they're
smoking a fucking lazy calling you lazy.
It's hilarious.
It's like an ally that I need to smoke
weed to stop me from doing too much
fucking.
This is a slow me down.
So like a normal level.
Why listen yet
it,
it can fucking slow you down and you
know,
you can sit and smoke fucking weed all
day and sitting in the couch and watch
TV and eat pizzas if you want like you
know,
but if you're smart you use it when it's
the time to use it.
And I like,
uh,
sometimes I like to smoke a little bit
of cardio because it opens my broncos
and I get a better fucking will count or
it's generally in the evening when I'm
relaxing or if I want to do something
creative like I'm writing or something.
It helps me like think a little bit,
um,
but there will be times when it's
appropriate and times when it's not
appropriate and that's it,
you know?
No,
I completely agree.
I just think that it's a lot like what
we're talking about earlier with fats
and sugar,
that there's this misinformation that
continues forever.
It's like once you get an idea in your
head,
oh,
low fat is good,
high fat is bad,
and then somewhere along the line you
realize that that's bullshit.
Like what you might realize that you
might do the research,
you might go into the article and then
look at the studies and go,
wow,
this is insane.
And how did this happen?
And go into the New York Times article
about the sugar industry,
bing.
But once you get to a certain point in
time,
you realize like most people are not
going to do all this.
They're not going to look into this.
They're not going to get.
So most people are going to hear what
they heard when they were little
marijuana is for losers.
Marijuana makes you lazy.
You're going to be a lazy stoner.
I don't want to be that marijuana is
bad.
Like jeff sessions,
the fucking guys on record saying,
good people do not smoke marijuana.
Dude.
You're talking about millions of people.
You're saying none of them are good
people
generally.
Is it?
That is a thing of the people that smoke
marijuana are generally nicer.
Kind of more thoughtful people and
realize that in some way we're all
connected.
We're all,
we're not fucking independent,
so how's that better
thing?
Because he doesn't smoke pot.
That's the problem.
Oh,
we need to fucking hold him down and
make him smoke pot.
That's what we need to do.
But he'll freak out.
Apparently Joey Diaz gave pauly shore
some stars of death on his podcast and
now polly won't release the podcast.
He's like,
hide it,
burn it,
burn it with fire,
kill it,
kill it like a demon.
I mean,
cannabis is so good that when you smoke
it,
which is full of fucking tall and
costage ins and everything in smoke into
your lungs,
it doesn't even damage your lungs.
Yeah.
I think it's supposed to be a different
type of smoke though,
like the smoke that you get,
it's probably harsh,
but it doesn't have the same,
but the properties of it don't have the
same.
Like the,
the issue apparently with tobacco in
particular,
like just regular tobacco.
If you're smoking,
a regular rolled cigarette of hand
rolled tobacco,
just pure tobacco.
No,
no.
Uh,
other bullshit ingredients is not as bad
for you as a cigarette,
but still bad.
I've got a ton of chemicals in this.
Hundreds of chemicals by the way,
approved by our government.
They're like,
yeah,
pour it in there.
It's good.
It must be good,
man.
It's going to get people to throw it in
there.
Government govern what government's
meant is your mind.
But marijuana smoke has been shown to be
an expectorant actually can clear the
lungs of certain issues.
It
highlights the Broncos as opposed to the
backhoe is closing them all the time.
Um,
I don't know if you're familiar with a
study that was done here at Ucla.
I believe a guy called Donald Tuscan.
He did it over 20 years.
It was a properly funded study.
While I was at properly funded,
because it was funded to look for
negative results,
so the purpose of this study was to
prove that smoking cannabis damages your
lungs just like cigarettes,
right?
So the followed three groups over 20
years,
cigarette smokers only or tobacco
tobacco and marijuana together and
marijuana only and to tobacco smokers
over 20 years,
of course,
loss of lung function,
a lot of cancers,
all the stuff we already know.
The middle group was way less and the
marijuana group smoker,
like daily smoking over 20 years was no
increased cancer.
There was no loss of lung function,
in fact,
that had a slight increase in lung
function as compared to nonsmokers
other exercise and taking big tokes.
That's what he gets
because you're taking in,
but not only that,
because the cannabis is dilating the
broncos all the time.
If you keep dialing and keep dialing and
keep dialing,
it's going to get more.
You know it's going to get more
functional.
Well,
it makes sense.
I mean just it's counterintuitive to a
lot of people that think that's
negative.
It's bad for you.
So I just see it as a super health
supplement.
I don't see anything negative.
I don't see it as a drug.
Just the plant and yeah,
you get high and you feel good.
So what's in your life?
It's silly shit.
Good for you.
Right?
I agree.
And I think that people are starting to
understand that more now than when we
were kids for sure.
Yeah.
I used to smoke when I was a teenager
and in England we mix it with tobacco or
this,
just until I came here.
I don't know,
like people smoke it pure.
I don't mix with tobacco now because I'm
realizing the weed is good and tobacco
is bad.
Before I didn't know both.
Probably bad for you and I'll give a
shit,
you know?
Yeah.
How did that get started in England?
Because every time had been over
England.
They do that too.
They're like,
do you make sure we'd.
With tobacco it's was like,
what?
Yeah,
I don't know man.
That was like,
that's how it was always done that way
when I grew up.
Um,
I grew up in Birmingham as a ton of
Jamaicans,
you know,
so the Jamaicans were the guys that
brought the weed and,
and stuff like that,
but even they used to mix with tobacco
and a lot of people smoke cash.
So how she got to,
you got to Mexico,
you know,
with something.
Right.
So people mentioned it with tobacco,
but I think last time I smoked tobacco
was probably like eight,
nine years ago when I became educated
and I was like,
wow,
this cannabis is really good on its own.
A lot of people in America,
they take a cigar,
they take out the,
the tobacco.
Yeah.
And they make a blunt out of it.
But you're taking in tobacco and belief
and he gives you this weird high.
Yeah,
because you're getting that nicotine
buzz,
like a head buzz,
but you're also inhaling in a way that
you don't do with cigars.
You don't.
Usually you puff it out,
right?
Yeah.
You,
you get the tobacco,
it gets into your body from your mouth,
but you don't really inhale deep into
the.
I like to use it,
the
hemp papers and also I vaporize extract
as well.
Yeah,
like dabbing Nicole here.
Um,
so I do that.
I find,
I don't know,
I find it a bit different between
smoking weed and Dab in the extract
smoking weed.
I find it a bit more relaxing.
Dabbing the extract is like,
I'll do that before I go on a bike ride
or
cardio or something.
And I'm like,
man,
they don't get tired,
don't get tired.
I know,
right.
Isn't it amazing?
Uh,
you can,
you know,
whatever you do in running.
First of all it's,
it's dilating your bronco so you can
deliver more oxygen.
But I think also it's the mental thing
they like get in that zone and perceived
pain is less.
Discomfort is less.
So you just keep,
just keep going.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah.
One of the guys in Brazil,
like all smoke before the do Jujitsu
because it helps to be relaxed,
right?
When you're doing that,
you know,
want to be all tense all the time.
Not just relaxed but also singularly
focused.
Yeah.
It's America to giant percentage of
people smoke pot for the Jujitsu.
Yeah.
It's a big,
big thing.
Bought bodybuilding as well.
Really mean I'm the only one that talks
about it because all those guys are like
scared,
like uh,
it's going to be viewed negatively or
their sponsors are gonna like,
you know,
drop them or something like that.
Yeah.
Well I can tell you like half the guys
on the Olympic stage,
they'll stone us because it helps you
relax after training.
You can't drink.
Right.
You know,
because the calories and if you're
drinking the next day you're not going
to perform so well.
I mean you can get totally fucking high
tonight and you can go in a gym tomorrow
morning.
One hundred percent have a negative
effect.
Right?
Zero.
Do you remember the Arnold?
I'm sure you do.
Arnold is numero uno token on a little
one though.
I mean that was.
People were like,
what is he doing back then it was almost
like he was getting drunk or something.
Yeah.
People didn't even think about it and he
was the only one.
It wasn't.
He wasn't passing it around other
people.
He was the only one on camera smoking.
Yeah,
they look guys,
we'll probably schedule on the smoke on
camera,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
it's still viewed negatively,
you know,
like,
uh,
an athlete say he smokes marijuana,
he's risking maybe losing is a
sponsorship and uh,
uh,
I don't give a shit.
I don't have sponsors.
I'm independent.
So you know,
a bit more free to speak out.
Well,
the crazy thing to me was the nfl,
the nfl saying that these guys can't
smoke pot and they suspend them for
smoking pot.
Meanwhile it's okay to run full speed at
each other and smash into each other and
the massive amount of damage that's
doing,
that's,
that's not,
that's not a problem,
but the problem that would actually help
with brain injuries because a lot of
studies,
you know,
with Alzheimer's and stuff like that,
that's very protective on the brain.
So maybe it could have helped them.
If anything I would definitely wouldn't
hurt.
No
harm them.
And even if it's just cbd oil,
it's a neuroprotectant canabinoids yeah.
Yeah.
It's,
I mean,
we living in an age where information is
leaking out there and people understand
things more today than they ever did
before where there's still a massive
amount of ignorance that you have to
combat,
but it's,
you know,
it's a head of 10 years ago.
Yeah,
right.
And,
uh,
I live in Europe,
although I live in Spain now and in
Spain it's not legal,
but it's,
um,
it's legal to grow in your house for
your own use is legal to smoke in your
house for your own use.
So what's happened is,
um,
these collectors are being created,
so,
all right,
so I can smoke in my own private
residence and I can grow whatever,
let's say three plants for myself.
I'll get bullied.
So what if there's 100 of us now in this
collective,
in this club.
So now we can grow 300 plants.
And so that's how it is.
It's supposed to be nonprofit
organizations.
Um,
so when you go and you buy your weed,
you're not technically buying a weed,
you're contributing to the upkeep of the
collective.
That makes sense.
So that's how it works.
Uh,
and then uh,
in Holland it's um,
tolerated they call it technically is
not legal is tolerated,
so the console in the coffee shops there
and whatever,
and Amsterdam,
so those two countries a little bit
ahead,
but everywhere else is still still not
legal.
Like in UK where I come from,
it's not legal,
but the police have already stated then
going to arrest people for smoking weed
because they're considered a waste of
their time.
Um,
so any major city in England,
you go walk down the street,
you can smell weed.
People just walk down the street and
smoking weed.
If the police are there,
they might say,
hey,
you know,
come on,
put that out.
But that's as far as it goes.
So technically it's still illegal,
but it's kind of like,
you know,
the police are not,
they don't care about it unless you're
selling it.
I think Canada is set to essentially
legalize it nationwide and think that's
the most recent revelation from Canada.
They're essentially ready to just kind
of has always been a pretty good weed
country.
Right?
Yeah.
Well,
the Vancouver in particular,
there's a great documentary about the
marijuana industry and it's impact on
Vancouver.
It's called the union fantastic
documentary.
Just showing how ridiculous it is and
how inexorably tied marijuana is to
their entire economy in Vancouver.
I mean,
it's,
the money that comes in from marijuana
is just a gigantic portion of their
economy and it's all this.
So that's why Colorado setting such an
example of making so much money,
like we got to be other states looking
at it like a think fucking Detroit
should get on that.
Trying to fuck.
Yeah.
Detroit's a mess.
Right.
And coming back with like,
um,
handmade stuff,
there's a bunch of things like different
industries and different small
businesses are starting to emerge in
Detroit that are kind of very,
very promising.
But yeah,
that would be a huge factor.
Now there's a huge industry out there,
uh,
not just grow in the,
all the other.
I come here and it's like I'm a kid in a
candy shop.
You know,
you got chocolate and it's like tells
you how much thc is in each square.
We've got breast brave man,
you got butter,
you've got cakes,
you've got everything man,
and I'm like,
yeah,
you're careful with those cakes though.
Yeah,
well,
edibles.
I always tell people,
be careful with edibles because if
you're smoking a joint and you take a
couple of puffs,
it's going to hit you pretty much
immediately to your brain,
so you're going to feel it and you're to
decide whether you want to smoke some
more on that or maybe you want to just
put it down right and chill,
but when you eat it,
it's going to take 45 minutes to an
hour,
so hit your system and you don't know
what,
how strong that's going to be and if
it's too strong,
which most of the time it is.
If you're not experienced then you're on
that fucking ride and you can't get off
hours and it can be pretty unpleasant,
mean like too much thc.
For somebody that's not used to it,
you can feel very paranoid and very
uncomfortable.
You can feel nausea,
she might vomit.
You're going to get low blood sugar a.
all this stuff is not going to be a nice
experience and probably then you're
going to have a negative view of
cannabis.
Like,
fuck that shit.
I'm not going anywhere near that again.
Um,
so unless you're experienced,
I would just say stay away from edibles
or like just have a small piece and wait
a fucking hour.
Don't,
don't be tempted to like,
oh,
I don't feel anything.
I'll take another one,
then you're going to be fucked.
That's great advice.
Go stepped gingerly.
Yeah,
go very slowly.
And the edibles because it takes time to
digest it.
Time to get into the bloodstream and
time to feel it.
So most people will eat some and say,
I don't feel anything.
I don't have another one.
And then,
you know,
it's,
I've seen it happen so many times that
it's too late.
Yeah.
And it's not going to be over in five
minutes.
You're going to have hours of that.
Like,
you know,
and then they just to say that's,
that's kind of stuff is bad as you know.
It's horrible.
It's fine.
That's the beautiful thing.
Even after a horrendous,
terrifying,
nothing bad can happen to you
physically,
you might vomit as like the worst thing
that could happen,
but you got to be careful because I read
the other day,
right,
that uh,
there is a level at which cannabis can
kill you.
So you've got to be careful that you
don't smoke 628 kilos cannabis in 15
minutes because if you do that,
that could be toxic.
That could be lethal.
Someone out there is going to try to
prove you wrong.
Yeah.
One point five fucking tons in 15
minutes.
If you're going to hail that,
like good luck to you.
I think that's actually the ld 52,
which means liesel lethal dose for 50
percent of the population.
Fifty percent of the population are most
definitely pussies survive that anyway.
I mean I couldn't smoke a fucking,
I dunno in 15 minutes.
How much could you smoke?
Like five grams or something.
Like,
I don't know,
in the.
You could do more than that,
but in a vaporizer you can get pretty
deep.
But yeah,
you're not going to get anywhere near
620.
I don't know why that came at 628.
Six hundred and 27 or 600.
Twenty nine.
I Dunno,
it's theoretical anyway because no one's
ever died from it.
No one's ever died from it.
So like what other substance?
Kenya not die from it.
Even water is you have too much water.
You drown.
Right?
So I mean this is pretty harmless
fucking substance.
If there's no,
there's no feasible toxic level.
Alright,
600,
28 kilos.
I'm taking the piss like,
you know,
I couldn't smoke that in my lifetime.
How often do you smoke pot?
Every day.
Damn Day man.
Gentlemen,
every day I take my vitamin C everyday
as well.
Fish oil.
The rest of us are at all,
like all antioxidants.
I said daily thing man.
I might go,
I go sometimes with not smoking for a
week or two just because I want to have
the discipline to,
you know,
to say I don't need to do this everyday,
but I fucking luck to do it everyday.
So why not,
you know,
I hear you man.
And we're not.
You know,
I don't get up in the morning and smoke
when I got shit to do because it might
not help me do that stuff,
but if I'm working out or if I'm going
to lie on a beach,
I'm going up the mountains.
Yeah.
I'll take a joint with me.
One.
Why not?
It just enhances everything.
You know,
enhances you.
Your experience enhances food and sex.
Enhances music.
You're preaching to the choir,
man.
I know.
You know,
other people are listening.
I know what I'm saying.
I'm saying I'm with you.
Yeah.
No.
Uh,
I mean I couldn't agree more.
Listen man,
we just did three hours.
I crazy can went quick like that.
Yeah.
I wouldn't say that like an hour and a
half or something.
Anything else to say to the people
before we wrap this bitch up?
A.
I hate to be the guy that goes on.
Chet chosen promotes things,
but I'm going to have to do this.
Please do.
Yeah.
Am going to be in Vegas on Saturday and
we got a thing called swiftly the,
uh,
the date.
Actual date.
Saturday is 29.
Ninth.
Okay.
I'm going to be in Vegas,
we've got a competition called Super
League and this is for bodybuilders
slash strength athletes and it's
somewhat functional because,
you know,
you get a bodybuilder on stage and the
general public look at that and say what
the fuck is this like strange and maybe
a product of just taking drugs and they
don't appreciate the work that goes into
that and how strong and athletic some of
these guys can be.
So this competition is,
has two rounds.
The first round is lifting,
so you get judged on eight different
exercises you score a maximum of 12 reps
at.
So um,
there's that and then there's the
physique round,
but it's,
it's done by computer,
so it scans various areas of your body
and gives you a score on that.
Sounds a bit complex.
But if you want to go on superleague
live,
it's got explain everything.
Have you been doing this for?
This is going to be the first one.
Ah,
and uh,
we weren't sure like what reaction we
get with the first one,
but it's been off the fucking hook and I
think we're going to get a new breed of
athletes that are maybe not purely
physique bodybuilders as like the Mr
Olympia.
We've got guys coming from power
lifting,
we've got guys coming from bodybuilding,
there's a lot of guys out there in the
gyms around the world that are fucking
athletic,
strong,
freaky guys and girls.
We've got both categories that maybe
don't want to compete in a bodybuilding
competition for various reasons or they
do want to compete in a bodybuilding
competition and they want something
alternative to do.
We've got a competition between a team
la and team Atlanta as well.
And we've got interest for the roll this
out internationally.
So
keep your eye on that man.
People go to it.
Where,
what
superleague alive.
And the contest is in the city Athletic
Club,
German in Vegas,
which is like the biggest German Vegas.
Okay.
And so the website for it would be
hopefully live or superleague.live.
I'm not sure what superleague live.live,
something like that.
And uh,
I'm going to be there Sunday and a lot
of other people from the,
from the sport and
on invite Joe Rogan.
If you've got spare time.
I'm actually going to be at the UFC
Saturday.
It's in Anaheim,
so unfortunately it's a good card.
Very excited about it.
Jon Jones and Daniel Cormier.
Oh Great.
And that's in Vegas as well?
No,
that's out here in Anaheim on a cowboy
cerrone and Robbie law.
It's a great car.
It actually,
it's one of the best cars in a year.
I'm just joking.
So I would do whatever you want folks,
but superleague is going to be awesome.
I'm sure.
Listen man,
it was an honor and a pleasure.
I really,
really appreciate you having me on.
It's been A.
Yeah,
like three hours has gone like nothing.
Like nothing.
I'm sure we could talk for fucking 24
hours,
but I bet we could.
It's time to smoke a joint.
I agree.
Alright.
Alright everybody.
Thank you brother.
Appreciate it.
See you guys tomorrow.