Oh boy,
here we go again.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight flush.
Yeah.
Great.
No,
that's great.
It's not.
It's not right.
It's more well known than dildos.
There's no like one dildo company that's
known as much as the flashlight is
known.
Right.
You put your wiener in winter.
Yes.
Like it's for fucking like it's not.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Fuck it.
Why?
What's the point of having a light?
Oh,
it's not really a light.
That was just a job with John half.
Ron had a great joke about it should
have a light because no one ever knows
where their flashlight in his,
but everyone always knows where your
flashlight is,
which is very funny.
It's really and very wood for the folks
on it.
Brian has just pulled the actual
fleshlight I it at the bucket and you
pull it out.
Blanche opened her mouth and she has
horrible fish.
Breath.
So the second you did that,
I smell that it was interactive.
Would be a dog who's sitting in her lap.
That's blanches a dream.
I guess that's.
She can smell anytime.
What I thought it was,
this one's a bottle that's really tiny
out essentially is right.
I mean that's what you're asking for
sure.
It's the same thing.
I go both ways.
It's just the whole.
This is a fake one.
Is that defend you when you see like a
fake vagina to defend me.
Some people get offended.
Some girls they don't like because you
should be fucking me instead.
No,
it's not.
Some girls,
I'm sure you know,
needy girls.
It probably would think like that.
Right?
Don't you have some crazy girls?
Yeah.
Yeah,
for sure.
So you're saying like,
girls are like,
why do you need that?
Yeah,
that's such odd.
They can get angry.
You dudes have a.
well,
I don't want to ask her boyfriend.
I don't want to ask you if you've ever
had a sex toy.
We want to offer up any information.
Feel free.
Ready now go.
I will tell you this.
Uh,
I don't prescribe to that ideology
because I feel that it will set you up
for disappointment.
Like no man is ever going to be able to
move as rapidly as a vibrator.
So I just completely abstain from that
and it's fine.
I've been given like I'll do shows and
the vehicle get out free dildos and it's
embarrassing to walk out of there with a
hose and like one time for my birthday a
comic came and he bought like a bag of
sex toys and you know,
your parents come to visit,
like you don't want that around and I
just don't.
Dude,
I'm with you.
I'd rather feel less good most of the
time to get that added.
So it looks like a squid.
Go to Joe Rogan.net.
Click on the link for the fleshlight.
Enter the code name Rogan and you will
get 15 percent off.
And I'm going.
Sorry Joe,
you know a tip that we've never thought
of it.
You could only have to buy the vagina,
a version of the flashlight because the
other side does have something that
looks like an asshole.
At least an asshole enough that.
Yeah.
But it doesn't fit into the thing,
right?
You'd have to have a different sort of
setup.
Like you can make your own probably.
Yeah.
You'd have to have some sort of a
different face to it.
Yeah.
The what you're saying essentially.
I see what you're saying.
What you're saying is it doesn't have to
be one or the other.
It should be both.
Yeah.
You should have it on both sides.
Like,
like a real woman.
Yeah.
You know,
but it would be in a weird.
It's not the same spot.
Like right next to each other.
We didn't only work.
No,
I mean just make a flashlight that
you're on your.
If you're on your side,
they're next to each other.
Yeah.
But not like this.
Just make a flashlight that you can fuck
both sides that has caps on both sides.
It just caught like A.
Yeah,
my saber instead like a light saber,
you know?
Yeah.
No,
I see what you're saying.
Totally got a good idea.
What he's saying is it should be two
sided,
like the butthole should be one option.
Sometimes I feel like sometimes I feel
like a nut.
Sometimes they don't see what you're
saying.
I feel you.
I feel you on this.
Would that.
I guess that one would cost more than
um,
yeah,
but you know what,
how much more I really want a superior
product you'd be putting out.
But anyway,
the fleshlight as it stands,
solid product,
Brian and I give it two thumbs up or
there should be a subscription base,
you know,
like you can just like have it,
you get 20 bucks a month,
you can have any flashlight you want and
then when you cancel it you have to send
them all back of legislator.
The month club.
Never trust the fact that the one that
you were getting it not been fucked
already.
The shittiest one and they just sent it
because it's part,
it's part of a prescription.
I think it should live up to its name
and like a carnival game.
The hardy.
You fuck it.
The more it lights up.
So you know,
you're doing a good job.
What are we?
Well,
we're on such a strong delay.
I'm looking at the image on the screen
and that's the amazing artwork that
somebody sent you.
Yeah,
I got to get that dude's name.
It's so amazing that I just want to
stare at it all day.
That's one of those amazing pieces of
art that you can sit there and find so
many things in.
Just random guy's name.
He sent it to my manager.
Just some super cool fan,
dude,
whoever,
whoever you are.
Thank you.
Thank you,
sir.
I love what you've done to this.
A studio show.
Well,
it's my office man.
A studio.
I just threw up some pictures and needed
some,
some life on the walls.
I had accumulated a bunch of cool
pictures but done nothing with them.
And then finally I put them up there.
Just fucking room was like right out of
hoarders.
Now though.
It's so crazy.
Shit.
It goes above the litter box to be fair.
But it's true.
That is one of the components you need.
Yeah.
My cat,
she knows she doesn't really like to be
anywhere else,
uh,
at night than in my office.
And it's like my kids are always
wandering around the place my kids don't
wander around is in my office.
So I figured,
you know what,
I should just keep to her box in my
office.
Who should bite the bullet?
It's so gross though.
Smelling cat shit all day,
dude.
It's gross.
I gotta get in there and open the top
and scoop it out and flush it and my cat
waits until I'm there to take the nasty
shit.
Like she waits.
I know she does because I'll come home
and I'm checking my email and I hear
scratch,
scratch them.
Like oh you little bitch.
And she just drops a fucking stinker.
I had something worse happened.
Joe Mike had recently was sick and had
like some kind of urinary track
infection I guess.
You know.
So I tried to get a cranberry juice for
awhile,
but nothing.
It's hard to give cranberry juice to a
cad work.
Yeah.
It has to be a good news and bad news.
Urinary tract infection gone.
But it was trying,
it started doing that horrible shit were
just start peeing because it couldn't
control itself and it did it in my bed
all over my head and Cat pee if you know
anything about canopy and NASA.
I haven't looked really nice fucking bed
and now it's just most like happy and
I've washed it,
scrubbed it.
I can't do anything.
So I'm about to find something that
smells worse than copy just because I'm
so sick of that cat pee smell.
It's unfortunate,
but you got to get rid of the mattress,
the mattress that you can get that stuff
that they sell at your in gone.
Yeah.
But it doesn't really work.
You're in,
you're out.
I mean it works a little sort of what it
does.
Is it some sort of citrus base thing?
You know,
it breaks down the smell of cat urine to
a certain extent,
but it's is like glitter.
That's never gonna go away.
When you would go,
I don't know if you,
your grandparents were like mind with
grandparents.
They start shitting in a certain way
where it really fucking smells awful
like old people.
Shit is like the worst drugs in it.
You think old people shit,
like they're dying probably the diet,
not that healthy diet and they're dying.
And um,
uh,
I would go in after my grandfather would
take shuts and there would be a spell of
like air freshener in the air that was
like the most offensive smell.
The air freshener cover up over shit.
This shit.
It's just terrible fucking smell.
It smells awful.
It's humid,
humid smell,
human smell.
And we're also sponsored by on it and I
t.com,
makers of Alpha brain,
shroom,
tech,
sport,
shroom,
tech,
immune and a new mood.
All these things are different.
Nootropics,
nootropics are,
if you're interested in and they're
essentially vitamins and nutrients for
your brain.
I really believe in them.
I know they work.
Um,
you know,
there's scientific studies that we're
going to do right now.
There's gonna be some.
We already discussed this was a double
blind,
placebo,
double blind,
whatever it means.
The most stringent scientific tests they
can for figuring out whether or not
people's performances are improved with
their mood's improved.
They're not going to know what they're
taking.
Some people will take a placebo,
some people will take a combination of
different things.
Some people will take Alpha brain on its
own and we'll see what the results are.
I,
I have been taking nootropics for a long
time.
If you're interested in it before you
buy anything,
just google it,
just google the idea.
Uh,
there's a lot of really fascinating
papers and different things that have
been written on them and there's proof
that some of them actually can help
people with Alzheimer's.
It's really their nutrients for the way
your mind functions couldn't hurt.
But yeah,
you're not supposed to take five htp if
you're on antidepressants.
Well,
those people are ridiculous
antidepressants.
Totally thought you were just going to
make the best show ever.
Is there a reason why they decided
against the triple blind?
They just don't want to know.
What that means is there is a triple
blind as to blinds enough.
You greedy bitch.
Just do it.
As always say,
look,
I,
I take all this stuff.
There's shroom,
tech,
immune.
It's great for your immune system that
actually somehow or another,
it's a mushroom that tricks your body
into thinking that it's a potentially
like a bug,
like a cold,
and so your immune system fires up for a
fight that never takes place.
Uh,
so it's,
uh,
it's uh,
like a,
an immune system booster and probiotics
is something that we don't sell,
but that's one of the things that I
really recommend if you,
if you're a person who really cares
about your health,
one of the cool things you can do is
enhance your health with organisms,
live organisms,
probiotics,
and Kombucha tea.
I'm a big believer in that,
that,
that stuff is excellent.
Keep you from getting sick.
I mean,
it really,
I,
it gives me an enhanced feeling of
wellness.
It's like taking in like healthy
soldiers.
I also take acidophilus.
No,
I think if,
yeah,
I get it and get the good stuff.
Get the stuff that you need to
refrigerate the real live culture.
It's fucking great for you.
Kay.
I love Kayla.
Drink Kale shakes every day so high
right now.
Good for grass would be healthy.
No,
but wheat grass juice is healthy.
Chlorophylls very healthy taste like
shit,
but it's very healthy.
There's nothing.
Well,
there's chlorophyll and glass and grass
rather chlorophyll.
Yeah.
You fill in all plants.
There's.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of different types of
grasses.
You know,
I don't know what grass specific list.
What if we were designed to only eat
grass grass,
we wouldn't have these pointy teeth.
Well,
maybe that was for like digging big
things out of the ground compared to
other animals.
We have the most bitch ass teeth ever.
Nothing.
They're like these little fragile flat
things.
They're designed to chew mushy food.
I mean how we eat other animals that are
designed to actually hold onto things
and then eat those things,
tear them apart and eat them.
And if you look at like a,
a champs teeth compared to our teeth,
they're designed to fuck you up.
Designed to fuck you up because I always
look at blanches mouth.
Even like when she's sleeping you,
when you live with an animal.
I live with a tiny carnivore,
right?
Carrots and she's sweet,
but like genetically programmed to like
find live things and rip their necks in
half and eat them.
Yeah.
It's weird,
right?
Even though she's a little love bug.
Anyway,
go on and talk dog o n n I t dot Com.
We tried to make your mattress.
Yeah.
Camera.
You master's son.
Can't fucking.
You know Joe,
I put two comforters on.
Enjoy it all.
Smells.
It was awesome.
Here's why you have to get rid of.
Let's get rid of this commercial.
Let's get this commercial though,
right when we started this podcast,
I know this is going to be.
No,
we haven't even started your whole week.
Grass truck.
Anyway.
We have for the first 30 pills,
whatever you buy,
we offer 100 percent money back
guarantee.
It used to be whatever you buy,
we offered a 100 percent money back
guarantee,
but there's some douche bags that bought
a bunch and then try to sell them on
Ebay after they got their money back,
which you ruined it.
That's human nature,
but we try to make this as easy and as
clean as possible.
One hundred percent money back guarantee
and your first 30 pills,
and you know what?
If you think it costs too much money,
I urge you,
go and buy the ingredients,
take the directions offline,
whatever the ingredients are clearly
listed on the website,
on it dot come and steal it and make
your own blend.
Who cares just if you're into it,
try it.
Check it out,
and if you want to buy them from us,
go to Joe Rogan,
not net.
Click on the link for Alpha brain and
entering the code name,
Rogan,
and you get 10 percent off.
Okay?
You'd already freaks done.
See,
that's the Commercial Eliza.
It's over now.
We play music,
so that was good podcast.
That's the best way for us to do
commercials.
We have figured out was I in that
commercial?
Okay,
dude,
you are fucking awesome.
And it was one of your best,
best pieces.
I'm going to submit that to the tonight
show.
You could do that.
I bet it's a solid piece.
Yeah,
it was a solid piece.
Give it a rush.
Eliza,
live slessinger professional stand up
comedian.
Yeah.
We all share a comradery.
You know,
it's funny comics,
you know,
like when you meet someone that's a
comic,
we all share this kind of weird thing
like I did the Rosie O'donnell show.
Yeah.
People are like,
why do you want to do Rosie O'donnell
show?
And I'd be like,
[inaudible],
she's a comic.
You know what I mean?
Like we all share,
we share something.
Tell us about that.
What was that like?
She was very nice.
I haven't got to talk to her for a short
period of time.
We had a,
we sat down for about an hour and we
talked about,
she talked a little bit about the
government.
She had a really good point about how
people look at the government.
Like it's a benevolent father and I,
I absolutely agree with that.
Agree with that.
Yeah.
And she was,
you know,
she's like,
really?
She stuck her neck out and she was on
that show.
Like a chicken
view.
Yeah.
Well she got,
she got it.
Trumbull
and the view.
I mean,
I'm sorry she got in trouble in the view
because she was um,
she was talking
about nine slash 11 and she was talking
about tower seven and if you don't know
this,
there's three towers fell on September
11 and two of them obviously I got hit
by planes,
but one of them went down,
one of them just went down and there's
the crazy conspiracy theories that say
that it was a controlled demolition.
Now I am the first person to tell you I
am no engineer.
I have no idea how buildings are built
or what their tolerances are.
But if I saw a building like that and I,
you know,
I saw just catch on fire and it had some
holes in it and shit,
but it just felt like that black bitch
apps,
you build this,
how the fuck did you build this?
You know,
come on man.
Really is what kind of Shitty work is
designed to go down.
Like it was,
it was saying it was.
A lot of people believe it's a
controlled demolition.
I don't think necessarily she is saying
that it is or it isn't.
And I certainly am not.
I don't know.
I don't understand that.
You know what I believe more.
It was a controlled demolition.
Yes.
But with a by us.
No.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think that's always been the case of
the,
the argument.
They don't think it was done by the
terrorists.
They think let me know.
No building the tear.
What?
No.
What if the terrorists,
uh Oh,
they did a controlled demolition.
It wasn't like if somehow they had tea
because I probably could easily.
I think that would probably be before
hijacking planes and flying them into
buildings before that would be putting a
bomb in a building.
But it's not that easy.
See,
like when you see what happened in
Oklahoma City that was multiple bombs,
you know,
in Oklahoma City,
they actually,
there was all these reports of the FBI
removing bombs from the building like
that didn't explode.
And if you talk to these guys that are
demolition experts,
they say there's no way that was a
fertilizer bomb.
There's no fucking way.
They said that.
If you look at the amount of damage that
did and look at where the blast radius
is from the way it blows out,
it doesn't blow the.
They're not designed to.
You're saying spelling because we've all
seen the loose change where you watch
the lights go off around the building
one floor by one.
It's like,
yeah,
but see they don't see.
They don't know what that means though.
That also could be.
If the ceiling is coming in and slamming
into the floor,
all the windows would do that.
They don't know that that's explosions.
If it really was collapsing like that.
See no one's ever seen a building
collapsed like that.
So when they say that those are blips
and those are squibs,
I don't like that because then I'm
saying you're.
You're saying you know for sure what
that is and I'm saying the fuck you do.
I don't know.
Even the.
Someone's got an.
There's just because someone has to
know.
I'm not saying it was as.
I'm not saying it was an inside job.
It just seems odd ergonomically that you
would design a building that if
impacted.
At a certain point,
the entire thing would demolish what
structurally?
What purpose does that serve?
Well,
the.
Yeah,
the weird.
Well,
it could just be in competence.
That's possible.
If you look at humans,
that's our most likely option,
right?
I mean when did they make the world
trade center so fucking long ass time
ago to get so cocky to build a building
that's 100 God damn stories high.
And how long did they think that was
good?
Stay up there for,
you know,
what if it started falling apart or
rotting what it was,
it was just a,
just a wonky piece of shit by the time I
got hit by those planes.
Yeah,
that's totally true.
I mean it's fucking thing was oldest
shit.
That thing was around as black and white
television.
Jessica Lange,
King Kong.
I mean.
Yeah,
but what's retrofit?
It's the cheapest goddamn floor and the
cheapest guy.
A bitter,
you know,
that tells you that how many floors was
fitted with bombs maybe.
Well that's the crazy idea.
What W,
what we're saying about a building seven
or,
or the other building that terrorists
could have done it.
I mean,
I guess they could have,
but how the fuck are they going to get
in there and put all those explosives
in?
It's dynamite a time.
Red Sticks of dynamite.
One up your ass.
You're working the fucking thing.
Five years everyday.
You're fucking putting it into this
closet.
So funny.
Back then they didn't have security that
sticks.
You're walking down the hallway and you
just smell shit.
Open this door.
What's in this smells like shit and it's
just shitty dynamite state.
It's like a fucking log house built with
shit and dynamite sticks and little
hairs.
A pee mattress.
The idea was that know that somebody had
to do something in Oklahoma City on the
view.
Well,
what she said on the view was it was the
only building in history that never.
That collapsed skyscraper that wasn't
hit by a plane and she's.
She's true.
No,
no,
no.
It wasn't.
Yeah,
and it was the only building in history,
a skyscraper of its kind that fell from
a fire and she's right.
I don't know if it needs anything
though.
Could could be incompetence.
It could be just some crazy coincidence
that it actually did fall apart like a
controlled demolition,
even though it wasn't a controlled
demolition.
It could be.
I don't know,
man.
I think there's so much chaos involved
in any sort of catastrophic situation
like that and all these reports we heard
explosions in the building.
Are you.
Do you really remember what you saw?
For sure.
How much.
You know what I mean?
So a lot of nuttiness going on when,
when right after something like that
happens,
you might want to remember something
from before you might.
You must be so jolted from that sort of
a situation that after it's over,
you know,
I,
I would,
I would imagine there would be several
people that would have distorted
perceptions.
I do not believe that everyone can
handle truly traumatic incidents.
I'm not claiming and I can more than
other people,
but I,
I,
I don't think most people can handle
like really crazy shit going down and
you can't trust a few people's memories.
Where were we?
You got to take it into consideration,
but you can't totally trust it.
I think you know,
the amount of trauma that contributes to
a confabulation about whether you saw
something or not.
I mean,
you can take those reports all day and I
think there's that mob mentality like I
heard sounds.
Oh,
so did I.
You know,
what creeps me out with always with
American people out and this is how you
get minor conspiracy theorists.
Not even sure if I am one is when there
is no explanation by
your all powerful government and that's
what leads people to think,
oh,
the government was in on it because
you're like,
you're supposed to be the American
government and you don't have an idea
how this happened.
That's when people start to feel unsafe
and get nervous.
When they had bin Laden.
You didn't take any pictures.
Really.
Not One.
I believe they caught him.
It's just odd when there's no answers.
They're like,
we're not sure.
JFK.
That's a weird thing.
Like how do you not have an answer?
I've talked to military people,
just straight up military people about
the Osama bin Laden thing and every one
of them has said that guy was dead for
years.
Every one of them,
I have a couple people that were
skeptical.
I bet that where you would have valued
their opinion,
you know,
I bet they fucking tortured him.
And,
and for years people telling dudes,
man,
right wing straight lace.
That wasn't the war.
Military guys there.
And they're like,
that guy's been dead for years.
I bet his own pee.
I mean I don't,
I don't think they're scaled.
I think you've just because you have put
a couple of bombs somewhere.
These are not,
they're not using like biophysics to
kill anyone.
So I think his own probably friendly
fire probably blew himself up on fucking
accident.
They might've just fucking crashed one
of their helicopters and this was their
crazy cover story.
They might have fucked up,
crashed when their helicopters and goes,
listen boys,
you see lemons,
ice lemonade.
Here's a story.
Crashed a helicopter because we killed
Osama bin Ladin.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We lost a billion dollar helicopter.
Whatever,
whatever.
We're going to blow that up.
It doesn't matter.
Brave soldiers survived that crash.
We got it.
We got them.
We got only dumped him and see we dumped
them.
It's because we do want to make them
harder.
What are you talking about?
You're telling everybody you shot him.
It's just an it in visual form.
It's not the same as you fucking
admitting it with your mouth.
The president getting on TV with his
fucking mouth and admitting it
seriously.
He's looking at the camera and he's
saying it.
We killed ourselves like we.
That doesn't make him a martyr woody.
You have to.
There has to be a visual representation
of it.
That would be something I would have
liked to have seen footage like his face
would you have for us,
but not for them.
Them saying that they're excuse,
that they don't want them to be a
martyr.
Then why the fuck are you admitting you
killed him on TV?
Why are you getting there wasn't a
Martin.
They didn't want the reason they didn't
bury him or do anything.
They didn't want them to be a site that
people could go to,
but the reason why they didn't show any
photos is because they didn't want them
to be a martyr as well.
I think that's because they don't have
any photos that epic would it have been
if Barack Obama,
he's like,
we've captured and killed Osama bin
Ladin,
but before we did our gis,
each had a turn fucking him in the mouth
and thanks to flip cam,
we have it all on our youtube page.
Fuck some crazy old terrorists in the
mouth.
Very soft.
I thought guys like to do that.
You know?
It was so disturbing seeing that other
guy get captured
and dragged through the streets and
fucked in the ass Kadafi.
That was so fucked up.
I am good as a stick apparently.
Oh,
was the.
I did something for that kind of stuff.
Like if there were a picture we wouldn't
have shown.
We're not.
We don't show graphic things like that
and our people don't like to see that.
We don't like to see death.
We like people to die and so on.
We want to completely lose.
I don't want to see it ever again.
Well,
you can.
You know,
the real problem is you get access to
something really shocking.
That's not really happening.
So you,
when you in watching anybody get
murdered,
watching anybody get fucked up,
you have access to something life
changing,
but you're not really there.
That's weird when you can just access
that all the time because then you're
getting influenced by far more than you
would in a normal life where you
actually survive.
Also desensitizes us as a country.
We're desensitized to war.
We have all of our video games,
all of our media,
all this stuff.
We're like war.
Very few of us have actually will call
upper class,
upper middle class have actually been
made privy to anything tangentially
related to war.
And so it's very easy to be like,
yeah,
we'll just send some troops and I've
been to Israel just on vacation and it's
so fucking hot.
I couldn't stand it.
So just imagine being over there like
with all like we have no frame of
reference because we're so desensitized
were detached from it.
They don't.
It's not a part of our daily lives
unless you have friends and loved ones
over there,
you know,
watched something on tv or where they're
talking about the amount of money that
it caused to air condition.
The tense and Afghanistan is fucking
crazy in Iraq and some insane about it.
It's like billions of dollars in a
woman.
It's so crazy to keep the AC on.
Yeah,
they're just leading.
The whole thing is nuts.
It's fucking nuts.
It's nuts that they talk people into it.
It's nuts.
It's still going on to send troops over.
We're living in a Gi joe movie.
That's what it is.
He will even think about it.
I get goosebumps thinking about it at
all.
I don't know why it resonates so deeply
with me to think about our troops over
there.
I think because you're smart.
I love my country so much that I just
want like,
I just love my country and anything
having to do with that.
Look at this.
It's all standing on all my.
I to be in a patriotic commercial.
Do you drive a chevy truck,
a blazer?
Everyone thought I was a lesbian for the
longest time.
He plays it for 10 years.
I drove it out here.
Look,
I think,
uh,
the idea of what America is supposed to
be.
This is awesome.
You know,
I think there's a lot of fucking
creative people here.
A lot of cool people come from America
for sure.
But there's also a lot of clients,
you know,
that,
that represents America as well.
Unfortunately,
you know,
we're doing the shit that we do around
the world.
It's just creepy as fuck.
But we also do great things in life,
better for us to be on top.
And then some,
some wacky countries.
Right?
And we're.
The only ones will take your land.
We'll give it back.
We'll say,
sorry,
we'll make reparations.
We were the only ones with a real
conscious about the Indians.
We
give land back to American Indians.
Gave him some,
given the shittiest spots where there's
no deer like Vegas go.
Yeah.
You want to open a casino?
Go ahead whenever you want to hear
anymore.
They have seven,
11 different Indian.
I'm saying like they have convenient.
They can go eat at a restaurant.
You don't need to worry about.
Well,
I mean people who go like what we did to
the Indians and I'm like,
Oh man,
I wasn't what?
Yeah,
we weren't here.
So at one point in time does the current
living humans who I know they've
benefited from the shitty work of the
past,
I just trust Indians.
Marianna,
you trust them on.
It seemed more like down to what I would
like to hang out with Indians or pirate
pirate guys,
Indiana,
new inspiring farriers.
Have you seen the Jesus Western sky
commercials.
It's like one of those things where it
gives you money before your payday.
Western sky.
It's like a,
it's like a check cashing and it's got
this like Indian drum.
It's like dude.
And this girl that looks like an Indian
native American,
Gina,
go sean with a braid so you know,
she's native,
she's like Western sky,
we'll get you off the payday track,
get off the payday trail western.
And it's so fucking intimidating.
And she's like,
sure it's expensive,
but it's worth it.
And I'm like,
this is the representative for your
people.
Some fucking creepy.
The Indians expensive.
He says that.
So they take like a certain percentage
of your check in order to catch it early
of your soul.
That's like they're into that.
I don't know.
There's actually been some talk that
they're going to release the photos of a
Sama bin Ladin and it's.
Yeah.
And it's like so awesome.
Because I'm thinking like how long did
it take to make Avatar?
Okay,
this is not the same time.
They've probably got some better
technology that Pixar probably has.
Like we have this whole vip section that
we don't talk funny.
Could you imagine if one day there's
cameras that don't just capture a two d
version of what you're saying,
but somehow or another they figure out
some sort of a camera that can actually
capture three dimensional video that you
can walk around inside.
It'll create holograms,
like really potent holograms.
So you could actually be there standing
right there next to the troops.
Why they killed Osama bin Ladin press
play.
Yeah.
You know,
that's,
that's entirely within the realm of
possibility.
If we can create what we can create
right now,
I know it's way more complex,
but it's what we're doing right now is
already impossible to us.
You know,
I don't see any reason why they can't
come up with some really intense high
definition hologram type shit and the
financial reality where you can walk
around in the scene like you can
actually probably do.
I think American.
No,
fuck.
They would line up for that.
Just keep that in Tennessee somewhere.
Yeah.
It's like call of duty,
but with stopping.
Do you ever been in places like
Tennessee or West Virginia and I spent
Christmas in Virginia,
Virginia,
backwoods Virginia.
Whoa.
What are you doing having Christmas?
Do you know somebody?
That's great.
Do you have a friend from there?
What was that like?
Oh my God.
I went to the APA Maddix Maddix.
What's in that courthouse?
Like the civil war.
It's like this tiny went to a civil war
gift shop,
which is not really civil war gift shop
as much as this dude just ordered a
bunch of shit with confederate flags on
it.
So you have like a bathing suit or
whatever.
Homework.
It's really like all small towns in
America are the same.
The more southern you get,
the less teeth,
but for the most part most of America
looks the same and amazing that there's
some assholes out there that are still
fighting that war.
What does it heritage not hate.
That's what it says under the
confederate flag because I understand it
means something to them,
but if I'm a black person it's still.
That's like a swastika could mean peace
and was it jainism?
But most people are like.
It's kind of a shitty thing.
It's a very good point.
The swastika is a very good point.
I mean,
no one believes that.
It means peace.
He's the general of that though.
Like who's the guy in charge of.
I hate the kid rock.
He's from Michigan.
Yeah.
It's a weird thing that you get as the
south of the north.
The North and the south are still at
odds in some spots.
Yeah.
They still use terms like Yankees and
they get angry if your Yankee.
They deal.
It's very weird.
It's weird because we don't have that
feeling.
It's a clear,
the conquer and the conquered northern
as we don't have that problem with like
we like southern accents sound
sophisticated,
sound hot southern accent makes someone
sounds a man of taste and culture.
Who appreciates the.
I hear Amanda Tasting called Georgia
Southern Gentlemen as well,
right?
Texas?
No,
no.
Long drawn out thing.
It sounds like.
You know,
I'm going to Walmart to get some of
that,
but there's also in the dudes that are
intelligent than have that accent.
It's pretty bad ass.
It's one of those things and one of the
appeals of Bill Hicks,
I believe that that Texas accent was
fucking cool.
It's cool here and people from Texas
talk,
Texas,
Texas is one of the coolest ways to
talk.
I really believed that he'd been.
It depends on,
and this is for anything where you're
from because there's a Texas accent and
then if you're from Dallas.
To me it's this very preachy.
I just.
I'm reminded of my teachers that were
like,
no ma'am,
you cannot get it.
Maybe that's just.
Maybe it's just me.
Did anybody ever do anything to you in
Dallas and you drive through,
just stuck in your head like,
you know,
there's certain states of mind that you
entrap in certain areas.
Like for the longest time I would go by
my high school in Newton,
Massachusetts and I would drive by the
high school and I'd be paranoid,
panicked thinking that the,
the I missed a class and they're going
to drag me back in.
I'm not going to get my diploma and I'm
fucked and I have to go back to school.
Like being from there.
Being from Texas,
I think of that teacher talks to you
like this.
We don't like Jews.
Did you ever have a teacher actually say
that?
No,
but I did have a friend who,
this is my really old.
I got out unscathed for the most part.
I had a friend who told me,
uh,
we were like best friends her with
summer and she told me one day we were
like playing and it was like five.
And she goes,
if you don't accept Jesus Christ as your
personal Lord and Savior,
you are going to go to hell.
And I guess I had seen a movie recently
that had this wild,
like we were like six,
five or probably five,
and I guess I had seen a movie in my
automatic response was I have naked
pictures of your mother.
I had heard it like on a movie or
something.
Her mom calls my mom now allows,
said something inappropriate about
having naked pictures of me.
My mom was like,
well to be fair,
you told your daughter,
told my daughter she was going to hell.
And her answer,
her response was,
oh,
well we'll have to talk to her about
that.
She's not supposed to start witness
until she's older.
That was like,
what?
We have supposed to start witnessing.
Oh God.
So you,
you think of things like that?
Not Southern Gentleman.
Oh my God.
Well,
you know boulder,
Colorado,
everybody thinks of hippies,
but it's also a Jonbenet Ramsey from.
Yeah,
that is where that happened.
I still think of hippies,
but I didn't think of Dallas in that
way.
Well,
it's just,
it's a perfect combination of southern
charm with money in a snotty attic.
It's like the Hollywood of Texas.
They're the people of Texas.
I mean,
I love Dallas,
new Cambie.
It's got a lot of money.
So the hardest part of yours,
I'll tell you,
had more semi black out.
Even the whole state of Texas.
We used to do that.
Addison Improv.
My God.
Yeah,
with Joey Diaz.
They'll place was chaos and addison was
the only.
This is not no one cares,
but addison was the only county within
Dallas where you could drink for a very
long time,
like in the eighties,
I think that was World War II.
Yeah.
I feel like parents have these special
tickets.
You had to have something now it has all
the bars,
but you can drink anywhere.
Obviously.
Kind of makes sense that they did that.
That kind of makes sense because it's
such a wild place.
It's a perfect place for that Improv.
That's a great club.
Math club in pro res should fears
headline in that.
Yeah.
He's got a headline that you're in San
Antonio.
You're not impressed.
I'm not impressed.
It's nice.
It's my hometown,
so they had me ex boyfriends ever show
up.
[inaudible] shows.
I've invited them to high school or
something.
Yeah,
that's fine.
Okay.
That's fine.
I don't think so.
I don't know how you communicate with
your ex boyfriends from high school?
No,
but not out of disdain or anything.
Just one you know,
you don't talk to.
And then another one is probably married
and don't have any relationships where
it's like,
I don't want to fucking see him.
I swear to Christ.
None of them know.
It's always ends amicably.
If I saw someone,
I'd probably give him a hug.
I don't know if they would give me a
hug,
but you're usually the one that pulls
the trigger.
I don't think I've ever,
uh,
never been dumped,
which is not going to be anyone like me
anymore.
But yeah,
just funny.
No,
not out of like,
oh,
I always win.
But just,
just,
you always.
When somebody come to a natural end and
listen,
it's part of your spirit,
your competitive.
It's not a bad thing.
You defend it.
It's harder for the person doing the
breaking up.
I think sometimes it is.
You don't want to hurt someone's
feelings because I've been in
relationships for a while,
but I just didn't want to hurt someone's
feelings.
Yeah.
And then when you're the one that has to
do the breaking up,
if you're ever feeling bad about in the
future,
you can't call them because you're the
one that initiated it.
That's like a dick thing.
So you just have to keep it to yourself
and be sad.
So sad.
So hard.
Some people are not meant to be and that
that person needs to find whatever the
fuck they're meant to be with my porch
bitch.
How do you fix one of those domestic
violence holes that sometimes you get in
your walls so you know what it's like a
humongous holding.
Punched you.
Yeah,
because that's something hardcore or is
that really easy to.
Do you ever done any wall board?
Yeah.
Have you ever done any dry wall work and
like I think maybe a patch.
I punched the hole in the wall.
Well you got to be careful because you
don't know what the fuck you're doing.
You could actually,
Natalie,
you know you're going to have to use a
razor knife.
You could accidentally slice.
You're an electrical cord.
All right.
You know you should hire someone to do
it.
I should leave it as a warning to the
next girl.
You know what,
you should do glue some false eyelashes
and fake blood around the edges of it.
And.
Oh,
I thought you were going to.
No,
just because it's in the back.
Make it look like a little like
evidence.
I guess if the girls had just went right
through it.
That's the evidence,
you know,
subtle.
Nothing crazy.
Not a wig.
It's in the bathroom now.
Right.
Toilet.
So it looks like I have a hidden camera
in there now.
You should put a hit on my girlfriend
has to do.
You should put a camera there.
Yeah,
I should have done a webcam up and shit.
Didn't the toilet roll there and make it
look like a road when that role,
no one.
Does it allow people to watch you shit
for like five bucks a month.
I bet you would get.
I bet you'd pay your rent.
I pay to watch you shit.
That could be a good way.
Not Me.
People would definitely do that.
If they could.
If you could,
if you could have subscribed to a 24
hour webcam that's only above the
toilet.
You would get a lot of.
Especially if you're a girl.
When I put the camera in the toilet to
watch the press,
probably illegal.
You're saying showing the actual poop,
showing the actual plant.
That's probably illegal.
Weird show animal poop.
Well,
you know when you get into obscenity
areas like,
like that Guy Max hardcore that got
arrested.
They arrested him in the most stringent
place in the country,
which was like this area of Florida that
have the harshest laws and that's how
they prosecuted him because he was
selling stuff on the Internet.
If you sold stuff to that area.
He's prosecuted by the laws of that area
just to terrible fucking evil porns
where he would do nasty terrible things
to girls.
It's like really,
really like,
but it wasn't shit.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean it is and it isn't because he's
poor fucking girls glut.
He opened up this girl's asshole with a
tool like this thing.
Speculum,
I guess it wouldn't be pissed inside of
it.
And then had her drink the pis through a
straw.
Yeah.
It sounds like something you'd make up.
Exactly.
It sounds completely ridiculous what she
must have been addicted to drugs as
well.
I think,
you know,
there's some really last people out
there,
man,
and he's taking advantage of them and
it's,
it is illegal and I guess it shouldn't
be.
I mean,
I'm not the one that's saying that we
need extra laws,
but I am the one that's saying he's a
fucking creep.
The fact that you would want to do that
to somebody,
you know,
nobody wants you to do that to them.
It was creepy man.
And that's just one of them.
He pisses and girls miles.
I can somehow know the guy who could
piss with a heart on it was really
weird.
I can do that.
Well,
it's just about bending your feet and
pushing it down,
pushing down.
So if I have to,
but do you ever have to pee while you're
having sex?
Ever?
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
I will stop in the middle of the morning
sex all the time.
Oh,
well he pee all the time anyway.
Well he actually,
I was,
this girl was giving him and he,
he's,
he's got a full boner and he pees into
her mouth and it's like falling out.
I mean it's a lot of Pii and then he
shoves her head back down and again I'm
like,
why am I watching this?
I don't know why I'm laughing because
it's gross.
My girlfriend has always been.
I know that poor girl,
she was like,
you know,
like your next door neighbor and you
knew that her mom,
her and you grew up and you know,
she was like that 14 year old girl that
looked to you for guidance and peed in
her mouth.
No,
a car hit the wall.
Yeah,
he did some time.
I think he's out now.
I think.
I'm not sure,
but it was a really controversial,
um,
sort of a situation because nobody
wanted to defend him.
I mean,
not nobody,
a lot of people did,
but a lot of people were,
you know,
a lot,
a lot of people in the porn industry.
We're saying good,
fuck him.
He's a creep.
Like what he does is gross and there's a
lot of people that like,
they don't want that to be in the same
lumping as regular size there.
Right,
right.
Well,
beggars can't be choosers.
My girlfriend has this hot oil she puts
in her hair in the shower that's
supposed to help damaged hair or dry
hair kind of issue.
Black kind of.
I wasn't even joking.
I don't use hot oil.
Well what we do,
but not like black people.
Anyways,
it's spilled in the.
She wasn't using it but it's spilled
into the bathtub and I stepped in the
bathtub.
Did one of those like seriously,
like three stooges.
That back flip by God,
I'd hit the wall less,
Huh?
Yeah.
So that's how you got this whole.
He has announced this huge bowling ball
hole.
You're super lucky and people die that
way.
Man.
The Tub is actually a way that people
die on a regular basis.
Will slip in the shower.
Were you supposed to get rock hard right
when you guys started?
You get super hard,
like the hardest you've ever gotten.
It's kind of like that.
The death building.
Yeah.
I've heard that and I've heard it's only
if you get like certain poisons,
certain certain toxins,
your body or something.
I just want to die.
I certainly want to do.
That'd be awesome if it happens.
That's what I'm saying.
What a death Boehner wasn't in that
movie too.
That's the one that the Nicolas cage
movie where he played a Elisabeth Shue.
He played leaving Las Vegas,
leaving Las Vegas.
Original title was deaf.
Like yeah,
it's not going to sell in the blue
states in the red states or other.
Sounds like rock band.
Awesome.
This should be a fucking band.
Just her for sure.
I'm sure there is.
Can we google it?
Yeah,
but there is.
Owner of a dog is ripping apart.
Yeah,
right.
Absolutely.
I mean,
I think if you ask any guys wikipedia,
skinny guys,
you would want to dive,
have a boner,
but I don't think if you asked her,
you know,
with no,
if you have a boner,
I think injuries,
spinal cord injuries known to be
associated with prep,
a priapism,
injuries,
injuries to the cerebellum or spinal
cord are often associated with pariah.
Prism is that it prepares them in living
patients.
So it's when,
when some people,
when they're talking about like death by
hanging executions,
shit like that dude's Dick,
get hard.
That's the way to go.
Is that because they've observed the
effects of the genitals of both men and
women.
Jesus Christ,
where they shoot a chicken the head and
then check to see if she's in the lobby.
Oh my God.
The Labia,
Labia and quit.
Quitters becoming gorged and there may
be a discharge of blood from the vagina
here.
Uh,
yeah.
My God.
It's like nature's Hail Mary.
Hail Mary in nature's like listening.
We might be dying right now.
So just like any.
Let anybody fuck us and maybe we'll get
pregnant.
Bloody death.
Tier blood is already your body's,
your body doesn't know what to do.
That's what it is.
It's a rap song.
Wow.
Fatal gunshot wounds.
The brain that's happens.
No is just wikipedia and some articles
that references,
but it's.
It's actually a real phenomenon that
happens sometimes.
Pretty fucking nuts.
Debt,
boner.
You Die.
What do you want to be?
Wet Du du Du,
Du.
Look,
do you want.
Do you want.
Why would I care?
Because we know all guys would want to
have a bone corner looking and I don't
want anywhere.
Report really.
Shoes really wet.
Like I just want to be a nice normal
death.
Nothing like freaky.
Does it drive you crazy?
That coordinator gets the CNA who at my
husband,
whoever finds me to be like,
she was so key.
She was so turned off because that makes
you weird.
Then they're gonna Think,
oh,
she died when she was watching the
golden girls and she was like,
you're going to think it's a thing.
I don't want any of that.
Yeah,
it's going to be on your death report.
Wet that's under,
under under moisture was watching golden
girls because I watch it every night
before I go to bed.
God forbid I have an aneurysm medium and
ready to rock.
So you're that addicted to the golden
girls that you've named or Dog African?
No,
it just happens to be a coincidence.
Yeah.
Should I just picked an old lady name
and blanche came into my head and then
as of late I started watching the golden
girls,
but this was.
I got her like three years.
Have you watched the golden girls?
Is it because it's on when I go to bed.
I love it.
Good show.
It's relaxing.
A warm hug to you when you watch the
show?
Yeah.
What's one more time?
It's the writing is so smart.
I haven't watched that sit common
friends over.
It's on a one of our affiliate,
whatever.
If you had to sleep with one,
which one would it be in mind?
It's always Betty White.
Why would you say back in the day she
was the hottest ones.
She was a young qc.
Feisty one.
You remember?
They were all like 900 years old.
Well,
one was creepy,
one was that quagmire that whatever.
That's why wouldn't you want to sleep
with Rue mcclanahan?
She was the one that quagmire.
She was a woman.
That was her thing really for
rheumatoid.
Okay.
The Betty White played rose and she was
an idiot.
Bea Arthur played Dorothy's born acc who
was really smart street feet tall.
Yeah.
She was a lesbian and real life.
And then rue mcclanahan who played
blanche devereaux who was a self
proclaimed slut and she was always
running off to lack sleep with some
eligible young men.
Right.
And you would want to sit with that one
because she was Betty White all the way.
That was the Krissy,
Krissy.
Oh Chris,
who is the best one?
Who's Chrissy?
And the third one.
The third one was Chrissy.
She was the second one.
First one.
First is Ann Summers.
She was back in the day.
We're in this little shorts and she was
the best one.
Yes,
definitely.
Would you ever want to sleep with an
older woman?
Like I was asleep.
Uh,
Suzanne somers,
like older,
like 60,
like 68,
68,
probably not.
Suzanne somers is probably that unlocked
the secret to living young.
She has the book on it.
Alright.
Demi Moore on drugs.
She's not 68 by any means.
She's like almost 50.
Okay.
That's different.
Yeah,
she's hanging in there.
I guess she had some sort of a reaction.
Did you hear about that shit?
It was like red bull or something like
that.
That's where they're,
that's know what it is.
She said,
well,
she apparently drinks nitrates and she
did Salvia.
And that's,
that's what it is.
Hearing this from.
You can't just say this.
Allegedly for TMZ.
TMZ was reporting that it was a whatever
the nitrous oxide,
which could be true because she had a
seizure.
She fished,
but that last like five to 10 minutes
I've fished before now.
Salvia.
The police report they had,
they censored the nine one,
one call because of personal privacy and
then they,
they,
uh,
the police report came out as that she
smoked something.
So you don't smoke.
So I'm thinking it's Salvia.
I'm thinking that was.
What was she smoking?
Are you sure that the police report said
she smoked something or you just hearing
this from tmz?
TMZ was reporting on it,
so that's what it is.
Really.
Say that though.
Then I'll finish it with allegedly.
Why don't.
Why don't we just google it real quick
just so that we don't get in trouble?
No,
I'm 99 point nine percent sure.
What was I talking about?
You were talking about her.
Well,
I just,
I don't know.
I just feel bad if the information is
probably out there more.
You're saying that it was nitrous oxide
and so I heard it was red bull.
Someone called it a death puddle data
wet.
Oh,
a smoked.
Her Pr people wouldn't put a spin on it.
The media doesn't have an allegiance to
the truth about celebrities,
so it's whatever they hear,
they're going to NBC right next to
Rachel Maddow.
You need your own.
Because I said allegiance.
No,
you'd be great at it.
You're very articulate.
You've got a great vocabulary.
You'd kick ass on one of those shows and
you'd be able to make fun of Shit.
Why don't you just.
What I want is that what you want to
have a pilot we're doing with vh one.
I want to have my own late night chit
chat,
like a talk show podcast,
yet I have a website that I do every
week.
Oh,
you do a on.
Of course one loves sound off on why
people are wrong every Monday.
What is it?
What do you do?
Call the weekly news,
the weekly news,
type it in.
Go to the stream as in water,
the stream.tv/and
then put the swimsuit or underwear
weekly.
W E a k o y for five years.
Yup.
Demi Moore and three m dot TV.
What is their a slash weekly wea.
Why?
Demi Moore has smoked something similar
to incense and semi conscious.
Barely said the word voice on the 911
call to get more help.
So similar to incense.
Fucking idiot who smoked.
Closest thing to.
Similar to incense of Salvia.
You think I'm a hundred percent.
She smoked Salvia.
She didn't already shifted into a
different world.
You know,
I'm going to have you ever saw that
video is awesome.
Similar to incidents.
That's sage.
Salvia,
yes,
Salvia.
So she went to the other world,
which you can easily do dmt style.
Like I mean you can get it pretty close
to dmt kind of effects from it.
She,
but my question is why did,
maybe she,
her body had a little stroke because of
it or something because of her age,
because she's not that old man.
The old for a hot chick.
She's not like,
oh,
like she's in trouble.
The only reason I say that because after
you know,
10 minutes,
15 minutes,
you usually are fine.
So unless the ambulance was right next
door would be speculating.
Yeah,
maybe I'm totally speculating.
Something similar to insights does sound
like Salvia because sage,
the sage is something that people
frequently burned to like ward off
spirits and shit.
And then sage is the Salvia plant.
It's like the same plant.
Whoever was the same.
Exactly know what she was doing.
So they're obviously covering up the
fact that she was doing something that
they don't want the public to know that
it's possible.
I would like something similar to
smoking and no one would say that that's
such a ridiculous thing to pull out of
your ass.
I just don't think they want to
advertise that it was probably because
it's still legal in most states and they
just don't want to advertise it at all.
That's right.
That's a good point.
That's a very good point because if it
was an actual illegal drug that would
want to know what the drug was and since
probably that makes a real a lot of
sense to do.
You should be a fucking detective.
I know.
Forgot that.
You should just.
You should really for CSI or something
like you totally did the math there.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because if it was anything else,
if it was like she was smoking cocaine,
like Whoa.
They would tell you,
hey she.
This is a sensational story.
She's a poor girl.
She's smoking cocaine,
which is smoking something similar to
incense and that's why she salvia can
fuck your world up.
I'll have to do is look at that video of
Ra on your or me or you talking about my
face,
but when Ra was on your show?
Yeah,
when he was on TV and he did Salvia and
just melted into everybody.
Yup.
Yeah,
and he was calling up a Sam.
It was so cute.
She and if somebody talked to her to
doing that and she's not used to
psychedelics,
if she hasn't had a second,
I'm just not used to something and she
had a bad trip and maybe she's on some
other things or it could also be that it
know,
ignited some,
like horrible insecurity in her too.
And she had a panic attack.
Been secure about the arts.
I'm totally kidding.
I love you to do that.
I typed in the stream.tv
the weekly,
but it says,
oh,
the stream.tv/slash
w slash o weekly w e a k?
Yeah.
Oh,
okay.
I don't have a strong point of view.
I got.
Oh,
okay.
You create a show.
We did one on Monday.
The weekly news.
Powerful.
And so you do this every week.
Every Monday we have a studio and it's a
network and those other shows on there
and we'd been doing it for about five
years.
Oh really?
You know,
eventually this is going to be a
television station.
Huh?
I mean that is the future.
He's got some the owner of the thing.
It's got some pretty cool things going,
but that's my little forum.
Cool.
Alright.
We'll tell people to go there.
Fuck yeah,
for sure.
We're not too sure.
Boom.
It's done.
We've just made a date.
We had a segment called who should be
shot where we argue the lesser of two
evils.
It usually has to do with who should be
shot.
The supplier of the demand and then we
talk about something so you can.
You can either.
You can pick what side you're on
supplier or the demand for specific
things for terrible things like guns or
something like that.
Well,
no,
it's more.
It's not as heavy handed.
Like last week I was talking about how
much I hate chocolate fountains,
so who should be shot the fat fucks that
wait in line or the caterer that's like,
Ooh,
chocolate Belgian.
Let me give you one,
why is it bad?
Strawberries with chocolate?
Yummy.
That's fine.
But then people start to get into like,
oh,
what else can I dip in the road?
Stop?
And by the end it's all like there's
garbage in it and you partying with the
wrong people.
Yeah.
Like golden corral.
I have to stop hanging out with those
people.
Golden Corral.
What is that?
That's where they have a chocolate
fountain.
It's the golden corral.
Poor people.
The crowd.
It's like you've probably somewhere in
the valley.
It's a like a family,
like,
you know,
like a,
um,
would it be like,
like a,
you never heard of hometown buffet or
like a Bob Evans,
like it's like a place,
like a lot of food for a little money.
Not Super Nice,
but trying to think of some names in
different places like tabulate that
escaped me.
Less nice than a red lobster.
Yeah.
Kinda like that.
A little bit nicer to is their big thing
is that they have a chocolate fountain.
So.
Well that's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about if you go to
somebody's Dope Party and they've got a
chocolate fountain,
do you ever go to someone's part of that
just goes ridiculous.
I went to this dude's party.
He had this crazy party in Malibu and
he's like some super super billionaire
type character and he had brought in
snow and the whole hill was covered in
snow and people were sledding at the
entrance to your little community you
live in.
There's a big thing that says snow day
like because you know this dude had it
on.
He had a ramp built like it was
constructed because they didn't have
enough of a grade for a hill.
So he built it up just for the party or
just for the party.
That's cool.
It was crazy.
They had so much shit going on,
but no chocolate fountain.
I was this bitch ass party and I think
they become so pedestrian like everyone
has them now.
I wouldn't want it.
I loved them with strawberries.
Strawberries are not the same.
It's not the same chocolates like it's
shitty chocolates,
but I have a blog about it so I don't
want to repeat my blog will repeat it
because I'm not going to read it.
No,
no,
no.
I'm just saying like I don't want to.
I don't want it to look like I read my
blog and then I go into like chocolate
pellets that you can buy it.
Like,
no,
not like that.
It's like a special kind of chocolates.
Kind of like it's just gross.
It's just not the good chocolate
chocolate.
And if you're a deli,
dark chocolate,
some some fucking bad ass chocolate and
that was melted.
Would you be down?
Because I also don't like chocolate
tolerating far as.
Oh
my God,
she's such a strange woman.
She is so strange.
I don't like chocolate with her dogs.
Substitute for a child.
She fucking hating chocolate.
Candy and dumping men undefeated streak.
She's undefeated.
The undefeated streak of men who a dog
everywhere with her.
Do you mimic nursing that with that dog?
Ever terrible.
I wish I could say that I not only gave
birth to her,
but that I nursed her up.
I mean,
do you,
uh,
do you have the urge to reproduce out a
baby one day?
If you could have a baby with that dog
with one dude that you decide to keep
around because I'm going to say,
listen,
you know,
you're,
you've been picked for your genetics and
intelligence,
but don't tell them what to do here.
We're going to make a baby together.
I'm going to kill him now.
What if you already jerked off that day
and he's got nothing left for you?
What?
What'd you have for sure?
Yeah,
I think it gets weird when you don't
want to be the girl that nagging your
boyfriend about it or something you
don't want me to go and talks about all
the time,
but I think,
you know,
we are genetically predisposed as women.
We're maternal.
We do want that one day.
So I take care of this little dog,
but I don't.
It's not like on my mind like,
I'm just going to babysit you.
Happens to draw pictures of what you
want your baby to look like or anything
weird like that.
Does that
the fuck?
Is that what you're black raven?
Way To make blogging creepy as fuck.
If anybody could make that the most
beautiful of natural urges.
Seem creepy as fuck.
It's you picturing some fucking crazy
lady sitting there sketching out what
she wants her kids teeth to be
because I like that.
I think you fucking know.
Yeah.
Well that's the thing man.
Some people like anything.
There's a lot of people that like all
kinds of crazy shit.
You know?
That's one of the worst things about
growing up as experiencing the different
things that people not only tolerate but
actually love and then you try to bring
them up with another person like get the
fuck Outta here.
They get angry at you.
I do it all the time.
I dropped my weight.
I want my baby to look like.
I'm sure somebody has for sure so many
mustangs.
They must've.
Babies are a little weird looking at
first.
Sure.
Well,
they're terrified to know.
You look at it terrified object.
You're like,
oh Jesus,
poor little thing.
They have like dry skin sometimes and
you're like,
what the fuck's going on here?
I'm like,
it's very tricky man.
Raising little babies is very tricky.
Keeping them for diseases.
Shots,
you know not to eat cat poop.
I can't imagine like,
oh yeah,
you
gotta watch them every step.
I had my one and a half year old is just
now at the stage where I can let her get
like one or two feet in front of me
doing something.
You've got to be right there right
there.
What are you doing?
What's going on?
And then maybe a.
sometimes she'll be in an area where she
can't mess anything up.
She was wandering around the bathroom
like,
okay,
I've got an eye on you.
I'll let you walk a little,
but you have to always be right there in
case you're like,
what is this?
I like this and stick it in there.
You know?
They don't know.
They don't know anything.
Your baby
crazy.
How you have that desire to protect her
in the like.
It's not hard for you to make sure she's
safe.
Like it's a natural instinct.
Even people who don't have children
really have no idea what it,
what the experience is like.
It's,
it's so hard to describe.
I thought I could kind of guess what it
would be like before I actually had
kids.
I would think it was probably really
intense love and you know,
it's probably really hard to probably
test your patience,
but you're,
you know,
you really want.
It's not like that at all.
You actually get let get love and
pleasure from it.
That's what I didn't understand.
I thought it even like the difficult
times of raising kids.
I thought it would be stressful and it
would be,
it would be something that you regret,
but you get like,
you get so much love from it.
It's so fun.
It's like you actually get.
It's rewarding.
That's what I didn't anticipate that.
It's like the fun involved in raising
kids.
It's like if you're enjoying it,
you know,
and you're enjoying like raising them
and talking to them and hanging out with
them and playing with them.
It's,
it's so rewarding.
I didn't anticipate that.
I thought it was just going to be,
you know,
loving but difficult.
It's so much different than
I thought that initially.
I mean the fact that you're.
This is not a slight against men like
women are obviously more in tune with
being maternal and mothers and all that
stuff,
so it's not about being a guy,
but do you think being a comic,
because when I watch comics that are
fathers reluctant fathers,
not everyone planned to have a kid.
I was get the vibe that people hate
their marriages,
hate their kids,
so that's always the way I felt like,
oh,
I got this kid off my kids annoying and
I'm like,
do you think you felt that way?
Because a lot of your friends or whoever
you would watch when you were coming up
had a disdain toward being a father.
Think as comics,
you know,
we,
we're all can speak for the whole group
and say that we're pretty much all
fucked up and super selfish,
super selfish and fucked up in one way
or another.
You know,
I don't,
I don't know.
Everybody's got their own little kink
and most,
for most of us,
it came from our childhood,
right?
Most of us,
it came from either parents splitting up
or you know,
being ignored or weird shit that makes
you want,
not all of us,
but the vast majority,
the overwhelming need to do it.
So much so that you'll,
you're willing to risk your self esteem
by going onstage,
in front of strangers.
Right?
You know,
and I think when you've been through
that,
you're automatically apprehensive as a
potential parent of like recreating same
sort of environment that you had to
experience when you were a child.
So you're really reluctant to be in some
situation where you,
you know,
you're gonna fuck up the same way
someone fucked up with you.
Oh,
that's one way of looking at it.
Okay.
That is exactly how I looked at it.
You know?
And then there's also the part of being
connected to this other person,
responsible for them,
not the baby,
the other person that you've made with,
um,
because you have to choose wisely
because I have friends that have had
babies with fucking crazy people and
their life is chaos there.
Life is craziness and the woman is
constantly fucking with them and trying
to make him jealous and doing horrible
things and saying bad things to the kids
and it's just constant chaos,
you know?
And then he's got to always deal with
the,
the new boyfriends and all these new
guys that are run as kids.
Like I've seen people that have that
have had kids with the wrong person and
it's just been a disaster.
So there's that too.
It's so weird because in my early
twenties,
like,
that's when you,
you know,
you're on your own for the first time
and you're whatever I'm in say La and I
would watch these male comics and a lot
of them.
And I'm sure you and I know several,
we have several in common where some guy
probably in his forties,
just some woman and she happened to be
the one that stuck around,
so now he's married and he's like,
you never hear him talk about his wife.
He kind of doesn't like her or he like
had sex with a crazy girl and now they
have a kid and he likes the kid,
but he hates the woman.
And I think men get to dictate the way
society feels about marriage because
just being the stronger of the sexes and
whatever guys like is always like the
cooler thing.
Girls are always,
no one ever wants to do the girl stuff.
What do you mean by that?
Like women always want to wear men's
clothing.
Women want to go with the guys are
always like,
guys,
you know,
girls always want to be part of the
boy's club.
No guys knocking down the door to get
in.
The girls club been like to be part of
the,
you know,
we want our comedy is male centric and
everything we do,
we want to be one of the guys.
And taken seriously like men,
so the view on kids and marriage,
you at least as a comic,
I'm watching them and they seem so
unhappy so it all of a sudden becomes
like uncool to have a baby.
And that's.
I've noticed a lot of girls saying
things like,
I don't want to have kids.
I don't want to get married.
I don't want to be in a relationship the
fuck you don't.
You have to.
Of course you do.
It's just become the thing.
Does your to say that you don't want
that because women think men find it
more attractive.
Oh Wow.
How many women are running that game?
So pretend they don't want relationship
or they think they don't.
I mean,
I host a show and I hear girls all the
time and I'm looking at it.
You're a skank horror.
Like I'm looking at your eyeliner job.
Like I can tell that you saw dick a lot.
So I minor tells you that they suck.
A lot of it depends on the book and I've
loved it for the rest of us can tell you
going to wear like white eyeliner.
Your let's get serious.
Okay.
Girl with white island lashes.
It sounds like.
It depends.
It depends on where you have your
makeup,
but I can tell by what you're wearing.
I can tell and then you hear them and
they're like,
I don't want a relationship.
I don't want a guy checking up me.
You want
the right that you're not immune to it
and you say that because you want to
draw the guy in like,
oh really cool.
I'm totally no woman.
I mean I like my space,
but I would be upset if the man I was
dating but never called me weird.
So grow.
But it's not necessarily her fault.
Yes.
How many at a time?
Uh,
I had a boyfriend and we lived together
when I was 25 for about a year and then
I had a boyfriend who visited for a
summer and then I have a boyfriend who's
from months on end but never like we
both signed the lease and it's always
kills it when you're young or if you'd
like to do that.
You should never do that when you're
like,
I've never seen that.
I did that when I was 21.
It's totally killed our relationship.
I really loved her.
Before that,
she was fine.
I was like,
oh,
this is a disaster.
I guess it depends on the car.
I probably in the messier,
like I tend to date guys that are
opposite me,
so I enjoy living with someone because
I.
it's nice to have someone to hang out
with and talk to.
That's nice if you find a good person,
but it's very difficult to do.
When you're 20,
21 you're saying you don't even know how
crazy you are until you live with
something and then they let you know how
crazy you are.
Crazy as of late and it's great because
then like as a girl,
if you like to bake,
then you can bake for them and you don't
have to eat it because guys will eat
anything you like to bake and not eat
things.
I like to.
I love baking.
It's Cathartic.
I have so fascinating.
Listen to your point of view as a,
an intelligent woman explained to us the
traps.
That chick setup that we already
suspected.
We all knew it.
We've had these conversations with
ourselves.
Tell me when a girl says to you,
I don't want relationship,
what do you think she's telling you we
can fuck.
That's what she said.
It means two things.
She probably doesn't like if you're,
you may be gone on a couple of times.
She's like,
I'm just not ready.
She doesn't like it.
She does to you,
but it's a lure if she likes you.
And she's like,
no,
I'm totally cool.
Like she might be a cool girl,
but she does want a relationship.
No girl wants to be cool with you.
Just like sleeping with other girls and
stuff like that.
And if she does,
she's got that issue.
What about girls?
Were this the one hot girl that has all
these guy friends?
I can't do that.
That's a weird one.
I'm a tomboy.
When I wrote my cosmo article on,
I have that in there.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Uh,
first of all,
as the girl who was always been a tomboy
and always had guy friends,
when you have a sick,
like a serious significant other,
it takes the place of the relationship
you form with a lot of guys you don't
need because you have that male
influence in your life.
You don't,
you can't just ditch your friends.
You seem to need it more than most.
So you're very aggressive.
What's that about?
But your womanly,
you're not like Nike,
but you're very aggressive.
What is that about?
Know?
But it's a warm.
It's a warm,
friendly aggression.
Like I never feel around you.
You're always friendly,
but I can tell that you're like friendly
animal.
Yeah.
Well you're like,
you have a good competitor and some
something athletic.
I wasn't afraid of getting punched in
the face.
I could have been a really good fighter.
Oh,
well you just got to learn Jujitsu,
get get a good clench,
high guard d video game,
and start slowly with a good trainer.
How old are you now?
Twenty eight.
Damn.
It's not too late.
You can still get in there.
Not even Mario Kart.
No,
I don't do video games.
I don't pay.
Are you strong?
I'm really strong.
Really?
Yeah,
but I'm a man.
You don't have guys that are met.
Not the same weight class either.
Can I punch too confident?
You could.
If somebody taught you how to do it,
you could throw it killed my dog.
Your dog,
your my dog and your cat.
Whoa.
I bet your kid and killed my cat.
Not the male that he would fuck you up.
I actually wanted to take a class.
You would think you'd kill them.
Let's say you grabbed them.
They start when they bite.
You are such pussies for countless
trying to kill you.
If a cow was like trying to kill you,
you think so?
If he got a hold of your neck,
what if he bit.
I'll drive it into the concrete.
Yeah,
but what if you're both dead?
What if you're both dead owner and
you're gone?
It's a wrap,
but the cat.
You should have asked.
I want to take like a class.
I will go.
Maybe I'll tape it.
I'll go.
I want to take like one,
maybe like a boxing class.
Well,
no,
you don't tape it.
What you want to do is,
especially in the beginning,
you need someone to stand with you and
and adjust things like adjust your
shoulders,
adjust your hand position because
especially in the beginning,
it's very important that you learn with
proper technique because the foundation,
the principles that you learn,
the habits that you formed in the
beginning,
a lot of times they stick with guys and
they get really good.
So when they get tired they go back to
their shitty technique.
So you have to learn correctly from the
beginning.
You don't want to have to correct
yourself.
So you're thinking while you're out
there.
So from the beginning you only want to
do it one way the correct way.
So if you really want to learn how to do
it,
where do you live?
Well,
don't tell me on the air in Hollywood
shit.
Fuck.
Are you doing?
They're going to find you.
Why do you live in the devil's ball sack
one?
Why do you live right there?
Just because you live in like a really
nice neighborhood,
but like Hollywood is taking it dirty.
Like I'm surprised that you're not like
Burbank.
Exactly.
Burbank in his butt hole was a nice
place.
Dinner.
It's relaxing.
I don't have to worry about people
fucking peeing on me.
How much is your rent a month?
A two bedroom apartment is $1,400
rent.
I have a mortgage yet.
But have you bought a place in
Hollywood?
Did you get a condo or a condo?
That's not bad.
Why?
Just say like smart and the area is
getting better.
Eighties Hood.
Somebody had a,
it was one of those TV shows.
They show the insides of people's houses
and uh,
like Paris Hilton or someone famous like
that might not have been her,
but someone had a one of apartments in
on,
on Wilshire,
you know those penthouses on Wilshire
Boulevard where they have like valets.
They have like 24 hour concierge,
like the older,
like all the way to Santa Monica on the
way to say it was really nice one.
Yeah.
The super duper luxury apartments.
This was the dopest view.
Like I didn't know what kind of view
these,
there's no views like this in La and
it's so high that you know,
you're,
you're way up there in this tower
looking over the city.
I'm like,
wow,
I'm not really into living in the city,
but if I was,
this would be with the shit areas.
I feel like it's where your grandparents
lived that I would want to have an
office in that place.
I looked at it and the thing I thought I
would want to buy one of those
apartments and use it as an office.
That'd be amazing.
But they're really expensive.
They're stupid.
They're like 20 million bucks or
something crazy.
It's on the west side is as bad as the
west side.
Then there's no comedy clubs over there.
That's true.
There's no.
I mean for the most part,
everything I need is in Hollywood.
That kind of dictated where I bought
something I liked to.
Because you have the luxury of living
farther out.
You have a bit more control over your
career than I do,
but you have to go to Hollywood all the
time almost every night and you have
your gig set or you don't.
You're not auditioning like a crazy
blind move.
I moved down here 10 minute drive.
Tango grows.
Why Burbank?
It's not cool.
It's I'm living just to have a quiet.
I can go in my backyard and be quiet
night.
I can.
I can have parking everywhere.
You have a backyard fenced in.
Okay,
cool.
So you can just plan your funeral now.
Plenty.
Your funeral.
I go to Hollywood.
Takes 10 minutes.
I'm on fucking sunset.
I just hang out in Sun.
Then I drive back home to my nice quiet
castle was that,
but instead of going and staying in the
party that's in the center up all night
while people are torturing your house,
if you like.
Um,
Manhattan.
Do you like that kind of city in New
York?
Do you really?
Would you live in Manhattan?
What I've missed,
like if I were to move there now it
would kind of be like I'd have.
It wouldn't help me and be like a
lateral move because it's not like I'm.
I always think it's so funny when you
might actually be a step down.
You have to start over with the comedy
clubs and everything.
I think it's so funny.
When I meet girls like actresses or
other hosts,
they're like,
I'm back coastal.
I'm like,
oh,
really?
Is New York just calling you just every
month?
You got to go back heads.
Don't know.
You fly to Florida once a year to visit
your parents.
You're not bi coastal.
I was bi coastal for about two months,
two apartments,
so I'd fly back.
I'm like,
why don't even have this fucking place?
Especially when you deal with the first
winter and get a nice winter in
California.
Like,
what the fuck am I doing?
My whole family's from New York.
Really?
Actually,
they're all from New York City.
The city people.
I mean they start then and there from
long island and those are the various
trainings.
People who are born and raised in New
York City,
the city,
the animal,
they don't understand.
They don't understand a lot of parts of
the world today.
I don't even know what a pizza is.
Don't.
A lot of them don't drive.
Don't ever drive.
They don't ever get licensed
so they want to go somewhere on
vacation.
It's a real pain in the ass.
You have to go get a driver's license.
They take driving classes and learned
how to drive and then when they're on
the road somewhere they're incompetent.
They really shouldn't be driving because
it's its own microcosm,
but I do relate to how aggressive New
Yorkers are and the like the how
forceful they are when they taught.
Like I like that because I feel like
that's how I come off.
Do you like like really calm men?
Yeah.
You like,
like dudes are like sweeties want to rub
your feet and not,
not pussies,
but just very mellow.
Very important.
You're very much right.
Yeah,
but I mean I'm not like in bed,
like don't look at me,
turn it right.
Like it's on your book and they can be
aggressive,
like a quiet aggressive.
You can't be on top,
but you only like two minutes of a sex
at a time and let's get very tired after
you have to pee a lot so you can have
sex for like,
oh,
went all night.
I ain't got it.
You just don't enjoy it.
There's girls out there that are free or
they probably were white eyeliner.
Why say why not?
Why do you have to hate?
Why can't they just be different than
you can you just enjoy your two minutes
and they enjoy the couple hours.
That's fair.
Cowboy touch.
Your girls like getting fucked all the
time.
There's just some freaky bitches.
Crazy amounts of.
Was this the one that you all left your
podcast early?
Oh,
that's sad.
Girl that sat next to you on the
icehouse chronicles podcast,
right?
Yeah,
that was.
I walked in and you were like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Right when I walked in,
you were going after.
I was like,
oh no.
What do we keep saying?
They're like,
you gave it to her.
You were polite.
You are being mean,
but you were laughing.
There was some certain things that she
was saying.
That's the way it was.
That's all it is.
It was just sad.
You know that that same.
That's like really obvious struggle for
attention by being overly sexual to put
that podcast never was released.
Yeah.
I always just.
You know what?
It's fun to talk about sex,
but I honestly feel that a straight up
sexual,
it can be the lowest form of
communication,
especially between men and women.
Like if all else fails,
you can always talk about how you get
off and so when we go right to that it's
like,
oh,
we're not going to attempt to discuss
anything.
Alright,
sure.
Quite hitting on me.
I'm sure everyone listening,
we get hit on a lot by women.
I don't put myself in situations where
lesbians are coming at me.
No,
I mean like you have to have a fan base
of women that are lesbians.
Do you ever get girls and say,
I don't want just like you.
And then I figured it out.
Fuck man.
Meet me at sunset and I have come to the
show.
Really.
I mean,
not like in droves,
but would you have sex with rosie if,
if it was offered,
offered?
No,
but I do think people are a little hard
on her.
She's not.
She's a heavy woman,
but it's not like she's repugnant,
like whatever.
She's very nice.
I'm sure she is.
I really enjoyed talking to her.
I was really looking forward to.
I flew in really early just to do our
show.
I had like a 6:00
AM flight.
She's,
I mean she's been around.
She's putting in the work member.
She's nice.
Was it exit to Eden?
Wasn't one where the snm club or the.
Yeah,
I remember.
I remember the scene where she was
dressed up in the crazy output leather
bullshit.
Then choosing like the Flintstones to
her crying in baseball.
You're so good enough.
At the moment she played the mentally
challenged girl on the bus riding the
bus with my sister.
Oh my God.
That had all their shitty movies and
Mcdowell who I think is the worst fake
southern,
like worst thing ever.
Rosie O'donnell is retarded in this
movie and what I don't buy about it is
that she's a mean retard and retarded
people aren't mean.
She's amazing.
She's mean and smart and sarcastic one.
So it's just like rosie o'donnell,
but a little slower.
Oh No.
Like it was just like she was like,
you want.
He didn't like her really as a.
She was like a mean retard.
You Watch this movie and it just.
There was nothing to her face.
Did it look retarded?
She was just like bitchy.
So she was just,
she came off like a stupid person,
you know?
I consulted whenever a person who's not
really mentally challenged plays a
person who's mentally challenged.
Was the movie Pacific,
whatever the fuck it was were.
What's his name?
Downey.
Robert Downey says,
never go.
Full Retard.
Oh,
thunder.
Opposite of Tropical Pacific Retard
because he played simple Jack Sippel
jacket.
Never go.
Full Retard.
Retard.
Come on.
I mean,
it's so true.
Every time someone does,
but people try it.
Everyone thinks they're good enough to
try it.
Even fucking Sean Penn went there.
Was it?
I think they do.
You can have brain damage and not be
because if you're retarded,
your face will look different and their
faces are all still stunning.
Mean Down Syndrome going to be retarded
without having to have a problem with,
you know,
like even the word retard has been kind
of distracted from the vernacular,
you know,
we're,
we're saying we're throwing it around
real easy.
We're going to Piss a lot of people off.
Just retards that.
Listen here.
It's a tricky word now.
It didn't use to be and it doesn't mean
down syndrome.
Well it does.
In this rosie o'donnell,
chase,
what retarded actually means slow.
Like in music,
you have a retard retard out when things
go slow.
So taken up with the Italians will.
It should not only that,
the,
you know,
the fire has been retarded.
You can say that.
Okay.
And I retired in chip.
Well couldn't use it.
Yes.
It retardant,
yes.
But couldn't you say the fire has been
retarded because of the,
uh,
the,
the gas we are spraying
on it.
The fire's been retarded.
You could say that.
It wouldn't necessarily buy is this.
This is crazy,
crazy retarded.
Yo.
We taught it.
Yeah.
Well I had this woman came up to me
after a show once where I used to do
that bit about knowing the arc,
you know,
I do this bit about knowing the arch and
the bit.
Was that an eight year old retarded boy.
You can tell him the story of Noah in
the Ark and he would have some questions
and he was so you would tell like I had
the best storytellers in the world who
told this incredible story that no one
arc.
And then the eight year old retired boy
will go,
oh,
there's a lot of holes in the kid sits
down.
It just breaks down Noah's our.
I had this woman come up to me after a
show and she goes,
I thought that was really funny except
the fact that I have a retarded son,
whatever.
And I'm like,
you know,
I don't know what to tell you.
You know?
I'm sorry.
I'm not really making fun of retarded
people.
I'm sort of saying smart.
Well I know it's.
We have to sort of admit in,
in,
in any,
like anything you do that's creative.
It's supposed to be an expression of how
you view life and the culture,
right?
We are.
We supposed to never use retarded people
because they don't exist.
We can't use him as an example.
What she was laughing at all the other
jokes that of yourself and others.
So.
So when it pertains to you,
we have taken exception.
I could see people in regular returning,
like we're now are people that make fun
of themselves.
What I was doing obviously is actually
including a retarded person in my act
and that's where saying it,
she's retarded.
Stupid.
I don't know man.
If that was your kid,
I think you would want someone to know
that it hurts.
I understand where she was coming from.
I have a friend who's a comic there and
she's very funny.
I'm one of her sons is autistic and
because she's a comic sheet,
not make fun of him,
but she has a sense of humor about it
and like her email is rain mom instead
of rain.
Man,
you know,
she gets it and she makes jokes at his
expense,
but then he's very,
she treats him like an adult and so
there's,
you can be one of those people that gets
it and gets their,
how they fit into the world or you can
be weird and be like,
oh,
well he's retarded,
so no one can say that.
We weren't talking about her son and his
Pacific.
We were talking about me making fun of
the fact that she had an issue with that
is stupid.
Kind of see her point a little bit.
I stopped doing the bid because I got it
onto a CD or DVD.
Right.
But I would've kept doing.
That was funny.
It was the point,
man.
He was the hero in a bit.
Yeah.
He was the smart one.
Who was the one who wasn't getting
fooled by this stupid fucking book.
Coffee.
Yeah.
I don't know man.
It's A.
I could see it from her point of view.
Especially if someone was being
malicious.
No,
you can't obviously do what you want but
can't harp on the
exception.
And that's true too.
Comedy's about generalizing.
I know and it would be nice if everybody
had a fucking sense of humor,
right?
Retarded son.
Then we can all just fucking make fun of
them every time people want to like you
can bring it back again.
Just poop on you and then you put your
crazy dog.
You're a crazy dog lady.
Yes.
Obviously it's fine.
You need to learn some more kid.
Be More of a grappler or kickboxer.
Anything to throw.
Throw Duke.
So girls,
what do you think you'd like to choke a
bitch?
I'll tell you the truth.
Tell me the truth.
I think punching is more useful but no
one expects you to kick him and take him
to the ground on a Saturday night
waiting in line.
Inside.
True.
So I don't know.
I think I'd have to take an aptitude
test,
like a physical aptitude test to see
which of my limbs is quicker and then
we'll just play to that strength,
physical aptitude test to see which of
your limbs better with kicking.
And my quicker,
my quicker with punching like which am I
better at?
Nobody naturally predisposed to the only
issue with kicking as it takes a while
to get good at it and you have to think
about,
yeah,
you're going to get kicked,
kicked in the legs to do it correctly,
you've got to learn how to leg kick and
you've got to learn a balance.
You have to have really good balance
because otherwise someone's going to
take you down.
It's easier to take someone down when
they're kicking,
especially if chicken into the body or I
don't ever plan on being in a fight.
It would be nice to know how to defend
myself in case somebody gets crazy,
but I don't want to get kicked in the
Shin.
That's good thinking.
That's good to think that way.
Yeah.
You don't want you to kicking the leg
kick in the thighs.
It's really hurt or a lot of times you
get kicked in the CAF,
like the lower shin,
like the fibula,
the little skinny bone Tibia and fibula
dudes will kick the shit out of the
outside of your outside of your calf.
What they should do,
instead of having tasers,
they should have.
They should have little necklaces with
like little vials that are just filled
with aids blood and then everyone knows
what that is and so if somebody is
attacking me like,
Hey,
I got my blood,
don't make me throw this on myself.
That would be.
Yeah,
throw it in their face and their eyes
and stuff.
You still wouldn't want it to happen.
Right?
But it's a little tiny vial.
I would take my chances,
but it's related to your violent open to
that.
I think I'd beat your ass.
I think I would rather have aids blood
thrown in my face.
You unscrewing a vial?
No,
I don't think you'd get a guy with a
vial.
How big is it?
Just like a little.
You know,
like those little perfume samples.
Dude,
if that broke on you.
What if somebody opened a door on it?
What if.
What if it's like a titanium.
It's a cool kills.
Someone like you,
you'll go to jail for that.
If you willingly knowingly give someone
a attacking you,
you could just say you just threw some
blood.
Adam.
Why not just have.
That's better than like if somebody
attacked me,
you're allowed to shoot them.
Right.
If you say,
hey,
yeah,
he.
He attacked me.
I think some blood on him.
I think that's less than shooting
science attack.
The dumbest thing I've ever walked the
face of the earth.
You really are the same age.
Blood probably is cheap and like a guy
that has aids could sell his blood and
make his own weapons for you and then
that could help him pay his bills for
having aids.
Wow.
Why wouldn't you?
Instead of giving him aids kinsmen
that'll mess with them temporarily.
Like mercury poison.
You can't look.
You can't talk to him.
He goes this far out and fucking spazzy
have aids and you're looking for ways to
make money.
Make money.
His brain has aids only his brain in the
part of his brain,
that forum sentencing support as aids.
It's a very specific form of AIDS.
It only hits.
He hits one area of the brain,
the form logical sentences.
That part as ever.
Thank you.
Had AIDS at the time.
I had an aids test.
What?
I got health insurance.
The first time I had health insurance,
I was like 23.
I was terrified.
Nervous.
Think of all the girls you fucked
without a condom.
Yeah.
Google first came with living in Boston.
When you live in Boston,
you don't have time to put a condom on.
Girls will get angry.
I check.
Yeah,
just stick it in white.
You could do your best as quickly as you
could get away from those monsters.
Did you live in the city?
I lived all over the place.
I grew up in Newton,
but I lived in revere and in Medford I
lived a couple different spots.
I lived off symphony.
I lived in Lynn.
Right.
You'd never go out the way he came in
eight Pi.
They're really stoned one night.
Oh yeah,
there was the grossest place ever lived
like that was on the ocean.
Ocean was nasty.
It was never.
It never felt cool to be on the ocean
air.
I couldn't appreciate it either.
As you know,
19 or 20.
You have.
I thought I had aids once.
There was this girl that I used to fuck
around with.
One of the girls that like only had a
threesome a couple of times by one of
the girls.
It was the girlfriend that she was a
hippie.
She used to be a hippie.
I ran into her and she was like looking
hot.
She was unhappy anymore.
She has big boobs,
so we fucked up a couple times.
She had a boob job.
She always had good boobs,
but now she was just hot girls,
hot girl.
And so we fucked around.
Uh,
we,
you know,
back in the day they used to have a
Webcam and I fucked her on Webcam.
You now,
thank God no one ever require a 37 and
then.
So it was basically only used 12.
Yeah,
I thought you were younger.
Not like immature.
I just thought you were right.
And then,
uh,
she uh,
didn't live in the city and so she got
pregnant and then she came back and I
had to like sell all this stuff to pay
for the baby hammer or whatever.
It's called abortion.
And so,
uh,
then I found out from a friend that knew
or there's like,
dude,
she's been doing heroin lately.
You know,
she,
she's,
I guess she's been doing heroin a lot
now.
She's just fucked up and I'm thinking,
oh great,
I fucked a heroin addict,
you know,
with no condom on,
and I'm like thinking.
And then one day I have no nowhere.
She called me up,
he goes,
Brian,
I need to talk to you about something.
And I'm like,
no,
no bad color,
you know,
I hung up because my girlfriend was in
bed with me and I was like,
I can't talk to you.
And for a couple of years I was like,
what,
what did she want to talk to me about
it?
And then so then I went on Google when
Google first came out and I'm like,
uh,
I'm thinking any kind of symptoms I have
noticed I've had.
And one was like sweating at night and
I'm like typing,
sweating at night.
And I was like,
oh,
aids.
And then I'll be like,
I want to say that and I got to like
type in something else,
you know,
like a headache or something that,
aids,
it kept on going back to AIDS.
So for a couple years I was freaked out
and finally I had some kind of a mole
removed and they,
they had to do a full blood thing and
I'm like,
can you add the aids bonus test to that?
And I was fine,
but it was such a relief.
And then later I found out that she
wanted to tell me that,
uh,
she didn't ha was pregnant,
she never gotten an abortion and that
she just wanted money to buy more
heroin.
She had a confessed to you 10 steps.
Yeah.
That's one of those things while steps
whatever it is.
Yeah.
You have to right the wrongs.
Have you ever dated someone that was an
alcoholic?
I went on two dates with a girl wants.
It was really cool and it turns out to
be an alcoholic.
The first day we had a great time.
I was like,
wow,
this chick is so cool.
She didn't drink.
I don't think we did.
No,
we just hung out and I remember talking
to her.
I'm like,
she's so nice.
So normal.
And then the next night it was a at some
bar in Hollywood where there was going
to be a comedy show and she had got
there before me with her friends and she
was fucking Amor,
hammered right away,
hammered and,
and for some reason mad at me and I
hadn't done anything.
I had done like nothing.
I just got there.
I was like,
what's going on?
Or something crazy.
I was like,
why you so drunk?
I go,
what the fuck happened to you?
And I go,
where are your friends if someone here
with you?
I'm finding myself like she pulls away
from women.
Women are.
So this one was,
was never bought one.
She knocked a glass over and it was like
the whole deal stumbled,
lost a shoe and get her shoe and put it
on.
I was like,
wow,
I really liked you.
Like the first date.
I like,
this girl is cool.
She totally was like girlfriend
material.
She was fun.
She was friendly,
she was nice.
And then boom,
next night,
just like to the point of like,
there's no way you ever hang out with
someone who gets that drunk go,
oh God.
Because they don't get personal.
Then she really will be mad about
something.
And what's also when you look real
alcoholism in the eyes and they're just
floating around with the rest of us.
Like most people that I know that drink
could not drink from now to the,
like between us,
like Red Duncan,
Joe,
Joey,
all of us.
We sat around and we,
you know,
and we found out that one of us did
never drank again.
And that one of us,
uh,
just uh,
you know,
one of us just drinks every night now.
It would be,
I would be more likely to believe that
they would just give it up.
Like,
I don't think any of us would have a
problem
giving it up.
I gave it up the other day for four days
because I got so drunk Thursday for four
days.
And did you,
did you hear what I did?
How drunk I got Thursday?
I didn't even tell you this.
All right.
So I went to,
that was going to say though,
but is that before you say this though,
is that that's most of us,
but we all do know one person who's not.
That way.
We know one person who you.
You give them a couple of drinks and
they're fucking gone.
And I didn't know it existed until I met
people in Hollywood.
I grew up.
I didn't know anybody like that.
And you meet people in comedy in
particular.
I'm sorry,
I.
It's true that I remember there's this
one booker who is super cool and then he
would just be really mean to me.
Oh yeah,
the enemies in comedy and I never
understood.
I'm like,
what did I do wrong?
Like why is he mad at me?
And I found out he was a raging
alcoholic and if you're not,
if you're unaware of those types of
people or how they act,
you don't know how to handle it.
Because I never knew what it was.
So bizarre when they literally change
personalities.
Do you think it's you?
And not only that,
you're actually,
you're trapped with a crazy person.
Like if you ever in a conversation with
them and they're drunk and you're like,
Whoa,
whoa,
well this person doesn't even see
reality.
They see reason.
So what was you,
what were you gonna?
Say
I got Eddie Bravo drunk the other day.
Indian drunk at St Tropez not,
you didn't get him drunk.
You got you got as drunk as he gets me.
Me and Veronica were uh,
going to the show.
We both hadn't ate all day and we're
going to eat,
but we were running late so we were
like,
you know what,
we'll just go for a bit and then we'll
go get something to eat.
And I guess there was a,
somebody told me there was was that
moonshine there and in China and I did a
couple shots of Moonshine,
but I thought it was just shots of you
on the hazard.
And so I,
I got so fucking drunk that I don't,
I blacked out.
I completely don't remember.
What is the outcome?
What's regular proof?
Moonshines hundred proof.
What is regular alcohol?
Five,
I think 70.
I don't know.
But grain,
grain,
alcohol.
It's way more powerful than Tequila.
Right.
And people making themselves.
Yeah,
hundred percent.
So how many shots do you think that
represents at a regular alcoholic?
I don't know,
but I had.
They have these alma walkie cans about
that big.
I had three of those two shots.
What I thought was just vodka three,
the old milwaukee giant old milwaukee.
Oh,
I thought you were saying oh,
milwaukee cans filled with that.
Oh No,
no,
no.
I was like,
wow,
are you alone?
And so I,
that night I got home and I was going
through my phone and I was remembering
all the shit that happened,
train piece things together.
One of the things I did was at the,
at the show,
somebody was yelling out Veronica's name
when she was on stage at the nightly
show and he was like,
well,
you know,
like whatever.
So I decided to make fun of them and
outdo his heckling.
So I was,
I have it on tape.
It's on youtube.
I was going for,
I want to shit on your face,
but I did it 12 times.
Louder and louder it ever in the eye is
looking back like,
what the fuck is this guy wants Ronica
so you're not tackling the heckling.
Why we are so inclined to do the video.
Video is hilarious though.
If you look at it,
Veronica,
I want to shit on your face on Youtube.
Oh my God.
So then I felt videos available on
youtube right now and so I felt so bad
that.
Anyways,
then that night I went to across the
street to that where we always ate the
standard when you stole his commentary
and we went in and there was not.
There was only one other table in the
whole entire restaurant so me and my
girl were eating there and the other
table was a drunk Japanese guy at big
tall black guy in an Armenian and they
were about 50 to 55 years old and they
were wasted just being slobbery wasting
and the Armenian dude staring at my
girlfriend the whole entire time and
like to the point where I'm like,
why is this guy staring at you?
So when we eat I go,
I'm going to go to the bathroom.
Then we'll leave,
so I go to the bathroom,
I come back and he got,
he was in the middle of this table.
He got out of the table.
He was leaning on the table,
freaking my girlfriend at like trying to
hit on or doing something.
He knew I was with her.
He saw the whole time I was there.
So I walk up to this and I'm like,
okay,
I'm wasted black out wasted.
I'm going to act like a fucking psycho
and this is how dumb I was.
I said,
go ahead.
What's up man?
How's it going?
Like I like,
I was on cocaine or like I was just
like,
I'm going to say what are you doing
that's like get the fuck out of here
man.
And he's like,
Oh,
I'm so sorry.
I don't think.
Don't make me fucking shoot you man.
Like I said,
don't make me.
It got to the point where the standard,
the security comes up and goes,
do we have a problem here?
I'm like,
no man.
And he's like,
Hey,
here's your bill.
Knight tip them 100 percent.
It was like $43.
I tip them like $40,
$30,
$40,
you know,
because I was like,
why?
I was acting crazy.
I was just like a security,
here's,
here's a 100 percent.
And then like I'll come out and you hear
the guy sit down and he's like,
he,
he's,
he's right on.
I don't know why I did that,
you know,
like I could hear him saying that and I
go have a safe trip outside asshole or
something like that.
And then the guy's like,
man,
stop moving,
stop.
And I just walk out and I'm walking out
and I'm like,
Holy Shit,
this,
get the fuck out,
but I could have easily poker.
You play play bloke.
And I bluffed in a,
it works.
And the funny thing is before I went to
a,
before I did this,
uh,
I was like,
Hey,
let's do a podcast while we're eating,
you know,
to,
to Veronica.
And,
and I forgot that the waiter came up or
something like that.
And so my,
I recorded the whole thing,
the old version of it.
But I am so embarrassed by I,
I do not want to release it.
I listened to it.
I don't even know now I,
I don't want anyone else.
Brian.
Brian,
this is a beautiful thing.
No,
no,
no.
It's so embarrassing thing ever
documented everything.
You already admitted to it,
but you already admitted to it.
I know that,
that just,
that thing alone was like,
listen bro,
you're like a little slot right now.
You're using on the world.
I,
I might release in the release it.
I don't think.
Come on.
You already brought it up.
You already,
you already.
So embarrassing.
You mentioned it's so you've got to
release it to embarrassing.
It's not,
you're crazy acting like a fucking
psycho.
Well listen,
you were,
you felt threatened.
There was a bunch of men,
you know.
And see what,
what's so funny is that she did the same
thing on yours.
I think I talked about like where we're
getting threat.
We went party downtown and it was one
street from the shelter and we were
drunk at like 2:00
AM.
Walk,
walking to our car.
Uh,
and with a friend that wasn't drunk that
was driving us and uh,
the,
we are going through what was like the
homeless were all the shelters are and
stuff like that.
So the street was just all homeless
people,
about 100 of them in one block,
you know,
just like zombies walking around in our
car was in the middle of it and then
like all these people kept on coming up.
But Hey,
drunk thriller.
Yeah,
it was like through,
it was exactly correct.
Yeah.
And so like this one,
all these people,
my girlfriend's high,
you know,
dressed up new year's eve style,
like buttholes showing out and,
and it was interesting,
the whole girl ain't even fashionable.
Yeah.
And so like all these people kept on
coming up for money and stuff and her
response,
like her defense mechanism,
it's just going like,
just like.
And people are like,
damn that girl and crack,
you know,
like that.
So I think I did the same thing and I
was so wasted.
I don't know if you remember that she
had done that.
That comes from a weird place to be
like,
I'm going to act a crazy person.
I don't think I could do that or think
it's just too much confidence.
Liquid confidence,
you know,
like I'm just gonna.
Well you sounded like you were in
another world,
man.
It sounds like you were so drunk.
You don't know what the fuck your
butthole out.
That's normal.
It's a cigarette butt hanging out.
It's Halloween and if there's ever a
time the butthole was,
we'll,
we'll launch.
We'll launch blossom.
The butthole blossom picture by the way
of what?
He's like,
can you do Joe's podcasts?
And I was like,
let me check,
let me see what I'm doing.
He was like,
it's a 4:00
PM and then I click on my text and
there's just a picture of a dog with a
cork in it.
Oh yeah.
I just wrote back,
I was like,
oh yeah,
we can't poop.
I'm like,
don't send me stuff like that.
That's such a weird for me to be like.
And now here's Joe was address the time
and don were the corporate as well.
I've gotten,
I could not like it.
You know,
I,
that's not real,
it's a photoshop,
but I liked it but I love sending random
photos and like I was homesick or if he
has a,
he's busy Friday and he's like,
I'm in Minneapolis,
so I sent him a picture of a big black
guy with his dick out and he goes,
that's unnecessary.
Like you done this to me many times.
I think we've all seen enough disgusting
crap like just from him sending a text
message and it's an image you can't see
what it is.
Like it's at nighttime at a comedy club
or something like that.
I clicked on the image and it's a black
guy with a giant Dick and a white guy
sucking.
It was funny when it's a black guy's
penis funnier,
no jail.
This last weekend it was my girlfriend's
birthday and she was turning 30 and I
was like,
I'm going to be a material center.
Neurotic cake.
And what they do
when you call for the erotic cake is
they take you through the entire order
process and at the end tell you how much
it is.
And it was like $200.
And we're like,
not even close I guess was a regular
tank.
You have to pay more for the buck.
Like it depends on how much like at the
grocery store,
$100 to make a dick can have it
delivered to.
But it was like in Houston it was so
uncomfortable because I'm already
calling them like it's like a big and I
had to get a black penis because it's
funnier for some peanuts on the cake.
And then he was like,
alright.
And he was so over his job.
He's like,
you won't come.
You want hair on the balls.
I was like,
I literally was like,
please don't ask me that.
It's uncomfortable.
He's like,
what I do is what I do.
So for 200 bucks you got a black penis.
And I had them write and have an elegant
birthday.
I didn't want to be like,
so could you dirties?
So I wrote something nice.
If you're actually,
why would you not want to say that?
I wanted it to retain some.
Saved that dignity for the tourists.
Thirties.
Yeah.
You started.
I used to always get boob cakes from my
family growing up from like 12 on or
something like that.
From them,
from them or for them from them,
like every day.
That was like the big thing that my dad
was 12 or 13 and they were actual
nipples.
Well they weren't real enablers.
They were made out of Hershey kisses
Hershey's,
but it would look like two white
nipples.
It's called quip.
So.
But it would look like that.
It would look like,
whoops.
It's fine,
you know,
like I don't think there was,
I,
I think I feel like there was like gyms
and the batter or something.
I take that back.
It wasn't full boob.
It was the one where the bikini,
but you could see a little boob like in
it a cakes,
but the older I got I started having
nipples but my 18th birthday,
but the older I got,
I started moving up,
but when I was 18 with and boy would
have changed the cake when I was 18,
I was a black one.
You think you ever molested that?
You don't remember.
It's possible.
I hope not.
I hope.
Do you think something,
something must've happened though right
when you were younger that you're trying
to block out bouquets growing up.
That is weird.
Why was it cleveland cakes and then I
think when I was 16 it started becoming
big cakes and almost 18 was black.
They had open vaginas,
vaginas with like who is like,
let me slice into this.
This looks great.
The midwest boom cakes were I guess more
accepted.
I don't know.
Social well there wasn't a lot to do
that.
Right.
I think just anything,
it seems like,
you know,
people that lived in West Virginia and
where you're from or where in Ohio,
Columbus,
Ohio,
but I think that whole little chunk of
area,
I think people were had to look like a
sick sense of humor in Texas.
You remember?
I remember her sense of humor.
Like I remember like you'd go to,
you'd go to these people's houses and
they would have like little statues that
were silly and there was a penis
involved.
Do you know,
like.
And that was at your grandma's house.
You know,
what's your grandpa's elephants on
there?
You lived in a sad world,
then you go cut wood country.
I don't know.
I grew up in a Stephen King Movie Kid.
Yeah,
it did.
It was a Stephen King.
That's what it is.
It's just like people were just not
happy.
Had more humor for humor or sexually
sexual humor.
They're more just perfect.
Well,
it sounds like your friends in
neighborhoods,
families.
I'm talking within the dirty comedians
you're hanging out with here.
Like what are you to.
I'm just saying that they were like,
oh,
I grew up feeling like everyone had a
dirty joke thing.
Like everyone's families had like dirty
magazines and everyone's like,
if you find the dad's got like some
playboys and like one or two things,
but not like on the mantle boot cakes.
I think we're more accepted.
I mean,
I think that was normal for a lot of
people that get a boob cleavage cake
when you're 16.
Really?
Yeah,
absolutely.
I believe you.
It just seems weird to me.
Yeah.
Your mom have to order it now.
My mom would never give me a boot.
She should give me Jesus.
You ever have one of your friends,
um,
who had,
uh,
like a buddy of his friend's mom now
just know anybody to do that.
Yeah.
I knew.
I knew one kid can only see your eyes
right now.
I remember one kid who,
uh,
fucked his friend's mom is friends while
I was kind of a freak and I think they
smoked weed together to bang his
friend's mom.
She was a single mom.
I was like 16 or 17 and I think he was a
year older than us.
He made it been 18.
It might've been like a year out of
school and we were sophomores mean
buying the student's mom for the kid
whose mom?
Yeah.
Nobody was happy.
Dudes don't like that.
I remember when that.
Yeah.
When I was in the boy scouts,
one of the fucking 18 year old kids was
hitting on my mom in front of me.
And it was for the guys who just got out
of the.
He's flirting with my mom about the time
my mom was in her thirties.
She was still pretty hot.
That's crazy.
It was gross though,
being a little kid going,
what the fuck?
Just thinking,
dude,
what's up with your mom?
I would imagine that's awful.
I'd never thought about anyone voting
that's probably going to go through your
head one day.
You're going to have to tell some little
18 year old kid to get the fuck away
from you.
You're taking your kid to school.
I do.
Now it's having to take.
Do you do now?
Do you ever want to like teach them?
Show them what's up?
No,
no.
Grab a boy by the hair.
Come here and try to find a good one.
I can't.
I really don't have a thing for guys
that are younger than me at all and so I
just get very.
There's a PA that works on our show who
is adorable and so cute and I'm so
attracted to him,
but not in the way that I want to make
out with him,
but I know it's hot every time.
His name is Joey and every time I see
him I'm like,
no,
he's so hot,
but I.
There's nothing.
I don't want to sleep with him.
I just want to like hug him.
I have no sexual attraction.
I can tell someone's hot,
but I have no sexual attraction.
Anyone younger than me because it makes
me feel so old.
I don't like feeling old in my twenties.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
It's not attractive.
I don't know.
And then everything starts to hurt.
I feel so old as it is because you're
very smart for 28,
you know?
That's the problem is that a problem
must be a problem with dealing with
dudes.
The most guys in their twenties or even
dumber than girls,
their twenties because of testosterone.
Testosterone fucking clouds your mind
and really massively slows down your
ability to accumulate information
because there's just so busy chasing
posted.
Especially when you're in your early
twenties.
He barely learn a God damn thing until
you're like almost 30.
You're a dude.
Get the feeling that a lot of guys,
anybody that knows me obviously isn't
hitting on me like they know me,
but I get.
I get this vibe.
That was totally one of the gang,
but I get this feeling that comics who I
know just from seeing around different
clubs or whatever,
that they're a little afraid of me and
it's not because I want to like hurt
anyone's feelings,
but if you come up to me,
you say something stupid,
I'm not going to be like the money.
I'm going to be like,
what?
And then they get nervous,
but I don't mean to act like a person if
you're going to come talk to.
Some men are just fucked up talking to
women and some men are so insecure when
it comes to talking to women that they,
they fall apart and so quickly
translates to hate.
But you know what it is.
I realized that when I had a friend who
was an ugly dude who broke it down to me
once where he's talking about girls and
you know,
I was trying to tell them from a girl's
perspective and I'm like,
just imagine if you're a girl and a guy
like you is constantly trying to fuck
her.
Yeah.
You know,
I mean in any said,
well here's the deal.
He goes,
I have to admit,
he goes,
I'm not good looking.
He goes,
it's just I'm not so they don't not
attracted to me,
so I have to try harder and forced
myself in say yes,
yes,
someone will give in.
Someone will just be overwhelmed by his
confidence,
but at the end of the day they get angry
at you and for a lot of these men it's
becomes.
They just have this direct association
in their head with women with feeling
bad,
feeling rejected and they just want to
strike out and that's where a lot of
them that anger towards women comes from
like my twitter feed or my facebook
grown men and this is the weirdest thing
to me.
I understand guys can be gross.
I don't fault anyone for you know you.
Oh fuck you.
All right.
That's what people say.
When I go on my facebook page and you've
written something like,
want to fuck you so hard,
I come to Christ.
I'm like that.
And your facebook picture is of you and
your wife.
Like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
Like you just had such an uncontrollable
boner that you had to ejaculate words on
my page and it just,
it's not flattering and it's or people,
right?
Like really mean,
like I've been on podcasts before and
even probably today and people will be
like such a fucking color door folk.
You're aggressive and you're like,
why?
Because I spoke like men get amped for
stuff like that.
I'm going to check my twitter feed right
now.
How you're really going to open it up to
date,
a woman scorned.
It's like the word I think a guy scored
and it's probably worse because they get
rapey raping a lot of men,
especially dudes who don't do well.
They do associate women with being the
source of their misery.
You know?
It's unfortunate and you know why?
Because prostitution is illegal.
That's why because of prostitution.
Well,
legal,
there'll be brothels and someone can
take care of those guys.
Physical needs.
I'm not saying that women should be
prostitutes,
but I am saying there's some women who
are going to be prostitutes and it's not
a bad thing necessarily.
It ain't a bad thing.
It's a service to the community.
It's our idea that's bad one.
So okay to massage a guy,
but it's not okay to massage his dick.
I say bullshit.
I think it should be legal or illegal.
Totally illegal.
Should be regulated.
The girls should be checked.
They should do it.
Like the handle it in other countries.
You know,
we're so because we're.
So.
I think we've talked about this.
It's ridiculous.
By the way,
grain alcohol is actually 100.
Someone wrote Brian d dot Morton wrote
it's 180 to 200 proof and Jack is damn
it.
Oh,
that hurts.
My liver just is five percent to to just
talk.
You just said 200 proof.
Just stop and think about that.
I don't know how to comprehend that.
I never sent out God.
It's 100 percent of $43 in tip.
Oh my God.
What a fucking explosion in your liver.
That must be your whole bloodstream.
Must be like,
what the fuck did you just do?
Need to get a blood transfusion.
Just add some more.
You know,
proof is 50 percent,
moonshine is 100 percent.
So that's what someone said.
So Moon,
Chinese,
100 percent.
I'm just reading a tweet.
Wow.
Yeah.
I've heard of some ridiculous.
A high percentages of disgusting
alcohols,
but that's the highest I've ever heard.
I've never heard anything about it
before.
Yeah.
I drank a shit ton of absinthe once is
200 proof.
One hundred percent.
Is that what it means?
What does it,
what does it mean?
I think 200.
I think it's always 50 percent.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
How could you be this map?
Work isn't an fund to be a comedian.
It'd be fucking ignorant.
Fucking never added things.
I went to South Africa when I was in
high school and absence was legal there
and it wasn't legal here yet.
And you hear about the Green Butterfly
and hallucinating and it's awful.
It feels like black licorice,
like it's not good.
I liked it.
Didn't drinking a drink and drink.
You get with the sugar.
The thing I just got shit faced.
No hallucinations because it's not made
with wormwood anymore,
which is what makes you do that.
Can drink absinthe all day long.
You will not hallucinate from it.
So That's interesting.
Does anybody make it the other way with
the wormwood?
Nobody had done it.
So in general I think poisoning you.
Whoa.
But anyways,
you can't like it's just,
it used to be that way and it's not an,
it's not quite the same as drunk.
Right?
It's a little bit.
I sit down,
say I describe it as that.
It was like a cousin of drunk.
I also drink a lot of other stuff.
I enjoyed it.
I did it in Vancouver with the hottest
South Africa.
Did you like his accent?
Say First Black Guy.
What if he said something really racist
right before.
What?
What have you said something really
racist right before he put it in because
you just saw the gate.
They get kinda racist.
You may not with them though.
Thinking about that bathroom and then we
got kicked out because I probably
wouldn't.
You're a dirty bitch.
I love it.
That's what I'm talking about.
So are you drunk and angry?
Drunk or a happy to answer a question
that.
Why are you putting the angry part out?
They're tired.
Drunk wine.
Red Wine.
Drunk is the worst.
Can I just,
well,
here's my thing is my birthday's coming
up and I'm going to do one.
Did you like a full on asshole birthday
where you get drunk and were like a tiny
dress and get a table?
Right?
Really?
That's my last birthday in my twenties,
so I want to have a party like I'm in my
twenties.
I have addressed.
It's this big.
It's actually a sock and I'm going to
fit into it and I'm just going to bring
a bunch of girls with me.
Can we videotape and we just let know
what bar is.
Can we videotape?
Sounds like there'll be a good address
for following day.
Smell.
Brian?
I get afraid because I never drink.
I mean I just don't ever have a chance
to go on part.
I'm afraid that I'll have two drinks and
be tired and miserable.
Right Boulevard.
Well,
do you take vitamins?
You take multivitamins and deed healthy.
I eat very healthy sleep.
Good hours night.
Do you really need.
Well that's awesome.
That's awesome.
Nothing to get up for in the morning.
That's good though.
That's good.
You're well rested,
but vitamins are important.
Even on a healthy diet,
um,
I believe very strongly in vitamins have
had health issues that were corrected by
vitamins.
Take them every day.
Take that shit.
That's the shit for you.
You want to take it with them?
I'll give you the all the other stuff to
you don't want flashlight.
What am I going to use that for?
Practice friends to come over.
I don't want anyone to come over and see
that it can be a novelty.
I mean sitting on my couch and one of my
bras was behind me and it's not like a
cute,
like rather large breasts.
So do you have to have special
supporting sears?
I'm not poor,
but oh my God,
you know,
one of the few places you can actually
have like custom made brawls if your
boobs are too big for a normal playing,
they can.
One of them is well yeah,
it's a little wishbone in there and
that's where the wishbone and like a
tooth.
Well we could,
we could take it out,
but we might you to choose which just
wish bone and tooth written tit sounds
like rappers.
That's my new group.
That's my policy.
It is my,
my boy wishbone,
and this is a written tit anyways,
my brothers behind me and that was
embarrassing enough that someone saw
that I don't want a flashlight sitting
around me,
ugly Brown.
These are strangers and I can understand
if you deliberately do it,
but when someone sees into your home
without you knowing like the fact that
they saw that and I hadn't,
I wasn't aware of it.
No,
it's an ugly bra also.
It's not like,
oh,
that's hot.
Like no one's ever looked at like a nude
colored Bra.
And like is that to minimize under your
tee shirts?
Like this is not right.
I guess if I was at CIC.
Yeah,
it's not like kids don't give a fuck too
sweaty shirts and shit.
Oh,
I thought you meant for looking at
broad.
Coming over a girl's house and find ugly
broad cupra is fine.
Your mind,
and this is grandma,
but grandma Lee,
by the time I'll just show you a picture
of an ugly Brah.
I don't know what kind of guys you're
hanging out with,
but any guy that gets turned off by a
fucking brawl and around turned off,
but there are more attractive.
Not that I want to turn.
I don't give a fuck.
Are you crazy?
You just showing different idea of
what's good and bad and what's nice and
not nice Villi.
We walked in your house.
There's a blog on the ground.
We would laugh.
You would,
but.
And I understand guys don't care like
girls like,
oh,
it doesn't match.
He doesn't give a fuck.
I totally get that.
I'm just saying if you had a choice of
looking at like a really cute lacy black
versus like grandma's nude,
full coverage utility Bra,
you'd rather see the cute one?
Well I guess,
but I really don't give a fuck.
It's all for you.
Would not.
Most guys don't give a shit about
lingerie.
Get that shit off.
I want to see your body.
I agree.
I don't get turned on by.
You can pick your dog up because I have
a litter box in here for real,
for her breakfast.
Smelled like shit.
That would be the circle of life.
You're such a strange personalizes,
Joe.
Your little animal that you take care of
them.
Bring everywhere.
It's got teeth and shit.
That's not weird.
She was probably developed like kill
rats in the sewer to write her.
She breaks her neck.
She's half long or longer.
Chihuahua.
What kind of.
What is the first one?
Half long hair.
Long hair.
I see that.
That's a cool mix.
Didn't they make Dotson's for that very
reason to go after things like that's
where the long bodies.
A little short legs going rat holes or
something like it.
Wasn't that like Jack Russell terriers
known?
They bred them for that.
Jack Russell terriers are aggressive
little doggies going after squirrels and
shit.
It's just blanche ever bark.
Is it a barker barker like squirrels and
stuff.
She's not a social dog.
She doesn't care like for other dogs.
When your dog eats poop,
does it make you love her?
Little bit less.
She doesn't do it.
It's disappointing.
It's like finding out your daughter
does.
She's a good girl.
I mean look at that face,
but that's what my dog does.
We eat.
It's not like she takes every day,
she's not going to pass up on it if it's
on the.
Yeah,
it's got to have a bit about that.
Didn't you park on gross just with your
pets,
with your daughters?
Like could you like.
Do you ever get this like aggressive?
Like with my daughter's?
A little bit,
but not really with my pets.
It was freaked my cat out and my dogs
pretty big.
You don't really want him getting him to
do well.
You don't want to your face,
but when you love something in my act
they talk about how I want to rip her
face off.
Like when you love something so much,
I just want to hurt it.
Like that's a girl thing.
Yeah,
that's a girl.
That's why relationships always end up
fucking hurt you.
The little freak seems like that's true
though.
Like good girls always want to hurt with
me.
Well,
you might.
It might just be you.
I mean,
how many times fake abortions did I pay
for?
Powerful people?
Powerful people.
This fucking podcast is over this
lesson.
Zero.
People want to find you,
if they want to catch you out there in
the wild world.
What did they get on twitter?
You're on twitter at Ilm.
Which z?
A.
And we,
uh,
we will tweak this after the show,
which we did it before the show as well.
And uh,
what's your website at?
[inaudible] DOT com.
Really?
How'd you get both of those spells?
Her name like me.
Oh,
that's awesome.
you're so lucky.
It's so easy to remember it,
but no one spells like that.
So everyone's like,
I tried it with an e and I couldn't find
you.
Where are you going to be doing your
little standup comedy routine at the Lol
Comedy Club in San Antonio?
Lol.
Comedy Club in San San Antonio.
What part of San Antonio is a near the
river?
That's off the for 10 loop.
Oh,
okay.
Cool.
And so there's two comedy clubs in San
Antonio now.
I don't know.
I think there was another one,
right?
Wasn't there another one?
We're pauly shore.
Get punched the fake punch incident.
I don't remember that.
They made a fake video about beating him
up and everybody gets so excited that
it'd be that he got beat up.
It was really horrible,
man.
That was the first time because there
was one of the first celebrity,
things like that where it got fake.
Something like he punches him,
isn't that a guy gets on stage and the
guy is fucking huge and the and then the
video,
they released it afterwards.
It's him working it out,
but the negative comments after the
first video was,
fuck that.
Faggot.
Punch him in the face of the things they
hate that he received must have been
horrific to know that people feel like
that about you.
So many people and that it was so
accepted.
There was no one standing up for them.
There was no one was going,
hey man in the army now is one of my
favorite all time movies.
Fuck you.
You know you're,
you're the asshole police job.
Makes millions of people smart.
That was some hardcore.
That was intense.
It was intense.
It was horrible moment in your life.
Texas.
They fucking party though.
I do love going back to Texas.
We haven't been in awhile.
I think a next next Gig is going to do
as an Austin,
trying to work that shit out for the
spring.
Probably don't play clubs.
You do like theaters?
I do clubs and theater.
See I've been coming to this one club in
Austin for so long.
It would feel weird if I didn't go back
there.
Yeah,
I performed,
I did my first DVD there in 1999,
so I can't,
that's my spot.
A really humbling moment I had at cap
city.
Aside from when a fan brought a buck
knife to meet me on his belt.
So you saw it or was behind him?
Yeah.
Oh good.
It came up.
He was like,
hey.
It was very like,
what is your problem?
Uh,
when I called and I was like,
Hey,
I'm driving over,
um,
where can I park?
And they didn't care that I was a
headline and they're like a.
There was a hobby lobby across the
street across the freeway,
just park over at the hobby lobby.
I'm like,
there's no parking from no hobby lobby.
oh,
I'll just make the height the headliner.
That's not even true.
You know there's a back alley where
there's always.
It's always park right behind.
Not only do they wait for us to,
but I think we are men.
It's different.
Sorry.
Weird.
Maybe I should've been more assertive
and general.
I should be more aggressive.
Maybe it was a.
was it a girl answering the phone?
Maybe she didn't know or maybe it was
like a night,
like a manager that didn't know and I'm
not the kind of person they'd be like,
do you know who I am?
She's on her way.
Go get her.
What?
We're talking about cap cities.
You were saying you love Austin and I
was saying I'll be in San Antonio.
Yeah,
but you were talking about them not
giving you.
Oh,
lobby.
Do you think that that's like a girl.
The girl just didn't want like she was
answering the phone,
like fucking female comedian going to
come in and lie on.
Females ain't even even get it because
it wasn't even the first night and I
think it was so many times we don't
realize how a lot of people that have
jobs in general.
You were in a comedy club.
They're not necessarily up to like,
they don't really know what's going on
on.
Could've been that or maybe there was
something,
there might've been something going on
where they were doing maintenance and
you couldn't park.
I just,
it was such an odd thing and I as a
girl,
it's so quick.
You're so,
it's so easy to get labeled a mean name
that you stand up.
So I just,
sometimes I'm just very like,
okay,
no problem.
Did you hear that?
Um,
what,
what the fuck is his name again?
The good fired and brill who got fired
from letterman?
He say,
he said,
uh,
what was it?
Women?
Something about how women try to be more
like men in their act and that's why
they're not funny or something.
I 100 percent think that there's no way
he got fired because of that one
comment.
Like,
let's get serious.
I don't know what else he did,
but no one stands up for women that
much.
Like women get raped every day and
people can still keep their jobs.
Probably just a bad poker hand.
Yeah.
But it's,
it's different when you're on a show
like that where you hear the judge.
Yeah.
When you're the one who's a,
your job is to discern who's capable of
being on the show and if you say
something so blatantly sexist and so
blatantly judgmental,
like he's formed an opinion and it's one
of the reasons why women can't be funny,
man.
He didn't even qualify it with know.
There are some women that try to be like
men and you know that it's a balanced
and it's a balancing act,
which it is.
I think it's more difficult for a woman.
Some shitty comics,
sorry.
A lot of them are shitty and watch those
tapes and I've never sent in a tape so I
was actually upset that his sentence
wasn't.
Except for Eliza Schlesinger,
she's awesome.
I genuinely thought I would be included
in the conversation.
Were you upset when you hear shit like
that?
Like someone said,
do you feel like the debt like gives you
like a ramp that you have to like run up
where everybody else has like a,
an even start?
I gotta be honest.
I feel that my act is just so different
than every other girl that I just don't
include myself in the same category as
the most female comics was that I just
do,
I just,
I see the audience,
I see my material,
I see topics that most women talk about
versus what I talk about and the
approaches and stuff like that.
And I just have never viewed women as
the competition.
I think of everyone as a competition,
but I just don't.
Um,
I've never seen a girl.
You really do though.
You really do think of people as the
competition,
which I always thought it was
fascinating because that was a very
competitive person,
but I tried to never look at other
comics has competition because I think
it's unhealthy.
I think the way to look at comics as use
them for inspiration,
be inspired by them,
but when you know,
it's not like you're playing a game with
it to keep you from doing it.
It's not like you're playing football
and they can keep you from getting the
ball.
No direct competition.
It's,
you know,
you're,
you're smart about it.
I don't,
I don't go online and watch everyone
else and going,
I don't Google other people.
It's not like that,
but I don't ever watch other acts at the
clubs and stuff and I'll.
Sometimes I'll go on,
I'll watch certain ones that I really
liked but I don't do it out of being
envious and I,
you know,
you keep an ear to it.
Oh that shit,
he auditioned for that or she did this
or that's a showcase you get.
I like going and watching people online
because it gives me like a charge.
I get excited if I see somebody good.
Like if somebody sends me a clip,
hey check this guy out and I go watch
and it's really fun.
I go,
that's fucking funny.
I'm going to write this or I'll get
charged up like,
well I want to create something cool
that does to me or does to someone else.
The way that did to me.
I felt the first time I saw Dane Cook,
like,
this is a long time ago,
this must have been five years ago,
and I had just started and someone took
me the laugh factory and it was like
that tour guides and it was fucking like
no one else had.
When did you start with you?
I must.
I graduated college in 2005,
so maybe I start 2006.
2,000.
That's pretty fresh.
That's kind of amazing.
You know,
and you want.
So you won the last comic standing.
You have only been doing it for like
what?
Four years?
Three years.
That's amazing.
When I see comedy,
I like it.
It makes me happy.
I've never think,
oh,
I want to start headlining on the road
right after last comment.
That is crazy.
They were like,
by the way,
your headliner now and how much time did
you have?
I had 45 minutes already after three
years from doing last comic.
You just start building.
I'm not saying it was the most solid,
but when they tell you,
by the way you have to headline,
now you have one shot.
The headline,
and if you fuck it up,
they're going to put you at the bottom
of the list and a lot of guys did do
that so and I,
I knew that and I was just like,
I'm not going to give it.
I'm going to make sure I had all the
people that did really well from last
column.
It's like you.
I'm Heffron Ralphie May
and a couple of other people,
right?
John.
John,
John Reed did really well.
What is that,
Rick Ross,
the rappers I sent you.
Rick Ross.
Just like some black guy,
black.
I was cock hanging out.
The big.
That is for me,
that just in case I might need that
uncircumcised.
That's gross.
Sacking of uncircumcised.
This podcast is brought to you by the
fleshlight fleshlight thanks to the
legislature for being hilarious.
He's always really,
really fun.
This was.
This was even better.
We know each other better than the last
time we did it.
It was much more loose and relaxed.
I think you're going to take me
fighting.
I would totally.
I'll tell you.
I'll take you to the gym.
I'll teach you some more Tai Chi class,
kick people's legs.
It's fun.
It's great exercise to it.
It gives you like something like it
gives you some,
it gives you a scale,
but it also gives you like something to
do at the gym or something to fall back
on when the standard is.
I bet you can be a serious fighter if
you want them to be very,
very smart and you're very competitive.
All you have to do is do the right
steps,
you know,
don't slack off.
Be disciplined on where do those are.
Those are legit,
right?
Those,
they're not silicone.
Well that's good.
Well,
they actually have a chest protectors.
They have a silicone.
These things.
Yeah.
You were like a hard plastic goes like a
protector sort of.
Yeah.
I don't know how much it helps.
I mean I don't know what the science
behind it is.
They've developed some pretty good
science for the balls recently.
They have some new stuff to politics.
Paul Science,
all our best ball scientists have been
hard at work,
but they've been hard at work.
Clang.
Trying different combinations of things
and hitting balls at balls.
Alright.
That's the end of this fucking hot cast
allies here.
The Shit.
Thank you.
Thank you for joining us.
It's uh,
it's nice to have so many cool friends.
We're so lucky.
All of us for real,
right?
As comedians.
We're so lucky to have all these fucking
cool friends.
It's like one of the coolest things
about this podcast is this big group of
people that we have brought together in
the last year and the fold.
You're in there.
You're in the fucking mix please.
Thank you.
Alright,
thanks.
The fleshlight go to Joe Rogan.net.
Click on the link for the fleshlight
entering the code name,
Rogan,
and you will get 15 percent off the
number.
One second.
Oh Shit.
And we were also brought to you by on it
on [inaudible] dot com on it.
The makers of Alpha brain o,
n,
N I,
t.com,
makers of Alpha brain,
the cognitive enhancement supplement,
a shroom tech sport,
the endurance and energy supplement for
extreme athletic pursuits.
If you're into kettlebells or crossfit
classes or Jujitsu,
try out some shroom tech sport.
It is the shit.
I enjoy it.
I'd take it before every one of my
serious workouts were also brought to
you by shroom tech.
I'm using is a bunch of different
products on [inaudible] dot com.
Go there,
check it out.
If you go to my website,
Joe Rogan.net,
click on the link for Alpha brain
entering the code name.
Rogan.
You'll 10 percent off and as always the
first 30 pills,
the first size you buy,
whatever it is,
first order rather.
If you don't like it,
you get 100 percent money back
guarantee.
Don't even have to send it back in.
All right,
we love you.
Freaks out soon.
Yeah,
tomorrow it'll be one of the best shows
ever we could ever put together.
It'll be little aster.
It'll be Joey motherfucking Diaz.
Duncan trussell,
Brian Red band,
Jason,
t.co,
and me all the ice house.
It's only like 15 bucks,
right?
ICEHOUSE comedy Dot Com and Ice House is
by the way,
run by some of the nicest people.
The waitstaff is cool as fuck.
The whole place has a great vibe to it.
It's a really cool old school comedy
club in Pasadena that's been around
since the 19 sixties.
I think it's really bad ass.
It's one of my favorite places and it's
also where we do the ice house
chronicles podcast,
which is why we're doing shows there.
Simultaneously.
We have a studio and we do podcasts at
the same time.
This last year,
you've been on that podcast twice.
Once was a scratch and when when we do
it,
it's really your key.
Your dog just went in there.
Go get.
He's eaten shit.
Jesus Christ.
Anyway,
I'm helping you out with whatever on
a.com,
blah,
blah.
Okay,
so this Thursday night,
how'd they get to an ice house?
Ice House comedy dot Com.
We also have a show Friday without Joe
Rogan by a bunch of other comics,
so icehouse comedy.com.
Also Friday if you're going to be in
Vegas,
I am going to be with Joey Diaz and
Duncan trussell.
We're doing the house,
a motherfucking blues at the Mandalay
Bay.
Then the next day it's Carlos condit and
Nick Diaz.
Christ fucking stars have aligned.
It's going to be crazy.
It's gonna be an awesome epic weekend
between two of the best fighters on the
planet earth in two of the three best,
170 pounders in the world.
And this is going to be chaos.
I can't fucking wait.
The whole card is the whole card sick.
Um,
and so that's this weekend,
Friday night house of Blues Tomorrow
night,
Thursday night,
Pasedena ice house for all information.
Go follow me on twitter.
Follow Red Ban.
Follow Eliza,
I,
l,
I z a super easy and anybody else they
should follow any friend you want to
pull our twitters and texts from
Bennett.
The twitter account that I told you
about.
That's hilarious.
That is like a billion followers.
Michelle,
do you explain it again?
It's this guy a mac lethal and he's this
white guy who's got a cousin who thinks
he's black and the guy sends him texts
all the time.
He doesn't know that he has his account.
It's the funniest,
most ignorant stuff you've ever heard.
And he's created this account,
but he is a huge fan and he wanted you
to know.
Oh,
please,
I'm going to right now tweet.
I'll show you what does the text from
what its from Bennett v e n n e t t
alright.
Alright that's it.
Sorry.
Page doesn't exist.
We love you bunches.
We'll see you soon.
Bye.