Brothers,
what bitches Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by the
fleshlight,
but you know that right?
This ain't your first Rodeo.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link for the flashlight
and entering the codename Brogan,
you will get number one sex toy for men
at 15 percent off.
Wonders of wonders,
way better than masturbating,
but I gotta warn you and you feel like a
fucking loser once it's over,
especially when you're cleaning that
bitch,
but it's worth it.
You will shoot big loads and they will
make you think clear,
right?
Denny?
Just like fucking Kundalini Yoga.
Basically the same type of shit.
Clean the mind open.
The pipes release the hounds were also
brought to you by [inaudible] Dot Com,
o n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain,
a cognitive enhancing supplemented I am
on right now.
If you're like,
Hey Joe Rogan while you talk so smooth
Joe Rogan,
why you got all those words at your Beck
and call Yo Dawg?
I'm on Alpha brain and people like,
hey man,
what's the science behind alphabet?
And go to [inaudible] dot com.
All answers will be given o,
n,
n I,
T,
and we're constantly looking to improve
that.
Any criticisms that we've had the past,
we absolutely appreciate it.
We are actually about to start a double
blind study with um,
what's that mean?
Like to,
to blank.
Like shut up.
Shut your out Brian with this double
line.
Well,
you got to fucking read online.
Needed to read Google,
Google,
double blind spot on the street.
Suddenly the disrespect site on the
street as you take the fucking bill,
you drink coconut water and you jerk off
into the cup and you look in the Cup
afterwards.
That's fucking mind boggling right
there.
Okay.
I,
that's the fucking deal.
Do you take the two pills?
Whatever the fuck.
CEO.
We're also a.
We make a shrewd anyway,
so people that have been asking for more
tests,
so we're on that.
It's going to work.
We're spending a lot of money to make
sure that this stuff is all legit.
It is legit for me,
I use it.
It works without a doubt.
No questions for me.
I've tried it,
I've gotten off of it.
I've tried it again.
I've fucked with myself as much as
possible to see it placebo effect.
It's not there,
it's legit.
I also love shroom Tech Sport,
which is the [inaudible] mushroom
supplement,
a supplement that,
uh,
it aids your,
your body's aids in your body's ability
to process oxygen really makes a
difference in any extreme exercise.
If you're into Jujitsu,
if you take like Kettlebell classes are
into crossfit or anything like that,
you will definitely find an advantage.
You will definitely feel an effect of
the shroom tech sport,
but if you just like a regular person
who doesn't exercise or you barely
exercise,
don't,
don't waste your money back.
If you also go to [inaudible] dot com,
we also have a shroom tech immune which
everyone should check out.
It's fascinating and the way it works,
the way it's been explained to me,
I'm obviously no scientist,
but your body recognizes this mushroom
different mushrooms than the shrimp tech
support.
Your body recognizes it as a possible
disease or a cold,
so your immune system fires up for a
fight that never takes place and so just
really generally boost your immune
system.
I,
I am a big believer in a bunch of
different things to keep your immune
system strong.
I'm a big believer in this room,
tech immune,
but I'm also a big believer in
probiotics and everyone should look into
that.
I have no financial stake in this,
but drink a Kombucha tea.
You know,
a lot of people have been,
um,
just just talking so highly about the
benefits,
the health benefits of this stuff,
you know,
for years and years.
And I never,
I did it when I first came to la.
I tried it,
but I was like,
the stuff tastes kind of nasty.
It's a weird sort of an acquired taste.
But then about a year or two years ago,
I started drinking it on a regular basis
because gts,
Kombucha and they make synergy and all
these different,
uh,
different flavors.
They started selling them at whole
foods.
So it was like super easy to buy.
And I started drinking them all the
time.
And one thing I noticed is I stopped
getting sick.
I think it has a big difference when you
take in a live organisms like
probiotics,
whether it's Acidophilus,
that's another great one to take and
spend the money and get that shit that
you have to keep in your refrigerator if
you can afford it because that's what
you really want.
They're really healthy live cultures and
essentially what it does is you know
these live cultures act as a security
force and they fight off all the country
cultures,
so any any country bacteria that you
come across,
you want to have these probiotics at
your beck and call like a live army to
fight off the cons of the disease world,
so look at it that way and this is by
the way,
nothing that we sell,
but get your ass on some acidophilus.
Get your ass on some Kombucha tea
checkout.
We also have a new mood which they five
htp enhancement supplement and what that
is is a five htp actually helps your
brain,
builds serotonin and interesting stuff.
If you were on antidepressants,
they recommend you not take it because
it actually can give you too much
serotonin along with your
antidepressants together.
Combined is not so good,
so talk to your doctor and all that
stuff,
but by itself,
if you're not on any medication,
it's absolutely safe.
Just don't go crazy and take the whole
bottle in one sitting.
You fucking freak.
You're on cocaine today.
No,
no.
I'm healthy.
I'm healthy and working out.
I've been working out for the first time
in months,
man,
about this fucking pulled muscle.
You are.
You're on fire today.
I did kettle bells.
I did.
I kicked the bag.
I'm a fucking.
I'm back.
Bitches.
Oh Shit.
Anyway,
go to [inaudible] Dot com o n I n o n n
I t o n n I t.com
entering the codename Rogan and you will
get 10 percent off.
Most importantly when you order every
order that you get is 100 percent money
back guarantee,
but only for the first 30 pills.
And he say why?
He used to be 100 percent guarantee all
the time because the world is full of
concrete.
That's why.
And because some douchebag thought it'd
be cool to odor a fuck load of bottles,
get all of his money back and then sell
the bottles on Ebay.
So because of the cost of the world,
even as you make a big order and you
decide somewhere along the line that you
don't like it,
you can't get your money back.
So if you,
if you do want your money back and it's
a big order,
you have to send in the unopened
bottles.
The first 30 pills though you can eat
them,
you can stuff them up your ass,
you can throw them in the toilet,
whatever the fuck you want
to do with them.
And then tell us I don't like it and we
give you all your money back.
Why?
Because I'm in a weird position.
I'm in a position where people are like,
what do you try to rip people off?
Absolutely fucking not.
But I do believe in this stuff.
And there's only one way to sell
something.
You believe in it.
You got to sell it and make it as easy
as possible for everybody.
And make your intentions as positive.
And as clear as possible,
and I don't think you can be any clear
than offering someone 100 percent of
their money back.
If they don't like the product,
you don't have to send it in.
You don't have to do shit.
Just if you the first 30 pills,
just take them.
And then if you don't like it,
you get your money back.
Also,
if you think it's too expensive,
I urge you,
go to the website.
All the ingredients are clearly listed
in the exact doses by all this stuff in
bulk.
And save money and do it at a discount.
Make your own Alpha brain.
Try it out.
I don't care.
Use other people's stuff.
Have a good life.
Eat nutrients,
take vitamins,
eat healthy food,
eat fresh vegetables.
Get Your Dick sucked.
Every now and again,
am I right Joe Diaz?
Come on,
am I right?
Eddie?
Bravo.
Fucking old jokes.
Add that in there too.
You've got some old couple jumping
jacks.
A little swimming.
Let's kick this.
Kick this motherfucker.
Here we go.
Joe Rogan podcast,
my life.
Thank God men like Nick Diaz exist this
weekend.
Nick Diaz and Carlos Condit.
Thank God those guys exist.
Thank God those guys exist and thank God
those guys have built themselves up to
the point where this is one of those
matches were five fucking round,
man.
You can't wait.
You're gonna.
Be Palm sweaty.
Rubbing your hands together before that
bitch.
I don't know who's going to be the
referee for this.
I don't know who it is,
but before that one person looks at the
Blue Corner and works in the red corner
and then said,
fight.
That shit is going to be crazy.
Carlos Congo,
who's been trying for eight years for
the fucking fight,
fucking training.
Every two months they change a folder.
It's perfect.
He said,
19.
Fucking apologize.
Batman.
He's on one.
It's really for him.
I think it's perfect because he's.
He's so prepared.
It was a perfect time for him.
You know?
60 plus 1:30.
The line is not that bad.
It's minus one six.
You would be crazy to pick a favorite in
this fight.
I think he'd be crazy.
I think that this is one of those who
the fuck knows what's going to happen.
Fights this could be.
Who knows?
It's going to be amazing.
That's Roy Nelson to tell about that.
Oh,
how about Hanan Barao and Scott Jorgen
that Hanan Barao dude,
he's the dark horse of the pound for
pound division because he's not a
champion yet,
but he might be one of the top pound for
pound guys.
He's right up there with Aldo.
He's a beast.
Did you see his last fight with brand
picket?
He hit home boy with a knee to the face
with no jump.
Just fucking leapt up with this knee,
you know,
instead of that thing where they lift
the front leg and then they come up with
the right leg.
They'll start with the left leg and then
they use it as forced to kick up with
the right leg.
Some of these bad ass Brazilians like
Anderson can do it too,
where they just fly through the air with
one knee and just lifted that knee up
and crack caught.
Caught Brad Pickett in the chin.
I mean,
he's a beast.
Do M is Jujitsu.
It's fucking sick.
You know,
as soon as Brad Pickett,
like stumbled and he saw position,
he'd jumped on that back.
So quick man.
It was a thing of beauty man.
I saw the UFC special on Nick Diaz.
Carlos condit.
Which one?
Episode one Shit,
I don't know.
Episode two.
I don't know if it's aired yet.
Is it the one where they haven't been
years like kindergarten teacher.
She remembered neck.
Remember Nick,
and this is.
I learned a lot about nick and I come up
with a hypothesis.
You know before,
when was in the early days if you were a
black belt in Jujitsu,
shit,
you had a shot at the title and then it
became if you were an Olympic wrestler,
damn you have a shot at the time.
Now it's obvious now it's becoming more
like all other sports,
like if you didn't wrestle,
do Jiu Jitsu and,
and worked on striking since day one as
a kid.
[inaudible].
There's so many kids doing that.
All three now.
You don't want,
you're not going to have a shot in the
very near future.
And I think there's one.
There's one more factor,
and that's the Nick Diaz factor.
There's obviously he doesn't like
cameras.
He's,
he said it a million times.
He doesn't like to talk in front of
cameras.
He's not,
you know,
um,
he's,
he's not into it and maybe he shy in
front of the camera or whatever.
And his teacher was even saying that he
wasn't the most vocal guy and,
and,
and he had trouble expressing himself
and all that shit.
And um,
when he gets in that cage and that door
slammed shut and the crowd is roaring,
there's no more fucking talking.
He just comes alive.
He looks at his opponent is like nobody
can fucking hear you.
You can be the most articulate,
funny,
charismatic guy on the fucking planet.
But you know what?
I fucking run all day.
Swim all day,
do box.
I got a crazy Chen.
I'm gonna fucking kill this
motherfucker.
That's like a,
that's an x factor right there.
If you didn't like,
you have to look for that.
I think in the future in fighters,
like do they have that switch where when
they fucking get in that cage,
it's just,
it really is like life or death.
His is a very good,
a
different thing than anybody else's.
First of all.
His approach to it is so different than
anybody else's in that he does like
endurance training,
like long distance marathon type
training and basically forces these guys
to try to keep up with them.
I mean he basically puts them into an
endurance contest and tries to get them
to keep up with them.
That's why he does a lot of juking and
lot of getting in their face.
All that stuff tenses you up,
all that stuff.
All those punches that he throws at 50,
60 percent,
all those tighten you up.
You know,
one of the things that frank shamrock
said was that when,
when Nick Diaz was punching me,
pitch you so often you can't breathe.
You don't know when to breathe.
You can't relax because you,
you never get to relax because they're,
they're just,
they just keep coming,
which is just different.
He just,
he just fights in a different way.
I think the way it does it is brilliant.
It's so brilliant because no one else
did it before him.
No one else figured out that that way to
fight no one else really would not just
have great skills,
but have ridiculous worldclass endurance
like swim from Alcatraz endurance.
That's the shit man.
They said they went through a countdown.
He sparked like some ridiculous amount
of rounds that he ran five miles and
then he swam for an hour and a half.
That was just one day.
He just does that all day.
You still maybe maybe he has some kind
of condition where he's obsessed with
exercise.
I don't know.
I mean,
I think he loves it for sure.
when he was a kid,
he said that he,
you know,
he,
I think he said it was one of the
countdown shows.
His,
uh,
his,
think it was his uncle or someone was
like a track coach.
Yeah.
He used to take him,
his grandfather,
Danny.
Proper ghosts.
But that's the other thing too.
The other thing too with him,
you know what?
He doesn't like fucking talking.
You smoke a joint.
What do you feel like?
Do I go for a fucking run?
See what happens to you.
It feels great.
It feels open.
Joint.
I go to fucking swim fit for an hour
where you feel like fucking Hercules'
when you.
That's my world.
I love this fucking world.
Smokes weed.
What his insurance comes from from
going,
I don't want to hang out with these dumb
fucks is I might stab somebody.
I'll just smoke a joint rental,
left the fucking highway.
Where's law?
And he runs the fucking two hours.
When I lived in boulder,
I used to smoke and run and the high
when you finish fucking run is a
complete different dimension.
Yeah.
Even when you smoke and lift man,
everyday feel you feel all your muscle
tissue.
Like when he pressing weights,
he feel it.
You feel your whole body moving and
swipe in.
At Roland they say,
well,
not just at Yoga and smoking the way
you're supposed to do,
and I used to eat it to take a little
piece of banana bread or a little hash
cookie.
I take it in seven in the morning,
go to 8:30
years old.
You know,
my head is at 8:30
and the bitches smoking.
Yeah.
And I would just go into it little by
little and it's amazing.
It's fucking amazing when you walk out
of there,
you don't know what agent you really
don't.
So that's what my thing is with him,
that he just,
you know what,
he's not the type of guy that's going to
go to a club or whatever.
What would you do?
Smoke,
smoking.
Joe.
He's the last guy I'd
want to fight because think about it,
like compare them to GSP and even John
Jones and Anderson Silva that what he
has,
they don't have.
Maybe they will develop it is he will
stand right in front of you and exchange
with you and he's down to go to war
right in front of you.
I mean,
not very.
GSP ain't gonna do that,
Jon Jones probably won't even do that
and if you decide to take him down,
he'll fuck you up on the ground to his
Jujitsu.
It's amazing.
What the fuck are you going to do that?
What are you going to do with Nick Diaz?
And he was killing you.
Going to do with him Cyborg.
You was killing sideboards standing up.
So sidebar took them down and whip
armbar within 30 seconds he had him in
an arm bar.
I mean,
GSP might be able to take him down.
What is he going to do?
He's not going to pass this guard.
He's not gonna pass.
Nick Diaz's guard.
He doesn't get tired when you're on top
of him either.
You know a lot of dudes,
man,
you put them on their back and they just
get exhausted.
They get demoralized,
they get exhausted unless we see his
chin fall apart.
Man,
I don't,
I can't see him lose.
Well,
you know that can happen to some
fighters when they take beatings.
No,
that can't happen.
We've seen it happen over and over.
You know,
and vandelay and so many guys,
chuck eventually that they had iron
chance and they would come even if they
got randomly,
never had an iron chin.
Vandelay got dropped a lot.
Soccer.
Robert dropped him.
A lot of people dropped them.
Henderson had.
I'm really badly her.
He just was a lot worse.
Now.
It's a lot worse,
arguably,
but you know,
he was already just this dude who ran
face for first.
You know,
he did.
One of the things that made vandelay
great was,
Whoa,
how reckless he was.
You know,
he didn't give a fuck.
He would charge that.
You literally like a wild dog.
You know,
he built like a pit bull just running at
you.
But that style,
it gets you hurt.
You know that style.
I mean he's not,
it's not a coincidence that he's the
only guy of his era that had to have
facial reconstruction so he could
breathe,
you know,
his,
his nose was flattened,
smashed flat.
And if you go and look at his face from
when he first entered into pride and
then his face in his first UFC fight
with chuck,
he's a completely different person.
You didn't even recognize him.
He was a handsome guy when he first got
into interpride,
who's I have fucking some guy vendelay
look at values.
Hot.
Pretty sexy.
I danced with him.
If he was cute.
He was a sexy.
It was a completely different looking
person,
you know?
No Kara as well.
No,
Gary's face looks way different to.
How about nate fucking Diaz?
Holy Shit.
And it's like a carbon capo.
Nick Diaz.
Nick Diaz is.
We don't just have one that's fucking
incredible.
He was just like maybe a year behind
Nick Diaz sort of in development.
It seemed like maybe in Jujitsu was a
little behind and in the striking
striking power.
And now he's like caught up to nick had
some weight problems to where he didn't
cut the weight.
Right.
And now he cuts it right.
And now he has way more energy because
when he went up to one 70,
you know,
he had some fights where he looked bad
ass like the rory mark and fight holy
shit.
And I thought,
man,
you know,
this kid is draining themselves too much
to get down to 55.
But then he figured out how to do 55.
Right?
And he came in and the goal fight just
fucking lit me up.
But serone fight was even more
impressive because he did it for three
fucking rounds.
So it shows that he's got endurance at
1:55
two.
And he lit cowboy up.
Man.
I mean that.
I thought that was going to be a crazy
close fight.
It's like sort of how I feel about this
condit fight.
I don't know what the hell's going to
happen.
I look at it,
I'm like,
man,
both guys are tough as fuck.
Both guys have mad skills.
Both guys can survive.
Some dudes can't be the nail.
You know,
some dudes can be the hammer,
but when they the nail they fall apart.
Conduct doesn't fall apart.
Man.
And Connie got bombed on by Jake
Ellenberger ellenberger had him in all
sorts of trouble and ellenberger puts
people away.
That kid hits fucking hard.
He's one of the hardest hitting guys at
one 70.
And he bombed condit and conduct,
covered up,
weathered the storm,
and came back.
That was the first fucking around man.
He was in all sorts of trouble in the
first round where a lot of lot of
referees would have pulled that trigger
router.
A lot of referees would have stopped
that fight if they didn't respect him
and they didn't know him.
If he was like a new guy into the UFC,
how did that fight end?
Again,
he wanted a decision what?
A close decision,
but it was a great fucking fight.
But what it proved to me is that conduit
is no front runner.
He's a dude that is in it to win it.
The Rory Macdonald fight.
Another perfect example of that third
round came back and stopped him,
lost the first two rounds,
came back in the third round,
stopped them.
And that kid is a fucking phenol man.
That Rory Macdonald,
man,
he was a fucking elbow.
He got it.
He crushed them on the ground.
He broke his face open on the ground.
He,
you know,
contents on animal.
He's a real fucking killer.
That guys is straight killer.
What he said in that countdown show was
bad ass.
He goes,
I want the rest of the referee to
rescue.
I want the referee to come in and save
your life.
Save your fucking life,
man.
And that's the way to do things like
that.
That that's a killer man.
I mean,
if he wasn't doing this,
he would be somewhere working for the
military that I wrote.
I always said that about him.
He's a killer.
He's a fucking kill him.
And that natural born killer.
That's not just a nickname.
You know,
you can talk all that tough Guy Shit you
want.
What happens when you actually get in
there and you're throwing down when that
guy is actually in there and he's
throwing down,
he's a fucking stone cold killer.
They both are.
They're both stone cold killers.
Neither guy is going to be scared of the
other guy and both guys are going to be
just going in there ready to just let it
all hang out.
This is going to be a crazy weekend.
I wish I wasn't working.
I wish I fucking get Kenny Florian to
fill in.
I want to get hammered.
Sit Cage summit.
I'm going to take.
It would be an honor to to call this
fight.
Don't get me wrong,
but there's fights like that where I
wish I could just go.
Oh,
got you.
Gosh.
Checking my peers.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
you kidding me,
man.
Both peers.
Peers is dangerous for everybody.
Here's why.
He's one of those guys that eventually
he's going to catch on.
You know,
eventually pierce is going to hit his
stride and he is going to be Johnny
Hendricks and dudes.
You know,
like Johnny Hendricks just took out
finch.
There's his wrestler dudes that are
just.
They're striking is slowly getting
better,
slowly getting better,
but the power's always there.
It's just a matter of figuring out how
to put face to face and they're getting
better at it.
And Johnny Hendricks,
man,
the way he put out John Fitch like that
with one punch,
I'll tell you what,
Johnny Hendricks hits anybody with that
punch.
Anybody and your Foxville fucked.
That guy hits really hard.
There's some guys who watch them hit
dudes in the cage and you know,
you know,
you say,
well,
hey,
that's a strong guy.
That's an athletic guy.
Hendrix is one of those guys.
He's got that extra.
There's an extra.
There's some dudes when they hit you,
you hear it.
When you hear them hit the bag,
you know you're not ever knowing when
you hit it.
I hit the bag and they go,
this motherfucker's got that extra pop
to it.
That's what Hendrix has gotten you here.
The have that or you don't have that.
I mean,
you can certainly make your punching
power better.
You certainly build your muscles up a
bit,
put some weight on learning how to turn
your body into things better.
But some dudes just know how to throw
and that Hendrix cat knows how to throw
and sodas.
Pierce,
he knows how to fuck.
Especially that left hook.
Oh,
who he's got power and cost check to
man.
Caustic is dangerous as fuck man.
That man,
he was fight.
That was,
that was a brutal assassination man.
You know,
that was a,
it was a brutal ending to that fight.
Which you kind of knew what was gonna
happen stylistically.
You like,
well here's two really good wrestlers,
but one of them had stupid knockout
power and the other one you know,
has been knocked out a few times.
It's not,
it's not the best stylistic matchup for
Hughes.
You know,
now he's going to fight again.
Who's looking for another fight?
Hughes man,
he's an hoists gracie.
They should make that happen,
man.
He'll kill hoists.
That doesn't matter.
It's good rematch.
Hoy's wants it really bad.
No matter what happens.
If I shouldn't be,
I shouldn't say always because you never
know.
What the fuck is gonna happen and who's
great.
She's a legend,
but based on that first fight,
I would hate to see that again,
unless there was something wrong with it
is he's claiming he was sick or
something.
I don't know who he.
His voice is an all time great.
He's the original legend.
He was the first Jujitsu Guy,
the first guy to show the world.
If it wasn't for him,
I would have never known.
None of us would have ever known if it
wasn't for his accomplishments in the
ultimate fighting championship.
None of us would have ever known,
but that was a long fucking time ago.
You know,
and errors.
They pass for reason and at a certain
point in time,
your body just has not moved the same
anymore.
You know,
and the world passes you by and when
that happens,
you got to step aside,
man,
you got to step aside.
You can't just be going out there and
getting knocked out all the time and get
hurt all the time because it's just,
it's just reality.
You know,
reality.
There's a certain point in time where
all of us are going to be dust band and
the only way this sport really works is
that we stop people from competing when
they hit that point because they don't
believe it.
The same thing that makes someone,
a great fighter make someone say,
no,
you're all wrong.
I'm going to prove the world.
I'm going to go out and one more time
I'm making a comeback that.
But that's,
that's how guys get fucked up.
But they got to decide for themselves.
A voice wants to fight.
I want to.
I would love to see Hoist Matt Hughes.
He wants it.
If Matt huge wants,
wants another fight.
That's a great remark.
What if you got them mad?
What if he was good on his back?
Just like before.
That'd be bombing them in the head.
Dean would come in and stop it at the
perfect time.
I don't know,
man.
I don't want to watch that fight again.
I don't want to watch what happens.
I love voice too much,
man.
I love that guy.
I think he's like I said,
he's a legend.
He said he's not going to get killed.
They'll tap.
I don't want to.
I want to see him fighting that in the
end.
Unless there was something really wrong
with them and unless he's different now.
I.
You want it really bad.
I think that's good enough.
You know?
Who else wants Hughes?
Who Your boy?
Mike Hardy.
Oh Shit.
Damn hard,
he's been calling them out and hard to
do a good fight to him.
Apparently.
That'd be a good fight.
Yeah.
You don't think it'd be able to take Dan
hardee down fairly easily.
Oh,
Dan's worked really hard on his rest.
I'm assuming he's working like day and
night on takedown defense and diffuse
goes back to the way he was wrestling
when he was at his peak.
I mean,
if that's possible,
if his body can still do that,
man,
remember those days,
like the saccharide days when you,
you know,
people forget how dominant that
motherfucker was.
You know,
he was dominant man.
He was like,
one of the first dominant wrestler is
actually that learned submissions too,
so he wouldn't just beat you up.
He started strangling guys taken back.
He started getting armbars frank trigg.
Fuck Ya.
Beat him twice.
Twice with a rear naked choke the second
time after he got kicked in the balls.
Yep.
Those were great memories.
Picked him up and walk them across
after.
After Frank trigg was bombing on them.
Frank Trigg,
God is back and it looked bad,
but frank trigg does not know how to
finish that joke,
his know how to defend or finish and
that he was picked him up,
walked into the middle of the fucking
cage and threw him against the ground.
It was awesome,
man.
It was awesome.
That was like one of the best moments
like mma moments come from behind,
you know,
from being stuck,
got kicks you in the balls,
hit you with a bunch of shots,
takes your back and this is that in a
rematch of a fight where you fucked him
up in the first fight and he didn't want
to fight him in the second fight anyway,
and then he starts winning and then he
was just mustered all up and turn it all
around.
That was amazing.
That was some amazing shit.
Yeah.
Some good high guard action in that
fight as well.
Seeing that a guy like he was.
I mean I think he uses a great fighter,
but I think a certain,
a certain number of knockouts,
the they have to step in and stop you
from doing that.
Whether it's your family,
whether it's your friends,
whether it's,
you know,
your boss,
there's a certain amount of times,
you know,
I've talked to a,
there's a,
a guy that I know very well who is a
brain is a traumatic brain injury
specialist and what he deals with is
rehabilitating people and um,
and helping people like with all these
mental imbalances that people have due
to traumatic brain injuries.
One of the things that happens is your
body stops producing testosterone.
You get really lethargic,
you get depressed.
Like that happens to a lot of guys that
have a bunch of head injuries.
They get depressed.
The apparently your brain can only take
like a few concussions in your life who
needs to retire right now,
who,
I would never tell any of them to
retire.
But there's a few dudes that I would,
I would pull aside and I would say,
you know,
think about this a little bit.
You know,
who I don't want to say because I'm in
my position,
you know,
being a commentator.
But there's,
there's a lot of,
um,
any,
any dudes who have been knocked out a
gang of times,
but there's guys that violate that shit.
Like Alistair Overeem,
Alistair overeem been stopped a bunch of
times.
Dude,
he's been knocked out a gang of times.
How many times?
A lot.
I would bet he's been stopped at least
eight times.
Damn.
Yeah.
Yeah,
he's been.
Chuck knocked him out.
Okay.
Badr.
Hari knocked him out in,
in,
in kickboxing.
Um,
what does that big dude that used to
fight king of the cage?
Real angry guy.
Hoffman.
Bob Hoffman.
Bob Hoffman knocked them out.
How about Bobby Hoffman?
K Odem.
I'm Shogun Kod.
I'm,
I believe I'm a bunch of dudes.
Stopped him at a bar.
Oh,
Keratan off.
Knocked him out.
A bunch of dudes stopped overeem.
But overeem figured it out,
man.
And one of the things he figured out,
he was just too fucking small.
He was too small at two.
Oh five.
You know,
when he moved up to heavyweight.
But then again,
Keratan a pink Keratan of Jack intimate
heavyweight.
He started,
you know,
I don't what,
what changed in him?
Man,
what changed his ultimate dedication?
What changed in his intensity?
What would change,
but no one's ever turned it around like
overeem.
No one's ever gone from being stopped
like eight times and you know,
back when he was fighting at two.
Oh five.
As you know,
in mma,
he was thought of is,
you know,
a tough guy,
but a guy who would gas out,
he goes from that to be the first guy to
win a world title in both MMA andK ,
one kickboxing.
No one's ever done that before.
No one,
everyone that k one Grand Prix and one
in mma title and looks like that.
You know who the fuck looks like?
Alistair overeem means the Goddamn
Superhero in a comic book.
He turned it around.
So when you got a guy like that,
you kind of can't say anything.
You know,
you look at Mirko Cro cop and you go,
man,
I love Cro cop.
He's a legend.
He's got one of the greatest highlight
reels of all time.
Those head kick knockouts,
one after the other,
but at a certain point in time,
how many times can cro cop get knocked
out before someone doesn't want to,
you know,
you feel bad for them,
you know what's amazing,
the alertness of the whole concussion
thing,
like everybody's hip to it now.
Like I was watching 60 minutes Tuesday
night and they interviewed Roger
Goodell,
the,
the whatever,
the NFL and a Monday he reviews tapes to
see who gets concussions and they showed
a guy hitting another guy,
like a wide receiver getting hit by a
defensive back and he pointed to the
defensive back getting the concussion.
It stayed in the fucking game.
So they're finding them know if they.
They stay in the fucking game with a
concussion because you know,
you don't want to go to fuck out.
You're rocking your plane.
You know what I'm saying?
So you don't even feel it,
but it's amazing how the guys are
standing voluntarily.
So who the fuck are you to tell a
dangerous man?
It's really dangerous in the football
players.
They're finding out now you know these
guys,
by the time they even get to college,
a lot of them are fucked up.
That dude who remember that dude who
died,
henry something.
Henry died in a back of a pickup truck
filled football player really recently.
Do you don't know what I'm talking
about?
Him and his girlfriend were arguing.
He jumped in the back of a pickup truck
and try to google that shit.
Brian,
if he can.
Henry something.
Henry football player,
dead pickup truck.
Anyway,
the dude died.
Don't dump about Olin.
The dude died and he was only 28.
I think they.
They checked out his brain and the brain
of like an old man,
it was.
His brain was all fucked up.
His brand showed massive damage because
he had been kod.
Who knows how many times.
By the time he got to the pros,
you get killed in high school.
You get out and junior high school.
I talked to a dude who had a fucking 11
year old son and his 11 year old son got
knocked out for a half an hour and they
put them back in a month later,
a month later that kids playing football
game and I'm like,
you're crazy.
What are my students got knocked out?
And Chris Henry.
Chris Henry.
Yeah.
That was his story.
He doesn't say anything about his brain.
A Cincinnati bengals football player.
Chris Henry died after he fell.
Hold on after he fell.
Oh Shit.
It just went away.
Um,
he fell off the back of a pickup.
The back of the APP.
Pickup truck.
Fuck man.
These guys,
man,
they don't realize a lot of people they
had no idea.
So they would just throw in these people
back in,
over and over and over again.
And now they're starting to put it
together.
When you went over there,
Joey,
what are you doing?
Chicken soda.
Well,
one of my guys got knocked out last
weekend and the amateur show and he
wasn't knocked out completely.
It was controversial.
Almost like the rest stop that it could
have.
It was on the fence,
whether it was early or not.
He got up right away and was
complaining.
He was never out,
but he was like a little rock.
I didn't complain about the stoppage.
It looked.
It looked legit.
He got rock standing and then got taken
down a couple of ground and pound
against the cage.
He never was out,
popped up.
By the time we got backstage,
by the end he sat down.
He didn't remember anything about the
fight.
Not One.
I don't remember anything about the day.
He wasn't even out though.
That's the crazy thing.
He wasn't even out and he doesn't
remember.
He didn't remember the name of the hotel
we were in.
Well,
you remember when we saw Tim Sylvia,
we were in the hotel bar.
We're waiting to get our car to the
airport and it was the next day after he
fought randy coture,
he fought five rounds against randy and
lost his title and he came up to us and
he goes,
dude.
He goes,
I don't even remember the fight.
And he goes,
uh,
I,
I remember the,
the,
the bell ringing.
And then I remember sitting in the
corner asking,
uh,
my corner,
what rounded was,
and now it's the last round.
And he's like,
what the last round,
like you just fought five rounds on
instinct.
He had no idea what happened.
He got hit with one righthand early in
the fight and just had no idea what
happened.
Wow.
Yeah,
that's what you don't.
We don't.
You know what,
that's why it drives me crazy when
someone would call a fighter a pussy.
Oh,
this guy,
you know,
he never brings you the fights.
Like a wet blanket.
You go get your,
you get your fucking brains rearrange
Sun.
You get someone shit and kicking you up
the side of the head.
You know,
there's a lot of guys like criticized
guides for being boring.
You know,
it doesn't bother me at all.
I don't,
I mean maybe I don't necessarily want to
see them,
but I respect what they're doing.
I respect like,
like Antonio Mckey,
a lot of guys give him a lot of shit,
you know,
because he,
he kinda like wrestled to the ground.
He never never gets into standup
exchanges with guys too much and it
doesn't take any damage,
but that's the key.
He doesn't take any damage.
Yeah.
Might not be the most exciting thing in
the world,
but if you want to fight,
that's really.
That's a smart way to fight,
man.
Smartly.
If you just closed a closed shop,
clothes,
everything,
there'll be no punching that we know
nothing.
There'll be you on your back and be
punching you a little bit here and
again,
but nothing crazy because I don't want
to get submitted and then I'll win every
fight.
You know,
it's,
it's not the smartest way to do it
because it's a,
it's a sport and you're also marketing
yourself.
It's entertainment,
but I understand that.
I'll never call one of those guys are
pushing.
It's a smart way to fight,
man.
What'd you think of these fighters?
Last weekend was tough match ups,
you know,
first of all,
uh,
the Damien Maia fight Weidman do cut a
shitload of weight.
He took that fight on 11 days notice and
you could tell when he was in there,
he,
he struggled.
And even Ray Longo gave it away in the
corner.
Ray Longo said,
you know,
I saw what you went through yesterday.
I saw what you did yesterday,
you can do this.
They said that his,
his cut was horrific,
but he,
that kid is so fucking tough.
He just did it.
And he went out there and he grinded on
Maya and he wanted a decision.
But you could tell by the end of the
first round he was dead.
He was dead walking.
And My,
uh,
luckily for him was dead to Maya Look,
look like really?
Like I heard he had a flu or something
like earlier in the week.
He did not look good either.
So both guys,
it was a,
it was a real endurance issue,
you know,
like I was talking to Jeremy Piven at
Germany and was like laughing about it,
know,
because I didn't interview them and he's
like,
would you have said to them?
So it's safe to say endurance was an
issue in this fight because it really
was like,
it was kind of,
you know,
it wasn't the best fight to showcase
mma,
you know,
but it was just a circumstantial
situation is nothing you could do about
it.
You got one guy was a fucking stud
wrestler with all this God potential
that Chris Weidman could be the king of
the world someday.
He could be the John Jones of 185
pounds.
He's a,
he's a beast.
He's a wicked wrestler.
He puts guys to sleep.
You put Tom Laurdis leap with that
fucking darce choke.
He's nasty man.
He's strong as fuck.
I saw him fight Galvao in Abi Dhabi.
He avoided everything and he got golf
vowel in a fucking.
Doris didn't tap him,
but the fact that he was able to sink it
in and lock it up and had galvao
fighting to,
to,
you know,
to get his legs under him and to defend.
Pretty fucking impressive for a dude as
a wrestler.
I mean,
I don't know what is Brazilian Jujitsu
rank is,
but he's one of those kids that,
you know,
he's really fucking strong willed,
really smart,
and he's just a winner.
There's some dudes that are just
winters,
man.
They could have a torn meniscus,
they can have a fucking herniated disc.
They take you down anyway.
They take you down.
Anyone they still strangle you while
they're in pain.
There's dudes that can just force force
through shit like that.
And that's Weidman's one of those,
man,
he's a fucking animal.
And then Damien Maia,
you don't want to think about my man.
He's in limbo right now because my at
one point in time was just taken
everybody down and strangled them.
He was all Jujitsu and that's when
everybody loved him.
He was nasty,
but somewhere along the line he figured,
you know what,
these nate Marquardt,
these guys,
I can't take down.
They beat the fuck out of me standing.
I got to get my stand up better.
But in doing that,
his Jujitsu is just not the same.
It's not what it used to be.
You know,
he submitted to jail sonnet and he
submitted at Herman.
He submitted all these guys.
He was strangling people,
man.
And it was nasty when,
when he got you on the ground,
you were Foxville pulled guard on those
guys.
He refuses to pull gardener Chael
Sonnen.
He hit it with a fucking lateral drop.
You remember?
I mean he was nasty but.
But his stand up is not good.
He's a mechanical,
like he moves like the whitest guy on
earth.
You know what I mean?
Like if you look at the way he moves
around,
he's got like this and he does the same
thing over and over again.
He paused with the right and then throws
the left pause with the right and then
throws the left.
It's way too predictable,
you know,
he needs to.
That guy needs to.
If he really wants to work on a stand
up,
he needs to go to Holland and just hang
out with tyrone spong for a year.
It just do what that guy does.
Move the way that guy does,
you know,
go,
go train will go con Saki,
go train with,
go to Mike's gym and workout with Melvin
manhoef.
See the way those guys move,
you gotTa,
move like that.
Imitate them,
move the way they're moving.
Do those kinds of combinations.
Maybe your body doesn't exactly move the
way that body moves,
but try to emulate it.
The best strikers all have a particular
style like specially kickboxers.
They all have a particular style.
You Watch men who fight,
he moves and he throws,
Fain Tito's feint,
boom,
and he throws kicks.
He's got a very particular way of moving
and that the way of moving is the way of
an elite striker.
You know a dude like when you see it was
that dude's name Shale Sanderson.
You ever see that?
Do a wrestle.
That dude gets low and he moves on
dudes.
There's guys that you look at them,
you look at the move around on the mat,
you go,
that's a fucking killer.
You know,
like Mark Schultz back in the day,
you would look at Mark Schultz,
move around like that is a killer.
There's a certain way that guy moves you
like that's an elite wrestler,
no doubt about it.
There's a way he hits those,
hits those take downs.
It's elite.
You gotta imitate those guys.
You gotta if you want to be a real
striker,
you got to figure out what those guys
are doing it,
figure out that style and then do it.
Apply it to mma,
but you've got to imitate the way they
move.
And right now Damien Maia does not move
the way those elite strikers move,
you know,
he's so good at Jujitsu.
I know that he could be good at
everything else,
but it's kind of a leap,
you know,
at 32 years of age,
it's,
it's tricky,
right?
How many is about 32?
I'm not sure how old he is,
but I,
I really think that,
that,
um,
him eliminating the pulling guard
strategy as really hindered his game.
I mean,
there's only three things you can do in
a fight.
You can fight standing where the dude,
you can try to take the guy down or you
can pull guard.
That's all you can do.
And Damien Maia always had that third
option.
Most MMA fighters,
most of you seen fighters don't aren't
good at that third option,
their guard isn't dangerous enough to
pull and attack.
Look at Paul Harris,
Paul Harris,
that he who?
Who is the guy beat.
They put her in a leg lock.
Oh Mckenzie.
Oh yeah.
That guy.
I'm that guy.
Could have been an Olympic wrestler and
a k,
one champion.
And Paul,
it didn't matter to Paul Harvey.
He took that out of the equation.
He took us through a little shot and he
pulled guard and went right after his
legs.
He bypassed the superior wrestling.
He bypassed the superior striking.
He had the third option.
Most fighters don't have that third
option.
Damien Maia was one of the few that did
have the third option.
If he was having trouble on his feet and
he couldn't take the guy down,
which comes up all the time,
having trouble on your feet.
Can't take the dude down.
If you don't have that third option,
you're going to just stand up and either
lose a decision or get knocked out.
And,
and that's,
I would love to see Paul Harris and
Damien Maia.
And remember at the height of Damien
Maia,
he was pulling guard.
He was taking shots.
If he didn't take them down,
he would pull garth.
He would sweep them,
get on top and attack.
He's not doing that no more.
He decided,
some,
someone convinced them that just be a
striker to stand up,
try to take a guy down there.
So many guys out there that he's not
going to be able to take down.
And there's so many guys that he's not
going to be able to strike with Wa
Weidman.
Yeah.
What are you going to do now?
And you know what he's,
you know,
he was tired and sued for both guys.
Weren't in the best shape for that
fight.
They both obviously had some sort of
physical issue.
Would it be didn't if Weidman was at his
best.
It's a terrible fight for him.
It's terrible fight.
He's not going to take the.
But if he would have been the old damen
meier where he would have taken a shot,
you know,
sprawled,
he would've pulled guard.
His guard is dangerous enough in
submissions and sweeps where he could
have did something to Weidman,
but he took that out of the equation and
then he decided to kick box with them
and now all those years of Jujitsu,
he's so good at Jujitsu.
It's not even in the game.
It's a kickboxing match.
Why would you do that?
You know,
if you can't take the guy down,
the drag them down.
Otherwise you have to kickbox and my is
not a kickboxer so stupid.
I look at Paul Harris,
look at bars.
What he did,
he took a lazy shot.
The guy sprawled and sprawled right into
guard.
Went right to a leg lock.
The fight was over in.
Those blocks are ridiculous,
dude.
His legs are ridiculous.
That was watching him move around and I
was like,
this dude has like grapefruit stuffed
into his cafs.
Cafs really looked like that.
Nobody's built like Paul.
People should watch that fight.
Pahara his last fight and look at that
as a serious way out of a fight that
you're having trouble and if you're in a
fight and you're beating them standing,
fuck it.
Stay standing.
You've got this motherfucker.
Don't take them down.
If you can take them down.
If it's pretty easy to take him down,
take him down,
get on top,
but if you can't strike with them and
you can't take them down,
which comes up and so many fights,
it's so common.
You got to have your guard dangerous
enough so that you can pull guard either
with leg locks.
You know,
whatever liquid Baha'is look at early
Maya.
Yeah,
he's got to figure it out,
but too bad.
His Jujitsu is awesome.
It's awesome.
The old days watched him is awesome.
He's definitely got to figure it out
though.
It's fucking crazy.
Game,
man.
The fight game.
It's a ridiculous game.
Ridiculous way to make a living,
man.
We want to talk about the craziest,
most dangerous way outside of war to
make a living.
That's it,
right?
Imagine getting pushed into face
everyday training.
Yeah.
I can't fucking shit again for sure.
Every fucking day,
10 fucking years.
I remember when I first,
uh,
the thing that really got me thinking
about what kind of damage a striking
does to your head was when I started
transitioning from taekwondo to
kickboxing man because I was a novice.
My striking was not very good.
My hands were not good.
I could punch hard,
but I didn't really know how to box yet.
And I would go in there with guys who
didn't know how to box and even if they
weren't punching you hard,
they were hitting you a lot and you just
go home and you're fucking what would
lie in bed.
And my head would throb foam,
foam,
foam is that terrible female.
Like what am I doing in my brain?
No,
this can't be good.
Lying in bed with headaches after a
sparring session.
That shit can't be good.
And he'd go everywhere.
The,
the light would hurt.
Like I wear sunglasses because he was.
The light would like hurt when your head
is pounding from getting punched in the
head.
Shit is so bad for you.
That's why Jujitsu so beautiful.
You get the,
you get the thrill of the kill,
yet there's no brain damage it except
you know the guy who scares everybody
the most.
It's Paul Harris because everybody else
just kind of taps you out.
Paul Harvey's rips your legs apart.
He rips through his legs apart.
I mean he just gets a hold of your leg
and like,
sorry ain't walking right anymore.
That's it.
You be legs.
Fuck for like a year.
Good luck.
He might be the first guy to leg lock
his way to the top because if he just
keeps doing what he's doing,
what is he doing?
He's not really striking too much with a
little bit.
He's just going to shoe and you're gonna
sprawl because the shot wasn't that
good.
He's not a wrestler.
And then he's going to pull guard right
into your legs.
So what are you going to do against
that?
You can work on your takedown defense
all fucking day to your head explodes.
He's going to pull guard on you.
He's taken all your wrestling and just
throwing it out and fucking garbage all
you're striking.
You're wasting your motherfucking time.
He's just going to take a shot and pull
guard.
He's a beast.
It's an amazing talent and skill to work
on and not.
I don't think that many fighters.
Um,
well,
I know not that many fighters are
working on it and Marsha,
they should go explore what's.
So how much did you love Chicago?
Sweet.
Do you have a great fucking time but
still fucking spending.
Goddamn,
we had fun,
right?
The fucking stage,
man.
It was overwhelming.
That was one of the best shows we've
ever done,
I think is the best show we ever did.
When I walked on stage.
I had a study for step for a second,
like the weed and the fucking stage hit
me all at one shot.
I couldn't digest my brain.
It was like I had a concussion for the
first three minutes.
It was very surreal.
And then once I got my time and go and
it was all over,
but it was very surreal at first I could
absorb it.
I'm used to doing the feeder with a
bottom of the top,
not a bottom or top of the other top on
top of that.
Another top on top of that filled to the
brim of the people fucking yelling.
They know who the fuck you are.
The energy level.
Esther's parents.
Just everything about the show is nuts.
The line after we heard little esther's
parents wouldn't let her,
didn't want her to take her to the UFC
or didn't want to take her.
They just didn't want to drive.
She lives about 40 minutes outside of
where the UFC.
They didn't want to drive and go to the
traffic and the traffic was nuts.
Yeah,
they were Nice,
nice people.
Nice to us.
I don't know what they did to her to
make her a little less gray.
Lebeaux drive with Damien fucking great
guy.
Dan Dan is awesome.
She was um,
she,
she fucking killed dude killed and she
went on after Joey.
Joey lit the place on fire and then
little lester goes up and I mean,
she had a fucking killer set dude.
She's got some great jokes.
She's,
I,
I really.
I'm going to send this to her parents
and I'm not bullshitting.
I go.
She's way funnier than I was at her age.
She's way better than
I was at her age.
She's,
she's going to be a killer man.
You know,
she's right now.
What is she?
Twenty three or something like that?
Hold the sheet.
Yeah,
23,
23.
I was blown away.
The night was great.
The fans are great.
The people I talked to was great,
but my night was made with little,
uh,
parents where they don't have parents
come on.
Great.
Is that for your parents to come see you
in the theater?
They know.
Not just your parents.
See you.
Anybody could see you when you were on
hbo and you got your hour.
I'm talking about the night that it hits
you.
It hits their parents.
Finally,
what their daughter was really doing.
You know,
you come home as a kid,
you're like,
Dad,
I want to fucking jump off planes.
What?
You're going to come work in the factory
with me.
That's it.
What?
Nobody in his family ever jumped on the
fucking planes.
Fuck you.
You're going to die.
And for two years,
that's all you get is torture.
And then finally something you know and
every family has,
I'm not going to come see you.
You know,
your father is not going to come see
you.
He doesn't approve of you boxing and all
of a sudden one night you followed us.
Come and you know what?
She just wasn't with Jenny on a bunch of
girls.
She was with killers.
She was with Marines from the comedy
store bootcamp training.
They went to Canada Pendleton.
I followed Paul Moody.
She was dead.
So I seen her growth right there.
When she got off stage,
her little face.
I had tears in my eyes.
Doug.
I was,
I was so excited for her because you
can't describe that,
uh,
parents with that pro.
Yeah,
she was a,
it was incredible.
It's the best show.
It was the best show we ever did for
sure.
The biggest show we ever did to now I've
never sold out that many people.
We sold out that whole place.
It was like 3,300
seats or something.
It was nuts.
That's nice man.
300 is giant.
Giant records of it.
I've got videos of record,
right?
You saw another guy that had a desk
squad tattoo.
Yeah.
Another guy on a desk.
Squad Tattoo Joey Diaz shirts.
I was just fucking overwhelming.
I'm going to email you this.
You could put this on the thing.
It was very.
It was very just,
it's just to fucking.
I had a hot beef and Italian sausage
Combo Sandwich that I almost stayed
there.
Almost fucking moved their red band with
hot and sour peppers and sweet peppers
is the beef.
I mean this shit was fucking delicious.
The restaurant went to the first night
was delicious.
The fucking Fogo.
The second night when went to that
state,
it was just fucking done.
My asshole life Sunday smelled like I
had firecrackers and they're like,
I have gunpowder in.
My Shit was heavy duty meat.
They put heavy duty gunpowder in the
meat and Chicago.
That cattle is the real fucking deal.
They got Deca in it because my asshole,
I had a light candles and the fucking
hotel.
It was hard.
I walked,
you know,
Joey and I were uh,
we were staying in a corner of the hotel
and so we had our own.
We had a door that would go into this
area and then he had a door and I had a
door,
so we had like two doors.
It was like our door that to get into
our little area and then we each had
individual door.
I would open up my door in Chicago,
by the way is fucking 30 degrees
outside.
He's got his windows open and you hear
the wind whistling in like a haunted
house.
I would open up the door and literally
say,
it wouldn't sound like,
you know,
like there was a hurricane going on in
the next week.
You know,
was still sweating at night.
You got to go to a doctor,
so I was still sweating to listen to
dog.
I walked into the doctor's office
yesterday for my preop.
I walked in there a quarter to nine.
I hadn't smoked reefer,
didn't smoke reefer.
The night before I had 10 hours of
sleep,
drink water.
I was relaxing on my blood pressure was
at a 45 in the morning.
One 85 over 100.
No,
that's horrible.
That's fucking murder.
Then after they took the blood out,
it went down to like 1:40
over 90 and that's okay,
but it's still not acceptable.
You know what I'm saying?
My engine runs hot all the time.
I take the medication,
I take the.
Well,
you lost a Shitload of weight at one
point in time.
Don't matter.
How much did you put back on?
That's it.
I'm 95.
I was shocked yesterday.
I was even shocked yesterday,
but some of the weight I put back,
I lifted.
I fucked.
Some of my legs are strong again.
I mean I'm trying to fucking really do
this.
I wouldn't want to get in shape.
You can be an in shape.
Fat Dude.
You know what I'm saying?
Like it can't be opened your titties and
shit like that.
I really fucking try at this.
You know what I'm saying?
I take my pills,
I drink a lot of water,
but if I'm eat,
if I'm in Chicago,
Joe Rogan,
you're not going to go to weight
watchers to suck my fucking salad.
We always eat salad,
mixed Greens for breakfast.
I eat fucking oatmeal.
I'm real careful about.
Not eating too much,
but we had like two hours,
two hours because my blood pressure a
little bit better shape.
I got to figure something out for blood
pressure.
Straight vegetable diet.
That's the best way to trim your body
down.
Fifteen hundred pounds.
Plus I probably gained 20 pounds.
When you're that big,
how do you know?
Because you go to a regular scale.
I always kept thinking.
Got The fucking meat scale.
They got to where they give you the
Jihad attack where they shoot the speed
and you get on the fucking bicycle and
start running the ship.
And that day was for fucking 15.
Oh my God.
So that's the biggest he ever.
That was November of 2009 or something.
And I said,
no.
He goes,
come back in January and we will put you
on a,
on a diet that fucking,
you know,
the lap band,
whatever.
Oh.
And I was,
you know,
I'm scared of needles.
That's a couple of times you got to go
see that motherfucker.
Not just a scared and Nino thing when
people break those things many times is
Ralph.
He had that operation.
He had the other.
Yeah,
the other one.
The bypass.
He broke it though,
right?
He busted the needle.
Snap the fuck.
Well,
he made us.
He made them a smaller stomach and then
he broke through it somehow or another.
Some overstuffed themselves.
I don't know.
Why didn't you have him on your podcast?
He was talking about how he almost died.
He was very good man.
Yeah.
What did he say?
It was just one of those fucking things.
He was light.
He was burnt down.
Do you look at a guy like Dan?
As long as this bitches alive.
Catcher,
canary bird,
pull mine.
You know what,
man?
I know how hard it was for him to
travel.
I know what it was like to get on a
plane when you're 415 pounds and the
seatbelt don't even fit in fucking
firstclass.
Okay.
I know what it's like.
How to walk out,
how your joints hurt.
That's why I love these personal
trainers that you know.
I,
I go to north Hollywood parking lot guy,
400 pounds walking around the park.
It's not going to work.
My friend,
it's going to last three weeks is a tap
out.
The joint pain is unbearable.
Put them in a fucking pool and make them
eat vegetables and shit like that.
You know,
and I know what it's like to sleep.
What it is a joint pain.
That's the real issue.
It's amazing.
And every time you fucking fly,
your ankles swell up and he's flying to
eight times a fucking week.
You know Ralph constantly on the road
every week.
He's on the road already.
How bad is it?
So he's in Tempe for superbowl weekend.
Eight fucking shows the whole fucking.
So he stopped.
He stopped smoking weed.
Is he eating it?
Nothing.
No.
Wait.
You can't do nothing.
Oh,
that's so sad.
Why did he stop?
Because because of what?
He had blood clots in his lung or
something like that.
How would we.
The hurt that it affected his lungs.
We did all the smoking it to smoking it
in the fucking flying and the fucking,
you know,
not breathing and it adds up after the
whole thing.
He would make all that traveling fun,
you know,
they do.
They do all these tests on marijuana and
they do tests on the guy like Eddie
Bravo,
who's a normal weight yourself.
When you add 400 pounds,
it's got to do something to your fucking
lungs when your lungs are this big and
you're trying to.
What's going on Brian?
Oh,
that's what's going on.
Fucking essentially found treasure
affects you at every level.
Man.
The reef is just something that they
told him to stop smoking as a
precautionary measure,
but I think the smoking anything is
probably not so fucking good.
Nobody,
you know,
there's no evidence that it causes
cancer.
It's very different from tobacco smoke.
We have smoke all putting in the same
category,
but it's not.
It's not.
But there's other options.
It's got to do something to you that
I've been smoking for 30 years.
I've coughed.
I've split fucking colors.
Fucking smurfs.
The whole thing.
Something's gotta be going on with your
life.
You know,
these people sit there so well.
Harvard did the research and that's
great.
It's got to do something to you.
So you got nothing is fucking free,
you got to pay somewhere along the
fucking line.
So knock it the fuck off.
Reading high time.
Some scientists would a be with sandals
on.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm telling you that somewhere along the
line smoker,
for 30 years I've been smoking weed for
fucking dirty is.
And I'll tell you what,
I know for a fact.
I got that seat.
The whole PD.
I know for a fact that OCD,
no POCD pocd shit with your lungs when
you hear the little bells and whistles
and your lungs.
So you know when you right now you're
ever going to be breathing on the have
you ever still below me breathing on the
microphone.
You're fucking stupid.
You ever do a thing on the microphone?
You go join me here.
You're breathing.
You hear you breathing.
Do you hear any breathing?
That cop did something.
So what I usually do is look at the fuck
up.
Don't look at that look acronym.
What?
Remember,
I used to take the steroids that used to
breathe in and it gives you a fucking
know that the one doctor said as my
asthma.
Yeah,
so what I used to do is whenever I hear
the bells and whistles,
you just go run around three labs.
Both claims are that really have been
doing that for years.
Whenever I hear a bell and whistle that
museum walking enough cock suck and get
on the blow the whistle.
Did you get that thing that Brian's got
you.
That's great.
That's great and shit,
but you just got to get out and walk.
Forget computers.
Right?
But the beautiful thing about that,
it tells you what you're telling
yourself.
It tells you how much you're doing
and if you think you need it and you're.
You don't have any money,
just write on a piece of paper.
You're lazy.
Fucking put in your pocket.
And that's what I've realized that,
that,
that what I do,
look at it and I'm like,
Oh shit,
I'm lazy.
I know this already.
I could.
I could have saved myself $100.
And so you're not.
You're not changing your habits.
And I can see myself trying to beat my
score before I can kind of see that,
but unfortunately I just had this
lifestyle that I'm so fucking busy that
the only way that I can change that,
it's just to make sure I work out every
day where this is more like for people
that I guess,
uh,
like have time,
more time to try to jog more is totally
doing a totally different approach to
what we're doing.
Brian is working out solely so that he
can get more pussy.
That's fine.
That's his issue.
That's why 60 percent of people take
fucking steroids.
Had an athletic.
I'm telling you,
you go to a bar,
there's 18 guys looking around.
You think they'd gone from Ms Dot
Olympia and you're like,
where do you live in Glendale?
So what's all these weights for?
For what?
To Do,
what?
To be a bartender for like a buck,
a local club.
Not to pick up pussy.
That's a lot to steroids.
Not really.
No.
You just looked like a fucking tree
trunk,
but you don't do steroids.
Okay.
You like the barbarian brothers?
Eight 36 seconds for the last three
years.
Every fucking day.
Well,
Brian is just doing it to keep up.
It's got a freak on the line.
That's what he's gonna do I need a
couple more people don't get fucking
serious until they got shredded until
they get rushed to the hospital.
This obesity epidemic in this country
isn't til you get rushed to the hospital
with two coming out of your ass and
you'll be at the gym doing jumping jacks
borough or you're gonna fucking die.
When did it,
when did it affect you?
When did you really start thinking,
I've got to do something when my fucking
spine was hurting,
when I do blow,
blow,
blow back of my neck was fucking gone.
When I would do blow,
when I would have to wear underwear to
go to the gym because I was pissed my
pants because I couldn't catch my breath
when I was throwing punches with Jesus
Christ when I fucking realized it and I
knew that I wasn't going to get the
operation that wasn't not gonna fucking
work at all.
So I knew that I had just eat right.
And you just can't deal with the idea,
but it will.
You were also talking about it like it
was like a weak thing to do.
Working out the I should know.
Yeah.
People think in this country.
Everything Bro.
Look at that fucking kids we've got now
a kid has a fucking bad day.
They put them on a fucking pill and then
when they get older,
the computer crashes.
Now I got to put them in London.
They have a nervous breakdown.
You're going a little league and fucking
Sherman Oaks.
You know you can't yell at the kids to
Stryker.
You suck or swing.
These kids are fucking pimp.
But that's why half of them on fucking
pills guy.
So what you're trying to tell me is I
can go to burger king every night and
he'd like a fat slob.
I'm 35 and call Mr.
Lap band and get my shit together.
And that's what you're telling this
country.
So half of these motherfuckers gone for
the right thing.
You got to,
when you're 400 pounds,
you're not sick.
It's your character.
Something's not right.
So if you get up and walk to the corner
every fucking day,
eventually going to get bored walking to
the corner.
So you're gonna walk another corner,
then you're going to walk another
quarter national.
Don't even walk to the YMC like I did
and you got to get on the bicycle for
five minutes and there's 10 minutes and
it all helps out.
See in my world,
when you're a comic,
you think that you only come home
Mondays and Tuesdays.
So if I work on Mondays and Tuesdays and
what's that gonna do for me?
Nothing.
Not True.
Even two days a week [inaudible].
I didn't know that.
That's the mentality I took him like,
you know what?
I'm fucking snow blow.
And the sick thing was that always kind
of worked out at the.
I always lift the weights.
I always did fucking something.
You know what I'm saying?
I wasn't like,
so that's why when I got sick and
bothering me,
but I felt like I was too much behind
the eight ball get you're about to get
knee surgery.
Fuck yeah.
And I'm ready.
I just,
like I explained to you yesterday,
you fainted on the way up from the
fucking.
You don't even feel limitation.
I mean it's 2012.
These new vampires.
You don't even feel the fucking needles.
They could fuck you in the ass 80 times
and you won't even know it no more.
Listen,
I put San Tan on my ipod and I looked
the other way and two minutes later the
bitch bent my fucking arm up.
I didn't feel the fucking needle.
I didn't feel the fucking need ipad.
You put an ipod all the time.
When I go to the dentist,
I put something on why sit there and
look at Bela Lugosi when I could fucking
every fucking dentist look like Bela
Lugosi to me when they're looking at
your fucking mouth.
You know what I'm saying?
You don't feel rude,
but just tuning out,
know that most dentists have tvs.
My fucking wife goes to a place that has
fucking big screen tvs with headphones
and one dentist because he would ask me
stupid.
You know,
he was just uncomfortable.
I'd have like really bad conversation,
like clunky conversations with them.
I was like,
when you get your fingers in my mouth,
what is the talk about listening?
Let's understand each other.
I'm going to lay back and open my mouth.
Tap me when a tap me when I'm fucking
done enough.
Tap you if it hurts because that's what
they say.
Tap.
When you feel the drill or something,
you put the fucking ipod on.
You.
Close your eyes.
You're not in there.
Eddie Bravo.
What's happening?
Cock suck.
You're a month away from having a kid.
You're sitting there like fucking Buddha
with no fucking food.
Talk to me.
I love ready for this man.
Are you ready?
You got to be fucking ready.
Don't this shit?
Hell yeah.
You got to be ready.
Have you picked a name yet?
A TV show on discovery.
I want you to tell me you went to your
uncle's house and change some diapers
for awhile and we tried that.
Well,
this was planned.
This was not an accident.
I want her to kid.
I'm proud of you.
I'm happy if it's going to be a
fascinating experience,
man.
A different fucking man for sure changed
me as a human being.
First of all was the refund.
When you came to me,
you said you had the best ice cream
Sundae in your life.
The way you gave it.
To me,
that was beautiful.
And then next thing you know,
Mrs Rogan came on the scene.
I seen the whole thing.
I will never forget that day Eddie Bravo
got me high.
We we went and had an ice cream Sundae
and I had the most massive revelation in
my life.
I couldn't believe how God damn good.
That ice cream Sundae taste was the
first time he ever straightened up.
Before then,
you were fucking ape was still bent
over.
If I drew you a banana,
you need to fucking pill.
Seriously.
When you were back,
you were back.
Your chest was up.
Well,
you guys know me.
I don't know me as well as you guys
know.
Please.
That was it.
You will walk different person.
I'm a lot more relaxed and everything,
but it must've been interesting.
Much more for you to watch someone
change their personality.
So fucking beautiful thing,
man.
I love to see evolution.
I,
but people watch it.
I love to watch people.
Shut your fucking mouth.
Let him walk into that whole,
you know,
don't say no,
but I think coming from,
you know,
my background,
like doing martial arts competitions my
whole life and then just transition
right into comedy.
I had never relaxed.
I never settled down.
I never,
I never learned how to just be calm,
you know?
It was my,
my whole body and my brain,
my personality all developed under
duress.
It all developed under physical combat
all the time on a regular basis.
Constant training,
constant fight,
constant tournament's.
That was,
that was my life from the time I was 15
until I was 22.
All my formative years was all spent in
stress and I remember when I first
decided that I wasn't going to fight
anymore.
I was like the first time ever in my
life when I was like 22,
my,
my last kickboxing fights.
I've the first time ever where I could
relax.
I would always be nervous.
Like,
when is the next?
When's the next fight?
When's the next thing I've got to get in
shape.
I can't be drinking this.
I can't be doing this.
Couldn't live my life because I was
always worrying about getting my ass
kicked.
I was always worrying about like,
I have to make sure that I do everything
right or to be prepared.
I don't want to get fucked up,
you know?
So it's like,
it's,
it wasn't the best mindset to go into
stand up comedy for,
that's for sure.
It's like a constant battle because
stand up comedy,
you've got to totally the opposite.
You've got to not give a fuck.
You know,
you gotta you gotta be relaxed.
You gotTa have fun instead of be tents
and ready to go at any moment's notice.
You know,
you sent me a.
by the way,
whatever you sent me,
it doesn't work.
One of them doesn't work.
The other two do.
Check your email.
You sent me two things and both of them
are like movies that are one second
long.
What?
Here
again dude,
I know it's.
I know it's good.
My full reascended okay.
Fucking 15 to 22.
My mind wasn't fighting them.
I wasn't a fighter,
but I was in a different type of hell.
I was in my own head.
I was putting myself into,
you know,
it was so weird when I became a comic,
what,
six,
seven,
eight years later or something like that
and how I took that wildness into the
fucking comment and nobody understood
what I was saying until I met you guys
store.
I filed the fucking home.
I was always.
I used to travel on the road with trible
and do all these little roads.
I remember when I first met you,
the store,
everybody was fucking terrified to you.
Yeah,
it was crazy.
Nobody knew you and I,
I remember being like the only guy,
like when I first met you,
that was like,
he's great.
What are you talking about?
I love that guy.
I never was like,
Oh,
here comes Julie Diaz.
Like,
where's he at?
I like with gravitate towards you
because you didn't scare me.
You were nice to me.
You weren't a scary guy to me.
You were a regular dude.
I see.
You were like one of the only guys there
that I could relate to.
There was like a lot of guys that I
couldn't relate to.
I knew dudes like you,
you know,
I mean,
not you,
but you and my friend Johnny B,
the Pool Hustler,
very similar characters,
man.
Very,
very similar characters.
You have both way out there.
You both like not give a fuck guys,
and you're both guys that were like
polarizing.
Some people would love you to death and
then everybody,
you know,
there was a lot,
a large group of people,
but for whatever reason,
they'd be upset at you.
Like I remember having to defend you.
Even I rare even dom irrera was hating
on you for every body,
every and I loved it.
I fucking love that because that's what
I,
you know,
it's so weird that this whole surgery
thing really taught me about fear.
My fear has fucking done wonders for me
because that's why when I wake up in the
Molesta,
first thing I fucking do is grab my
fucking cock because for years I was
scared.
I've always insecure that immigrant
fucking thing shizzle into my fucking
mind.
Since the streets in New York City with
the immigrant thing,
not knowing the language,
not feeling good enough like everybody
else,
not beat a fucking American and it sits
inside my fucking soul.
So for me everything has been riveted on
fear.
Every time I get on stage,
it's like the other night fear was real
in Chicago.
I got on stage in between the reefer and
whatever was going on and the lights.
I got fearful man,
but you know what?
That's normal to be scared.
That's a great emotion,
especially when you're a stand up comic
because the more scared you are,
the better you're going to fucking do.
Especially in my case,
the more riled up I am.
Two minutes before I go on stage,
the more energy I'm gonna give that
fucking audience.
But I've looked at my life and I've seen
how much fear I was petrified to go get
that fucking needle even though I
fucking knew nothing was going to happen
and I was going to walk out of there,
but I went in.
I took the needle after I walked out at
me like,
what a fucking killed 10 fucking people
with my bare hands because you overcome
one of your biggest fucking fears.
Till this day I get little emails and
people,
you know,
I,
I suffer,
I suffer from a social disorder and I
don't know what to do with the answer
and taking a fucking pill.
It's checking your fucking confidence
and grabbing your balls and walking into
a circle and saying,
fuck it.
I'm here.
You know,
my mentality was always go into the
mouth of the lion and put a chair down
and sit the fuck down and let the pieces
fall where they may.
And if you're not going to live like
that,
fuck them more.
I'm at the store too.
Fucking nights,
Joe Rogan.
The first fucking night Eddie Griffin
bumps me.
You know how embarrassing that is?
You become a regular on a Sunday.
The first fucking night you let bring 11
people that come see you.
Your landlord comes and you get bumped
by Eddie Griffin and the second night I
go up there and Steve Greenstein says to
me,
Hey,
last weekend you fucking audition here
for missing.
You said one of my jokes.
I said,
it's February 11th.
I just come off a plane January 29th and
you're already accusing me of being a
fucking thief.
And remember he had his violin case.
Who?
Steve Greenstein,
I don't remember.
What was it?
Creepy guy.
Older guy that hung out at the comedy
store and he had a violin case.
So this is a Tuesday night.
It's black night at the comedy store.
It's 8:00.
The main room is packed with the
original room would be empty because
people were scared to go up there and
black knight because we're going to get
fucking mug.
So the original room was always empty.
So Steve Greensteam was up before me.
He,
this is my second night,
the comedy store.
I just got away.
I'm a fucking criminal.
I've been in prison.
I got all these problems,
but I,
for the first time in my life I got a
little fucking daylight.
The comedy store,
this lady made me a regular all my life.
People were like [inaudible] in you as
Mitzi shore scene you.
She going to make you a fucking regular.
I get down there.
I'm a regular is the first time since my
mother died.
I had any luck.
I had been in prison.
I had been divorced,
you know,
shot the whole fucking deal and the next
thing you know,
I become a regular.
It's Tuesday night and I get off stage
and I'm waiting to hang out for a little
while and Steve Greenstein comes up to
me and he says to me,
dog,
one of your jokes is like my joke.
I said,
which one?
He said something about Oj Simpson's
made.
I go,
Doug,
I didn't steal the joke for me.
I just fucking got here two weeks ago.
Wheels comes out.
He goes,
this guy didn't steal the joke from you.
The only problem was the guy put the
violin case behind this fucking legs and
I spotted it.
So he starts threatening me.
He's like,
don't even next time you do that job,
we're going to have a problem.
I just pushed him.
Joe Rogan.
He fell over the violin case.
Why has these fallen down?
Mitsis Limo pulls up.
That's it.
I'm like,
I'm done.
This is my life.
I'm fucking Gone Outta here.
I'm never going to get another fucking
spot again.
I'm going to go back to selling.
Fucking blow and wheels got between us.
Scott Day got between us and Mitzi came
and go,
oh,
what happened here?
And he started saying,
he goes,
no,
this kid's Cuban,
blah blah,
blah am.
But Mitzi seen the kid on the floor and
fell in love with me after that because
I pushed that motherfucker.
She liked something from myself.
Sure.
You got lucky.
She was crazy.
She liked that happened at the FEC and
Improv.
I would've been out on the fucking
street.
How often did you perform at the Improv?
Now in those days?
In those days.
Every week because the Guy Richard
Cooper loved me,
the talent coordinator,
but I got to La January 29th.
That was a regular at the store.
February 19th on my birthday.
I didn't fuck around this town when I
got it,
but you couldn't do the Improv and Mitzi
found out,
but I went to Scott.
Dan said,
dog.
Richard Cooper gives me spots.
So I would go over there and I had a
couple of problems over there.
Right off the bat.
People thought they were cute over
there.
You know,
you leave your fucking girlfriend and a
seat.
You go to bat and you come back and
talking to them like they know that is
an,
it's a fucking issue.
And you gotta you gotTa stop.
I'm like,
I told you like Hitler in Munich or not,
you're going to have a fucking problem
dog.
So I would say things to people and uh,
all of a sudden you're a bad fucking
person.
So what the fuck?
I don't give a fuck.
And we're here 12 years later and we're
still rocking and rolling.
They could still suck my dick and call
me shortly.
We're doing a show.
If you're in town,
Pasadena,
this Thursday night,
I'm don't come if you're a stalker.
Thanks Pasadena Ice House.
Thursday night.
What Time Brian?
A dirty Joey Diaz.
Joe Rogan,
little esther,
a bunch of other people,
and we also have a show Friday.
Good ice house comedy.com
for the tickets.
Oh,
snap freaks and Vegas Friday night.
Eddie Bravo is coming.
He's going to play the drums and shit.
You come in.
We're looking into.
That might go in Saturday morning.
Not sure,
not sure.
No,
I'm fucking.
I'm just central drive and next time I
go to La.
I'm not driving this time.
Next time I go to la though,
I'm driving vegas.
Vegas Memorial Day weekend to see,
uh,
to see junior dos Santos against my man.
If he recovers the surgery.
I'm tired of fucking flying man.
I would rather just take the big flood
Cadillac escalades.
Let's go out.
I got a new one.
I got one of these are going to be
things with the music and the whole
fucking thing.
Hey Brian,
come here.
Help me.
You can export these things.
It's not exporting,
right?
But then they'll pull us over like snoop
Dogg,
those cocks up because every time they
see snoop Dogg,
if they smell you anywhere near them,
we're going to jail.
It's right here.
What a shotgun.
The fucking house.
I retrieved the video.
Denny Pluto posters here,
fresh off his fucking 19 Wednesday,
Sunday grants.
Enough flights.
It was a epic day for 10.
What was the gracie nationals at the
gracie nationals.
Was was an la this past Sunday.
And Rose Gracie,
the granddaughter of Heleo Gracie,
the grandmaster Gracie Jujitsu.
She decided to go old school with the
gracie nationals.
She's been running it for the last few
years and she,
you know,
the whole point system that Jujitsu
tournaments,
um,
uh,
run by or just ridiculous.
I mean it's just people are fighting for
points and stalling and it's,
it's ridiculous.
And Roads Gracie decided to,
you know,
make her or the great or late great
helio gracie proud and make an all just
a submission only tournament.
And these,
these tournaments are becoming this
format.
It's becoming more and more popular.
They do it in the Pacific north
northwest at,
at,
at that sub league in Oregon and they
run smoothly.
People have been afraid of sub only
tournaments because of time constraints
and all that stuff.
But rose gracie made it work.
She had the balls to go,
no points,
no advantages,
15 minutes a submission only if,
if,
if you go 15 minutes without a
submission,
both competitors are out of the
tournament.
So that's the ballsy as format there is
out there.
And,
and now the gracie nationals is the most
prestigious submission only tournament
on the planet.
And I think that's the future for
Jujitsu cause you know,
it was a lot more fun preparing for a
submission only tournament.
All we worked on was the fun stuff.
The good stuff about Jujitsu that the
finish,
the closing the deal that we're working
on,
our squeeze for the Nogi Worlds.
Um,
we had to spend time working on stalling
techniques because when you're playing a
point game and it's like six minute
matches,
a guy will get a point or just a little
advantage,
which is even less than a point.
And once they're up an advantage,
the hold and they won't do anything and
people aren't used to wrestling with
guys that are just holding,
holding onto leads in class.
You don't just hold onto a lead,
there's no one's counting points in
class.
So you actually have to prepare for that
yet specifically prepare for tournaments
that are run by points and um,
it's just so not fun.
Preparing like stalling techniques and
stalling live drills and prepare.
What are the do just hold on.
It doesn't do anything.
It's ridiculous.
So rose gracie decided to eliminate all
of that and make the gracie nationals a
submission only tournament.
And um,
she's also doing the Gracie worlds in
July,
July 15th in San Jose.
You know,
finally,
you know,
you're going to be able to get a world
title in a submission only format,
which is the greatest.
I mean,
it's so much.
It means so much more to win in a
submission only tournament.
Then by points you're a world champion
and you won by an advantage world
champion at those days.
It does nothing for the development of
your Jujitsu.
It just gets you better at holding and
installing out and running out the
clock.
It's just ridiculous.
So mad.
Huge props to Rose Gray and her husband,
Hobie Vasquez,
who put this tournament together and you
know,
I think this is the future.
I think a submission only format is the
only way to go.
You know,
we're taking bias refs completely out of
the gate.
The refs have nothing to do with the
game.
No,
well there's no time limited in the
final,
but in the qualifying matches is a 15
minute time limit,
which is plenty enough to have plenty of
time.
And if there is no submission in those
15 minutes,
both guys are out.
So it's,
it's amazing.
We had sold are out.
So if two guys are just like Marcello
Garcia and jake shields stall each other
out,
they're both out.
Whoa,
that's crazy.
But in the finals,
no time that we had some epic matches.
Epic matches,
um,
10 planet San Francisco went 12 and one
I wish I had about,
you know,
maybe how many affiliates you got now I
got to over 30.
I lose track.
Isn't that crazy?
You started out just doing it as
something to do,
you know,
like,
man,
what should I do?
Maybe I could teach now and then boom.
Now you got like an empire,
man.
It was all an accident.
It's weird in a weird.
I thought I thought that that when we
were working on the man show,
we were going to parlay that into some
trey parker.
Matt Stone.
Shit,
you know,
it was all a dream.
I used to read word up magazine,
Salt,
pepper,
heavy d up in the limousine.
The next thing we're gonna do is we're
going to get a fucking comedy club.
I decided while I was taking a shit
today,
high as fuck on the toilet bowl.
That's the next move.
The next move is a reality show about,
about this fucking place,
about doing,
doing a podcast and doing a comedy club
and have an all connected the way we do
it,
man,
when we have this show,
so Thursday night
we have podcasts going on at the same
time as the comedy show and everybody
just rotates in.
It's the greatest fucking thing we've
ever done.
The greatest thing we've ever done.
The perfect thing.
You go on stage,
man,
you're.
You're already flowing.
Like when you had to go on stage right
now.
Yeah.
You'll be able to show the Lucy snore
brush story.
What is it?
What's the name?
Lucy Snowe Bush.
If you have,
you told that Lucy snore Bush story and
then when of the stage right now you
would be in private.
That's the most ridiculous thing I've
ever told.
Greatest story of all time.
People want Root Lucy Snore,
Bush tee shirts all by broken aluise
store machines room and eight or asked
the middle of the night.
They want that tee shirt.
Oh my fucking God.
I on here.
And then we got Vegas Friday.
Fucking night.
Yeah,
we will.
We were in Chicago.
Like I said,
this was the biggest show we'd ever done
and it was pretty crazy.
I made a video how fucking crazy it was.
Really how big this place is.
I don't know if you can tell.
Look at the size of this place.
Wow.
How long did you do?
An hour and 22 minutes.
We stayed outside and signed pictures
for fucking hours,
man.
I had to pay those security.
I had to pay like 2000 extra dollars in
security because they had to keep them
around because it's like union is like,
you know,
laws,
you have to have rules,
you have to pay.
People look at the play,
the second one,
the second video is ridiculous.
We were,
is when we were signing,
and this is a,
all this the line of people that were
waiting to,
uh,
to,
to take pictures with,
with Joanne and Dunkin and,
and,
and sign posters.
Mike Maxwell made a poster just for the
event and a check this shit out.
This is,
hold on one.
Say,
okay.
This is bonkers,
man.
This is when we were in the upstairs
balcony area.
This place is fucking huge.
That Chicago theater at one point in
time,
it was a silent movie house.
It was built in 1921.
Sinatra performed.
They had several little estis father
took the mother to the see Sinatra
ladies seven.
Holy Shit.
When he was forgetting his lyrics and
the wig was crooked shit.
Motherfucking Sinatra Jack.
It was still banging bitches too with a
Sinatra died before Viagra kicked in the
boat.
He's in the midst of those grumpy old
men.
They couldn't get any pussy anymore.
There was no reason to perform.
You know,
there was,
it was all over.
Even though it was Sinatra.
You only got a hard on like once a month
at the end he was still getting pussy
with the wig,
like a pimp dog.
Brian.
It's obviously something,
Brian with an iphone.
The way the iphone interpreted it.
Can't you rotate that?
No,
not on the flight,
but look how easy that is.
You know why it does that right yet?
Because it's a piece of shit.
No,
no,
no.
Before you hit record,
look at the icon.
If it's tilted sideways,
it's going to record it sideways.
Look how nutty that is.
That
is,
man.
That's just all the people waiting to
get into or to get into line to take
pictures and shit.
That was a fun,
fun time.
Thank you.
It was dirty.
Freaked that pulled her tits out and I
had everybody sign her tests.
She had great tits.
Don't don't put it down.
Nice.
Twenty four year old for a little
fucking cheese and she was afraid.
She got a little boy for that.
Looked like fucking.
What's the guy?
You little bars.
I just was ready to go.
Yeah,
it didn't.
Somebody throw the guy under the bus who
wasn't a Jane and James used to date.
Is that.
Is that Bruno Mars?
And it stinks.
That song.
Yeah.
Well,
Bruno Mars and the other guy,
right?
Yeah.
There's two guys who sings.
Who's the other one?
I can't remember.
There's a the rapper guy and then the
singer guy.
Which one is which?
Great fucking tune.
Whoever the hell it is.
Did you hear about those English people
that got arrested at the airport and.
No,
you didn't hear about this shit,
dude.
It's one of the weakest things I've ever
heard ever about.
The TSA is sad with this country has
become these English people.
They were coming over here for a
vacation,
so they joked around and they said,
hey,
we're going to go over to America and
we're going to fucking destroy America.
We're going to dig up Marilyn Monroe's
body.
I mean,
it sounds like some shit that Joey Diaz
would say if he was British.
Right.
We're going to come over here.
We're gonna.
Have a fucking party.
This is what they wrote.
I'm going to destroy America and dig up
Marilyn Monroe.
That's what they said on his twitter.
They came over here to party.
That's all TSA.
Check them for shovels.
These dumb fucks you wouldn't remember.
We're going to do.
Oh,
did they tweet this or something?
So now they're looking at her twitter.
Yeah,
man,
they tweeted,
they're there 26 years old,
man.
They're they're kids.
They went to party,
man,
Department of Homeland Security Way to
go.
You fuckheads these silly fucks.
They're supposed to be protecting us.
They pulled aside this cute punk rock.
Look in British couple that look like
sweethearts.
You know?
I mean it's just let mean.
Look at this.
This is what.
This is what a dude wrote.
Free this week for a quick gossip prep
before I go and destroy America.
That's the question.
Like a joke.
He's going here to have a fucking party.
Like he's going to destroy America.
Jesus cry.
They checked the shovels.
They sent them back home.
Man.
Not only that,
they arrested them,
lock them up with Mexican drug dealers
that they also caught versus 12 fucking
hours because they're immigrants.
They throw them in with the other
immigrant criminals.
They throw them in with Mexican drug
dealers that they busted,
so these guys were locked up with real
hardcore criminals for 12 fucking hours
and then they flew him back to Europe.
Fuck them,
soul.
Unbelievable.
It's unbelievable.
I mean really,
you can't have one rational person who
looks at those two angles and it starts
laughing.
His.
It was his what he writes also three
weeks today.
We're totally in La,
pissing off people in Hollywood
boulevard and digging up Marilyn Monroe.
Haha.
He's joking around,
man.
You really,
this is our tax dollars going to work.
This is 2012.
You know w we're not talking about 1950
like we jumped into a time machine.
All of a sudden they have twitter in
1950.
What?
They're going to destroy America now.
I think it was just to set an example
like we're going to fuck anybody up the
plays around.
I don't.
I think it's a bully and an abuse of
power.
That's what it is.
I don't think in Sydney example at all.
I think they knew these were kids and
they could fuck with them if they want
it to.
I think they found someone to fuck with.
They found someone to fuck with and then
and then they did.
You know,
it's really,
really sad.
They came here and have fun.
You fuckheads Jesus Christ,
check them for fucking show.
They're,
they're,
they're checking twitter for joke joke,
things that you say job tweets about
coming to America and getting fucked up.
Like,
do you really think that that's what a
chair was?
Would white hm this week?
Free for a quick gossip before I go
destroy America.
Like,
yeah,
that's what you have to worry about.
That's where our tax dollars are going.
What do you think about anonymous?
Listen man,
somebody needs to stand up for this
fucking the wacky world that we're
living in man and would anonymous
represents is the internet.
Well,
the Internet represented most of the
time is justice.
You know,
most of what they go after,
most of what they do is the right thing.
There's a lot of shit that goes on like
this Dana white thing where they're
hacking into his,
his,
uh,
social security and putting it all
online.
That's Douchey Shit.
I heard it was fake.
I heard it wrong.
No,
it wasn't fake.
They got the information that you don't
understand.
First of all,
it is dad's named Dana white as well and
they got a lot of.
Lot of the information they got was his
dad's including liens and you know,
where his dad used to live and now some
other guy got harassed because they,
you know,
because his information got put online.
So this guy like Dina had to go to this
guy's house and apologize to him,
but the kid is apparently a 13 year old
kid from Australia mean he doesn't
represent anonymous.
He represents people on the Internet
that don't like when people in the
Internet challenged them.
You know,
like you say,
you can't hack me.
I dare you.
They're going to hack,
you know,
they're going to fucking hack you.
But that's not what.
What I like about anonymous,
what I like is that what it represents
is people feel helpless.
They feel helpless to this gigantic,
oppressive power that is controlling the
world and running things in a way that
they don't like.
And when these guys go after Department
of Homeland Security,
all these different websites,
when these guys try to take things down,
what they're doing is they're there,
they're lashing out,
and they're saying,
hey,
we can touch you,
we can reach you,
we can find your information.
Like when they went after that guy that
pepper sprayed,
all those fucking kids in the face,
those kids at uc Berkeley that were just
sitting on their knees and they got all
that guy's information.
They put that shit online that I liked,
that I liked because that lets that guy
know,
hey,
you can't do morally fucked up things
because you're doing it under the,
the,
the blanket of your job,
the umbrella of protection that you
think has offered you by being a police
officer.
You're doing something reprehensible,
man.
You're spraying kids in the face with,
with chemicals,
you piece of shit for no reason.
Yeah.
And you got to feel that man got,
feel that.
And you know what man?
I saw a video where the people were
trying to justify like,
listen,
this is what happened.
This is the full story.
What you saw was edited,
you know what they saw?
They saw the kids just sitting there for
a longer know.
Yeah.
They didn't move when they were told to
move.
That doesn't mean you get
the spray in the fucking face.
I heard there were some shit in La.
Was it oakland re the other day and the
cops were arrested like a crazy amount
of people,
like 120 or 30 people,
but they were tear gassing and there was
like kids.
They're like one.
I don't think it's probably the best
idea to be bringing your kids to things
like this.
Assholes who are bringing their kids to
these rallies because these things,
things can break out in violence at any
moment.
Especially in Oakland.
Oakland is kind of crazy man.
Too Short.
Yeah.
Short dog.
Oakland is not to be fucked with.
Right.
Oakland's a tricky place.
You be in just for the hub for that shit
for the last 40 years.
They have no.
They play it every year.
That's where they go up there.
These people know how to react to it.
The sick and tired of it too.
You know,
and it takes two to tango,
but I love the idea of somebody checking
somebody.
I've always loved the idea.
Listen man,
I grew up in fucking death.
Wish you know what?
The cops can't be there for you all the
fucking time.
I love the idea of somebody blast on the
motherfucker when you fucking do
something wrong.
That's the best way.
I love it.
I'd love to.
Net.
I think at the Internet is eventually
going to be the government.
That's what I think.
I think the way that we're going to
govern things just through the Internet
because instead of these oppressive
groups that see what what really fucks
us is that we don't really get a say in
everything.
Well,
we get to do is we get a representative.
We get to choose a representative and
they almost all get into office and
immediately just do whatever the fuck
incorporations that got them into power,
asked them to do.
That's what they do immediately.
They pass a bunch of bills like the
national defense authorization act that
everybody's going crazy about that.
Obama passed that.
He said he would veto all of that stuff
is stopped.
If you put that for vote to America,
like at on the online,
what do you want?
What do you guys want to do?
No fucking way.
We would vote for that.
Were you going to arrest us and detain
us with no warrant?
Because what people have to realize is
the people that you're saying yes to
today,
when you make a law and you say,
okay,
here's the law.
These people today may not be the same
people.
You're saying yes to 20 years from now
or even 10 years from now.
You can put laws into place that give
evil,
corrupt people.
I'm not saying Obama Zebulon corrupt,
but I'm saying what he did is an evil
and corrupt thing and he opened the door
for evil and corruption.
No doubt about it because if someone
wants to do that,
some future Douchebag,
some Dick Cheney of the future.
If he gets into a position and in the
national defense authorization act is in
place,
guess what?
A bunch of people going to go to fucking
jail that are just protesting.
The government have got a bunch of
people going to go to jail for
obstructing the.
The way the United States runs,
they're going to go to jail as enemies
of the state.
That's real shit,
you know,
and that none of that would take place
if the Internet was how we did our
government and it sounds ridiculous,
but why shouldn't it be that way?
What what our government is supposed to
represent is what the people want and
what the people want can easily be found
out on the Internet.
It's easiest,
the easiest way to contact people and
find out exactly what the fuck they want
regardless of nationality,
regardless of the state.
Where they live in is the internet.
That is how things are going to be
ruled.
It used to be you had to go to a place,
you had to write down what you thought
and put it in a fucking box and that's
how they decided things.
You only because that was the only way
to do it.
Any problem with that though is there's
more opportunity for hacking and things
like that.
Unfortunately.
Now,
right now there is.
Yeah.
But you know what,
that can be worked out too.
And you know what,
that's also in part,
a lot of that is in place because also
because of corruption.
Look at the fucking.
The computerized voting machines.
Yeah.
If you don't know about this,
watch a documentary called hacking
democracy.
It was something that was on Hbo Awhile
back where they showed that these
machines,
these diebold machines are designed to
be altered.
They're designed so that a third party
can come in and change the results and
they were so fucked up.
They changed their name.
Diebold isn't even diebold anymore.
I'll find out what the fuck her name,
ours now so he can't be tricked,
but we live in a corrupt system and the
what the Internet recognizes is that the
will of the people is not being
represented what's being represented as
the corporations and that's why
everybody's hovering around all these
fucking,
these,
these bill w,
w with this occupy thing is everyone's
hovering and collecting and gathering
together around all these sick areas.
Yes.
Yeah man.
We,
we had to short on a podcast last night
and it was really amazed at the rapper,
the rapper,
he has like 19 albums out,
but of the cool things
hearing him talk about was a big.
He started off so early in the game that
people didn't even know what rap was.
And like he would just like open up his
car doors to and they have like a beat
playing and just rap,
you know,
like really loud with it.
And like one guy came up to him,
he's like,
man,
I like it,
I want to have that.
And then he just popped the cassette and
sold it to him for five bucks and then
he started selling it to like,
all the drug dealers want heard about
it.
And they're like,
that lived in Oakland,
like all the king pin guys.
And so they all wanted their own
personalized wrap,
a cassette.
So then he was like making,
like having to write all these songs
like nonstop just to keep up with all
these drug.
How'd you the guy who knows him?
Uh,
we had Kevin Black on who's a sex tape
guy who I,
you know,
he's the one that gets all the sex tape,
like the Paris Hilton sex tapes and
stuff like that.
He's one of the only guys that has even
seen the tupacs a sex tape.
Uh,
and uh,
he's friends with them.
He's friends with them with your short
shorts.
So what's up with that?
Tupac sex to a white girls or African
Americans?
I don't know.
I didn't.
I said,
why can't you release it?
Two Bucks.
Family?
Yeah,
I think it was a family thing.
I think.
I think the people
powers of be diebold changed his name to
premier election solutions incorporated
or p e s I,
that's the new diebold.
Isn't it funny when companies do that,
they get caught doing something fucked
up.
So they just changed the name and they
just were evil,
but whatever.
You got to blackwater did the same
thing.
They changed.
The man was.
I'll find out.
How far do you,
I think anonymous can go.
Do you think that could ever get shut
down?
Can they know it's impossible?
The idea.
Because I think a lot of people get
confused what in anonymous is the whole
point why they can't get shut down
because no one knows who the fuck they
are.
There's tons of figure it out.
There's tons of people though,
will.
If they started arresting people,
it would be the most impossible thing
that'd be like trying to have an army
put together that attacks the whole
world.
It would be like world war for real
This is crazy.
Blackwater.
So fucked up.
They change their name twice.
They changed.
They went from blackwater to x e and
then they went from x e to academic with
a new logo.
They just changed their name.
They figured this.
No one's going to know.
Just keep changing it,
keep changing it.
Stopping anonymous would be like,
yeah,
they could spend all this money and time
and they'll find some 13 year old in
Australia and then there's like a
million.
Well,
the thing is that guy,
you know,
what,
what can they do to,
to,
um,
to prosecute people that the catch and
how far they can go as far as shutting
things down and controlling the
infrastructure.
That's what people worried about what
this Sofa with this sofa,
what they're worried about.
Again,
it's not the people you're saying yes to
today.
They might not be the same people you're
saying yesterday,
20 years from now and if you give the
government the ability to just shut down
websites,
which by the way they already do.
They just did with Mega upload.
Yeah.
No,
they just closed down mega upload.
I'm so,
I'm so bummed about mega upload,
closing to a good website.
Okay.
But let's play devil's advocate.
They close mega upload because they said
that Mega upload has a bunch of
different illegal files on it,
like where's,
and they have a of like movies and shit
that screeners and mp3s if there's a
website should.
And if you're offering that service to
people where they can just upload shit
and then you sell advertisement,
which they do,
right?
Isn't that how they work that shit?
And they sell subscriber.
I think if you have a free account,
there's limitations and they serve
advertising.
I think they also have a paid account
that I don't think has advertising,
but I think what it is is that it
shouldn't be the company's fault.
It should be the user.
So yes,
they find dances with wolves on Mega
Upload Server.
They find out who uploaded a day bust
him.
I don't think it should be mega uploads
fault for having a service where you can
legally you're supposed to share file,
but let's play devil's advocate.
Let's play devil's advocate.
If you do have a service where you're
just sharing files and providing
bandwidth,
you should be responsible for how much
of that stuff is pirated because
otherwise you're a distribution angle.
You're.
You're essentially a distribution
highway for illegal shit.
I think maybe yes you should be,
but I think it should be more of like,
I don't know,
sharing of a personal information.
If you are doing something illegal
should be allowed.
Maybe hearing a personal meaning like
if,
if the FBI comes to mega app logos,
look,
we know that you have dances with wolves
on your server and they're like,
okay,
we need to know who this user rising.
I think then mega upload should be like,
okay,
here's the person's there for really
using this should give you up.
If you're doing illegal stuff.
I don't think it should be mega uploads
fault.
I don't think mega upload as a
corporation should be shut down and for
a business because you want to share
dances with wolves.
Well you know
better the corporation be shut down in
the user's going to jail.
That's the other devil's advocate is
that these are just kids and they don't
know any better and they think they're
going to get away with it and they think
they're just helping people out by
providing files that everybody wants to
get ahold of.
You know,
look,
the pro,
the real problem is people have kind of
grown up knowing that they can get shit
for free now.
You know,
that's like sort of how they're.
That's how people feel.
They feel like shit is free,
you know,
hey,
I can get movies for free.
They joke around about it.
I've had people joke around on my own
website about stealing my shit online.
They think it's cute,
you know?
Yeah,
I'll get the torrent,
lol,
you know,
and you're like,
wow,
you know,
like right in front of you knowing that
you,
it's just,
it is what it is.
That's who you want to be.
That's,
that's all good.
But it's like they're so accustomed to
stealing that they talk about it openly
in front of the person's face,
on the website of the person who's
selling the shit.
Yeah.
But that's just ignorance and stupidity.
But yeah.
So they,
they feel obligated,
not obligated.
They feel like they're entitled,
you know what it should be.
It shouldn't be throwing people in
prison.
I don't think it should be like,
yeah,
you,
you were sharing dances with wolves with
seven other people and I don't think
that person should go to prison for 20
years.
I think you should have some kind of
thing like maybe.
Right.
You're not allowed to have the Internet
for a year.
You know,
Kevin Mitnick
punishment,
that's what they did to him,
but the real issue,
Brian,
is that,
that actually has crushed industries.
You look at the music industry,
the music industry is fucked.
You know what,
you know,
one of the things that Dana White didn't
wait actually wants to come on the
podcast and he wants to talk about.
So,
but um,
let's talk about all the shit that
happened,
you know,
I talked about interviewing on my own.
Let me interview for UFC.
It got DOTCOM.
He goes,
you know what?
It'd be better.
Let's do your podcast.
I said,
all right,
we'll do it.
So we're going to figure out when to do
it.
And so he's,
he's totally into free speech.
You just don't want him any ripping off
his fucking product.
And then,
you know,
the,
the amount of piracy is so widespread
that people were actually pirating
streams and then showing them in bars
and charging people to go to those bars
to watch pirated streams.
There's definitely cases like that day,
obviously that's,
that should be attacked.
Well,
there's also people that put streams up
and then they sell advertising.
They have Google ads and they actually,
you know,
it's not just like a free thing,
they're making money off of the stream.
Right.
You know,
that's,
that's a big,
there's a big difference between that.
That person is putting that up there and
making money for people.
Thousands of people that are coming to
the site and the person who's 14 years
old can't afford the UFC,
who's downloading it for free.
Yeah.
So that's what the real issue is.
What they're really.
What they're really concerned about is
the people that are actually profiting
off pirating their shit,
you know?
And so it's,
it's a tricky thing.
Like my take on it has always been that
the Internet without a doubt has
promoted me and helped me more than
anything.
So the more people that have stolen my
stuff means the more people who have
enjoyed my stuff,
which means the more people will come to
see me,
the more people will come.
Like this Chicago show or anything else,
you know,
I mean that's the purpose.
We could easily charge for this podcast.
I mean,
some of you probably willing to pay,
but we know a lot of people that make a
lot of money every month because of
their podcasts,
you know,
they have subscriptions where they have
like one extra podcast they do every
month,
but I think the best way to do it is to
give as much people as much shit for
free as possible.
But that's also because we're live
performers,
you know,
that's how we see it.
You know,
we're,
we're live performances,
like the key to for us as you know,
come out and see us,
man,
devil's advocate on the devil's advocate
of the UFC UFC thing is that honestly
there's 60 bucks and nowadays there's
like two or three UFC.
He's a month sometimes.
Even to me,
I liked the UFC to a bit like I,
I know if I was a hardcore UFC guy,
I'd order everything.
It's a lot of money.
I know that's a lot on.
It's like,
man,
I don't argue with
that's $180.
I think sometimes it's every week.
I think that if UFC was smart and a lot
of these people were smart,
they would do a subscription based thing
like you're paying 20 bucks a month,
you get everything use,
you know,
what else would be kind of dope if they
had it laid the way Hbo pay per view has
it where you are if you like,
don't want to watch Oscar de la Hoya
fight or floyd mayweather fight and hbo
pay per view next week.
The next Friday.
It's for free on HBO.
Yeah,
that's good.
That would be pretty,
pretty dope.
I agree with,
you know,
if like they had like huge cards,
like say Alistair Overeem,
fight junior dos Santos and it's a big
paper of card.
How I'll throw it on Fox the next
Friday,
you know,
you could watch a replay and that way
also they'll know that they're going to
put on some bad ass fight.
So if it's some,
you know,
if it's one of those fights,
it's not the most entertaining fight.
I mean I live fights are much better
shore for Fox.
Maybe it's not fox,
maybe it's an fx thing,
showed on fx the week after.
Not a bad idea,
but the thing about MMA is a lot of
people by the replays,
they'll buy it again and they'll bite
level.
They're here about how good it is.
And they'll buy the replay.
That probably kills a venue thing about
two weeks.
WHATSAPP,
that kills it about two weeks.
So you've got to get all the money you
can,
you know,
what he was doing over the years is
after a fight,
um,
they would put it up to use a leash,
maybe six months.
Now they fucking put it up at UFC at
least a month later.
Yeah.
That's good.
That's really fucking good.
Good.
Uh,
the fight,
uh,
not this week,
but let's say a Vic Diaz against Nate
Diaz against the serone,
you know,
I want to see that,
beyond this month.
That was new years.
So it'll be on first week of February.
I miss all those spike guys.
Those guys were awesome.
Well,
you know,
like I said,
right now is the best time.
Listen,
right now is the best time ever for
another band.
Susie's.
Yeah,
like me.
Look,
I go home right now.
I tape UFC tonight.
I tape fucking pride with Kendra Perez
from nine to 10,
which is better than the,
the pride they were doing before.
They eliminated a lot of shit that you
didn't need to see.
And now they even cut it down.
They got cro,
cop against fucking,
uh,
the Russian.
I've been watching this tension that my
Alexander.
Oh,
that my head is almost exploded.
Not to mention,
you know,
you've got the round table with Jay.
You got,
you know,
late night fucking,
uh,
were UFC reloaded,
which those are fucking lightning quick.
Okay.
So let's see.
The Ben Henderson fight against Frankie
Edgar is the 25th.
It'll beyond by the last week of March.
Plus you got fucking,
they got the contract,
not spiteful together.
Two thousand 12.
So on Wednesdays you could watch fucking
old fights all fucking day and you know,
spike anything that fucking fx does.
Now they counter it with like this week
they had all of her shots,
fights.
Believe it or not,
a couple of people fucking watch that
shit.
I think it's good.
This is good.
I'm happy.
I don't miss anything.
My dvr is UFC.
We loaded UFC tonight.
Tonight is to count down at 6:00.
Fucking Pacific,
9:00
eastern.
They've given you a ton of fucking May.
You got to fucking steal something for
what the fuck you going to feel
something for that.
What else can they fucking give you
on the music tip?
What I've found for me personally,
like with itunes and Torrance is not
good as people.
I mean the whole industry,
the record industry just fell apart.
But what's happening and I know they got
to feel this,
but I'm buying all my old shit on
itunes.
I don't want to pull out the CD's and
load them into my computer and then
upload them to my ipod.
I just want to get on my phone and I
think of a song that I already have from
my old record collection.
I'm bree buying all my old shit.
What about that?
You know,
I know,
you know,
we're not buying as many cds,
but I think people are buying all the
old shit stairway to heaven about 30
times in my life.
Yeah,
there's definitely a few cds of 10
times.
I don't want to.
I know you can get it for free
somewhere.
I know people
just like,
let me go to itunes.
Ninety nine cents,
make it so you have money,
you know,
for really poor college kids.
They do exactly that,
but they go to a website or they go to a
torrent bit.
Does or even where sites anymore.
Not really leaving an itunes yet.
They finally fucking.
Who are they?
There's a couple of bands that still to
this day they will be.
It's just got on it recently.
Pink Floyd.
A couple of bands.
Well,
why I don't understand.
I don't know.
Weird.
You know those motherfuckers I set 1970,
so I just like,
like red band said when it's something
that you can download illegally,
like music or movies or anything,
it just sell it for as cheap as possible
so that you got to sell it so that it's
not worth going.
And what he did with Lucy gets.
So this whole special for five bucks,
you'll get that money.
I will never spend $180 on a UFC,
you know,
a month.
But if I were to the option for 20 bucks
a month,
I got everything.
I would do it even if I never watched a
books militia.
Louis C dot K dot.
Well yeah,
but you're just used to.
People get a lot more people.
You're just so used to our pricing
structure that was created by boxing and
in like the eighties because the paper
view is so amazing.
Right?
What if you had any idea how much it
costs to put on a production,
you would understand why you didn't have
to charge so much.
It's ridiculous,
but if you have 20 bucks no more.
No you wouldn't.
You wouldn't sell enough to compensate?
I don't think so.
Well,
Louis CK did.
Joe Rogan was with the most brilliant
thing and can be done in 20 years.
Yeah,
he.
He's like anonymous.
He checked.
Everybody checked.
The whole central got checked.
I told got checked.
By the way,
I'm doing the same thing I'm working on
right now.
I'm thinking about doing an Atlanta in
April.
That's what it gave it away for free or
something for a DVD.
But here's the beauty of it,
man.
Dope.
Everybody benefited on this,
but nobody benefited as much as the
fans.
Louis did it for his fame.
Five bucks.
I found load.
Is that what it was for the actual hard
copy download?
Well,
that's all you need.
That's all you leave.
That's it.
I guess.
I think it can download,
downloaded more than once.
Take it so cheap that they can't really
make out.
It was the.
It was a million dollars.
The idea of the UFC.
Twenty bucks a month then.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
I don't think they would do it that way.
It's not ready for $20 a month or two
years.
Three years away.
The subscription monthly subscription is
not a bad idea,
you know,
that would be pretty cool.
Sure.
You get everything.
You get the webpage you get there.
What is the club?
What's in fight club?
Fight Club.
I don't have like a thing that they do
that with the NFL.
They have nfl packages that you get on
direct TV,
all the Games but games,
they make a ton of fucking money.
Well you know,
we came,
they came real close to having a UFC
channel,
you know they were going to have a UFC
fucking channel at one point in time.
They were thinking about buying like a
spike tv or something along those lines
and start their own channel and that
might very well be the future,
you know,
who knows after they're done with the
Fox deal or they might do it with Fox or
you know,
who knows how all this comes together.
You know the
Fox things are strange man.
It's a,
it's the same but it's not the same.
It's the same.
But there's like all this extra talking,
you know,
I see all this sitting around the desk
and all this shit and I watched it.
I was like,
I feel like,
you know,
the way we did it spike style,
they could slide in another fight.
You know,
there's some bad ass fights and that
undercard man,
you know,
they could have in
Charles wants to cut out.
Yeah,
totally shit that we could have slid in
there,
could have slid something in there
instead of everybody talking.
I would rather not talk other than,
you know what I mean?
Look,
everybody knows what it is.
I'll,
I'll hype it up in the beginning and
everything like that.
But I want to get that fucking walking
going.
Let's go baby.
Let's go.
You know,
I,
I can hype everything up plenty.
While these dudes are walking into the
octagon,
I can answer any questions or propose
any possible scenarios.
I just want the fucking fight to take
place.
I say the less talking the better.
But I think they're used to like desks
and shit.
Fox used to like dudes with paper in
front of him.
They love the whole fucking crazy
listening to a superbowl music with UFC
mad.
That's not super well music.
That's Fox sports music.
Well that's the music you hear.
They get all crazy.
By the way,
God is your specialist.
$5.
We should mention that.
The first card gets me in the priest,
right?
Yes.
It's either you or the priest.
The first cargo payloads.
Payloads.
But hopefully that I like to UFC Brian.
I like what they do as a fan.
I like what they do.
I really like everything about it.
You know,
when I watched the short time,
I got a load of fucking volume.
Okay.
And when I watch Fox,
I don't mind Kenny Florian there,
the other guys like a miniature fucking
Joe Rogan with his little haircut and
his little fucking suit.
He looks like Joe Rogan.
Who's radio?
Yeah,
he was like Joe Rogan on news radio.
He needs a pointy sideburns.
Right.
So.
Well it's so weird that.
What the fuck was I talking about?
Anyway?
Who knows?
They got the first fight was a fucking
nightmare.
We went to it.
You go kind enough to give myself any
tickets.
First off,
the fight started at six.
Nothing happened till 6:40.
That's too much.
Joe Rogan.
I can't sit there for 40 minutes just
talking.
Everybody else was taught at least now
they giving you three minutes.
We sat there.
No national anthem though.
Peanut.
Nobody get daddy and give you a fucking
drink.
We didn't know what to do.
You can't get up you campaign.
We don't know what the fucking next
file.
Yeah,
they didn't treat it the way we always
try to live have been tremendous.
This last one was beautiful.
I watched.
I taped the Fox thing that the main
fight,
except for the bisping Simon fight,
which is pretty exciting.
The main fight weren't as exciting as
the fights and the undercard.
You know
bro,
it's the curse of Fox.
The cursor.
No,
it'll be fine.
Look at fx fight that Melvin Gallard.
Jim Miller.
Jim Miller is a fucking animal dude.
Jim Miller's an animal.
God Damn that dude.
Melvin was lightening.
Bob.
He was shot.
She can take it to him.
Man.
He could take it in the way he took that
back,
dove on that back mountain.
Man.
I've always been scary from low side of
those guys from that side of the woods
in Jersey.
They come up to creedence clearwater and
shit like that.
Close to Pennsylvania.
Those motherfuckers will kill you.
That,
that,
that other side of New Jersey.
That's what I love.
See you guys will be living in Georgia.
People over there.
Yeah.
That's fucking different.
Wherever the fuck he's from.
Yeah.
That's.
That's a different angle.
Yeah.
Jim Miller is a hunter.
You know,
you don't think of that when you think
of Jersey like outdoors.
You got the Jersey shore,
you've got those crazy fucking mountain
men.
Had you got to northern New Jersey.
That's it.
Do you want me to build?
Yeah,
totally different.
Three different fucking confidence in
what the Jersey shore.
Just it just passing off.
Ed just.
I started watching Jersey shore and I
thought,
can't love him and Dina.
Oh my God.
You love it.
For Real.
I'm addicted to it because they're so
retarded.
I love watching.
I mean,
snuggie and Dina are female versions of
Beavis and butthead and they're,
they're like,
for real,
they're actually alive if it's not
animation.
These are real people.
No,
Eddie,
there's their,
their,
their setup fits fake reality.
It's sometime or whatever it is.
Hold on though.
Did you see sneaky get punched?
That shit was not fake.
It's.
That was.
That was one or season two,
but yeah,
but the majority of the shit now is
like,
hey,
we're going to put snookie inside this
barbershop,
barber,
barbershops,
super gay because we cast him gay,
you know,
and it's just gonna be ridiculous.
It's completely fake.
And you know what's even worse about the
whole fucking Jersey shore thing is that
new movie,
a three stooges.
How might.
This is a classic franchise that's been
rebooted in the trailer.
Fucking snookie's in it and it's just
like this,
this derby.
I love her.
I just want her to talk.
Her and Dina Dina's,
her best friend.
She's amazing.
It's incredible.
All they do,
every episode is going to be a part in
the episode where they're all getting
ready to go out and they're all doing
their fucking hair and putting on their
makeup.
They go to Karma and it's the same shit.
You know that's crazy about it is those,
they are so retarded that you would
think with all the cameras,
with all the cameras and all their fame,
that they would have girls crawling all
over them.
Girls would you would you would think
none of the girl.
You would think that guys would have
girls crawling all over them,
but it's not what you think.
It's like girls don't want to go back to
that house and be on TV.
Fuck yeah.
Not only are going to get fucking loser
credible.
They go out and they go out and
sometimes they don't get pussy.
They got cameras all over them and
they're super famous and they have
fucking bad nights and the girls are
banging or like regular fucking skis
is that they've been banging for a long
time that they're incredible.
It's like a big edge though.
That's as good as Jersey shore is as
good as Jersey shore is the best show on
TV.
Nothing flux with mob wives do.
If you haven't watched mom lives,
go fuck yourself.
That is the watch that you watch.
Watch,
watch,
watch.
You know.
The problem is I knew too many of those
women,
those women that I knew,
guys that were like in and they would
like fucking threatened you.
I'll fucking make one phone call right
now.
These bitches are just fighting every
episode they want and they have money.
They're in their forties.
You would think they would have some
class the last few years on their
twitters.
Oh yeah,
I do.
I follow all of wife.
The one is divorced and she keeps
calling her ex husband.
This man disrespected me one with the
big head.
Oh wait a minute.
Ralphie May.
Is her husband out of jail are in jail.
Her husband divorced her.
I don't know.
You think he was about to go to jail
again?
The doll?
Yeah.
That's.
That's a skill it to Reagan.
He's Puerto Rican.
Her father,
they're saying that she married,
she married or he married a to get into
the model.
That's what they're saying.
They're accusing.
Her name is Hector Judea.
Really?
How many fucking Italians you know,
name is hector.
He's cute,
but what happened was,
remember we had this discussion the
other day.
I read her sweater.
Staten Island was a fucking garbage
dump.
Brooke,
by the fucking Indians,
just really put the Indians.
They throw him out of New York.
Then they decided,
fuck,
we got this property over there.
Let's build on fucking staten island
with garbage.
Got Hill.
So it was all just garbage.
It used to half of it was a dump.
That's why when you're driving Bro,
it's 20 minutes from Jersey.
That way that's when they give you.
Tell you what Staten Island to me wasn't
doing all.
Like when I used to do gigs in New York,
Staten Island had the most unfriendly
environment.
There was one club.
I'm standing on GRANDPA's.
That was.
They wouldn't give you a seat for your
girlfriend.
You would show up with your girlfriend.
They would like to sit down in the back.
No.
You see two for customers like wow,
like your performance,
like they don't even have like a little
site,
little spot where the performer can sit
down and your girlfriend can sit down.
Like they would want you to,
you know,
go stand outside.
Stupid.
You're not a part of the show.
I went to.
Let's just a weird vibe.
Let's start with the one time because I
got sick and tired to go to Harlem.
If they caught you weeded Harlem on the
way back from Jersey would confiscate
your car because you were interested in
transporting over federal lines.
Those bridges in that tunnel?
Yeah.
That cute.
But if they catch you bringing drugs
over,
your car gets confiscated.
It is in California,
so that's what happened there.
So they would wave.
So you had to go in through the George
Washington and come back to the Lincoln
tunnel after everyday you get sick of
gold over there for weed.
They said the Jamaicans had gun to
Staten Island.
Okay.
There's a Jamaican able to stand down
when they sold the best.
So one day 94 being my buddy go over
there.
No biggie.
We drive in Papa,
Papa,
Papa will,
looking for black people.
We can't fucking find.
We can find.
I can't smell though fucking incense.
I can't do nothing.
Right.
And all of a sudden what do I see?
I see 20 fucking Guido's on a quarter
with white tee shirts on with white
shoes on Pinky rings the whole day I
pull up,
you know,
at the light.
They're like,
what are you who you are looking for?
Not that we're looking for a little bit.
Pull over,
pull over.
Come on.
Over and before,
you know,
have 20th Italians around.
Yeah.
What are you looking for?
I want a 20.
Alright.
Park the fucking car and go into the
fucking pizza places.
Somebody will come up that I parked the
car and my buddy.
You know what?
I'm hungry.
I go to the pizza place.
Guy Comes in.
What do you want?
I want a 20.
Okay,
listen from now on,
when you come over here,
you see fucking whatever his name was.
Angelo [inaudible] us for Angela.
No problem.
Okay.
One day it snows a month later.
You know what?
I don't want to go into this city.
Let's go on to Staten Island real quick.
The weed wasn't bad.
I pull up.
I don't see Angelo.
I don't see nobody.
Actually.
20 fucking gillies.
I don't know.
None of them.
I pull over.
I go into a pizza place within 15
minutes.
I had 15 Italians in there.
Three of them were bats.
We don't hear disrespected.
We polled you when you come up here.
You got to see Angelo.
You want asking for Louis?
I didn't ask her.
Nobody asks for fucking slice of Pizza.
It was an hour and a half drama.
They get a $20 bag of weed.
Where's the wind?
You know what we did?
I don't know what a witness.
What a witness and I was like,
you don't want.
It was too much for me Bro.
It was too much for me.
It was just one island vibes and bad
vibes.
The pizza was delicious.
The bread was delicious to everything
was great,
but I never went back over there and
that's what I see when I watched my
spots like was not comfortable for you.
That's the first.
Last year,
and this is why once he a good father,
good father Ted,
who you with,
that's the person they asked you.
Not with nobody I came with.
No,
no,
no.
Eddie Bravo.
Who by the way reinforced by all those
shitty mom movies.
You know.
So many people got a bronx tale and all
these different.
Bronxdale wasn't that bad,
but I got the greatest movie of all
time.
They were all great movies.
There's a great bunch of them.
Father too,
and I forgot to tell you some.
It's better than the fucking the first
movie ever.
That's better than the first one.
Not to me because Marlon Brando is rock
over fucking everything.
You know what I'm saying?
It was rocket when he told us that
motherfucker at the table that,
you know what?
I do have all this situation here.
My son has to come back,
but if for some of fortunate fucking
situation,
he should be struck by a bolt of
lightning or he should be handled at his
fucking jail cell.
I will blame the people at this table
and that I will not fucking forgive.
That's the greatest speech at the top of
the arm.
The data,
stupid.
He didn't know he douchebag wants to be
that guy.
Marlin Brando was beautiful.
The fucking studio book.
After he did that,
listen,
Marlon Brando than ever.
The Marlon Brando was one of my idols
because he told Hollywood to suck his
dick.
He went down to a lot of men suck his
I have a photo of it.
If you put on the bounty,
he went down to mutiny on the bounty and
bought a fucking island.
Nobody's ever bought an island.
Nobody's ever been that fucking quit.
Tyler Perry after.
Now.
This was 1970.
It was motherfucker and then impregnated
half the women on that island.
All of them are named Marlin.
Every fucking killing.
It was Marlon Brando.
That was part of living on the island.
You got to suck.
There was this island off the coast of
Hawaii or say wherever you shot,
what that thing.
I went to Dr Moreau.
Warner brothers went down there and
wherever the fucking people what it
looked at the tapes and you're like,
what is this birds and pigeons where you
been?
Where the fuck you been for the last
month?
He,
he's like,
God,
that'd be fucking these Hawaiian chicks
up the ass a great fucking time.
So,
um,
when the godfather came along,
they didn't want them.
They're like,
this guy wasted millions of fucking
dollars.
Yeah.
Put that up here.
Brian.
Put that up.
Look at this.
Oh,
you can't do it on Ustream,
right?
But if you just Google Marlin Brando
Sucking Dick,
it's actually an artistic shot that
really stopped the car.
That's how big the motherfucker.
And he doesn't even look that fat back
then.
Kills the fucking.
Listen,
I got to Boogie with Stu.
I love you.
I'll see you Thursday night.
I got to.
I need six up under the Bob Hope.
Fucking senator to get everything in
shape.
Don't forget payloads.
Don't forget fucking kill you.
Motherfucker.
Pay Load.
Bravo.
Don't forget the Sandy Bravo a gift for
his fucking kid on twitter.
Send it to.
Oh,
some guy emailed me.
They bought you a camera cock sucker.
So I want them points Thursday and
Friday night we're going to have a good
time.
House of Blues,
Vegas,
Mandalay Bay,
Duncan Trussell,
Joe Diaz need
the whole pile.
And one more thing I wanted to talk
about before we get out of here because
this is pretty fucking fascinating shit.
You know,
we talked about that,
uh,
the problem in the ocean that big a pile
of a plastic that they have the garbage
patch,
they just found them a mushroom and the
Amazon that eats indestructible
plastics.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's pretty fucking nuts man.
So we're gonna throw a bunch of
mushrooms on it and then the water's
going to be all trippy and we're all
gonna.
Die Eats
polyurethane man.
The mushroom is called pedal lot too.
Sis.
Pedal up top assists.
Photo micro spora a o pestilence,
pestilence,
t opsis,
Pesta Lottie opsis Mike grow spora.
Why do they ask the name of the stuff
with the Latin?
Let it go,
bitch.
It's 2012,
you know,
awesome.
Plastic eating mushrooms,
that's the official name.
It's spelled p e s t a l o t I o p s I s
micro s p o r a.
So it's a resident of the Ecuadorian
rainforest and was discovered by a group
of student researchers led by molecular
biochemistry professor Scott Strobel as
a part of Yale's annual rainforest
expedition and laboratory.
You know,
they go down there,
man,
they have these scientists and these
researchers go down there and every now
and then they'll find some fucking crazy
shit that there's like all sorts of
medicines that have come out of the rain
forest,
incredible psychedelic drugs,
all kinds of nutty fucking things in
that shoe,
in that bitch up every day.
So the mushroom like disintegrates the,
the plastics or what's the,
do it,
eats it,
it's able to the fungus species will it
absorb,
you know,
mushrooms absorb things.
They,
they,
you know,
it's really like they're,
they're the,
the,
it's Karma.
It's like Karma free living the way
mushrooms live their speech.
They literally live in Shit.
You know,
they lived the most humble life
possible,
but there it's a living organism.
It's the first fungus species to able
to,
to be able to survive exclusively on
polyurethane.
So it lives on fucking indestructible
plastic.
And more importantly,
it's able to do that in anaerobic
conditions,
meaning the same conditions found in the
bottom of landfills.
And this makes this fungus a prime
candidate for bio read remediation,
remediation,
bio remediation projects that could
finally provide an alternative to just
burning plastic and hoping for the best.
I wonder how long that process takes.
Like are we talking about like 30 years,
million years?
But at least it's better than what the
plans now.
Now they need to find some shit that a
nuclear waste.
It's probably in the Amazon.
It's probably a frog.
Probably snookie.
It's a frog.
They're going to give it this frog.
It's gonna eat nuclear waste.
And that's going to become fucking
Godzilla.
Oh No.
There goes Tokyo.
Go,
go Godzilla.
Danny proper goes to want to step up to
the mic and to be on the podcast here.
Sign is our boy danny.
We've known Danny since he was a little
child since he was a small boy.
And now he's a black belt world
champion.
First Tenth Planet Jujitsu,
black belts.
The viewers have been looking at his
feet for the last two hours.
That phones headphones.
Okay,
so everybody knows that you know what
you sound like much,
but at the gracie nationals this past
Sunday,
not only did 10th planet get the first
place,
team title,
the Gracie nationals,
but Danny also got got first place in
his division tapping out to black belts.
He twisted a Joe Merera black belt and
he guillotine UFC star Damn Fan.
Denny Denny had a.
He kept off of an epic day for 10th
Planet and there was a flying d isn't
going flying one jumped up.
No,
no,
no.
He shot in for a single leg on my right
leg.
And uh,
I just wrapped his neck and I drove my
hips and he fell back.
I hooked his right leg with a triangle,
stepped over with my right leg,
crossed my feet,
arched my hips,
looked up.
It was amazing,
man.
It was just getting nasty.
We know Denison's what we,
what were you like a purple belt when
you started training with that?
A blue belt.
Blue,
blue,
blue.
But I started,
actually,
no,
I started training with Eddie when I was
an orange belt.
Uh,
but.
So that's like little kids.
Yeah,
I was 15.
Let me go
tell them about our first private
lesson.
He lives in San Francisco.
He's been there the whole time.
I'm in La.
I had just opened up.
I had my first school open for maybe two
years and uh,
I'll never forget,
I'll never forget when it was after our
tournament.
Me and a couple of well known Jujitsu
players were in the parking lot,
smoking some weed in our car and here's
this little kid,
like two cars away,
just standing there looking at us and
we're like trying to hide the,
we'd like to know there's a kid that
hide the weed.
We're like hiding the weed and he knew
exactly what we're doing.
Like Ah.
And then we came up in San Francisco.
Yes.
Yeah,
he drove down for the kids.
Learn about weed when they're three.
Dude,
it's been legal there for like 30 years.
Nobody gives a fuck.
I got it.
The first time I got offered a smoke
was,
I was in fourth grade.
There was this.
Tell us about,
tell us about your first experience
with,
um,
like remember your birthday and all that
kind of stuff.
Oh yeah.
Uh,
so for my 15th birthday,
uh,
my brother and I were going to go down
to the scree convention.
It was like this Greek dancing thing and
I'm like,
all right,
I want to,
I want to take a private with Eddie,
you know.
And uh,
he taught me the rubber guard back then.
He actually taught me London and taught
me the invisible color,
the basic path and uh,
taught me some twister stuff,
taught me the meat hook and I basically
went back and all the stuff,
I've videotaped it.
He is,
he had his brother drive down from San
Francisco,
so it was pretty cool.
So that's pretty crazy.
I had this kid and I usually don't do
privates,
but this kid shows up and I'm like,
you know what I have,
I like to save all my energy for my
group classes.
I really don't have energy for privates.
Really just rarely do I give them and he
comes down,
you know,
there's 15 year old kid drove all the
way from Frisco.
I'm like,
okay.
And he ended up.
I knew right there,
right.
I knew that this guy,
there was something special about them.
I knew that.
I mean,
if he's willing to drive all the way
down from San Francisco to take a
private,
that he's down for life.
This guy was.
Yeah,
that's most of the most important thing
that anybody could ever show.
It was just,
if you want to be successful at
something,
you have to be really fucking dedicated
to it.
Really dedicated and doing something
like that come all the way down from San
Francisco.
That shows him.
It never waver because even to this day,
to this day,
I'm not just saying this to this day,
he's,
he's definitely the most decorated 10th
planet.
Yeah.
He's,
he's,
he's one of the most titles.
He's competed the most at the highest
levels.
Um,
in straight grappling.
I have guys that have done mma and
they've done well like Scott Epstein at
all,
but it pure grappling denny has done the
most and it's because he.
He drills and practices way more than
anybody I know.
I mean he's a Jujitsu fanatic.
Not only does like yesterday.
We're rolling.
We're rolling and every move,
every little trick I had,
even the latest shit,
the latest tricks,
he would call it out.
He would tell me what I was thinking.
Nobody can do that.
Nobody can break down the 10th planet
system like Danny,
tell me exactly how I'm planning to
trick them.
I've never had anybody do that.
He was calling everything out.
It was fucking me up like,
Holy Shit,
this guy's reading my mind.
He studies the template system like no
one else and he studies the.
All the new games that are coming up
like,
like all the 50 slash 50 stuff,
all the leg lock,
all the latest stuff that the Brazilians
are coming up with like halfway on
Mendez and Cabrina all the spiral and
della Hiva.
This guy studies it.
Like he has ocd,
like,
like he's obsessed.
He's definitely focused,
it's important
to be around people like that,
you know,
in life there's always people that are
willing to take things to another level
that are learning quicker than everybody
else,
to have more passion that's so
important.
So important.
And it rubs off on a student's.
Check this at this,
at the.
I had,
uh,
maybe about seven or eight of my schools
compete at the tournament and his
school,
the San Francisco school by far did the
best.
They were 12 in one.
All that.
He had four guys competing 12 in one.
And the one loss was in the finals.
It was like a 30 minute match,
37 minute match and the guy lost,
but it was,
he didn't even tap.
He went to sleep.
That's incredible though.
Thirty seven minutes.
That's amazing.
I mean he's got incredible students like
future stars like Adam Sachin offi
called big Red Adam sached office 230
pounds.
His Rubber Guard is insane and he's got
black belt level guillotines and
endorses and Japanese necktie.
And then,
and then,
uh,
my killer brand and Travis Travis
Micheala.
Yeah.
Some crazy stuff.
And
by the way,
if you're in San Francisco,
Danny,
how did they find your place?
A lot of people already come to your
place because the podcasts,
right?
Yes,
yes,
yes.
The year a podcast has helped me.
Thank you very much.
How do they,
how do they get their,
uh,
were,
on,
uh,
through,
through Valencia street,
suite 100 inside Valencia street muscle,
the gym.
And my website is 10th Planet Jiu Jitsu
SF.com.
And for folks who,
you know,
look,
I get emails,
I get twitter messages all the time
saying,
thank you.
I started doing Jujitsu because of the
podcast.
For people who think you can't do it,
if your,
if your body,
your body works,
you can do it.
All right?
You don't have to go in there and jump
in.
They were killers.
You take beginning classes,
you learn some technique.
And it's fun.
When the Indian,
you know what man,
you just gotta you gotta be able to be
tapped out.
When you get tapped out,
just tap,
just tap and go right back in and figure
out what you did wrong and learn.
And it is a vehicle for developing your
whole life.
All martial arts are yield there.
When you get through difficult things,
a lot of people never physically get
pushed.
They don't.
They don't understand what it feels
like.
They don't understand what it's like to,
to.
To,
to really exert yourself and to try hard
into grow and accomplish.
To accomplish,
you know,
something.
To learn some new techniques to develop
an advance.
It's so important for that you do.
When you get really good at something as
difficult as Jujitsu,
it makes everything in your life better.
And when we say anybody can do it,
anybody that's not a sales pitch,
anybody can do it.
Girl,
little girls,
little five year old,
six year old girls do Jujitsu,
old ladies do Jujitsu.
Anybody can do it.
You know,
know contrary to popular belief,
you go to Jujitsu school,
it's not these barbaric animals that are
want to rip your arm off.
It's the opposite because the nerds.
Yeah,
it's mostly classes.
I'm also the computer nerds who will
kill you.
Yeah,
exactly.
Computer nerds that are addicted to
gaming.
Like cade,
like if you didn't know Kate,
you know cade cade Nelson,
who's wicked is Jujitsu,
is wicked and he's a very small guy.
He's like 140 pounds at the most,
right?
He's not on.
He's won 30 black belt,
nasty technique,
but if you look at him,
he's like all skin and bones Mazda,
the nicest guy.
Nicest guy.
You know,
it's,
it's totally not a bunch of killers who
just literally,
yes,
you learn Jujitsu.
You,
you are learning how to kill people,
but they're not animals.
Not mean people.
They're like,
like really cool,
nice folks.
You know,
like so many of them,
like Brent,
you know,
you look at brand,
like what a nice looking guy.
He seems like a real friendly,
nice to everybody.
Check your fucking lights.
The sport itself,
what it,
what,
what's going on?
What makes it so much fun is a filter
for douchebags because in the sport of
Jujitsu,
you're good.
The sport is.
The game plan is to tap someone out to
put someone in a position,
in a choke hold or an arm bar.
None of it,
which I did.
None of it hurts.
You just tap out when you feel like you
can't get out and you tap out,
give up,
and then the guy,
let's go the whole.
So that's like a kill for you.
No one got hurt,
but you're tapped out.
You couldn't get out if you douchebags
can't go,
can't walk through the fire.
Those beginning stages where they're
getting tapped out,
they're losing the game because they
take it too personally.
Everybody has an ego,
but Douche bags have the biggest egos so
they can't go into Jujitsu and and go
through the learning phases where
they're losing or they're tapping out,
losing a game of death.
You know,
they can't handle it,
so they never even get to Jujitsu.
The only guys that make it through are
the guys that have a complete control of
their ego where they tap out at the
beginning all the time.
You're always losing in the beginning,
you're just tapping out.
It doesn't hurt.
You're tapping out,
but your ego can get bruised if you
don't have control of it.
So what ends up happening is Jujitsu is,
is the ultimate douche bag filter.
You're left with a bunch of guys that
were had no problem tapping out and no
problem submitting,
no problem dealing with reality because
the reality is every dickhead wants to
think that he's the full command.
Every guy wants to think that,
you know,
there's so many guys,
like if I got into m and a,
I'm telling you where it now I'm not
ended at MMA,
but if I get a new fucking be running
shit,
fuck GSP,
I'm a natural born fighter to some
dudes are just natural.
And those guys,
they can't handle Jujitsu because some
little cade dude will choke their
fucking lights out,
you know?
And that's also one of those guys are
scared of weed hollow as especially
edibles,
edibles.
Expose your douchey ness as well.
Meanwhile,
edibles are the best things to roll on.
Ooh,
I don't like cookie.
Realize you just never know how much thc
are getting into.
We talked about before with lately I've
been on,
but on a good roll with these trips,
I decided a couple couple of pumps for
teaching.
I'm all good.
I don't need to get crazy.
You guys ever tried the cold list?
No.
Dot It's a.
it's like a breath thing.
You tried it.
That was it.
Pretty good.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
But eventually they're gonna have like
fucking filtration systems and air
conditioning.
When you come into you come into work
and just get high.
What about the new vapor pens?
What does that.
Oh,
the like old school.
Like they look like those magic.
The cigarette.
Yeah.
The cigarettes.
Electronic cigarettes.
Yeah.
They're like soaked in thc and there's
zero smell.
Don't just approach and talk about that
because someday you're gonna want to use
those in someplace.
Meanwhile they're monitoring twitter.
These cons.
Yeah.
We used to.
I used to have the electronic wines,
but they weren't accurate.
You know,
like it seemed like you weren't.
You just suck on him for awhile and
you're like,
I'm not getting anything.
This is bullshit.
It's eventually.
It's all gonna.
Be Legal.
We're,
we're,
we're battling at right now.
Here's some crazy shit that was on
MSNBC,
MSNBC DOT com.
It's for royders in London.
These scientists did these studies on
people tripping on mash magic mushrooms
and they.
It's given them the best picture yet of
how psychedelic drugs work,
and these British scientists are saying
the findings suggest that such drugs
could be used to treat depression.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
I mean it's amazing.
This is not.
This is all becoming mainstream shit.
One after the other over and over and
over again.
There's these studies that are coming to
light now that are suggesting that all
these different drugs,
ketamine,
they're seeing the ketamine can be used
as an instant cure for depression and
one of the reasons why kids get addicted
to ketamine is the first thing that
ketamine does alleviate all your
worries,
like does one of the reasons why people
are doing it so that other suggesting
that ketamine can be used as some sort
of an antidepressant,
as some sort of an instant
antidepressant quality,
as well as suicide.
On two separate studies,
the effects of Psilocybin,
the active ingredient in magic mushrooms
showed that contrary to scientists,
scientists expectations,
which of course is based on propaganda.
It does not increase but rather suppress
activity in areas of the brain that are
also dampened with other antidepressant
treatments,
so they don't even understand it.
It's like they're saying psychedelics
are thought of as mind expanding drugs,
so it's been assume that they work by
increasing the brain's activity,
but they don't.
Surprisingly,
they found this.
Psilocybin actually causes the activity
to decrease in areas that have the
dentist connections with other areas so
they don't know.
That makes sense though,
so it quiets your brain down so you
could have an outer body experience.
That makes sense to me.
Sort of
less activity,
less activity.
Just like when you meditate,
you meditate,
you know people are addicted to
meditation because you know,
if you could,
if you could just think,
think about one thought,
like a water drop or whatever.
You get into that zone.
People,
that zone is the frequency of the
universe.
That's where everyone's trying to get.
They're trying to get that and you do it
by just thinking about one thing,
so that makes sense.
You're quieting your brain,
removing all negativity.
You're thinking about one thing and it
aligns you with the universe.
I mean,
maybe you know,
no one knows exactly what it's doing.
I mean,
it might just be facilitating evolution.
It might just be giving you a better way
of thinking because that's my hypothesis
because the free the universe is at one
frequency that science.
So it makes sense that we should try to
get to that frequency.
If the universe is at a frequency,
one frequency all throughout the
universe,
we know that.
It makes sense.
What do you mean by that?
What's his frequency?
You're talking about it.
The whole universe is at a frequency,
like one frequency,
and that was in the debate between a
creationism and evolution.
That was the strong point,
right?
There's a science proved that the whole
universe at one frequency.
So the creationists are saying,
see,
that's proof of God.
That's proof of intelligent design.
How could the whole universe by accident
be at one frequency frequency mean
though?
Um,
I don't know exactly,
but it's like the frequency.
What is the frequency of smoking,
man?
Yeah,
that shit is so gross,
dude.
God Damn.
Or they put a fan on or something,
but the frequency is like,
like what's a frequency of vibration?
It's a vibration vibration.
Frequency of cigarettes give off.
Dude,
that's fucking calm for 93 point four
brands for real man.
Unless you've got a window open or
something,
you got to send a smoke sucker.
Shit ain't doing nothing,
man.
Know what I mean by that?
Like what's a frequency?
And it like a radio station is a certain
frequency.
It's a 95 point five.
What is that like?
Well,
you know what's a frequency and if you
turn that dial,
Bam,
you need to get that frequency on 95
point five.
If you were listening to Kayla.
Yes.
So the pinnacle of science is that they
just discovered that the whole universe
is one frequency.
I don't know what number that is,
but it's a certain frequency in music.
You got to be on the same frequency or
you got to be on frequencies that
harmonize with that frequency.
So it makes sense.
Like to me,
it makes sense that if the whole unit
so,
but,
but the scientist saying,
no,
it doesn't prove intelligent design
because we are finding that we're not in
just one universe where there's a
multiverse,
there's,
there's endless universes that each one
is at a different frequency,
so that has improved any intelligent
design.
I don't really give a shit about that
argument,
but to me it makes sense.
We're trying to get to add on the
frequency of the universe and that makes
sense to you because I have no idea
still and I'm like trying to get on the
radio station of the universe.
That's,
that's another had meditation and Yoga.
This is my hypothesis is what?
This is what I'm.
This is my guess is that Yoga and
meditation,
unconditional love sex.
Certain drugs will get you in the
frequency if you love the man.
What about dog sex?
What about you fucking donkey?
It's the same frequency.
Is it the same frequency animals?
I'm saying the only thing that I'm
seeing here is from God like
productions,
which right away you go,
okay.
What they're saying is that all
beings in the universe connect through a
single frequency and there's a bunch of
videos I guess you have to watch to,
to understand where they're trying to
say.
Yeah,
makes sense to me.
I looked tense and it says it's a song
from the butthole surfers.
Really bad.
It's a good song.
Yeah.
I mean,
no one knows what
the fuck is going on when you were on
mushrooms.
It's,
it's certainly something that should be
studied though.
And that's what I think is missing in,
in,
you know,
and people's ideas of mushrooms.
Everybody's got this propaganda based
opinion on it.
Everybody thinks it's bad for you.
I mean,
I'm,
I remember I had this conversation with
Michio Kaku wants when we're on the
opiod anthony show and I suggested a,
you know,
I asked him if he's ever done mushrooms
and you know,
he asked like I said like,
Hey,
you know,
you ever,
you ever smoke crack?
You ever do math?
You know,
it's like,
to a lot of people that's like the same
thing.
Like you say,
do mushrooms and they don't want to mess
up their brain,
but so much insight,
so many different people have come up
with insights because directly related
to psychedelic experiments,
and I don't know if it's true,
but the rumor was that Francis Crick,
when he,
when he was dying,
admitted that he was a frequent user of
lsd and then that's how he came up with
the idea,
the concept of the double helix of DNA,
you know,
that he came up with and under the
influence of the LSD has been an up a
bunch of this.
I think the guy's name was carrie.
Another guy came up with other insights
on LSD and it's been geneticists and
different people that have done Iowasca
that have had weird ideas and expand on
these ideas that came directly as a
result of psychedelic experiences.
Who knows what it is,
man?
I don't know,
but it would be awesome if they were
allowed people to fuck it,
study it instead of locked you in a
fucking cage for experiencing something
that's been here a lot longer than
people have.
You know,
so stupid.
It's just we have a bunch of stupid
people,
like we were talking before,
this happened about,
uh,
the presidential debates about watching,
like watching Newt Gingrich is
hilarious.
Like how is he even even in the
presidential race,
I mean that you're saying that guy
doesn't rob him and Mitt Romney are
arguing about because they both had an
investments in some,
some,
uh,
they both made money off the economy
going to shit based on their investments
and they both did,
but there were arguing live on tv,
on CNN about who invested more and that
that alone should tell people that are
both full of shit.
Well,
he just lost the Kim and second place in
Florida new.
Can you imagine if Newt Gingrich's,
the president,
Mitt Romney,
Mitt Romney met with a kid who had
cerebral palsy and he marijuana
would say,
why don't you wouldn't even answer him.
He wouldn't even answer.
You said,
what?
You put me in jail.
He said,
well,
you could try synthetic marijuana
synthetic.
Marilyn.
He was suggesting that that was a good
idea that I'm not for medical marijuana.
I've told you I'm not for it.
Like you're not for it,
you're telling for why,
why?
For what reason?
Under what reason.
Why?
Because you're a whore because all these
goddamn companies that gets you into the
position that you're in right now tell
you that that's the stance that you
should take.
See that video of Mitt Romney's flipping
and flopping.
There's an awesome a mormon man.
Not that there's anything wrong with
being a mormon,
but when you're a mormon,
you're not allowed to run the
presidency.
You're not around the run the country.
You're just not.
You're not allowed to any wacky
religion.
If you're a super catholic,
and I know jfk was a Catholic and
everything like that,
but this is with different times.
It's 2012.
You know?
Really,
you believe that Joseph Smith,
a 14 year old kid that lived in 18,
20 pound golden tablets that represented
the last work of Jesus.
The guy was a con man,
unknown con man.
He said he found a stone and the secret
stone and he looked through the stone
and he could read the large works.
Jesus really,
really come on,
man,
which was that in a goof ball.
It's just,
it's just fucking amazing,
man.
You know,
I have friends that are friends of
friends actually that are Mormons that I
know.
They're very nice people.
It's one of the nicest religions and
what it gives them that's great is a
great sense of community like they have.
Their churches have been a mormon
churches before.
They have a really nice sense of
community.
They're very nice to each other and they
really promote that they're promote like
that feeling of family and that positive
frequency and it does really.
It really makes a difference.
Man,
you know,
I,
I was at a mormon funeral recently and
these people,
man,
they really believed that this guy was
in a better place and it really helped
them that their loved one had passed on
into a better place.
It really did and I and I,
I really support that.
I think that's awesome,
but just just that's just because the
ideology happens to be in a good
frequency,
but if you break down what the ideology
stands for,
it's ludicrous.
It's absolutely ridiculous.
It's absolutely doing some good for some
of these people,
but so would just being nice,
it would do the exact same thing,
so we'll just being humble and giving
into love and just being nice to people.
You don't need some wacky shit that was
made by a con man,
a 14 year old con man who found golden
tablets and then when the people came to
him like,
where are these tablets?
He was older angels took them away.
Angels took.
It's like,
it's like,
you know,
it's such a dumb story.
It's a terrible story.
Yeah.
I mean,
to me,
I growing up,
I despised all religions.
I thought I thought it was all just crap
and destroying society,
but as I get older,
I,
for me,
my opinion on religions,
if you do it right,
if it's based on unconditional love and
doing the right thing,
different religions are just like.
It's a way to get your soul and the
right frequency.
There's different ways.
Get your body physically,
like there's kettlebells and then
there's some people like to just run.
Some people like to swim,
all different ways to get your body
align,
and I think all religions,
as long as you do it right,
whether it's Muslim or whatever,
cat,
Catholicism,
like my grandma,
she did it right.
All she cared about was doing things for
others and she was hardcore Catholic.
Went to church every day.
That was per exercise of the soul.
That is what got her frequency in the
right place.
Some people do yoga,
some people meditate.
Some people you know,
believe this.
Some people worship rocks.
If you really believe rock the rock is
the frequency of the universe and it
gets your soul in the right place.
Um,
I'm all for it.
It's an idea of just believing in
something and then having a code that
you live by and moving your life always
in a positive way,
and that's good.
No matter what you call it.
What do you call it?
Hindu do you call it Kundalini Yoga,
where you call it Catholicism.
If you're really moving in a positive
direction and you really believe in love
and you really are being warm and open
and you've given the idea of giving into
a higher power is not because God wants
you to be humble where God wants you to
be in all of his greatness.
What,
what it,
what it is is saying there's something
above you,
so not taking yourself so fucking
seriously and instead not being out for
number one and sort of realizing that we
are together.
Like there is a brotherhood and
sisterhood of man,
you know,
that's,
that's really what it's supposed to be
all about.
That's the good of religion.
And that's where I've seen religion help
people for sure.
And that was just like you growing up
man.
And it was both of us was the same
reason because we had seen the system
fail us.
You know,
we had seen all these people that were
supposed to be correct and you know,
these people that were supposed to be
adults.
We saw they were retarded.
We saw there were assholes.
We saw that was all bullshit.
We saw that,
you know,
religion was being used negatively a lot
of the time and it was a lot of guilt
and there was a lot of yelling at you
and it was a lot of.
So we just,
we just trashed.
So
I like,
I would never,
if my grandmother was still alive,
I would never try to like knock some
sense into her,
try to prove that the Bible is written
by Matt.
It worked for her.
That was her kettlebells right there for
assault.
It worked for like,
you know,
and well,
that's the way I look at it now.
I think religion is,
is if you do it right in and uh,
you're,
you know,
you always look to do the right thing
and it's all life is all about a
selflessness and a unconditional.
And what people don't understand is that
benefits your man.
You know,
you can be,
do,
do that and do it in a selfish way.
I mean,
it sounds stupid,
but if you're a selfish person,
you really want to succeed.
You really want good things for you.
You want to do it selfishly,
be nice to everybody.
That's the best way to get ahead.
The best way to get ahead is just be
nice to everybody.
Tip people whenever you can,
tip more than you're supposed to.
Tip.
Give people hugs.
When you can be nice to people all the
time.
When you put out that good energy,
you get good energy back.
You can like almost of it like people
are almost looking out for number one,
you really want to look out for number
one,
look out for everybody else.
Look out for everybody else and that's
how you really look out.
For number one,
I have had the most benefit in my life
by being nice to me,
but the most benefit in my life by being
generous and being friendly and being
warm and every time I have not been
that,
it's always fucked me and when I run
into someone,
especially now at this stage of my life
when I've had my own personal
revelations in my own successes and
failures and have kind of assessed what
what helps me and what doesn't help me.
When I run into someone that's life is a
mess and I run into someone that's got a
lot of troubles,
God damn it.
If it's not a big chunk of what the fuck
got them.
There is the way they think about
things,
the way they behave.
Think about things the way they take a
cigarette.
Fucking throw it in the street.
You don't realize why your life is kind
of shit while you're littering
everywhere like that.
That's not.
You're not putting out good energy while
you're throwing you fucking mcdonalds
bag out the window because no one's
looking.
You're being a cunt.
You're fucking up man.
You're,
you're,
you're ruining space.
You're sending out bad things.
When you fuck somebody over in a
business deal,
you're like,
well,
I profited.
Hey,
it's a dog eat dog world bullshit.
You just put out some negative shit and
it's gonna.
Come back at you,
man.
That guy hates you because people you
fucked over in that bad development deal
or whatever the hell you did wrong.
Those people don't like you.
Now.
They hate you and that's gonna.
Come your way,
do nice things and nice things come from
it,
man.
Think always.
Think,
talk and act man.
And that's the best way to end this
bitch.
Right?
Let's wrap this motherfucker up.
So San Francisco,
if you're down,
if you're down to get your shit
together,
if you're down to learn the ancient
martial art of jewelry it.
So if you're down to have a vehicle for
developing your human potential,
go to 10th planet Jiu Jitsu,
San Francisco,
Jj,
Tenth Planet Jiu Jitsu SF,
Jujitsu forward,
10th planet,
Jiu j I t,
s,
u,
f,
go there.
Just change.
Have a shorter version of that.
Well,
you could just go to Nogi,
Jujitsu,
SF DOT Co.
If you go to 10th planet jj,
,
j.com.
And there's how many affIliate
locations?
We've got over 30 worldwide,
melbourne,
rochester,
victoria,
Canada.
Portland's,
by the way,
if there's no one near you and you want
to learn 10th planet systems,
you could still go to 10th planet j,
j.com.
And you can learn from the videos that
are available in the database.
There's.
You could literally see all the lessons
that we're learning in class in san
francisco.
Eddie puts those up there.
You just have to pay a small monthly
fee.
Just like we were talking about.
What five perfect.
That's going to charge 30 or 25.
A lot of people are.
I just want just a little bit.
I wanted to charge for bandwidth website
gotta.
Charge a little bit for $99 a month for
the entire 10th planet system at your
fingertips and there's also dvds
available to tell them about the dvds
and whether you can get those.
You just go to 10th planet,
Jj.com,
the book,
and if there's not,
if there's not a 10th planet school near
you,
just go to any brazilian jujitsu school,
any school,
it doesn't matter.
You know,
if the guy's A douche bag,
find her another school,
whatever,
but it's any jujitsu as better than no
jujitsu.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's a good thing to have the skill to
protect your family,
to protect your loved ones by being an
expert at scientifically subduing
someone and putting them to sleep
nonviolently and getting the hell out
and get the safety,
you know.
And it's a fun way to exercise,
man.
A lot of people don't like going to the
gym,
just riding a bike.
It's fucking boring,
you know,
and a lot of people can't motivate
themselves to do that.
Jujitsu will motivate you to do it.
It's fun.
So 10th planetj,
,
j.com.
all your information,
get it.
Go get yourself some skills.
I'm learning this friday,
house of blues in vegas,
joey diaz,
duncan trussell and me almost sold out.
There's only a few tickets left.
So jump on that shit.
Go to,
uh,
go to my facebook page.
Facebook.com.
Hob.com.
That's the best way I got some seminars.
Okay.
Quick seminars are at omaha February
11th,
um,
Michigan February 18th.
And I'm,
there's all this on 10th planet.
Jj dot.
Uh,
yes.
Yes.
So if you can remember it,
just go there and denny's.
Doing,
uh,
all the ultimate nyc absolute in New
York.
There's going to be february what?
February tWenty fifth at all the top
guys make riot hall 25th that they're,
they're mixing 20 9:35.
Forty nine and one slash 62.
And we're all meeting at 1:55.
Yeah.
That's like a mini abu dhabi dude.
It's,
it's not even a mini.
It's like just as good as apple.
Damn,
I'm going to be in Japan.
Oh yes.
Like a motherfucker.
Jake's fighting on that card.
Oh yeah,
he's funny.
Nakiyama around man.
Stand up.
Going good.
yeah.
Do jason was getting better man.
You know he's a,
you know,
he's a hard worker dude.
I've been working with them.
Uh,
I got to train with them last week.
dude.
He looks awesome and a stand up is
getting better.
It's just getting there.
I think all of his skills are getting
better.
His wrestling and jujitsu.
Stand up.
everything beautiful.
I love jake is good dude.
Alright,
thanks everybody.
Thanks to fleshlight for sponsoring the
podcast.
And uh,
they were the first sponsor and we will
always be loyal to theM as much as
people give a shit about it.
Oh,
I should probably say something about
this fear factor thing.
Yeah.
Fairfax had got pulled off the air.
Uh,
we weRe supposed to have a,
an episode where contestants drank
donkey,
semen and a donkey urine.
Um,
apparently folks think it's too much.
I agree.
Okay.
After we did it,
I'm going to be honest with you guys,
and I haven't told anybody this,
but I think I got high with you after it
was over that day.
And I remember thinking,
I might haVe told you,
but I think we fucked up,
man.
I think we went too far.
I just,
it just seemed wrong,
man.
I'm like,
people are not going to like,
this is gonna make people angry.
Whatever.
Man.
Somebody.
Somebody signed off on it.
And then apparently the baCklash was
crazy and it shut down your thoughts all
together,
all the episode,
the episode.
and there's one episode that's gonna
air.
February is our next one,
and there's one other two hour ePisode
that's gonna air.
Sometime after that they haven't figured
out when I put it on the dvd.
No,
no,
no.
I think it's never going to go anywhere.
It's going to be buried and I'll never
do it again.
I think they went too far showing throw
this shit and not really.
But the stents are so much bigger now.
This show is so much bigger and crazier
that they tried to push everything.
I just think they went too far.
I think it was nutty,
but I don't think they went to.
I know exactly where there's.
Everybody has their own standards.
I just don't think that it's fair to ask
people to do that.
It sounds ridiculous coming from me.
What?
They don't have to do it.
I know they don't have to,
but I mean to ask them to do it,
I think it would've been cool if
everybody said go fuck yourself.
And then we had like scrap stunt.
It would have been funny.
Have you had that happen yet?
No,
but that would have been a good time,
you know?
Um,
but,
you know,
I think it was way easier for girls to
do that guys,
you know,
obviously,
I mean for real,
even girls were even joking around about
it.
It was way easier fitting it on their
chest and rubbing it in.
Oh,
brian,
that's your world.
And you live in a dark world.
Uh,
so look,
I'm,
I'm sure if we had go back in time they
wouldn't do it again.
And the only way you find the limits of
these things is you push them.
You know,
I think it was a mistake.
Oops.
So it's over.
And uh,
it,
it would probably never see the light of
day or five years from now it'll air
because there's no way they would have
considered doing it five years ago when
fear factor went through its first run.
I mean,
in season one it was so tame and calm
and easy and,
and,
you know,
and small compared to what it's like
now.
Now it's just ridiculous.
The stumps are huge and crazy and
explosions and nuts.
Who knows if they'll ever show that
again.
I,
you know,
I'd rather than not,
I think people shouldn't have to do
that.
I think it's too much.
They fucked up,
but you know,
whatever we learn,
kill the show kelly episode and we'll
march on because we got some good
episodes coming up.
It's a better way,
a better show than it ever was before,
you know,
I hope this doesn't fuck it up for
everything else,
but uh,
I think everybody realizes that was a
mistake including nbc and,
you know,
they wanted to push things and just,
you don't find out how bad things are
until you get people's reactions.
And that's the reaction.
Woopsies we're sorry,
sorry.
Um,
so that's it.
So I've commented on that.
So go to a.
Oh,
dina dina,
thursday night,
right here,
10:00
PM a thursday,
thursday night.
It's at 8:30
8:34
fridays at 10 good ice house comedy dot
thursday 8:30
PM,
me,
Joe Diaz,
little lester,
brian red band,
and who knows who else.
And we'll also have the ice house
chronicles podcast,
which is only available on desk squad on
itunes.
Subscribe to death squad.
It is free as of all,
all our podcasts are,
and you can get,
there's a gang of podcast there,
sam tripoli's,
naughty show.
There's thompson girl and christina
brzezinski's.
Uh,
your mom's house there accounts too
short a naughty chauvet.
Put it up later tonight.
It's amazing.
Okay.
And also,
um,
what was the other one?
Do you got?
Oh,
icehouse chronicles and the ice house
chronicles,
of course,
all of them free.
So thank you to the flashlight for
allowing us to keep all this shit for
fleet fruitfully property.
Go to joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for the flashlight
entering the code,
rogan getchell.
So alfred afternoon,
pushing off on ninth little dick toy.
And also thanks to onnit.com
o n n I,
t,
makers of alpha brain,
makers of shroom,
tech sport,
shroom,
tech,
immune and new mood,
the five htp supplement.
Thanks to everybody for tuning into this
podcast because,
uh,
without you guys,
it would be fucking strange.
World life has changed considerably for
all of us because of this podcast.
And,
uh,
we,
we put,
we put a voice out there that didn't
exist before,
you know,
and I,
I think for us,
and I think for you guys,
we found you guys and you guys found us
and uh,
who would have known,
right?
Who would have known to do it would've
been a podcast.
You know,
if have been an audience for a podcast
like this,
you know,
we,
most of the time thought they were just
a bunch of assholes sit arounD talking
about stupid shit while we're high.
Literally we know that the world is
filled with assholes that wanted to hear
that guy.
So,
uh,
it's awesome for us,
as muCh as it's awesome for you.
We love you All.
And thanks for tuning in and we'll see
you probably tomorrow.
I've got an idea for tomorrow and then
thursday too.