All right,
sweetie.
We live.
What's up?
Hey,
finally,
finally across the table from Joe Rogan
himself.
My pleasure,
man.
I watch a Netflix documentary today too.
It's great,
man.
It's intense.
Thank you very much.
That was when I first saw it.
I was like,
what is this going to be about?
But you get into it and you're like,
Whoa,
there's a lot going on in this
documentary.
There's big guys had more than fuck.
It's not just that.
It's like they just went,
they went deep into your life and to
everything.
The struggles to the heart condition,
the whole deal,
man.
It's,
yeah,
it's heavy.
It did a pretty good job.
Yeah.
So where are you staying now?
Like health wise?
Oh,
oh,
okay.
Um,
yeah.
Uh,
I fought my way back and just recently
this June,
uh,
had another set bag,
had no other major setback and a heart
attack out of the blue.
And I thought I was a gun,
right.
Again,
Joe,
but I'm still here.
So you had a heart attack.
They fixed your heart.
They put in an artificial valve and then
what happened with the second?
Okay.
Uh,
then that lasted for 12 years.
I had oh five,
I had the surgery to open heart surgery
actually passed away or flatline three
times during that surgery.
And then this past June I did the blue.
I'm thinking,
well it's not really out of the blue on
kind of had a few signs,
but I thought I,
you know,
I didn't think it was that serious.
I mean I had another heart attack
sitting on the counter at home and uh,
I thought I was gone for sure man.
Well,
what's confusing to a lot of people is
you're obviously this like intense
healthy guy and you're,
you're fit and you're lifting weights
and you're looking jacked.
Like is it a condition that you were
born with a genetic condition?
It is.
Most definitely hereditary.
My mother and all nine of her siblings
all passed away from heart related
problems and my mom had the chf lungs
and you know,
so many of them,
we have pastor 72 are,
my mom died at 63 they all passed away
and I will do now I'm 58.
And so you've gotten through two of them
so far?
Yeah.
So far.
And what did they do after the second
heart attack?
Well,
they,
they the,
the next thing I had a pacemaker
installed in a,
I got the already had metal valve and I
think they'd done just about all we can
do this or this one.
I got you down.
So they tell him next step is a
transplant
man.
That's intense.
Yeah.
But you know what,
Yo,
uh,
it's not so intense for me.
I think I have a,
um,
uh,
had bandage to somebody else who might
be getting the news.
Uh,
and the advantage is I've been through
so much already man,
until,
you know,
it's just,
and when you three times it ain't too
much else.
Can you know,
throw you for too many loops.
I got a lot of faith now.
Um,
so you,
are you in line for transplant now?
Is that how that works?
Yeah,
well it's a really long process,
Steve,
and get on the west.
So I'm going,
you know,
through that process.
Now I'm,
I'm,
I'm almost through lean,
uh,
but it's a really long process.
If they presented my case to the doctors
who perform,
asks for a transplant and they said that
I'm a good candidate and everything's
looking at right now,
except I may have a little throwback or
I had a a cancer biopsy yesterday and if
that's positive,
then that's going to hold me up a little
bit for heaven.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah.
No,
it's just crazy because when you look at
a guy like you and you know,
you look at you,
when you,
especially in you and your prime,
you think there's,
nothing's going to stop this guy.
Shit,
I didn't think so.
I mean,
I feel like your muscles are strong.
Your heart's a muscle shit.
His heart's got to be ridiculous.
Yeah,
I probably,
I thought I was indestructible.
Go,
but obviously I was wrong.
Well,
you pretty much,
I mean,
correct me if I'm wrong,
but you pretty much became famous from
the Internet right now.
Definitely launched it right there for
me,
man.
I ain't,
nobody knew who I was.
Do I got fit when I was 53 until I was
53 years or when I was world champion?
Nobody knew what gave a fuck about who
pretty much when I found out about it.
And you're like,
when you first started making youtube
videos,
that's when I found out about yet I
think someone on twitter sat me,
uh,
you know,
like people send me cool shit on twitter
all the time,
you know,
like,
and retweet it or I'll find out about it
and send it to other people.
And someone sent me some,
um,
well I've seen a bunch of your videos,
but one of them was you working out with
Tyron Woodley,
UFC welterweight champion.
And I was like,
Jesus Christ,
he's going to break them.
He got tired of doing all these crazy
super sets and all this different shit.
And so if you worked with a lot of MMA
fighters,
not a lot,
but a few and uh,
oh man.
Are we going to talk about the fake
feud?
That that wasn't an yeah,
we can talk about it,
but it didn't,
it wasn't a fake.
Oh man,
it really,
your light is killing me.
Oh yeah.
Keeps lighting your face.
I've got to talk about it and got to
talk about thought that we were really
upset at each other.
I was,
the debate was,
and this is a constant debate in mma,
whether big muscles in enhance you or
hurt you.
And My,
my take on it is they do both.
My take on it is the bigger the muscle,
the more power you have.
And I think tyron is a perfect example
of a guy who's figured out how to use
them perfectly.
Like what he does is he conserves as
energy and when he sprints you can't
stop him.
So like when he's in the,
in the cage and he has these moments of
explosion,
the amount of horsepower that he can
generate in a short period of time is
just above and beyond everybody else in
the division.
And it's a terrifying thing for
everybody in the division.
But he can't operate at the same pace
constantly.
Like some of the guys can't.
Some of the guys who have less muscle,
the cane around less mass,
they have a less oxygen requirements.
They can go longer,
but they just can't generate the same
kind of power.
But what tyrons figured out how to do
pretty brilliantly is how to conserve
his energy into these bursts.
And,
and then now,
like his big criticism earlier in his
career was that he would gas out as he
got into the later rounds,
but now he's able to fight five rounds.
No problem.
He just fights it at his pace.
Exactly.
But that's not exactly,
I want to start it with this two.
Okay.
Now,
uh,
for all the people,
all the people said that I would never
be able to sit down across the table
from Joe Rogan.
I want to take a special moment to say,
fuck Yo.
Right man.
Uh,
I'm here and I'm in.
I attacked Joe Rogan on the Internet.
I attacked him and I want to explore.
I got the opportunity to explain to you,
it's true.
I did attack Joe Rogan and I want,
I have the opportunity to explain to you
why exactly I did that.
Okay.
And I want to do that because I don't
want you to think I'm just an asshole.
No,
I didn't think you were an asshole at
all.
It didn't bother me at all.
Oh,
okay.
I didn't change my feelings.
I never attacked you back.
No.
So she,
you should did you,
but you know what you did do too,
but then I couldn't get you to do before
that was,
you've actually talked to me and tried
to talk to me.
I wanted to talk to you though that I
had people,
Eh,
uh,
you know,
cause I'm really cool with a lot of UFC
fighters and I said,
wow,
I wonder if he even knows him.
But they had people that was especially
set out to keep tagging you until you
were going to get you on the podcast.
So he knows that that shit does not
work.
That's the way to get on the podcast is
to get a bunch of people that,
oh my God,
the CCTC team who then we're going to
get you.
Hey Joe.
We won't tell our CTO and I,
you know,
my,
my response is always,
you know,
Joe,
he probably don't even know who the fuck
I am man.
Just,
you know,
quick tag him.
He don't,
he don't even know who the fuck I am.
Just quit tagging them.
Don't bother the man.
That was my,
uh,
you know,
response to them all the time.
All the time.
I just said,
look,
don't behind the Joe,
he's busy.
You don't know the fucking ham.
I'm not,
you know,
not in that league,
so don't even bother him.
And I said,
well,
you know what,
I got these fighters,
I know all these fighters and they
friendly with me.
I said,
maybe till do know who I am.
And I'm like,
you know,
after I made it,
you just don't like my ass.
So I see,
you know,
Tony Tyron Woodley thing came up and
they was talking about the muscular guy.
I said,
well,
you know,
here's my arm turns.
Hey Joe,
you don't know what the fuck you're
talking about.
And as soon as I could,
I said,
hey joe,
that motherfucker don't know what the
fuck he talking about.
Then you responded to,
I responded to you cause I like you.
Oh Wow.
Responding.
Yeah,
why?
I really didn't.
That's why I didn't attack you back.
I get why people,
he has a thing.
I get why people would think that I
don't respond because I don't like you.
I just can't keep up.
Oh Man.
I understand him.
I found out I have 1.6 million fake
followers though.
Oh Wow.
Apparently that's not a real,
a good measurement.
You know the,
the twitter audit,
it's just,
people don't use their account to tweet.
Maybe they just check twitter.
I Dunno.
I Dunno whether or not,
but I've never paid for any of the fake
ones.
They might be Russian bots.
I don't know what it is.
But um,
there's too many people.
I look at my mentions and,
and then at least 1% of them are
assholes so that you read one assholes
things like,
fuck this,
you put your phone down.
So it's,
it's not a matter of like me not liking
people.
It's a matter of me in it being in an
impossible situation.
There's no way I can keep up.
You're only one guy.
I am the only one guy.
I don't let anybody fuck with my
twitter.
Nobody's,
nobody's doing that.
That's all me.
So,
yeah,
so there's,
if you get a tweet from me,
it's from me.
Why don't I,
there's no way I can keep up with all of
them.
So people that try to talk to me and get
ahold of me,
if you think I'm ignoring you,
it's just I'm ignoring everything.
Yeah.
Well man,
Nah,
I don't feel so bad
that was in,
I wanted to kick to or tend to,
uh,
I was trying to get that.
That's what,
so that's why I came out with the attack
and,
and uh,
well it worked.
Yeah,
it did.
At least you got,
I was trying to be nice for as soon as
I'm going to ask.
So then he responded.
I said,
oh man.
okay Joe,
you're absolutely right.
I jumped over you.
I seen the jumped on you like that.
But we do,
um,
we do possess a little difference of
opinion on the muscle guy.
Yeah.
You deal.
So it's,
tell me what you think.
Okay.
Uh,
I was trying to explain that y'all never
know.
You have to have known guys like this
that are naturally,
naturally just more muscular.
Yes.
More built and they look like they lift
weights and work out,
but they don't write guys like,
you know,
I didn't know this guy,
uh,
Herschel Walker.
Sure.
Outstanding Athlete,
you know,
and uh,
both Jackson for example,
these guys,
fantastic athletes,
muscular,
very Muslim guys.
But I think if you were born,
born muscular,
there's a difference in the guy that
goes to me,
Jim and works out three,
four hours a day and adds muscle on.
He started out,
you know,
normal guy.
But if you were born with that muscle,
then you were born with the
cardiovascular system,
the lungs and what not to support that
muscle and it's,
yeah,
take it way,
way back to guys like Jim Thorpe.
Okay.
Uh,
head and shoulders above all the other
athletes of his error because he was
born that way.
So he was born.
The good Lord gives us the cardio system
in the lungs and everything to,
uh,
you know,
to go along with that extra they've,
we were born with in some cases,
in some cases.
Now.
I thought they were making a blanket
statement and it covered a lot of,
you know,
the all muscular guys aren't going to
tire out because of the extra muscle and
I disagreed because I think if they were
born with that muscle,
then they were born with the support
system to support it.
Demos.
I think there's a lot of logic to that.
I think it makes sense,
but I do think that if you have a
certain amount of muscle,
like there's just no way you are going
to be,
you're going to have the same
cardiovascular capabilities as someone
that's been like a marathon runner.
You're not going to have,
the marathon runner has.
There's advantages and disadvantages I
think to all sorts of body types,
especially when it comes to fighting.
There's a big advantage to be in
powerful,
scary look at you look at a guy like
Woodley and go,
oh shit.
You know,
like you know you can't stop him like
it.
The only thing that's going to stop him
as him getting tired or you've got to
catch him when he's coming in.
Right?
He's just faster than you.
Stronger than you.
So there's,
there's benefits to that.
But I think that when it comes to like,
there's no,
you never going to see a marathon runner
that's built like Woodley.
They just don't exist.
So even though he has the,
the cardiovascular system and the
support system that's designed for that
build that he's born with,
he still is never going to be able to
compete with like an elite triathlete
because your body has to be smaller.
You have to have less oxygen
requirements,
less weight that you're carrying around.
There's just no,
there's no way.
But there's benefits there.
Certain,
it's a real,
it's a real like balancing act,
I think at mma because you have to have
some muscle,
you have to be able to get guys off you,
you have to be able to get up from the
bottom.
You have to be able to explode.
You have to be able to close the
distance quickly.
There's a lot of like real benefits to
being powerful,
but then there's,
you know,
it's,
it's like,
uh,
it's a balancing act,
you know?
Yeah,
you're right.
Go.
Uh,
but,
um,
ah,
here we go.
It's not just muscle,
Eh,
you don't see,
um,
marathon runners did or you know,
250 pounds either.
They can be fat,
smooth butterball,
and,
and still,
you know,
uh,
not,
it's not because of the muscular
musculature that they,
you know,
just bigger guy period would have a hard
time being a marathon runner.
So the musculature,
that's where we have a little,
I don't think it's the,
the muscle trip because that
musculature,
if you're born,
if you're just born more muscular,
and if you can look at little kids in
grade school and you see some of the
kids are going to have a six pack,
they're going to just be built better
than the other kids.
And the,
and if fear,
if you're at that muscle,
you were born with that muscle,
in my opinion,
it's just my opinion,
Joe,
if you were born with that muscle and
that musculature,
it's not,
you know,
it,
it's not going to be detrimental in your
system is made for,
you know,
it's good little major system able to in
a bit.
But you're right,
you won't see,
uh,
anybody built like turn rhyme wouldn't
be running in the New York marathon or
winning the New York marathon.
He could run it.
But he was,
when you read that Oprah and me
like four hours and 20 minutes reading,
pretty fucking impressive to beat me.
Right.
But I think that uh,
uh,
that's just a bigger person period is
not how they're defined or the
definition that musculature,
you know,
I know boss route and I talked to her
boss route and a little bit about it and
I say,
man,
boss have built like a fucking statue
and shit.
And he goes,
oh,
and he was quick,
hey man,
but I don't lift weights.
And I said,
you're proving my point.
You're proving my point,
dude.
That's what I'm saying.
If you were born that way,
you didn't go in the gym and lift
weights.
I don't lift weight.
I don't like it proved my point,
but I see it.
Right.
You don't,
uh,
you know,
you didn't get that muscle from going to
the gym and pumping iron and get good.
You born that way and so,
well he was born that way,
but boss also does a tremendous amount
of plows,
like lot of explosive stuff like all of
his bag work.
You'll see boss hit the bag.
Oh my God man.
Oh man,
that dude is bad.
It's ferocious and everything he does,
he does like with a thousand percent
effort.
So you know his workouts,
like he would tell me that the way he
would work out was when he would prepare
for five minute round.
When he would start to get in shape,
he would go as hard as he could for like
a minute and then like be exhausted and
then he will work himself up to a minute
and a half.
Then worked himself up to two minutes
and then by the end of his training
camp,
he'd go five minutes full clip.
I'm like,
that's fucking crazy.
Method can work.
But in,
you know,
against that,
his boss,
his body started to deteriorate because
he's so God damn tough.
Like he has no cartilage in his knees.
His knees are completely shot.
He kept shooting cortisone and all of
his joints.
Like whenever you'd have injuries.
So it was,
joints are all fucked up.
He has got tendinitis everywhere.
It's just his mind was too strong for
like the vehicle that it was carrying
his mind around.
Wow.
Yeah.
Roche,
this dude,
this dude one.
Yeah.
The basketball time.
What do you think about Matt Hughes?
Ah,
I love Matt Hughes.
Okay.
How's he built like a tank if you've
ever seen them.
Gas?
Yeah.
Well now no,
but you know Matt Hughes in his day.
Let me see how to put this.
Like,
first of all,
he's not built like a tank.
Like maybe the way Woodley's belt is a
little bit,
a little bit more slight than Woodley
but still pretty God damn thick.
Um,
but also like what he was able to do too
was he was such a good wrestler.
He was able to dictate where the fight
takes place and a good wrestler can
control situations,
take guys down and then,
you know,
once you're on top,
like you get a break,
you know,
you can,
you could rest and then,
you know,
he would use his ground and pound and
submit.
Guys was one of the first guys ever too.
There was a high level wrestler that
started submitting dudes.
Yeah.
Submitted George.
Good.
Good friend of mine also built really
well.
Like a brick shit.
Another one and a cardio is pretty damn
good and I'm bad.
Yeah.
You make you make it my point
just,
I just think there's a,
there's requirements,
right?
And if you,
if you can get into a physical shape
where you can use those muscles,
uh,
the way you need to,
do you know what you need to do inside
the octagon.
I mean there's,
there's obviously a great benefit to
being Moscow.
Well,
I,
I think that,
uh,
guys there were naturally born like that
and I say,
I think Saint Pierre and he was both or,
I mean,
it wasn't a matter foreign boy.
Yeah.
I think those guys were born.
Sure.
Yeah.
And if you're born,
if you're born like that,
then I think,
you know,
but the guys are going to gym and put on
muscle.
They act,
the muscles are what they call bill.
I can't build muscle.
So
small hands.
Smaller frame.
Yeah.
The one he got that built muscle that
built muscle tires out real fast.
And I,
and I agree with you 100% on a guy that
has built most,
so they went into the gym comp time and
guidance muscles that way.
I agree with you 100% joey.
Absolute correct.
He's going to tire out those added on
muscles,
oxygen's going to suck the winner and
he's going to be tired as fucking no
time.
Uh,
you were of Francis and Ghana.
Oh yeah.
He's fighting this weekend and Francis
and got just broke the world record for
the most power ever shown in a punch.
They have this machine that they use
worldwide.
It's a widely accepted that there's like
one of the best ways to measure a punch.
It's,
it's this large pad and you hit it with
full power and it generates and Frances
and who beat the second place by some,
some insane amount of power.
I mean,
he's a ridiculously powerful dude.
He's,
he scares the shit out of everybody
here.
He is ready.
So they,
uh,
they show show this is this thing.
It shows what the original world record
was.
And then in Gando broke it by like 3000
pounds.
He's ridiculous.
He's terrifying.
You know,
they found this dude,
he was a homeless guy.
If he was home,
he was homeless living in France.
And uh,
he made his way into a gym and I believe
he wanted to box and when they brought
him in,
so I guess is see 129,000,
161 units.
The previous one was 114,000.
Like what tyrone spot?
Who's a beast.
And uh,
so frances and Gannon,
who's fighting this weekend,
who is fighting?
Alistair overeem is another,
so fantastic,
funny predicts chaos.
That's the same Dick Chaos.
Good for dig suit right there.
Yeah.
I mean
I don't,
we were talking,
I was talking about this on my a Lma
podcast that Alistair's been stopped I
think in mma.
MMA.
He's been stopped at least 11 times and
I think he's been stopped three or four
times in kickboxing as well.
There's like 14 Kaos plus knocked out in
his career,
either Tko or knocked out.
Like,
that's the guy that's got to be worried
about getting hit by the guy who got the
world record punch.
Yeah.
It's,
it's going to be a youth and exuberance
versus the experience craftiness.
Yeah,
sure.
Yeah.
That's what it's going to be.
Consequences of allister getting hit
though are so brave and Ghana was so
terrible.
Yeah.
It's you thing,
I mean,
yeah,
it has to be able to use,
they're pretty good.
Yeah.
It's very interesting.
Ghana was supposed to fight junior dos
Santos at one point,
which was also really interesting fight.
But I think the Alistair overeem fight
is more dangerous for him,
but also it's going to let everybody
know because Alistair's at the top of
the heap and the heavyweight division
right in Ghana can get by ouster most
likely he'll get a shot at the title
very soon.
Right.
So what do you think his ground game?
Well,
we don't know too much about it.
He submitted one guy in the octagon and
you know,
we know that he does have submission
skills.
He was one fight by submission,
I think Anthony Hamilton.
But I think,
uh,
you know,
he's for first of all,
every fight starts standing up,
you know,
you gotta get through hell to get that
guy to the gown,
good luck,
you know,
and he's been taken down before and
survived and came back to knock the guy
out.
So,
and he's also,
you know,
still learning and growing.
I mean,
he just started really,
you pretty much only been doing it for a
few years.
He's terrifying.
Yeah.
Well,
you know what I think he represents,
I think he represents a real world class
athlete that's fighting and mma,
whereas like,
maybe that guy would have gone to
football or somewhere else in another
era for sure.
But now that MMA is,
you know,
it's like I said the same thing about
Jon Jones.
Jon Jones I think could have done
anything,
but John Jones got into mma and you see
what happens when you see a real world
class half?
Oh Man.
Dang,
Dang good.
Uh,
I like John and I got to meet him a few
times and he told me that he listens to
me before he goes out.
And,
uh,
you know,
before it goes out and fight.
And I was a real honor for him to say
that.
Yeah.
He likes to say I am the one speech that
I did and he always used to say it along
Whitney Cpa,
we were staying in there and gail and in
his phone
and he goes out and kills people like he
does.
He's a murderer man.
Yeah.
I hope he,
I hope he sorts all his problems out.
I don't know what's,
what the fuck's going on with this
recent positive drug test.
So we'll see.
It seems like the only guy that can beat
Jon Jones.
Jon Jones used to say about Tyson.
It's true.
It was true.
It's,
you won all of your world records drug
free.
Yeah.
Yeah,
100% a drug free.
Uh,
I a Jug free for 37,
38 years.
But I did try,
I did try roids uh,
in 1980 or 81,
I believe it was before it became
illegal.
I tried.
What'd you try?
I try and I went to a doctor and I don't
know if I should say this fucker's name
cause he might still be in business,
still vying for the same doctor that
Arnold and uh,
uh,
all the guys who were in the magazines,
you know,
I thought everybody was drug free.
I didn't think,
you know,
I didn't think nobody talks.
It's a weird thing about those
magazines,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Oh fucking man.
I couldn't wait before I get,
some of them are meeting her ass shit,
man.
So they got me for sewer.
That's what he was taking about.
Uh,
uh,
I want to a couple of little contest and
a guy,
uh,
the guy who was promoting the contest,
he came to me and said,
hey,
what are you taking?
Ct and a half,
28 arms,
you know,
then I didn't,
I thought everybody had thought every
fucking by not seen those magazines or
on or anybody else was drug free.
He goes,
what are you taking?
And I told him to me going to ask us and
shit.
And he goes,
Oh man,
what,
what kind of steroids are you taking?
I said,
what's that?
And he said,
you don't know what a stair radius.
You didn't even know what,
I don't even know what the fuck he was,
man from Canton.
He told me,
you know,
you gotta go to this doctor.
And uh,
and uh,
gave me the address and everything and
he said,
I don't know if I'd say the doctor's
name,
but I still remember.
And,
uh,
I went to the dining thing.
Guy Looked at my nose and ears and shit
and listen to my lungs and gave me a
prescription for,
uh,
decker.
Yeah.
It gave me a prescription for some
decades to Rovelyn.
And I took it right.
The Kaiser Pharmacy and a pharmacist.
Uh,
I said,
you know,
what they see is,
and I said,
yes,
fucking steroids are thinking.
He said,
yeah,
it's bad.
You don't need this shit.
You know what?
Look,
I want to give you,
try it.
I want to be a professional body
building.
They told me if I want to be a
professional and be like Arno and
Franklin Reza Guy,
I gotta take this shit so I want to take
it.
And he gave,
he gave it to me.
We are judging me.
You get fifth wheel prescriptive where I
took it home and I take my deck then and
then,
uh,
went back to doctor [inaudible] and he
gave me no picture for testosterone.
So I took Deca and testosterone.
And did you notice a difference?
Fuck yes.
I know that the different I got off of
it.
Yeah,
I got off of it,
but I had a,
I had realized I had reasons and you
won't judge Jv with those words.
Sure.
Okay.
It worked.
It definitely worked.
Uh,
I got fucking hard.
It's,
you know,
just tight as fuck.
And uh,
but,
uh,
I also,
I don't know if it does,
it does this to everyone.
People,
when I told him,
I tell him about this sometimes and know
it's you,
you must've been an ass hole beforehand.
And that's quite,
quite possibly true because I was a
pretty much an asshole because the way I
was raised,
you know,
I had a bad attitude going in.
So when I got on scene it and it seemed
to amplify my bad attitude and every
matter a short fuse like this is a
fighter.
UFC fighting him short shortfuse yeah,
yeah.
Well I should have had that nickname way
before.
Head hurt me man.
Cause I had fucking short fuse big time
and everything.
Everything pissed me off.
So I had a really bad attitude.
I was married at the time,
you know,
I had a real bad attitude and my wife
and she couldn't do shit wrong,
you know,
I mean nothing man and but okay that,
that was part of it.
Another big,
big fucking thing with me is what I love
more than muscles and lifting weights
and fast cars and I love all that shit.
It's sex and a big giant,
big old giant.
Why rolled over to have sex and nothing
was happening.
I said fuck these steroids.
When he got off of them,
he told me,
it was like,
oh you got to take this,
this other shit to make this five dead.
Anything,
Joe,
anything boners
fuck it.
Fuck it.
Oh No,
no,
it ain't,
nothing is going to do.
And I'd rather be 110 pounds soaking wet
and still be able to,
you know,
get my boner,
uh,
fuck that,
you know,
so there must have the effect of you're
lifting too because what comes is just a
giant dip and your natural testosterone
when she get off of it.
Oh.
Oh,
it's bad.
Huh?
It was the,
because I,
you know,
I decided,
hey,
I'm out.
Fuck this shit.
Fuck this shit what you want for a total
of six months.
But what they do is they told us back
then you do two months on,
two months off.
So it took longer.
So I do two months,
it'll take two months off,
two months on two months.
That was the protocol.
Yeah,
that's,
that's what they told us.
That's what doctor man,
man,
whatever his name is,
uh,
talks how to do.
So it was told six months,
but it took longer than,
because they had two months off in
between two months.
And,
um,
uh,
that stuff it fucking definitely,
definitely.
Uh,
w what they don't tell you is when you
stop taking it and shit and we just
stopped taking it cold Turkey like that
every fucking thing that you gained
during that time.
And I gained,
you know,
I was ready for,
I had one like little small,
the Boone County,
cause I thought I was ready for fucking
Mister America after this shit.
You know,
I'm like Oh fuck I'm,
I just got so much tighter and I had a
more veins and shit than ever and I'm
like,
Oh man,
this is great shit.
But when you get off they see everything
that you came,
you lose it.
And then some I lost any strength gains
that I might've might've gang got from
it or any,
you know,
the harness at me.
I had to start from lower than where I
was before I started taking it.
They say you do gain something and you
keep something once your body
normalizes,
you know,
you do have some sort of gains.
That's one of the arguments that they
say about people that have taken
steroids and gotten off of them,
that if you can normalize your
testosterone,
you're still gonna have an advantage of
where people that have never taken it
before.
Genuine.
I don't know how true that is.
I felt like that,
uh,
every single thing game than I possibly
can.
I think I,
I mean I felt like I lost ground
actually.
Uh,
cause I just stopped cold Turkey and I
think I actually lost Brown.
It's still supposed to wean yourself off
and stuff.
But,
you know,
but I'm telling me when I roll over,
I'm fucking 21 years old and I thought
that sex every day was the normal.
Right.
I mean you,
you,
you just,
that's what you get married for sex
every day,
man.
That's one of the benefits.
And if I don't,
if I can't have sex every day,
then you know something's wrong.
Right?
Yeah.
Like this,
you know,
so I just,
that was my normal normal thing.
And I'm probably pretty sure that my
wife,
who at the time probably didn't think
that,
but I was like,
she's probably got tired.
We this motherfucker that was a,
she had a break when the steroid things,
we got a little break for the first time
ever,
you know who was married.
Like you know,
like,
oh no,
no,
no.
Anything that's going to fuck with that.
But that's what gets people back on it a
lot.
Yeah.
You couldn't get psychologically
addicted,
of course.
I mean,
uh,
who,
I mean,
you,
Jack and I talked about it,
you know,
and I was,
I was interviewed and magazine articles
and stuff a few times when I was world
champion back Lena.
I brought it up in the Arctic cause I
never thought it was anything that high,
you know,
or anything like that.
I said,
yeah,
you know,
I,
I wish that I had never done it.
I wish I could say now we got it from
the were saying,
I can say I have,
I have a perfectly clean record.
Like my,
my training partner,
Richard Sherman,
were for 20.
We've trained together for 20 years.
And this guy,
perfect record,
never even tried it.
Well,
he was stronger than me.
He was,
his mind was stronger than my eye.
Peer pressure and wanting to be in the
magazines and wanting to make a living,
doing something that I love is did a
punch in the clock every fucking day.
That that appeal too great for me as a
young guy for me to pass it up.
I wanted to do something that I love and
make money at it way back then.
But I wind up working at the Post Office
for 28 years.
Well,
it makes sense.
I mean,
it,
it definitely makes sense that the
appeal would be so strong.
And so it's a very,
it works.
I mean,
that's the big reason why people want to
take it out of sports.
And I don't know if he ever watched that
documentary that's on Netflix called
ICARUS.
Have you seen that?
No,
I haven't seen incremental.
ICARES is all about the Russian,
uh,
anti-doping state sponsored program.
The Russian,
well,
I should say pro doping.
Oh,
Yay.
You go ahead early.
Give steroids to every single one of
their athletes.
It's a crazy documentary man because the
guy,
Bryan Fogel,
who's the director is also,
he's in it because he was an amateur
cyclist and what he wanted to do as an
experiment.
So he ran it or he cycled this race one
year,
totally clean,
and then the next year he went to this
Russian doctrine,
said just fucking juice me up to the
gills.
Like let's do this.
And they just shot him up with
everything.
And in the process of him getting to
know this doctor,
the scandal broke out about the Sochi
Olympics,
about the Russians cheated during the
Sochi Olympics.
And it's all documented in this film as
the news is breaking.
And then the guy who's the Russian
doctor has to flee Russia.
He leaves his family behind,
they take his family's house and they
take all their money and they're
basically making this family homeless to
try to get him to come back to Russia.
He's in protective custody and America
right now.
And he detailed the entire program.
Everyone was hot.
Everyone,
everyone was on something.
They want 13 g.
What's hilarious?
They just took some of the metals away
and the metals they took with the most
bullshit metals like gymnastics who can
have this one.
Like they took like four bullshit metals
away,
but they kept the big real,
yeah.
They kept wrestling.
They kept all the big ones.
It's bullshit.
Indeed.
I did see big,
strong fast.
Um,
uh,
that's crazy.
They take yeah.
Right.
Because they're pro steroids.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
That is interesting.
Pro Steroids and a lot of people are,
yeah.
Well the,
the argument is,
I mean,
uh,
see,
I see it in the terms of fair
competition.
I see the argument against it for fair
That makes sense.
But like,
I also see the argument in terms of
like,
if you're going to be taken amino acids
and creatine and all these different
things that do give you some sort of a
benefit,
why don't I take the shit that gives you
the real benefit?
Well,
I,
you know,
uh,
I,
I don't find a fault with people who
would be side too to take roids because
like I said,
I'm 21 year old kid and uh,
I took,
so how the fuck can I talk shit about
anybody who's,
who decides to make the same decision
that I,
that many years ago,
you know,
I,
I be a hypocrite asshole if I was,
you know,
to do that as long as everybody in the
competition that you're in,
whatever that competition might be,
if you fucking flipping pies or
whatever,
whatever the fuck it is,
a tech and grab whatever fuck it is.
If everybody else is doing it then,
then it's a level playing field that,
but when you got guys that are trying to
compete naturally,
right against guys that are not,
then it becomes unfair.
So,
uh,
if they,
if they have a division and they do it
in a lot in these weight lifting contest
and things,
now they have divisions that are called
natural divisions and they actually test
for steroids and stuff like that.
And maybe they should do something like
that for the fighters to,
hey,
we ain't going to text you guys if you
want fuckers.
He just come on in here and whatever you
bring,
bring what you got.
Yeah,
we're kind of doing that in Japan.
Really?
Yeah.
Japan has an organization called
[inaudible] where it's essentially an
offshoot of pride or at least some of
the people are involved.
It that were involved in pride and
pride.
Like I had ensign anyway on the podcast
and he was talking about his pride
contract.
He said,
it's specifically stated we will not
test you for steroids in all caps and
shit.
Some fucking animals.
I was it a lot of ways and a lot of
people's eyes.
That was the golden age of MMA.
He's just in terms of just sheer
performance.
Oh man,
you gotta wonder like all those guys
like fader and Cro cop and all those
guys in their prime,
like how much shit were they on?
Were they on things?
I mean,
nobody wants to talk about it.
Yeah,
that's in the Goddamn in the contract.
I was just back then,
you know,
maybe they
possibly we're for half.
And then you know,
when people want to say it like fate or
who most people think is like the
greatest heavyweight of all time,
or at least it's an argument,
right?
He,
he was real good friends with Putin who
is at the head of the Russian doping
state sponsored doping program.
Like what are the odds that they just
let him compete clean?
Like what are the odds that didn't juice
them up,
but they're not testing you?
I,
you know,
I don't know.
He didn't have a steroid by it though.
Well,
you say that,
but in the early days,
he sure as fuck did.
Really?
Yeah.
And you pull up that picture of a,
of a fade or with the kettle bells was a
famous picture of him.
He was a big proponent of,
I mean,
he didn't lift weights per se.
He did like Kettlebell exercises,
which are weight,
not like,
you know,
bench press.
Right.
That kind of shit and curls.
He did a lot of,
um,
pliers and a lot of,
uh,
explosive,
strength training exercises and things
on that.
But this,
when you still get this picture,
like he was pretty fucking jacked
anyway.
We definitely knock your fucking head.
Oh,
he's an animal.
Looks like a power with,
yeah,
exactly.
He was built and then there's early
fights.
He was very built and then later in his
career there's was a lot of things going
on later in his career.
But it seems like when he came to
America,
one of the first he did,
if I,
if he was ever on anything before,
he wasn't on it when he came to America
because it looks like you also stopped
weight training and only concentrated on
sports specific exercises,
which a lot of people disagree with.
Some people say that you have to have
some kind of weight training,
you have to have some sort of strength
and conditioning program.
Right.
I W I w you know,
of course I'm from that background,
I would say yes.
Yeah,
I would agree with that.
I think so too.
I think you need both.
Um,
and I think you certainly need skill.
That's the most important thing.
But in order to really highlight that
skill,
you've got to have that body up to full
potential.
You gotta be peaking.
You gotta be ready to rock and roll my
boy man,
Maitri Maitri own mountain or those.
Yeah,
that's a huge feather in his cap.
And it's my buddy.
I love that guy.
He's hilarious.
Funny,
funny,
funny dude.
You gather and you got to know him even
better.
And we had been talking and shit.
And I get to talk to a lot of a lot of
fighters.
Man.
I really,
when you're an inspirational dude,
you know people like you.
Yeah.
You know I'm just blessed man.
I,
I tell you what do I have no idea why
that you know,
the first video I did for you to the
strong man ain't never heard of.
I don't know why people watched it.
I'll tell you why.
Cause cause it's fuel.
Everybody who wants to do something in
their life has ups and downs and we need
fuel.
Like,
I'll tell you,
I got some fuel today.
When you were in front of those kids and
Compton and you were talking to them
about obsession being a good thing.
If you want to be great at anything,
I wanted to shut that fucking tv off and
go run the hill.
Man.
Fuel like that is important for people.
Like seeing someone like you get fired
up and talk about things.
It energizes the people that are
watching.
Like every time he put out one of those
youtube videos and a million people
watch it.
How many of those million people engaged
in an activity that maybe they weren't
gonna do that day?
How many of them went to the gym when
they weren't going to go to the gym?
How many of them just decided to get
their fucking career in order to get
their life in order to just get their
shit together when they maybe weren't
like,
we need each other.
People need each other.
Yeah,
in a weird way.
Then people need people like you.
You know what's the reason why I
surprised with drugs?
Because I told him right in the video,
if you don't like what I'm saying,
turned to my fuck off.
Perfect.
You don't fucking,
I don't care.
Look,
I didn't even,
I didn't know that they paid you.
You know,
they do too.
And I was broke as fuck.
Anyway,
I was walking back and forth to the gym
to train people.
I didn't happen.
I was a horrible personal trainer.
People would come,
you know,
uh,
I,
first of all,
I went to try and get a job as a
personal trainer,
a lot of different gyms.
And they would ask me if I had my
certificate and I said,
look,
I'm a six time world champion.
I don't need a fucking certificate.
I know how to lift weights.
And they'd,
Oh yes,
you do my fucking,
if you don't got this certificate,
get on.
You know,
I would leave on my little,
my little plaques and Shit under my arm,
you know,
and I got,
I got turned down a bunch of time and
they finally,
I went to a hardcore gym and say,
Hey,
you ct Fletcher.
Yeah,
yeah man.
Hey,
we know,
you know I had to go to,
but I went to these changing,
so when who turned me down?
Fuck it.
Yeah.
Oh No.
And I had,
I was the right side of the harbor first
shitty breaking those pictures.
Oh my God.
They come in and they'd say,
Hey,
at one session,
one session,
they pay me for a month,
but they trade one time with me and
they're like,
hey,
no,
hey if you no pussy,
fuck pussy out that fucking fast.
Take your fucking ass back home.
Here's your money.
Take your fucking money.
And I needed that fucking money to Joe.
I needed it.
Bad Man.
Like I said,
I was walking,
uh,
cause when I had my heart can you,
I used up all my sick leave and stuff.
I working at the post doc,
I can use it for all the sick leave and,
and uh,
they let me go.
They let me go from it and he thinks you
can't get let go from a government job
is bullshit.
The Kid,
I'm gonna live in exams.
So they let you go because you're sick.
Well,
I used up all my sick leave and
everything.
I had a rough recovery.
The recovery was rubbed.
So I,
I stayed out too long.
They gave me so much and I stayed out
too long.
My son sick,
sick week was all worn out in it and
they actually let me go.
Uh,
but before he let me go,
they granted me a full,
you know,
um,
health,
uh,
health related.
Um,
they gave it to me.
So for a year and yeah,
everything for a year and then
unexplained to be the same doctor who
granted it to me,
which was their doctor,
took it away a year later.
So a year later broke as fuck,
I don't got no time and I've got no
benefits after working for 28 years
there.
I don't got no kind of retirement,
no nothing.
So I'm walking around,
that's what I'm trying to get a personal
training job and walked around town and
get person training.
I mean,
they find me,
gave me one at a hardcore gym and gave
me a,
uh,
a personal training job.
And then like I said,
I didn't have very many clients at all.
The guys that had called the original
iron addicts.
So the guys that stuck with me and uh,
you know,
even I put him through hell,
they liked it.
They come back for more.
They can,
those are the guys that I call the
original iron addicts.
Yeah.
There's some people that are just not
going to have the mental fortitude for
that.
But you are,
you're,
that's like for someone starting out.
It's kind of crazy.
Tony.
You,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
I'm definitely not for the,
again,
you know the average guy.
No,
no,
you didn't.
I mean,
and
what you were saying to those kids is
very important.
Like there's a difference between the
kind of effort and focus that you want
to put in in order to get yourself fit.
I just want to be in good shape.
I just want to be able to do 10 pushups
and 10 chin ups and normal shit.
There's a difference between that person
and the type of person that's going to
seek out excellence.
It's,
that person's going to go to a guy like
you and go,
I just want every day to give 100% I
want to drain myself on that bench.
I want to drain myself at that squat
rack.
I want to have nothing left when I leave
here.
Can you do that?
Most people,
most people know it.
Sounds good.
Fuck that.
After like three weeks of that fucking
joints,
her aiken and your,
your body's
falling apart.
No.
Fuck.
You see them keep the money.
Me and sometimes,
I mean it would show at once and I
didn't see him no more.
No explanation.
No.
They need even say one person told me to
go into the bathroom.
I never seen him no more.
I'm going to bathroom fucking coming
back.
Did you get a lot of injuries when you
were training?
Um,
no.
I was lucky in the,
in that,
you know,
my first career as a power lifter,
I didn't get injured and ever had any
injuries and I didn't,
you know,
wrap up or really,
really crazy.
I had a cracked bones.
My bones are really strong and tendons,
no shoulder problems,
shoulder problems.
Wow.
That's an even Dorian that Dorian Yates
is all fucked up now.
I had him on the podcast and one of his
arms is just jacked.
He can't do pushups anymore.
It's shoulders all fucked up and all the
connective tissues torn off the bone and
just,
yeah,
it's amazing that you don't mean you
must have an excellent genetics in
tonight.
Yeah,
that's,
that's the,
uh,
that's what I created to,
exactly.
It's just to do genetics.
Uh,
you know,
as much as my dad,
I don't,
I hated them growing up.
I got a credit buddy fletcher for that
man I hated to do growing up.
John.
Really good.
That was a big part of your documentary,
man.
That was intense.
You know,
when you,
uh,
were told that story about getting a gun
because a,
you were supposed to go and apologize to
the teacher because you had said
something to teacher.
You're like,
you were disagreeing about evolution and
your father got mad at you and said,
you're going to go apologize to the
teacher,
but the teacher was sick.
Yeah.
And you didn't even get a chance to say
no,
she was sick,
you just said no,
and he broke her nose like that.
That's a heart wrenching story as a
father.
Yeah.
That's buddy fluxes rule right there,
man.
I mean,
he tell you to do something Goddamn to
bear to do.
Yeah.
So when I,
when I went there after,
you know,
growing up like that,
I was,
uh,
I grew up,
in fear.
Yeah.
I was afraid of my dad all the time.
And uh,
but growing up with in the buddy
Fletcher's household when I went into
the military was a piece of cake.
I was used to it.
I was already used to guest sir.
No Sir.
Standing at attention and saluted and
shit and doing impossible shit or
whatever you asked me to fucking do.
I was already used to it.
So the army was,
you know,
ah,
shit already been doing.
Every guy's crying and shit.
I been doing this my whole fucking life.
No.
How did you get on Youtube?
Oh,
a guy came into the team into the gym,
uh,
and he said that his name was,
arrives,
Babu,
I got to give a Ross credit for that.
He was a strength project and he had a
big following already on a youtube.
He said,
Hey,
can I interview you,
uh,
for you to,
I don't know what the fuck is you to?
And he said,
uh,
well,
it's just a social media thing.
And I,
I'm,
I,
I have one question.
Can I say whatever the fuck I want to
say?
And he said,
yeah,
you can say whatever the fuck you want.
I said,
can I cuss and say yes,
cuts all you want to.
I said,
fuck it.
It's,
um,
that's cool.
Yeah,
Guy,
man.
It,
think about how that works.
I like one thing leads to all these
other things like that guy coming in and
talking to you,
led to you inspiring countless millions
of people.
Yeah.
Crazy.
It is absolutely crazy.
I never thought,
I never thought in a million years,
you know,
that something like that would happen.
I never did.
You know,
I always wanted as a kid.
It's funny,
I want it to,
uh,
inspire people because my dad was a
preacher.
He was a Korean War vet,
uh,
and a preacher.
So,
uh,
I grew up soup in a super religious
household,
super religious,
everything was the same.
Every fucking thing was the scenes or
you couldn't do shit,
you know,
dating girls.
I was saying going to the movies,
ever seen,
listen to whatever kind of music that
wasn't gospel music.
It was a sin.
I think I'm telling you it was,
everything was a fucking saying.
So,
uh,
but you know,
Buddy Fletcher is,
you know,
I recently,
since this last heart attack,
I recently went to him,
I was waiting for 58 years to hear an
apology from him that was never going to
come and eat meat up,
toast,
tearing me to fucking pieces,
man.
Because I would,
you know,
being an old dude,
I would wake up at night punching and
kicking and shit and I'm still fighting
buddy fletcher at 56,
57 years old.
I'm still fighting this dude cause I'm
still carried around this hate.
I hated him,
but it was okay cause the hate was
neutral.
I don't think I just hated him.
He didn't hate me.
He told me he got what?
He got up in church and he made an
announcement.
He said,
hey look,
I know what it is.
Um,
between that sign,
which was me and pointed me that,
that sign right there and he,
I can get on with the rest of,
you know,
my other brothers.
No,
no problem buddy.
He hated me and he says,
because he's so much like me.
That's why I hate him.
And went to know that.
That's why we can't get along.
I hate you because you're so much like
me.
She's,
yeah.
So I was like,
Hey,
no problem.
I hate your ass too.
She has never worked it out.
Oh yes we did.
We did.
But it was,
uh,
have you seen the movie?
I hadn't had,
it wasn't worked out during the movie.
I still didn't like him during
the movies.
They asked him,
they asked him why.
Do you have any recollections of,
when you see t growing up,
when his childhood,
do you have any fond recollections of
you and cte?
You know,
as a kid and out boy,
I was looking at them jobs waiting now
where I really,
I really want to hear if he was going to
fabricate something right?
Because I didn't have man.
And I'm like,
oh,
I want to be with this motherfucker
going to say to this questionnaire and
he didn't have anything.
And I was like,
okay,
cool.
You know,
but I was ready to stop the fucking
movie and just make an ass out of
myself.
And like,
no,
you're,
that's bull shit.
We ain't got you ain't one fucking time
that we ever did anything pleasurable
together.
Motherfucker.
And I was ready to go off,
but he didn't have any.
So when he didn't have any fines,
okay.
Now that's the same recollection that I
have,
but I really didn't forgive him until
his last heart attack in June.
And what happened then when I had the
heart attack in June and it seemed like,
uh,
a revelation came to me and he was like,
I'm,
it's not hurting him.
It's not hurting him at all.
My Dad is 86 years old.
He's fine,
man.
He,
he's,
he's good.
I don't,
he's like,
well,
you know,
I don't think he thinks that he has
anything to be sorry for that.
I think he thinks he's,
he's done a fantastic job of raising me.
And uh,
I was just waiting on a policy that was
never going to come,
but,
but it was still that hate that I had
for him was eating me up.
I had to get that burden off me and I
think having that last harder,
I didn't want to die carrying that
burden with me of hating my dad.
So I went to my dad and I asked him to
forgive me.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Damn.
How did you say that?
What did you,
what did you say?
I said,
you know,
looked at,
I have blamed you.
I told him that I had recently had a
heart attack and I have blamed you my
entire life for a whole lot of things
that went bad or when you know that
always,
you know,
blames you fix and,
and I'm sorry.
Uh,
you know,
I don't,
I don't want to blame me for that
anymore.
And would you please forgive me for
carrying this against you from,
you know,
my whole life.
I don't want to die,
you know,
letting you think that,
I love you man,
and I want you to know that.
Wow.
Yeah.
How good does that feel?
I can't,
I don't wake up punching and shit
anymore.
I probably be out of breath if I did it
anyway,
but I don't wake up with those night.
Why haven't had that nightmare since
then?
Wow.
Yeah.
How did he react to that?
He was,
he was a fully accepting of my ipod.
He graced me or he was graciously
accepted.
My apology.
So,
so do you communicate regularly?
No.
No,
no.
Still don't.
Still don't communicate regularly.
I just really wanted to,
uh,
you know,
get that off my chest.
Released the birds.
Yeah.
I just really wanted to get that off my
chest and
get the release that burden and uh,
you know,
uh,
I probably,
try to communicate more after I get this
new heart.
You know,
it's,
it's Kinda fucked up,
but in a way,
and I don't know why this is,
but sometimes people that have gone
through terrible childhoods,
they wreck.
Recognize what it means to be a good
father.
Oh No,
I see you with your kids.
I see it in the documentary and I,
and I see how your kids are around you,
right?
Yeah.
I think they came and they were like,
shit,
they want to meet Joe Rogan too.
But uh,
yeah,
I have a super,
super tight.
I made,
you know,
I want to make sure that was,
if somebody asks my kid,
you know,
uh,
20 years from now,
what,
do you have any fine memories of your
dad and your child and how you go?
I want to make sure that they got plenty
of fucking fine memories.
You know,
they can say,
you know,
my dad was my dad,
we did this together and my dad was,
he was loved me to death.
I never had one doubt in my mind.
My Dad loved the shit out of me.
I don't want my kids grow up,
you know,
like I get,
so I put four for extra African.
Makes sure that's,
you know,
that's not going to happen.
So in some sort of way it turned out to
be positive because you're such a doting
father.
You're so,
you're so into it.
I mean,
so obvious that it's like you,
the,
the negative consequences of how your
dad treated you.
Like it came out of you the opposite
way.
Yeah.
I made it,
I made it up fucking point man.
Cause this is miserable on their kid.
But,
but also John,
you know what good came out of that?
Uh,
the childhood that I,
the kind of time that I went through,
I get in,
I'm sure what I get is just a 10th of
what you get,
but it's so many thousand thousand
people that contact me and tell me,
hey man,
my dad,
you know,
I had a fucked up childhood and I,
and I see how you were able to come out
of that or some kids,
kids contact me now that I'm going
through a fucked up childhood ct and,
and because you made it because you
will.
So that when I looked back and I used to
think,
why did I have to go through this?
Why did I have to have such a fucked up
time?
It's because of that,
because I can talk about my childhood
and it helps so many other people,
so many other kids in the go.
All Joe,
I look back on it now and I said it was
so worth it that it wasn't even finding
me.
It's so worth it.
Everything that I had to go through.
I wanting to hide every time I heard my
dad's keys in the door,
wanting to just,
you know,
run away from fucking home warranty.
I hated,
hated my child,
but it was so worth it.
Everything was so worth it.
Just being able to help one kid who
might be going through the same thing,
it's so fucking worth that counted as a
blessing.
It was just the place,
right?
That right there,
that attitude.
This is reason why people attracted to
you because you really do like helping
people like you really do.
You're happy that you suffered so that
you can help other people.
That is one of the reasons why people
are so attracted to you.
Wow.
Yeah,
I guess,
but after I tell him,
you know,
hey,
look,
turn me to fuck off.
You're just trying to weed out the weak.
I mean,
and weed out the payments.
Not even the week.
It's the people that aren't willing to
take the leap.
Like you can't have any excuses.
It's like the excuses are a real problem
with people.
Oh my God,
it's a real problem because you give
yourself a way out,
like you can fail at things,
so you could try and not be able to do
it,
but the excuses for why you can't do it
or why you're going to fail or why you
don't feel up to it today or why you're
tired or why you have other things on
your mind while you have others.
Things you have to deal with first
before you can start working out.
That's all bullshit.
Oh yeah.
And I told him,
yeah,
he did tell them they needed to hear it.
They need to hear that shit.
You need to hear it.
Because they create their own
boundaries.
They create their own borders to create
their own obstacles.
They create their own things that cannot
be surpassed,
and they'll,
all those things are just products of
the mind.
And it's just the ego protecting you
from failure,
from protecting you from that horrible
feeling that you need to experience in
order to move forward.
If you want to move forward,
you got to experience some falls.
You got it slip,
you got to fall down.
You gotta get back up,
you got to,
you got to try and fail because if you
don't fail,
that means you weren't trying hard
enough because nobody just fucking
excellent in everything all the time.
All the time.
It's impossible.
Good person.
That means that one point in your life
you fucked up.
Yeah.
You figured out how to be a better
person.
There's no other way around it.
There's no,
no one's just great from the womb.
No,
I mean,
unless you're the Dalai Lama or Buddha
or some shit,
no one is great from the womb at
anything as correct.
It'll be 34 yeah.
Or Buddy fuck being a human being,
an athlete,
being a whatever,
a doctor or whatever the fuck you are
trying to do,
you're going to,
if it's difficult to do,
you're gonna fuck up along the way.
And some people can't handle the fuck
up.
They can't handle it.
So they don't even try.
They don't even try it.
They can't,
they can't.
Oh,
it's my thyroid.
It's all,
it's,
you know,
I just,
I have a problem with my metabolism or
Oh,
you know,
uh,
I,
I have a chronic fatigue syndromes.
It,
it just fucking get up and go.
Just one foot in front of the other.
Keep moving.
Just keep moving tomorrow.
Do more.
Can I get up in the morning?
All the alarm clock.
That means you get up.
Do you know,
do you get the fuck up?
No.
That.
Press that button.
Get the fuck up and go.
And if you don't have an out,
if it's impossible to not get the fuck
up and go,
then you just do it.
So just don't allow that other part.
Don't allow that.
I'm going to hit the snooze button.
Fucking snooze button is the worst shit
that's ever been invented.
Do you really feel better after nine
minutes?
That shit doesn't do you any good.
Get up bitch.
Get up,
get up,
get your fucking ass up out there.
Got Goddamn bed you,
you shouldn't do.
That's one thing.
Here's a,
here's a business view.
He should do ringtones,
ringtones and,
and alarms.
An alarm,
a ct fletcher alarm every morning where
it goes instead of beep,
beep,
beep.
Just you saying
just fucking ass out of bed.
I don't,
we hear no excuses.
You know what,
there's I do something similar to that.
Yeah.
I be cussing people out my whole life
for method and it got this thing,
a book cameo,
iron addicts@bootcamp.com you can find
me on it and the people,
uh,
pay 25 bucks.
I think I have 35,
35,
one of them,
uh,
for me to cut some out.
Yeah.
So I get on any custom mount for two
minutes,
two minutes straight.
I cussed him out and tell him you'll
call him all kind of motherfuckers and
shit.
Then I'd been doing my whole life for
nothing,
you know,
and now you know that people pay me to
do with man and it is wonderful.
It is wonderful.
Yeah.
Hey Ma,
one guy told me and I want you to cuss
my ex wife out.
Yeah,
yeah,
no,
exactly.
Fights.
So I had to let had to let her know
right up front,
hey,
this is not me saying this.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
no,
yeah,
I did.
I said,
no,
no.
I did it.
Not me seeing if this is great.
Gregory and Greg,
he said,
he told me you can leave him the fuck
alone and he is not interested in your
ugly ass no more.
Stop stalking him,
bitch.
But this is gregory talking.
Not Big.
So if you get your gun and shooting,
make sure it was gregory and not buy.
She ever get ahold of you.
No,
no.
I'm expecting her to book one for Greg
and that's good way to keep the business
going back.
Yeah.
We
think that those videos that you do are
very important.
I really do.
You know,
I just,
I think that inspiration,
this is like a people for some reason
there's,
there's a bunch of people that like to
mock that stuff.
They like to,
and most of those people were out of
shape.
They liked the mock that and they like
to make fun of it.
And I'm not talking about Comedians I'm
talking to,
you know,
which is,
it can be really funny doing that.
But I'm talking about there's a lot of
people that sincerity,
like for whatever reason bothers them
and sincerity when it comes to
inspiration and motivation and those
kinds of things.
Like some,
and for some people,
some people overdo it,
like go to some people's pages and their
instagram page,
just all bunch of quotes.
It's all other people saying shit,
it's fine every now and then,
every now and yeah,
it's like,
it's like your diet.
Yeah.
You know,
it's okay to eat a piece of cake every
now and then.
Don't eat cake all day.
You're gonna fucking minor and cake.
And if you see just nothing but
inspirational memes all day long,
you like,
this is not working anymore.
And they don't,
they don't get in too much.
But a real person,
a real person like you who's already
accomplished a shitload of things,
who understands the benefits,
real hard work and intensity and focus.
When you do those videos,
man,
I get fired up.
I get fired the fuck up.
I see those videos.
And I just want to go to the gym right
away.
Fucking fire.
Let me see.
I didn't even think they were broken.
Knew who the fuck I wish
I knew who you were in once I get upset
when you were getting mad at me.
Don't even know who the fuck I am.
No.
People know who the fuck you are man.
I mean how many millions of people have
seen your video?
Oh maybe one or two.
Yeah.
You know quite a few people who I've
seen it in weight way more than I ever
thought it would,
that's for sure.
Cause I mean you go on Youtube and you
tell people they turned me to fuck off.
I mean people are going to keep
watching.
There's motherfucker says turned me to
fuck.
I don't give a fuck if you watched me or
not.
You don't like what the fuck I'm saying
turn it off motherfucker.
I mean people are going to keep watching
and
that shocked the ones you want.
Oh my God.
Once you want,
I'm going to keep watching and rush.
I been able to travel the world man.
And,
and,
uh,
due to this due to arrives,
prabu coming in to see him going all
over the world.
I'm in the army base.
I've been to Russia,
Australia,
Germany,
I've been all over the fucking place.
Fuck you see tv for so many people at
the airport in rush and they all had
beards.
They all had fake beards are the women
men.
Everything about 120 people met me at
the airport and he,
here's this poor kid from compton,
you know,
and that who a lot of times I didn't
think it was gonna make it out of my
childhood to go to Russia and have all
these people with these beers on can
yard steal.
Steve motherfucking said,
man,
Joe,
it's know.
It's like sometime I think I actually
did down in the operating table and now
I'm in heaven.
Man,
I'm just,
this is my heaven.
You know what I mean?
So it's,
it's,
it's fantastic.
It is unbelievable.
And I'm sitting across the fucking tape
of Joe Road.
I'm sitting across the table from ct
Fletcher and after all he's going to
fucking say,
oh yeah,
it's this big giant few,
but you can do,
he'll never,
you'll never be on everybody who said,
I'd never be on this show.
Fuck yeah.
Bothered me for a second.
That was never upset at you at all.
But I could see your point of view and I
could see why you'd be upset at my point
of view.
I get it.
It didn't bother me.
No,
I don't take things very personally.
No.
You,
you know,
and immediately when he responded to me,
I said,
hey joe,
you're an absolute we 100% right.
You know,
it was,
I just want,
I really wanted to get your attention,
man,
more than anything.
I thought,
uh,
I d I did feel,
you know,
I felt we had a little difference.
It's in,
it's a slight difference because I agree
with about 90% of what you said.
It's just a slight difference that we
don't agree on.
And as soon as you say,
hey man,
you didn't,
and you came in here,
attack me like a fucking wild man.
And you.
Yes.
Yep,
I did though.
You're absolutely right.
I apologize for it.
I shouldn't,
it came at you that you're African.
That was,
that was the end of the few right now.
Maybe I can I be on your soda?
Well,
shout out to Kevin Pereira.
Forgetting Kevin Hill.
Yeah,
man.
Thank you.
Brought them with you right now.
Yeah.
We're doing this patriarch campaign,
which I'm going to be honest with you.
I hate,
um,
to,
to ask anybody for anything.
I hate that.
I,
I been,
I've had a job,
I mean I'm working jobs since I was 12
years ago and 12 years old.
I've worked in a gas station pumping gas
and it was during the fucking gas crisis
when the gas lines are super long.
But I've always worked for,
I hate asking people going in this
patriarchy campaign.
It's like asking people to help me,
you know,
now that I'm not able to travel the
world or not able to get out there and
promote things like I used to,
patron is a way that they can support me
in and it's called,
uh,
define Dev.
I wanted to call it my last will and
testament because if,
uh,
if I don't,
if I'm not successful in my fighting and
if I don't get a heart transplant,
I do get a heart transplant and rejects
and I'm dead.
I have a record at there was a wreck.
And I thought last will and testament be
the best thing to call it because if I
lose the fight,
then people can go back and see and
hopefully get some better.
They can see how I faced.
You know,
he hit a lot of people.
I have so many people telling me,
oh sweetie,
don't worry about it.
We were praying for you.
We got your back.
You know,
but hey,
none of that matters when you're in that
operating room.
Man,
I appreciate the good wishes and the
goodwill and all that.
But in the end,
you got to face it.
It's,
it's a solo experience.
You have to face death.
Everybody will,
you have to face death on your own and
nobody else can step in for you and died
for you or,
or,
or it's how you deal with it.
So this is uh,
a permanent record of how I deal with,
uh,
you know,
being in a,
in a,
in a situation where I could possibly
die and I want people to be able to look
at it just in case we want to make it,
don't make it whatever.
They can look back and they say,
well this is how cte built with it.
This is,
he's,
he's facing a transplant.
He didn't make it but he went in with a
shit ton of faith and he believed he was
going to make it.
He was bleeding,
he was going to make it.
And then if I don't make it fucking,
I ain't going to learn about it anyway.
You guys talk all the shit they want to.
But I went in with a very positive
attitude.
I want to be able to see that now when
they do a heart transplant.
If you talked to anybody that's had a
heart transplant,
yes I am.
Yeah.
And,
and you know that those are the people
that I really,
really want to hear from because they
can,
he said,
and I appreciate it's,
I get a shit shit.
Turn of well wishes and support and I
think from iron addicts all across the
planet.
I mean they all behind me and I really,
really appreciate it,
but I actually,
it's easy for me.
He said,
hey joe,
be tough.
You're going through.
Yeah,
I know you're going through this thing,
Joe,
but I want you to be tough.
I want you to hang tough and I want you
to,
you know,
I'm rooted,
but have I actually gone through when
I'm asked to circumstance that you're
facing the difficulty to facing right
now?
Have I actually had any experience with
it?
Because it's hard for me to listen to
you to tell me to,
you know,
be strong and be tough about getting
into heart transplant and you know,
you ain't never had nothing but a
fucking hang nail or something like,
you know what I mean?
If you've actually been through
something,
then I can listen to you a lot better.
It's like a fighter,
a guy who's never been in a fight trying
to tell a fight or what to do in his
next cage.
Right?
Hey,
hey,
you get in there and want you to put
this on.
Put them in,
right?
Yeah.
That fight.
I'm not going to be listening too hard
to a motherfucker.
Don't have no experience.
Experiences to me is still the best
teacher.
Especially something like a hard time.
Yeah.
I mean I how it fit.
What percentage of people have ever even
happen?
I mean,
how many people have successful heart
transplants a year?
Do you know?
You know,
I,
I've tried to look it up,
but they don't give you too many numbers
on,
on a,
I think that uh,
the survival rate is 75 for the first,
no,
I think it's higher.
80% for the first year.
Now it was lower,
you know,
years ago.
But now it's up to 80% survive for the
first year and they go some pretty
intense drugs just to keep your body
from rejecting the organ.
Right.
Definitely.
But I'm taking a shit load of drugs
right now to take.
Now I got 15 different pill,
15 different drugs,
uh,
and I take every day just to survive.
What are they all for?
Uh,
the kid water off my lungs and lower my
blood pressure,
kidney,
all kinds of fucking different pills
and,
and just to,
that supposedly helped me function.
And then sometime I honestly think they
fucked me up.
Uh,
some of them fucked me up.
This,
it's hard for me to,
you know,
function properly on a daily basis,
just a day of feeling normal.
If I can feel normal for the whole day,
oh,
that's fantastic man.
Not good or,
you know,
great.
I feel great today or there's no such
thing as me getting them saying I have,
I had a fucking great day to day,
but if I can just feel normal for that
day,
then that's fantastic man.
And this is since June?
Yeah.
So before June,
you were fine.
Even with the artificial heart valve.
A,
I wouldn't say I W I was,
I was,
yes.
For,
for 11 and a half of those years,
but six months prior to the,
the heart attack I had signs.
So he started feeling it coming.
Yeah.
Hanson,
do you do any cardio or what?
Are you doing any cardio before?
Uh,
not really.
I can,
you know,
the way I work out,
it's kind of cardio.
You be sweating,
you know,
big puff of a sweat on the floor,
like a calorie muscle.
I remember I put them through a workout
and I was trained a lot of pro wrestlers
and stuff too when I put them through
the workout.
And Kelly Muslim who had the best,
uh,
he said willikers
that was the best one.
You said,
damn ct,
he fucking crazy man.
But that was the best,
uh gee,
that's bringing it way back Eddie
Griffin show.
Yeah,
right,
exactly.
Kelly was on fear factor.
Yeah.
Waze.
Yeah,
yeah,
I do.
Do you fell off of a car?
Oh,
what didn't work.
They have suspended over a,
uh,
was like suspect.
See if they could find that giant
giant.
It was a one of those dots where you had
to carry your own weight,
like climbing over thing.
Oh Shit.
He's like close to 350.
Yeah.
So he's doing that.
It's just,
it was the wrong stop.
Yeah,
I bet it was.
I,
I adopted that guy.
My son.
He's fucking,
he's,
he's got an interesting story.
I'm so,
oh my God,
he's got a youtube story.
Yeah.
Hell of a story,
man.
He's a real,
real good.
And the good thing about him,
he's the same way on and off youtube.
Yeah.
He was a very friendly guy when I met
him.
I enjoy talking to him a lot.
He's jacked as fuck.
Oh yeah,
definitely.
Definitely counting muscles.
Jack.
Yeah.
I interviewed,
one of my favorite interviews was hoists
gracie.
Really?
Yeah,
I got the interview.
He's crazy.
And it was incredibly,
uh,
we had some incredible similarities in
our train of thought and how we think
he,
yeah,
he told me that,
uh,
on the day of fight,
he made no plans for after the fight.
No plans.
No,
we're going out to dinner.
You're gonna celebrate none of that.
He was,
he said I was completely 100% prepared
to die in that octagon.
And I'm like,
fuck.
Yeah.
That resonated with me so hard because I
remember my last context cause you know
they told me about my heart valve and
uh,
the 90s,
in 95 at my last congress,
greatest bench press in America,
they say you're going to miss it for
two.
You can go out there and in front of all
those people and,
and,
and uh,
your valve could break,
burst and you could die right there on
the bench press in front of all those
people.
Are you going to go?
And I looked at him and I said,
fuck yeah,
I'm going,
are you out?
Took my doctor looked at me like I'm
crazy.
I'm looking at him like he crazy.
Fuck yes,
I'm going.
Hell yeah.
I your mind,
what a glorious,
wait,
what did is way to go out doing what I
fucking love to do what I chained to do
my whole fucking life in front of all
these people.
Oh Man.
I couldn't ask if I was writing a movie
script and couldn't be any better.
Wow.
Fucking died right there on stage in
front of every fucking body bitch brush.
So I'm felt the same way.
I felt the same way because he's crazy
and it just really made me feel good
that I wasn't the only crazy
motherfucker when the plan,
he's
definitely crazy.
He's the most important figure in the
history of martial arts.
His UFC one in 1993 changed the world,
changed the world because people thought
that you had to be like the bigger guy
and then all of a sudden he showed that
no,
there's,
there's this thing called Brazilian
Jujitsu and this dude coming out wearing
pajamas is just going to fuck all you
people change the world of martial arts.
Everybody started training Jujitsu.
Oh my God.
I don't even know what it was.
I didn't have no idea what it was.
No idea.
As soon as it came out,
I was like,
I'm enrolled.
I went to Carlson Gracie,
I went to Hixon Gracie's first and then
the Carlson gracie's.
Yeah.
And I think that is why,
uh,
up in,
blow some smoke up your butt there,
Joe.
I think that's why you said two
fantastic analyst.
I think that's why you're the best at
what you do because you get to ass in
there and actually experience it.
And even when you say
a hold or you see a Omoplata or whatever
it,
you know what the fuck you're talking
about.
And I think that helps.
But I think I'm very,
very fortunate that I have a series of
jobs that help each other.
Yeah.
And that like being a Canadian and being
able to talk on stage in front of all
those people.
I'm comfortable.
I'm comfortable in front of a microphone
doing a podcast.
I'm going to see and I'm comfortable and
I love MMA.
Obviously.
I'm a huge fan of martial arts,
so this is good.
It's my chance to express myself about
something that I really enjoy it and I
don't,
I don't feel burdened down by the,
the moment of like the camera on me
counts.
Yeah.
The performing in front of a live
audience and you're being comedian or,
or what did you do for the,
Oh,
you have seats way,
way easier.
Yeah.
It's very,
very,
it's,
I wouldn't say it's easy because you
have to have,
you have to understand what you're
talking about.
You have to have a lot of information in
your head and you have to really care.
Like it's my job just to represent the
experience that these guys are going
through it.
When I,
when I think about commentary,
I'm thinking about he's these guys been
through months of training camp.
They've dieted,
they've,
you know,
cut weight just to get down to their
weight class there.
Rehydrated there's so much emotions and
intensity.
It's just my job to honor their
experience and to do my best to make it
fun for the fans at home and make a
traumatic.
That's all my job there.
They have the hard job.
My job is just to not fuck up and to try
to describe it the best way that I can.
It's way easy than stand up.
Aye.
The live art.
Oh Shit.
I know.
I'm just being,
uh,
well I can imagine not going around the
world giving speeches and uh,
seminars in front of live audiences.
It's much easier for me.
And now I'm,
this is a big ass thing,
but it's much easier for me to sit
across the table,
Joe Rogan and talk to him.
Then he used to do his people,
you know,
shooting all kinds of questions at me.
Yes.
All right.
It's going to be odd for you to
experience this late in life too.
I couldn't do it.
I,
if I had to sit across the table from
Joel going to 21 days or I'd be too
fucking pantry fried to do it,
I think he would talk and I think you
would loosen up and then you'd be
yourself.
I'd be choked up for a while.
Maybe fucking two.
I'd be tied to him that wouldn't be able
to,
once it's just people,
people relax.
I don't think so.
I was to,
uh,
to uh,
wound up emotionally as a 21 year too.
Who isn't?
Oh Man.
You know,
I could imagine I was talking with a
buddy of mine cause I started standing
up at 21 and I was like,
what the fuck did I have to talk about
when I was 21?
I didn't know shit.
Wow.
You literally don't know anything doing
anything.
Yeah.
It started at 21.
Wow.
I don't know a fucking thing.
We now 35
fucking 50 50 old bastard.
This guy's fucking 15 years old.
I started in August 27th,
1988.
Wow.
Thanks very much man.
I have my big for Joe Rogan's.
Looks good.
It's fucking fuck man.
What's it like when you don't die?
It's white as fuck.
Cause it.
Yeah.
I'll give someone gave him Santa Claus
and run for fucking money.
Get rid of black beard.
Oh,
I had to make the loan for lacking that
shit up.
Who gives a shit?
Yeah,
I know.
I do.
I know just for me and better start
paying me for this fucking Shit,
man.
I've been advertising for them fucker
for years.
They should get in there with that comb
right here.
Yeah.
I'm getting in their work it out and
making that shit black.
So how often do you do youtube videos
now?
Uh,
we released a new one every Saturday and
they have changed so much.
Your last week I had a cooking show.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
A vegan cooking show.
Yeah.
You're doing all the Vegan Diet now,
Huh?
Well,
you know,
I can't call myself beacon.
I call myself plant based.
I started out seeing I was Vegan and
then I realized how crazy new Vegan
folks in and I said,
you know,
I'm not thinking cause I'm not doing it
because I,
I'm thinking about the animals and
they're going be,
you know,
fuck your ass up out.
That shit is super serious about that.
I'm not doing it because of that.
I'm doing it for,
here's a lot of people that are Vegan
that are Vegan for the right reasons.
They're Vegan because the conscientious
cause they want to do it for health
because they want to have the least
amount of impact on the environment
because they want,
they don't want animals to die.
But then there's a lot of people that
are Vegan that really just belonged to
something.
They could have been scientology or he
could have been a moonie.
They could have been any.
They found that and they ran with it and
now they are fucking ruthless against
people that aren't in that group.
And they,
they generally give like goodhearted,
kindhearted,
vegans,
a bad name.
And it's a small percentage,
but a lot of these motherfuckers,
they have like Vegan in their online
name and there,
you know,
and they
tack like you look at their,
like their comments,
they're all attacking all the old people
at constant.
Yeah.
Angry people that found reason to be a,
an aggressive person.
Like you've found a greenlight,
oh this person's not vegan.
I can attack them.
And you're the reason why the world,
you're the responsible for the pollution
and all the car.
Did you know that if you were Vegan that
this would be less suffering and this
would be,
oh my God,
this.
And they do the worst job of promoting
veganism because people see those crazy
ass holes and then they go,
fuck these people.
I'm going to go eat a steak just for
you,
but I'm going to shoot this fucking cow
right now and I'm going to eat them
right in front of you.
Fuck you,
man.
It was,
I didn't want to be associated with
them,
that radical part of at all.
So I stopped saying I'm being,
I just don't eat meat.
I would like to get you connected to
some real nutrition experts that could
break down why that might not be the
best idea.
And what,
what is important in your diet in terms
of like essential fatty acids and
healthy fats in terms of like,
like a lot of people think that refined
carbohydrates are the big problem with
heart disease are fine carbohydrates and
sugar is what contributes to heart
disease.
Do you know the whole thing that came
out pretty recently in the New York
Times did an expo say about the sugar
industry having paid off scientists in
the 1950s to put the blame on saturated
fats and cholesterol instead of sugar
and then yeah,
is a complete total fabricated
conspiracy by the sugar industry because
they were,
they were doing these tests and they
were realizing like,
Holy Shit,
like sugar fucks people up.
It's terrible for you.
And so what they did is they literally
bribed scientists and not that much
money,
which is kind of crazy.
In the 1950s they paid them something
around $50,000 and I don't even know if
it's $50,000 today,
I think it was the equivalent of $50,000
and these people just fabricated these
reports and got everybody convinced that
saturated fat,
which is an essential part of the human
diet and cholesterol,
which is the literally the substrate for
hormone production,
like cholesterol is important for your
body and that these things are
responsible for heart disease and not
sugar,
refined sugar and refined carbohydrates.
They're completely unnatural in the
human body.
You're not supposed to be able to just
scoop up a fucking tablespoon full of
sugar and dump it in your mouth.
It's not real in the world.
I give you get sugar in the world.
It's attached to an apple.
You know,
as you get carbohydrates,
it's in plants,
it's fiber you're eating to end.
Your body knows how to process that.
Your body doesn't know what the fuck to
do with bread,
especially the bread that we eat today
sprayed down with fucking all sorts of
shit to prevent pesticide.
All these pesticides and it's the,
they changed the wheat and made it more,
more complex glutens,
so your body's a hard time processing
it.
So a lot of bad food.
No,
I'm not a Vegan,
but I respect the people that are doing
it because they're doing it because they
don't want to cause harm and I respect
the people that are doing it that think
they're doing it for their health.
But I've talked to a lot of vegans that
were formally Vegan,
especially Chris Kresser who is an
actual scientist and is one of the
leading experts on the,
the real issue with the Vegan Diet and
how it does work for some people,
some people with their biological
requirements and their,
their physical requirements in terms of
like what their activity is.
They functioned fine on a Vegan Diet.
As long as they're careful,
they make sure they get enough.
12,
they make sure they get their fatty
acids,
make sure they get their essential fatty
acids from coconuts and flaxseed oil.
And there's a,
you know,
avocado,
there's a lot of different ways you can
get oils for your body,
but your body needs that shit.
It's essential.
There's a like a lot of essential
things.
I would love to connect you with these
guys.
Yeah.
And I'm,
I'm open to very open to it.
I changed my,
uh,
outlook,
you know,
after this last for architecture.
I changed my outlook a completely and
that's,
that's what made me even trying to,
yeah.
A plant based Diet.
Um,
you know,
I,
I had,
uh,
I have a supplement company that's earn
an experience,
a hardcore hardcore forts.
It's billed as for the hardest core
motherfuckers on the quick kind of Shit.
Yeah.
You know,
preworkouts and pumps and stuff.
But after he had,
I started,
I started another brand,
uh,
Odyssey.
Nutraceuticals is completely different.
Our named Odyssey because that's what I
consider my life is this isn't an
artist.
He can punch a difference.
I got one hell of a legacy going on.
But anyway,
it's a a plant based protein or is very
health conscientious,
a very health conscious entity.
So
I'm a fan of plant based protein.
Oh,
pea protein is really good.
I love hemp protein.
That's my favorite.
I think hemp protein is very easy for
you to body digest.
The real problem with a lot of plant
plant proteins is,
I mean,
if you just eat just plants,
especially eating whole foods,
you're not nest that your body's not
breaking it down the same way your body
would break down a steak,
say or grass fed beef.
I'm going to send you a fan,
pulled my shit.
I'd love to get it.
And you tell me what you think and uh,
uh,
I see nutraceuticals.
I had to get there early and on the air
before Joe King can fuck off.
What is the website?
You have a website for nutraceuticals
dotcom and go check it out.
I've got to get that city and before he
kicked me off,
yeah.
You know,
when we were going back and forth,
I remember one of the questions that I
had to ask you,
I said,
what is I?
S y m f.
S what the fuck is that?
Cause it's something under your thing
all the time.
And when you told me I was laughing out
loud in front of my computer,
still your mother fucking says exactly
what it stands for,
Jo.
And I love that.
But if you,
uh,
it's really based on,
my mom,
uh,
my mom was raising rom.
Not completely retarded.
I mean,
I,
I think I'm seeing my retarded,
but I'm not complete or retarded.
That's not a,
I shouldn't say I still allow it.
Okay,
thank you.
Joe.
It doesn't mean the disease a dummy.
Yeah.
I'm not saying I'm not completely,
you know,
it retarded and intent.
She'd just be noises that you make the
convey intent.
I don't,
that should be magic noises.
Can't say,
Ooh,
God dammit Joe.
that was,
that was deep.
Yeah.
I think people are too sensitive.
And then on top of it,
people are looking to tell you to not
say certain words.
We all took that,
the art board,
wrong word now it's problematic today.
Oh my God.
Oh yeah.
So it came from my mom.
My mom was,
I tell you that her now,
all of his siblings died from a heart
related prom.
So she was sick most of her adult life,
I swear.
I remember mostly,
I remember very early when I was very
young,
my mom being healthy,
but she was sick most of her adult life.
Most of my memories of my mom when she
was sick,
but every day,
every day,
and I mean,
she was really sick in and out of
emergency rooms and said,
if you ask my mom,
hey,
I,
Mrs. Fletcher Hard,
she would say I'm blessed.
Her standard answer was always blessed.
And the reason she told me the reason
why she would say that is because I'm
still alive.
I'm not dead.
So if I'm still alive,
I ha ha,
I still have life.
If I still can go on,
I still could make a change.
I still can make it different.
So it's,
I got it from her no matter what the
situation,
how bad it may seen,
how people complain,
that man,
you still alive motherfucker.
So you said your life and you're still
alive,
you still have a chance to make a
difference.
You're still going,
what's the worst thing that happened?
I could die.
Okay,
well if you ain't dead,
motherfucker keep going.
You ain't did it scare you?
Said Fuck.
Yeah.
So yeah,
she was blessed and that's why I always,
you know,
people,
hey,
how you doing sweetie?
I'm blessed.
No matter what the fuck's going on,
I'm still alive.
So I'm blessed.
That's awesome that people need to hear
that.
They do need to hear that and they need
to hear your attitude about excuses.
Cause both of those things are very
important.
It's very important for people to
process.
There's a lot of people have like bad
patterns in their mind and these bad
patterns,
the way they've interacted with the
world,
the way they've approached all sorts of
different problems.
They have these patterns and they fall
right into these patterns and maybe they
learn these patterns from their family
member that maybe they learn these
patterns from their environment.
Maybe these patterns are like defense
mechanisms to keep them from challenging
themselves.
But you got to recognize what those are.
It's not you like you're not a lazy
fuck,
but you've been behaving like a lazy
fuck.
Well,
you are as a human right,
and you could be anything.
You could just decide to me,
you know the story of David Goggins,
David Goggins.
Damn.
This navy seal.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I recently looked them up.
It was super fat.
Fully out of shape.
Like,
like literally like on death's door,
healthwise guy just starting school I
fucked with,
but a sided.
Yep.
The enough is enough.
Just literally in his own mind decided
he was gonna win the world record for
Chin ups decided he's going to be like
this incredible endurance athlete did.
It just did.
It just does.
It just forces his mind.
And he has this thing that he says that
I think about whenever I'm tired.
He said,
most people quit at 40%
wow.
Believe I believe
that too.
I believe that most people get a little
tired and like,
oh,
fuck this.
You know,
but you couldn't go further.
You can't go further.
Yeah,
man.
Yeah.
I just recently read a on and I had
watched the video of him.
Somebody sent it to me.
He's a savage.
He's tricked me.
Mental savage.
Aw,
yeah.
I love it.
I love those guys.
Those people are important.
You've got to know that those people are
out there and him in particular,
he's really important because he was
super out of shape.
It's not like he was always this ripped
super athlete like he was like fat and
terrible diet and poor health and poor
depression.
The whole deal and just tightened it up
and now he's an animal.
Now you can't fuck with them.
Fucking beside.
Yes.
Decided to and anybody can do that.
All the people out there that think
they're lazy.
No.
You've been behaving like a lazy person.
You've been following lazy patterns.
If you just decide tomorrow,
first of all,
if you decide tomorrow you're going to
be a discipline focused person,
don't expect to have the kind of energy
that someone who's been disciplined and
focused for years house cause you're not
going to,
that's we're going that your body's not
going to be conditioned for it.
Your mind's not going to be accustomed
to the strain,
but you can still do it right.
You just,
you're going to scale,
you get tired quicker and then hopefully
by next week you'll have more endurance
and then by the week after that you'll
have more and if you keep building six
months from now,
you'll be unrecognizable.
Yes.
Right.
If you stick with you definitely will,
but everything's got to start from right
here in important.
That's why you're important.
That's why your videos are so important
because your videos,
I guaran fucking tee it.
I don't know the number,
but I want to say 100,000 people
probably watch your videos and change
their life.
I guarantee you real.
It's a lot more than I though.
I bet you've changed people's entire
outlook on things.
That's,
that's everything in this life.
This is a little,
because you can get information.
Books are wonderful documentaries and
one full.
What's really great is inspiration.
The fuel that the little push,
just a little push just to get you
moving.
Sometimes that's all it needs and then
next thing you know it and then people
like you because you've had a lifetime
of this discipline and dedication and
obsession that that reinforces it in
people's heads.
Like I want to do what ct does.
I want to be like that.
I want to have that kind of energy and
focus.
Joe Rogan,
me ever started about thought about
getting into the octagon yourself?
I want to know I'm too old now.
I almost did at one point in time,
but not at this point.
No,
no.
What earlier?
Yeah.
Well when I was kickboxing man,
I got a lot of fucking headaches and I
was really worried.
I,
I came from a real meathead gym and we
did like hard sparring and I did a lot
of hard spot in this one kid in
particular who was a really good boxer
and we'd beat the fuck out of each
other.
Oh.
And um,
the problem is like I would go home and
you know,
this was going on over a few years.
I would go home and my head would be
pounding,
just boom,
boom,
lying in bed.
And I was thinking,
what am I doing myself?
Am I going to be stupid when I get
older?
Am I going to not know where I am?
I going to be stumbling on my words.
I was terrified to brain damage because
I've always been,
I've always been a very curious person
and I've always been fascinated by the,
the way you can change the way you think
about things and by being in.
So that's why I'm so excited about
talking to you,
like inspiration and motivation and even
information like having these things in
your mind.
You can forge these things together to,
to,
to make your mind going a certain
direction.
So the quality of my thoughts has always
been very,
very important to me because I know that
that's what made me successful in all
the different areas that I've chosen to
pursue.
It's like the quality of your thinking
and being able to recognize what's good
and what's bad,
but the mind itself,
if the mind itself is compromised,
then you're not going to be able to do
all those things that you want to do.
Gonna be able to appreciate life if you
don't remember where you are and you
don't know how to talk anymore.
And I was around people that I was
watching their ability to talk and
their,
their cognitive function to k is
fighting is,
it's glorious.
But you gotta know when to stop.
You got to know when to stop.
And for me,
when I was,
when I stopped as 1989 there was no ufc,
there was no money,
there was no money in kickboxing.
Like I think I got offered a fight for
500 bucks and that,
that was a,
I was doing amateur fights and I got
offered a pro fight for like madmen 400
bucks.
I don't remember how much it was,
but it was like what I was like,
that's crazy.
Like I'm going to train for months and
maybe get my ass kicked and maybe get
head kicked for like 400 bucks.
And I was getting these headaches.
The headaches were bad man.
And uh,
so I just decided early on,
if the UFC was around back then,
I'm most certain I would have pursued
it.
But glad it wasn't.
You did a whooper fans ass one time a
fan.
Well not a fan.
A guy talking shit.
Oh,
the guy on fear factor?
No,
I just grabbed him.
He,
I thought he was gonna hit me.
I didn't hurt him.
No,
he's [inaudible].
I just tied him up.
Damn Boy Thai clinch.
I was thinking of choking him,
but I was like,
I better not choke them because if I
choke him,
you know,
maybe they could sue me.
So I just decided,
I decided if I grab a hold of him and
grab him by the back of the head,
he'll probably realized once I lock on
to him that he's pretty helpless and
he'll probably stop.
And he kind of did.
He kinda just flailed around a little
bit,
but he's like,
oh,
when someone grabs your neck,
there's something about controlling
someone's neck.
It's a very,
it just does not feel good.
You feel powerless.
You,
that was a guy that he had attacked a
counselor before on another television
show and he had thrown his girlfriend to
the ground or his wife on another
television show.
And they had told me about him before he
did the show.
They're like,
this guy's a series hothead.
We're thinking about not having him on
the show at all,
but we thought it'd be good drama just
but be careful.
And so he punched some God or she
punched some guy on the show and I said,
the wife punched the guy who was those
heckling him.
And I said,
you can't hit someone.
I go,
just because you hit your husband
doesn't mean you can hit other people.
And then the guy got in my face and
there's a lot of it,
there wasn't on film that they didn't
put on tv,
but I pushed him out of my face.
He goes,
don't touch me.
And I said,
or what?
Bitch,
what the fuck are you going to do?
And he got in my face again and I pushed
him again.
And then I said,
this is just two,
two tents.
I go,
I'm just going to grab this guy.
I'm like,
I'm not getting punched in the face.
Cause sucker punches happening.
And especially if you're not,
if you're not ready to get punched and
you get punched,
you can get fucked up.
Especially if you don't think someone's
going to punch you.
And then they do.
You know?
So I'm always thinking when someone
raises their voice,
they're ready to punch me.
So I'm just going to clamp down on this
dude's neck,
get ahold of them.
So I just grabbed him.
I didn't hurt him.
I was fucking man.
I always liked to when I was a fucking
Joe Rogan Fan,
he called the police on me though.
The police had to go over the,
he,
he would claimed I hit him.
He claimed a bunch of shit.
The police had to go over the videotape.
They had to show all the,
uh,
the footage from all the different
cameras.
Yeah.
I never really hit him and the fucking
real
man.
Fuck yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You have a guys a challenge.
You'd have no social media.
No.
No idiots.
Maybe friendly.
Yeah.
No,
but in real life,
when people meet me,
I'm always friendly.
It's so many idiots on social media.
There's a lot of guys have,
yeah.
Somebody,
oh,
I'll kick your well that's,
see that the idiots of the reasons why I
never was getting your information in
the first place when you're reaching out
to me,
cause I'm not paying attention to
anything.
Right.
If I dip my toes in the water
occasionally and like see what the
fuck's going on in the world,
like,
oh Whoa,
fuck outta here.
Yeah.
It's,
I've seen too many people,
it starts their day off in a bad way and
they get obsessed with it and they start
going battling back and forth with
people in the comments.
Guilty,
guilty as him up where I'm ask you and I
had the discussion.
You rang back and forth and people,
oh,
so Joe Rogan has got some fucking fans,
man.
They wanted their fucking string mine.
How dare you talk to Joe?
Like I said,
motherfucker,
this between me until the fuck you want
to jump in.
Oh,
they won't get killed me and fucking
assassinate you want to make you feel
bad.
It's what they really want to do.
They want to figure out a way that they
can point out that you're wrong or make
you feel stupid or they just,
it's almost all of it.
Almost all of it is unhealthy people
unhappy,
right?
Maybe not bad people who are doing this,
but it's an unhealthy practice to just
lash out.
This is not even people that are really
in your life.
It's one thing,
didn't have a debate about things.
And I think this is where we as human
beings have to learn how to use social
media better cause there's nothing wrong
and having discussions about things,
but you got to figure out a way to do it
where you're not just trying to
someone's feelings all the time and
lashing out because that's what a lot of
it is.
It just bitter,
very small minded squabbling.
Even if you're using big words,
the intent behind it is very small
minded.
Exactly.
People see me videos of their work,
their been working out all the time and
uh,
you know,
some of them are not doing it correctly.
Right.
But I don't criticize people.
I never,
you know,
because it really,
most important thing to me is that
they're trying,
they actually in the of trying to,
trying to do something,
but man,
the people,
other people don't look at it like that.
Oh you're fucked up.
You're doing that fucking wrong.
You're fucking why you don't know what
the fuck.
They jumped on him immediately.
You know,
that they're trying to discourage them.
People that are at least trying to do
something,
they've tried to discourage him and he's
got so many fucking experts out there,
or are you not doing this correctly?
Your farm is fucked up.
I'm like,
man,
why?
Why do they,
I mean,
if you really want to do that,
then direct message to people,
right?
If you're really trying to help him
direct message,
why,
why put it out there so everybody can
see it?
You know,
you're just trying to draw attention to
yourself.
There's a lot of that.
Oh,
so rod,
if they just want people to look at me,
I'm going to explain what the fuck I'm
doing.
Fuck them guys I don't like.
Yeah.
And it's what's interesting too about
exercises is there's some things that
are debatable in terms of the way to do
it and what not to do.
It does not necessarily always a
consensus about how someone's doing
something,
right?
Whether it's like,
you know,
like,
uh,
there's just a lot of people online that
are just making a lot of noise.
It's hard to figure out who's right and
who's wrong.
Yeah.
I,
I think it's only right and wrong for
you.
I mean,
you try.
If Joe Rogan tells me I had to do
something a certain way and I try it and
it works for me,
then I'm fucking,
I'm going to do it right.
I,
if it works for me,
because we all are so goddamn different,
it's like we're not,
nobody's exactly the same.
So when somebody,
somebody says,
Hey,
if now somebody says they got the
perfect routine,
it's going to work for every fucking
body,
then that guy,
you gotta be Lyria,
he's going shit,
because nobody has one routine is going
to work for every fucking buy.
It's just impossible.
It's not going to happen.
Yeah,
I agree.
I think especially,
it's really interesting with mma because
the fact that hoists gracie bursts on
the scene in 1990 3000 not that long
ago,
right?
I mean that's really 24 years is not a
lot of prep time.
It's just too similar or it's too close.
And so there's all these different
methods that have been sort of devised
along the way and nobody really,
I mean,
until someone comes along the real,
you know,
someone's like an Anderson Silva that's
like super successful doing it one way,
and then you go,
well,
how the fuck is he doing it?
We've got to do it his way.
Yeah.
But you're not him.
Right?
Like maybe you started out as a
wrestler,
whereas he's a Moyie Thai guy.
Maybe it works good for him,
but maybe you need a different approach
and nobody really knows how to do it for
you.
You have to kind of figure out your own
way when you've got to hone it and tweak
it along the way while you're competing.
So,
yeah,
it's hard.
Yeah.
Well,
the,
the rule,
uh,
innovators that are real guys,
it didn't,
you know,
they,
I'm sure that they did that.
They,
they,
they're not trying to copy.
Yeah.
It's so important to be an original,
uh,
at Danny.
Anything.
I mean,
it was set out to try to beat Joe Rogan.
You're gonna fail motherfucking cousin,
April one,
Joe Rogan.
And he and so try,
I tell him he's got no time.
He sees me.
I want to be just like,
you don't be just like me,
my damn self,
you know,
be yourself,
man.
Be,
don't try and beat just like Joe Rogan
be.
You said,
cause you can't be doing,
it's hard to tell
people that though.
If you,
if you see someone who inspires you and
you admire them and you want to do what
they're doing,
it's,
it's hard.
But everybody starts out in the
beginning,
like special in.
You're a young person.
When you admire someone,
you kind of copy a lot of their
mannerisms and the way they do it.
But eventually you've got to find
yourself.
Oh yeah,
definitely.
I mean,
I used to go around,
uh,
float like a butterfly back.
Muhammad Ali.
Oh,
I was my home and I read when I was a
kid,
man,
I want to do,
you know,
I wanted to be him.
And then I wanted to be Bruce Lee and I
got into fucking,
uh,
term,
point karate,
you know,
point turning tournament.
Oh yeah.
Joe Brooks.
He didn't know that.
No,
I didn't know it was a point fighter and
I came very close.
Uh,
Goddamn Typo,
typo billy blanks.
Every planes came very close to find a
billy blanks in the long beach arena.
Uh,
ed Parker's Kenpo karate put on the
international rights EMC baby.
Yeah.
And I was very close to find billy
blanks and I,
every time I see billy now say,
hey billy,
I thank you so much.
Cause the guy when I seen the finals,
billy,
fuck that guy up.
He was supposed to be point and he
knocked him my fucking house.
Or Billy,
you know,
fought even in point.
Like they would hit each other hard.
Oh hell.
You know.
And Billy was knocked out before two
people got knocked out.
I know,
I know.
They made them fight after they got
knocked out.
Nobody knew any better.
Brown yourself back.
Revive yourself and getting,
keep fighting,
man.
Yeah,
it was,
uh,
it was pretty good.
I look good.
I love Marshall,
but my favorite sport,
I think bar none in Nepal or not
overweight lifting and mma is getting
really close.
It was really close,
but I think he's boxing.
He loved boxing going,
Oh,
I love it.
What's your favorite fighter deal face?
Ooh Man.
Ooh,
that's,
that's really hard.
Uh,
as a,
uh,
a role,
minor,
I guess a Muhammad Ali would be my
favorite block as a role model,
but not because of what he did in the
ring.
It's more so because of what he did
outside the ring is why I hold him in
such high regard.
But Roy Jones Jr course,
Mike Tyson,
but Roy Jones.
Oh my God.
It's prime.
There was nobody like Roy.
Oh,
on a completely different level.
He wasn't even Javin.
He was in with a left hook and he was
most career too.
Oh yeah.
And it's,
it was weird shaped.
His biceps were giant,
but he has a small triceps biceps with
Jack.
He went all the way up to heavyweight.
Remember that?
And won beat John Ruiz.
The heavyweight title too.
I remember.
You don't want to talk about boxing.
Yeah,
yeah.
Go Man.
I'm all fucking boxing,
man.
Really?
Well,
I'm a fan of boxing too.
You know,
even though a woman made your number one
though,
right?
Like mma better because anything can
happen.
You can get head kicked.
He get kicked down,
strangled.
There's,
to me,
there's so many possibilities that it's
more complicated.
What I call him and May I see,
I'll call it high level problem solving
with dire physical consequences.
Ooh,
that's what it is.
X for days,
these tools,
you have all these tools.
He has all these tools.
You'd go in there and you try to figure
out who's got the best approach and
who's going to be able to use their
body,
talent,
their skill,
their dedication.
Who's going to be able to figure out a
way to solve your problem?
Wow.
What do you think about nate bees?
It's a bad motherfucker.
I love fucking,
and I met him at a,
at a fight in UFC fight.
He was the humblest.
It was so nice.
And he goes,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not fucking Jack like you,
but I do my pig.
Like fucking you are fucking killer man.
He's a great guy,
but he's another,
he's another guy.
It was a perfect example of how you
can't make everyone trained the same
way.
He's incredibly successful,
but a lot of his training is not weight
lifting here.
He does triathlons,
does his Jujitsu and it's kickbox
singing all the other stuff.
But on top of that,
like he does crazy endurance work.
Yeah.
Nick and nick.
Amy,
I love brothers,
man.
Yeah.
I may have to King Mo.
Uh,
he was real cool.
A lot of guys at fights.
Uh,
uh,
the most famous referee,
big John McCarthy,
McCarthy,
excellent guy.
Uh,
he was really friendly.
I was a very good guy.
Trying to think.
I didn't,
I couldn't really figure out why the guy
liked me so much.
George Saint Pierre,
he said,
I want you to make a special,
uh,
a video for me before.
It's one of one of his big fights.
So I'm going to,
I'm spitting all over the mic and shit.
Fucking hardcore.
And then he made a video back for me the
game.
I had his fucking fuck George Saint
Pierre had his fucking phone number,
man.
He calls me and says,
ct,
I want,
can you do a one arm pull up?
I said,
no,
I can't do what he said,
I can't eat.
Let's see who could be the first one to
do a one arm pull.
I say your own George t t.
And I'm like,
I don't,
I don't know.
Uh,
I couldn't really,
uh,
understand why fighters like me so much.
I couldn't understand why he didn't like
me.
So fighters need motivation,
man.
I guess what it is.
Yeah,
that's a big part of it.
Well,
because you're real,
you're 100% real.
You are,
you are who you are.
You don't put on any false airs.
But also inspiration is critical for
cause.
They're always tired.
They're always trying to find the energy
to keep going.
They're always trying to find that that
pushed to get up and keep going.
When you're two months into camp and
every day is a grind and you're just
exhausted,
you know,
and it's repetitive there.
You're constantly drilling,
constantly sparring,
strength and conditioning.
You're swimming,
you're running,
you're doing this,
you doing that,
and then the,
the,
the impending moment of that fight is
constantly looming in the background of
your life.
There's no escape from it.
And like you need like sometimes you
need like a ct Fletcher video to get you
over the hump.
Wow.
I guess I,
I mean I could,
I have the utmost respect for fighters,
boxers and or mma guys especially,
I mean,
anybody is,
I'm going to be the guy who gets knocked
out every time he steps in.
I respect the fuck out of him because he
had the testicular fortitude to step
through the fucking gate man and get in
there and actually do,
do you know Joe?
I know,
you know,
but people don't understand how much it
takes to just take that trip down in
actually getting that cage and face
another man who's trying to take your
fucking head off.
That takes a tremendous,
I remember how much you took fighting at
the long beach arena and just the crowd
there.
And I know there's nothing compared to
him.
He may cry in the half people.
That crowd makes a big fucking
difference.
It makes it,
I got so fucking nervous,
everything that I had learned,
I fucking forgot.
As soon as it got kicked me upside the
head,
I forgot her every fucking,
every quarter,
all that shit went right out the window.
And I went and tried to kill,
I forgot everything.
And I went straight to compton there.
I forgot all my cards and everything,
man.
And,
and I,
it's,
it takes a tremendous,
and that's why I respect the guy so much
because I have an inkling of an idea.
I don't have a real idea cause I ain't
never done this.
But I have an inkling of an idea of what
it takes to actually get into an octagon
and before all those downs of people and
put when the millions of people watching
on TV and perform.
Oh yeah.
And rise and rise.
He can sit fucking case
guys actually literally fight better
than they train better inside the cage.
And then there's the rare human being
that when the chips are down,
when it's difficult,
when the situation is intense pressure,
they shine.
Why are at their best?
Do you have a problem?
Uh,
do you think you would have a problem in
your youth?
If you got a guy in trouble to pound on
that guy?
It's hard if you've been hurt before and
you know what you're doing and the guy,
you know,
I think a lot of guys get very upset
when the referee doesn't stop the fight
in time.
And I think for good reason,
like they'll look at the referee then
and go,
what the fuck?
How many times you want me to hit this
dude?
Man,
he's barely defending himself.
Obviously he's out.
But you know,
in the moment,
in the heat of the battle and you,
you catch someone,
you're smashing him,
you know,
it's like,
uh,
I think it also depends on what,
how you feel about that person.
Like the recent fight between,
uh,
Tj dillashaw and cody Garbrandt,
they had this intense and tense feud.
And then finally,
um,
tj catches him,
hurts him,
drops of,
and then puts him out and you could tell
when he smashed it and when he's out,
you know,
he's not,
he's not thinking good things about
lifting off the game.
No,
he's trying to kill him.
And then when cody got up and he was
just still days and t j's in his face
screaming in his face,
the,
there's nothing like fighting.
It's like,
no,
like any others
for,
um,
I,
uh,
talked to a UFC fighter I'm at,
and I'm not gonna mention his name
because I think,
yeah,
I don't know if he wants me to or not,
so I'm not going to do it.
But he told me that he goes into some
fights,
not all of them having a real fear of
hurting his opponent.
And I think it's really hard to do your
absolute best when you have that fear
of,
you know,
doing real damage.
To your point,
I think it's one more element.
Think this guy,
I think he would be a champion.
If you completely get rid of there,
it's very hard.
But when you're going in the ring
hoping,
I mean in your Aco job,
Brian,
to stop this guy to stop you up on it.
And if you're going in and hoping that
you don't hurt him,
then he,
I don't think you can perform to the
utmost capabilities if that's,
you know,
a really,
uh,
foremost in your mind and I don't want
to hurt this.
Yeah.
I think fighters only have a certain
amount of time they can compete as well
for the overwhelming reality of what
they're doing.
Set Tent.
I mean the beginning,
when they're 19 2021,
they're just fucking full of piss and
vinegar and shit and lightning and
kicking people in the head and just,
yeah,
it's just chaos.
And then as time goes on,
you deal with your own injuries.
You,
you start to see people just suffer the
repercussions of a career in combat
sports.
And then as you get older,
you just realize like,
what this is really that you're doing.
So you think rumble Johnson was really
smart.
I think ramp,
well
rumble is the scariest fucking guy at
two oh five pounds.
Terrifying.
Right.
And then decides after a world title vi
like,
I don't want to do this.
I don't want to hug do's.
Get hit in the head.
He goes,
I'm not really a fighter.
He goes to,
as a really good athlete,
I'm preaching real good at it.
Take it easy everybody,
man.
Uh,
you know,
I talked to Ron on social media back and
forth,
really cool kid very early too,
and I respect the fuck out his dcs.
Yeah.
And I respect him,
but he's talked about coming back now.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean it's,
I'm sure that some of them is going to
make him an offer he can't refuse then
he's very marketable.
I'll tell you that.
Yeah.
They do what he can do.
The people destroyed.
GTFO man,
just fucking be strong.
He's a good,
uh,
examples.
Also,
if someone who cut weight when they
shouldn't have,
I hate weight cutting.
I think it's the worst thing that
fighters do to themselves.
I think it's even worse than finding
these guys that get organ failure.
A woman just died in Australia who was
cutting weight for an amateur kickboxing
fine.
It's just a terrible,
terrible practice that people do.
But he was one of the biggest weight
cutters ever.
He was like,
well over 200 pounds getting down to one
70 and when he was at one 70 he was
smashing people.
Yeah.
But as long as it was quick because you
write dehydrated himself so bad that
when he gets into the third,
fourth and fifth round,
he just had nothing left.
He just was so drained at heavyweight,
he will be fucked.
Terrified.
Terror,
terror,
terror.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
If he really wants to do it,
maybe he just needed a break.
I mean who knows?
Sometimes guys just need to take some
time off and he's gonna offer him,
cause he's a very marketable,
I think he's in the weed business now.
I did see a rumble puppies or to
grabbing a few things going on.
Yeah,
he's got a candle.
Yeah.
He's involved
some businesses and you know,
he's obviously not damaged like when you
talked and he's totally,
totally there.
He's not suffered the damage that a lot
of fighters have suffered.
So if he did decide to get out,
now he's at a good place in his life
where he's,
you know,
he's accomplished a lot and he's also,
he's going to walk away unscathed.
Yeah.
As long as he,
you know,
can make money doing other shit.
I don't see,
he would just touch people.
Yeah.
And he would see the lights go out.
Oh my God.
Like glow over to sheriff.
Oh,
nobody ever did that to clover.
Like upper cut and it's over.
It's over.
Go home.
Yeah.
I want to see him punch that thing that
Francis and gone no punches.
He might be right up there with Francis.
I would like to see yeah.
To Randall's and terrifying
human.
Yeah.
Terrifying.
There's a,
you know,
it's,
it's a very,
um,
it's a very interesting sport to fall
because there's so many exceptional
human beings that are competing in this
thing that,
that are involved in this high level
problem solving event.
It's just,
you see these human beings that are
pushing themselves,
their mind,
their bodies to such extreme limits that
it's,
uh,
it's very valuable for people.
Much.
Like I say,
your videos are very valuable.
It's very valuable for people to be able
to watch someone competing at
[inaudible]
high level
paper.
Who Neck?
Man,
if I ain't there in person,
I'm buying anything.
I won't miss it.
Yeah,
me too.
Did He fucking say me too?
It's true,
but I am a fan at all of them,
man.
Not at all of them
than ever before.
I have seen a couple of North American
paper views
really as too much traveling man flying
Australia and shit breaks you down.
I couldn't,
yeah,
I couldn't imagine because like before I
had the heart attack,
I was traveling every weekend.
I'm in a different city,
man.
Yeah,
I have rarely.
It will really run you the fuck down.
Yeah,
but I know my travel schedule,
we had to be nothing compared to yours,
but one year it was a rough one year I
think I did 24 events.
That was the most I ever did at 22 or 24
and it was crazy.
It was like every other weekend I was
flying somewhere and wow.
That was before someone else started
doing like picking up some of the work,
like the UFC then hired a second
commentary team and they started doing
the Fox sports events and different
events.
Yeah,
you gotta have his shit going too.
And I have a family,
you know,
and have some time for all that shit.
But I'd still enjoy it.
I still love it.
Of course we're fine.
How,
how many uh,
uh,
comedian gigs do you do?
Well,
I work all the time.
Like I'm working tonight.
I'm at the comedy store tonight.
I'm working tomorrow,
this weekend.
I'm working in Detroit.
The night before the UFC I got a couple
shows in Detroit,
so I'm always doing stand up.
Stand up is like in a lot of ways like,
um,
like an athletic event and that you have
to be in shape for it.
He can't get out of shape.
If you get a shape,
you'll,
you'll build rusty up there.
And how you deal with hecklers,
John,
just shutting down
most of the time you'd,
you know,
most people don't heckle.
It's the rare dummy out.
Once a bark at you will get them rear
dummy up our rear dummy everywhere
dummies exists.
Map they do.
So listen,
brother,
I gotta wrap this up,
but okay.
I wish you the best and I'm,
I really appreciate you coming here and
I'm really excited that we got a chance
to talk and what I said,
what I said.
I really mean,
I think you're very valuable.
You know,
I think what you've done is,
I mean,
I know it just kind of came to you out
of nowhere by accident,
but I think you've helped a tremendous
amount of people and I know you've
helped me.
Oh Man,
I appreciate that so much and I
appreciate the opportunity to be on your
show.
I feel like I finally made it on the Joe
Rogan experience.
Well,
listen man,
keep us posted with your,
your health and uh,
you know,
we're gonna send you all the best
positive energy and wishes we can and I
really hope you get that transplant and
everything works out well and we'll have
you and afterwards we'll talk about it,
man.
All right.
But actually do ct Fletcher,
Ladies and gentlemen.