Mm,
first of all,
Mr Ventura,
I'm a big fan,
but I'm a bigger fan now that I know
that you're pro fanny pack.
This is huge for me.
I've been trying to bring back the fanny
pack for years.
I've been nothing but ridicule James.
I sent my way.
I find that strange because I'm a huge
fan.
I care.
I have one locked in my hotel right now
in the safe.
You know you gave because they give you
them little safes in the room.
Well I carry my passport in it.
I carry the things that I need to
travel.
If I'm doing airline travel,
my schedules,
I carry two sets of reading glasses.
I carry my sunglasses.
What could be better than a fanny pack
to carry all that sucker.
I don't have the,
you know,
I tend to wear my pants a little tight
and I can't put things in the pocket.
Things break when they get in the
pocket.
No,
I'm a huge fanny pack advocate.
I,
I've warned them now for 20 years I've
had them.
Me Too.
And now you have one of ours.
Yup.
Happy to take it.
Thank you.
I'm honored.
It's a superior carriers stuff and I'll
put it to use.
Thank you.
Well,
and I also,
I've stated this in Minnesota,
I have legit conceal and carry where I
can carry a weapon.
Right.
Where do you think I carry it in your
fanny pack?
Well,
they make fanny pack specifically that
Velcro open instantaneously.
They.
They pop right open.
Yep.
Well if I'm,
if I'm not wearing my shoulder holster,
it's in my fanny pack.
Do you mean how does that work?
Do you.
You're only allowed to conceal carry in
Minnesota and if he goes state?
No,
no.
Many of the states now are honoring the
others.
I say you got to check though,
but generally speaking,
if you can shoot pretty much across the
country now for most part,
if you have a legitimate conceal and
carry in your home state,
the other states will likewise honor it,
but you can't go to the airport with it.
Right?
Of course you can't do anything like
that with a judith to be driving.
That's one of those subjects were much
like the subject of your book marijuana
manifesto.
It's one of those subjects where as soon
as you bring up that subject,
concealed carry,
people just go,
oh,
well,
it's interesting because it's,
it's.
I help shepherd the law through when I
was governor in Minnesota because,
uh,
I was mayor of Brooklyn Park first and I
went to my police chief to get conceal
and carry and he denied me.
I was the mayor.
How could he deny it?
Because it was up to police chiefs.
But why says he don't like it?
Oh,
we just didn't like it and you didn't
like it.
And so I sat back and thought,
wait a minute,
this is ridiculous.
A police chief shouldn't have that
power.
It should be uniformally.
Yeah.
Shall issue if you're qualified.
It shouldn't be left up to him because
like in Minnesota,
if you lived in northern Minnesota,
the rural north,
you could get a concealed carry,
like nothing because the police chiefs
up there didn't care.
But if you live down in the cities,
Ha,
you couldn't get conceal and carry if
you bribed them.
That's interesting because there's a
state law that's Washington wasn't.
It was,
but it was left up to the police chiefs,
so if you went up,
I went and changed that and made it
universal across the state shall issue,
but we required you had to go through an
accredited gun training course.
You had to go to the range and shoot a
minimum of 70.
You had to have a complete background
check done on you criminal background,
everything,
and in the case of a five point,
oh,
eight with alcohol,
with driving,
I made conceal and carry point zero,
zero.
Well those are good and if you're
carrying your weapon,
you are not under the influence of any
alcohol.
None.
That's a.
those are all excellent ideas and that's
where we passed it.
Now if you qualify for all that,
it shall issue.
What?
So what do you stand with?
The NRA has been.
They pushed back and I understand why
they push back against Gun.
Any gun regulation,
anything that comes up.
Regulation in regards to background
checks,
regards to anything because they feel
like ground lost is lost forever and
ever.
It is and it.
And it is a.
where I feel is is that you,
let me put it to you this way,
life experiences.
I was physically in the Philippines,
Philippine islands.
I was physically in the Philippines.
The Day Ferdinand Marcos became a
dictator who I was there now.
I was in the US military on a US
military base,
so it didn't really affect us.
I mean,
we'd go into town and all that,
but there was a.
Then you had a soldier on every corner
with a machine gun.
When he did it.
Well,
here's what I'm getting to.
He became a dictator and gave himself
the power of the president,
the Congress and the supreme court,
complete dictatorship.
The first thing he did as a dictator,
he gave the people of the Philippines a
10 to 12 day grace period to turn in all
guns,
or it was the death penalty.
Now,
my question to the people who oppose gun
rights are,
are are anti guns.
Why would a dictator make his first
thing of business to disarm the public?
Why would he make that as number one
priority?
And it's pretty obvious he doesn't want
to.
Alicia.
Exactly.
Yeah,
and people fail to realize our second
amendment is there for us to be able to
defend ourself against our own
government.
That there it's not there for hunting
and fishing.
When they wrote the bill of rights,
if you didn't hunt and fish,
he didn't eat.
That was irrelevant.
It was there because the British used to
come and occupy our homes,
steal our stuff.
So the British cars,
the Second Amendment to happen to where
our forefathers says,
no,
we're going to allow the people to be
able to defend themselves against
oppressive government.
So do you think that the opposition to
it is just a lack of foresight?
Like the,
the idea that you're living in this time
where for the most part things are very
peaceful.
It's probably the most safe time ever to
be alive and that people have forgotten
that it's entirely possible that tyranny
could erupt at any moment.
Maybe so.
And they don't realize that maybe,
maybe we,
you know,
you got to movements that happened this
year.
You had the Bernie Sanders Movement and
the Donald Trump movement originally.
They wanted the same thing.
They could never get together though,
because once the firefighter left the
others,
the firefighter,
right,
but that what they wanted was a turnover
in Washington.
They were sick of business as usual.
Let's run these bums out,
let's start fresh.
That's what they're two movements were
about and the more we're seeing day to
day,
I mean,
I think Hillary Clinton is obviously a
more rational choice than Donald Trump.
She's obviously a person who speaks
better,
a better representative of the people.
She's intelligent.
She's measured unless she flip flops
constantly,
constantly.
But she's obviously deeply,
deeply embed with the banks and special
interest groups in this most recent
wikileaks release of emails.
It shows that she's been,
she's been with talking with bankers,
making sure that marijuana stays
illegal.
I mean,
this is something that she has vowed to
push back against with all of our might.
And that's a disturbing thing to see in
2016 because my,
uh,
you know,
there's more people locked up.
I don't know if people know this,
but there's more people locked up for
marijuana in this country then for all
violent crimes combined.
And that is terrifying.
It's horrible.
It's terrifying.
It's horrible too.
When you get to.
Like when I did this book and went into
the history.
What's terrifies you there is that our
history books,
our government written with the
government's view of history of what
they want you to know because what
astounded me in doing this book was to
learn that marijuana was the economic
backbone of this country for its first
160 years of existence.
That if George Washington and Thomas
Jefferson were alive today,
they'd be raided by the dea.
They'd be doing 10 to 12 years in the
federal penitentiary for being major
drug dealers because they both raised
massive amounts of marijuana and sold
it.
And and there was a time that England,
when we were the colonies forced us to
grow it because they needed it for their
sales on their ships and the rope and so
that they could colonize the world with
their navy and they forced us to grow
it.
And here you have a product and now all
the.
The reason that I personally have gotten
on the bandwagon,
and I've made this a personal focus is
because I had completely lost my quality
of life and marijuana has given it back.
How so?
Well,
I won't say because of privacy,
but someone extremely close to me,
developed epileptic seizure disorder and
was seizing three to four times a week
and I was taking care of these seizures
three to four times a week.
If you've ever dealt with someone with a
seizure disorder,
it's a feeling of helplessness.
It's a feeling of pain.
You can't even imagine what that
person's going through.
This is the person taking care of them,
and if it's someone you love,
the pain is unbelievable,
and so the person was put on four
different,
one after the other pharmaceutical
medicines for seizures,
right?
None of them worked.
They all had horrible side effects.
The seizures continued for two over two
years.
Finally,
in desperation,
we went to Colorado.
The person got quote,
medical marijuana,
three drops under the tongue three times
a day.
Amazingly,
the seizures stopped.
You have a good friend whose son has an
amazingly.
Now the person's completely weaned off
all pharmaceutical and that's now in
pill form.
The person takes a pill in the morning
appeal at night and has been seizure
free for two and a half years.
Now they've taken a pharmaceutical based
Pilliga,
Marinol,
or they know they're taking real.
It's the other stuff.
The O,
m,
the other.
Not The thc,
but the other thing,
cbd.
Yeah.
That person needs the seat and fact this
person takes zero thc.
All CBD,
so they're not psych.
It's not psychoactive.
What's at all,
which is really a non [inaudible] non
now not even if it were.
Who Cares?
Exactly.
You know,
like my friend Tommy Chong told me,
Tommy Chong said there should be no
difference between medical marijuana and
recreational.
He said the entire plants medical,
those that are smoking it for the
euphoric feeling are doing it for mental
health.
Oh,
absolutely.
Yeah.
So how do you get through this life if
you can smoke a joint in the evening and
it makes you relax and what's the matter
with that?
What's the difference between that or
having a glass of wine or having
anything else while we're just victims
of the propaganda of the 19 thirties and
whether people know it or not.
It was all organized by Randolph hearst
and race spacing,
race based,
and William Randolph hearst who owned
hearst also earned,
owned a bunch of paper mills.
He owned these factors of Timberland and
they came out with a machine called the
decorticator,
whether people know this or not,
and the decorticator made it
economically easy to process hemp fiber,
so they came out with this in the 19
thirties and the popular science
magazine at the time.
It had a cover that said Hampton new
billion dollar crop based entirely on
this new invention that decorticator
because before that they used to use
slavery than when the cotton gin came
around.
They use cotton instead of hemp because
it was easier to get your enjoyable
because I don't have to say all this was
one of those things that I've always
forever tries to be fucking crazy.
After you've done your homework,
it's wonderful because usually I go on a
show,
I'd have to do the explanation,
you know that,
but with you,
I don't have to.
You know it already.
Well,
William Randolph hearst was a real piece
of shit.
He really was.
He was in charge,
not just have these paper mills,
but he was in charge of disseminating
the news.
I mean this guy ran hearst publication
26 newspapers in all white rug,
country and marijuana,
two to race bait to blame the devil weed
that black smoked and then they'll rape
your daughters and your children and
your wives and all that,
and Lazy Mexicans.
That's why they lay around and these
brown skinned people,
these Mexicans are all smoking pot.
You live in Mexico after about four
months out of the fuck is less lazy than
Mexicans,
illegal workers I've ever met.
Exactly.
It is one of the dumbest stereotypes.
All time.
I'll Mexican gardeners go,
oh,
I'll tell you this.
I live off the grid I live where there's
no electricity and our from pavement and
an hour from electricity.
A neighbor built a home down there and I
had nothing to do,
so I'd go watch it everyday.
That's how I lived down there and I
watched these Mexican workers build a
whole lot of cement from scratch.
They didn't have electronic cement
mixers.
They mixed every bit of that cement by
hand and one day I'm watching me.
No,
the rebar,
two guys had to bend rebar by hand,
jerking on it with a pipe to put it at a
45 or 90 degree angle,
whatever it was,
up to code to inspect that building.
Well,
the point was,
I started laughing and I said,
you know,
if you brought the American construction
worker down here,
he'd quit the day.
You will quit in a day where because all
they do is deliver raw materials and
these Mexican builders would build
cement houses out of nothing,
out of raw material without a bit of
electricity.
Yeah.
I'm a big fan of Mexico and I love it
down there.
I love the food.
I love the.
I love the life I lead down there
because it's the exact opposite of here.
Down there.
I live off the grid and I only pay
attention to what I can see.
That's nice.
Relax.
Called flushing your brain out.
My family lives down there.
My parents do.
Yeah.
They decided to chill out down to Mexico
to only do the retirement thing.
I'll tell you what else is great to
taxes and we always laugh at the Mexican
government.
Oh,
they're corrupt.
They're this and that.
On property taxes,
they are way superior to us.
That works down there.
No.
Here,
at least in Minnesota,
which is pretty much universal.
If you buy a home and you're a good
citizen and you fix the home up and
improve it,
how do they reward you?
You pay more for your taxes.
Go up for being a good citizen.
So using their analogy,
you should buy the house,
let it become the shit hole on the block
and they'll reward.
Yeah,
you'll pay less.
Here's how it works.
In Mexico,
Mexico,
you're taxes are due in March.
Property taxes,
if I pay them in January early,
they knock off 20 percent.
If I pay them in February,
they knock off 10 percent.
I go down January 28th,
February's a short month,
so in 30 days I get 20 percent on my
money legally.
Tell me where I can do that.
That's pretty beautiful.
Twenty percent in 30 days.
Now granted it's only a couple hundred
bucks because property taxes are cheap
there anyway,
but that's a couple tanks of gas for my
pickup truck.
Do you feel weird living down there?
Not a bit.
Not at all.
No.
I don't even know the language.
You don't know Spanish now.
Why don't you know?
Because I've never taken time to bother.
I get it down there.
You just basically talk to me.
Well,
between what they know of English and
whatnot,
I know of Spanish and to mining,
we figure it out.
Wow.
It's like,
okay,
all you got to know to survive in Mexico
is one word,
which is just look at all.
No,
look,
not all.
Uh,
that's high.
I see.
I know a little bit now.
No,
no.
You look at it and Mexican smile at them
and say Cerveza and you'll get a smile
back.
Surveys to see.
Oh,
so you just getting hammered all the
time,
just say beer to a May.
Love to drink beer so that will smooth
out any situation.
Just smile and say Cerveza.
Most people don't know also that almost
all drugs are decriminalized in Mexico
in,
in response to the drug laws and the
drug war starting to get there.
The Supreme Court ruled on for people,
but only those four people can grow and
half pot.
It takes three more cases before it
becomes the law.
Yeah.
I don't think it's legal,
but it's decriminalized like mushrooms
at decriminalized getting their
President Fox,
who was my friend,
he came out and said he wants to
decriminalize.
Said I'm a rancher
farmer.
I want to grow at your friends with the
president.
Yeah,
that's pretty dope.
I knew both of them saw a fox and a who
was before him,
a well member.
I was a governor.
I went there on a trade mission.
Oh,
and that's Fox and Fox and I actually
Fox and I actually established a trade
thing in Minnesota via Mexico because
when I was down in Mexico they took me
to the,
uh,
to the corona brewery and when they took
me,
there were pallets of corn all from
Minnesota.
Yes.
He actually send their corn from
Minnesota to make corona beer.
So when you say,
I would assume that like corona is such
a weak beer and as soon as it's probably
grown in America.
No,
it's corn,
but it's United States courts.
Minnesota corn.
That's free.
That makes corona.
Yeah.
Gluten free.
Like if you're one of those gluten free
fucks,
you can have a corona.
So the one of the few beers I think
Heineken to some rice based beers.
I think budweiser actually leave it in
corona though.
They get all the.
They get all their corn from Minnesota.
So you just surveys ended up back there?
No,
I don't drink.
I don't even know.
Drink.
No.
So why do you say Cervesa for your
friends?
Well,
because that means beer and Mexican and
all the Mexicans love beer.
Oh,
I see.
That's why if you just smile and say
surveys,
Adam,
you'll get a smile.
Surveys.
So see.
Oh,
okay.
So you're not asking for.
Well,
I'm not asking for one.
Oh,
I thought you were just doing gay
friendly.
Oh No,
I don't drink.
So what do you do down there?
I wake up in the morning with nothing to
do and when I go to bed at night,
I'm half done.
Ah,
can you tell?
I've been asked that answer.
You can tell.
No,
I stole that from a friend down there.
He said at one day and I said,
can I use that when I do an interview?
He said feel free.
So I wake up in the morning with nothing
to do and by the time I go to bed at
night I'm half done.
Well you obviously wrote this book so
you're doing something.
Yeah.
So why,
why do you write books?
You just get bored and you know,
I write them if I'm motivated.
So you got motivated because of this
epileptic seizure issue.
I don't know if you've ever paid
attention to this,
but,
uh,
the navy seals had an issue with
epileptic seizures as well from the
rebreathers.
Um,
apparently there's something to do with
getting the bug.
I found out about it because I started,
um,
uh,
eating a ketogenic diet,
getting my body to process fat instead
of carbohydrates,
and one of the reasons that the seals
are looking into this is because it
prevents seizures in people that use
those rebreathers as opposed to,
uh,
you know,
the ones that don't make bubbles.
Yeah.
I used them all the time.
The Emerson,
I dove them.
That was the majority of the thing I
dove when I was getting there and I
never had a seizure.
Let's not,
I never heard of anyone having a
seizure.
Some people have them apparently.
I don't know.
I never heard of it the entire six years
I was in.
Well,
it's also a epilepsy in children.
They've used ketogenic diets to,
uh,
to control epilepsy in children.
But again,
like you were saying,
there was another big.
I would think this,
I would think if anyone had any type of
seizure disorder that would him
from the seals.
Yeah.
I don't think it's a disorder.
I think it's a direct result of using
the rebreathers yeah.
But I would think anyone that had that
result from a rebreather would be washed
out.
Yeah.
You think right?
Well,
because you couldn't take the risk that
the person would have to do that job and
could have a seizure while attempting to
do it.
Yeah.
I don't know when the seizures occur.
I don't know if this is the first I've
ever heard of it.
Dr Dom D'agostino,
who is a,
um,
one of the premier experts on a
ketogenic diets and nutritional ketones.
He's,
uh,
he's spoken about this and I've read
some other articles about it as well
about where you've got to be with kids
with epilepsy.
You gotta remember when I was in the
teams it was a whole different mindset.
Well,
it wasn't even called the seals back
then,
right.
You recall the ball fields to were
underwater demolition teams and the
shields both.
It was called Udt seal bugs,
bugs.
Bud stands for basic underwater
demolition slash seal.
What happened was we were the frog man
in in 1962,
John F Kennedy had enough foresight to
realize that wars would be fought by
small units from now on,
so he took the frog men out of the water
and he put them on the land with an
executive order because up until that
point in time,
the navy could go,
not go past the high watermark.
From that point,
it was the marines.
He required President Kennedy to sign an
executive order that allowed the navy to
go past the high watermark,
which he then created.
The Kennedy came out of the Navy,
so he took the navy frogman and put us
on land and they re re named distend
seals,
which the acronym seal stands for sea
air land teams,
which means we come from the sea,
we come from the air,
and we come from the land.
Any of the three.
That's interesting.
That's where the.
That's where it all came from.
Kennedy Forum to seal.
He took the frog man out of the water
and put him on.
The marines were angry because they felt
that the land was theirs in the navy.
Shouldn't be there.
That's always been weird to me that the
rivalry between military units,
you would think that the United States
military is one big team?
No,
because if you're not in a common war
then you got to fight each other.
Isn't that bizarre?
Yeah.
People are fucking crazy.
I went crazy.
When you're in the military,
it's just your.
Your mindset.
Yeah.
You know,
it's your mindset and you get bored.
So if you haven't got an enemy to fight,
then you fight the other.
In the bars,
you fight the other surfaces.
So we used to do it all the time.
We did trouble all the time.
No,
but doesn't that seem stupid?
I mean as well.
One big team wore stupid and if so,
why?
So why?
Why wouldn't there be stupidity along
with wore that?
You're dealing with people with major
egos,
high testosterone rate and their and
their warriors.
You know when you play that game,
that's a game for real.
You know,
many times you don't come back and play
again.
They didn't like football and he didn't
like any of these sporting events.
It's A.
It's a game of functionality.
Did it feel like a game when you were in
the military?
No,
it was my job
most.
Well,
again,
as a pro athlete that your job too,
it feels like a job.
It's your job,
it's your job,
but it's also your life.
I mean it's not a volunteer job,
but you volunteer of course,
to go into the budge,
you have to volunteer,
volunteer unit.
You can volunteer in,
you can volunteer out.
It's whether you want to do the job or
not.
When all that shit went down with Chris
Kyle and the.
When he said that he punched you in a
bar and get you sued the family like,
no,
I didn't.
Well I didn't choose glute ham rather.
Excuse me.
I shooed him and he died and then the
shoot automatically goes to his estate.
That's the way the legal works.
She was never in any jeopardy because in
any writers contract you have insurance
from the publisher,
so it's me again.
They portrayed and I became the villain
going after the widow and the kids.
Exactly.
That's the biggest lie.
It was a big insurance company that's
covering the whole thing.
They're not out a penny and they won't
be out of pain that you had to explain
it,
I'm sure over and over.
No,
I couldn't explain it,
but the tie,
the trial got overturned because the
insurance came out,
so it's okay to lie in court,
but if the truth comes out,
you can get a new trial.
The insurance came out.
What does that mean in court?
You're not allowed to say that insurance
is paying for everything,
even though it's the truth.
You're not allowed to say that in court.
So what happens when you say it in court
while it came out and the judge allowed
it to a limited degree and then the
appeals court ruled that the judge
shouldn't have did that
because having the judge say that it
sways people.
They think that if it all against
insurance companies,
because insurance companies a big.
Even though the other side is doing
what's called poor morale thing,
they're getting up and saying it's
taxing them financially and lying
insurance is paying for all of us.
Don't get up and lie about it.
So the other side was saying this is
going to devastate our reality.
Trying to influence the end and in this
case,
let me state this.
How overwhelming must be evidence of Ben
for the jury to go against the grieving
widow of the dead war veteran?
Yeah.
It must be pretty overwhelming.
The evidence was overwhelming.
The the,
the jury went from.
They came for me.
They said he was lied.
This didn't happen and we're awarding.
Why do you think
he did that?
Did you know him?
No,
you didn't know him,
know him.
I know even thing happened.
We were there on the same nights we were
at [inaudible] because I was there for a
graduation of class 2:58 AM,
class 58.
It's traditionally every hundred classes
if you can,
you come back to the graduation.
So class 2:58 was graduating the next
day on Friday.
I came out along with my team mates from
58 to attend that graduation the next
day.
So why would I say bad things about the
seals if I'm there?
That's what he said he punched me for
will tell,
because people don't know what we're
talking about because probably a lot of
people listening to this have no idea
what we're talking about.
So let me just fill my real clear right.
The,
the book,
American sniper.
The movie with Bradley Cooper was just
giant hit movie,
very patriotic movie about a guy who was
one of the most successful snipers in US
history,
right?
A very successful warrior,
navy seal,
war hero.
Everybody loved him.
Then he goes on the opiod,
Anthony Show and he says that he punched
you out.
Know there's a chapter in his book where
he writes that he called me scruff face.
Yeah.
And you said that.
I said seals deserved to die.
That in other words,
she accused me of treason.
Yes.
And I was out there for a seal
graduation.
If I felt that way about my old unit,
why would I be attending?
So he wrote in the book,
He gave you a nickname in the book,
scruff,
face,
whoever.
I mean he might not have,
even when he wrote it in the book,
he might not have even thought that it
was going to give that to you.
I mean,
who knows what was going on.
My thought was at the time I was trying
to wrap my head around why anybody would
do this and I was thinking,
well maybe he's just trying to generate
as much controversy as possible to
generate as much income as possible from
his book.
And it just got out of hand.
I don't,
I mean,
I'm sure I was trying to put it together
because there was a couple of other
fabrications,
right?
There was a,
um,
a shooting at a gas station that never
took place.
And he said that he,
during Katrina he was on the home and
shot people who were looting.
Yeah.
That was disturbing because that's
murder.
Yeah.
And he also lied about his medals.
The navy had to come out and.
Correct.
He said he had two silver stars and five
bronze stars.
He had won silver star.
And three bronze star.
So we lied about three medals.
Well that's one in three is impressive
enough.
Exactly.
Yeah,
exactly.
And then they try to give them an excuse
saying,
well,
he was confused.
No,
you're not.
When you get a medal like that,
it's like graduating from college.
They give you a certificate that puts on
your wall.
If you win the bronze star,
the Silver Star.
But as a,
as a seal yourself.
And he threw me under the bus.
What does that feel like to you?
Because reason.
But this is obviously,
this is something that's very near and
dear to your who?
Hugely.
He has made it to where I can't go to a
reunion anymore.
There were 170 seals that wanted me
kicked out of the Udt Seal Association
over his lie
and the lives of his buddies who came up
and tried to testify for them.
So what it.
It got embarrassing?
His trial said that it actually
happened.
No,
they couldn't say it,
but they tried to say everything else to
make it seem like it did.
Well.
How the hell they do that?
Well,
because they dance around the questions
and the lawyering and well,
you have to piece together.
There wasn't one witness that saw me get
hit and there wasn't one witness that
heard me say anything.
See attributed to me.
And weren't you visible the next day?
No photographs that night.
Them posing for pictures with me.
If I had said all this stuff,
why would they have take pictures with
me?
What is that feeling like when someone
just fucking lies horrible and when it
makes a lot of terrible,
terrible.
And what's worse about it is the media
jumps on it and convicts me of it
because why they broke the story when I
went off the grid,
Mexico where I couldn't even come back.
So they broke the story.
Do you think they knew?
I'm starting to believe that,
but weren't.
Didn't it happen on the opiod Anthony
Show?
Yeah,
but I don't think that was planned
because I know those guys,
but there was the whole ball.
They all show did it.
He did it that day on O'reilly later
that afternoon.
So he wants.
He named you.
He just started naming you ever.
Oh yeah.
Then it went viral,
it went viral,
and everyone convicted me because they
said,
well,
this Iraq war veteran wouldn't lie.
Really?
I just,
I watched a.
well,
let me tell you all that.
It's destroyed my life.
I can't get hired for a job during my
trial.
After it was over,
guess what happened?
Thirty four major media conglomerates
entered the,
the,
uh,
the trial with that Amis Ama,
cc,
they call it or whatever have of
influencing the court of appeals to
overturn my verdict.
And they did it.
Thirty four media conglomerates that New
York Times the Washington Post.
All of these media conglomerates appeal
to the Court of Appeals to overturn my
verdict.
But why?
Because I won on something called unjust
enrichment.
They want the ability to be able to
defame you and profit from it.
In other words,
I'll put it what they had,
what these judges accommodated them
with.
There's gonna be another trial.
They've ordered a new trial.
So I got to go through it again,
but I'm glad because when it comes out
to juries and two judges find kyle
guilty who's not going to believe it
then and.
But the point is they.
They've ordered a new trial,
they've,
they,
they throughout the whole verdict of the
jury,
the federal judge who wrote substantial
evidence supporting the jury's verdict.
They did all that and they violated
their own rules.
A 76 year rule.
Here's what it states if,
because it happened during summation,
where the judge allowed it in the my
attorney,
it ended up for questions in an 11 day
trial and a half,
a page of a 20 page summary and it was
overturned on that and they overturned
it because they felt that it was undue
influence on the jury that they found
out that insurance was paying for
everything.
So as one factor,
well,
and here's the deal.
If the rules state that if in final
argument they say something,
you must object,
you must object.
So the trial lawyer as a chance to rule
during final argument and the jury has a
chance to hear the ruling,
they never objected
dead,
so they must object to undue influence
because of the fact that it was
wait,
they never objected.
The jury was dismissed at 1158 at 12.
Oh two.
They then objected.
The judge overruled him and we were done
with it.
Well,
these two judges,
Riley and shepherd have now overturned
the case on something that was never
objected to in trial.
They objected to it,
so they overturned the jury and the
federal judge Van.
They also overturned my unjust
enrichment claim because the media
didn't want it.
What they've allowed now is the media
can defame you and profit from it and
you can't get any of their profits and
no matter how they harm you,
while that's the equivalent of if you
went out and robbed the bank and they
caught you and they sentenced you to two
years in prison for the bank robbery.
But when you get out,
you get to keep all the money you took.
So that's in this particular,
this particular,
which will now be the standard,
there's they've ruled that way,
they now make it to where you can profit
from wrongdoing because of this case.
Yep.
This is such a touchy case because it's
so indicative of the complications of
people because people are not simple.
It's really very touchy.
He lied.
He did lie,
but to me with his lie that.
But that's not what I'm saying.
What's complicated is he's also the
subject of this gigantic movie and this
symbol of patriotism where so many
people will say,
Chris Kyle,
rest and peace.
So many people would have a cloud.
That was.
Someone took a photo in the cloud and
that's on a cloud.
That's Chris.
Chris Kyle.
It'll look like a sniper in the car in
this.
It's Chris Kyle guiding a,
guarding the skies.
Like it became a meme.
I mean he became this where it wasn't.
He was a representative of the brave
military,
like the portrayal,
but honestly the betrayal that Bradley
Cooper played in that movie,
that movie was so simplistic and so it
was,
it was like a brand of a Joseph
Campbell.
Okay,
perfect.
Hero's journey.
Had I not gone to court,
that would have been in the movie.
Really?
I had to stop it.
They were going to have him punch you in
the movie.
Well,
the book,
Holy Shit.
And I had to stop it because I know when
we were,
when we were in trial,
you know what they tried to do to
diminish my role because when they knew
they were going to lose their lawyer got
me on the stand and he said,
Mr Ventura.
He said,
would it surprise you to know that the
first draft of the movie doesn't have
you in it?
Trying to prove how insignificant my
first draft of the movie.
That doesn't mean shit.
Well,
the first draft of this.
Yeah,
but so what if the second draft?
Yes,
you ended though.
I said,
here's where my response.
no,
that wouldn't surprise me at all because
I said we've sent two letters to warner
brothers warning them that if I am
indeed in in this movie,
they will be next to be sued.
So we put Warner Brothers on notice that
if this chapters included your movie,
you will get sued next and you know,
people out here,
they don't want to step into a lawsuit.
That's the only thing that kept me from
being punched out in that movie and
portrayed me as a villain in that
frickin movie,
just to fill in way more than a villain.
Right?
I mean,
that is insane.
It is insane because what's.
What's crazy to me and what's
complicated about this is that there are
thousands and thousands of brave men and
women who have risked their lives,
sacrifice their lives,
and this guy becomes.
This is for your head and where is he
rises above including me,
including you.
Yes,
very important,
but he rises above all of this and
becomes this iconic figure.
Yes.
This iconic figure that you can't
tarnish and then the truth is irrelevant
and they're willing to sacrifice people
like you and the truth just for this
overall image of patriotism.
Yup.
It's crazy.
What a crazy place that must've been for
you
still is.
In fact,
do you know that this person that I told
you about,
what the seizures,
the seizure disorders started right
after this.
I'm sure she didn't die from doctors
have said seizures can be caused by
stress.
So I hold Chris Kyle directly
responsible for the seizure disorder
also that I had to face that marijuana
cured.
Did you ever communicate with him face
to face?
Only one set.
The first,
uh,
when we first in June,
I didn't even know who he was.
And then at,
in June of 12,
after the book came out in January,
we had a settlement conference where he
kept saying that if he met me in person,
we could work it out.
So at this conference we agreed I would
meet him in a room,
the judge in the corner and just ski and
I,
like you and I are here.
We sat down in the room and I looked him
right in the face and I said,
why did you do this?
You never punched me.
He looked me back and said,
yes I did.
I turned to the judge.
I said,
there's no need to go any farther.
if he's not going to admit it didn't
happen face to face one on one and I
challenge his courage because yeah,
he had the courage to go to Iraq.
He had the courage to shoot all these
people,
but he didn't have the courage to tell
the truth.
Daddy,
what a bizarre moment that must have
been sitting across from that guy.
Yeah,
and he looked at me and said,
yes,
I did.
What was the look in his face?
I believe,
and I'm not a doctor,
but I've done some studying.
I think he was a sociopath.
Sociopath can lie and hold a straight
face and they lie to the point where
they believe their own lie.
How bizarre is it that this iconic
figure?
Well,
and then look how he died.
Yeah.
Well,
he had no training and posttraumatic
stress.
He's not medical and yet he's taking
this marine to a gun range.
Who suffering from posttraumatic stress
wouldn't common sense tell you not to
put a weapon in the hands of someone
suffering from posttraumatic stress.
Stress is different.
What do they tell him to man up?
Why would you put a weapon in somebody's
hands?
Who's suffering from posttraumatic
stress when you have no medical
training?
How is quite qualified to treat this
guy?
Well,
I would assume it would be based on his
own posttraumatic stress,
but he didn't have it.
He didn't have it at all.
He was never treated for it.
He may have had it.
Maybe that's why he did what he did.
I don't know God,
what a crazy place today,
but.
But the.
For me,
it's like I've been accused of something
I didn't do.
I don't even know the guy.
Never.
I may have met him that night.
Briefly.
Let me some it.
I obviously didn't get a one 1000000th
of a percent of the amount of hate that
you did,
but just read.
I got read off September 11th of this
year.
I was in New York doing this book tour
and I got read off in a hotel lobby over
this.
What does that mean?
Read off?
A guy yelled and screamed at me in front
of the entire hotel lobby,
Jesus Christ.
That's what I live with now and I
haven't been damaged.
My reputation isn't damaged over
something I never did.
What I was gonna say is I obviously
haven't experienced one,
1000000th of the hate that you have,
but I read.
We read this article on the air.
We were trying to figure out what
happened when your case was going on,
and so we read this article that was,
I don't know,
it was in the New York Times,
see if he could find the article
detailing all the various lies.
Oh,
that's an Yorker magazine.
New Yorker in married.
They did an investigation of him,
but it's stunning and just reading that
the the fucking amount of hate tweets
and facebook tweets and you fucking
coward and you this and knew that.
I'm like,
Hey,
I didn't write it.
Okay.
I'm just trying to figure out what the
fuck is going on.
If someone puts something like that in
the New Yorker with verified claims.
I mean,
everything's verified.
What they were saying that he said and
what actually had happened was all
verified.
It's very,
very,
very confusing that somehow or another
this slipped through the cracks and that
this became their iconic figure.
Again,
not discounting along with you.
The thousands and thousands of patriotic
Americans that risked their lives
to.
Nobody's denying.
He wasn't a great sniper.
Nobody's denying he didn't do his job.
I've never denied that from him or said
that about him.
He,
he may be the best.
I don't know.
I'll still put my money on Carlos half
cock though.
The marine as being the best sniper.
Well,
especially now,
but uh,
he,
he did his job and he did it well,
but why did he have to take an old
veteran that would be like me taking a
world war guy and throwing him under the
bus.
Why the fuck would he choose you?
Because I had fame.
He,
I think he got jealous that night.
We were at the bar because everyone
crowded around and wanted their picture
with me.
Wow.
I don't know.
He'll never be around.
Answer it.
I'd love to know why he picked out me.
I think because I'm probably the most
famous maybe,
or I develop to be the most famous seal
other than Dick Marcinko,
the rogue warrior.
Great books.
Read his books.
He's a friend of mine.
Richard Marcinko.
Yes.
Sat down and you're talking to this guy.
How much time were you actually in the
room with them?
Oh,
a couple of minutes.
Was all the minute.
The minute he looked me in the eye and
said,
I sure did he hit you.
I turned to the judge,
said,
we got nothing more to talk about.
You didn't want it.
I offered him.
I said,
if you will walk out to be with the
press and admit you fabricated this
story,
I will forgive you in front of the press
and we will go on with our lives.
He would not do it.
He did not have the courage to stand up
and tell the truth.
It takes a lot of courage to admit you
lied about something that massive.
I mean,
this isn't line about speeding,
right?
This is.
This is a massive,
massive.
What about ruining my life?
Ruining my reputation,
ruining my wife's life route.
I lost my conspiracy theory show because
of it real.
I can't get hired right now.
I can't get a job.
My last job on the Internet at Aura tv
because the owners Carlos slim from
Mexico.
From that you know who I'm hired.
Do you know who I work for now?
The Russians.
Russian TV.
Our,
the only people that will hire me
because 34 media conglomerate centered
this case to overturn me.
You think they're going to hire me now?
Explain that.
Why do you think they did that?
Do you think they did that?
Because if they overturn your case,
if they can somehow or another because
they don't want to check.
But is that it or is that discrediting
you in like that was a gigantic hit
movie.
But if they,
if they can discredit you,
it makes that movie still valuable.
Not only that,
it stops me from running for president.
Don't.
And if they can discredit me,
do you want to run for president?
I thought about it.
Even living in Mexico from Mexico would
have had to forsaken that.
That's why I didn't do it.
They know the,
uh,
the reason why you didn't run for
president because you had to have
forsaken live in New Mexico.
Now I might fucking when I know I,
I think I could have one.
No.
The Libertarians contacted me twice to
come to their convention.
They wanted to nominate tessie,
come back to America.
Com.
Ken and I chose not to do it because I
was up for the campaigning.
I was up to taking on,
taking on the damage and repubs,
but at this point,
at age 65,
I wasn't up to do the job for four years
where I'd have to it and my lifestyle
and Mexico because people don't realize
when you take,
when you get one of them jobs like
president or governor,
your freedom leaves that day.
You don't have freedom.
You're 24 slash seven,
your body at 24 slash seven every day.
You have no freedom whatsoever.
I couldn't go in 100 percent on that and
I felt that if I,
if I to go for president,
you have to be 100 percent committed to
do the job.
If you're not,
you're cheating yourself and you're
cheating all the people that voted for
you.
If you're not 100 percent committed,
I could not reach 100 percent.
So I chose not to.
So is this because of your own personal
feelings about living in Mexico and
having freedom and relaxation and
enjoying the quality of life and also I
knew what would happen to me if I looked
like I was going to win,
I would be politically assassinated.
They would pull up everything they could
on me.
You know,
one of the things they missed,
which I laugh about today when I ran for
governor,
they never found it out and I've
admitted it so it'll show up now,
but they never found out because I'm
sure they would have tried to use it
even though it's irrelevant.
If I'd had gone for president,
they would have,
you know what that is,
but I used to be sergeant at arms of the
Mongols Motorcycle Club.
Really?
What does that mean?
Let's sergeant at arms.
He just the guy third in command,
the Mongols or I've watched some
fucking,
one of those really terrible news shows
where they do
reenactments of.
Well,
the Mongols are strong here in southern
California where the black and white.
We're the ones that fought war with the
hell.
What's the black and white?
That's our colors.
Oh,
okay.
The angels are red and white.
The Mongols are black and white guys
have shootouts with the angels
occasionally.
Do you have one of those jackets worthy?
Worthy?
Yeah.
I have that at home.
No.
I was an officer so I was allowed to
keep mine.
So what does that mean?
Like what did you guys do at that time?
It was 1973.
I rode harleys and I was still in the
navy.
I used to leave the base and put my
colors on the went like sergeant at
arms.
What does that mean?
You had to carry guns?
No.
Sergeant.
And you got the president of the
chapter.
You got the vice president.
Third is the sergeant at arms,
fourth is the secretary is very
militaristic.
Nobody wants to be the secretary.
Yeah,
you do.
That mentioned officer job,
you know,
but you keep track of all the money and
stuff.
Well,
what the fuck the do like do you just
drive around bikes and party?
But why do you need all that,
uh,
those rankings and file and because
there,
because it's a club,
it's.
No,
it's,
it's like,
uh,
the,
the elks,
they have presidents of the elks club,
they have presidents of whatever other
stuff there is at the elks club.
Doesn't get any gang wars with the Moose
Club.
Well,
you never know.
You never know.
They might have or know a turf war could
happen in the navy and the army,
like the elks and the Moose Club.
And in my day a lot of the outlaw bikers
were former military.
Yes.
And that was a big thing with the hell's
angels because you can haul coming back,
you had your camaraderie,
Brotherhood if you wanted.
I did.
Felt disenfranchised.
Right?
I did it more for the adventure I was
getting out of the seals.
I'd done two tours,
a 17 months in southeast Asia.
I was going to transition into private
life.
I was riding a Harley,
my two buddies that I'd written with a
year earlier.
We're now full patch Mongols when I came
back from my second deployment.
Let me,
let me pretend to be a douchebag
politician running against you here.
Yeah.
I would say are you really prepared to
have a former sergeant of arms from the
Mongols Motorcycle club running the
United States of America?
I don't think so.
Ladies and gentlemen.
And I would counter that and say nobody
messes with the Mongols.
Nobody will mess with the US.
Wow.
That's,
um,
that's.
People didn't mess with the Mongols
though.
And you don't really know that I would
have to help you.
Let's not do that.
No,
they don't.
They do mess with the Mongols,
right?
Don't they have warrants something if
those guys have,
don't they shoot it out and like Texas
steak houses and Shit,
didn't they have flexible hours?
Which ours was Harrah's nightclub and
uh,
in,
Nevada law.
That was.
Yeah.
When was that?
That was back in.
Oh yeah.
But there was a big one a couple of
years ago.
Right?
Not with,
not with,
with the Mongols.
With us,
you're saying,
oh,
so you're still with them?
Huh?
They're like a marine.
You're a marine for life,
that kind of thing.
You got a card on you.
What are you just going to pull out his
God damn on gold card.
I don't believe this.
When he got in there,
it's got a wallet.
He's going to pull out a Mongo card.
Let's see.
Right.
Next is Disneyland Year Pass.
Oh,
let me see here.
I've got to.
Got to Disneyland.
I got to find it.
No,
cause I tuck it away.
I actually.
You have a Mongo card?
I would think that you would need a
tattoo.
I would say.
Listen Bitch,
if you really want to be down for life,
we're going to get.
Get a tattoo.
I already have a tattoo of the Mongols.
No,
what is it like a UDP tattoos?
I have to try.
The Budweiser Tried Trident and uh,
you try and find your Mongo card.
How many of those cards you actually
heard mine look at that.
And there's the card from Geo.
The Hollywood press gave me his last
time I saw on Bam.
Motherfuckers legit,
too legit to quit.
That's hilarious.
That is hilarious.
And My name was,
I dunno.
What was your name?
Find it on there.
You never go by your real name?
Superman.
Super.
Why did they call you superman?
Because I was in such a physical
specimen that when I was prospecting,
they make you do pushups and stuff and I
liked it.
Oh,
so this is back in the Jesse before the
Jesse.
The body Ventura,
yeah.
This was back when I was transitioning
out of the shields into civilian life
and in fact if there's a good transition
I can tell you about that shows how a
book should do due diligence before they
write something.
There was a book written by William
Queen and atf agent who infiltrated the
Mongols.
It's called under in the loan and he
infiltrated them and put like 25 of them
in prison.
Well,
in the book they wrote that I was a
former Mongol governor,
Jesse Ventura,
Blahblahblahblahblah Blah.
Right,
right.
You know what they did before the book
was published,
a sent me an entire copy of the book.
They should.
Governor,
please read this and if you have any
problems,
call us.
Show.
I read the book.
I didn't hide from the fact that I was
in the Mongols.
I never do a.
But I did want them to change something
and they did.
When I called them,
I said,
you stated the history of the Mongols
that we started off like all white
supremist outlaw motorcycle clubs.
I said,
I would never join anything that was
white supremist.
I said to me,
a biker is a lifestyle and the color of
your skin has nothing to do with it.
And I said,
and the Mongols were not white
supremacy.
And she said to me,
well,
governor,
how can you prove that?
I started laughing.
I said,
I think I can prove it easily.
She goes,
tell me their stay editor at random
house.
I said,
at what time did Mexicans become white
supremacy?
Because I said the Mongols are 75
percent Latino,
Mexican.
I was one of the few white guys who
could ride into east la and never be
bothered because of my patch.
Uh,
so how can you call us what the Mongols
started?
Because they weren't,
Mexicans weren't allowed in the hell's
angels.
See,
I sold like this.
So the Mongols were the Mexican bikers
started their own bike club because they
weren't allowed to be angels.
Will they allow white guys?
But how did they miss that in writing
the book?
That seems stupid that it's any better,
but that seems like a giant error.
It was.
That's why I had them pull out white
supremacy.
I said,
and she started laughing when I said,
well,
I've never met a Mexican white
supremacy,
have you?
She said,
no,
I haven't either.
I said,
well,
we're 75 percent Latino Mexican.
She goes,
really?
I said yes.
And I gave her the history.
The Mongols started because the hell's
angels wouldn't allow Mexicans.
That's hilarious.
And that's how the Mongols got started
in 1970 because they're 75 percent
Latino Mexican,
but they didn't have the same.
You could be white,
you know,
I was a minority in the Mongols to know.
Was there crime involved in the Mongols?
I don't know,
doing it,
like I told them I was still in the navy
and they used to protect me whenever
we'd have church,
trash churches meeting,
they call it church and whenever we'd
have church,
uh,
if it got to anything that was at all
illegal,
my pres would send me out to watch the
bikes.
That's fucking weird.
Well,
they knew.
No,
they knew I was in the military.
Yeah,
I finished.
Doubles are too,
you know,
because I'd faced double.
I'd face military justice as well as
civilian.
A lot of these guys are old military.
They did it to protect me.
I appreciate that.
But didn't feel bizarre to you to be a
part of a group that was probably doing
some illegal shit.
No,
because I thought at least I won't go to
jail.
Not Me,
because I don't know nothing about it
and he didn't care.
You love them no matter what I loved
riding are.
You should see what I'd get pulled over.
We get pulled over by the CHP,
California highway patrol back then and
I'd pull out my active duty military id
and they'd look at me.
And what are you doing with these guys?
I said they liked to ride bikes.
So do I can't just ride a bike by
herself?
No.
No,
because cars have no respect for you.
So you're right by your writing.
If you're riding and looking like you
showed what they're up on the screen a
little while ago,
you think the cars are going to bother
you?
They're going to get the fuck out of
your way.
It's right.
Oh,
that's interesting.
Well
wow.
And d still put on jackets and still get
on the Harley.
Yeah,
except the Aina.
Harley.
What do you ride now?
I ride a custom chopper that I had built
and it turned out there's not one harley
thing on it.
I have an ss one slash 24 engine,
which is bigger than anything.
Harley's got v twin by ss out and Viola
Wisconsin.
Uh,
I,
I have an ss 1:24 cubic inches.
The biggest Harley I think is 102 CD
drive.
This around Mexico?
No,
I drive it in Minnesota and uh,
and I have a,
it's a rolling thunder frame.
Arlen ness,
front end and primary cover,
a ref tech,
a six speed transmission,
curiosity and gears.
It turned out when I built the whole
chopper in the end,
there wasn't one thing Harley on it.
Is that good?
I don't know.
It's all custom made notes.
I put the old sissy bar that goes way
up.
I made a.
I made a custom bike to these things.
The APE hangers.
You do that?
Yeah.
I got the.
A pen or some others?
No,
mine aren't that high miner about right
here.
Right here.
Seems logical.
Yeah.
That seems logical.
These guys know I don't go that high,
but I haven't extended front end.
Why did they do that though?
With the up up high handlebars be cool,
but you can't steer.
It doesn't matter.
It does.
If you have to get that thing to an
outline,
not to us.
And through us,
it's all about man,
Mr. No,
it's all about being cool.
I get it.
But you're a bunch of things like sissy
bars,
you don't have them today.
The guys who built the bike didn't even
know what they were.
What's the sissy bar?
That's the bar that sticks up high in
the back.
Oh,
okay.
Well yeah,
that's.
They call it.
So you don't slide off the seats.
But she to me,
I don't like saddlebags shore Sushi
bars.
The replacement.
I'm going to bungee anything I need to
take with me on the Sissy Bar,
like the sleeping bag and anything else.
You're taking a bungee it to the sissy
bar for when you drive down the road
because I don't dig saddlebags.
So you'll drive down the road to go
camping somewhere?
No,
I wrote,
actually I rode when I got out of
office.
I wrote all over Minnesota fly in my
colors and no one even recognize me.
You know why?
Why I went to a place I had a full beard
after I taught at Harvard and so Johnny
Depp had come out and in Captain Jack
Sparrow.
So I went to a place with a pitcher and
I says,
can you make my beard look like that?
And they go,
sure.
So they braided my preamble when you
were doing that.
All the braids,
right.
But then they talked me into letting me
put dreadlocks.
They sold them into my hair and they
dyed my hair jet black.
I had dreadlocks to hear the thing like
that.
I rode one year after I was out of
office,
I drove all over Minnesota with
dreadlocks to my shoulders.
The beard,
no helmet because we don't have a
helmet.
Law and people were locking their doors.
I had my Mongo colors on and here I'm
the governor.
It was great.
Never recognized as so never recovered
because I had dreadlocks.
They gave me all the way to the
shoulders.
Now why are you riding around with no
helmet on?
Why?
Because you don't have to in Minnesota.
Yeah,
but why wouldn't you want to protect
your head?
Ah,
I don't like helmets.
I don't think they should be mandatory.
I think something far more.
You know what?
I laugh at what?
When you see someone wearing a helmet
and riding a bike with tennis shoes,
it's far more important to have over the
ankle boots as a biker than a helmet
wise that you feet touched the ground.
What's the.
What's going to stable you?
If you start sliding out your foot,
right?
You don't want tennis shoes.
You want an over the ankle laced up
boots,
so your boot or something dump.
You'll be able to protect your head.
I don't know,
but I.
it's a choice of freedom,
but what about when a little skullcap
jammies that go like a hat?
What if?
What if my head starts itching?
Tasers.
Christ.
Scratch it.
No,
you got to rub the helmet.
That's why when you see a biker rubbing
his helmet,
it's because his head's itch and what?
We'll just look at me,
put it to worry about an itch.
Wait,
I'll accept helmets on motorcycles when
they make people in convertibles that
don't have roll bars.
Have to wear them.
I have a convertible.
It doesn't have a robot.
Then you should have to wear a helmet.
It's good point.
What if you roll that car and you don't
have a helmet on?
It's a very good point.
There you go.
I think about skills.
So the day that you got to have a roll
bar is the day I'll put the helmet.
All right buddy.
Relax.
And I can't wait to see these women in
Beverly Hills with their convertible
Mercedes having to put helmets on.
Well those actually have roll bars built
in.
They pop up on one wheel,
goes off the ground.
And if you know about that.
German engineering.
Yeah,
they're very.
They're on the ball.
Well I owned Porsche portion on Abbott.
What do you mean portia doesn't have it?
What year?
I got a 2000 and a 2003.
You.
So you have a nine,
nine,
six?
No,
I.
well I have a,
I have a boxster s and I have the twin
turbo.
Okay.
Well that should have that built in.
It should have it.
So when I'm a hard worker,
I'm a hard top though.
I'm a boxster.
Know the twin turbos a hard top.
Yeah.
Right.
Okay.
That doesn't have a roll bar.
Yeah.
But you,
you have a voxster Yep.
The boxer,
she'd have something.
It has something.
Yeah.
Because anything.
I think anything past the nineties
that's a convertible has some sort of a
built in Rollbar or some sort of report
or seen it?
Yeah.
Well you haven't flipped it,
but the new ones that I'm getting rid
of,
both of them.
I'm buying a tesla.
Oh,
you're getting crazy.
Go into Tesla.
Test drove a tesla.
It's unbelievable.
Oh,
they're amazing.
Oh yeah.
I and I want to feel young.
It's a computer driven car.
No gas.
That makes you feel young.
Yeah,
because I grew up in the sixties with
all the muscle cars and I never dreamed
there'd be electric cars that can beat
any combustible engine out there off the
line because the Tesla can beat
anything.
Pretty much.
Yeah.
My,
my twin turbo professionally driven will
do zero to 60 in two nine.
The Tesla does it into six
unprofessionally driven.
Yeah.
No,
they're ridiculous.
Ridiculously fast.
Yeah.
It's called,
you know what they call?
It's called the ludicrous option.
Took it right out of spaceballs.
Yeah.
Ludicrous.
The guy's got a sense of humor.
He definitely does the ludicrous option,
but no,
I and see I'm going to do my house in
Minnesota,
totally solar and I'm going to do it to
where it's 105 percent so that way I can
also feel my car's up off the sun so I
will be completely off any type in my
home or my cars will all be powered in
Mexico and Minnesota by the sun.
That's excluding my cars.
That's awesome.
As long as you don't have to go on a big
road trip,
they now have it.
It's all computerized to where you can
show where you can charge up again and
they're getting 300 miles now to
recharge and you know,
what else is great about the Tesla?
Well,
it depends how you drive.
You know,
what else is great.
Is there a warranty?
Eight years,
unlimited mileage,
and in that eight year period,
any improvements made to the car.
You get free upgrades like digital
upgrades,
anything that's amazing for eight years,
so eight.
You could own the Tesla for eight years
and some doing an ad for them.
You could own a Tesla for eight years
and the car you own eight years from now
will be identical to whatever they're
selling new.
Yeah.
I drove one for a day.
There's a a.
What does that fucking company called?
Skirt?
Yeah.
There's a company called skirt and they.
It's like a uber for rentals.
They deliver a rental.
You drive for a day or what?
As long as you need it,
and my issue was at the battery.
Just ran out way too quick for me for
what I do.
I just do too many.
For me.
It ain't because I live in Minnesota and
I never drive over 100 miles in a day.
Right.
Golf course and that far right.
I get it.
I know for me in my lab,
65 now,
I don't need to be trapped.
I've never.
Do you know something that'll shock you?
I've never owned a cell phone and I
never will.
I was going to text you.
I,
you can't.
I don't have a cell phone.
I've never given.
You don't have a cell phone for what?
I like talking to people.
Are you kidding?
I was out in New York,
I was out in New York doing this book
tour and I forget I was at serious and
we were in the green room and there were
10 people in that green room.
Nine of the 10 sat there the whole time
doing things with a phone.
Right.
I was the only one who sat and looked
around the room and watched nine other
people zeroed in on a screen,
which if you count TV and that what we
spending 16 hours a day now looking at
screens,
I believe in evolution.
What's that going to lead to?
It's going to lead to some strange times
for sure.
But a strange people to.
But wouldn't you rather just have it and
have the discipline and not use it?
No.
No,
just fiber one.
I never took typing.
So if I'm going to send anything it'll
take me too long.
The thumbs when I taught,
when I taught at Harvard,
uh,
I actually sent my only email there to a
student because on email he will always
lie.
Ended up,
I send a couple,
but they actually taught me how to use
computer while I was teaching at Harvard
in my office and I actually students
would want to talk to me so I'd have to
line up a schedule and I actually,
I sent an email to a student or I told
them,
this is the first email Jesse Ventura's
ever sent in his life.
Do with it as you see fit?
I'll Betcha the students still got it.
Knowing that I have the first email.
Jesse Ventura ever sand.
That's when I left Harvard.
There went the computer.
I haven't done it since.
I don't have a computer.
My wife does.
Wow.
She does all that.
I don't.
So that's probably one of the main
reasons why this whole Chris Kyle thing
blew up.
And you had no idea about it.
I was in Mexico.
In Mexico.
You don't have any internet?
No.
I have Internet there.
Yeah,
that's how I learned.
My son sent me an email telling me about
what happened.
So you had an email?
Yeah,
and I have skype so I had to end up
getting through that satellite.
I had to get my attorney to file the
lawsuit immediately to stop him from
from this story,
but he.
They continued promoting it for another
six months.
In fact,
you know how bad the book company did.
Harper Collins,
who's the same company that owns Fox
News,
they're all under the same umbrella.
Harper Collins,
if you would have typed my name and on
the Internet,
would have immediately sent you to the
Chris Kyle Story.
They did that to sell more books.
Wow.
See the conspiracy that I went against
in this deal.
Now I got to go through it again.
Well,
it's so long ago.
It's so crazy that it's still going on.
I mean,
this is 2012,
right?
Yeah.
It happened in 2012 and it's now 2016.
It's over four years.
It'll be.
It'll be five years in January.
How do you stay calm and all this does.
Is it this stress lessened at all or no?
What are the consequences for you?
If you lose a financially it's cost me
over a million dollars.
Jesus.
No one's while I'm the plaintiff.
No one pays for me.
It's cost me over a million dollars for
years of attorney fees and the courts
and everything that's gone with it.
It's cost me a million dollars to clear
my name.
Now.
If I had done this,
why would I do that?
Never happened.
Why would I spend a million dollars in
court clearing my name has over time
when more information has come out about
the other things that he said that
turned out to not be true.
Has Public opinion started to shift
towards your way?
It has now.
Someone has to somewhat,
but you still have these people who will
accost me in hotels had happened in
Mexico to what happened when a person
came up to me in a hotel lobby and read
me off and what do you say?
I say,
but I didn't do it and all I'm doing is
seeking the truth.
You don't want to leave.
They don't keep it going after the
family says that,
yeah,
they think I'm going after the family,
which the family isn't going to lose a
nickel.
It's a big insurance that I'm fighting
hired.
Anybody knows this,
this read a Britain a book,
because in your contract it states if
any lawsuits come of this nature,
the publisher will handle it.
Right?
The publisher handles it,
but there is there any consequences to
the family where they don't profit as
much because of the fact there's a
lawsuit.
The lawsuit cuts back in the profits for
the book and the movie?
No,
because the insurance company will pay
the whole lawsuit.
It seems to me where they hire and they
hire them before the books ever even
written errors and omissions,
right?
Yeah.
What?
Yeah,
and show no,
it won't affect an anything in the
lawsuit itself won't effect the
popularity of the book unless unless
they find out he was a liar and don't
choose to read his book because I've
never read his book.
Why would I?
He wrote a lie about me.
How could I believe anything else in it?
What a terrible position to be in.
Oh yeah.
Especially when you're innocent,
not just innocent,
but you are either respected celebrity
in his sixties in this happens.
This is.
It's kind of a crazy feeling.
Yeah.
Especially when you didn't do nothing.
What else could you have done?
I mean,
it's almost like you have to go to court
over this.
I had to.
It was such an iconic movie and such an
iconic thing.
Have you ever talked to Bradley Cooper?
No,
I don't hold nothing against him.
Of course he shouldn't have hector doing
a job.
Now you know my friend directed at Clint
Eastwood.
He's a friend of mine in Christ.
And what did you talk to clint?
No,
Jesus.
No.
The whole thing is so fucked up.
It's just so crazy that you sat across
the table from this guy and he tells you
he did it.
He tells you I did punch you.
Yeah.
And I know he didn't and I know he
didn't have the courage to face up to
the truth or,
or mental capability of him.
Wouldn't let him.
I don't know what it was.
Something wrong.
Some fuse blown.
So I don't know.
I don't know.
But why would you take one of your own
and throw them under the bus?
Would be like me doing it to a World War
II guy.
Just fucking crazy,
you know,
and especially I like to tell people,
remember us Vietnam veterans,
we weren't cheered.
We got blamed for the war in which is a
big part of what the hell's angels was
all about.
Trying to find comradery in another
group,
but we got blamed.
The politicians blamed us for the war
and the public sentiment here in that
country.
At that time we were baby killers.
We were all these horrible vial you guys
got spit on when they came home and it
was the first time in history in the
United States history that veterans came
back and were treated that way.
Whereas every guy will tell you this for
10 years I didn't even acknowledge I was
a Vietnam vet.
Wow.
Because you didn't even acknowledge it.
No one wanted to know you were.
Nobody said,
welcome home to you.
Nobody.
Thank you.
These IRAC guys,
they get parades for them.
So interesting because it seems like in
that sense they got that right.
At least at least.
It's not like the way the Vietnam
veterans were treated,
but this,
this fucking story just doesn't sit
right with me.
It's just horrible.
It's so uncomfortable.
It's so uncomfortable because how would
you like to have lived it for five years
like I have,
I couldn't imagine,
but what's so uncomfortable about it is
that I feel like the sentiment behind
the movie and the public's perception of
the movie and the public's,
the public's love and gratitude towards
him and the rest of the military was to
me like a a,
an amazing moment in a lot of ways.
It's like people.
People wanted to let me get.
Let me,
let me give you a different perspective
for a moment.
[inaudible].
I talked about this on my internet show.
Who's more powerful?
God or government?
A government.
You want to know why?
Yeah,
well,
God says something very simple.
Thous shalt not kill.
There's no asterisks by it.
There's no except for this reason or
that reason.
It's simple.
Thou shalt not kill,
but yet you can kill at the behest of
government and it's okay.
Yeah,
it's super complicated.
Okay,
wait,
and if and if you kill a bunch of people
at the behest of government,
they make you a hero.
Yet God says,
thou shalt not kill you.
Had a fight,
kill a lot of people for the government.
I'm a hero.
How can that be?
How could there be a double standard
like that that swallowed shows
completely that governments more
powerful than God because government
allows you to kill when God says you
can't and government rewards you for it
and make gives you hero status for it
and God doesn't do anything about it.
It is pretty complicated thinking when
God is a big part of the military.
I mean when the nine slash 11 happened,
when the nine slash 11 attacks happened
and George Bush on television said that
God is with the troops.
I mean the worst thing I ever heard him
say when he was trumping up the Iraq
war,
I'll never forget it because I opposed
the Iraq war before it even app.
I said,
this is ridiculous.
Iraq and have nothing to do with nine
slash 11.
Why are we invading Iraq?
Well,
I'll never forget bushes.
Press conference where he walked out and
announced that he was sending in our
military.
We're going to attack Iraq and he was
getting ready to leave the stage and a
final reporter asked him,
Mr President,
did you consult your father?
Meaning Bush senior because you know
Bush Sr had that Kuwait Iraq thing
happened during his watch and I'll
never.
George Bush turning around to the press
and the American people smiling and
going,
no,
I consulted a higher father.
I was sitting in my chair at home and
almost fell out of it.
I said,
this guy wants me to believe that he
talked to God and God told him to invade
Iraq.
You're saying you consulted a higher
higher father.
It's like going up to a rock and in Iraq
what you should do with your life,
like you're not getting any answers,
but excuse me,
and then I said,
I've been on the earth as long as this
guy.
I'm twice the man George Bushes and God
ain't never said a word to me in my
entire existence.
Yet this guy wants me to believe God
talks to him.
Yeah.
They just let that go and just say,
just talk to me.
Just let that slide.
He consulted God.
He consulted a higher father there,
be right back,
so in other words,
she,
he wants us to believe that his invasion
of Iraq had God's blessing and all the
people of this country,
except that it's one of those convenient
acknowledgements and Jesse Ventura can
say it because I've come out of the
closet.
You've come out of the closet for what?
I'm an atheist.
You're an atheist in that you don't
believe I don't believe in higher.
No,
ain't selling me on that.
Do you tell the possibility of something
happening when you die?
No.
You don't know if he die.
You just go dark.
I don't know if that's a wrap.
That's a wrap.
Hmm.
There's no proof.
Right.
Then anything else happens.
It's just definitely need proof just to
belief to me,
I don't believe it because like I said,
I've been on the planet 65 years now in
God's never spoke to me.
Now if I'm wrong,
people said,
well,
what if you're wrong?
I'll say,
well,
God made me with a brain to think did
me.
He's going to condemn me because I used
it.
Well,
religion in a sense,
it's pretty ridiculous.
The idea that God came to people a long
fucking time ago when the books and you
told everybody about the world.
Have you heard about water?
Everybody just pass it down.
You know about horror?
Sure.
Well,
horace was an Egyptian God who has the
identical same bio is Jesus only
predates and buy a couple hundred years.
So who's the real one?
They did this.
They were both born of a virgin.
They both walked on water.
Allegedly,
they both healed the sick.
They both were crucified and buried.
Rose again from the dead.
Jesus did it.
And so did horace.
What is a ton of parallels throughout
history and that's my point.
That's why I'm not a believer.
Well,
I'm not opposed either.
Interesting that ancient people said
about be communicating with higher
powers and passing down laws that must
be without a doubt followed and some of
them are ridiculous.
You can't wear the same tie back.
Two different types of cloth.
I mean,
you can be put to death for wearing two
different types of cloth.
Mean,
I don't know if people know that.
There's a lot of really fucking goofy
ones.
What about the story of who is the
gentleman in the Bible where he was bald
and two children mocked him for his
baldness,
so a God sent to bears to attack the
kids and more of them and killed them.
That's in the Bible.
Old Testament stuff.
Yeah.
Make Fun of a bald guy like you and me
and a fucking bear comes and kills kids.
What are your rights?
What do you find these barriers?
I'd like to recommend is that I've been
made fun of enough.
Could I have a couple of attack bears?
Then the next day,
the biggest fund,
the most ridiculous thing to say and to
put that in the Bible,
like the fact that two kids can make fun
of you being bald and so God punishes
those kids by having a fucking bear
attack them.
How about it doesn't bother you if you
bald like,
well,
a lot of a pussy.
Are you taunting you?
How about the fact that they tell you
that the world's only 5,000 years old?
I think it's 10 or 10,
whatever,
five,
10,
whatever the hell it is.
I don't keep track of it,
but I mean how ridiculous is that?
Well,
they've done it very scientifically than
counted up all the ages of all the
people in the Bible.
So I don't know how you are arguing with
this.
They're very accurate book.
It's hilarious to that.
They'll say,
well,
that's old testament.
You don't follow the Old Testament.
Oh,
so you want to follow the book that was
written by Constantine and a bunch of
fucking bishops.
Not only that constant team wasn't even
a Christian until he was on his
deathbed.
Constantine converted when he was at
dying old man.
He wasn't a Christian through his entire
shoulders.
Hope for Jesse.
Hope for.
I'll just follow Constantine when I get
to the dying bad.
If I find out there's God,
I'll just see the light is hedge your
bets.
Look,
if there's no,
it's like a liquid Danville's.
Arian would say you can't lose in this
bet because if you're wrong and there is
no god,
like if you.
If you get to the deathbed and you
convert to Christianity and you're
wrong,
and there is no god,
it doesn't matter anyway.
It's all just darkness,
right?
You just go blank.
But it kind of.
Right.
You know,
it's kind of like the Republicans and
the Democrats.
It's Kinda like you filing your taxes
January 28th.
No,
his slip in a couple of days.
It's like the Republicans and the
Democrats was that.
Well,
they vape.
When you go to their conventions,
the lobbyists 10 both and they pay off
both sides show it doesn't matter who
wins the presidency.
They've already.
It'd be the equivalent of betting on the
superbowl.
If you bet on both teams,
you don't lose,
do you?
Well,
that's,
that's what the lobbyists do.
They bet on both teams.
So whether Hillary or trump wins,
they got their base covered.
It don't matter to them.
They've already paid them off.
The only thing that really changes
whether it's right to left,
is the the aspects
of society that are affected by the
social changes.
Like Obama was much more lenient towards
gay marriage,
towards a lot of social issues,
but he was much more strict on putting
us under more surveillance,
which is a social issue.
Yes.
Uh,
so it,
it plays out the same way.
He may have been lenient on certain
social things and then more people are
now in jail and look what he does to
whistle blow as far as.
Yeah,
I was going to bring destroys them and
show everybody that syncs.
Obama is kinder to the people on social.
Not really.
It seems like it on,
on the surface when you look at his
demeanor and the way he carries himself,
but then when you look at the actual
actions ventral.
Yes.
Well he's the most presidential
president we've had,
and I'll say this,
he's the most dynamic speaker since Jack
Kennedy.
See,
I don't think he's that dynamic more.
I think Obama,
I think he's kind of beaten down by
time.
Nobody's eight years in now and you've
heard of long enough.
But he is the most dynamic speaker since
guy,
but he's not.
The actions don't back the words the
words before he ran,
when he was running for office,
I was like,
Holy Shit,
this is the guy.
This is the guy,
and the same thing's gonna happen with
Hillary.
All the women out there that think,
oh,
we're going to get our first female
president.
Yes,
you're going to get them,
but it ain't gonna be nothing different
and you're going to get the same
government completely because Hillary's
a globalist.
She supports all the global initiatives.
She's also for war.
The finger troubles me when they attack
trump,
and I'm not a trump supporter,
but hillary,
they claim Hillary as the experience.
Well,
let's look at it.
When she was a senator,
the most important vote she took was to
vote in the affirmative to invade Iraq.
She now admits that was her biggest
mistake.
Excuse me,
Madam Clinton.
That was the most important vote and you
blew it.
Now you're going to have your finger on
the button.
What happens if you make the same
mistake that you made with the war on
Iraq,
which you now admit was the worst vote
you took as a senator?
Approving the Iraq war and yet she took
it,
didn't she?
She voted to the affirmative.
Let's go to war with Iraq.
Yeah.
It's very troubling.
The momentum of influence of all these
lobbyists and special interest groups
and all the money that's behind her.
All the bankers,
all the different people that are paying
her for these $250,000 an hour speeches.
At what point in time do you gather up
enough money where this doesn't make
sense anymore when we start thinking
about your children and your children's
children in the future of the world,
or do you think that she thinks she's
doing the right thing?
She thinks she's doing the right thing.
That's the system that that's the system
you have to play within the system.
The system they've created,
the Democrats and Republicans is a
system based upon the concept of
bribery.
Now,
if you do bribery in the private sector,
you go to prison,
but in the public sector,
it's completely alive and well.
That's why I don't trust any career
politician because that means they are
comfortable in a system of bribery,
a corrupt system,
and if they're comfortable to work in
that corrupt system for all those years,
that means they're corrupt too.
You could when you know you could be the
president.
I know you were one of the few
independents that I know they really
could win.
I know.
Especially now.
You see what's going on now with trump
and the what I call grab the pussy gate.
If grab the pussy date gate doesn't.
He's fucking moved up in the polls.
He's moved up since the first debate.
What?
This is madness.
I mean we're.
We're dealing with a mad,
mad world right now.
Well,
we're dealing with what I see in the
United States today.
At least a faction of it.
We are going down the identical road of
19 thirties,
Germany.
Look at what we're doing.
We're marginalizing one group of people,
the Mexicans.
They're responsible for everything bad
in the country.
Right?
What did the Germans do?
They did that with the Jews.
They got all the other people angry at
the Jews,
all the Germans so that they could ride
everything we're doing right now.
Parallels 19 thirties,
Germany to a t.
You know what's really crazy waging wars
throughout the world were invading
countries.
Uh,
I don't know if you know this,
but there was a poll taken three years
ago by Gallup and it never got any
publicity here.
International poll,
3000 people I think.
And they pose no Americans,
nobody from the US.
And they posed the question,
if your country where to go to war
today,
who do you think it would likely be
against?
Twenty three percent answered the United
States.
Eight percent answered China.
Six percent said Pakistan.
So one out of four international people
believe that if they go to war,
the United States will be the adversary
eyes.
A veteran.
I hang my head in.
Shame over that.
Brian Jessee run too late.
Come on man.
Too late.
Why is it too late?
You'll have to wait until 20,
20.
Now it's too late to get this one.
I'd have to go to the libertarian thing.
You've got to a ballot access.
Yeah,
but 20,
20 is a good time.
Well it will be 70.
We'll get you on the general.
I'll be almost,
I'll give you some,
my healthy diet.
I'm almost 70 and I never say never.
You know,
maybe when if Hillary wins and the women
see there's no difference having a woman
as we learned,
there's no difference having a black man
in there.
It's still business as usual.
Uh,
maybe when they learn all that,
if the revolution continues to happen
because you know,
here's something interesting.
The Bernie people and the original trump
people wanted the same thing.
Yeah,
they wanted but they couldn't come
together because one's left ultra left
the others ultra,
right.
The,
the status quo is now using that to
survive.
They're keeping the revolutionary
separated so that they can survive with
business as usual.
Well,
there's two completely different
factions.
One that wants to dissolve the system
because he thinks it's corrupt,
but he uses certain aspects of the
system to make vast amounts of money.
The other one doesn't really care about
money and really thinks that people
should make more money for them.
I mean,
there's a lot of things that I agree
with both agree to clean house.
What we got now is a mess.
Exactly.
And clear the house out and start over.
Yeah.
Both agreed to that.
Well that's one of the things that
people support and trump and they wish
that he wasn't the guy he is and so they
try to pretend that he's someone other
than who he is.
I,
I really believe,
and I believe this,
if I would've gotten in the race and,
and gotten into the debates,
I could've won.
Oh,
you definitely could won.
You're a way better speaker than either
one of them.
Even the speaker.
It's,
I don't have the.
I don't have the baggage.
Right.
And,
and did you know,
here's some interest.
His finger aspect is a huge issue.
I,
when I ran for governor,
I only raised $300,000.
That's it.
Yeah.
I made more money doing the job than
what I spent to get it.
That's the,
that's unprecedented.
Yeah.
That's why.
That's why they don't want to talk about
me.
That's why they are.
They want me gone.
I've beaten them twice.
While you're also an actual military
veteran and you're also a man is
actually held office before and you're
actually not a career politician,
but you've done the job and you have a
very good insight on what it's all
about.
You're also a conspiracy theorist,
which scares the shit out of him.
Well,
but let's remember,
they did a huge study in England and
found the conspiracy theorists are
generally more intelligent.
Are you got to meet?
Some of my friends know they're more
intelligent monkey because.
Because they don't accept things.
They do their own personal studies
before they bring up an opinion.
Right.
But then there's some flat earth people
and chem trails and there's some wacky
shit that gets thrown into the mix there
too.
Dinosaurs aren't real,
but I'll tell you something as crazy as
some of them sound.
Sometimes after a few years go by,
you start thinking,
you know they might be right.
What do you think about people in on the
moon?
I think we were there.
Okay.
Yeah,
absolutely I do.
Do you think any of the footage is fake?
I like to not believe it is.
I don't know.
I've never studied it,
I've never sat down and really stammered
out.
I was 18 years old.
I just graduated,
revise school would allegedly walked on
the moon.
That's the only.
I was fucked.
I far more concerned
at that time of Woodstock and uh,
that,
that also happened that year.
The real issue with conspiracy theories
is the absolute proven ones like Gulf of
Tonkin,
which got us into the Vietnam War that
you were part of like a operation
northwoods,
which was signed by the Joint Chiefs of
staff and vetoed by Kennedy where they
had planned attacks on Guantanamo Bay.
They were going to arm Cuban friendlies
to attack one ton of obey blaming on the
Cubans and let us go to war with Cuba.
They were going to blow up a drone.
Jetliner.
They were fire jetliner,
blow it up,
blame it on Cuba.
They were going to do all these
different.
After knowing all that,
you know,
are you all show out to include the
murder of John Kennedy?
Yeah.
I don't buy.
I don't either at all,
at all.
What they've told us.
And let's bring in nine slash 11.
Well,
the murder of John Kennedy to me is
first of all,
there's so many aspects of it that
people like to conveniently ignore,
like the magic bullet,
not,
not just the path,
because bullets take crazy paths.
I'm sure you know that bullets.
I mean,
you could shoot someone in the front and
the boat will come out of their
eyeballs.
It does happen.
Things ricochet off bone.
Weird Shit happens,
but a bullet does not go through bone
and come out looking like that.
Not only that,
it can't be bigger than it originally
was.
Exactly.
There's more particles inside the body
that are missing from the bullet itself.
Exactly.
So it does show the bullet camp get
bigger than what it originally was.
That bullet went through Kennedy,
shattered bones and connolly's body and
came out looking for Stina.
I've shot a lot of bullets.
I know what happens when you hit animals
with bullets.
When you hit bonds.
I have these two copper bullets from an
elk I shot and there are fucked up.
Well,
I'll.
We recreated it.
Unconcerned she theory.
I couldn't make the shots and I'm an
expert.
Yeah,
I mean you couldn't,
the finger was hard.
You couldn't work that bolt [inaudible]
quick enough like they claim he got the
shots off and like six seconds.
Ridiculous.
See the fastest I could do it without
even aiming was seven point eight and
that was not even taking a name.
Well,
I think if the gun was lubed up,
well if you practice really well,
I don't have a problem with someone
being able to do something
extraordinarily quickly.
Carlos couldn't.
The sniper,
Carlos Health,
they created the whole thing for him and
he couldn't make the shots and he's the
greatest sniper and history and even
laughed about it and said,
you're going to tell me Oswald could
outshoot me.
Isn't it possible that he got lucky?
Man?
Isn't it possible that he got lucky
shot?
No.
In.
Why wouldn't you like an Oliver's movie?
Why?
If you want it,
why didn't you take it when he's coming
at ya?
Well,
he couldn't get into that position if it
really was acting alone right there.
Okay.
I cars coming right at you before it
makes the turn that way if you miss the
next one is going to be closer.
The weird thing is that they had to come
up with the magic bullet theory to
account for a bullet that hit the
underpass and ricocheted off of the curb
and hit a guy and because of that,
that's
why they had to account for one bullet.
Oh,
the damaged bodies.
I interviewed Mr Newman and Mr Newman's
was the physical person closest to the
fatal headshot.
He's the guy you see who covers his kids
in all the movies.
That's Mr Newman and I asked him this a
few years ago.
I was doing the show.
I met him there and interviewed.
I said,
where did you think the bullet came
from?
He said,
oh,
it came from over my shoulder,
which puts it right at the picket fence
because he was right down there and he
said it came from over his right
shoulder and he.
We had his FBI report there,
write one page,
and I said to Mr Newman.
I said,
well,
Mr Newman when you stated at came over
your shoulder,
which put it at the grassy knoll.
I said,
how did the Warren Commission respond to
this?
You know what he said to me?
He looked at me,
said I was never called in front of the
Warren Commission,
and I went,
you were the co,
the closest living witness to the
headshot and they never even brought you
in to ask you a question.
Nope.
Why?
Because they saw his initial report
didn't fit with what they were going to
put out,
so they conveniently didn't call him in.
There's also two different accounts from
the autopsy,
the Bethesda Maryland version versus the
Dallas version of the entrance wound on
the neck,
you know,
they call it an entrance wound and that
the Tesla Maryland said it was a
tracheotomy.
Ruined.
I mean they,
they changed it from a bullet hitting
him in the front to a trake wound.
Well,
what's his name also changed at Joe
Ford?
The back bullet.
He moved it up.
Yeah.
Now how do you do those things?
You know.
And then the other interesting thing was
Harold Weisberg wrote about it,
news,
great books Whitewash Harold.
It took him 10 years to get the minutes
of the Warren Commission.
It came out that a Houston newspaper
stated Oswaldo was a paid FBI informant,
had his number and the whole thing.
So the Warren Commission had to hold an
emergency meeting and it took harold 10
years to get the minutes because they
withheld them now you'd think they were
meeting to discover and find out about
this right.
The whole minutes to the meeting had
nothing to do with that.
The minutes to the meeting dealt with
completely.
How do we cover this up?
Now?
The guy who is going to cover this up
pretty ridiculous.
You know the guy who was the closest to
play devil's advocate,
when when any sort of a chaotic event
happens,
you're memory is usually fucked up
because you're dealing with adrenaline,
especially someone who's not used to
being in sort of combat type situations.
Human memory is one of the most faulty
pieces of evidence you could ever get.
People remember all kinds of shit that
isn't real.
And if the story started getting out
that there was people shooting from
behind the grassy knoll,
it's entirely possible that someone can
fabricate something in their own mind
and not even be deceptive.
Maybe.
Maybe,
maybe.
But if I would think
that if you were there and you heard the
shot and you felt it go over your
shoulder,
I would think you,
if you told me,
been around.
I think.
I don't know Mr Newman.
Yeah.
I,
I never quizzed him on that.
But I thought he was.
But there,
there were other others too.
Not just him.
Right.
But you have to.
There's a lot of witnesses said that
they had.
In fact,
there's a photo where you see smoke
going across the plaza right from the
grassy knoll in the air.
Have you ever seen.
Did you ever read a David Lifton's book?
Best evidence to amazing book.
That was the book that got me on the
conspiracy theory theory trail,
but there was an analysis done.
The one you need to read is whitewashed
by Harold Weisberg.
I'll read it this weekend.
Whitewash.
I'm,
you got me fired up again.
There was a,
um,
a,
a crazy analysis of all the witnesses of
the Kennedy assassination and how many
of them died.
Untimely.
Death is fucking terrifying if you
haven't seen that.
Folks.
Jamie,
see if he could find that witnesses to
the Kennedy assassination that died.
Untimely deaths,
I mean,
but they did a statistical analysis of
the odds of all these people getting
murdered and just random random murders
and fucking bizarre suicides.
That's insane.
Well,
how about Dorothy Kilgallen,
the greater Washington reporter.
She went out and got an interview with
Jack Ruby.
She came out of the interview stating
I'm going to break the Kennedy case wide
open,
got back to New York and they found her
dead the next day.
Woo.
Dorothy Kilgallen,
she's one of the most famous reporters
in New York,
and she got an interview with Jack Ruby
and she came out of the interview and
all she'd quote was,
I'm going to break the Kennedy Case Wide
Open.
Yeah,
I'm.
And then.
And then she was found dead within a
week.
What's interesting too is this idea that
Lee Harvey Oswald either acted alone or
the government assassinated Kennedy,
Juno of Judith,
very baker of.
Why do I know that name or she was
Oswald's girlfriend.
Okay.
In New Orleans and she's written a book
called Lee and me.
Great Book where she talks She Lee was
going to divorce his wife and her and
judith.
We're going to get together.
That's what she says.
Ah,
I think that's what she said on record,
but it.
But it adds all these speakers.
They weren't living together at that
time.
This is the,
uh,
all the different people that died.
Untimely deaths.
Yup.
This is fucking crazy.
It's all heart attack.
A unknown.
What w,
what do we got here?
Drug overdose.
The one that's really the bad one is the
guy who was in the tower there at the
train thing.
Suicide,
suicide,
suicide.
They found,
they found him dead.
Minor accident,
minor accident dead.
One car crashed dead heart attack,
heart attack.
And these [inaudible] died quick.
This is what's interesting.
They died.
They all died within a very short amount
of time.
Gunshot wound to the head.
Well,
you know what,
judith was involved in an Oswald.
They were.
They were at New Orleans attempting to
create a fast moving cancer that Lee was
supposed to deliver to Mexico City to
try to kill Castro a fast moving cancer
and what killed ruby a fast moving
cancer.
Yeah,
I guess.
And you know who's in charge of it all?
That guy that's on all the New York or
the New Orleans Saints football are.
Who's the famous doctor?
The clinic.
That's who judy worked for.
The cancer expert.
Thank you.
Give you cancer.
No,
they.
They were attempting to create a fast
moving cancer.
And you think they give that to Jack
Ruby?
No.
Yeah,
because they were attempting to kill
Castro with it.
Now,
do you think that Lee Harvey Oswald was
involved?
I think Lee Harvey Oswald was an
undercover operative of our US
intelligence agency.
Yes.
You think he was involved in the
assassination attempt?
Maybe I or he was involved or thought he
was stopping it because oswold loved
Kennedy.
The whole thing is just such a crazy.
Liked Kennedy.
He didn't dislike him.
It's a crazy story.
So why would he kill him and why would
he use a weapon when you can get any
weapon in Texas?
Why would he use one that had a,
a paper trail on it?
What's interesting to me about this
story too.
Anyway though,
enough of Kennedy and I just want one
thing is that it shows how uncomfortable
people are with embracing the
possibility of corruption to the extent
where they would kill the president.
It,
it shows me why Jesse Ventura at times
is not popular.
Why do you talk about yourself in the
third person like Roy Jones?
Uh,
because he is a third person because he
is a third person.
Jesse Ventura is not,
you know what,
who are you?
That's my business.
Oh,
okay.
You're superman,
right?
Yeah.
Anyway.
Uh,
uh,
no.
What was her manner,
Jessie?
She calls me honey.
You.
Ah,
that's sweet.
After 41 years least she's not swearing
at me.
There you go.
I've done something right.
Anyway,
you lost my train of.
Sorry,
I forgot where I was going anyway.
I don't remember.
Anyway,
it doesn't matter.
Um,
do you partake in marijuana yourself?
Only in Colorado,
one in Colorado.
What about California?
Only in Colorado,
but this right here,
buddy.
I'm,
I might in California.
This is liquid is a spray.
Spray it under your tongue.
This is liquid too,
but it's not as powerful.
This one put you on Pluto.
You gotta.
Be Very careful about this one.
The uh,
I made some mistakes.
I only,
I only uh,
uh,
partake where it's legal.
It's legal here.
No one ain't checking medical.
I get you a doctor.
He'll be here in five minutes.
Well until you.
Until you do that.
I don't.
I'm not legal.
All the laws put online.
I can do it online.
You can do it online now.
You can do it online here.
I
just,
I know how I could get it.
You know how I could do it.
How I'm a veteran.
I get dreams.
Can't sleep at night and we'll also do.
You have had hip replacement,
right?
Yep.
Yeah.
Well there you go.
That's,
that's.
I actually had the new technique.
They'll called hip resurfacing.
So what do they do there?
It was new at the time in [inaudible]
eight.
I learned it from a neighbor and
Mexico's a triathlete and you should all
the triathletes get hip trouble.
Get this.
The differences.
They still cut you and they still
dislocate your hip,
but they don't cut the femur.
Oh,
okay.
Clean up the ball and socket.
Cover them with carbon titanium,
steel and puts you back together.
Just like resurfacing the road.
A new layer of asphalt.
So I,
my,
my femur bones completely intact.
Oh,
that's so much better.
Way Better Way,
way,
way better.
And so I,
I actually now I do over a marathon a
week on the elliptical machine.
That's incredible.
So it doesn't,
you don't have any pain at all?
No.
In fact,
a week ago I did 41 miles that week.
That's amazing.
No,
no restricting of your movement.
Nothing.
Well,
I'm 65.
When I sit down in a chair,
I tightened up and when I get up it's
like a.
You get and that feels good.
And these,
these are a really good tutorial for
anomic chair.
For me.
It also was,
I didn't learn until I got to Mexico
with the physical therapist during my
wrestling career.
I had actually knocked my pelvis out of
alignment.
Oh Wow.
And he said,
that's what's giving you your back
trouble.
So he gave me a bunch of stretches to do
where I got my pelvis back in alignment
and between that,
and I'll make a plug here.
Do you ever watch on TV?
Those teeter hangers?
Yeah,
they're phenomenal.
I'm in the back.
Oh,
I love them.
They're a godsend.
Yeah,
I do it every day for 10 to 12 minutes.
I hang upside down and I and I played
golf.
I haven't been back to the chiropractor
in two years because of that.
Yeah.
They every day,
every day at the end of my workout,
I hang up and down like dracula or like
a band,
and you actually get so comfortable.
You go into kind of a limbo.
You know where you.
You're almost a conscious thing.
You're conscious,
but you're not hanging upside down.
Yeah.
You're blacking out.
Well,
not blacking out.
You're just so relaxed.
Yeah,
no,
I get it all the time.
Yeah.
Oh,
I see.
I and I tell people this thing is a
godsend.
If he called me,
I do ads for him.
Well,
it is a legitimate way to decompress
your spa without machines.
It's healthy.
You can.
And people,
uh,
you know,
I talked to a doctor wants to sit.
Your muscles are holding you in place.
You're not.
I'm like,
no,
they're not.
I relaxed my muscles.
I know how to relax my muscles.
I'm an athlete.
I know.
I know when my muscles are tense and
when they're not like,
you can absolutely get some relief and
decompression in your spine.
When I get full upside down,
then I mentally go,
okay,
relax your feet,
relax your ankles.
I go through my whole body till I get
all the way to the shoulders and the
neck.
I'm going to show you a have back there
now though.
Then when I hang,
I'm totally relaxed and sometimes you
actually feel yourself slip right back
in and then you'd go,
ah,
I wanted to do.
Yeah,
yeah.
I have one.
It's like a harness it straps to adore
and I pull on it,
click,
click.
And I'm like literally hanging by my
neck.
It's a spinal decompression device.
So that's not one of them sexual things,
man.
Now,
uh,
I had a bulging disc in my neck and uh,
I relieved it that way and so it made a
huge,
huge difference.
Like I said,
I,
you know,
I got the aches and pains of a 65 year
old I'd have,
I've had my hip done.
I stopped running because my orthopedic
surgeon says no one over 40 should
because really the pounding my friends,
49,
he just ran 200 miles still ultra
marathon.
The pounding that he can't do it,
but he's going to pay the price,
the pounding of his body,
like,
like this Dr Truesdale told me today
with the technology they got,
you can run without pounding,
right with elliptical machines,
machines.
He said it's the pounding.
It's not that you can't do it.
Anyone can do it and train for what he
said the where,
that that's going to cause on your body
after age 40.
And I have to agree,
he's the predominant orthopedic surgeon
of the Mayo Clinic.
Well,
you know,
there's also another issue and it's the
creation of the running shoe because the
running shoe,
having that big wedge and the heel,
that's not a normal gait.
The normal gait as you supposed to land
on the ball of your feet.
If you watch the little kids run,
that's how they run,
but when they created the running shoe,
they allowed people to run and have all
their weight come down on their heel and
it acts as sort of like a little spring,
but that's not normal.
It's your body has a natural spring
built into it.
The design of the foot bar or you can do
the natural way the seals do.
How do they do it?
You're running the sand.
That's great too.
Yeah,
that is the best way.
Paula had gotten even worse when they
take you in the soft sand dunes.
Dune running is fucking amazing.
I,
uh,
I.
There was an old chief there.
We used to call him superman.
He was 41 years old when I was in the
teams.
Forty one and the softer the Sam,
the faster he got.
Oh,
we used to call him the Campbell.
That was his nickname.
I one thing about chief,
but we called them the camel because
when we'd hit the soft sand running
normally in our team,
he was probably in the top six and
running.
When we'd hit the soft sand,
he was up first or second.
Why is that?
I don't know.
He could just run in the soft sand and
it didn't slow him down to.
They have like big wide flipper feet or
something.
No,
he was actually a little whiter,
rebuilt guy.
He also,
he was able,
we had this big rope.
He could wear a pair of twin,
96 tanks for diving and he'd pull
himself up to the top of this rope just
using his hands.
Ninety pounds?
No,
twin nineties.
That's what is called there.
How much do those weigh?
I don't know,
but they're heavy.
They're heavy as hell.
They're the old twin.
90 Scuba tanks there.
Big Old metal tanks.
They were and he used to go up that rope
using just his hands.
That's a strength or why rebuild?
Not a big muscle guy.
Just why rebuilt?
We call,
we called him superman.
That was his nickname and the teams you
lead pt every day you do pt.
With him it was like in training unit,
every set of pushups 50.
Every time you do pushups with him is 50
50 a pop and you probably do at least 10
to 12 sets.
That's great for tearing apart 600
pushups a day.
Then you'll do a thousand flutter kicks.
What's a flutter kick?
Wham.
You're back at your kyc.
That sounds like a good time.
That along with running up sand dunes at
a party who's running sand dunes and the
other thing in training they don't
account for,
but you have to Rodan to run.
Every time you're moving and budge
training,
you have to be running.
You have to run to run,
so you're when you'd run out on the
beach,
but you have to run to get there and
then you have to run to get back.
Those don't count when you do a four
mile beach run,
it only counts on the beach.
It doesn't count the run to get there
and the run to get back to run to the
Chow Hall,
the Rhonda and everywhere you.
When you're in budge training from the
time you start in the morning till they
secure you,
you have to be running anytime you're
moving.
Oh Jesus.
But,
but you do it as the airborne shuffle.
That's kind of that shuffle run where
you're,
you know,
you're running,
but you're not really running kind of
jargon.
Yeah.
He just hustling.
They call it the airborne shuffle
because that's should do a jump school.
What led you to want to write this book,
this marijuana want the experience I had
with the seizures and that's what
motivated me because I knew there's
other people out there suffering.
Our government should not be standing in
the way and stopping people from using a
plant that could help them and it's time
to end this ridiculous prohibition.
My mother who lived through the
Prohibition of alcohol told me before
she died,
she said,
the war on drugs is identical to the
Prohibition of alcohol.
All you're doing is making criminals
rich and powerful and it's also,
there's an industry and keeping people
in jail and as an industry,
you catching people in,
locking them up,
check your rights,
losing your rights,
imprisoning people.
And when you find out that there's
prison guard unions that are lobbying to
keep marijuana illegal so they have more
work.
It's terrible,
it's horrible,
it's horrible.
And they don't think of it as horrible,
but that's the perception.
Got The dea who's out there making money
off,
keeping it illegal and you know what you
do.
They're doing it to fight for their
jobs,
but I've already got another position
for them.
But let's end the war on drugs.
Let's take the dea and let's make the
dea do put as much effort into sexual
crimes.
Like what kind of sexual crimes?
Molesting children.
Uh,
we just went through one in Minnesota,
Jacob wetterling,
where they finally caught his murderer,
but he's not going to go to prison for
murdering because he plea bargained what
happened?
You know,
the famous Jacob wetterling case.
You don't know where that could happen
way back 20 some years ago where he was,
him and his friends were going to the
video store and a guy took him at
gunpoint and you disappeared.
The Minnesota Vikings wore his thing on
their uniform and it was a whole
national thing when Jacob wetterling was
abducted while they just discovered his
dead body a month ago.
Oh,
because they caught the guy who did it,
but he wouldn't confess unless he got
immunity,
so they had to give him immunity and
then he led them to the body so they
could get closure over 20 some years
ago.
So he got immunity to that.
But is he getting prosecuted for
something as getting prosecuted for
child porn?
That's it.
Yup.
Now I say you take the dea and you put
them out catching child molesters and
sexual predators.
That would be a good job for them to do.
It would be a good job for them to do,
but I would rather take people that are
molesting children as our smoking pot.
Well,
the problem,
the problem might be they might have to
investigate the Catholic church and
that'd be off limits,
wouldn't it?
Well,
how about that one?
A good one.
Here's a good one.
I love good ones.
My Club,
the Mongols.
We got busted for the Federal Rico laws,
right?
How come they don't apply the Federal
Rico laws to the Catholic Church?
It's a good call.
Yeah,
I'll come.
They don't child molestations of felony.
They covered it up.
They lied about it.
They continue to do it.
How come the church hasn't been
investigated under the Federal Rico Laws
and charged their questionnaire?
The church.
That's why.
And you're not allowed to.
Well,
that's also why they hide them up in the
Vatican because the Vatican is its own
country.
I don't know.
I'm not into all that.
I'm just saying that.
How come the Rico laws don't apply to
the child molestation that's gone on.
That's a very good point.
It's a very good point.
And when the,
when Pope Benedict resigned,
that was,
uh,
one of the things that they were going
after,
they wanted to prosecute him for crimes
against humanity because this guy was
shielding child molesters.
He killed a child molester that went on
to rape 100 deaf kids.
I mean,
what in the fuck.
And this guy targeted deaf children
because they couldn't talk about it and
now they,
they stick them in the Vatican.
And once you're in the Vatican,
the Vatican is
protected.
It's literally got its own situation
where it's like a country.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean I still don't think there's as
many people doing that as there are
selling and buying drugs.
So the dea
maybe not,
but what has come some other is the
worst effect.
One hundred percent.
I agree with you because I know people
that were molested and never recovered
from it.
Their entire lives have been altered.
Yeah.
And it goes for generations because
generally you find the molester was
molested?
Yeah,
always.
Yeah.
You know,
usually that usually that's the
situation.
So I would rather take our focus away
from people doing consensual crime
against themselves because addiction
shouldn't be treated a criminally.
It should be treated medically.
I mean,
you can be addicted.
I always like to use this for an
example.
Imagine tomorrow if they took away
coffee and caffeine.
Oh yeah,
we have riots on the street.
There you go.
And those are all addicts.
People addicted to it.
Hoodies.
What are you trying to say,
man?
No,
they're coffee.
They're addicted to it.
Well,
they need to understand that.
Then how dare them say you should take
away a drug from someone else.
Of course,
when I.
They have their fix.
Yeah.
How come theirs is legal?
I also don't think that we have to find
jobs for people that are doing something
that should be against the law.
It should be against the law to arrest
people for marijuana.
You don't have to find jobs for people
that are doing something that should be
against the law.
Arresting people for marijuana is a
fucking crime.
And I've said this time and time again,
but if you lock someone in a cage
because they smoke a plant,
that makes them happy,
you're a fucking criminal,
you're a criminal,
you're.
You are doing a crime against human
beings and freedom and that's what
you're participating in.
So the dea is doing is a crime.
I don't think we have to find jobs for
criminals.
I think the only thing that's saving
them from being labeled as a criminal is
some shit that's written down on paper
by a bunch of people that are profiting
from keeping it in that same way.
It's a crime.
It's all crime.
Yep.
And there's nothing.
Zero,
Zilch.
When it comes to the.
When you talking about the side effects
or the negative effects of cannabis,
there's nothing.
Zero.
There's no evidence.
I agree.
And if there was,
they would parade it out there.
And even if they did paraded out there,
what we're finding time and time again,
the most recent story that was in the
New York Times about the sugar industry,
paying off scientists to say that sugar
is okay for you,
but it's saturated fat,
saturated fat.
Which is so important that it's one of
the main substrates for creating sex
hormones.
It's one of the most important parts of
human diet that saturated fat is bad.
And that's what's giving people heart
attacks.
Meanwhile,
people getting fat as fuck from shower.
I,
I love to talk about this,
which came to light to me 10 years ago.
Uh,
I grew up in the fifties when they put
fluoride in our water.
Yeah.
Wade.
And they put it in there for our.
Well,
isn't that your parent's job to teach
you how to brush your teeth and Gargle
with Florida dated mouthwash?
Is there any benefit?
White Flora?
Wait,
why would you put a chemical in the
water?
Yeah,
there's a benefit.
I'll explain it.
Who,
who do you think was the first people to
put fluoride in water but the Nazis?
Yep.
Now why they do that now?
First of all,
I'd questioned anything the Nazis did
right away.
I'd say,
well,
Gee,
they don't have really people in mind
do.
They were really good at making engines.
Well that they were,
but uh,
that.
No,
they did it because fluoride is the
major ingredient of PROZAC.
So you think that played in the water.
You're getting these daily dose,
daily dose of PROZAC.
Does.
Why?
Why would the Nazis do it?
What would be the only reason to.
Not People Docile,
but did they do it in a large scale
fashion or they do it as an experiment
because they did a lot of fucked up
experiment.
Well No,
they put it in their water.
Germany was the first country that put
fluoride in the water under the Nazi
rule.
And did they picked it up for their
teeth?
I guess that was why they did it.
I don't know,
but that's what we sold our people.
I remember.
And here.
Did you see the movie Fargo?
Yes.
Member of the town.
Brainerd?
Yes.
Well,
brainerd Minnesota.
About 30 years ago.
I remember it.
They voted.
They did not want fluoride in their
water.
They weren't going to put it in.
Federal government came in and made
them.
And why do you think they did that?
Is the fluoride industry paying them
off?
I don't know because they want to get
rid of.
Why would the federal government come
into a city who their own water supply
and forced them to put fluoride in the
water.
Well,
do you think they did it because the
fluoride industry paid them off because
they didn't want to lose profits?
It doesn't make sense.
Or did they not want an example that you
can have water without fluoride?
It's possible,
but if they really wanted to protect
people from Wednesday,
go after sugar or is it like Vince
Mcmahon?
He fired me because I wouldn't
relinquish my copyrighted name so he
could exploit that.
I owned it and I refused to give it up.
The copywriter named Jesse,
Jesse Ventura.
I had it before I worked for them and I
copyrighted it federally so that I would
own it and I wouldn't release it to him.
And that's what ended up getting me
fired in the end where I had to leave
the wwf because,
uh,
he,
he had to control all of the marketing
that was old school before wwe.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
I don't know why fluoride in the water.
I've looked at it very peripheral,
no reason for it really.
They tell you it's for your teeth,
but shouldn't you do that yourself?
Will not.
My thinking is if they really were
concerned about people's teeth and
people's health wouldn't look at all the
different kinds of sugar that we're
consuming.
All the corn syrup and people's Diet,
all the sugar and that tell you the
fluoride there for another reason then.
So you think there's a large scale
organized conspiracy to keep people
docile by putting Florida and the water.
I don't know if it's a large scale
conspiracy or if it was just done and
it's too difficult to unchange it.
She wants government gets established
doing something and it's done for
decades.
It's very hard to get them to change
their position and is it in some ways a
lot like the dea in that once fluoride
is a business,
is a business and selling fluoride,
putting fluoride in the water.
There's people that have jobs.
They're doing that.
They lobby to keep that in place.
And what evidence is there?
The floor has beneficial.
Is there any evidence?
I don't know.
You don't know,
but if you know about this,
why don't you look into that because I
don't drink fluoridated water,
so it doesn't affect Mexico,
doesn't have Florida.
You drink out of A.
Well,
yeah,
and,
and in all my home,
she,
I only learned this a decade ago,
but ironically,
all the homes I've lived in have been
kind of rural and I've had my own.
Well all your life pretty much other
than when I grew up as a kid.
Maybe that's why he still rebellious.
He didn't get your dose of Flora.
Exactly.
That's why I asked questions and stuff.
I haven't been.
I haven't been on PROZAC aided.
I'm not on the PROZAC.
Well,
it didn't work with me because I've
drank a lot of fucking fluorided water
constitutions are different than mine.
I don't know,
maybe I'm just better.
They say it calcifies your pineal gland,
but the people that say that,
they all smell,
they all smell like natural deodorant
and feet.
When mother fuckers,
like I said it,
uh,
you know,
the brainerd tried to do it and the
federal government came in and just
slapped him down.
It didn't matter,
the people voted,
didn't matter,
nothing.
Federal government came in and said,
you will have fluoride in your water.
What year was this thick?
It was back in the eighties.
I wonder if that would fly today because
people today are so concerned with
genetically modified foods and I think
they'd still do it today because you
still got it.
Nobody's ever said nothing.
Like,
why don't we remove fluoride from the
water?
Yeah,
I don't.
I don't know.
I mean,
nobody.
Nobody brings it up.
Yeah.
I don't even know.
Florida is beneficial in toothpaste.
Uh,
there's a lot of people that don't
believe floor at should be in
toothpaste.
I think that with the cleaning of your
teeth is really what gets the.
The plan goes.
Yeah.
Who knows?
But someone must have just a major
ingredient of PROZAC.
I'm going to go looking into that now.
Dammit.
Another rabbit hole.
I got to whitewash.
I got to go down on PROZAC.
Rabbit hole.
PROZAC.
Fluoride,
rabbit hole.
Flora.
Just flow.
But when you think about it,
why would they put it for your teeth?
Your parents do that.
They teach you how to brush your teeth
and use mouthwash.
Why would you put a chemical in the
water?
That's a good point.
Why
would a chemical be introduced into
clean drinking water?
Well,
not only that,
there's a lot of people that don't even
drink water from the faucet anymore.
You know,
a lot of people use the faucet water for
bathing and cooking and they drink
bottled water.
Yeah,
well that's another scam they pulled on
the bottle.
Yeah,
completely.
I did it.
And conspiracy theory,
we went up to Michigan.
We're nationally is.
Yeah,
they,
they take water.
Well,
the law says you cannot take water from
the Great Lakes.
Right?
And the Great Lakes region is 20 percent
of the fresh water of the world,
so naturally goes up there and builds a
million square foot,
plant the things huge.
It's bigger than our dome stadium.
For the Vikings.
They got this huge plant up there and
all they do is they punch in at a
tributary,
so they're technically not taking it
from the Great Lakes.
They're taking it before it gets there.
The Great Lakes have now fallen there
six inches lower than they used to be
and I was taken to a stream that used to
have white water rafting.
It now does.
It's dead water just because of Nestle.
Yeah,
they're sucking it all out of the ground
before it can get to the Great Lakes and
they're putting it in plastic bottles
and selling it to you.
More expensive than gas.
It is bottled water costs more than gas
and that fucking.
Imagine if you've got a company and you
sell a product that's free and you and
you don't have to do nothing to it,
but put it into a bottle and sell it for
more than gas cars.
They persuaded us.
It was the only way to consume water.
Like when I was a kid,
you'd go to the schoolyard and play
football all day on the way home.
You'd run up to somebody whos you'd turn
it on and everybody would drink out of
the hose.
We didn't die.
Nobody got sick.
We survived.
Yet all of a sudden here came.
Bottled water had to be bottled and it
was a whole thing they did on people.
The only pure clear water you're going
to get comes from bottle.
Well at eight,
they're pumping it out of the ground the
same way as they pump anything else out
of the ground.
They're just putting it into a bottle
and selling it to you for more than
gasoline.
Your friend is interrupting here.
What would you like?
I got to go.
This is the reason why I don't let
people in the studio,
Jesse,
but I,
I know you have a hard out at 1:15.
I'm your book.
It's available now.
Want to come out I think on the sixth
and you're going to be at barnes and
noble and Santa Monica tonight,
tonight at 7:30 7:30.
And people come meet you and explained
to you why fluoride in the water.
They're going to go crazy now.
They can do all that stuff and what we
can talk and visit and uh,
I'll weave a few stories in.
And like every,
the only thing I worry about every book
signing I do,
I get pleads from people on why I'm not
running well.
I'm bleeding,
I'm bleeding.
Look,
somebody needs to run.
That's not corrupted by the system as
well.
Think you're corrupted by the system.
There's only me.
Yeah.
Well I think there's probably a few
other people that are thinking right
now,
but they don't want this.
I only raised 300,000 bucks to become
the governor of Minnesota,
but that's Minnesota.
I mean,
I think my dog might be able to win
government.
Not really because the devolution repub
spent $12 million that year.
Well they spent 12 million bucks.
Your Jesse Ventura was famous or
thousand.
Yeah,
but I had to go through the media of,
of them a degrading me.
How could a wrestler be a governor?
Right?
How could,
how could somebody from the private
sector who's never come up through the
corrupt system be expected to govern,
but also don't you think it helps you
have an awesome Minnesota accent?
That's the building official.
You definitely do.
Oh,
I don't do that.
If my friend,
Randall Carlson,
Minnesota.
You don't know it.
My friend ran from Alabama.
You don't have.
You don't have an accent,
Alabama.
No.
They have to know my friend Randall
Carlson.
Sounds exactly like you.
And he's from Minnesota.
Exactly.
You said you have a very clear of
Minnesota accent.
Yeah,
we have it and uh,
you know,
I'm born and raised there,
but I don't know how to skate.
You don't have a skate?
I don't either.
Good for you.
I'm down.
Well,
I,
I did it because I in the winter I swam.
We have in common.
You and me.
I was just like fanny packs.
We both don't know how to skate.
We both like pot.
I was a swimmer.
I could swim.
Yeah.
No,
I did it though,
but I mean all winter and summer I was
competitive.
Now my claim to fame,
I actually swam in the same pool once
with Mark Spitz.
That's big for me because as a swimmer
he was God the Var air right in the long
game.
Phelps,
who I never thought could win another,
a more medals than mark did know the guy
who likes pot.
Yeah,
remember that he got shamed,
they fought shame.
Do you know what I woulda did?
If I'd have been him and they did that
to me,
what would you have done?
I would have immediately moved to
Australia,
applied for Australian citizenship,
and I would have came back and beat the
United States if they prosecuted me for
the pot.
Yeah,
but they weren't prosecuting.
You thought about it.
Did they really?
Yeah,
about prosecuting.
Oh,
it went onto.
that's right.
Wasn't it like South Carolina?
I don't know,
but uh,
but all I know is a fight of been
phelps.
I would've moved to Australia.
I'd applied for Australian citizenship
and I would've come back and swam
against the United States and say,
stick that up your ass.
That's very rude of,
you know,
at a renegade.
No,
it ain't.
It's very rude of them.
After winning those medals,
don't you think he earned a joint?
I do.
And you do as well?
Yeah.
They wouldn't have said nothing if he
had guzzled a bottle of beer.
I want to find out what the fuck.
Narc Dunham.
We should make that public.
Whoever that shit had is,
it took the picture of Phelps.
Exactly.
Arrested him.
Michael Phelps case.
What people were arrested that had pot
that gave him pot.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Did you see that thing about the woman
in in western Massachusetts or near
Amherst?
She's an old lady and she grew her own
medical marijuana.
Her son was in the house and a swat team
showed up guns blazing for one plant,
one plant in this woman's backyard.
That's how fucking ridiculous.
I'll.
I'll tell you all ridiculously are.
When I was governor,
and we'll finish with this.
we had a three panel myself.
Kathleen blatch who was head of the
Minnesota Supreme Court and the attorney
general,
the three of us with the pardon board
where we could expunge records.
Right?
And I was glad they thought like me
because everybody that came to us that
had a marijuana conviction of 10:20
years ago,
we cleaned it off and one of them.
I'll always remember wally here,
this story,
this guy,
when he sat down in front of us,
the first thing I did,
I looked at him.
I said,
how are you and your sister getting
along?
And he smiled at me,
says,
we're okay.
I said,
okay.
I just wanted to check.
You know what happened to this guy?
He was 18 years old at home.
His little sister was going to dare at
the time,
you know that dare class while they
teach at dare to turn everyone in to
rap.
Everybody turned them in.
So this guy's got a bag of weed in his
bedroom.
His little sister sees it,
calls the police,
the police come.
She's there to let them in so they don't
need a warrant and they go bust her
brother.
She ends up her brother and her brother
now has had this on his record for 20
freaking years of marijuana bust that
his sister turned him over on because
she was at Derr and Derr said your rad
everybody.
So the sister thinks she's doing the
right thing.
Puts her brother in jail for having a
bag of weed in his bedroom.
So sad.
And that's why I asked him,
how are you and your sister getting
along?
You said we're fine,
and I sit and we cleaned his record.
We wiped it right off of there.
Now who?
I wouldn't do that for child molesters,
who came in and I had a girl there who
came to testify against this guy so we
wouldn't do it.
I called her up to me and I said,
young lady,
you don't have to come back here anymore
because as long as I'm the governor of
Minnesota,
this guy will never ever get his record
cleaned.
You don't have to worry about that.
Go home with a clear conscience.
You don't have to come back here.
It's not gonna happen because all of
them child molesters re-offend.
That's why they want their record
cleaned off so that they can get in a
position of being a Predator again and
re-offend again and and they bring in.
They bring in people from the clergy to
testify for them and all these joined
the church.
Now they've done it.
They do all of this stuff.
They pull in that smoke on me.
I to me,
a child molester,
it's a d.
They could never be cured.
Jesse Ventura for president in 2020.
Make it happen folks.
Two thousand 16 is a wash.
We're fucked either way.
Hang in there for four years.
Four years.
I can tell you what.
I'll tell you what if it ends up that
bad,
I promise you I will run into 2020 Jesse
Ventura for president.
Meet him tonight.
Santa Monica Barnes and noble.
Seven 30.
Thank you sir.
Thank you.
Had a great time.
My pleasure.
Fun to talk with you and I'll tell you
why else.