Wow,
on your phase three or the ID?
Every picture has her id.
You could get fucking busted.
Are we going right when you're talking
about child pornography?
Dude,
we're live.
Eddie Bravo.
How dare you.
That shit with standup.
Eddie Bravo.
How dare you bring up shit that we're
talking about off the air.
Okay.
I'm saying start the fucking podcast off
with that.
It's my cousin.
Anyway,
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for tuning into the podcast.
We are sponsored as always by the
fleshlight fleshlight.com.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and you click the link,
this is a place where you can go to and
you get 15 percent off.
And the,
what is the code that have put in Logan?
And this is a fat boy.
Slim mix.
Yes.
Fatboy summer mix.
Two thousand 10.
You know what?
I love the song back.
I did that.
Uh,
weapons of destruction.
Is that what it's called?
Yes.
Yeah.
The one with a Christopher?
No.
Christopher walken.
And did the video is dancing fucking bad
ass video.
All his videos are all.
His music is pretty good.
I've,
I've really never really got into them,
but that one really grabbing or our
guests as always.
My Buddy,
Mr Eddie Bravo,
Bravo,
the 10th planet.
Jiu Jitsu Jujitsu of um,
you can go to twitter.com/Eddie
Bravo.
And um,
where else can they get your shit?
You still have a myspace page up with
all your music,
right?
Yeah,
but then move that to another site
eventually.
Man.
I'm like behind on every fucking thing,
man.
I got to put out the mastering the
twister DVD.
I did.
I'm so behind on everything,
like musicians are still using my space.
Some of them,
right,
because it's convenient.
Yeah,
it's got that music player that you
could see your,
uh,
your views or your hits.
That's pretty important to music.
That's super important.
If you have thousands of hits on one of
your songs,
people are gonna go,
Oh shit,
let me check that out.
If there's four hits,
paper just going to bypass.
Right?
And when you embed a video,
you can embed it with the number of hits
in.
It can't show.
That must be something new.
I don't know about that.
I mean if you embed like a youtube clip
or you see as the window,
you don't see how many videos are,
how many people have watched this for,
you know,
but that would be a good feature I
think.
But no one goes on my space anymore,
you know,
I'm always on my website.
10 Planet j Dot j Dot Com.
I'm on that motherfucker like,
you know,
like Joe on twitter and shit all day.
Okay.
So if they want to see your music
though,
they could still go to myspace.com/the
twister.
Those are all old videos and shit.
They're like three or four years now.
Old.
So.
But they're still bad ass.
Brian,
what are you doing over there,
buddy?
Just fine.
Tweaking the audio.
Fine.
Tweaking.
Find does become quite a podcast mogul.
He's been broadcasting,
not just this podcast,
but the uh,
the unfortunate brody Stevens projects
that was.
Did you watch any of that?
What,
what,
what was your going and call it that?
The unfortunate brody's project.
It looks like he's going crazy.
Yeah.
Then that way he's allowed to get crazy.
I just think I need a taser though,
you know?
I think if we do that,
it's a character character.
Just it's like,
I think it works great for standup
comedy,
but I think for a podcast,
I don't know,
it was hard because I felt bad for the
last episode.
He brought his roommate on again,
any screamed at his roommate the whole
time to the point where his roommate I
saw look like close to him and his cheek
was twitching because he was so upset
and then I went outside because I was
freaking out.
I went outside and he comes running
outside and goes like in the middle of
an interview he just took off and brody
was just left there on the couch going,
oh well,
you know,
I don't know what he was doing,
but the guy who's like,
I can't take this anymore.
I don't know what to do.
And like he was like,
he just got raped.
That's what,
that's what,
that's what the conversation was and
that's when it came to the conclusion
that what happened is,
is that they act together.
Him,
brody Stevens in his roommate act
together,
like if a couple were to break up and
they had to live together for like three
months,
you know,
like that,
that anger kind of that and it just,
I don't know,
man.
It freaked me out.
Real
fucking anger to money ever been around
someone when they,
they,
they're breaking up but they still
haven't moved out yet and then the chick
start seeing another dude.
Then they have complications or the guy
starts seem the check that that would
never happen.
I would never put myself to that.
I mean you have to be a brokester and
understand or some kind of.
I don't know what's going on with the
lease or something.
Maybe there's like a problem.
They're both on.
People just love drama.
They never figured it out.
They never figured out how to be cool
with each other from the moment of their
relationship,
but just a,
it's an eventual explosion.
It's like,
how,
how fucked up is enough to get before it
all falls was the only way I could
understand a situation like that is girl
breaks up with boy,
boy is begging for girl back.
Girl goes,
you know what,
we're not getting back together,
but I'm fucking staying here for two
more months because I paid the rent and
boys like,
fuck it,
stay in it.
It's like it's going to give them more
time to maybe change your mind.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I could kind of see that when I broke
up.
I lived with a chick a long time ago.
The first time I've ever lived with very
nice girl,
but we were both kids.
You know,
I was 21,
she was 20.
We were both retarded.
Right.
And uh,
when,
when I lived with her and we broke up,
there was a period of time,
like for like two weeks we were still
together and she was still like staying
in my house,
but we were,
we were not together anymore.
We'd broken up.
So she had started dating other dudes
and I'd start dating other checks and
you know,
she'd be cool with it and then she would
tell me about dudes and I wouldn't get
jealous,
but I would tell her about a chicken.
She get mad at me within two weeks.
She's 20 years old,
man.
Twelve years old.
You're retarded.
You don't know what the fuck's going on
in love with her?
No,
no,
no.
Definitely not because I didn't freak
out when she left,
although I did try to get her back on.
I came off like a huge.
I
don't know if you've ever done that
before.
When you get devastated by a check and
then you try to figure out a way to
bring a bag.
It's almost like an ego thing really.
It's like the relationship was boring.
Did she break over there?
Yeah.
That hurts now.
How long were you guys living together
before?
Not that long,
man.
I did not last very long.
It was a disaster.
Six months maybe.
Something like that.
That's not enough.
You can get deep and six maybe not even.
I'm not going to think it was six
months.
She was a nice kid.
We were just young and stupid and.
But she started banging other dudes and
I started banging on the trucks and it
was,
it was real weird because we're living
together and every now and then like she
would get horny and I'd fuck her anyway.
It would be.
It was very strange.
It was like a retard retard
relationship.
Shit.
Like the shit you do when you're 21
usually.
Generally when someone breaks up the
girl generally for most people the girl
has so much more power than the guy.
The girl can bank 10 dudes that day they
broke up like the guy like the guy might
not be able to get laid for a couple of
weeks.
He hasn't been in the game for awhile
and that's the reason why they're
breaking up was because the guy found
someone to already.
That's true.
That's track tracking.
Boston marijuana lived.
It was way harder to meet people.
This is not the same place,
man.
People are not nearly as friendly.
It's not nearly as easy to go out and
meet people or going to a bar or club or
whatever.
It's a fucking grind.
It's not easy and everyone's in jackets.
He really don't know what the fuck
you're getting.
You don't know what you're getting here
to look at girls jeans,
how vacuum sealed or these fucking
things like clubs,
even clubs you really can't tell,
so some girls can cover their fucked up
shit.
When you get them naked,
you're like,
Whoa,
fuck.
They confuse you.
If you go into a club there,
they got glow sticks,
they got glitter,
they got fake fake.
It's dark and they got so much fucking
makeup on and the covering the ship
strategically,
they know how to cover them.
Rolls Up.
How crazy is the idea of dollar club?
How close crazies the idea of a
nightclub,
he go to a place.
It's a designated meeting area where
everybody goes that supposedly is single
and wants to fuck.
You know?
It's like,
can you get it?
That's the big question.
Can you meet?
Can you meet somebody?
Are you compatible?
Do you get it?
But we're going to provide you with
music,
so you get to move around and grind
against each other.
We're going to give you drink so you
make shitty decisions.
We're going to set you up in a place
where it's probably going to be people
that are selling drugs.
If you were going to do something more
fucked up,
it's all together in one big spot and we
stay open until 2:00
in the morning.
That's one place.
I never pick up chicks that though I
never pick up chicks at the dance club
because if I'm dancing it's an acting a
fool.
I'm not like taking it serious,
like breaking it down.
You know what?
I was totally the opposite.
Like for me,
I swear for me when I was like 21,
22,
the way I would make moves on a check is
I would find the best dancer and then
dance with her and I always thought like
I could just,
I could get them with the dancing man.
I
was dancing before I could even walk.
My aunts would just hold me out because
my ad to answer a couple of years older
than me and they were just holding me up
and everyone will be dancing like
fucking fools all the time.
So you still dance?
I went to school dances.
I was always dancing.
Do you still dance one once in a while.
If I'm at a club and they're playing
some good shit,
you know,
some good fit is sam or something.
Some new ludicrous or something.
I'll be dancing.
Got To be good though.
Oh sure.
That's wake the fuck up.
No,
you know what that is?
That's an alarm.
Call Your Business Manager.
Check on your funds.
Like everyday it goes up.
Keep keep that shit going every day.
But I usually wake up reminder to check
your fucking money.
Dude.
Slow down.
What are you spending too much money?
I don't keep track of it.
Yeah,
that's my problem.
You know when they get a business
manager,
I don't have to keep that.
I'd like,
you know,
I always envied you man.
How many years did we know each other?
And you had a business manager and I had
a handle all my shit and do all my
taxes.
You never worried about shit since I've
known you.
You just have a credit card and you
don't worry about shit.
I remember a couple of times you told me
go man,
I could have 2 million in the bank.
Um,
I didn't want to disclose that.
Okay.
So anyways,
he brought the comic books.
Have you,
did you grow up liking comic books?
Um,
no.
I never read comic books,
man.
It wasn't into it.
I was,
I hated.
I hated superheroes,
man.
I wasn't into him.
I was spiderman for Halloween and it's
so weird playing the role of like a
superhero at a party,
like A.
I went to this huge party and I was
dressed up as spiderman and I realized
when I had to walk around the party,
I was walking around the party like I
was spiderman.
Like I wasn't just stepping out like,
like I didn't do it on purpose.
I just,
it was so wrong.
I was really stoned in it.
I don't know if it was weird.
So you're really still in.
You thought you were aspiring.
I just caught myself walking
differences.
The same dude by the way,
that.
So that he doesn't like certain video
games because now when he sees buildings
he wants to jump from one building to
the other.
This is,
play this in games.
He actually thinks that he could go do
that.
No,
no,
no.
He won't know what you're getting lost
in the character,
which is totally cool,
man.
I was talking about.
I played so much of this particular
video game in a short amount of time,
like,
like all day long that it got to the
point where I was driving and I'm just
like kind of space out and think,
oh hey look at building.
I could jump on it.
I could see,
you know what I mean?
I thinking of retarded shit.
You never usually want to talk about
thinking about that shit.
Like man,
like I'm actually thinking about the
fucking video games jumping around just
because you played how many hours
straight dude plant.
Uh,
at that time I had played it for like
all day long.
I wake up,
go to bed,
you know,
that's ridiculous.
For a month though,
that was the only time I ever became
addicted to my little nephew.
That's his problem right now.
They got to take away that fucking game
controller because he plays all fucking
dates,
fucking up his grades and all that Shit.
And my sister's like,
oh,
we only
let them have that video game on
weekends.
And they got,
they take the controllers and they
fucking hide them.
He goes looking forward and breaks them
fucking roll.
So all they really need to do is have
like a video game controller,
like dealer at school.
I hit little plug in.
How easy is that?
I'm real lucky that I didn't have video
games when I was a kid.
I mean we have like stupid,
like the ones on tv that you,
you'd play like a.
I forget what they were,
but they weren't.
I think Mike Tyson's punch out.
I think we had that.
I think that was like when I was around
high school,
I had a Atari the peasant later.
That was all I had.
That wasn't data addictive.
I mean it was okay,
but there's nothing like call of duty or
it was amazing back then.
Space invaders at your house.
It was amazing.
Like fuck.
Yeah,
but I'm talking about the sheer at
diction value of it.
It's not even close to the video game
Sunday.
No,
these people are having real problems
with their kids starving.
It's like a regular basis because
they're not feeding their kids because
they get lost in these massive
multiplayer war.
A world games like world of warcraft
games,
man.
This substitutes these people's lives
like the sims and there's farmdale girl
just beat her kid to death because the
kid was crying and it was interrupting
her Farmville game.
Yeah,
it's fucked up.
You know that new call of duty game that
came out last night?
Modern ops or whatever.
I don't even know what the name of it
is.
I just saw that it's in three d.
that's one of the first video games to
like release to be made to be played on
a three D tv.
So you know that three d we saw the
other day at this by Holy Shit and
playing call of duty.
Now,
dude,
I did not realize how bad ass three d
looks now with,
with a movie that's animated for Three d
and then you get one of those three d
glasses and you watch on the new three d
TVs.
It's fucking incredible,
man.
It's just like,
it's overwhelming.
Like you look at it,
you're just going,
wow,
isn't it weird that it's fired me taking
off?
I mean we had three d back when I was
10,
but it's not taking them out.
It's a huge fucking trick.
It,
it came out almost a year ago.
You know how many blue ray DVD,
three d movies that they're out to,
two or two or three.
I think the third one just came out the
other day,
like hd,
same thing.
There wasn't going to hd channels,
but you stick around,
there's no way to.
D is going to fuck with three D,
three d,
it's going to take over all.
They're making all movies in three d
now.
Like every shooting porn in Three D.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They've been doing it for awhile.
That's still the way to bring porn back.
How are you going to do three d?
You can download three d and that.
Ultimately you'll be able to doubt it's
going to make a big company.
We invest in porn.
Is that like a market?
It's got a bit.
That's actually smart.
That's actually.
That doesn't make download bruises pop
off the TV.
Right?
You could smell the food for sure.
For sure.
That kind of have loads coming at you.
You're gonna have to dodge a dodge them
know there's going to come right at the
screen and then we're going to shoot
through a girl's face and she's going to
be able to cover the loads,
the loads coming from behind the camera
or something.
Right.
Imagine.
Imagine if it was so good though.
If you had a wall projection TV and the
legs were just being wrapped around you,
it's really going to be gay porn and
that takes off from three because what
could a girl did with three d while
she's having sex?
Like the titties coming at you.
I mean,
how often are,
it's just pop it,
you know,
the depth is way better when it's not
just that,
you know,
you'd have like tricks that was like old
three,
d number,
jaws,
three d.
There was only one thing that happened
that the shark went through the glass
and you're like,
ah,
he's coming after the rest of it was
bunk.
It was like tricks,
but now it's not tricks.
It's like they're doing that.
Yeah,
it's like that.
What was the monsters versus aliens is.
That was the animated show that we were
watching.
That was in three days.
It was insane.
It was so vivid and there was so much to
it.
There was like the depth was like.
It was really shocking.
Yeah.
That's what it's going to be.
Pretty soon it's going to be like where
you look at your wall and it's like
you're looking into the next room that
bats what's going like you're watching
Seinfeld,
like as if Seinfeld was in your house.
If it's gotten as far.
I mean,
what it looks like.
It's pretty fucking incredible man.
Way better than the movies because
movies a big or what happened last shit
went bro.
We lost one of the channels for the
head.
That's what happened.
All on the same as you can get more
creative with gay porn,
you know,
lost loads.
We're losing.
Well you've got a bad connection on the
headsets.
All right,
so anyways,
it's in there,
but it looks way better than the movies
because movie theaters,
it's like kind of shitty resolution.
It looks like grainy,
you know,
even if it's a gi,
it's better.
Even if it's a giant screen,
it's not nearly as good as like a giant,
like 55 inch plasma screen.
The depth that you get when you look at
it like a real good tv.
That's like the resolutions like way
crispr did you see jackass in three days
that was using old school,
three detectives.
Dildos coming towards your face.
So chapel wasn't using depth.
That was act.
They actually slowed down like things
that you could see it come at you and
they really.
That was the best movie that for the
Three d content.
Real awesome for three days.
All I kept thinking about is,
I mean they're,
they're getting fucking some head trauma
going on there,
really jacking their heads up for sure.
At least one of those dudes,
one of those dudes is going to have
gehrig's disease.
You after watching that show on brain
brain trauma,
that was real sports.
Yeah.
What it was.
Are you more aware of that shit?
The whole time I was watching jackass,
I'm like,
God damn it.
It's funny.
It's all fun and games right now.
You're making a lot of money,
but they are really fucking themselves
up.
I mean,
I saw the interview with Michael,
not Michael.
I'm with Muhammad Ali when he was
Cassius clay and he was talking about
retiring when he got to be a certain age
because I don't want to be one of them
to fighters is old and it hit in the
head too many times is talking Dah,
Dah,
Dah role.
Whoa.
Yeah,
whoa indeed.
It was like,
it was so creepy to.
To listen to that.
Like you,
you're the king of dirt or you're the
guy.
Whenever you talk about anybody where
anybody looks towards someone getting
damaged from fighting
in it being a sad case,
he's the one and there's a lot of people
that are trying to say that he has
Parkinson's.
It's not related the fuck.
It's not related.
That's a bullshit politically correct
argument.
Yeah.
He's got Parkinson's.
What does that mean?
It means it's fucking brain is falling
apart and why do you think he has it?
You don't think that has to do with the
fact that he got battered in the brain
for decades.
You don't think that has something to do
with that.
That's crazy.
They had this thing on 48 hours with
Jerry quarry.
Jerry quarry was like this great white
hope from the 19 seventies and they
followed this dude around and he was
like 53 years old when he died and they
followed him around when he was 50 and
he was gone,
gone.
There was nothing there.
He had no idea what was going on,
didn't know how to write his name.
His brother had to help him write it,
so he had Lou Gehrig's disease.
He had everything.
He had pugilistic dementia,
that's what they call it.
That's what they were calling it.
No,
as far as is it Lou Gehrig's disease?
Lou Gehrig's disease is is the same
thing that Stephen Hawking has.
It's your,
your,
your body loses its ability to move
itself.
There's a bunch of different things.
I mean,
Muhammad Ali has Parkinson's,
you know,
this guy had pugilistic dementia,
which is just dementia brought on by
being punched.
The whole deal is,
you know,
it's,
it's scary because we see it all the
time,
man.
We see guys getting checked in the head
all the time.
You know,
it's a big part of what we do.
Trill Shit so much fun to watch though.
God is willing to put their brains on
the line for our entertainment.
Well,
it's just they gotta know when to stop.
That's the thing.
I mean,
you can do it a few times.
You can,
you can even get shut off a couple of
times,
but you gotta know when to stop and it's
everybody's when is different and that's
when it gets tricky.
You know?
No one can tell you.
Remember Alastar overeem when he was
getting knocked out all the time and I
lost our overeem,
was getting like jacked over and over
again.
Surgery Keratan off Jack Damn.
Chuck Odell,
Jack Them,
a lot of guys stopped him.
I think he's been stopped like seven or
eight times,
at least six.
So I mean he had been beaten up a bunch
of times both in kickboxing and in an,
in an mma,
but then all of a sudden he makes his
fucking tremendous come back and now
he's one of the best fighters in the
world.
So it's like you can't never say that a
dude's done because he made a comeback
and then made a Sitcom back in striking
and k one,
you know,
the fact that he was able to have that
kind of success in just straight
striking.
I mean,
that's,
that's pretty God damn process.
So you can't tell it got to stop because
I would have told Alastar over him and
stuff.
You know,
who the fuck are you?
When do you draw the line?
Is it five cows for cows?
You know,
I think Peter has been stopped some
crazy amount of time,
like 14 times over the course of his
career to something nutty like that.
Think about that,
huh?
Yeah.
What if they find out?
What if they find [inaudible] get to is
fairly new.
What did they find out that,
you know,
if you get choked out like unconscious,
like from a rear naked choke or at Doris
or something like 20 slash 25 times
you're,
you're susceptible to get Lou gehrig's
disease just from getting,
you know,
really getting shut off.
I found out.
Who knows?
I would say that they know that you
can be deprived of blood to the brain
for a certain amount of time before
there's damage set in,
but how do they know that?
I mean they,
they know that people have gotten
damaged because there had blood shut off
to their brain for x amount of seconds
or x or is it a minute?
I mean how,
what is the amount of time where you
start getting brain damage?
Number two,
what?
This one's where you're saying like if
you really hated somebody,
you'd choke them out,
but not to kill them,
just hold on for 90 seconds and started
and that's a character who wanted to
develop a guy who's like,
he's like a,
like a dexter or you know,
he just kills people,
but he doesn't kill him.
He just chokes him out just for 58
seconds just to turn them into a
vegetable so he doesn't,
he doesn't go down for murder.
No one knows how this person became a
vegetable and they just make it a
romantic comedy.
And then like one dude and the conflict
is three jokes becomes a level,
does it for money.
He's just like the secret assassin.
He's not killing anybody.
He's just turning your enemies into like
you pay them.
And then one guy,
he didn't choke long enough and the guy
can kind of talk and he's trying to bust
them out so he has to figure out how to
fucking get near him again to choke them
out of the guys pointing out was like,
I got to put this motherfucker and an
arm triangle one more time.
But Tom,
but it just,
so that missile thing a lot of people
don't notice,
but there was a missile was fired last
night off of the coast of California.
Malibu area.
Yeah.
I heard it on Carson radio show this
morning.
And he said that,
you know,
he,
that's where he lives.
He didn't see anything and he had all
these radio show.
Carson Daly,
Carson Daly has a radio show on k rock.
I think he does.
Yeah.
In the morning kid rock is Kevin and
been a,
I think maybe after,
uh,
but he,
he,
uh,
he was saying that he didn't see
anything.
So he had all these callers calling and
then it was like two hours later
everyone said they saw something but not
with the time that everyone else is
saying so.
Well they have pictures of it.
Yeah,
it is.
Something happened.
Yeah.
There was one before that happened.
I remember I was driving,
I was in Hollywood and the sky was like,
it was just turning dusk,
so it was kinda like half dark,
half light.
And they launched a rocket and you could
really see whatever this thing was,
this missile you could really see like
the contrary all behind it and
everything.
It was pretty dramatic,
you know?
And then they had a,
you know,
tell people that they do these things at
night and that this one was a,
it was from at Edwards Air Force Base I
guess,
and they shot it at night,
but it was just not dark enough.
They miscalculated the time so people
get to see it.
So it's like,
what do you mean they just shoot shit up
in the air.
Did they do this all the time?
Yeah.
My friend is in the navy,
says they shoot missiles all the time.
Where do they go to the water shoot dead
missiles.
And imagine if you were in a fucking
rowboat and nobody knew you were out
there and you got hit in the head by a
missile.
Just a random mean people have been
shot.
They've been shot by people shooting up
in the air.
The bullet goes up in the air and then
lands on people.
That's happened a bunch of times.
Could you imagine if you got hit in the
head by a mess?
Jones is saying about this missile thing
or if he even knows about it,
how it is.
Basically the new world order,
the elites.
I'll move.
I gotta move my fault.
The new world order.
The elites know what the fuck would he
say?
He would say something stupid.
It was Obama.
Say something about life extension.
We had a crazy experience in Texas with
Alex Jones with show ideas.
What happened?
Joe?
What did I met?
Lit the Alex Jones show on fire.
What?
Off Milestones fucked up and this is
where he fucked up.
He had joey come on and it was his idea
to bring joey into the room.
He's talking to me about what about chem
trails?
What about what about what's going on
with the environment?
You know what's going on,
what about they're going to kill the
dollar.
So he's got all this stuff that he's
bringing up with me and then Joey's
outside and we're just talking kind of
like straight real conspiracy theory.
Alex Jones style.
But he brings Joey in and we.
We were at the end of the show,
so he goes,
well,
we're going to go into overdrive right
now and we're going to overdraft super
secret overdrive a lot on the Internet,
but uh,
you know,
you can swear it's all right.
It's not FCC,
but don't try not to swear.
So He'd fucked up.
He gave the green light to joey.
He let joey know that Joey can just go
off.
And so joey starts going off.
First of all,
he's going off about Cuba,
about how this is a free country.
Well,
the real,
when it really went awry,
it was when he started talking about
smuggling drugs.
He goes,
I got get on the plane.
I had the sack under my ball sack.
I put the sack of weed and I was
thinking like a motherfucker and he's
going,
no,
no.
Alex Jones going,
no,
you didn't.
He goes,
no,
I did.
It was under my left arm and left leg
than my right ball because I'm right
handed.
I thought I had cancer for awhile.
So.
And he just goes deep.
Joey dss as an,
as Alex Jones is going.
Well No,
no.
That didn't happen.
No,
it didn't happen.
Cox,
I got Obama freedom of speech.
So He's,
he's going fucking crazy.
And um,
Alex Jones can't figure out what to do
and I am laughing my balls off.
So as I'm laughing,
you know,
Joey,
if he's got an audience and that
audience is laughing,
Joey knows how to finish the ages.
Ages rage.
It gets red,
he starts getting sweaty,
he knows how to finish the deal.
So he's going off about how stinky this
weed is under his ball sack and that
he'd go through the x ray machine and he
thought he was going to have to get
arrested.
And then the more more Alex Jones
protests,
the crazier guy,
joey finally,
you know Joe,
he stands up.
He always likes to stay up.
What?
He's going to end something and walk
away.
He's in a fury of frenzy.
He goes,
Joe Def,
facebook,
twitter.
He stands up and he goes,
check yourself before you wreck
yourself.
Big Dixon gas is bad for your health.
Stay black because that's the most
important thing,
to stay black.
And the whole time he's screaming into
the microphone to make it worse so you
know,
he's,
he's grabbing the microphone is big paws
and screaming into the best part is when
he first walked into like Alex Jones as
studio setup where the camera's facing
him like directly and he show,
he just stands right in front of it and
leans down on one knee right in front of
the camera.
So if you look at the video of you can
find the video anywhere like gets just
Alex
and then this big head like blocking his
view.
And then it's the cameraman all
scrambling for new shots.
And it's all like Joey Diaz,
his head covering everyone's faces.
Joe,
he's a fucking national treasure man.
You realize moments like this.
I mean I'm giving it no justice here
describing and I'm trying to describe it
right?
You got to see it.
We're going to have it up in a video and
it's available online.
You can see the whole thing,
but we'll,
we're going to edit it,
put together the right parts in a whole
video of the whole Austin trip.
Because Austin was and always is the
shit.
Every time I go there to film,
it seems like magic happens.
That is one of the best cities in the
fucking state or one of the best cities
in the world,
man.
It really is because it's.
Well,
it is one of the best cities in the
state.
It's also one of the best cities in the
country and if this is the best country
in the world that that's one of the best
countries or cities in the world.
I just fucked that whole thing.
Not only is the food amazing everywhere
you go,
the food is fucking amazing.
Everywhere you go.
The women are beautiful and awesome and
nice and loved a man.
It's a friendly place.
There's a few spots like that on this
country,
man,
where people are friendlier.
That's one of the best ones.
Austin,
Texas is one of the best ones.
Fucking great music,
but the smartest ones too,
you know,
just so many smart,
cool,
interesting people there.
It's just a.
it's a fun fucking place to do worse
highways ever.
The GPS just tweaks when it tries to
find the exit.
For some reason they decided instead of
make their highways wider,
they decide to stack them on top of each
other,
so the logic behind it is so strange and
if you make me miss an exit,
it's so impossible.
Yet the roundabout it you're fucked.
You're fucked.
Because almost every exit becomes a new
highway in another direction,
you know,
like,
where's this one going?
Steph?
It's death if you,
if you miss,
if you miss a spot,
you're fucked.
But other than that,
it's the shit.
Jessica Alba was here.
The first clip that we got those classic
from Austin was the clam thing with
Arctic plant.
They painted that whole green room to.
We did that.
That was sad.
The these,
the green room in the Austin Cap city
comedy club used to be covered with
graffiti and now it's just all painted
and it was like famous comics.
Some comics are dead.
I think Mitch Hedberg was on there and
stuff and they decided to paint this
green over it.
Yeah.
I asked him,
what happened?
Burger King buy you guys out.
Like,
fuck yeah.
It felt like a Kia or something like
the.
Why would they do that?
I don't know.
That was the biggest fail ever.
They should.
Somebody should take a picture of that
green room and just call it fail.
Well,
someone should do is find photos of it
all online and make wallpaper.
Glue it back on.
I took,
I've taken.
Most of them you should do is enlarge
everything up high resolution like with
some fucking Gene Hackman movie type
technology where they can take a big
picture and actually make it look good.
Maybe we'll wait until it's LCD
wallpaper and I'll just email them if a
bitch.
Yeah.
How could they do that?
Man?
That was that place in the Atlanta
punchline.
That's another one.
The Atlanta punchline to green rooms
just covered with.
One of my favorite ones is trying to be
Hicks.
Somebody had that as their avatar photo
on the Rogan board for Awhile.
The best one was in Austin when it was
always my favorite and that's the one
thing I always think it's that pee on
the toilet seat.
Maybe we'll keep women out of comedy.
No,
keep the toilet seat up.
Maybe we'll keep women at a kind of take
my own life and I'm not a person that
lifts might the toilet seat nps.
I'm one of the Ip through it because I
grew up with my mom and my sister and I
just use.
I just wash it every time he piss all
over the toilet seat and know my aim is
amazing,
but once in a while you'll get that one
little teeny drop.
So it's a once in a while.
Someone has to sit in your peers?
No,
because then I clean.
I always clean it with water and toilet
paper.
What about soap?
Was that enough?
If someone pissed on your fork and then
cleaned it with water and Toilet Paper,
you drink pee?
I don't.
I don't think I'd have to worry about
your little buddy.
I don't say it.
Do it every day and it's not mine.
It's his big difference between if I
said,
you know,
if I drank p for a stunt on a radio show
or if I piss in your mouth.
These are two.
Totally.
It's like the old thing,
like we just always talk about your
stand wiping up or do you sit down and
go through the legs?
Me and Joe are both standards.
Are you a standard wipe and then I
jumped in the shower.
I don't.
I just wiped warm shower every time.
Every time.
Wow.
What if your shower?
Every time he shit,
unless I'm like at a public restroom,
but my shift consistent.
Wow.
In the morning when I wake up,
10:00,
I'm ready to go.
I have a bad day.
I never even used that to Chris from
fleshlight did he tell you about a day?
A day that has like a laser that finds
your asshole then shoots water at your
asshole at the same temperature of your
skin and then it comes out with another
laser that shoots and finds the
hairdryer and it dries your asshole?
Yeah,
at some.
Well,
I heard about it in Japan,
they have these.
They're toilet seats.
It's not a bad day.
It's actually a system.
Maurice.
Maurice called me up and Maury Smith,
I call me under the Joseph.
This is a great business opportunity.
Okay.
Listen to this,
starts telling me about toilet seats.
I'll tell you what,
it's not a bad idea because that's one
technology that has not changed since I
was a kid.
You were a kid like that.
It's the same.
Wow.
You got cushion.
That's it.
Why aren't we perfected that shit?
Yeah,
but no one's gonna.
No one's gonna buy them.
It's hard to get $300.
I would buy 300 bucks.
Yes.
Probably a lot more than that though.
Probably really.
Lasers,
your asshole.
Find that shit's got to cost like
$7,000,
like cheeks and shit.
Probably that.
You know what I mean?
Blow dries you.
Who has a Taser and it was $500
installed.
I would buy it.
No Way.
500 bucks.
You would the ones that are 500 to going
to miss your asshole,
but how can it get your butt to hurt?
They're going to hurt you,
but it's going to be pounding in there.
It's going to splatter all the shit
around your balls.
Throw some heat warmers on that.
That I would do 600.
They have warmers too.
That's the other thing that he did the
heated seat sit down.
It's all warm and comfy,
but Bluetooth on it.
Seven Hundred Dollars Bluetooth you have
from her coughing your toilet speakers
behind you,
like really nice bose speakers.
You're just sitting there talking with
someone.
They hear the echo and they get mad at
you.
Are you shitting and talking to me?
I told you to disconnect the Bluetooth
on the toilet.
They'll have like a jawbone of a second
microphone that's outside and we'll mix
the two.
How about to somebody that gets upset at
you when you're talking to them when
you're taking a shit and now I never.
They never figured out.
I've told people before they get upset.
I've told people that this are you
paying on my campaign?
Is that okay?
I can hear you.
I like pretending we don't pee pad and a
pen and a big deal,
but if you're on the phone and you shit
and you like your ass explodes like one
of those nuclear sheds.
You know what I mean?
When you got to wipe you gotta clean the
toilet.
There's only a few people that can do
that with.
You don't usually want to do that.
Like when someone's on the phone and I
said your buddy,
but if it's like a girl enough for a
business meeting,
I have face time with our.
Sometimes I fall on the phone.
I'm like,
well I hope they don't.
They didn't hear that one.
I got to pull a but apart.
There was one,
there was one time when he called me by
facetime and he was shitting,
so I was like,
you know what,
I have to poop to.
Let's do this.
Facetime.
Double Shit.
I haven't used the face time yet.
You guys like it?
Oh it's great.
Now they have a Beta on your Max.
He could face time from a computer to
iphone.
So if somebody's at home you'd be like,
jump on your computer.
You know?
And so now you can face time between
those two devices.
One,
is that really necessary?
It's like your girlfriend and she's like
on the other side of the world or
something.
Well yeah,
you know,
we're all on the road.
That's about it.
Is that like your buddies did get on
facetime,
Bro.
Gonna fucking do that.
Well,
we talked about this before that
eventually we're going to have little
cameras in front of us on like fishing
poles.
You know,
her hang hanging from our fishing poles.
It's probably going to be like hovering
floating with you.
Right.
It'd be a proximity droid to miss the
best technology with the oldest
technology or fishing poles.
Don't feel the need for it.
But I mean that's what I said.
I used to say about text messages.
I used to joke about it.
It takes you four presses to get an ass.
Pardon my act.
The whole thing about.
Remember when you started the whole
thing about next town next to.
They don't have walkie talkies anymore.
Do they?
They still do that?
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
I think Brazil in Brazil next tell is
like fucking burger king.
No Dude,
they run shit.
They failed in the states.
They said fuck it.
We still got Brazil.
Brazil do next toe is huge in Brazil.
Really did love the walkie talkie
feature.
It's on verizon.
It's on all of them.
You know,
there's a funny story,
there's um,
there was this dude in front of a
Roscoe's chicken and waffles and he was
on a speaker phone and he was talking by
himself just standing there by himself
on a speaker phone talking and talking
out loud.
You can hear this conversation.
And so I twittered I said,
what is it about black dudes that like
to talk on the speakerphone is when
they're by themselves,
like what?
What is the deal with that?
And all these fucking people got mad at
me.
A lot of black people got mad at me.
Yo,
that's dickish.
That was dickish like what?
That whoa,
Whoa,
whoa.
I didn't say shit about you.
Okay.
I said,
what is it with all these black people
that like to talk on speakerphone just
because you're black and if you're doing
that.
I'm not dickish.
I'm just observing.
What is that?
That's a weird thing that I don't see
that many white people do them,
but I see a lot of black people doing
and it's not a negative thing.
Like what?
He does a lot of fucking douchey things
that white people do too.
But I'm not being racist here.
I'm observing something.
Are you saying that I'm not allowed to
observe because you share the same
melanin content is this person I'm
observing and even though you're not
even doing the same thing that they're
doing,
that's fucking ridiculous that we're,
we're real close with racism in this
country,
man.
We're real close to being ridiculous.
It is ridiculous.
The whole thing is ridiculous.
You know,
like with especially like the whole,
uh,
anger between feeling like you have to
fight somebody because of their race.
You know,
like there's people like beating up
different races just because of what
race does that mean?
That's legit.
Racism,
but I'm talking about is the opposite.
I'm talking about people looking to
point the finger at racism when you're
really just acknowledging something.
That's a fact.
I'm just seeing something.
I'm like,
what?
The fact that I said that they happen to
be black.
Yeah.
Well,
so does going to be black.
So why do they do this black?
Why do these brothers be doing that?
Or No,
they just do it.
I don't know why to do it.
But you didn't get an answer?
No.
No one has an answer.
No,
but most people were saying their
attention whores,
you know,
and that's what,
I guess one of the reasons why people
were getting mad at me as I was saying
that black people were attending.
So which is not what I'm saying.
I'm saying I see a lot of black people
that like to talk on speakerphone when
they're by themselves.
I don't see why people doing it.
It doesn't mean they're not doing it,
but I'm asking.
It's something I see and might not allow
it to see things because people are
black.
Like that's a tricky fucking road to
walk down.
That's nonsense.
You know what?
Maybe it's because they don't want to
get brain cancer and they're just more
concerned about it than white people.
Dude,
I know somebody that does that though.
I know somebody that only talks to using
the speakerphone function for some
reason.
Yeah,
but not in public.
Outside.
They do it.
They do it at olive garden.
Who is.
It has a slight esther does.
She's black or at least she likes Black
Dick for sure.
Why?
Why does she do that?
Uh,
I have no idea.
She records every single phone call
between her and her parents too because
it's fair.
Her parents are so ridiculous,
but she's just really weird with her
phone and phone calls.
That's funny man.
Sorry about that.
I think it's cool.
Do he really just trying to help you
out?
Yeah,
it's a tricky thing man.
There's,
there was a white girl at the airport
who's talking her ass off,
like just really fucking loud waiting to
get on a plane and it was kind of
annoying.
It's fucking annoying as shit,
man.
You can have a normal conversation.
Just put that fucking thing up.
Do you usually cover?
Usually cover my mouth with my hand.
I don't want people to,
to.
This is a big difference between someone
sitting there going,
hey,
yeah,
what's up?
What's going on?
How are you doing?
And someone going,
Yo,
what's up?
What's going on?
What are you doing?
Okay.
And then what happens?
And then the other person,
the other,
we're going to come down there,
right?
I have to listen to your shit,
man.
This is loud.
Maybe she just does it around me now.
I'm kind of paranoid that I said because
I'm like,
wait,
does it by herself?
Maybe.
I don't know if she only does.
She does it around me a lot.
Maybe it's a security thing where she
wants to do like,
Hey,
I'm talking to this guy.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I'm not hiding this around.
Maybe just being respectful.
Yeah.
I should start doing it around here.
I guess.
Just can't be that though.
It can't be that because there was no
way.
We've got a tricky thing in this world
about people being too fucking
sensitive.
There's a lot of to fucking sensitive
people that can't take a joke or even
take a a conversation.
How about this?
There's Michelle Obama.
Obama's wife is a apparently the center
of controversy because she shook a
dude's hand.
She's in Indonesia and there's a Muslim
dude there and they were saying hello,
you know,
some and some dignitaries,
and she shook his hand and it's like all
over the news.
So retarded.
It's all over the news.
Oh,
I was mad she was being nice to
somebody.
Oh yeah.
The,
the Muslims.
They're losing their fucking mind.
I can't wait.
Muslims are losing them.
Very upset.
I think I pulled it up.
But um,
anyway,
the fucking story is,
it's very simple.
Here it is.
Michelle Obama shakes hands with
Indonesian information.
Minister.
Try saying this dude's name took a
darker too fat to some ring as Obama
arrived in Jakarta and Indonesia.
Apparently conservative Muslim minister
and didn't Nisha who is being criticized
for shaking hands with Michelle Obama,
thus violating his pious claim that he
avoids contact with women not related to
him as you know,
as you're supposed to do.
And some sex of Islam.
What the fuck man?
Two thousand 10.
Dude,
this is in the news.
Some woman's shook a dude's hand.
You know what the fuck man.
What?
He just wanted to touch.
Get something that's touched Obama's
Dick.
You think so?
Yeah.
He went into connection like a Kevin
Bacon connection to Obama's Dick.
That is what you get to shake her hand,
right?
Yeah.
You get it off the way.
We get it all.
You get the whole package.
What would we.
What if she became president one day?
Michelle Obama would be fucking awesome.
Kinda of chicken.
The aunties black.
A black,
beautiful,
beautiful.
If she could be running shit.
If she was an exceptional person to run
shit,
I'd be down.
You know the thing about chicks running
shit as though they have to be really
good at running shit.
They can't just be hot.
That's the problem with this fucking
Sarah Pailin things.
All these faggots out there to think
that she's good enough to be president
because they want to fuck her.
I was talking about this on stage.
They think that life is like a fucking
Kevin Bacon movie where you're the last
vote that counts,
you know,
and then she finds out that you're the
one who got her elected presidents and
she comes to meet you and an unlikely
romance blossom.
So now there's a lot of idiots that are
willing to vote for Pailin because they
really do think she's hot.
But I mean,
you know,
if you can get some genius,
brilliant woman to be running shit,
I'd be just as Dan.
Would that be a dumb bench?
No,
no.
She's never going to become president in
Pailin.
No.
Well,
you know what?
I wouldn't
say never dude,
because I would've never believed she
would have the following that she has.
But everyone knows everyone that has had
a tv for the last year and a half,
two years have seen every single skit
with her.
And even if you like her,
you have that in the back of your mind.
Only you do.
You're not retarded dude.
Fifty plus percent of this country is
almost retarded.
There's a giant number of people that
are so fucking dump that there could be
some other issue.
Look,
how about this Jan brewer chick?
Do you know who she is?
She's a woman who was a.
She was made governor of Arizona because
the original governor left and went to
what?
What is her name?
I forgot what to the Obama campaign.
Anyway,
the point is this Jan brewer,
woman is nuts.
She's not an old and can't fucking talk,
and she goes on these debates and she
paused.
She went on to debate.
She's debating with this other guy's
running for governor.
She pause for 10 seconds,
said nothing,
just a stammering and not knowing what
to do and moving your hands and shit.
She had a full brain lock.
This bitch lied about there being dead
bodies on the Mexican border with their
heads chopped off,
and then everybody went,
well,
where are the bodies?
Like,
where's the autopsy reports?
Where's the police reports?
And it turns out it was all just
horseshit.
She lied about her fucking father dying
in World War II.
She said,
my father died defending on that.
No,
she didn't.
He didn't die in world war two.
He didn't.
She made it up.
Who died during World War II?
We didn't leave.
He's still alive.
That was the guy was alive.
Still alive,
still alive in his silence piece of his
soul died.
Dumb cunt.
More likely.
Now she's the.
She won.
And you know why she won?
Because she supports this crazy new
immigration law.
She wants to keep all the Mexicans out
of Arizona.
Hey,
and most of Arizona is white people,
most of us owners,
crazy old white people.
And they're like,
no,
fuck that Arizona's and nutty place,
man.
We have a good time there because people
like to party and you know,
the shows are always fun there and
people are always looking for fun stuff
too.
But if you look at Arizona as a state,
like it's kind of a wonky fucking state
man.
Totally.
You're allowed to just have guns there,
dude.
You can just be walking around with a
gun in your pocket.
You have to with all the Mexicans,
they got guns.
Ladies,
gentleman,
Eddie Bravo is Mexican.
So before you start fucking firing up
your pen and getting crazy with your
hate mail and firing up your twitter,
it's totally okay.
I could fucking make fun of Burritos.
Own.
Do you have anybody that you follow it
on twitter that you're following?
Just because they're dumb that you can
talk about?
No,
not that I can say.
Oh well,
you know.
No.
Yeah,
you got to be nice,
right?
Yes.
I like,
I like ridiculously dumb tweets or funny
tweets that inbetween shit.
I'm not into like that would just tweet
motivational shit that they've heard
like,
come on now.
I'm not for that shit.
I love motivational ones.
I love like dudes who are like older who
give advice like Steve Harvey's my
current favorite.
Check this shit out as a tweet.
I save them.
I save his tweets.
Your relationship with a man is either
off or on.
It cannot be off and on.
Ladies.
You have the power stop allowing the
back and forth.
Damn.
He's like a black doctor film.
Well first of all,
how do you know that?
The chickens and just looking to get
some Dick,
right?
Yeah,
it's off and on.
People are crazy,
man.
I ain't gonna always work out the trick.
He's trying to get bitches.
Let's trying to get them to like him.
Appear sensitive.
Right?
So it is totally.
Heres another one.
Good morning.
God will perform the unexpected time and
time again.
If you just let him talk to God.
Don't be too proud to pray.
How many followers does he prayed right
after?
I heard that.
How many followers is.
Yeah know he's got a lot.
Steve Farber was a famous guy.
He's good.
So 100,000
probably something like that.
Now I just hit 200,000
pants.
That's something to me.
How many a day do you get normally?
Like adders few hundred.
Few hundred?
Yeah.
I liked how it continues.
Once you get to a certain point,
you notice that you get an average of
like a certain amount per day.
Only have 16,000.
I treated like,
you know,
I,
I look uh,
treated like a,
like a little platform,
like a little comedy,
Farmville world,
you know what I mean?
There's a lot of times where I'd get on
there and I just promote gigs or a lot
of times I find like cool shit,
but I found in line like that I'm a
Italian song or that American guy or the
Italian guy was speaking of seeing an
American accent.
Like what,
what it was like jibberish.
He wasn't real American words,
but what he thought.
Can you find that here?
This is what I would love to hear that
and just someone making fun of an
American accent but not really using
really interesting.
Yeah,
it's really interesting.
It's kind of a cool song and if you see
the video but that like up to eat shit
like that or science tweets.
I was going to tweet something today,
you know,
they fired up the large Hadron collider
and made thousands of little big bangs
there.
Started doing that.
Man,
that's,
that's become a,
become a reality.
They're really doing it now.
So they have all these photos at the
lab.
It's fascinating.
Fascinating fucking shit man.
You know.
But you know,
so there's that.
I do.
And then also like I treat it like a
little audience,
you know,
I think you've got to give people things
man,
when you,
when you're looking to promote gigs and
use the internet and shit like this,
you know,
you can't just promote you gotta you
gotta give him some shit too.
So like the other day I was watching
ancient aliens.
I spent like a whole hour just tweeting,
talking shit on h and aliens that gather
new season.
So bad.
Well,
the first season was incredible.
The first season is awesome.
They ran out of.
They're trying to,
you know,
it was,
it was crazy.
All the shit that we're saying,
but if you look at it this way,
if you're,
if you don't believe in Ufos,
then that sounds ridiculous.
But if you do believe,
if you watched the disclosure project
and you listen to all the courses,
testimony,
the guy who used to work for the.
We used to be in the Pentagon and
fucking head of nuclear energy in Europe
and all that shit when,
when you hear his confessions and like,
like the deathbed confession of General
Ramy
and,
and just if you,
if you,
if you believe in Ufos than fucking
anything as possible,
then that means they must have been here
several times at least.
And if there were around during the
Greek time,
they must have tripped out on them.
That must've been a big news like these
motherfuckers.
And they must have like talked to drew
about,
uh,
you know,
painted about it,
talked about it,
wrote some scripture about or something.
And it's not that far fetched,
but that come into some like ridiculous
conclusions like about,
like the paintings in India that maybe
this was an alien,
will the Mahabharata the,
that's a fascinating text.
The ancient texts of ancient hinduism is
a,
is riddled with stories of,
of flying things and,
and you know,
things that flew through the air.
But you also have to realize that these
people took a lot of drugs.
These people were in the heavy
psychedelic drugs.
I mean Mana to the ancient Hindu tax.
They believe it's some sort of a
combination of psilocybin mushrooms and
a bunch of other different things.
There's a bunch of debate about what
Mana is,
but it's very clear that they were
referencing something that connected
them to the psychedelic world.
And if it was something that connected
them to the psychedelic world,
you know,
and I know you're going to see some
shit.
It doesn't mean that the shit you're
seeing is not real.
You know,
when you see the,
like when people think of
hallucinations,
like you think of,
oh you took a drug and you saw a monkey
that wasn't really there and he,
you know,
you think of something fake,
but what you see a lot of times when you
take psychedelics drugs is not like the
rest of the world.
And then all of a sudden some new fake
thing shows up.
It shows you like a whole new world.
It shows you like a whole hallucination
world which may or may not be real.
You know,
what,
what might be happening when you take
like big doses of any crazy drug as you
might be tuning into the next door
neighbor channel.
You know,
there might be the whole world,
might be a fucking radio,
have a million different channels and we
might be on,
you know,
1:06
point four.
And there's a 100,
six point five and it's right next door.
And when you take mushrooms you go
there.
You know.
So you know,
these guys saying that they saw these
flying things and talking about all
these majestic beings with all this
wisdom that very easily could have been
drugs very easily.
It could be.
That could,
it could be both.
I mean just because you have a
psychedelic experience doesn't mean
that.
I mean that very,
very.
I don't know how much I believe very
skeptical about crafts from another
planet that come here that are metal and
the traditional idea of like,
you know,
just doing a super advanced version of
what we already do.
I look at that and I go,
I don't think so.
This just seems too silly.
It seems to.
Mechanic testimony did.
Yeah.
But it doesn't matter.
It's a lot of testimony.
People being raped by demons.
You can go back in time and find
thousands of Napa who.
But it's not your size.
Yeah.
But these people which try and keep on
organizing and getting in front of the
Washington DC and the national press and
they don't have credible witness like
hundreds of them and Philip course.
So on all these guys that like in their
death bed,
like you watched the testimonies like,
do you think these guys are lying?
That's true.
But it doesn't necessarily mean that
they are telling the truth.
It might mean they're wrong.
It might mean that there's some crazy
government experiments that they don't.
They're not really sure.
I believe in that.
I believe there's definitely a lot of
this shit.
Maybe most of the shit that people see
and report our,
our own government make and shape.
But if you listen to Philip Corso
testimony,
he's saying yes.
A lot of that shit is our shit to say
that he saw things himself personally.
Yes,
he did.
Phil,
of course.
So was this part of Roswell right?
He wasn't at Roswell,
but he was involved in the shipping and
stuff.
He said he saw the bodies.
He said that he was intrinsically saw
them or saw them.
He saw that.
He said he opened the coffin song and
said,
Oh shit.
And He.
He knew so much that he was in charge of
taking crashed Ufo shit and taking it
to,
this is what he said,
taking it to like Hughes aircraft and
Mcdonald Douglas getting reverse
engineer.
Fascinating story about Roswell and
everybody thinks at Roswell's a silly
stupid story and no one knows exactly
what happened.
It could have been some sort of a Soviet
craft that crashed,
but the fascinating part is that they
flew the wreckage and two separate
planes because they wanted to make sure
of one plane crash.
They had a good chance that the other
plane would make it to Wright Patterson
air force base and they made sure they
separated the wreckage.
There's just so much evidence.
Even like today with like the chain,
the China Shanghai airport or an airport
in China closed down twice within a few
months because there were some shit
right over the airport.
They didn't know what it was.
They shut everything down.
I mean just shit like that all over the
world.
I mean there's.
So there's actually is evidence.
I mean people are put away for life with
no video,
no pictures of the crime.
Just testimony,
man,
they're just listening to that testimony
and putting people away for multiple
life sentences.
When you put all the evidence together,
just look up Phillip Corso with the sea.
What?
There's hours and hours of him just
talking about.
He wrote a book about it before he was.
He was an old motherfucker.
He was on dateline and shit.
I think an even more compelling one is
Dr j Dot Allen Hynek exactly.
Was Working on project Blue Book and he
was assigned to discredit ufo stories.
He what his job was as he explained it
was when he would hear about something,
he would come up with a reason that it
was something else.
Swamp,
swamp gas or circular ball,
lightning.
All this different.
She was hired for that by the government
like in the fifties and sixties.
And then when project blue book shut
down,
he dedicated his entire life to
investigating you,
fos and enlightening people on it.
Totally.
And he talks about it.
I mean there's interviews,
he's like ours and then there's like a
new theory.
Now the new theory is that the
government wants everyone to believe in
Ufos.
To keep their projects under wrap,
like they're black projects under wrap.
I'm like,
what?
What is,
what was this project blue book and all
this stuff or whatever saying that it
was swamp gas number.
Trying to calm everybody down.
Why were they lying?
I mean they would have just said,
yeah,
you know what?
We don't know what it is.
It's probably from another galaxy,
but we don't know,
but what we assure you we're going to do
whatever it takes to protect you.
If they really wanted people to believe
in the,
they'd be saying that shit not cover it
up.
So I mean if you look up,
look at the Phillip Corso testimony.
Look at the disclosure project.
There's already been at least two of
them.
I mean these,
there's so much credible and like,
like the top scientists of Europe all
got together.
I forget what the committee is called.
International Group was.
They came together in France and they
looked at all the Ufo testimony and all
the shit and they said 15 percent.
It's probably beans from another galaxy
or another solar system.
That's what they said.
All of them could have been explained
away,
but the 15 percent they said,
this is probably,
I would not conclude that it was
something from this earth that we
haven't discovered yet.
They,
especially when you look at the ocean,
well this is what they concluded.
They concluded that all the other ship,
85 percent of all the shit that like
that could be me,
that could be manmade,
that could be this.
This is probably some reflection off the
sun.
Fifteen percent.
They said the most likely because based
on the pictures and the way that they
got some shit from satellite pictures of
craft coming from the top down that they
couldn't explain it and they're like,
man,
what the fuck are moving?
You know that weird shit of things
moving and then changing angles and
changing direction and moving another
way.
The big,
the bigger incident that happened at the
US military installation in the UK where
there's an 80 motherfuckers that saw
this aircraft,
three of them came up to it as it was
parked.
They touched it.
They took notes that are on the
disclosure possibility.
Three of them went up to it and 80 of
them were all around going,
Holy Shit.
That's possible that it was a drone.
That's possible,
that it was something from America.
When they set it to God disappeared.
It was gone.
When I said,
if you have a drone,
I mean,
especially if we're talking about
different alternative sources of power,
we don't know none of those.
None of those motherfuckers and and it
came back.
They sent a guy to look into it and that
guy's in the disclosure project to like
two days later they sent the guy to calm
everyone down and they came back and
they saw it and these guys are the and
the.
When the military,
the UK embassy,
The d,
the Ministry of Defense,
they're there.
When the.
They came up to them and ask them,
what are we going to do about this?
What was that?
They go,
this doesn't.
If it doesn't concern national security,
we're not getting involved.
That doesn't sucker and we feel that it
doesn't,
it doesn't.
But here's the problem with this whole
story.
Okay?
You weren't there.
I wasn't there.
We're just talking about what we heard
people talking about.
We don't
know exactly what went down and until
you talk to these people,
you don't know how many of them are full
of shit.
How many of them are exaggerating,
how many of them were traumatized?
That's why I say based on the shit that
you see,
if you actually look into it and then
you make the judgment,
you're making the judgment.
Damn.
You know,
if you haven't seen the testimony,
then yeah,
you don't.
We don't know what what he said or it
doesn't.
It doesn't matter.
It's all on testimony.
When you're basing on the testimony,
you don't know anything about these
people.
You never know how much of it you're
getting square with 80 and this is what
they said to.
They said the response to the British
Ministry of Defense saying,
if it doesn't,
if it doesn't concern national security,
we're not going to get involved.
Then 80,
80 people fucking hallucinated that and
then it got 80 people,
80 people that are full of shit.
They got 80 bit needed as neither it
means neither.
That's not true.
If it means that 80 people were not
aware of what they were looking at,
that's all it means.
If they're trained to observe them,
they're in the military,
doesn't mean anything.
If the military people that are in the
know,
the people that are there at the scene
of the crime or the senior landing,
if they're not aware of the technology
that's available to the highest levels
of government,
they're not aware of whatever
experimental shit they're working on.
It might as well be from another planet,
so what are they going to say if they
don't know about horse?
Of course nobody knows.
Nobody was there,
but to make a judgment based on the
testimony,
you can totally not believe in God.
You know what?
I don't believe these guys.
Or You could look at it and say,
I'm going to look at what the open mind
fuck 80 dudes that are trained
observers.
Three went up to it and touched it.
They sat there saying,
it's out of this fucking world.
Definitely they're saying it.
That's what they're in the military.
The British Ministry of Defense is
fucking not even looking into it at all.
I mean to the conclusion are you,
but it's still a bunch of people's
testimonies about something they saw and
then you might not have known what they
were seeing and then you add all the
shit around.
That's just one incident.
Then you look at all of it,
you connect all the dots and you,
you know,
you can make a decision.
And my decision,
Mike,
is that there's some shit going on.
That's how I feel based on our decision
is not that at all.
My decision as is as there's a lot of
people with a lot of stories and we know
for a fact that there are a fuck load of
experimental government aircrafts that
they use for sure they're manned or
whether they're remote control and you
know,
all these people are just telling their
version of a story.
Something that they saw.
I believe they saw something I do not
believe that they know is from another
world.
So them even saying it was from another
People want shit to be romantic.
They want shit to be little gray man to
come here and spaceships from palladium
is wherever the fuck they are coming
from the galaxy.
They want that.
They look for that shit.
Fall in love and that's all true what
you're saying,
but you don't believe that there's Ufo.
What is this believe,
man?
You either believe me.
Don't believe that's not true.
Absolutely not true.
That is not true.
We do not have to believe you're right
in the middle real or something's not
real.
You just go.
I don't know because that's the only
rational explanation.
Yeah,
but you can't say you believe because
when you believe it,
throw everything else out the out the
door.
You said,
well,
this is the.
I believe there are Ufos.
I believe that aliens have landed here.
I don't believe that.
I don't believe we.
No,
I don't believe that.
We're absolutely convinced and I don't
believe that you believe.
Can you believe that Philip Corso was a
crazy man and it was full of Shit.
What do you do as adding words?
So what I'm saying,
12 year old ship based on.
Based on what you saw from Phillip
Course leave,
he's out there sucking cock and take it
in the ass and he's doing drugs and he
didn't even know what he was saying.
How about that?
Is that better?
I'm just trying to get courses.
Just a guy man.
I mean he's a guy that said he saw some
bodies and he's a guy that used to work
for the military.
Is he credible?
The Pentagon?
He was head of head of nuclear energy in
Europe.
Okay.
George Bush was the president and he's
an idiot.
Does it matter?
Like how high he got up there?
It's very clear to me that the entire
government is riddled with fucking
idiots.
There's idiots all over the place.
It.
Was He an idiot?
I don't think so.
He seemed like an interesting guy.
Did he see some shit?
I don't know.
What did he see in those with those
bodies?
What were they?
Who the fuck knows?
They might've been mutants.
They might've been fucking radiation
disasters.
They might've been a little children
that had a disease.
I don't know.
I don't know how much you saw it.
I don't know how close he got to it.
I don't know how much information he was
really truly pretty think Oj guilty.
I don't know if Oj guilty,
I assuming.
Yes.
There's a lot of evidence to dead
people,
knives,
blood in his car.
It's a little different than some dude
who says he saw a Ufo and doesn't know
what it is,
so why did they let him free?
What the fuck are we talking about?
Oj format.
Let's.
That's we're talking about evidence and
testimony and all that stuff.
That's what we're talking about.
A system is fucked up.
That's why because black people thought
that it was one on their side that they
were going to release him and if it did
not fit,
you must acquit and they wanted to get
back at the Rodney King verdict and so
they released them.
That's why was not a Ufo ufs.
You guys have like a,
like a couple that broke up and have
come together.
Careful.
You have to be careful when you start
talking about things that you haven't
seen yourself.
This is just my opinion when the same
way with you,
I.
I don't even if it was the most evidence
ever,
unless I knew for a fact I saw with my
own eyes.
I just too much bullshit.
I don't follow anything.
Why stress out about it?
It's there's too much bullshit.
There's 20 people are full of Shit.
Too many people exaggerate too many
people twist the truth and there's a big
business and talking about Ufos and
that's another thing to be careful of.
There's a gigantic business and writing
books about this shit and doing lectures
and seminars and these guys make a
fucking good living.
Traveling the country,
selling books and talking about Ufos.
Whenever you involve commerce in a very
strange discussion,
like the discussion of the potential
reality of our intelligent life from
other planets.
Whenever you involve money in that and
money and then in the stories.
I mean,
then it becomes sort of a faction of
show business.
I mean Whitley strieber is one of the
fucking biggest proponents of the alien
abduction story and wrote books on it,
communion and had movies made about it
and that guy is a fucking book writer.
He writes books.
He makes fiction.
He makes fiction and he created this
whole thing about getting abducted by
UFOS and everybody took it as fact and
man,
who the fuck knows of it's fact.
You got a guy who's a professional
fiction man and you don't know.
You don't know what's going on in his
head.
In his head.
There's no evidence.
It's like it's like there may be Ufo is.
Absolutely.
There may be.
There may be intelligent life from other
plants.
Absolutely.
There may be,
but you can't just jump on.
Yes.
Because you jump on.
What did I just jumped on?
Jumped on.
It did.
I didn't jump on it.
It's just so much research.
I fucking.
I'm obsessed with you.
I do a lot.
I didn't just jump on it.
I listened to a lot of tests.
You said you jumped at,
but I didn't just jump on it like you're
making it seem like you were like,
I heard one testimony and that's not
what I'm saying.
I'm saying you look,
if you listen to what I said,
what I said was that you,
unless you experiencing it yourself,
you don't know exactly what happened.
When you talking about people that are
talking about crafts that they think
were from another world,
you don't know where it really came from
and that gets very,
very tricky and if you choose to believe
or not to believe you're jumping on one
side or another,
if you're saying,
I don't think there's [inaudible],
I think everyone's full of shit.
You're sick,
you're jumping on.
No,
and if you say,
I do believe,
I believe you're here.
You're jumping on.
Yes.
Even if there's a lot of what you think
is evidence,
unless you're seeing it yourself,
unless it has been proven,
which clearly hasn't.
It's clearly up for debate.
Even though there's a bunch of people
that come forward,
whether there's 100 or a thousand and
they say,
I have crazy stories about things that
move too fast.
Who the fuck knows what that is?
Who knows?
Okay.
You don't believe in your phones.
Wow.
Dude,
are you.
Are you kidding?
You're kidding.
You're kidding,
right?
I'm not kidding.
That's not what I'm saying.
I'm not saying that I don't believe in
your fault what I'm saying.
You don't know why no one knows nothing
else.
No Man.
No,
no,
no.
That's what I'm saying.
Believe when you believe something,
it's like you know,
for like based on the evidence,
I believe there's some shit going on
with other galaxies,
so that's what I believe possible.
That there's life on other planets.
It's certainly possible.
It's also possible that life is a dream.
It's also possible that your life is
imagination and you've made it all up
and I'm a figment of your imagination
and each player is in your life to
provide you with some information and
try to help you and move you along in a
certain way.
It's very possible that this life is not
even real.
It's very possible that I'm in your
imagination in urine mine and we sell
create because a lot of different
possibilities that's possible,
but whether or not there's Ufo because
some people that you don't know who
you've never met saw some things that
you never saw and said.
They wrote it down and had conferences
and discussions about.
I don't know.
I don't know about that.
Do you guys like sweet potato fries?
It's just,
it's a tricky thing,
man.
It's we attach ourselves to what we
believe in and you obviously are getting
attached to this idea of being real
because you've spent so much time
invested,
so much time being fascinated by it,
fascinated with.
I'm fascinated with the testimony and
putting it all together.
You're making it sound like.
I'm like,
like mystic law.
I'm not man.
I'm not making a song that I am saying
exactly what you're saying,
but what I am fascinated by people and I
know that people are full of shit and
I'm not assuming that all these people
are pious.
are completely honest and without
ulterior motive and telling you exactly
know as they saw it.
The truth.
I'm not seeing that.
I'm seeing a bunch of believers and
that's the problem.
Even if you saw something fucking
completely insane,
I don't want you telling me you know
what it is.
I don't want you describing it that way.
I want you saying I don't know what it
was.
I want you to say,
I think,
you know,
it could've been some sort of a craft
that I'm not aware of.
It could be a Ufo means man and
identified flying objects.
You know,
you're not saying you,
you're saying aliens,
right?
Yes.
Well,
I'm not saying aliens.
I'm saying unknown.
And when someone says they know and they
start talking about it being from
another planet,
bitch,
do you have like some fucking serial
numbers you can track back to this
planet?
Like how do you know where it came from?
You don't know shit.
They're just taking a guess.
They see something in the sky.
I can't build.
It must be from space.
I mean it's that simple.
It's not that simple.
Like I go through that stuff.
It is that simple.
If you want to claim,
you know where it came from,
man.
Okay.
He can't.
No,
you can't.
no one's saying they know.
If you don't know,
if you haven't seen it,
you don't know where it came from.
You haven't watched the video of it
fucking flying off that planet and
landing here.
Then it's digital.
A lot of fucking guesswork.
It's a romantic idea.
The idea seems so cool.
The idea that there's fucking alien.
It's tricky because you get sucked into
it.
Like it seems so awesome.
So does the loch ness monster,
you know,
it's like we have this built in shit in
our head.
It's nothing like the monster van
lochness monster is like bigfoot.
Not bigfoot is a real animal.
You know,
they have isolated in an animal called
gigantic [inaudible] that they believe
if human beings came down to the bering
strait and they came from Asia,
gigantic [inaudible] lived in Asia as
recently as 10,000
years ago.
It was a bipedal primate that was eight
to 10 feet tall.
So I believe in bigfoot.
It's an animal.
It was whether or not believe people see
it.
What do the fuck knows,
man?
There was wooly mammoths and Saber Tooth
Tigers here 10,000
years ago,
seven foot tall,
giant fucking birds like a few hundred
thousand years ago.
There was animals on this planet,
in this continent that don't exist
anymore,
that were pretty fucking crazy.
Craziest.
Saber tooth tigers are crazier than
bigfoot.
Bigfoot's.
Just another big monkey.
If big foot was gigantic because it's
just another large primate that went
extinct,
whereas big foot supposed to be living
Pacific northwest,
which is if you follow the the traveling
down the bering strait,
which is where Indians came here.
American Indians
originated in Siberia and Asia and they
came down from there.
America,
what people don't realize is 10,000
years ago,
half of America was under a mile high
sheet of ice.
This was covered in ice.
It's like a barren land,
but something dramatic happened to the
environment of the earth and the ice
age.
When it ended,
the America opened up and that's when
people started moving here.
When people,
some of the people had already moved
here.
There was,
there was.
They found Chinese bodies here from
10,000
years ago,
but when,
when people started moving here,
they came from there.
They came from the Bering Strait.
That's like the number one theory of a
big percentage of the American Indians.
So they came down from Asia and this
monkey lived in Asia and if this thing
followed them with the fuck knows,
is there any compelling evidence for
Loch Ness Monster?
There's pictures,
there's their scans from radar,
they think it could be a big fish that
could have got landlocked that was
extinct in other places,
but not there.
The problem with Loch ness is it's
really murky.
They can't see and it could be a bunch
of other things.
Could be a bunch of other things that
people are misconstruing and there's
been a bunch of hoaxes,
but when,
when enough people have seen things,
you've got to wonder,
well,
what the fuck?
Is it an eel?
Is it when you got to think of all the
animals that are real,
you know,
is it a adult in Moseley floating wood
and just people knowing the story and
going,
oh,
there it is.
There's more evidence for big foot or
loch ness monster.
Probably bigfoot because bigfoot,
there's the American Indians.
That's a big,
big part of the lure of big foot.
There's over 250 American Indian names
for big foot.
Big Foot was born in the imagination of
an American Indian that just might've
made that mention.
It might've been 20 big foot was born in
the head of an American Indian.
That was just winning at attention.
You imagine one dude came up with that
and spread it happened in every.
All the other ones that somebody hearing
that same story and just being paranoid
walking through the woods later.
It's like other tribes,
other tribes with like these fucking
costumes,
like bear costume was the most
compelling evidence about.
Big Foot is actually the audio tapes.
There's these audio tapes of these crazy
primate howls that they've recorded in
the Pacific northwest and they're really
fucking loud.
They're really loud and interesting and
these have been done,
you know,
and and supposedly by legit scientists
that have recorded these sounds.
So it could be somebody let a monkey
loose.
They had a crazy pet monkey and they let
that motherfucker lose and he's
screaming in the woods.
We put you in the woods.
You could make up some sounds that they
would think of as big foot in lochness
announcements.
Baby.
What's the worst?
The conspiracy to like the worst one?
Flat Earth.
There's people that flat to the young
earth.
That's another bad one.
No,
no,
no.
Like today,
people don't believe that young earth.
They believe the young earth.
Yeah,
that's a big percentage of the Christian
population.
There's a guy on twitter,
I follow them all the time.
He's just crazy retarded.
Uh,
a Christian young Earth Guy who's always
talking about the evidence against
evolution.
Yes.
These youtube videos just,
just,
you can't watch them for more than five
minutes because the insanity radiates
off the screen and it starts to get you
blond hair.
Cute Lips was really nice.
They,
they believed that the earth is less
than 10,000
years old.
A lot of people,
more than 50 percent during a recent
Gallup poll in the United States believe
that the earth,
the earth is the age that is depicted in
the Bible,
which is less than 10,000
years old.
They probably don't even know what that
is.
I was going to the Bible say that.
Yeah,
it's the Bible probably.
What does,
what does Jesus thing?
Yeah.
That's all they have to hear.
There's a lot of dumb ass conspiracy
theories.
Big Foot's not the dumbest one.
Big Foot.
There's,
there's,
there's a real animal that they can lock
that too.
It's like if there's one,
the Jersey Devil,
some fucking giant monster,
that's like half the one God,
but I to Texas one.
Well the two Chupacabra,
they've narrowed that down to.
They think it's mange mange on coyotes
because they've had dead coyotes that
they've shot and killed that were
covered in mange.
Do they don't even look real.
They look like Zombie Coyote looked like
ghouls.
They lose all their hair.
It's an.
It's a common disease and they have
photos.
There's photos of him online.
If you look Chupa Cobra,
they have a headless when they chopped
its head off and it's a coyote to coyote
that horrible mange and it has like
almost blue dark bluish,
blackish skin and no hair and it looks
like a monster.
So that's most likely the origin of the
tube macabre because you're talking
about something that killed goats and
shit and killed chickens.
That's what coyotes do.
You know.
So they,
they have that narrowed down.
You know,
I was at the zoo this weekend,
man and I saw a leopard.
They had a leopard there and that it was
so sad that just pacing around just
doesn't get to jack anything.
Just pacing.
Look at all these people staring down.
Well,
they've started to find leopards in
America.
Brown.
Really?
That prints have made their way to
Phoenix?
Yeah,
there's leopard sightings in Arizona.
Wow,
that's awesome.
And now they're coming up through South
America and through Mexico and into
America leopards pro.
That's pretty good.
Leopards are no joke.
Could you imagine if you were the first
American to get jacked by a leopard?
Love it.
What'd you check?
There'll be leopard hunting season and
those motherfuckers will be wiped out.
Do you think so man,
tried to go into Texas in Texas.
They don't even have to open up a
hunting season in Texas.
They'll just start shooting them.
The kids will shoot him.
Who were we talking about the other day?
That was jogging and they shot something
and they had a newer,
more amazed that they had a gun while
they're jogging.
Somebody was telling us this story and
what the fuck told us that.
What was that shit?
That sucks.
I thought,
nevermind.
Didn't they do that in Colorado when we
lived there to jog with?
You have to have a gun,
right?
I carried a gun.
Yeah,
I did.
They have.
They have like jogging holsters.
You carried a gun.
Every time I went hiking.
Right.
Fuck you.
You fucking rifle behind you.
The last thing you want to do is be out
there by yourself with your family in a
fucking Predator attacks.
You don't have a gun.
Especially when it's somebody that wants
your daughters.
It's so easy to shoot things.
You know Kevin Gone.
You put it in your pocket.
I mean that's pretty crazy.
Technology.
You have this little thing in your
pocket that can protect you.
You know?
What are the.
What are the odds of that?
You got to use that shit.
I haven't been thinking really hard
about getting a gun lately.
Let me and like there's two of my
friends that were both saying like they
just called me randomly,
like,
Hey,
do you wanna get a gun?
I think it was Duncan or somebody added
a habit and not to need it.
Needed not to have it.
You can't control all these people and
this world living out in the wilderness
like you did.
We talked about this before.
It's a lot like you know,
no matter where you go,
you got to deal with some death.
Either you live in the city and you've
got to deal with muggers and rapists or
like gang bangers or something.
All you live way out away from that
shit.
No Gang bangers are going out into the
wilderness,
but then you've got to do with mountain
lions and shit like that to deal with
things and you gotta deal with weird
people.
At least you can shoot them and you're
cool.
Like you could just look at them and go
Bam and just blast them.
You can't do that top bugger until he
jumps on.
You got to be careful with bears because
bears are hard to kill.
It's very hard to kill a bear with a
pistol.
If you've got a bear,
you're better off shooting.
And what about bear Mace works?
Yeah.
You got to get them with it though.
They've got to be close enough for you
to get on with it.
I didn't even know bear mace existed
until South Park when I got to be
careful.
Oh,
was he?
He thought it was the bounty hunter that
was in the South Park is based on
evergreen.
That's where those guys grew up.
That's where I almost left.
I want to live in the mountains of
boulder,
but the mountains above Denver,
there's one town called evergreen that I
really liked and that's where a south
park is.
That's what it's based on actually from
Denver.
Those dudes.
Yeah.
That's anybody want a drink?
Coconut water,
coconut one.
Have you had these coconut waters?
I fuck,
yeah.
We need to be sponsored Brighton so they
can send us crates of them.
So if you're listening.
Oh,
what is it?
C T S C two o.
that's coconut water in the rural.
Better than that.
It takes brain box one.
Oh,
totally.
What it tastes like.
It tastes like you just ate a bowl of
fruit loops and it's the milk from the
fruit loops.
Oh sure.
You know,
that's what it tastes like.
Shit,
I'm a big fan on this stuff.
Yeah.
I living in Colorado is just as tricky
as well.
Cheers.
Salute.
Here's the.
Because there's gotta be a coconut water
alcoholic beverage,
right.
There has to be my go to a bar and say,
get me in.
I bought Seagram's for my dad's
birthday.
I bought him a crate of the shit that
you always drink with the mushrooms and
stuff.
What's that called?
Oh,
Kombucha created that in a creative
coconut water.
He loves the Kabuki,
but the coconut water he doesn't like,
but he uses it for a Pina coladas.
He doesn't like this stuff now.
He says it's weak.
He says he needs to add something to it.
I think when you get old you lose your
taste,
but vodka,
coconut water will probably this shit.
When you get older,
you lose your taste buds.
Yeah.
He started losing taste.
One of older people are more likely to
eat.
Ask them,
yes.
You would think that,
fuck no,
I would.
After all the shits,
they had an
the smelling and I remember that video
we watched a long time ago about rods to
remember that shit so serious fucking
video that this dude was in Mexico
filming all these people.
Yeah,
filling these people will sky diving
into this cliff.
There's a cliff that's like a mile down.
It's crazy.
It looks like someone took a an apple
core to the earth and cut this gigantic
hole out of the earth and these dudes
would base jump off that bitch and
skydive and fucking pull parachute will.
As they're filming a.
You see these things flying by the
camera like insane speed and they looked
like tubes.
They look like they're like wing tubes
and this guy dedicated his whole life to
fucking tracking these things down and
trying to find out what the fuck these
things were.
The remodels turns out it was just an
artifact.
It was a video camera artifact that when
something moved too quickly,
too close to the screen,
it stretched the image out.
So it made the imagery was a flying
snake.
Absolutely.
So this poor fuck literally made videos,
has websites.
Roswell Rod,
is he still on it?
He had a.
He had given up.
Let's go to Roswell.
Rovs.com.
So you just fucking dummy.
This is the problem man.
And this guy's making created guys
making money doesn't mean you have those
aren't real dude.
Just because that guy fucked up.
No,
it doesn't mean it's not real,
but it doesn't mean they're not real,
but it doesn't mean they are.
It's like you put,
like you said,
it's most likely I will say that I'll,
I'll take back.
I believe and I say it's most likely
real.
Gotten better.
Is that better?
Why?
Why even have a fucking.
This is about opinions.
Like what are,
you know,
you can't just pay,
just can't just speak to why.
Why?
Why become attached.
I'm just saying,
based on what I've seen,
it's most likely will take.
Decides down.
Fuck.
Kevin Kelly took.
He was videotaping mob.
It says this is the official website for
the mysterious frying entities called
rods discovered by Jose escamia over at
midway and jogger or something,
wasn't it?
It's just a light jog or he's just a
dummy,
a dummy.
They got tricked by some shit,
you know,
I mean,
these guys on monster quest figured it
out and fucking 10 minutes.
This guy has been trying to,
hey kid dot five,
roswell rods that come,
you're done son.
This,
it doesn't exist.
It doesn't exist anymore.
This guy fucking spent his whole life.
Do.
There needs to be a documentary on his
shit because you know,
he tape everything,
right?
They need to get that footage and then
get the footage of him.
Now he's probably penniless and insane
somewhere.
I wonder how many emails he gets by
mistake.
Like I heard you videotape a lot of
rides.
He actually had another one that he was
gay rights,
Gay Roz warrant.
There was another one that he,
uh,
was,
was chasing down another crazy thing
that didn't seem to make any sense.
Let me,
let me type his name because he had like
another thing that was like another
theory about something else.
And then someone on the message board
going,
wait a minute.
Isn't that the rods guy?
And that's who he is from now on.
I,
uh,
oh,
lunar rising.
Oh,
here he goes.
He's got some shit about the moon.
Yeah,
he thinks there's fucking anomalies on
the moon now.
Oh,
okay.
Here we go.
It's the true color of the moon.
For over 50 years,
we have been told and convinced the moon
is nothing more than a black and white
desolate rock with moon dust and craters
that thousands of photos released to the
public have always presented a black and
white moon.
Even with the most recent Hubble
photographs of the moon are black and
white.
NASA continues to perpetuate the lie
that in quotes that the moon is black
and white with this mother fucker is
crazy.
He's like,
tammy switched over,
switched over
bunch of spots that he says,
oh my God,
this is hilarious.
Is they believe that the moon landing
was a hoax.
Oh knows he's.
What he's showing is craters and he
believes that these craters are
different alien artifacts and these
craters like,
oh,
there's such a stretch.
Like the photos are such a stretch is
thinks that these structures are
artificial.
It's like fucking craters,
man.
Shit got smashed by rocks from space.
You know,
sometimes a little shapes come out of
that.
You fucking dummy.
Did you say the moon on Conan set last
night on his first episode.
How was the first episode?
Did you watch it?
Yeah,
it felt really cheap,
like you know,
how you watch the NBC show.
It felt like the furniture was high
quality if felt like those were real
plants behind them.
It felt like a good backdrop.
This felt like they got everything at
fucking sears outlet,
you know,
and,
and in the background was this horrible
blue painting that just looked really
cheap and generic.
And then there was this moon in the
middle of it that was kind of cool and I
guess it moves,
it moves,
but it just looked like the whole thing
look like low budget and it wasn't the
real moon or fake fake man or,
but it just look really low budget and I
don't know,
I was okay.
He had seth rogen on left side and
listen how gay you are you looking at
the set of control as a fan?
I was a fan of the show.
I was a role.
Was it a real moon or fake news?
I couldn't comment on the furniture.
It was a real fan of the show in a lot
of the reviewers of that,
you know,
like newspapers and stuff that reviewed,
reviewed it,
you know,
they made up an interesting point.
It's like,
why are you focusing on a 10th of a
variation of the tonight show?
You know,
that you're not being your own show.
You're being like the tonight show in a
version of the tonight show.
You have this new opportunity.
Why don't you fucking throw that desk
out a window and fucking do something.
You know,
people like that desk.
Isn't that funny that you liked having
people on it?
Isn't it better to do it like this way?
Just like this is like if we were here
or.
I mean we have a table so we have our
laptops and shit in front of us,
but I do have kind of a desto yeah.
But that's to put shit on that.
They don't see.
They don't see the dose.
There's always a pencil and a piece of
paper now.
Yeah.
But our viewers don't see the deaths.
Well,
I mean he.
I guess it's cool that he has notes and
everything.
What they could put that on a
teleprompter.
I think there's some security to the
desk because it's been there forever.
Just because you get boners when Pamela
Anderson from years ago was on.
Yeah,
it doesn't.
It doesn't look cool.
You get nervous when you're seeing
Pamela.
I'm gonna let you sit there on stage.
No desk and they're on a big lazy boy.
Just got a headset on and you don't want
to be too lazy though.
Just in the conversation will be
interesting.
Conan.
Just have a cool house and invite some
cool people over,
you know,
and just eating out.
That's actually now get some good
cameras.
Had some good behind it,
but just have Conan with his little
beard going,
hey,
check out.
Check out my garage just hanging out in
the garage and talk about your movie.
No,
the problem is that a lot of people like
to be in the audience and elect to have
an audience there.
It plate makes the comedy place.
Two hundred people are sad and my people
via skype.
That's cool.
All right.
That'll work,
man.
You know John Heffrons doin like comedy
shows through skype,
something like skype.
It's a new form of video conferencing
technology,
but he sits in a room and there's all
these screens around him and he's like
performing for all these other people
that are in the room with them.
It's pretty cool.
Shit.
It's actually two credible.
I hope that catches them not in front of
an audience.
Know he's doing some corporate gigs
where he does them on a desk and the
desk.
There's like,
there's.
There's cameras at Com.
Adam,
can you hear laughter,
your everything.
They're all connected.
Everyone's conference called up and it's
like,
you know,
5,100.
Hold on.
They're crazy.
I mean he's sitting there by himself in
front of a laptop and then that could be
fucking the whole world listening and
then you could hear all their laughter.
Can you imagine the shower?
Correct.
You have a stereo system and as well he
said it's really crazy because you could
see when you set it up you can see all
these people in front of you,
like you see them sitting like there's
not just one screen.
It was like a dozen screens in front of
him and he sees all these people in
front of them.
So it's almost like an audience.
Whoa.
At the shower ring convention.
Yeah man.
I'm not real interested in talk shows.
You know,
like when I'd heard about it I was like,
you know,
I'm not going to really watch it like a
podcast,
but it's not because it's seven minutes
and all they're doing is talking about
their moves.
They're talking about there.
I mean,
how often does someone have a really
interesting story?
It's not usually.
Most of the time they just pimping their
shit,
you know?
They'll have a little,
you know,
so what's been going on?
We recently had our second baby.
To me it's good because you lay in bed
and you're kind of like watching the
news kind of like,
it's like the news but mixed with humor
right now.
So it's kind of more just like,
it's like I wouldn't watch it if it was
like 8:00
PM.
Right.
I mean,
I like them.
I mean they're okay,
but I don't go out of my way to see him.
I prefer,
I prefer the Jon Stewart show.
Honestly.
I think that the daily show,
the way he does it is the best way.
He has a lot of shit that he fucks
around with like his,
his monologues and his megan front of
things in the news.
Even though it's all political for the
most part.
He,
I think he hit the mark more than
anybody.
He makes me laugh out loud more than
You guys already talk about the Golfer
granicus weed smoking incident on the
Jon Stewart show?
No.
Didn't know what happened.
Yeah.
He smoked pot.
He pulled out a giant.
Was actually
the bill Maher show was a dumpster?
No.
Okay.
It was real time.
But you know,
the executive said that it wasn't real
pot.
That was a prop they had to say.
Yeah.
But why do they have to say?
Why do they have to say it's not real?
Who the kids were,
this is the first podcast we've done
since proposition nine did not pass 19
rather did not pass,
you know,
and so there's a lot of fucking tears,
a lot of shit going on right now in this
country.
There's a lot of shit going on with pot
and disinformation and people thinking
that somehow or another,
if you don't have pot and it's more
accessible than it is now,
that the world's going to fall apart.
It's sad.
I never thought when I was a little kid
that we'd be here and now 2010 and this
would still be up for debate.
Yeah.
But you also know that it's never going
to pay.
It's not going to pass that easily and
the,
unless it's like an iphone app,
one single button,
all these people instead of having to
register and then go get fucking take
off work or go towards your lunch and we
do that.
Otherwise would be too much fraud.
Yeah.
But you know,
in 10 years they're going to figure it
out.
It's going to be on your fucking pagers
maybe.
But maybe there's probably some
incentive to keep it complicated because
the more complicated,
absolutely less people vote and the more
it's political aficionados that are in
the mix instead of just the casual
person.
I knew that was going to happen now.
Did you?
I wasn't shocked at all.
It was just like gay marriage,
you know,
you thought that was gonna pass.
But then you know what's shocking to me,
man,
when the polls are right?
Because I'm like,
how are they,
you know who fuck answers polls,
you know?
Do you ever answered a poll?
Like online?
Yeah.
Or if somebody called you up and you
talk to them or.
Yeah.
All the time.
I do pose to you like if you're on TMZ
and it's like,
that is Mel Gibson's butt look fat?
Yes or no?
I'm going to take the extra click the c
note just to see what the answers are.
No,
we don't.
You know,
first of all,
those aren't real polls,
but I made a poll is like you go
somewhere and it's a multiple page
thing.
We're asking a bunch of questions that
much.
Even a few questions.
10 questions sometimes like you know,
like once in a while,
like if a product that I really like
that you get that spam email with,
like please answer 10 questions for us.
Do you agree?
If it's a company I like I'll give them.
I'll take the extra minute.
Brian,
why not?
I don't know.
Anything that I could do to help the
products that like,
you know,
like if it's like whatever apple,
you do do that.
Like you,
you like make little videos and shit
when you like a product.
Yeah.
The only,
the last poll I took was like who's the
best submission artists in mma?
Bj Penn.
Oh,
and mma.
Marcel is nOt really an mma right
anymore because he'd done though
probably.
Yeah.
He's making so much money in jujitsu.
He doesn't need to go through all that
shit.
He's making a teaching.
Yeah dude,
his website man.
God daMn.
He charges 30 bucks a Month to get his
techniques.
Thirty.
YeAh.
That's a lot
of fucking extra thousands a Month.
That dude who um,
set it up that chessmaster joe,
josh,
I think his last name is waitzkin.
I don't remember exactly how to
pronounce his name.
Bobby fischer.
He's the one from that video searching
for Bobby Fischer,
the movie.
It was all based on him and he was a
child chess prodigy and now he's
transferred that into becoming a jujitsu
guy.
He loves jujitsu and he treats treated
just like chess or as a bunch of
openings,
a bunch of different counters and have
some broken down so he has the website
really like systematically organized the
way you would organize like chest
practice.
So it's pretty fucking interesting.
And someone who's a chess genius.
I mean that kind of a mind,
that kind of a like,
you know,
like retarded,
the word strategic that,
that kind of a strategic mindset apply
to jujitsu.
It's kind of interesting.
I bet.
I mean if you were making free money
just like 20 k a month,
which is probably in the area doing
nothing,
why would you do?
I'm in my money does flow in the
fucking.
He doesn't want to do it,
you know what I mean?
He doesn't need to.
You can just stick to being the greatest
jujitsu player of all time.
Well,
I would love to see just professional
jujitsu because I've always said that,
you know,
one of the best things about jujitsu,
Washington u two is you don't have any
guilt even though you're watching dudes
get jacked and even if you jacker guy,
there's no guilt.
It's because like when you knock
somebody out or you hurt somebody or
even watched someone get knocked out,
at least part of my brain is like,
that guy just got fucked up.
You know,
there's a part of that god is not going
to be the same again.
And like he got hit by a car when
someone gets really fucking head kicked
when,
when gonzaga cro copped procop,
when he had kicked broke up and knocked
them out.
I remember I had an interview cop
afterwards and he was just reallY,
it was a dumb idea to interview him.
I sHould've probably protested,
but we always interview the winner and
the loser and he was up and they said,
okay,
interview the loser.
So I just automatically went to it.
But as I was talking to him,
I'm like,
this poor guy should not be getting
interviewed right now.
This guy just.
He just got knocked unconscious.
He's not exactly sure what happened.
And I'm asking them questions.
You know,
when you see something like that,
man,
you go,
wow,
there's a fucking price.
Which jujitsu never feels like there's a
price,
you know,
guys get jacked and even if they get
hurt,
like he's going to be okay and most of
the time,
99 percent of the time.
But a marcella garcia man,
if he could Just do professional
jujitsu,
if they could have like a guy like that,
you could have professional jujitsu and
even put it on tv and it would be
exciting because he'd be just catching
people all the time.
THere's so many good guys now.
Marcello is still the king,
but there's so many guys out there and
still competing like,
like Ryan Hall and Jeff Glover and all
those new brazilians busted out.
I'm rafael mendez cold brina,
a rafael lovato.
There's so many guys that are good at
nogi that it should be in the olympics
right away.
There's no reason why no good jujitsu
shouldn't be in the olympics is a little
too slow for people that does that,
that board.
I mean,
you have a funny story about going
to watch what john jock.
Yeah.
That's one that I was always the guy in
class that asked the questions about
yanking on colors and yanking on sleeves
and asking like how is that going to
translate in mma?
I mean,
because I was embarrassed.
I.
WHen I first started doing jujitsu,
I would tell guys,
check,
check out this next slide.
This guy's a jujitsu guy.
He's gonna.
Fuck him up.
He's going to jack him.
And the first fight that I got really
disappointed with was a bustamante
against blender.
I love bustamante to death.
He's still one of my all time favorite
fighters,
but I couldn't believe that he couldn't
finish them off his back.
It was just baffled me.
I kept saying,
okay,
he's going to get them right and he's
going to get him on.
He's just setting him up.
He's going to get them and then it
didn't happen and I asked sean,
I'm like,
what's going on with how come we never
see sweeps and finishes off,
You know,
rarely off,
off from the bottom,
you'd never see sweeps and finishes at
the same rate as you Do at the moon.
Dealz at the moon.
Als are sweeping their,
finishing off their back.
Like,
I mean it's,
it's incredible how much action there is
like off your back,
but not an mma.
It was different.
So it's because they don't have to hold
onto.
Yeah.
Well if you practice setting up all your
submissions and sweeps,
yanking and pulling on someone's outfit
and that's actually part of the sweep.
You take that out and then you also add
strikes.
Man.
It just,
it's a whole different game.
So,
um,
you know,
what was the question?
How did we get this talking about john?
Jack watching matches with you and you
guys were both saying how boring.
Oh yes.
Yes.
I always,
immediately I was questioning the
[inaudible] going,
man,
this could be a problem.
This is makinG jujitsu look bad.
Like for me it was like,
how Does jujitsu and mma and then when I
went to the moon deals in 2000 as a
purple belt with jacques and we're
watching the black belts and like,
I can't even keep my eyes open there.
It's just so it just,
most of tHe matches,
one born there were some exciting magic
and there still are some vr.
There's a lot of exciting matches with
the gooey,
but generally,
I mean we,
I was sitting there trying to keep my
eyes open and john jack looked over and
he goes,
man,
this is so boring.
He wanted to leave.
And right there that struck them like,
damn one of the fucking baddest jujitsu
players of all time.
My master is bored with watching black
belts.
Uh,
played tug of war and the gi,
that's when I thought,
whoa man,
they're the key is a problem.
And for me,
the reason why I started teaching
without the g wasn't to separate myself
from Brazil,
the brazilian jujitsu community.
It wasn't,
I wasn't me going,
fuck you,
you know,
you guys went the ge.
I took off the g for jujitsu.
I did this shit for jujitsu and I,
you know,
that's the one thing I want everybody.
I want everyone to understand,
especially the brazilians that hate me
is I did this for jujitsu.
The most important thing for me is how
would you jitsu looks and nma and I feel
that the key is a problem for mma.
So I decided when I opened up the
school,
I want to try to bring jujitsu back of
a,
do whatever I can personally,
whatever I can do to bring jujitsu back
in
mma.
Well,
you did it also because you think that's
the most effective way to do it in mma?
I mean,
yes,
no,
of course,
of course.
I thought it was the most effective way
and I'm doing it for jujitsu.
I feel that if everyone lost the ge,
uh,
10 years ago and just focused on no
geese submissions,
setting up everything in the clench,
setting everything up with over hooks,
under hooks and had to control as
opposed to setting everything up with
yanking and pooling collars and sleeves.
If we would've started everybody 10
years ago,
we just killed the g of heleo would've
said,
no more gate.
We we need to come back.
We need to dominate nma again,
man.
The world would be a different place.
We would see.
We would see 100 shinya aoki,
a hundred havi vasquez.
Did you see when Ryan Hall said
recently,
you know a thing about how he doesn't
play garden anymore.
That always concerned with now is if he
winds up on bottom,
is sweeping,
getting on top to finish.
That's beautiful.
If you could do it,
but what about the guys?
You can't sweep.
Yeah.
He's saying that you can't.
He's saying that you can't rely on your
garden anymore when you can't rely on
sweeps all the time either,
but you're going to be on your back
regardless and if you could sweep them.
I'm.
Most of mY game is all about sweets.
I'm all about sweeping and getting on
top,
but you have to prepare for the worst
case scenario.
A guy That puts on your back and you
can't sweep them.
You better have a wicked finishing game
off your back as well.
You got to have both.
You can't finish everybody from your
back and you can't sweep everybody,
but if a dude stuff's just all your
sweeps and he stuffs all your finishes,
he's just better than you.
That's it,
you know,
but you got to have as much game as
possible.
It's amazing.
Somebody hasn't stepped up and tried to
make a professional jujitsu league,
you know,
I know reconciler really did that thing
for a little bit,
but you know,
he was,
he was having a hard time with it,
but I think.
I think it's more popular now than it
was then.
The problem with the ricoh temporarily
promotion,
which was professional submission league
psl,
great concept.
He just had like eight superfight
matches.
Man.
He had,
he had marcello and they're against.
Jake shields had marcello and they're
against cameron earl.
He was,
but he was the only way he thought he
could make it work and sell it to a
network or something.
Even like espn or something was to have
randy couture as the main event and
randy couture originally,
he retired a few years ago and he wasn't
planning on doing mma anymore,
but he,
he,
his plan was just to stay in the mix
competitively and do submission
grappling.
So rico jumped on and said,
hey dude,
you're going to be the poster boy to
this,
you're going to blow this up.
But then when you decided to go back to
mma,
he was left without a poster child.
And I mean,
I think,
I think he could make it successful with
the guys we have nowadays,
like make marcello garcia the poster
child and then bring in,
you know,
cabrina bringing rafael mendez,
bringing braulio esteem.
Uh,
bring in again,
Jeff Glover,
Ryan Hall,
hobby vasquez,
all These guys that I'm no hobbies back
in the mix in mma now.
But I think you could do it now.
I don't think you need randy couture.
I don't think what they really need is
they need to get some sort of a network
behind it.
Someone who's willing to step up and
take a chance with it.
But it's hard,
man.
Look at bella [inaudible] bell tours on
like fox sports net.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like they have a hard time getting
a network where people are gonna pay
attention to it.
If you have jujitsu on fox sports net,
it's going to be really tough.
You know,
there's not a lot of people that are
like focused on that.
If you get it on espn on the other hand
and made a big deal and the difference,
the difference between submission
grappling and mma,
the the advantage.
It can be a small advantage in some
people's eyes,
but people will get into it because
anybody can actually practice it and you
can go to your local Jujitsu school and
you actually can get involved.
So and as the potential is there,
of course it's not.
It'll never be as exciting as dudes
smashing skulls and and all that kind of
stuff.
But a submission,
grappling with the right guys can be
very,
very exciting.
And I hear,
I think it could be successful if they
got dogs and frisbees at 1:30
in the morning.
You can throw up some nogi Jujitsu up
there for sure.
They got the pool is huge.
I mean paul is on tv all the time,
so to starvIng to death,
but it's on tv barely.
It's barely on tv.
A lot of those matches that you watch
old matches.
The women have some on espn or there's
no money in it.
No one's making any money overseas to
make the real money.
Ms dot couple tournament's like the us
open.
You went out,
you went $40,000,
get to play for a week and that's only
the winner.
You know,
you get down to like the other people.
There's not much.
There's not much money in it,
but it's still on the air and I could
see submission grappling like that on
the air and no one's really making that
much money except for the top guys.
But then you got like poker that's
making money,
right?
who wants his fucking poker?
the thing about poker is,
man,
the thing about you watch poker,
I love about her is that you could watch
and you could know what we all have.
Like when you're watching at home,
you can't affect the outcome of the
game.
So you could see like if you had to
aces,
you had an ace and a king.
You could see without you seeing when he
had the people watching,
could see what he had.
So they know everyone is in on it.
So how's this gonna play out?
And it loaded.
What if facebook is like that?
Where you knew what the pitcher was
gonna throw like right before they let
you know.
That's interesting because if they let
you know a second before you throw,
how could he ever get to him?
How could it get to him that quick and
if he's looking somewhere else,
he's keeping his eye.
He would fuck them up.
That's a good idea right away.
Boom.
Yeah.
If you had the picture had like a little
thing on his mouth,
you know what?
It would have to be someone who could
read the signs because the catcher is
giving those signs or just do it like a
22nd delay because the catcher gives
those signs with the pitcher.
Give those signs.
Who decides what gets thrown?
Think a catcher,
the picture can say,
no fucking the pitcher has.
He's like the executive producer and the
producer,
but you can have like bitchy arguments.
You can totally.
You can see that you see him going,
oh dude,
no,
no.
Basically the catcher trying to get them
to agree like,
okay,
what are we going to do?
It's up to you,
but you want to throw this.
I'm just suggesting this,
but you could do that with football too,
like uh,
right before the snap boom.
It's going to be a run or something.
Dallas is one of the hardest things
about putting anything together
is getting two people to agree on what
should be done.
You know,
like if you have an executive producer
and you have the talent and they're
together and they're trying to figure
out how to work things out,
man,
that's a hard fucking thing to come
together on.
You'd have to put it on a ten second
delay then that would ensure that no,
for the baseball thing,
I mean,
if there's no,
uh,
you,
you've had that with music though,
right?
You've had that with music.
We're dudes are trying to fuck with your
shit and you didn't like it.
Remember that executive producer you
were working with for awhile?
Which one?
The guy down in san diego.
Oh yeah.
Where you wanted to do all this and do
all that.
Now.
That wasn't a sudden you'll fuck.
Exactly.
I was all time.
Yeah,
I've had it happen with everything I've
ever done.
Everything I've ever done that has to do
with creativity.
That involves other people.
They all want to do.
I am open to hear shit.
I'm.
I've always been that way in every band
that I've been in,
the rule has always been the same.
We are five of us.
I'm 22 years old.
Everyone's like in their early twenties
like anybody can write,
but we all have to like it.
Like if you want to come up with
something,
okay.
We all have to like it because when
you're on stage man,
what's most important?
You would rather play someone else's
good shit.
Then you're bad shit.
Ooh,
you don't want.
No one wants to go on stage and the
crowd's going,
what the fuck is this?
And no one's liking and the other guys
are going to talk behind their back.
Like,
dude,
I don't want to do this song.
And that's the last thing you want.
You want to avoid that.
It's,
you know what I mean?
So what ends up happening is real quick,
you end up gravitating to the guy who's
putting together the best shit.
There's always a band where you know
that they're just given this fucking
drummer a bone,
letting them sing right now.
There's always a few songs like that,
right?
Dude,
the perfect example is peter criss from
kiss.
He co wrote a song.
Keep thinks he wrote beth,
but really bob ezrin wrote it and he'll
famous producer.
And so it says peter,
chris,
and bob ezrin.
That was the biggest kiss.
Tsonga date.
Beth was huge.
It was a.
There was the first one that ever.
I was a huge kiss fan,
but it was the first one I made it on
the radio.
Yeah,
that was massive.
Beth is fucking huge.
So peter,
chris got a big head because I want to
leave kiss.
You guys are letting me only write one
song.
I want to write more songs.
He goes,
I'm going to make a solo album,
and Paul Simon goes,
doo doo,
doo doo doo doo doo.
We'll all make solo albums and we'll put
them together,
but let's not break up.
make a solo album.
That's cool.
Well,
I'll make so long.
So they all put out those salons at the
same time.
Peter christmas album,
the guy who wanted to leave to make this
all was not only the worst of the solo
albums,
but it's the worst kiss album ever.
He made.
He's known for the worst kiss.
No kiss fan has ever said they like that
album.
Really?
It's that,
that it's that bad.
It's bad.
Dude.
It's really,
really,
really bad.
So he's not in the in the band anymore,
but there's a fake peter criss now the
way they did it originally when the
peter and ace left,
they replaced them with new characters
like Eric Fox came on to replace of as
the fox.
Vinny vincent came on to replace ace for
the as the egyptian god or something,
but then then they finally took the
makeup off.
They went like 10,
15 years without makeup and then when
they put the makeup back,
they got peter and ace,
the original guys back.
They did a couple of reunion tours in
the exact same thing happened.
Peter fucked up,
fucked up.
so they kicked him out.
But this time,
what happened to the fox?
Where'd that guy go?
He died actually,
no.
Um,
but uh,
when they,
when they did the reunion tour,
you got to bring back the original guys
because there was two other guys that
were a trigger of this picture.
It's a really tattooed on this guy's
side.
He was a,
he was a Bartender or a server at the
cap city kid kidney bobby.
And he rented a ace and he was drunk and
he was talking all this shit to ace
Freely and he's feeling.
He goes,
fuck you kid.
So he gets a picture tattooed on him
with,
fuck you kid,
let's put it up here.
THat's amazing.
So yeah,
but I'll put it on my twitter later
today.
But he got this fucking tattoo of ace
freely tattooed on his whole side of his
body is permanently a big picture of a
shitty one to have ace freely where it
says,
fuck you kid underneath it.
That's incredible.
So when they decided to do the reunion,
they got the original guys,
ace and peter.
It's been like 15 years.
Of course they wanted to do.
They realized,
fuck we fucked up.
God dammit.
Why don't we leave,
kiss and get kicked out at the same
time?
It's like both.
They both got back in the reunion tours
were massive.
They did a couple and then peter started
fucking up at a.
Started fucking up.
Somehow they left.
so instead of getting new guys with new
characters,
they got new guys to play.
Ace and peter did.
And they,
they,
they kept to the guys and say as no,
they never did that.
They never did.
No,
they never pretended like that was the
real ace.
And that was the real peter.
Maybe they did the first few shows.
Maybe they try to do some shenanigans.
Not saying that did shenanigans.
I said,
they said,
you know,
and now starring as Bang,
and they say the guy's name.
I don't know.
They've never felt safe.
Never said no.
They said the real guys name the because
because what happened is when they did
the reunion tour,
eric singer,
the non makeup kiss drummer and bruce
kulik,
the non makeup kiss guitar player,
they got leFt in the behind because
we're going to do a reunion tour and
blow this shit up.
This non makeup banning happened to.
But.
But when peter left,
they got the non makeup dude,
eric singer to play peter.
So he came in and he didn't.
He always said he was eric singer,
but they know that most of the fans that
are coming don't even know the
difference.
Oh man.
I liked kiss me when I was a kid.
I'm gonna.
Go check out kids.
They're fucking cool man.
Rock and roll all night.
They have no idea.
They realized they never hide it.
They never deny it,
but they know that it doesn't really
matter.
They're just going to come up.
We're going to say,
that's eric singer.
We're going to say that's tommy thayer
plan a's,
but most of the people aren't even going
to notice what was the deal with age
freely and peter criss or why couldn't
they get it together?
The exact same thing.
Drugs and alcohol and peter and then
again all to peter.
Peter was not a very good drummer back
when he practiced a lot and when you.
I mean it sucked.
Jujitsu,
man.
You don't fucking keep practicing.
You lose your chops.
You have a drummer,
has to be like a fucking machine
literally on time.
And peter and paul and gene have never,
never stopped touring,
never stopped putting out albums.
Those guys that are machines,
they could sing their ass off and they
could play.
I mean paul is unconscious playing and
singing and gene.
He's a mo.
One of the most underrated bass players
ever.
He can sing fucking harmonies like the
beatles,
paul and gina machines,
bro.
So what they got,
they were decided to replace eric
singer,
the old non makeup kiss guy.
They brought them in.
They put peter criss makeup on him when
he can and he can sing.
Eric singer can sing it and he can play
his ass off.
He's an amazing drummer and he could
sing.
So they go,
we're going to bring this guy back.
Does he sing beth now this?
Yes,
this is.
This is.
They did a reality show,
you know,
they did a.
The success,
the gene simmons show was so successful
that they ended up doing it and they
would show spots of kiss during the gene
simmons reality show,
but then they kind of did a spinoff.
Why don't we just follow kiss?
So reality shows all fucking fake.
You know what I mean?
So most they had to make even the ones
that are real,
the camera that the facial reactions
like they have like one camera there and
how they're getting honey panning to all
these facial reactions.
They like storing these facial reactions
from what you know from two weeks ago.
There's a good one to look.
That's how they do it different.
Yeah.
That's how fake it is.
So with the gene set,
with a kiss reality show,
there was like a mini series wral or it
might be an ongoing show.
They have to create some drama,
so what are their following around and
eric singer who's dressed like peter is
like,
Jean,
can I do beth in the for the next show?
And then jeans,
all you know,
a promise,
peter that we wouldn't do beth.
I don't know if like,
come on dude,
let me do bath.
So then eric singer disappears.
They're about to do a show.
Where's eric singer?
We started an hour.
No one's been able to find them all.
They're all looking for uyghur singer.
He's like,
fuck it.
Let's get the roadie and get them and
makeup we're going to get.
We're just going to do the show without
them.
We're going to get the ready to do it.
They never show the roadie putting on
makeup or anything getting ready.
THey were just like,
oh man.
And then all of a sudden eric shows up
backstage.
He's all dressed up and makeup and he
goes,
they're going onstage and he looks over
to peter goes or to paul.
Stanley is gene can lmp two path or not
in paul goes,
bro,
Just get up on stage,
man.
I don't think so.
Something like that.
It's all ridiculous,
dude.
Fake drama and then he sings it.
I don't.
I didn't even get that far.
It was ridiculous.
It was ridiculous,
man.
Having them argue backstage about
singing.
Beth,
is there a way to do a reality show and
not have fake shit?
No editing allowed.
It's just one camera.
it is,
but it might not be interesting.
Yeah.
You gotta have it.
Got three cameras to some people.
I'd rather watch an hour that I know is
100 percent real than an hour.
That's like you said,
have just chopped up.
So that should insults the fuck out of
me when I watched like keeping up with
the kardashians and I see bruce jenner
running around town trying to fucking
meet a deadline or something stupid
where I know it's not real and like,
come on man,
the fake show on my shit is done just
all out of fun,
man.
We want it fake.
We do those fake.
We do.
We're storing a facial reactions and
stuff from people just putting them in.
We're having fun with it.
It's like all things.
What he's talking about is a
10th planet jiu jitsu.
Dotcom has got a thing called mastering
the system and it's like a fake jujitsu
reality show,
but there's real,
real techniques in there.
I real techniques,
but we just have fun with stan with
shenanigans.
That's hilarious.
Is the whole,
uh,
an auto thing?
What is the deal with that?
Is that.
Oh,
the latest episode that just went up.
He chokes me up.
We get in a fight and he talks about and
it puts out any leaves people.
Have people figured out what's going on
yet or do people think it's the most
people know it's fake,
but there's a small percentage.
Like I just got someone,
a forum member from the day one.
This girl emailed me yesterday,
said,
I,
you know,
I respect your you to death and all
that,
but I have to know once and for all,
is the helper thing real?
She goes,
I just got a note.
Either way,
if it's real,
it's real,
it's cool.
But if it's fake,
just let me know.
I just don't know.
Like,
wow,
you don't know.
You know,
there's so much evidence.
People are piecing together,
they're taking footage of the days of
our lives.
They're putting it on a forum and I just
keep deleting it.
Any,
any evidence?
I just delete it.
Just delete it.
It's a tricky thing,
man.
When people fake it,
when people fake anything.
You know that video I just saw the other
day of a alan belcher,
a pumpkin.
You.
You ever see that video after you've
seen it?
You haven't seen it.
There's a video of you punking him at
your school and then he punks.
You remember that was columbus,
philadelphia,
somewhere.
Somewhere.
But he got you.
I knew it right away.
I was like,
no fucking way.
I just thought he was crazy because this
guy's nuts.
I wasn't hearing what he was saying.
I was just going,
oh,
I guess I always start like the first
time I ever met alan belcher,
it was after an awesome victory.
I talked to him a little bit and invited
them into my school.
I thought he was like,
uh,
I got mad.
This guy can snap.
He was seemed like a snapper.
I keep just like I seen.
I'm like,
damn,
I'm like a little scared of him.
I didn't really know it.
Just in the first time we met,
he had just beat someone's ass.
His lip was all fucked up and it was
quivering.
You got to cut live and it was quivering
and I'm like,
man,
I'm like,
dude,
I would love to show you some,
some rubber guard shit you know,
and come on down to the gym and I for a
second,
I thought,
man,
this guy,
he could snap on him.
He ended up being a super fucking
sweetheart.
He's totally cool.
I love alan belcher,
but when he tried to punk me,
what was the premise of it?
I don't even remember.
He got mad about something.
I don't remember,
but I remember as soon as it started
coming,
as soon as it happened,
he was screaming.
I turned to the camera,
went no.
like he was trying to fight you.
No,
no,
it wasn't me.
I was on the outside.
You and you were trying to keep him for
getting mad about something and he was.
I think he was going to start a fight
with a bouncer or something.
He was getting nuts with a bouncer and I
was going,
oh no,
fuck.
We got a crazy amount of fucking.
He's gonna fight a bouncer right now,
but that is a problem if you hang out
with a certain number of mma fighters.
There's a few,
you know,
always one or two that's a loose cannon.
You never know.
A couple of drinks getting.
I'm shaking and that Judy Browning was
at my school last night.
Oh,
he's totally cool,
man.
I love
Judy Browning,
but before I actually met him,
he was the only guy ever that I saw on
the ultimate fighter and you know,
we're always backstage running into
these guys all the time and that new
season comes on.
I go,
oh,
I got to remember these dudes because I
want to be running to him all the time.
I don't want to not know their names and
feel like a total douche bag.
So I'm like this.
I'm like watching the show,
studying their fighting techniques,
seeing what kind of fighter they are and
what kind of personality they have.
One,
they showed joni browning on top.
I thought to myself,
man,
this guy can snap on anybody.
I don't want to get to know this guy.
I made the decision in my head,
don't get close to that guy.
That guy was holding in las vegas.
We're eating at nine and he was a really
nice guy and what happened was it was a
big fan of yours and that's.
I tried to avoid him.
I didn't even want to talk to him.
I just talk from the show.
They made him seem like a total lunatic.
Right.
So I'm in.
Sean tompkins trained him and he just
fuck somebody up and on spike show in
vegas and we're at nine the places I see
sean pumpkin's walking towards me and
I'm like,
I'd love sean tompkins.
So as soon as he came up I like,
you know,
we gave,
we gave each other a little hug and I
saw that.
Oh damn.
Johnny brown is right behind him and his
buddy.
So I hugged sean tompkins and kind of
look the other way,
trying to pretend like I didn't notice
any brownie.
I'm going,
fuck man.
Here he comes.
He's coming right for me.
Shit.
He's with sean tompkins.
I hear him right next to me.
It's like right over my shoulder.
And he almost passed me by booz buddied
from Kentucky.
Said,
hey,
there's eddie bravo.
And I'm like,
oh shit,
he's going to come up.
So he tapped me on the shoulder and I
looked over and I was,
hey dude,
what's going on dude?
Great fight.
Fuck.
And I'm thinking,
oh shit,
I'm actually talking to him.
Holy shit.
What's going to happen?
And then he goes,
bro,
man,
we're always studying your books and
smoking weed and,
and um,
and uh,
on the mat with your book out.
I do rubber guard.
I got a good twister.
And all of a sudden like,
whoa,
this guy's,
this guy's a 10th planet fan.
Like all of a sudden I got,
I got to get this guy a chance maybe.
Maybe I prejudged him.
and he turned out to be a fucking cool
guy,
man.
And he's thinking about moving to la and
to get away from vegas.
He's not partying anymore.
He just wants to clean up his life and,
and,
uh,
make a big combat.
Still a young kid,
right?
Isn't he?
And he's funny as hell too,
because when he's funny,
that motherfucker's funny.
He doesn't have to be drunk.
After jujitsu.
We hung out in the parking lot and uh,
he made all of us laugh quite a few
times.
He's got some video shit,
man.
He's a cool dude.
He just,
you know,
he had a bad upbringing.
His dad used to beat the shit out of him
and you're going to come up,
you're going to have order,
kinks,
kinks.
That's all.
I mean,
we've,
we've run into so many guys over the
years that started out like that and
then eventually got their shit together,
you know,
one way or another.
I mean,
it's fun to watch guys like that evolve
and become something better than what
they were like.
Chris,
a perfect example of guy started.
I was kind of a brawler and now he's
like a fucking like after you put erin
simpson away,
he's like a seasoned motherfucker now.
Triangled akiyama.
Yeah.
For real.
Chris stevens,
a bad man.
He's smart man and I believe that Judy
Browning,
I believe that he's too
smart to throw his life away.
He's not smart.
He's,
but he was an idiot.
He might.
He might just keep fucking hell.
You would benefit from hanging around
human if he,
if you understand troubled childhoods
and channeling that shit into something
positive and being around positive
people,
man,
that's the most important thing to,
for having a positive life,
being around a bunch of other people
that are on the same wavelength as you.
Trying to do the same shit.
And that's one of the cool things about
a 10th planet jiu jitsu in hollywood is
that everyone is super positive there
and it all trickles down from,
you know.
Well,
you know that right?
I mean it all trickles down from you.
I mean,
a lot of places if you go to there and
the instructors kind of douchey and
people can get douchey with each other
and there's none of that at our place.
Everybody's very cool.
All I'm doing really is acknowledging
that everyone has an ego.
I have an ego.
Everybody has an ego and I just,
every day I tried to do things to keep
that ego in check because if I don't,
if I'm not consciously trying to keep it
in check,
sometimes it just pops up and fucks up.
You know what I mean?
So,
you know,
I,
and the,
it rubs off on my students.
My students are constantly,
you know,
like the ego flares up,
they can catch themselves,
they can correct themselves.
It's a lifelong process,
man,
that you know,
everybody has an ego and they,
everyone struggled with podcasts is a
part of their two man.
I've talked to a bunch of people that
I've met all over the world.
One of the most important ones was this
kid that I met in boston who is from
Ireland,
who was explaining that man.
He goes,
I don't,
we don't have anybody like this near me.
No one talks like this.
No one gives us this.
There's no one around it that's a
thinker this way that thinks about life
this way.
It's openminded.
And he goes and because of this podcast
is making me like,
like reassess the way I evaluate life
and reassess the way I talk and think
about things.
Having guys like you teaching jujitsu,
having a podcast like this,
like this,
like a serious,
like a serious connection we have to all
these people and they helped me too,
man.
I've,
I've gotten a bunch of cool tweets from
people and inspirational shit and cool
articles that people tweeted me and cool
things that people post on the message
board and it's all like a big thing
together.
You know?
It's all a big thing.
Everybody helping everybody else now.
It's so much fun.
Every day I drive to class,
I remind myself on the way to class and
how lucky I am.
Like,
I'm dry,
this is my job.
I mean,
I didn't even look at like,
look at like a job,
look at it like a job.
Sorry.
But I mean every day is a day off for
me,
man.
And I appreciate so much just going to
class and everyone's just sitting there
and they're waiting for me to teach them
how to strangle like,
you know,
in an efficient way.
Like how fucking lucky am I.
I can't believe that every,
it's,
it's amazing.
And the cool thing about jujitsu for
people don't know is everybody's real
friendly to each other man.
I mean,
people catch people all the time and,
and you know,
an arm bars and chokes and shit like
that and you know,
you don't want to get caught,
but there's no,
no fights ever breakout,
no bullshit ever happens.
It's all just,
you
know,
damn,
I got caught.
Hi,
what did I do wrong?
Or you forgot to put your arm in.
Oh shit.
Oh thank you.
And you know,
it's a massive misconception about
jujitsu,
that jujitsu classes or a bunch of meat
heads,
they're douchebags dick heads.
And She would think it's like we trained
in a cage and it's a bunch of computer
nerds that,
that are playing the ultimate virtual
reality game because if you're into
video games and like killing someone by
pressing a button,
but no one's really dying,
but you enjoy that,
that feeling.
Jujitsu is the ultimate virtual reality
video game.
It's where we is going to end up feeling
more like a baseball bat,
like a golf club.
How about you can can actually kill
people,
you know,
theoretically or you know with jujitsu
you put someone under choke,
they tap out.
It was like you killed them because of
you didn't let them go.
You would actually kill them and you can
learn.
You can anybody.
there's so many jujitsu schools all over
the world.
You can learn how to systematically and
scientifically break limbs and put
people to sleep.
There's over 20 different ways you can
put someone to sleep just with the neck.
You know,
there's probably more,
I'm just guessing,
at least 20.
All of these different chunks.
So many different variations of
guillotines doris as a chat and it
becomes just a really fun game too.
It's an amazing guy killing game where,
I mean I hurt my arm like a couple of
weeks ago,
you know,
but like you know,
for the most part when you get to go to,
you know,
get involved in like,
like serious rolling with somebody.
Everybody's fine at when it's over,
you know,
you get caught with something,
he just tap and 99 percent of the time
you're fine.
Every now and then you'll get something
in something I'll get tweaked or you
need to get twisted.
I know you had a knee problem that
happened recently.
Both my are fucked up,
but it's so fun.
You never think about stopping doing it.
You just think,
man,
I can't wait for myself to heal up.
Exactly.
So I can get back in and you're like
fuck.
Like when you,
when you tweak something or like god
damn I probably out a couple of weeks
and it's just fun.
It's so much fun.
I mean it's.
Think about this.
You have to work out.
Everybody has to work out.
If you're in perfect shape,
you have to maintain,
you have to keep working on why not work
out and learn how to take people out,
put them to sleep at the same time and
it's and it's the ultimate video game.
It's exercise.
You learn some serious self defense.
It can come up at any time in your life.
It's valuable and it gives you so much
confidence and it's so much fun.
It's kills video games.
It's like there's anything.
You meet a lot of great people that have
their ego in check because if,
if you don't have your ego in check,
then those people don't survive jujitsu.
That tapping is that ego?
A douche bag filter.
The tapping because dudes that are just
just there,
it's where their eagle rules.
They can't jump on the mat and get
tapped out.
They run from it or they get on the edge
of the mats are like,
no way am I going to let people tap me
out and they don't really don't know
what's going on,
but subconsciously,
the fear of being dominated and tapping
out by losing,
looking like a week
lane that scares people away.
You got to look at it like you're just
learning.
You.
Of course you're going to get tapped out
in the beginning and the more the more
you come,
the more dedicated you are.
As time passes,
you start tapping dudes out
occasionally,
but still,
you're usually tapping or beginner,
but ultimately one or two years,
man,
you,
you can minimize those taps and you're
getting your learning.
If you did,
you just jitsu for two years,
the odds are in a street fight one on
one.
The odds are way on your side way on
your side.
If you know anybody could,
anything could happen in a street fight,
but man,
a guy that's trained jujitsu two years
against the guy who has zero training on
the ground.
Another great aspect of it is it a calms
down your body and it makes you realize
how much of an influence stress and just
the fact that we have this ancient
chimpanzee hardware in our system,
our bodies are set up for hunting and
gathering and carrying things and our
bodies are set up to exert a certain
amount of energy and if you don't exert
a certain amount of energy with your
body,
your body starts to betray you and you
start to get really stressful and you
start to snap at things they wouldn't
ordinarily snap out.
Oh,
you shouldn't rationally be upset about.
It allows you to put things into
perspective.
It calms your body down.
I was very important,
man.
Yeah,
I mean,
are you saying Jujitsu is better than
quake?
Are you going to start that?
There's a bunch of people put a bunch of
videos of cool video games that are out
there,
man.
Fuck.
You know,
lIke to try to tell me that there's all
these different video games.
Man.
There's some insane shit.
There's this one,
I don't know the name of it,
but they were.
It was like it looked like they were in
the jungle and they were like near
something like it looks like some mayan
temples and shed.
The graphics are insane.
Rushing attack.
I don't know what it is,
man.
I don't know what it is.
I don't remember what someone put just a
demo up and then someone put crisis out
of it.
I don't know what it was,
but at the demo was insane and then
crisis was another one that was pretty
interesting.
A bunch of dudes runnIng around shooting
people,
but then I put a video of went to watch
a video of quake online and I go back to
what I said nothing could fuck real
quick because I understand that these
games are beautiful.
I understand these games have all these
cool things you can do quick for.
All I want to do is fuck people up in
one-on-one death matches.
That's what I like to do,
but yet you're not even talking to.
I understand what you're saying,
man.
No,
I'm just saying that if you like death
matches,
they've taken that the formula of death
match and it just added onto it for like
the last 15,
20 years or whatever.
How long?
Well,
quake three was a quick four was 2000
something.
It was like 2005 or 2007,
so for the last five,
six on my number,
but they've taken the formula.
They even use the same engine on call of
duty when it first came out and they've
just improved it and proved it and
proved it and like a lot of these games
that like last week I was talking about
like keyboard and mouse necessarily is
better than controller argument.
My point is is that the games are better
now.
The games are better now.
They're not geared towards the accuracy
of a keyboard and mouse as much as they
are geared for just having a fun
experience.
Yeah,
there's a lot of auto wave going on.
It's just easier to.
People still do those driving games.
Yeah.
Yeah,
totally.
To me though,
the what,
what's fun to me about video games.
I understand all that,
but what's fun to me,
it's just I got addicted straight up to
one on one matches and even like the
death matches,
you know,
just the fact that you have this
incredibly precise control over the
eight year,
more like the pool statistic version of
video games.
I mean it's all just a very small
majority.
Yeah.
Most people like to play football games
and the control is perfect for that.
With quick games,
those one-on-one first person shooters.
It's just so precise.
It's so addictive.
Man.
When you were talking about,
was your cousin's addicted to know my
nephew,
man.
When I was a little kid,
if he hit me with some quake,
I would have lost my life.
I would have never got into martial
arts.
I would have never got productive with
my life.
I would have never paid attention in
school.
Joe.
There's a game on steam that you can
play on your mac that has nothing to do
with it,
but I want you to.
Next time you're bored and you just want
to spend it because it's a really short
game so you can't get addicted to it.
Like it's like literally you could beat
it in like six hours really,
but it's called portal and I think ours,
jesus,
I ain't got six hours like our kids.
No,
I mean,
but six hours spread up for like a
month.
But that's a,
that's an addiction.
You will that.
That game alone will set your mind
racing to wildland.
How crazy video games are nowadays.
So what is the best one right now?
If I wanted to get something for xbox
and something that just got blow my
fucking mind.
Here's a war for you.
I would probably go with more of like a
borderlands or something like that,
but I would actually find a game that
you could play on your mac.
You know,
like a game,
like call of duty that you can play.
I think he called dd four is on there
and there's a couple scenes from call of
duty for that will blow your fucking
mind.
You know red.
There's a red one,
red something cowboy one.
Don't get that shit.
That's just grand theft auto,
but using a horse and cowboy.
What's it called?
It's called red dead dawn or something
like that.
I gave it a chance,
but I was like,
all right,
this is grand theft auto.
I don't wanna play anymore.
That was a hugely successful game
though.
Super.
You know,
it's just people like that formula and
I'm sure it's bigger and better than
grand theft auto,
but for me I just played it and I'm
like,
I'm done with that.
I don't want to play that anymore.
I'm over that.
They say that ea martial arts game is a
bust.
Nobody's buying it.
Really haven't played the us.
Do you have like a good one?
Cool.
The new one that we're working on right
now,
who thinks it is?
What the fuck?
Pick up the phone.
Cock sucker.
That's not what happened.
Go back to that Alex Jones transcript.
Your calls.
Brian brian.
Callum must've just gotten to the tank,
but before we're going to do the
podcast,
he was about getting a tank for the
first time.
It was brian here.
No,
not here.
No.
At a place in venice.
The headquarters float lab.com.
So I think what we got today is that
eddie bravo loves ufos.
I love them.
And jujitsu.
Like bunnies and brian loves cats and
one hit of weed instead of three.
You got to hard today.
No,
no,
I'm just saying tHat I liked my high
high today.
One hit that.
I think that's all I need.
No more than two and two if they're
going to be too.
It's too light.
Ones your shit.
Fucking fuck me up this week.
and by the way,
like he,
like we smoked before we went on stage,
actually smashed.
Talk about that.
We smoked and then joey diaz told me
five minutes later going,
oh well I might put you up on stage and
I'm like,
what?
I'm going up.
Sold out joe rogan show.
No,
it.
Uh,
so I was completely baked out of my mind
the first couple of days,
but we dId this weekend.
It was different was we took str on the
road.
Who's little esther was brian's friend
who's a,
um,
an emerging standup comedian in la.
And she's only 22 years old,
he's only been doing comedy like two
years and we just said,
well,
let's just fucking just for an
experiment,
see what it's like to take this kid and
throw her up in front of a real crowd.
Like she did.
Great.
Yeah.
[inaudible] dot com.
Dude.
She's fucking good man.
She's confident and smooth.
And for someone who's only been doing
comedy for two years,
she's way better than I was two years
into it.
And I told her that when I was two years
into it,
I was a mess.
I was a clunky fucking goofy mass.
Is it okay that she's had she known for
looking really young?
YeaH,
that's her characters.
She looks like she's 12.
Seriously.
What's her name?
Esther.
Little test or little esther.
Her feet seriously are smaller than my
hands,
but smelled like they're twice as big.
Well,
just kidding.
Get the fuck man.
She's thrown under the bus.
She's,
she's funny man.
She was furious.
She did a good job.
And you did a good job too,
man.
It was interesting watching you loosen
up from the first set you did on
thursday night to the last set you did
on saturday night,
which was your best one,
right?
You slow to admit to your jetta.
That second set.
Saturday I acted like I smoked marijuana
before I went onstage before I went on
stage,
the second chat.
Remember before we all,
we all didn't really smoke out because I
was like,
no,
do it,
do it.
And I'm like,
no,
I don't want.
So the data show that you had,
was the one where you weren't high,
you went high at all?
No,
it must've been a little high from the
first time,
but that was like,
it had leveled off because you were
nervous.
Weed isn't that great when You're
nervous man.
And he realized that that you were
probably,
you hide got paranoid and I was getting
high like and then going on stage like
five minutes later.
That's not a good mix for me,
adam.
It's not good mixture of the podcast
either before we've done that.
Many times we get high right before we
do the podcasts,
like today,
first words out of my mouth while I
crawls and they don't come out that
good.
Right.
But like right now or two hours in,
it's all smooth and once you're killing
and you're really confident you can't
wait to go on state.
Then the weed will take it through the
roof.
Yeah.
But even then you gotta make sure you
don't get too hard.
I think red bull and vodka,
what are one or two of them before on
stage is the key ingredient for standup
comedy?
One or two red bull's and vodka.
Red bull vodka.
I like a little bit of weed.
Some calisthenics.
My best teaching always comes from me
being high when I teach because I'm so
confident with it that it adds to it.
Like I'll be pissed off.
Like if I forget,
if I forget,
like I forgot.
I don't have lead right now and I didn't
teach class today stoned this morning.
I didn't teach guide.
I felt pretty good.
I mean if it was a good class,
but I always feel like when I'm high
it's just like I don't want a class to
end.
I want her to keep going.
I want more time.
When I'm in that space,
in that zone,
like shit,
I'm running out of time.
There's so much I've got to say and show
when we don't show.
We got high in the car right before we
went in there.
We want like three.
Here's Alex Jones show would be cool.
High though.
Well,
it's bewildering though because when we
walked in,
no,
I walked in.
Joe there about two d a devalue the
dollar.
They're going to take the dollar way.
It's been proven to your forbes there.
Their ex rang your home.
They're driving by and vans and they're
taking photos.
You irradiating your house with deadly
radiation that can give cancer.
He's poor people,
so it's like you go from right out of
the car.
Everybody's laughing.
We're talking shit.
We're breaking down country music.
There was like some ridiculous country
music song,
you know,
below only girls make the best lovers.
We were laughing our asses off and then
you go right in their death,
destruction,
new world order.
He leads global warming.
What was he saying about the radiation
and is a crazy fucking real thing
they're doing where they're driving
through neighborhoods and they're
blasting these cars with these super
powerful x rays from these vans and
they're looking inside of vehicles.
They have photos of the show was in
forbes magazine.
He pulls up the story and shows it to me
and they're doing it to houses too.
They Just drive by and point this
fucking crazy x ray gun at cars and see
right through and they show all these
photos of people looking at like bricks
of cocaine.
The back of a van like this is nuts,
man.
Like they,
they can,
they can shoot x-rays.
It just makes me,
it just makes me really wonder though
how like people go on and the radiation,
like what exactly how strong it is
because the other day I was talking to
my dentist and he said like,
you know,
uh,
this radiation is about equal to
standing next to a microwave.
That's what he said.
Yeah.
Something like that.
I forgot.
I don't know what to where a lead vest
when you microwaves or popcorn.
I don't know.
I don't know what that's for,
but that he said it's not that big a
deal.
that's why he's not wearing the lead
vest,
you know?
And well the crazy thing is that there's
radiation around us all the time.
Make yourself space microWaving your
brain every time you put up.
No one knows what's happening with
those.
Right?
Yeah.
So what happens though when you're in
your car though,
and you got a hands free,
is that okay?
Well,
not when you have your phone between
your crotch when you're tryIng to cook.
And it was a study released recently
that.
So that laptops cook your balls.
Oh yeah.
Cook your sperm.
That's,
that's totally makes sperm and
effective.
If you have your laptop on your lap.
Yeah.
You cook in your balls but not up there.
No,
no,
no.
He did.
He cook shit balls.
I never put my laptop on my lap.
Yeah,
I got this thing for that very reason.
So I got this little pad that sits on
the laptop.
It makes them more comfortable anyway
because the bottom is soft,
so it sort of molds to your legs and
with that note you got that italian
song.
No,
it wasn't.
It says find youtube user does not
allow mobile views or something like
that.
So sorry.
Is this.
It would have been the perfect ending.
What is this?
Your plan?
Fatboy slim again,
another fatboy slim,
but at the same thing,
it's like,
it sounds like you love him.
It's like a two hour.
If you go to his website,
it's called fatboy slim summer mix and
it's just a free download.
It's like a.
I think you'd love him.
Like eddie loves.
You have photos?
I think I do too.
Not that much.
All right,
ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for tuning into the podcast
next week.
We're in ann arbor,
Michigan.
It's me and tommy sigora at the ann
arbor comedy showcase.
Um,
you're going to have to find where that
shit is.
I don't know where it is.
It's like an hour from detroit,
but we're doing two shows.
One eight and 10:30.
It's on my twitter.
It's on Joe rogan.net.
um,
thank you to the flashlight for
sponsoring this podcast.
As always,
you can go to joe rogan.net
and enter into the code,
I believe is rogan,
right?
Yep.
Rogan and get 15 percent off.
So fuck that shit yo ass thing ever.
Eddie bravo.
Thank you very much for coming on.
as always my friend and people want to
reach you.
10th planet.
J.
J.com.
That's it.
And on twitter It's at eddie bravo.
And of course brian red band at red
band.
If you want to tell a little esther that
you were in austin,
Texas and you thought she was awesome
and you were so proud of her.
She's a little esther.
Listen to her on adam carolla tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Oh,
okay.
When was that?
Uh,
I don't know,
just blowing the fuck up.
The kids blowing up.
She's on adam carolla.
We had her here first.
Bitch.
She,
we took her on the road.
yeah,
she's,
she's talented.
Something's going to happen.
Joey diaz is mad flavor on twitter and a
thank you very month everybody.
And um,
that's it.
We'll see you next week.
Love you budget.
See ya later.