Yeah. What's up everybody? This is a,
today is the 18th. 19th, what is
it, the 20th? 20th of September,
20 years now. It's really the 19th
for everybody that's paying attention.
It says September 20th, but
it's really Friday night,
Friday night at midnight. Um,
and uh, this is a lie. Five Pat,
uh, fight companion podcast.
Brian Count's supposed to be here,
but of course he's fucking late.
Brendan Chavs here
on the House and of course my
brother Edge Bra is here. Oh Shit.
And he bravo in the house and uh,
we're,
we're just looking at the
blank screen right now.
Why Mark Hunt is a gonna face.
Roy Big motherfucking country
Nelson tonight. Whole Shit. Yeah,
we get some of that in that too.
Um,
we might not be able to smoke weed
with Brendan Schaub in the room though.
I'll just hold my breath.
December six. Hmm. What's today?
We had some time about 13 weeks.
I'll just hold my breath.
Can you do that?
Are you good at holding your breath?
I know you have awesome cardio to fish.
We're good.
I'll just suck on this coffee real quick.
Usually go to bed at 11 sip tea,
usually in bed by 11 sipping
team guys, are you really? Yeah.
11:00 PM Evan every night. Wow.
Are you training tomorrow? No,
I trained twice today cause I knew
tonight's gonna be a doozy. When you, uh,
when you schedule like your,
when you ramp up for a fight.
So you're fighting December,
December, December,
December 6th when you're racing on h
one. Oh Shit. Where's that beast? Vegas.
Mandalay bay. Ooh. Two title fights
then my fight and Travis Browne.
Ooh,
that's um,
Vitorin Weidman to showtime and Melendez.
Oh Shit.
And then us big one. Good Lord. Uh,
not yet.
Not that I know of.
I don't want you to go seize
unless there's a chick flight.
And I hear you speak in a chick.
The one tonight is telling you guys she's
a little monster that you got an issue
with her. I do. So filter thinking
a little crush on her. Yeah,
she's Kinda hot. She was a little plump
and she got in some serious shit. Yeah.
Right. And it has down
like, she's like curvy.
She's like Kim Kardashian, but
Japanese. Yeah. Come on in.
How cool would it be if she came out
and, uh, the school girl uniforms,
they used to do that for pride.
He used to come out with pigtails.
Weird stay one dude.
It's the national pastime
is to be into school girls.
How weird is her biggest thing that she's
ever done? She dressed up like a bunny.
Ooh. I know this, I don't know
dirty, but maybe I did some research
and by research I mean maybe I jacked off.
Um,
we'll let you know as soon as the
fight start. I don't know why. Uh,
the fights are a little bit late.
It says 1205 on my phone.
Amateur hour smells like weed in here.
Says 1205 on my phone.
I don't know if that means I'm somebody
fucked up or they're having a problem.
There they were, we were watching it
earlier though. It doesn't make any sense.
It was the live from Japan Goldberg and,
uh,
Brian Stan calling the APP
action. Maybe it's just a delay
for the main card, by the way.
I fucking love fight pass dates.
Awesome.
If fucking love it tweeted that fight
pass is great. And everybody was like,
you fucking chill. I know. It's great.
Any fight you could think of in the UFC,
you could just watch it
and it works. It, it's crazy.
When I cornered Ben Saunders at,
at the Tulsa event, I get there Friday
night, I've never worked with Ben before.
He asked me to corner him like
a week before and he goes, dude,
you want to come down?
And uh,
he had been playing rubber guard off and
on over the years and he was playing a
different version. He was playing
a version I never played. And uh,
then he kind of moved away from it because
I figured, I figured that it would,
he hit hit,
hit a dead end with that style,
but I didn't want to say anything
cause it was kind of working for him.
And then he got cut from the UFC,
went to bell inventoried when,
when somebody lose some and I kind of
lost track of what he was really doing.
And then he saw the Hixson video, the
video that we did here. And, uh, he,
he, he twittered me direct
message was, hey man,
when are you going to
do a seminar in Florida?
He realized he was playing stuff wrong
and he wanted to fix it. So I said, well,
I don't have anything planned in Florida,
but I do have a little rubber guard
genius out there. Guy Named Tyler Woolsey.
I go, let me hook you up with them.
They hooked up. He, as soon as he,
as soon as he got done
with Tyler, he said, dude,
I want you to corner me next week. Can you
do it? I know it's last minute. And um,
did it.
And so Friday night I get that Friday
night and go right to his hotel.
He has fight pass hooked up. Right.
So cause he was studying his opponent,
his opponent, and I think,
hmm. It wasn't on, he wasn't,
I don't think he fought in the UFC before,
but he had bypass. So I said, Oh shit.
So we put on, I wanted to keep it really
simple form would rubber guard. There's,
it's so sophisticated and so vast.
There's pieces of the rubber guard
that I don't even know how to play yet.
There's new pieces. I'm like, Shit, what
are you guys doing over here? Right?
There's a new shit that's incredible.
Half Guillotine a guillotine
from the rubber guard.
Guillotine with your leg
on. Hold on a second. It's on. The
fights are on guys walking out. Right?
And what is this? I don't
know what you got here. Oh,
is it a different thing? My on the wrong
thing. That doesn't make any sense.
Live events. Let's see. Yeah,
you gotta press live live now.
That'll be it. So it didn't
switch over from the pre. Oh,
it didn't switch over from the prelims.
That's goofy.
That's goofy. Tell you what a different
stream is. Coffee, bulletproof coffee,
French jobs got a little bit of a
fucking coffee problem. Addiction.
And when I stopped siding, it's
going to become drugs. Well,
my point was with the UFC fight pass is
I get there Friday night and we kept it
really simple, simple rubber guard,
Michigan troll with elbows. We,
we put on Jason Day versus Alan
Belcher. Uh, that was a real,
an amazing display of elbows from,
from the guard and Matt Horwitz versus
Dan Miller. You know, just right there.
We would've, it would've been hard
to find those fights, you know,
I guess you could go to MMA core.
It's always tricky though, right?
You're like tough to find that. Yeah.
Yeah. But with UFC fight pass man, boom.
Any UFC fight,
is it every single fight that the UFC
has ever single fight the UFC has had and
every single one.
Another one of those too.
There's everything yesterday
on the phone too. Yeah. Um,
every single fight in pride to even the
early ones, like u of c to everything.
Everything. Everything. Wow.
All the Strikeforce fight.
Cause that's one thing that I can think
of came up. But I'm like thinking maybe,
maybe the,
the old ones,
maybe UFC one even there's offered
he sure if I'm wrong I apologize.
But I'm pretty sure in between,
in between these fights, that's,
let's throw it on my glass so we can,
we can,
otherwise we'll go off the screen because
it's running through my laptop, but,
but we'll figure it out.
I don't,
I don't think there's
anything that's not in there.
I mean there's also a crazy show called
UFC now with a couple of cutie pies on
their Kapow, Brendan Schaub and
Kenny Florian. Damn show relevance,
Horny and Shit. Man, man,
himself and his girl,
he's talking about himself
being acute. It was true. Oh,
you don't even paying attention.
He said Brandon Shab couple
cutie pies like Brennan and shop.
You got to talked to in the
third person. I'm, I'm sorry,
I was just really paying attention to
you. She's, I'm used to that with Callan.
Don't worry. Just keep on keeping
on towns the worst with that.
Like he'll get into
modes where he wants to,
he wants to say something and it doesn't
matter what the fuck you're saying.
What he has to say. Like it has no
relation whatsoever to what you're saying.
Oh Wow. That's great. I met
a guy, he wrote a book and
I'll go on to this fucking,
why are you talking about economics now?
Like how do we get an economic,
he's like, he has this thought in
his head. It's like a runaway train.
He's just trying to get out of the way,
man.
That's why he's so funny too.
It's like what's his face you
recognize about comedians?
It's like that same thing that makes
them like really funny. It's this,
this mad dog bum rush to
get attention. Madness, man.
Nobody's better at like commanding
attention and count. Brian called me.
He was dead serious. He goes,
Bro, instead of selling t shirts,
I got a great idea. He's never came
to me with an idea for shit. He goes,
good coozies we should sell to God. I
went, are you fucking kidding me? Disease?
Yes. Who Buys Beer?
Koozies still put mean.
W how much of it is
just a little insulated?
I thought you meant jacuzzis
you going to kick
can out of the warehouse.
You would need to keep an inventory
fighter in the kitchen that's not there.
That makes, that makes more sense
than a Koozie. But first for a second,
I'm like, they get, damn, they're
jumping on Brian. Poor Brian.
But then you said his
idea. I'm like, oh no shit.
[inaudible] trying to sell Jacuzzi.
What Natalie that I mean who? Well, it's
got room for a Jacuzzi. Kai,
Kai Yohji. Horry Gucci. I don't,
I'm not familiar with him.
Who's his opponent? Do we know?
We've got to pay attention here.
I got a bad ass because I've used it once.
Seriously, three years once. Let's see
who these guys are there to fight in here.
Powerful Aryana in Japan. Oh,
la. And seen her in awhile.
I thought maybe she was taking
a break. She's well, she's busy.
She's got a TV show now. Really?
Yeah. She's on overhauling
shush. She's the host.
Oprah. Yeah. Spike. Right. That's
uh, that's bud show. Brian,
her Gucci and Delos Reyes.
That's bud show where they
take a card and they, they,
they completely redo it for like a
week. He doesn't get it. Yes it does.
Now that's back.
But what owns it again?
Or it's a producer over it again.
One of those things that was his show.
I don't know what happened. I, you know,
I'm just happy he's doing it to get, oh,
it's all over. It's all never know. Never
know the smart thing. Recovering. Yeah.
He's, he's on the bottom.
You don't recover from that.
You can't let this though like
this though. He can. You can.
If the guy stays on him. See if the
guy was smart and he's a striker.
If he's that good of a striker, he would
probably try to get away, right? Yes.
100% because that guy would be much
more helpless in a non clinching.
The rubbish from the standup to Leo
Machida told me that you get hit to the
body, drop to your butt and to buy
time until the ref Stan job. Well,
Tito did that with him. Remember
he, he caught Tito. What?
That body shot that need of the body.
That's pulling guard though.
It was a slick move by. That's
pulling guard. He's being sued.
You're going to get finished. He's
peeing. Eddie Brown was being sarcastic.
He's a master mastercard player and 90%
I think 90% of the people won't catch
it. I'm just telling you right
now, I know that Eddie Bravo humor,
you've got to stand up. He's, you
know, he ended up to him it's like,
it's like chess moves that
are like really stupid.
You see someone doing a dumb
chess move and you and I are like,
what is he talking about?
Well,
other other people you know who know
Eddie and know exactly what he's doing.
He's, he's always said that. I mean we're
seeing it. We saw it with your arms.
You got to pull guard. We saw
at times you got it. You don't,
it shouldn't be our first option,
but it should be.
Look how, look how good Ben Saunders
control was. It was amazing.
If I'm for doom and Keynes,
eat me up against the cage,
I'm pulling half cars sometimes.
Sometimes you have God. Meanwhile,
this is a good fucking fight.
Yeah, it is really good fight.
He recovered. He got out of it
man. But that a hard gootchie dude,
that guy's got a nasty
left kick to the body. Oh,
he's trying to pay him back for oh
he did too. He did two or these guys,
45 hours. Um, they look on no fibers.
See I was going to say 35, 25 no, no.
I wait. Oh my God. Giant. No Way.
Well, you know these hoes shit.
No one is really a
fucking fly with anymore.
They're all like 150 pounds
and then fly away for an hour.
I mean that's what's going on now
with all these weight classes. Dude,
you know I have dolce on,
Jesus don't,
she was telling me that nick lense walks
around it like a buck 70 a buck 75 and
he gets down to one 45 and
he was struggling to get
down to 55 before he came to
dolce. Either way, there's
going to be diminishing return.
You know what I'm saying?
Like I don't care what dolce says and
I love dolce as much as the nice guy,
but no matter what you say, that can't
be healthy. I'll tell you what though,
be that big. No, no, but there's,
there's healthier ways to good generally
the healthier ways, but it's still kit.
There's no way performance. He says,
well, he says it. I think you're right.
The Way Nick Lens cuts though.
He was saying yes,
he walks around to one 75 or whatever,
but,
and he does get to 45 but he
does it. Oh, he heard him again.
Oh Jesus.
He's boys a scrap and these guys are,
oh, heart. Gucci is a bad
motherfucker. Eat soon. Jesus Christ.
Nasty striking. But he dos Rios
got some gummies back again. Oh,
but he's getting eaten up. Oh, these
are hard shots. Oh, he's in trouble now.
He's might be that. I usually stop.
That's it. That's it. He's a bad man.
Shit. The kids here, the kid is teas.
Is that a bottle of wine? You
savage? Of course he did. Yeah,
he would bring wine camping. If you let a
kid, he'd be that guy on a hunting trip.
Brian, I'm on your side today.
Okay. I'm not going to gang up on
me and you kid against these guys have
to worry about my feelings by before he
came in. I feel a count sacrifice. You
guys came down to me a little hard.
You didn't believe my nose story.
I mean it was very bad.
40 came in and he goes,
we should sell koozies which
sell pcs. I was like, Nah,
I don't think so man.
As Brian and Eddie Bravo was thinking you
should probably sell like some sort of
hot tub type equipment.
Maybe Jacuzzi.
The equipment just missed this part.
Gucci's a bad motherfucker,
dude. These are slight weights.
Can you believe these are one 20
fibers perspective issue? Yeah,
apparently it is. They might
be the four foot five. No. Um,
there is this, the height is up there.
Crazy. It's on the, the thing one guy,
65 inches.
You have to go 66 and I have a new
boyfriend so it doesn't really matter. Oh,
Brian Loves Akiyama. It's
importance without beautiful
man. He's a beautiful man.
He's a, he's a well, but he
always sings voice of an angel.
I know he saves our superstar.
Correct. Like Korea, right?
Auditorium, Japanese. He's got an
amazing voice. Well, he's a Japanese guy,
but he's of Korean descent,
right? I believe so. Set from him,
I believe is a Japanese name.
Yeah. I think for some reason,
and he's got some sort of a
Korean background, I'd look,
but my teeth with my, uh,
Jamie, can you, he's actually Korean
and Jamie, do you have any one?
He's half Korean, half Japanese. No
wineglasses dude. This is a man's place.
He's a good coffee mug.
You use a goddamn coffee mug.
You don't need a special glass for
your fucking fruity drink. Brian.
Brian figure Brian style cause enormous.
He looks like Godzilla
compared to that dude. Oh,
so that's why it's a perspective issue.
I'm with you.
As I said, that guy is a bad
motherfucker. Super Bad. Wicked striking.
There is no room for anybody but bad
motherfuckers at one 25 every a black belt
and everything, everything. And in
a black belt in cardio 70 and below,
you better be a black belt at every
job. Oh, you won't be here that small.
Especially in wrestling
and Jujitsu technique.
You have to be so technical to just
survive in the sport. Bang home.
Yeah, in everything. Right.
Everything in everything. I like.
I actually like watching
the lighter weights. Dude.
When you got a guy like a
Hector Lombard out there,
what terrified of that guy
who's not terrified to him?
To Hector Lombard is terrified of himself.
That's how scary Hector Lombard is.
Dude.
I'm never saw anybody
ragdoll Jake shields,
the way he did tossed around just smashed
him in the first round like a fucking
hurricane. Like refrigerators were flying
down the street and Kansas tornadoes.
It was just, Jake shields is tough
as fuck. He's beaten some chicks,
feels almost caught him.
He almost caught him and he gets him.
He got locked up in the bell, rang the
fucking Buzzer rang with Jake on his neck.
When you look at Hector Lombard,
he can't believe he gets down to one 76
he's got the street from a nice ass on
the planet. Yo Brian Cowen. Russell. Why
Bob? I'm sorry man. I'm so sorry. Hold on.
Fuck Buddy. Hold. Get a
little 2005 book Hojo, Yo.
And you're actually knowing
what that would it is 2005 book.
Did you like buy it on purpose?
Like you knew what it was when you went
out to buy it. How did you find out?
You'll say taste it and you tell
me. No, I believe it's good.
I'm not questioning when you know. How
do you, what do you know about one?
Because I like old world wines.
What's that mean?
The Europeans like earth in their wine.
You taste that earth. You say that.
It's like, it's like cheese. Meat.
Mushrooms are good. Yeah. I don't taste
any of those things.
I taste wine.
Callup fucking people married the
American palate likes an obvious Jamey big
wine for the most part. Bronco with
the old world wines. Listen Gentlemen,
serious question.
Who?
Who has the best acid MMA but without
question 100% and do a lot of dead lifts.
Watch health watch
question without question.
Why don't you a couple of honeydews
couple of honey dews with common stressful
for us. Without question. Hector lumbar.
I couldn't peel my eyes from the man.
He was in the air in the airport and he
was quite the security and he took his
shoes off and I could not feel
my eyes from his ass. You know,
there's a few guys like
that in the UFC didn't move.
They move it like a notch over.
Everybody Woodley.
Tyron Woodley when Woodley's on correct.
When he knocked out Jay,
her Ron just expose the movement.
It's like get out of the way.
Just get the fuck out of the way.
When he's got this rush,
you certain guys that have this rush
and Lombard has it too. You know?
They asked Woodley to fight Lombard
and he's like, Nah, I'm cool.
And it's showed up. By the way, Dana
said he was like, Dana was like, no.
He literally was like,
no, I'm good. I say,
same thing too, right? Find non cool man
necessary the baddest dude on the
planet. No, I'm cool. I'm good.
I'm going to go crazy. Is it that Dana
will bus these guys out like that? Well,
hey mean that's for his business. That's
the best move. But it's not even like,
you know all the guys
were like, oh no, hell no.
It's like they won't even consider it.
Well, no, no, no. Is that 100% true?
What are it's, here's the
thing, what are you selling?
If you're selling a product like the UFC,
I could see two arguments.
I can see one argument where you're like,
you shouldn't talk about that.
Cause that's private. That's the
fighter's business fighters fight.
But you're selling the
baddest motherfuckers on the
planet and the the push is
always like the tank Abbott.
Anyone anywhere. Anytime.
It's one thing everybody loved about
tank habit was the fact that he fight
anybody off a bar stool to Tj Dillashaw
cowboy Cerrone's exactly like it's a
double edged sword though. It's a
double edge sword Franklin about that.
Oh well it's most likely.
Depends upon your success.
I mean ask anybody UFC about the benefit.
Finish your point.
What were you saying about Joe?
You were saying you went,
you were talking about in the planet,
but him,
him saying if someone turned down a fight,
right.
It's like now you will believe him when
he says this guy will take any fight.
I'll tell you know I could call them
up anytime. Like Donald Cerrone, he,
he'll say that about ceremony. I can
call Donald Serone up and say, Hey,
I'm sending a fight with fill in the
blank. He goes, all right, let's do it.
He probably has a Budweiser in his,
he probably fishes the Budweiser,
then goes jet skiing.
Then probably fucking shoot some guns.
What were you saying about age?
What were you saying about [inaudible]
j Dilla shot. Well, he's another one.
He'll fight anybody. Tj fought, I mean
they changed it. His fight to Joe Soto
the fucking day of the Wayans,
the day of the weigh ins.
Burrell can't make weight.
Falls hits his head.
Joe Soto who had won
the belt toward title,
lost it to Joe Warren got signed by the
UFC one, a bunch of fights in a row.
Good fights came to the UFC.
He's fucking debut his UFC debut.
He fights for the title against Tj
Dillashaw. Dillashaw. I was like,
I'll take it that. That's
a little different. I think
that's a little different.
It was day of the fight. He's in shape.
He's in camp looking for a fight.
That guy steps up.
That guy's kind of screwed.
It's a different kind of animal to
call some like Yo Hector Lombard,
you've got eight weeks.
Like cool.
That's a different animals fighters
out there that get off on fighting the
scariest guys. Oh yeah,
for sure. Who's like that?
Like they want the next, he has Mark Hunt,
Mark Kahn. He wants the scariest guys.
Yeah. Like literally like when me and
him are going back and forth on Twitter,
the stuff you'd say to me and like me,
I was like, damn, this false for real.
It's like
he just wants to help my ass.
I'm trying to get paid
and get a title shot. Joe,
he just wants you to whip my ass. By
the way, this guy kind of McGregor.
It seems like the kind of guy I'll take
all comers. So is Dustin Poirier a man,
Dustin Poirier. He's a bad motherfucker.
That's a significant test from a Gregor.
I figured Gregor's sensational. I even
Gregerson say I'm a huge McGregor fan.
Boxing is phenomenal. Well,
his movement, he just,
he's like a snake like his in and out,
but I'm telling you we haven't
scoring Yay is fucking legit. I agree.
I can see him winning. He Eric
Coke. I was like, Oh shit. Yeah,
that's a coin toss. You and anybody
could land a big shot and change.
Really good fight though.
Those guys are both really technical
and and Mcgregor is very unorthodox man.
He fights from a south position. He
moves like a snake. He's trained for.
He's got this in and out style.
That's very deceptive man. It's not,
there's a lot of dudes and you see them
throwing punches and throwing kicks,
but they're very mechanical, right?
Step forward and they just throw a,
get a rhythm.
But Mcgregor's got like this wiggle,
he's got this wobble in and out.
He can,
he can counter off Google almost Anderson
Silva guys into these things and then
counters heal, heal, heal. Did
doc come back with a right?
He's just really good box jack slacks.
It did a great slip. He slipped.
The guy wasn't in the UFC. He's just
does stuff that you don't usually see.
Don't think he's ready for a,
for like a a top top level guy.
I want to see him get built up.
Dustin Poirier is going gonna be,
it's a hell of a big test look.
Poor.
Yay is no fucking job shit.
And the kid has been fighting
for a long time and he's not.
And he's young and he's not scared
of it. And it got, yeah, it's true.
And a guy like poor Yay is a guy that
you could see a giant jump from him and
just four or five months because he's in
his confidence groove now. He beat coke.
You know y'all, you know he's, he's at
the stage where he's like, he knew coke
was about the fight for the title.
Yup.
When the fight got
called because of injury,
coke is like set to fight
for the title piece. Yeah.
He was ready to fight for the title.
So poor ea beats him.
It beats him convincingly. I mean, that's
a big fucking wind, man. He's a beast.
You know how we're talking about guys
who take whatever fight. Just go. Yep.
Give it to us.
There's a fine line in this where
management comes into place because the
fighter should always accept the
fight. Always a five. She always right.
Always accepted by Ivo. Anytime I man,
let your manager saying, Yep, let's do it.
It should be a manager's job. Like, ah,
probably not homeboy like manager being
the guys who is his ego is presumably
not attached to any bullshit.
A true fighters who like, yeah,
I can beat anyone in the world came to me.
But when you're dealing with at,
say you have a client at
one 70 and they go, hey,
we want to fight Hector
Lombard in Australia where
he lives once you fly down to
the 20 hours to get that
ass, well you gotta fake.
It ain't going to,
a manager's going to be like,
I don't hold out a little bit. Yeah.
And there's, there's, I mean you've,
I'm sure experienced it yourself.
The difference between you now
and you when you're on tough,
if you could go back and fight
you when you're on tough,
you'd probably beat your ass.
Oh my God. I've last 20 seconds.
I was such a bad ass.
I was, I was so shitty.
Just super competent.
Just crazy confidence.
What do you think of the APP with the
girls? Just two episodes. Yeah, I did.
You know, I fucking love it. Do you
write? It's really good. It's good
that rose, that rose. So I trained with
her endeavor when she very first started.
She's your next showtime Pettis.
She can jump off the wall.
She can do flying armbars
she's a little pieces there.
You seen her flying arm bar finish.
You've seen his flight.
She is going home after this
chick. Have you seen it? No.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. She's a,
she's going after this chick. I
mean, they're going to war and roses.
Chase her down with combinations.
The grow clinches up with her.
Rose throws out fucking perfect flying
armbar and tasks or she's your next
superstar. If she does well on this
show, she's going to be your next,
her a grinding grappling on the
ground and position. I don't know.
That's the only thing. She's more
fancy. You know what I'm saying?
I know what you're saying.
I had sex with someone might be
able to take her wrestler. Yeah,
you might be right. You might
be right. But God, I very flashy
that fucking reply she's doing flying
armbars that she's gotta be at least a
pretty good blue belts the way she did it.
You got to see the way she did it.
She did it like a goddamn black
belt. It was like, you know,
sometimes there's those people that like
they have one crazy move and they're
like, oh, do a shrimp from me.
Right. What the fuck? That's true.
They came in shrimp [inaudible] bar.
It's cause they came to the gym and the
first day they came in they showed him a
flying triangle, a flying arm. But
that, but they can't do anything else.
The first fight, uh, that a huge
other areas. There it is right here.
Do you remember when,
uh,
paid a pano fought Vinnie Magallanes and
Vinny magalogs caught him walking shit.
Full flying trend data.
How wicked was that? Uh,
she's at that pictures while to look at
her. She's, she's, she has the rice. Why?
If you watch that again,
that if you watch it again,
look at these. He's not a
breath look. And he said,
don't think so. No, no,
no, no, no. Let's see.
Her legs are in a very bad
spot as far as an armbar.
Let's see. Look at her legs.
Look at this. Boom. Left leg.
Look at her and left leg
between the two arms. No.
Her left leg is between the girl's legs.
Well,
when at the end of it wasn't though,
right? Yeah. Let me see. I see it again,
but at the end she looked
at her arms in her left leg.
Look at her left. Boom. Left
leg left or you're right.
It's your trash leg
about
Jan Galera. That was glaring. Yeah,
that's true. I don't see it. Well,
every day I'm analyzing every
book like I'm an analyze mode.
The whole time I'm just looking
at everyone's techniques.
I can't help it every time. I'm
just correcting. That's so true.
If she got into the situation,
you think she should have tried to finish
it before she got her leg free or if
she felt strong,
should she had gone for it the way she
did because she was obviously tangled up
like that wouldn't immediately in trouble
was going on in your mind like maybe
she thought, I know my legs
in a bad spot, but she's not.
She's just leaving her leg hanging
so I'm just going to keep it there.
I don't know.
She must be pretty confident in that
girl's right leg was just like dangling
over. She was amazing
it to defend, but damn.
How quick did she hit that fucking flying
armbar man, that shit was beautiful.
She is the attitude to be a champion.
I'll put this down.
Wild man and that whole wild dance.
She did have the chef.
She's definitely the hottest one. That's
uh, that's, that's important too. It's a
legit, she's and she's a trashy. She's
with Jet Star and she is here by the way.
She is beautiful.
Her face is Angelina Jolie.
Yup. She's a cutie pie.
She's a straight a cutie pie. So
be respectful. Good work. Yeah,
he did well.
Okay.
So we got kind mono versus Richard Bro.
Thanks for the invite to dinner Brian.
Hey guys. There's fights going on right?
And I know fucking selfish
bitch. All right. Kiki Coonan,
Modo and Richard Walsh.
Companion to life ex friend Lou,
my brother.
Unbelievable catching the bad
positioning and the legs. Right.
I didn't see it because I'm with my
family. Nice. Fix that rose. Fix it. Pat.
Pat,
come on.
Oh, Cuna. Modo. Pat for sure.
Teacher that flying arm bar. Everybody
goes to the deep half now Eddie. Huh?
Keep your hands up wrong.
I miss that.
A lot of guys go to the deep half on
the ground now don't they? In and out.
You got to go in and out. You don't
have time to play around. Boy.
It's not crane set, right? The deep, deep
half. You just got to just go with it,
right? Yeah. Boom. Boom. Slingshot bro.
Everyone's growing their beard out though.
Huh? Sexy and I care. I can't do it.
Very lumberjack like you can't a beard.
I can't do it. You smooth. I'm Travis
Brown got me beat in that area.
So when you grow a beard,
does it just look like a homeless
Banjo player type beard? Yeah,
I look like like Venice,
Venice
Bullshit. Giant got cracked. Big Kick.
Oh look at that
wall.
She's a beached strong striker.
He looks like Kit Dale. He does.
My motto is in Japan, he
cannot lose coattails.
Got a funny Instagram page. Oh Coonan Mona
is busted up, man. Somebody busted up.
It's a lot of blood and it
looks like his nose though.
Oh, nice knee to the body. Yeah.
That is like a standard like masculine
look now the big crazy beard,
everyone's kind of doing it.
I know everyone's kind of doing it.
It didn't exist just a few
years ago. Well, it's weird.
It's kind of like the tramp stamp exist
in the 70s it's all cyclical styles come
and go.
Okay,
well you give it a lecture.
Is that why does some trends and like why
do people, our sons are growing beards.
Wah Bell Bottoms. That happened. What
is it? How do, how does it trend?
Do me jeans,
skinny jeans now you got big guys means
it's so interesting how I think it's a
culture.
It's something happens in a culture and
it manifests seven how people just pop
in pop culture. They see celebrities
doing it. Then they jump on. And Brendan,
are you using the diamond club?
What do you use to diamond?
Yeah. Diamond Cup. Yeah.
Only the best for this hot. Have you,
I hear you brother. Have you ever uh,
fucked around with a tie
steel cup? I have. Yeah.
Once it gets more in the way of things,
especially grappling.
Have you grappled in a lot?
Well, that's what I was to know.
I have never grappled in a tie steel cup,
but I would imagine that first of all,
you know I rolled with you remember
Amir Amir? A mirror? No, the other,
I've already near Renovar bed.
I rolled the mere renova
already at legends and he
used to roll with a tie steel
cup on and he would mount. You had used
it as a weapon. It was really rude.
Dance with it too. Strong guy.
Anyway, he's a strong guy. Crazy.
That is so crazy that
the IB,
Jj have outlawed cups.
You're not allowed to protect
your balls because of their,
so it cups are so dangerous. I agree
with it. I agree. We are not alone.
I agree, but I think like a s a cup
that doesn't hurt like a diamond cup.
I got softer Plastic Cup
I think should happen.
This should be a foam one, but you know
what I mean, Tim. I broke my balls once.
I had Blake Dick Bleeding once.
You know I only,
I only wear a cup when I'm fighting.
I'm only where a cup when I'm fighting.
I never wore a cup in football
all the years. Really. Only
when I fight I work up.
Cause it cause you might
get kicked in the balls. No.
Oh well you have to wear it in the UFC.
I was saying we are one if I didn't
have to one of the military because why?
Because there's liability lost a ball.
One of the military guys got it.
Forget his name and in training and it
was one of those things where you're like
ah, I don't need a cup.
We'll just go, go live.
And you sent me, you got you hooked.
Got me hooked up with the Diamond Cup.
Since you told me the story,
I still don't give a shit.
What's the difference Armstrong did with
one between a regular dog watcher has
one nut. Remember that if you, if
you think about like Lance Armstrong,
man, first of all, Lance Armstrong,
like you could never do what lands storm
was Armstrong was dude in the UFC cause
you'd get caught,
you'd get caught simply
because he's taken a lot of drugs.
I think that maybe him taking them out
of drugs was one of the reasons why.
And one minute, one minute, I'm the
same being some chemicals were involved.
I The fucking science experiment, man.
He was a fucking science experiment.
What everyone was though. Let's be
honest. Everyone says you're 100% right.
She'll sign it, said it best. You know
Chell son was talking to, he would know.
He's like, look, the guy was the best
cheater. He goes, that's what he was.
He was the best cheat here.
He probably gets some genetic data
with baseball too. They're like,
oh these guys steroids. Woah. The
pictures on steroids too, man.
I hate to tell you at the level
level playing field, oh it's over.
We missed the ending. We're
talking all this shit. Oh,
you hooked him on the left Hook.
That guy is tannish Oh,
oh.
Ah, that's got to hurt.
Ugh. It's tough though.
If there's anything to suck at in MMA or
to not be as good or suck in comparison
to your opponent. The scary
thing is striking. God Damn.
That's why a guy like a lumbar is so
fucking terrifying because he does both.
He does both.
He ever see a video of him breaking that
dude's lag and grappling competition
here at snap.
You've seen it as Hector Lombard
part of his leg? I don't know.
It looked like an ankle lock,
so probably his ankle or down
by horrifying. The bottom of his leg.
I mean he just snapped this dude's leg.
You hear it? You hear the crack. I don't
remember what kind of leg lock it was,
but it was nasty. Did he hang under like
Paul Harvey Stone? It just snapped it.
It just,
the guy screamed and it was over.
He's a fucking freak dude. Okay.
This fight is not over, man.
That was just in between rounds. Jesus.
Wow. That guy is still in there. Who,
by the way,
who is fucking tougher like PR as I like,
uh,
if you had like a generalization
about a nation for tea,
like guys who can take it. I know,
which, I know these guys can't fucking,
I actually know that
they've actually gone through the hardest.
So they've done some studies on that.
People that can endure the toughest.
Don't forget about the basics.
The toughest, toughest soldiers,
they say traditionally are
Koreans and Turks. Their ability,
there's legendary ability to endure
hardship and stuff. That's interesting.
But then again,
you would think Mexicans is tough.
Mexican's Koreans that are really good.
There's a few,
Korean fighters are really good.
Korea started to build like
this really good base now. Well,
Korea was in Baden 400 times home.
Enjoy making a comeback. Izzy. Yup,
I heard looking for scrap. Is he
getting his pituitary gland operate on?
He's one of those guys. He's like 600
pounds. Who's going to fight him? Nobody.
But like big foot was like way over 300
pounds. Remember he fought that dude.
Uh, the big Jujitsu, uh,
Eric Guy from Hawaii.
Eric Palae. Oh, Eric Pale Ale. Huge guy.
A big foot. That's right. Back in
the day. I think Eric Palae beat him.
I think he knocked him out. It was that
an elite Xc, goddammit. I don't remember.
Find that Jamie. Eric Palae
versus big foot Silva. Man,
I can't remember what happened that, but
Palae was huge. She was like 300 pounds.
This is this,
this big giant [inaudible] you hear
Mark Hunt started camp at 340 pounds.
What? It's nice and light from
Barbara. I know. It's beautiful.
He's in good shape. 300. That's what you
want. It really may barely made weight.
Had to [inaudible]. See, I've heard 14
year old Simone. Keep it all that way.
Just the blueprint of healthiness.
Just he's an animal.
I'm a Mark Hunt fan to the end.
I'm a mark so far.
I think everyone's a Mark Hunt. You
have to be so fun. And by the way,
he's got some of the most
beautiful walkaway Kaos.
He's Kao Stephan Struve and usher
and yeah. Yeah. Chris Tucker.
And uh, how about um, uh,
Chango God damn that
precision with that left hook.
He landed your black Bot. Scary
dude. Man always toughest fuck.
And by the way,
barely throws any leg kicks.
He's got legs that are like
fucking telephone poles.
They're the most frightening legs.
You think?
If that guy doesn't really throw him,
he would fuck guys up if he
threw a lot of leg kicks,
me throws him occasionally and
they have a lot of power behind.
His legs are enormous. They're
fucking a new one. If you block it,
you didn't get fucked up,
dude.
Anybody who doesn't incorporate
leg kicks in their game,
if they could have been there when I was
first starting to do commentary and I
got to see Pedro,
his Oh fight when he was in his
prime kicking Randy couture's buddy,
we'd be doing leg kicks.
It's such a ruthless weapon was in
the hand of a guy like Pedro, his,
oh Jesus Christ.
I never heard anybody's leg kicks
sound like that before crack. Oh,
why inspired me to go and kick the bag
like hundreds of times more just being
there from him doing that. Maybe want
to work out your leg kicks Brit d crazy.
My man. I guarantee when we
trained with Dwayne at your house,
you are kicking it all hard and my uh,
my best friend and my brother were there.
You're like, ah, brighten
your term. I was like God damn
joking. Kick like a mother fucker.
Ridiculous speed and power.
It's hard to kick after him. It's weird.
I tried to follow him and comedy. Yes.
I was trying to be funny. I like
made some joke or something stupid.
We tell some stories before, man, man, we
got in the car and my brother was like,
you a rolling guitar in you?
Huh? I'm like, yeah man.
Better kicker. Fuck you guys.
All right, big deal. Hey
check. Check this out.
When he caught up maybe 15 years ago,
I was hanging out with Joe.
We dropped off his car to get a new
stereo and we had a kill. I got two hours.
So there was a gym across the street,
kickboxing gym,
owned by some Middle Eastern brothers
that were going to come full and
kickboxing. Aw, sweet.
We just go, we show up,
we show up and Joe is just hanging out.
And I asked the guy,
I made it seem like we were interested
in joining. So I asked them, I go,
what kind of kicks do you guys
throw here? And he goes, oh,
we do with these kids and those
kids. And I go, uh, uh, can you,
can you show me what kind of kicks you
throw here? So he's all warming up,
stretching out,
and he's about to kick this bag and he
looks over at Joe and he sees Joe like
shadow boxing and all.
But as Joe Joe didn't want to,
I wanted to say I was setting them up.
I wanted him to kick the back first and
then have Joe kick and look at his face.
I, I've done this before,
like at John Jocks,
there's like an old thing that I
did and I, and I was setting him up,
but before he kicked the back,
he looked the Joe and it says,
have you ever trained? And Joe didn't
want, he goes, yeah. And it goes in what?
In a taekwondo and the knee.
It goes for how long?
It was quite a long time and he goes, let
me see what you got. So then Joe said,
okay, so Joe murders, this fucking bad,
destroys the fresh after he
gets done with this fear,
this flurry of hurricane cakes,
that guy goes, hey listen,
fuck that noise. He goes,
I do this for a living.
If I have a kicking contest with him,
I can get hurt my classes.
I'm going to teach. If you guys want to
come to the class, I'll show you this guy,
dude,
he's a smart guy and my mind
where he's kicking with Mike Della
rotting, whatever his name is,
guys play podcasts. He doesn't know
Mark Telegraph. I watch that fucking,
I watched this shut up. Shut up.
Both of you. I watched that video.
We work with a fucking professional
fights. No near the top 10 heavyweight.
No worries. I've seen a lot of guys
kick out like I've grown up in Jim's,
I've seen Duane Ludwig. I'm just saying
the hardest kicked I've ever seen.
I'll go on record saying, this is Joe
Rogan. It's not just because he's my boy.
It's the hardest cake I've ever seen.
Crazy shit.
And I thought it was gonna be
talking about my boxing. Right.
But no one said Shit. If I'm talking about
Romans kids as like, yeah, pretty cool.
Fuck that guy anyways. And just, you know,
it's like damn man, nutty shades insane.
If you've never seen it,
check it out.
I started doing it when I was a little
kid when I was trying to tape for King of
the cage back in the day.
This was like in 2000 I would
work with Joe every now and then.
He was trying to show me some shit
and man, I was holding back from an,
I felt that this was like 2000 2001 and
I'm thinking are kicks from a guy this
size supposed to be this hard.
I didn't know he was showing me how
to hold bags. I'm like, this is,
I can only imagine if I didn't
have the bags on my arm.
So I start at,
John Jackson was a bag one bag in
his Jujitsu school and it was filled.
The class was filled with guys
that were black belt in karate.
They were trying to add Jujitsu to their
system. We had a bunch of black belts.
So I wanted to know if,
if maybe this was just normal,
maybe all dudes can it like, so I would
say I would have guys that go, Dave,
can you kick the bag right here
due to the coach on the crowd.
So he would kick in. I go, Joe, now you
kick it. And then everyone goes, oh shut.
And then we're like, oh
my God, it is incredible.
So then I kept doing that over and over.
I wanted to just make sure,
just to make sure I was telling him
I knew what I was talking about.
So I remember commentating for King of
the cage and Rico Rodriguez was uh, uh,
backstage and we were hanging out
and he was the only one I saw.
They would throw turning sidekicks and
I felt Joe's turning side kick. He was,
he's right away.
He was showing me how powerful it can be.
And I remember taking a video of Joe
doing turning side kicks in his old house
and the garage showing it backstage
at Kink to Ricoh Roderick is,
there was no youtube or
anything. I'm like, look dude,
you got to take lessons from Joe
Rogan. You've got to throw it. And He,
I remember him looking at the screening,
you couldn't really tell on that little,
it was a little LCD screen from my
blog video camera, my video camera.
And he was like, hmm, I'm trying to show
him there's no technology in 2000 at all.
I had to show him what the LCD screen and
he was like, interesting, interesting.
And you know, and he was, he thought
I was crazy. The guy fear factor,
can it, can I watch that Instagram video?
I showed probably 50 people that you know
who can kick like a fucking mule and I
would beg him to kick. I would beg
him to kick Shankar Carwyn. I said,
when you fight Brock Lesnar,
throw this fucking kick.
Well he's just in that weird way.
He's like, everything is too
big. His shoulders are too
big. His hands are too big.
He walked into fucking um, uh,
the boulder Jujitsu school.
He walked him all eastern
spices and I swear to God,
it took me a half a second to realize it
was Shane Carwyn cause I thought it was
watching like a movie. I thought it
was watching a movie. We're like,
like the thing shows up.
He's,
he was practicing kicks and we
kept telling we got to use them.
You've got to use them. This is right
before I went in the tough house.
This motherfucker's,
I start using them for my,
tore my MCL the week before I went
to the ultimate fighter house.
So I went in the house with a torn
MCL. He kicked in once. I said no more.
You fucking imagine if you
look at how big his hands are,
if you see how hard the punching power
is going to directly translate to kicking
power, freaky punching power, he's
going to have freaky kicking power.
Almost always. It's just a matter of his,
has he put in the same amount of time? Oh
Wow. This chap got of, got hung in
there, man. Yeah, he's got this dude,
this is just trying to his back. If he
chokes him out, this would be incredible.
Betty,
how funny is it that almost everybody
goes with the body triangle now when they
take the back?
Isn't it funny though that she used to
be a thing to say that all the time?
Never going to disagree
with Eddie Bravo ever.
I'm just saying for my game personally in,
in MMA,
I'm not a fan of that body
triangle y flexibility. So
no, I can do it. I can do it.
Why aren't you a fan?
I just feel like, um,
especially guys are so good at defending
a blue belt in the UFC with those big
gloves can defend forever. So it's almost
a stalling technique. Now if you forget,
unless you're just a Henry
Gracie, Gracie, Eddie Bravo,
fuck Verdo fucking nasty on
someone's back. You gotta move,
you gotta move.
Got Trend just from the arm bar.
You got a transistor site control from it.
I ain't no problems with that.
I'm not disagreeing.
I wouldn't disagree with that.
I was going for the kill on the back.
I would definitely put the body
triangle and I would, but if I wasn't,
if I was thinking he's
too fresh as in MMA,
it seems like if you get the
guys back and he's fresh,
Tuft finishment the our transition
to spiderweb, the arm bar position,
I would go right to that.
Just would Rhonda.
Rhonda don't mess around with the back.
But if you get someone's back late
and they're kind of tired and hurt,
that's when you make a choking because
guys are, it's hard with the gloves.
Like you said,
they grabbed the glove though.
If you notice it and
you're not allowed to,
but they grabbed the
clubs so it's super tough.
Then it's tough to slow to sneak the hand
in around the neck because because of
the cloud.
Do you think that there could be an
argument because the fact that they're not
fighting with anything on their feet and
they're kicking each other in the face,
like why aren't they punching each
other in the face with no gloves on?
The reality being that if you did punch
incorrectly and if you were more wild
and reckless with your punches,
you would have to pay a price for it.
So we're really more protecting hands than
we've run our the fighter. And in fact
it's probably better for your brain
if you're getting bare knuckled.
If you're not allowed to tape your
wrists up and you're not allowed to put
anything on your hands. I'm sorry. You
just can't hit as hard. You just can't.
You're going to have some movement.
You're going to have some movement
in your wrists when you punch,
you can have a lot of
movement with your kicks.
You don't want to be fucking movement.
You're shinning people in the head.
There's no movement and thicker,
denser and like, like Terry Adam,
when Edson Barboza wheel kicked him Gibbs.
No movement in your fucking he'll man.
None. So that the amount of impact that
you can make with a heel like that,
like you're saying, you're saying people
should maybe wear pads on their feet.
The hands. No, I'm not saying get
rid of the gloves, the gloves.
I think there's an argument for
getting rid of the glare. Why?
There's not mainstream media.
Right? What'd you be like? What
fucking morons? It's a four ounce glove.
It doesn't do much. It's just perception.
I think the PR,
I think honestly it probably protects
the hand more than it protects anything.
I think Bella tour for liking the hand.
Bella toward gloves.
They have a good idea cause
it's more curved and it's,
it's more padded and it protects the hand.
Would there be patting your back of
the hand? Why do they have patty?
Can I get back fist? This dude's
you could spinning back. Jesus.
There should just be pads on the knuckles.
Not on the back of the hand.
That big thick thing. It's harder
to give you a bunch out. It's true.
But the but the belt or glove.
The reason why it's so fat like that.
The idea being that this,
it's everlasting. He gave
it to the Japanese guy, pat.
Whoa. Maybe he won that second
round. I Dunno. We didn't.
We were really barely paring it down to
that first round. Should have been dead.
I hate, there's no way this
should have been a draw.
I think what I was saying is the belt
or glove it supports and there's still
four ounce.
They're still friends but there's more,
there's more support because it's more,
you had hated even more Eddie cause
there's like more stuff on top.
It's like thicker on top. And the idea
being, I think that's what she said.
Oh Shit. Brian at chop. I think they um,
they found that they had
way less handbrakes though.
Once they started using it,
they had a bunch of hand to balance
for gloves. Yeah. They're a,
they protect that significant because
the handbrake and keep you out of there,
take you out for he cans.
Right, right. But Eddie, do
you see my argument or my not,
it's not even an argument.
I'm not married to it.
I'd be happy if they kept
fighting with UFC gloves.
But I think there can be a debate that
it would probably be just as safe with no
gloves and probably maybe even possibly
safer and way better for grappling.
Have there been less pokes to the eye
or more or has it been like a steady
amount happens all the time.
Yeah.
I would say with no gloves if
it's easier to knock a guy out,
good for the show,
good for the sport.
If it's easier to get submissions because
you don't have all that shit that's
good for the show, it would.
If it adds chaos and add
submissions, get rid of them.
I think that um, if, uh, I
think if you have gloves on,
you probably can kale people better.
I really do.
I think you have way more protection
on your wrist. That's a big thing.
You're hands are wrapped up. You feel real
confident with it. It's nice and tight.
Yeah. Anything to get more
knockouts and more submissions.
That's what we want to see.
We don't, we're not paying
for decisions. Yeah. I mean,
and also it's like how much, how
much work is getting done. I mean,
how much work is getting done
with those fucking gloves on?
Spend a lot of time wrapping the
hands for what really again? Yeah.
Got To protect those hands, man.
Those hands are precious. Yeah.
I mean think about like the
cheekbones killer murderer sockets.
That's it. This kind of weird, right?
Why won't they pat up the eye
socket have like, well this is all,
I think it's all remanence of boxing.
You know,
I think we have like a lot of ideas and
and we, we have their scoring system.
We told we don't have
our own scoring system.
Our scoring system is based entirely on
the boxing's corns to the 10 point must
system.
We just arbitrarily started using 10
point must cause the athletic commissions
had already prepared for it.
They already had judges that knew how to
score a 10 for the winter nine for the
loser. If it's bad
round, he scored an Nate.
I mean this is a way
different game than boxing.
It needs its own type of fighting.
Super Score.
I know we don't,
you think that we need a
more complex scoring system
when we work together with Eddie Bravo
used to do the in round scoring at the
UFC and it was fucking great because Eddie
had a sister. She'll unofficial judge,
unofficial in round score the hell.
So he would sit next to us.
It was sitting next to us. Then in
between rounds we would, you know,
would show a highlight or something and
then I'd say, Eddie, what do you think?
And Eddie would say, you know,
I gave it to this, to this,
I think for doomed did
that and blah blah blah.
And he would break down why and he had
a sheet and on his sheet who would write
kicks on one side take downs on their
side submissions on the other side.
And he would write like what type
of submission, how close it was.
And he had all that stuff laid out and
then afterwards he would give a detailed
reason why I thought that Kane
won that round because of this.
And then he would go over all the
various, write it down. It's so hard.
I didn't write it down. There's so
much that went on in that round you,
it's hard to visually see if he
was a question. If somebody takes,
if somebody attempts 10 takedowns
and the guy stuff's 10 takedowns,
the aggressor is more valuable,
but then he gets one.
You know that you don't let a question.
What about wins around for sure.
He's winning the round. If he's attempting
more, right. The guys stuffing it.
That guy is, he's not giving
up two months. So aggression,
aggression should count as
sure. Yeah, it'd be something.
What about a foma submission artist?
I pulled,
I pulled half guard and I'm
throwing all these submission tents,
all these Amish temps and the guys kind
of getting out of them. I'm getting,
I'm going to give nothing but judges see
the guy on top. He's getting the true,
but I see that again, that say that
again. A Guy's trying to sell it.
So let's say you and I are fighting.
You pull guard and you're
throne Ooma Plata triangle,
a armbars nonstop per five minutes,
nonstop moms.
The whole time on defending, I win the
round. That ain't right. That ain't right.
But, and you're doing and I'm
doing no damage, but let's say,
let's say in that Ben Saunders fight,
let's say that exact same
thing happened every round.
He ended up taking him down and just
assaulted him with those elbows and rubber
guard. But he didn't finish him.
I think when it's that clear,
the judges will give it to the guy on
the bottom. Cause it has happened before.
It just needs to be,
you know what?
Clear with some serious
that's up for debate.
You would think they would. I bet it'd
be 50, 50 depending where you're fine.
They shit, I'll fucking crazy.
Yeah. Crazy. Yeah. Cause uh,
thinking I think if the NFL,
NBA where like that where it's 50,
50 pence on, don't leave it
up to the judges. It's a,
Ben Saunders didn't get the Alma plot that
the guy survived and the time run out.
Who would I won that round?
You think the judges would have really
gave it to the dude on top? Probably.
He was the whole time.
I know,
but all they do is they just, a lot of
them are just mentally geared towards,
he's on top. He's winning the round
cause they're on educated with Jujitsu.
You know what ends up happening? I'll
tell you some of these judges, man,
they look at the replays and if in the
truck they're showing [inaudible] doing
all that stuff they've got,
okay,
they must in the truck think that
due to winning. So they do that.
They do that for 100% for sure.
100% for sure. 100% not all of them.
Not all the judges. Not all the judges
and a few, but I know what's happened.
This is the fight. I'm looking. Brendan
Schaub is a weird fascination with this.
I know.
I don't think it's about fighting.
I'm going to just choosing the young lady.
She looks,
look at [inaudible] her picked her up
for the UFC thick shoes like a little
Paula Hardy's looking at,
I think Michigan is very attractive.
Marion was attractive female.
She doesn't do steroids. No Way.
Oh look at that Japanese book. Look. So,
so tell me she's a cutie
pie. No. First of all,
Rin grew up doing gymnastics. Judo, she,
she takes, she trains every day. Takes
only one day off a month, 24 hours a day.
She has that fricking crazy workouts.
He's undefeated to look at those arms.
Come on. She's undefeated, undefeated
16 and no one. Look, there's no Joe.
She, she's asking right now. I'm
a huge Pratt. All of us. I hope.
I hope she's awesome. She
doesn't get smoke. Well,
what is that thing that she does?
Weird cheered photographs that she does.
She does like me. I'm awesome. Sexy
pictures. I'm not saying it's bad.
It's called marketing. It's called
marketing. You mean the awesome.
I'm just saying it was your mom.
I would say it's odd.
Are you going to a store?
Brian is
in my car.
It's weird.
You have one store in your car if
you're a pony to another party. Right.
Travis Browne,
Travis Brown water to fight you in a
rash guard and the commission, you know,
since they're allowing girls that
fighting rash guards, they decide, Ooh,
let's make it, uh, you know, it's
up. Leave it up to the fighters.
Would you allow if it was up to you,
would you allow Travis Browne to where
rash guard and you're fine? No. Why not?
Because, uh, girls wear them
all the time. It's true. Why
would you say no or would you say
whenever he wants it doesn't matter.
What would you say? I would probably
say no because if he wants to wear it,
there's some sort of advantage that he
thinks that he's going to have by wearing
it. So he must be Hella comfortable in
this rash guard. If I pull the power moon,
I'm like Nah son, take that rash
geared off cause I'm not wearing one.
You know what I'm saying? Friendly,
sharp playing mind games. But you can't,
you and you'd think, hey look,
look what could be the advantage.
I don't know. You're nasty and a rash
guard. What are you talking about?
Nasty look, look at this.
No behind you. Brendan Chop.
Did she shout? Whoa. Look at those legs.
There's all the photographs
of her but on her son,
her arms man cause too much. As long
as much I know a little much. No. No.
Because I think she would
be kind of submissive.
It'd be Kinda hot cause she's like
the super strong kind of advantage.
Do you show that you would have probably
a group, maybe a grip advantage. How, how,
how would he get him?
Because let, let's say, uh,
you're fighting a guy like for
breach over doom. Who you're,
you're worried about is you're going to
get a really good sweat and warm up on
before. So I'm a little more
slippery, you know what I'm saying?
You want to be slipper? Yes. Oh I see.
So you think that it would be an
advantage cause it, you would,
it would limit Dior defense?
Yes.
Especially with a guy like for
doom, right. That's what I'm saying.
Well you're dealing with us.
So what she's wearing,
what of Travis Brown wanted to wear
that you would object to it. Yeah.
It's slapped him the face at the press
garments slap in the face for even
considering it. What if the guy you
were fighting, okay. What if the guy,
you were filed Jon Jones Gacy what does
the guy you were fighting? Uh, let's see.
Who could it be? Did it help
him? If he wants to wear a mask,
you were guiding lactose. Carlos wore that
in pride. I'm down for that. It would,
if you were fighting cro cop and
he wanted to wear a rash guard,
would you allow him think about it? He was
not going to try to submit you. I know,
but I kept saying you would want to submit
but I kept taking, I fought cro gun.
Oh wait, that's right. You beat him.
Right. I forget. I forget. Yeah.
And not only that,
that was a panic.
So that would be a bad example
because a kickboxer would want to be,
have a really good guard like you would
want him to and he wants to get up.
But if he,
you're on the bottom,
how is that going to help people with
extra grip holding a guy onto, you know,
it be just try to get stood up
two bottles or loss gain.
Cro Cop did the same. So you, uh,
so you would be against that if they,
if you had a
sign,
a petition against,
are you for or against rash guards in MMA?
Men don't care that much.
But if you were a rash guard on when
we're wrestling shoes take in the face
wrestling shoes.
What if you were going up against
a guy like Paul Harris then? No,
no wrestling shoes.
No recipe boil these things.
Yeah, we're a little leg locks
illegal. I want to see the dude's name,
but I know a dude who would
lay in a mineral bath.
He would take mineral oil and lay in the
bath the night before and then he would
take a shower and dry off and then he
would make weight. Even though he was,
he was not wearing any oil on him.
He was so oily from the night before.
But as soon as you broke a sweat,
it would all come through his pores
and he would just be like a seal.
Just us seal does heal.
Do you think you could
beat in an MMA fight?
Do you think you could be Gabby Garcia?
Are you being, you being Farrell's?
Yeah. Yeah. You're talking to a man,
Garcia. I know it doesn't match and
then pushes images. She lost weight.
She got to slim 300 pounds real quick.
I like it. He should take, I think she's
very attractive. However, written the Chi.
Yes. Britain. The Chi. I
just feel like she keeps,
and it's going to be good for the sport.
Could you imagine if she became the well
to which are the bantamweight champion?
I've written to Chi if she's got all
these freak pictures of her in her
underwear,
you know,
wearing fucking little fucking
bunny rabbit slippers and shit.
Dangerous fight. Dangerous
fight for me. She's 10.
She doesn't know what to expect, but
she could be sent us a little bull dog.
What did she do? Her up.
This Japanese bulldog.
It doesn't necessarily mean she
doesn't know what she's doing.
She's gonna try getting her down. Oh,
she does know what she's doing. She's,
come on, she's stiff, but
she could still land man.
But she looked very stiff nerves. You've
got first UFC fight. Fuck yeah. USC.
No, I bet she's real strong.
Dude. Me Tastes gonna fuck her up.
Meisha Tate's later turn into the mic.
Aggressive.
How long has Ron show business?
My math is wrong with you.
He wants to be on that Mike. So bad. I
got hungry. Starving when he's eating,
he can't push it away.
That's my friend.
It looks like me. She was going
to dominate it does me just said,
oh you train everyday stuff for one.
Check this out me.
She looks very strong and very aggressive
and you know there's another thing
that she's coming off of a
fight where she wasn't. Oh Wow.
Bragged on Michelle's
digit. Pretty solid. Yeah.
Well her overall technique is very solid.
I mean she's the only person to ever put
Rhonda in a compromising position in a
fight. Let's call this Carmouche.
That's true. That's true.
But that was when used,
she still does.
She does that hip toss where
she grabs a hold the headlock,
the headlock and she gives up the back
all the time cause she wasn't trained
with a cage so she wouldn't eat.
She wasn't used to it and
got in a weird position.
I just feel like she's so
confident that it doesn't,
she feels like it doesn't matter
if they get her neck or whatever,
she's going to fuck them up.
That girl has such incredible like
laser beam focus towards victory does.
She doesn't have any doubt.
It's,
it's so rare that Beth career batch
Cocheco hair, that's going to be a great,
that can actually happen. And then the
next one, she's got Rhonda. So, uh,
work pissed off. She, she
looks like a giant stuff.
We'll compare to this check written
to Chi. Well, Nikai is very thick,
but it doesn't seem to be working out.
Reney Chi.
Better figure something out here. Not
that impressed. I gotta be honest. Well,
she's very stiff. I mean she is
still when anything can happen,
fights or she went with a
submission. You never know, man.
You never know. She's not going to win
striking unless she just has some, oh,
she got tagged with that knee.
Just lighten her own. Now.
Ameesha looks very smooth. Yes, she
does. Close to taking her down. Oh,
but I'm telling you, do weird things
happen when people are durable.
And this chick seems very durable. I'm
not saying she's going to win the fight,
but weird shifts can happen.
Yes,
he's written. It guides me like,
Holy Shit, I'm a use of sin.
That's what she's thinking right now.
Oh Shit. I'm in the UFC. Well, this,
by the way, this is like one of the
best versions of Meesha we've ever seen,
if not the best.
You don't think it's a she's facing.
I'm sure it has something to
do with it. No, but seriously,
she looks very good shopping.
Nice. No, he's being honest.
I'm being dead on dead on.
It's like when Overeem fight Frank Mir,
Frank Mir fan in the world, everyone's
like, oh my God, they'll redeem his back.
Or was he fighting a human punching
bag? Frank Meir did nothing. Well,
Frank's had a long career,
man. Danny, you got car I left,
got hit by a car. It was on a motorcycle
and the car literally hit his leg.
The car slammed into his leg,
but he's saying he still a
great fights after fights.
He had good fights after
that. Brock Lesnar, it took
him a long time to recover.
It took them a long time to
recover. I think that, um,
that was a devastating injury,
frankly, one of the best ever to do it.
Ever without a doubt. When the best
submission artists without a, she's hurt.
She's hurt. She's really
hard. It's over. Oh boy.
Nisha just chicks durable man.
Very durable.
The sport needs Misha Women's,
women's fighting needs. Misha Tate,
Bob Brennan show magic. I'm telling
you, cause she's attractive.
She speaks well and she
has some skills. Yeah. Oh,
she definitely has some
scales down. Shit. She got to,
you know what is a
chick like Nisha though?
Like what does she do with a girl like
Rhonda out there that is kind of a
prophecy to Stacy second.
Koizumi
second place. Second place. Second place.
Isn't that bad. It's like shake and bake.
It's shaken baby. Shake your shake
it. Rhonda shake. I mean she was big,
big. Hey Becky still lived in a nice
crib. Bake. Still had a nice brim.
Big wound up fucking shakes. Wife
remember shit got crazy. Shit gets crazy.
Crazy. Oh Marty. That was
what calls him up. He goes,
why is the TV on?
What you want the TV on the legal on
the same time because I liked to party.
How do you get the sound stereo
but still watching the TV.
That's such a good movie. Great shake and
bake. But nobody, I'm telling you man,
they're not good friends. Look at my
face and to always be little Zur. No,
they fucking hate each other. So No,
I'm just saying shaking baby. Yeah,
but being second place to
someone as ruthless as Rhonda,
like when they were doing the ultimate
fighter together and they were doing that
thing where they're climbing the
wall and Rhonda winds and she goes,
fuck you bitch. Hey, she fucking
hates her. Nobody does that.
Everybody else if is Gilbert and
didn't guys don't do that guys.
Brian is a different animal man.
She absolutely does.
Does she literally has hate in her heart?
Oh yeah. I don't hate anyone in the UFC.
I don't hate anyone.
No one Rhonda literally hates me.
Should tailor hates she's on.
She's on some next level shit.
She done some demonic next level.
She's got some fury in her and,
and you don't want to be Misha
Tate on the receiving end.
Well you need to be not only if
you do need to match her skillset,
which is good fucking luck, but you need
to be able to match that intensity man.
Fuck thing. He's really fucked as this
written Nikai okay. She's fucking like,
cause we're talking
about Rhonda right now.
This girl's only half ass double leg.
She's freaking,
I don't know what she's
doing. Turned on her. I
was planning out our kids and say no,
not with head movement like that.
No.
Oh excuse me sir.
She doesn't come on.
Get this and Brennan my like you more.
She's
checking the oil. You don't, she
doesn't have any oil in there.
[inaudible] was knuckle deep
in that Knuckle d women.
It's not an oil situation. The knuckle
deep meter hits Red Hot Friday night.
Taylor with a knee lube made from real
butter oil. Well it fits if you're,
if a guy has oil, does a gal have oil
as well? If we're not checking your oil,
checking your honey, checking
your honeypot, come on.
Sympathetic conversation.
Checking the Koolaid.
Let's not do this because this is bad
for the sport. I get answers path, man.
I was trying to stay out of
it with you guys directly.
Faults.
It's none of our faults.
We had been drinking and
we're not responsible for our
word, correct? No, I am. No,
I'm just drinking coffee. I'm sober
as shit, but things like that.
It's like getting kicked in the junk.
I don't ever know what to say.
If a girl kicks a girl,
I'm not coming up.
They showed me. How have they
stopped? No. What about this?
What about going to Haiti? Shot hurt.
Are you going to show it in slow motion?
You show the ball shots in slow motion
is my point and everyone goes, oh,
the whole stadium go home.
By the way, I joke about it sometimes,
you know I'll make light of it like no,
that is not fun.
You all say something like that,
but I'm not going to say that
if it's a girl punt a you said,
excuse me.
[inaudible] is on her back that up
throw. What did I tell you? Man
Opens when people are durable.
This little fire hydrant,
just keep talking.
Keep [inaudible] get this.
We'd give you big brown,
but listen Jeezy
don't win one and get the breath.
Let's see if she holds the back
body triangle. But no, look, she's hanging
on man. She's kind of hanging out with,
she's going to be in her garage guard.
Well,
let's see what kind of guard she's got.
Maybe she's,
she might have some NASA. Well, me,
she's a very good grappler. Yeah,
she's a better graph within.
She's a strike. 100% oh man. It's,
but you're right guys.
Hey guys.
Durable Little Gal. She's game. Yep.
Taking shots. Yeah, but now she's got me.
Y'all talk for dropping bow Chihuahua.
She's trying to set up an arm bar.
Look at this. She's good. She's
got good hips, man. Active hips.
This is a tricky situation for me.
Misha. She better be careful. Oh,
this chick's legit. Legit off her
back. But Misha, good defense.
All Straw on top.
It comes to Nissan.
Oh,
attempt there.
The more she can slow Meesha down on it,
the more she turns into a grappling
match. She got some good positions, man.
I mean, she didn't come close to finish.
She's winning this round right now.
You're in Japan to
remember the last part was,
I wonder if they're using Japanese judge.
I got a text from Dana saying that in the
fight that we were talking shit during
the whole fight,
the referee go grab the guy's glove.
I don't know what the
situation was because we were
just laughing and having too
much fun. We missed, we missed if
he's listening to it. Yeah. Yeah.
Dana was going crazy and
he texted me and he's like,
I'm sure you know that. If I
saw it, I would have called it.
But I told him in the text message,
I go, did, we didn't even see it.
We were talking so much shit. This is
the worst way to watch a fight ever.
I don't know that we've
gone some weird tangent,
barely paying attention to amazing fight,
but it's so fun.
This is my favorite way to watch my
timber loan. The guys got that single,
oh boy.
We were doing this, uh,
this my comment, oh boy.
We were doing this video
breakdown of Bryan caraway
the other day and it's funny,
Bryan caraway on his, on his resume
like they have, you know your resume,
like the fighters resume they gave me
like fought in Strikeforce. Funnily Dixie,
13 four records.
Hey said boyfriend of
me. She said girlfriend,
Misha Tate.
It said boyfriend of mishit tape that
was in his bio and he's a good fighter.
He's foreign one in the UFC.
He's a very good fighter.
He's beaten some very good guys.
It's just his girlfriend is
hot and they want the logon.
No saved his mom's
she went into,
she had had an asthmatic
attack and me's in like Shimmy.
She saved her life. Wow.
Yup. Meets your say save.
Whose life his or her mother
Bryan Caraway. Oh, look at this.
This is what she went for. She went
for a Tampon to got her back. Hmm.
Damn. I like it. There's something right
there. Do you see something right there?
What do you see right there?
What do I see where here she was
just completely on the side arm.
Triangle position. You know what
I love Eddie? Tell me about this.
Are you doing that arm bar where the
arms in that arm bolt where everybody's
doing it now?
Like a lot of guys are doing an MMA
with the arms trapped inside the legs.
Like um, like the pass the arm
to the side from side control.
You said Pat, the arm gets passed to
the side. It's like this. Yeah. Yeah.
It's totally stretched out and then
the guillotine goes on over it.
You know what I'm talking
about? I don't know. Anytime.
A lot of guys have been doing it
where they're getting the arm.
I'm completely pinned
up to the side he gets,
I think this is one. I think this
is one to one grab real quick.
I think this is one
one. I'm just going to throw
that out there. You guys. Um,
have you seen Brian couns wig?
A wheel kick.
Beautiful. Oh, back again.
She likes jumping on bags.
That was a good little combo.
She turned it on Japanese bulldog. That
looks like a very shiny outfit, man.
Mischa's clean today. Kimora
attempts here. This chick
is so strong, man. Look at.
Oh,
she comes and
she's jumping on the back.
Really Quick Hook once side.
That means you're right. She's
telling you. What did I tell you, boy?
Right there. You got instincts. I've
been doing this a while. Netflix,
you're out the Japanese bulldog
show you rooting against Tate now,
bro,
me or Brian, any one of
us. Does anybody here? No,
I love him. He should take. Okay.
If you could choose to be a tropic island
with one of them free. She taped me.
Go do this to me. Don't do this
to me. Don't do it. You, you.
You have a thing with the Japanese chick.
You would have, I think the party came.
She is a cutie pie. She's on that
brand and you can handle it. They're,
they're both of area track. Who Lie?
You find her jacket? Both of them. Well,
let's just,
let's admired them for their skill.
The traffic because their
skills are, oh me, she's out,
but she's struggling, man. Oh, elbow.
Big issue. It's a little tiny chairs.
Top angry man.
I thought she looked a little annoyed.
That whole Combo or she that takes down
to the back. That was really smooth.
How was much more difficult? Is
it for my beautiful girls? Tired.
How much more difficult is it for a
beautiful girl fight? Oh, big yawn.
A lot more pressure.
Well,
I met this girl the other day who said
she wants to get into fighting shoes.
She was stunning and I went, why would
you do saying like a girl like Misha,
she has a beautiful face,
whereas like body to go Vandelay Silva
and I mean everything. She's beautiful.
She's a great person too.
Very nice. Very smart too.
But let's think about like Vendelay Silva
is also a mixed martial arts fighter
now. I've been a fan of Andrew Lee
silver from the Golden Day. Tired today,
retired today.
His face has changed so much from
impacts and scar tissue and damage.
And we remember like when he fought
like Dan Henderson, he had this one,
he was actually handsome guy.
He had this one look and then over
the years of just getting smashed,
his nose completely flooded out.
And then he had to get an operation
to open his nose passage up.
He had zero like May and
Miller's the same way.
Man can't breathe out of his nose.
His mate is, no, just doesn't work.
It's just smashed from now. A girl
like me should take. It was my point.
She is in the same sport.
It's them.
It's very possible that I can hit
like a man though. She would've.
She fought that batchko hair.
She'd get hit, but she was
kissing God. I'll catch and
eat cheese. That's true.
She had a blow to the elbow,
but an average Wanderlei Silva
was going against a cro cop.
These monsters just can break your nose.
It's true. It's a little different.
Good point. That's a good point, but
still, you're a girl still scholar.
My daughter fight,
like look at this scar on.
Let's think of a big scar that
happened in MMA. Okay. Like Joe Lozan.
He's got this big scar that he had.
He had that gate, that Graston method.
From what? From a knee, I believe it was
a knee or a kick from one of his fights.
What to grass.
The method.
They take like a piece of metal and
talk about breaking up the scar tissue.
These are for injuries.
Athletes use it for,
it's like a high tech form
of that rolfing stuff.
It's like breaking down, which we've
ever done. Roffman yes, fucking painful.
It's painful but it could affect, it
leaves a mark for forever. You're fucked.
You're
saying,
you're saying the girl like Ronda Rousey's
Rumi state who has a really pretty
face. Yeah man. They could get a giant
like fucking gash across their face.
Like we haven't seen that yet,
but how weird is it going to be
when there's a chick that has like,
like John John, John Jack has that
cut from fighting frank Trigg.
He was shooting in for a take down.
He got caught with a knee and he has,
I mean he had perfect surgery done on it.
Like you can't pay attention,
but John Jack is a manly man. If he has a
scar, it doesn't hurt. The way you look,
makes it more hit some really
important girl. You're, Ooh girl,
a girl with a four inch scar,
a scarlet letter face because it's not
going to change much. Guys are so horny as
single leg. Is that, well actually even
bigger like Gina Carano though, man.
That face a guy that you
see whether it's happening.
Does that count as a point when she
takes her down against Toronto had a toy
like a boxing match,
but I'm saying that that should be scored
right when you take somebody down and
single accounts up,
but it depends on the judge to take
somebody down. Somebody stands right up.
Take a little pride, a
little thing there, man.
Damn.
Oh,
I bet you they'd give it
to a Rin Raisie really?
They might two rounds, right? He's a
superstar too. She got the back twice.
Ultimate fighter. How they have to two
rounds and a third. If they go a third,
the third decides that. That's a
great idea. Don't take the bad idea.
They used to do that in k one, two.
I think that's a good idea because
it eliminates that Misha is disappointed.
Those fights where you have three rounds.
The first two are kind of close,
but the judges gave it to like the same
dude and then the third round the other
guy beat his ass and he still
loses. It's true. You know?
It was weird though in the
tough house when I was on it.
When you go to round them
like you wouldn't know, you
go back to court. I'm like,
we're gone a third like Jesus
man. You know? I think it's,
it's easier to beg for that way. I
agree. It's kind of cool to know.
You know what I would do if I would,
if they were a brown one went by and
it was like uneventful could have went
either way.
I would just not even score that rally.
He would wait till the next round.
If we add another round like that,
I would give him one piece. I agree.
And then you know what I mean?
Why would you automatically,
I give someone around when it could've
went either way and maybe she didn't
give it to man. I don't know. We
were talking so much sugar in.
It could be the worst judges of,
I don't even know who the guys were.
Four judges.
They're going to give it to the car.
Oh Shit.
Let's see, man, I'm a seasoned
here. Foods there, any booze?
They don't even
respect the warriors chair
fights in Japan is awesome, man,
because while the fights are going on,
everyone's dead quiet. It's really cool.
She going to call out Rhonda here. She
needs to go to a and work on our striking,
powerful Brian Stann looking slick.
Got That bug
look. It's not my favorite sexy accent,
but goddamn Japanese is pretty hot.
Something about it.
My top stomp my feet.
I thought then uniquely sexy about
it. Really. The English accent.
Well, Spanish is pretty hard to
actually, let's say you're Mexican
modern family chick, that Cuban chair. Oh
Jesus. It's impossible to get hotter
kids with her. They called me.
I get hot to do it right.
They need to do an episode one,
like how did he get hurt? They need
a rewind. Go back. Who got her like,
how did they,
where did they pull that off?
Maybe he's richest shit
and she's a fricking,
maybe he'll get a dick like
Donald Cerrone's arm. So big.
The black belt in Jujitsu. Not, not giant,
not like she's just like a
fucking strong 155 pounders lead.
Exactly. 155 pounder. Who throws
hard with not aggressive attitudes?
Would they be online or just pulls it out?
She just pulls it out like
it's a fucking fighting a fire.
It's holds it out by just saying,
my index finger think she is
fighting a fire. It's hip,
not a big old angry piss hole.
Like a fucking one of those snake fish.
They can crawl out of a lake and
walk for a mile. That's what I look.
So you can see
with a cock flares out in the
mushroom head, it's got guilt limey.
It's always slimy.
Always just in the middle of the desert.
He pulls it out as Dick. Alissa
has a runny nose, runny nose,
Harry Salmonella, like aliens tongue.
Remember when the alien pulls,
timeouts everything drips,
looks like
tomato,
red veins and the length and
if I'm not around, he has been out for
a long time. Brought brought two years.
Jamie pullout Amir's the dollars record.
He's been out there two years for sure.
Wow.
He was a really good fighter and then he
fought Ludwig and Ludwig kind of picked
him apart and that was like,
that was a big loss with broke,
broken Ludwig Glue really lit him up
because he was really becoming a very good
striker, very high volume. He
was into that Moy Thai style.
But there's certain guys,
other guys were they,
when they begin their career and they
face the guy where they can't do anything
and they never, they never come back
from it. Well it was, it's weird, right?
Was the style matchup.
He had lost a recipes
before it came back stronger,
but Duane Ludwig when he's on,
was one of the most technical,
most proficient in most educated
strikers in MMA ever. Ever, ever.
He's so educated,
which is why Korea on both sides
of his life in such a good trainer,
the reason why he's such a good trainer
is because he's so educated in tall
tactics. [inaudible] he's been
there. That tells trainers habit.
When we were working out with him,
man,
I saw him correcting all
these little things with you.
And all I can think of is,
God damn, if Shab could work
with this guy every day,
if you could work with Dwayne every day,
it would change your game a lot.
You're a sponge and when you're with
that guy and he's showing you stuff and
he's a freak.
I love sponge in a freak.
He's trying to just fill you up and you're
like, come on, show me what you got.
And you guys were, that was a fun
workout session to watch. Oh so much fun.
But that fight was just a bad fight for
Amir was the wrong style. Dwayne was too,
God damn good on his feet and Dwayne
came into that fight, healthy, you know,
there was like that was always Dwayne's
things you is cut too much weight.
He's never healthy.
Too hard.
He's been fighting for so long and
kickboxing and fucking, you know,
it finally caught up to him when he got
to the UFC and Dwayne's the guy where he
came in.
Now you're talking superstar with his
skillset and his work ethic is just,
he was a little too late, you
know what I'm saying? Honestly,
coachings worked out for him with
tremendously, I'm just saying, you fell.
You fast forward and start
Dwayne 10 years later.
He's a superstar when he does his work
ethic. Dwayne is not genetically gifted.
He's got a a regular athletic body.
It's his intelligence and his
knowledge and his drive demeanor,
demeanor's demeanor. Listen, when we'd
come to the gym and they're sparring,
Dwayne be the first one. The cage means
Shane. We look at each other like,
I ain't going with them. You Go, is
that my ankle? When you go argue,
good to go first with them. He would
walk through everything. Keep going. Wow.
Why kickstand. Yeah. He was a fantastic
strike with heavyweights, with God,
and he talks to us like, you
better not. Don't take me down.
Don't be a bitch and take me
down. And we, I'd like, okay,
but I'm going to take the hit now.
So I'm sitting there striking with this
to him. What are you thinking about care?
Are you practicing turning sidekicks
or wheel kicks? A not Wilcox yellow.
Can we listen to his music please wait.
Comes up to the Sopranos Music. Brian.
It's boring.
So you've actually taken it.
No. Turn inside, man. That would be
a good fucking idea. He's right here.
He's your boy. We did a
little kicking something. I'm
coming to think about hardy.
I'm telling you this. I'm telling
you he's got it. We got some stuff.
I believe you.
We have the,
I will have the best stirring up the
Malik guys I'm bringing to Mimic Travis
Browne. I'm telling you, we
got it. You'll be just fine.
We'll working on dealing with
that front snap kick. He does.
Well, the biggest, fight them
on that too. The Jackson's camp.
They're really the hidden
that Jackson's anymore though,
but he's still going to train there.
He's trying to, he's not just, he's
doing the whole camp in Glendale. Okay.
Ron Does camp well. Look, he learned,
still learned a lot from 100% still
like still going to have that cheat.
Just Christ. How jacked his doctor
Yama looked at one 17 bodied up.
We call her [inaudible].
He said 1111 when we
got to make a new meter.
He certainly isn't all that GSP liquor.
A little pudgy.
He does and he's got a beautiful, he goes,
nobody does. That's kind of impossible.
No bullshit. He is fucking
unbelievable. Shred old trunk.
Did you see Captain America? He did a
good job. Oh fuck yeah, he did. Yeah.
He's got a a martial arts killer.
What do you think it would have fucking
greatest welterweight of all time was
also good at playing
the kids shredded.
Look at Akiyama.
He's doing very well where you get
what he's saying. He had one 80 feet.
Practice singing. You have to, your
body has to be in very good shape.
I think he's getting a couple
of fights at one 70 if not,
this might be his day.
What's usually five one 85 you'll see
the fight with Lieben leaving like you
didn't see one of the greatest fights
ever as far as entertainment value,
entertainment,
entertainment for
those last chip,
is that what it is?
Judo.
That's a famous singer and
he's a famous Japanese 35.
Do you think he's, do you think
he's uh, the married, I'm not,
I'm going to be faithful. A celebrity
or do you think he just running shit,
running stuff trains on Japanese women.
They did some weird shit
up shit on each other.
I'm not saying,
I'm not saying he doesn't too far,
man.
You mean when they wrap Saran wrap
and they just, then they breathe out?
Shouty is podcasts all shouting past
2:00 AM 2:00 AM and we're lit up like
Christmas trees? No, I'm only
drinking coffee. I'm drinking.
But when you do wrap your face and
Saran wrap bottom of his lats, the line,
he doesn't have a lower back.
By the way. I got a nice back.
It's hard for me to give it up. He's got
a beautiful back. It's shoot us the same,
but he looks, he's so, he was
always like a very fit, fit guy.
But at one 70 he looks like a
fucking alien. Wow. He's shredded.
Look at him boyfriend and I'm going
to start bowing before my fights.
Wait a minute. It says boyfriend
on his banner. I hope so. Yeah,
that's his girl probably right
there. This is people said, oh,
Amir suddenly took two years off.
Hey,
we got one flight at the dime piece has
taken some time off to Diane pieces.
Busy making bank saying
singing, painting, Hungry Day.
I agree.
That body keeps you hungry.
Here's a dollar doing for a living these
days. He hasn't fought in two years.
He's been teaching lots of the
year. Come on. Who has better last?
Pretty bouncy and who has better lat
Amir's movement was always good, man.
It was just Dwayne was just a step
ahead of him in that fight and drain.
Heard them with like a left
hook, I think. Left Hook. Yeah.
There's never been known for his power.
I feel like Akiyama is gonna have
some power. Yeah, that is true.
Akiyama to has some ball.
That's a big wakeup. Come on.
Seriously from the beginning.
I've never wore power.
My just stoned out of my mind. Oh No.
He's very big lats and he has
a chin to Akiyama can take.
So I took him down. Guys. I
want to use this expression,
but he's a high level judoka but
[inaudible] has some good Jujitsu.
He won some fights in the UFC and
is a the ultimate fighter dude.
He wants some fights with armies
fighting a high level tough house.
Finding a high level judoka
with beautiful skin.
I cannot skip it. It's not almost,
you can take almost out of that
statement. He's got cold skin. Fuck, fuck.
Be Ground. How about big
goals? Damn right ma'am.
Goal we call a medium goal.
Oh Man.
Well there's some Asians that
cross into that like darker relm.
They got a little pops in Asian and then
the wholesaler with the ties can get
really dark.
He's just straight Japanese and just
and goes to the Korean tanning salon.
Thousand 14 you comes from a different
land. He's a gold card to Brazil.
My boyfriend right there.
Step back into why would he step back
in and you guys are grappling as one.
He didn't like it,
didn't like something he thought maybe
was going to get us back to the why
didn't he?
Why would he go backwards?
That's the sign of his short
say body unsure passer.
Some show like to hold this position too,
right?
Randy couture said they're
not comfortable for grounds.
Guys who are heavy top grapplers stay in
half guard. They're comfortable there.
They can do damage and control scapes.
Yeah, that's what Randy was saying,
that his skin is straight.
Let's just all develop it's distractions.
All I can see this gold as well.
That's the only thing that matters in
this fight about the gold shorts to go
with the gold
shorts.
It's like a black on black Mercedes
roll down the street with a high tech
and the boyfriend patch on his shorts.
Aki yamas mirror window soccer.
Robbie used to go into the cage
with a shirt that just said water
and weird fake glass and
the Japanese look so good.
It's just like an ancient symbol
like walking in water like this.
Just the irony full of
written a symmetry to them.
Hi, I regrets. We're goofy Shit Shit.
Who's have Japanese things tattooed on.
They don't even know what it means.
Brian got in,
I think it was Chinese.
He thought he was getting Brian Tattooed
on his arm and it says waterfall.
He didn't know he wanted his.
Yeah,
he wanted his name tattooed on his arm
and the dude fucked it up. Waterfall.
Probably an American dude.
Oh,
big elbow by Akiyama doctor
Yama looks heavy on top.
Both such good grappler.
You know that those judo
guys are so God damn strong.
Gonzaga similar.
This Gonzaga is another one.
Like Shane car went in a lot of ways,
has knockout power.
When he gets onto the scale like and he
walks onto the stage where the scale is,
it's a different thing. It's like a stone
man is walking on. It's fine, he's fine.
And I know you know what's up,
Darling.
Just turn that standard crouch against
him. You know, you guys back up.
Look at this.
A real legit judoka
backing notes. Dan Kick,
no extension, no extension.
He hit it and then he pulled out of it.
[inaudible] American Jim it right. Well,
it's not that. No. These guys,
they don't have the extension.
It's an they're doing the technique
in a way that works. Who closed.
It's not the most, no. Even
when it's in close man,
still extent you could extend it.
Whenever you throw that kick.
It's never bouncing off ever.
You never bounce off.
You can always extend and landing always.
It's just a matter of they're doing it
wrong. It's a, it's a complex technique.
There's a lot of steps to the spinning
back kick or turning sidekick with her.
They're two totally different kicks
really. But everybody started,
we always called it the turning
side kicking the taekwondo schools.
But when I started doing kickboxing they
would say show them that spinning back
kick.
So I would start calling it depending
back here cause I figured that was the
karate guys. That's what they called it.
But it's, it's, it's, it's a sidekick.
It's the knee comes up high
and this is an extension.
That's how Akiyama through it
does the back kick version.
How chuck used to throw it
with the toes down, heel up.
And that's a powerful kick too. It's like
a donkey kick. It's a little different.
But you can fuck a guy up at that too.
It's all a matter of reps.
And most importantly when you do the reps,
you have to extend and a lot of guys
don't extend. They bounce off of it. Your,
your shorts kicks all on, or all
of them, all the ones he throws,
if they would,
if they land perfectly,
very hard to survive one full like
thank God I have a video, right?
Hitting somebody with one video from
that taekwondo till you finally have
something as a defense.
Nice one. It landed, it was
good. He just didn't extend.
See how he bounced off when,
when it should have been the opposite.
He should have it through the right leg
should have been forward at the end of
it.
It should have been so much force going
forward that his right leg was forward.
There's no,
it should have been an a no denial
thing and if you throw a front kick,
front kick is perfect example because
it's a pretty easy technique to master.
You'd pick the knee up.
It's very normal mechanics,
but when you throw a front kick, you
almost always go forward with the kick.
You very rarely throw front kick and
then pull it all the way back behind you.
Right.
That's not,
it's not a natural movement cause to do
the front kick and put weight into it,
you're going to naturally
step forward will the,
you should do the same thing with the
turning sidekick. It's just people.
They just haven't been
taught. Right. It's all it is.
There's the one thing that drives
me nuts. Nice high kick by said, aw,
there's a one thing that drives me
nuts at all martial arts techniques.
It is that one technique that spinning
back kick or the turning side,
so one that drives me nuts because I
know the potential of it and then I've
shown it to people and they'll go,
I didn't even know this. I'm like,
I know you didn't know. There was
a lot of people that don't know it.
It's just a matter of doing the
technique correctly. Like Dennis Seaver,
he does it correctly. Fuck
Gaydos. When that guy throws it,
that motherfucker extends and you never
know what's coming because he'll throw
that shit only like once
or twice in a fight.
Him have similar builds for that kick
though the toy. He's so good at it. No,
because my friend Larry Jones had a
better turning side than me. How bad.
It was like six foot three, six foot
four somewhere around then and he was,
he fought it. Heavyweight in
taekwondo tournament's Larry.
I was always short but Larry was always,
he had these ridiculous legs.
They would go up to his tits and he
would throw this front leg side kick like
you couldn't fuck with it.
It was the reason I developed my front
leg side because the way I developed,
cause my friend Larry,
his is way superior to mine.
There was like three guys that had these
vicious front lake sidekicks and Conor
Mcgregor almost, right? No, no way
better. Way better than, he's pretty good.
He's good with it.
But have you seen guys who've been doing,
telling you there was just one
of the guys that can break?
They break your insides man,
because they use it as they use
it as defense as you come in,
they'll time at and and use your body
as you move in. Dealt, dealt back.
You have all the other stuff.
They're just missing all the other stuff.
Akiyama keeps getting hit with this head
kick, man. This left high kick. Yeah,
but Amir's just like just grazing them
with, I know you're not committed to it.
My friend Leroy Rodriguez was,
he had kicks front leg kicks that we're
so fucking fast when people would spar
him, like when he was in his
prime, he was like one of uh,
Jay Kim's top black belts,
right. He tagged and ice,
right. Akiyama has got a vicious
right hand man heavy. Oh, this dude,
him and Larry Jones, this other
dude, his name was major battle.
That was his real name.
Larry Leroy. Major black.
Don't fuck with Larry Lee Baker battle.
Meanwhile,
three of the nicest guys
you'd ever want to meet.
And Leroy is still a good
friend to this day. But if you,
you saw those guys throw front leg kicks,
it would change your whole idea of what's
possible with those things. Oh, oh,
he's her. Oh No, I'm here's in trouble.
Oh Amir. Still throwing that kick.
He got tagged again.
Tough man.
He's just Amir's pretty good at keeping
guys off to them when he's getting
tagged about this.
He's got to get some distance
here to the ground and pound man.
But look at mears.
Got The heat on the hips,
but those judo guys are always
so good standing up there.
He's got him dead to rights
here. Look at this. Oh,
this new miracle throwing up
some not gonna work. Oh Man.
Yeah. I said, oh you guys
put words on your shorts.
Fuck that took this picture
of a watch out. Huh?
I've gold skin bitches.
I got gold skin picture isn't one check
on my Dick. It's right between your legs.
Herat to the sun. God, I'm a Ratu
has chosen me to be his messenger.
Boom. My point when I moved out to when
I was talking about these cakes shop,
you got long ass fucking legs.
You could throw some vicious kicks.
If you ever met my friend Larry who was
about your size and you saw with that
guy can do with his front leg.
He would fold bags in half with his
front leg side kick. Just shooting.
Just shooting. Chris Extend, you know,
he's big black guy and just long
fucking legs and just extend.
Oh,
folding back on foot sidekick.
He would kick box guys and do to it
never faced together at a front leg like
that. They had no idea what
to do with them. Right.
They couldn't figure out how to get in
on them really hard and maybe the problem
with it though is what it was all being
developed when there was no leg kicks.
So I think I a good Thai guy,
we just started attacking his legs and
it would limit a lot of the techniques
you could pull off.
But those guys were all above the waist
kickboxers and he was fucking them up.
And all that tells me is that that's
a technique that's not being utilized.
Well good up kicks by Amir Talos
use pancakes though. They do.
Some of those guys do, especially the
guys, the more Thai guys from Holland,
you don't make shit up.
Badr Hari that motherfucker throws
wheel kicks and I thought, hey,
you're going to raise a fighter
from the time he's five and on,
it's almost better to get
him into taekwondo early,
selling him to get them used to the
aerials at all the fancy crazy questions.
And then at 12 get them into Muay Thai.
So He'd be different distance.
He'll still throw the and distances and
it's a two different techniques like,
yeah, but it's not so, so if you had a
five year old and you had to train them,
what do you start them with? Taekwondo.
Yeah, because he's not a mastic.
It's also you're going to,
you're going to develop the dexterity
for those weird moves that are super
dangerous when you get really good
at them, right? Like you know,
any always equates, oh look, it's the
dog gets out from the back door almost.
Is he out? I might get into Jujitsu that
five. Well, Eddie always equates it.
That's not a bad call either.
But Eddie always equate it to like
rubber guard techniques because like if
someone,
if you teach someone rubber guard
techniques and it's the first time they've
tried it, like, oh, this shit isn't
going to work. I'm not flexible enough.
Well that's the same thing.
If you show someone a wheel kick,
can you tell me the wheel
kicks never going to work.
Hold the pad for a guy like Barboza hold
the pad and let him, we'll kick you.
Right. And you hit that pat and you
go, Oh shit, I need to know this. Yep.
Forces is a Pi's opponent to really focus
on that and take time away from other,
you gotta be terrified of that wheel kick.
You got to be terrified of all of his
catch part of the training camp to stay
away from that move away
from those fucking crazy kid
every day they're going to
be dealing with it. Yeah.
Stop Two fucking guys in the,
in the UFC with leg kicks.
I mean his kicks are brutal.
First John Jones is doing Jon Jones.
I would suggest,
and I don't know shit cause
I've never fun. I mean,
but I would guess I would hypothesize to,
if you want to be a striker or you want
to be a fighter rather, and the UFC,
if you're interested in
fighting in the UFC and, and,
and challenging for the belt one day
do a Jon Jones is doing as far as uh,
everything on your feet, including
the wrestling it and the striking,
especially he's stolen everything.
Jon Jones is throwing every,
the spinning back,
spinning back,
elbows turn inside kicks
come food kicks in.
There's not a kick that he hasn't thrown,
gave me that.
Maybe the jumps spinning
inside crescent kick.
We really haven't seen that one. Only in
Jackie Chan movies. That's the last kick.
That's the last of the
kicks. Well, you know,
there's a car spinning crest and kicked.
That's really effective.
Do you know what I'm talking about
when you're coming in with this side?
We haven't seen that one. It doesn't, it
doesn't work too much for me. At least.
Didn't work too much this way.
Like the inside crest kick
I gave up on a long time.
But if you heard a guy
standing and he's kind of,
and then you finish
with that motherfucker.
Have you ever just because of the angle,
have you ever seen me do a
spinning crescent kick? I
never showed you that. Yeah,
you showed me everything. I'm
sure. No, I bet I haven't.
It's like you hit like this with
the outside of the foot like that.
You Spit Sima knock out with that either.
We haven't seen an asset with that.
It's a close range kick. It's a weird
kick. You do it from a different range.
I never did it,
but my friend Ed shorter was really
good at my friend Ed shorter knocked out
guys with that.
He had a wicked spinning crescent kick.
He would throw that and more than
he would throw the wheel kick.
But it was an awkward, I think Jon Jones
throws everything except those I don't,
I think we still have those are the last
new kick I think was to make a a big
impact in all of them in
May and how everyone trains
is that front snap kick and
the rear snap kick right to the jar,
right to the chest.
Travis bound be thrown them.
I know you've been studying that shit.
And also Josh Thomson throws him a
la a lot so Rony throws him a lot.
And of course cocoon.
No is known for that Shit.
Just so now that is the hottest
kick right mass. The newest,
hottest kicked that people are actually
spending time trying to master it.
When before there was no special time
spent for that front snap kick butt.
Now what's real and oh we haven't
talked about that on video.
That's the craziest thing we talked
about a years ago. Like they asked you,
I asked you in your gym. I
said, why have we haven't?
We seen the front snap kick to the
fucking jaw and then you add you,
you said some great shit about it
and then boom. That's when Anderson,
that was the first one in the Machida
on unknown Radica tour and then now
everyone's fucking throwing them and
then you board Travis Browne on Alistair
Overeem. Yeah. You know what? I think
the next one is the ax kick acts.
Hicks are very effective. We don't
really see him. Totally home throws him.
There was this guy, this
Canadian guy, his name was jersey
long and that was one of the reasons why
I realized how effective and powerful
acts kicks where.
There's this Guy John Lee who had a
really good ass kick who was a national
taekwondo champion.
I have only seen it a number of men
because we haven't seen a guy who's really
good at it.
There's a guy named Jersey long that
was from Canada and he had a fucking axe
kick that was like a rifle shot.
It would just,
it would be up in on your job before you
knew it was happening. He just had this,
he would be concern and he would just
step in full split and slam you on the
head with that heel in Jesus.
He knocked my friend Larry Jones,
I'll cold or maybe in the beginning Larry
my friend that I was telling you how
good he is. That's the guy got knocked
out cold by Law by this Guy Jersey Long.
You know we seen any in k one a
few times but no. Well Andy Hook,
Sandy Hook and I,
Andy Hook had also had a technique we
haven't seen the spinning wheel kick to
the leg hug was the master at that. He
would never take that heel into the leg.
It was a straight movie Kung Fu kick
where he would get down, squat down,
do like a spinning at break dancing moves
and do a wheel kick to the guys thigh.
A low we'll kick. It's like doing a
wheel kick butt almost on your ass.
So dollar trying to set something up.
What?
What was the greatest crazy
movie technique of all time?
I say it was real CHONe and submitted
Anderson Silva with that fucking flying
trying or the Friday,
I think that was like the greatest all
time movie technique in an MMA fights
happened in uh, in grappling. Yeah.
But in like fighting Anderson Silva and
an MMA fight. True. And your real CHONe an
underdog. The guy at shoot the
box, he caught him in good time.
Anderson wasn't it shoot the box
anymore? You know, they had like a,
he was at Anderson Anderson at the
time though. No, he wasn't quiet.
He wasn't quite the match before me and
Hoya went the first time in 2003 he went
against a guy named Charles Pierce and
the match right before me and that guy
did his fucking flat,
the exact same heel hook that reader
CHONe entrain Anderson and almost had him,
he almost tapped out. Hoya, Gracie.
A lot of people don't know that.
Heuler escaped by the skin of his teeth
and then got us back and then choked
them. Oh my God. Since the fight. Since
you're talking all the time. Okay. Yeah.
We hang out party and shit.
Just checking
the guard. Oh, you weren't
here for the guard talk.
Eddie Bravo has the weirdest
sense of humor. Man sneaks things.
Talk About Eddie Bravo.
No bullshit.
If he wasn't such a great Jujitsu
fighter and he wasn't so into music,
great troll, he would be a
great fucking comedian. He just,
he just didn't have the time to get into
it. I talked to him and going on stage.
You went downstairs like
eight or nine times.
Really Dick a few times whatever workout.
Oh, he stopped. I had this two week.
He my one. He dominated though.
Robbie get on top. Did they just
send the fight and the fight?
I've been watching it though.
I've been watching a little worse.
Missing the vital.
Imagine if the fucking I like
the UFC said, listen man,
we've been thinking about your commentary.
We heard you've been doing this fight
pass thing. You're fucking terrible
fights. Brian's stands
doing these all from now on.
Oh see that was good movement
by Akiyama very relaxed.
Even though the head kick was
coming just slid out of the way.
Nice right hand just dominated this.
He's such a stud athlete,
but see that like that's like
some blue belt shit. Yeah,
but that's also on a moving
target. You know, he's also,
he's tossed it and he's fine. Yeah,
he's fighting an MMA fight. It just,
that's the one technique that I
think this that I'm telling you man,
there's gonna be some Francis Karmapa
dude who knows how to throw a fucking,
actually they cut friends
believe it one by one.
All the every a Kung Fu kick that
was once laughed at the one by one.
They're all coming back. I'm telling
you, that guy's Levy. Some Kung Fu.
It's all coming back. I won a type
one term taekwondo tournament with
all those comfort food kits
branded shop.
Could you imagine if you fucking axe
kicked Travis Brown and the head,
do you imagine how nutty the world would
go if you had the first ax kick Kao in
the UFC?
You step in and six six can catch
him crazy with this fee for Brennan.
Shop fucking goes nuts.
You decide for six months to just really
dive into kicks and you want to in six
months,
you want to transform yourself into this
fucking vicious kicker when that'd be
crazy.
She could do it from your response
time for that shit real trainer.
You found the right
trainer who can teach you,
teach you that style of kicking dude,
you'd be, you'd be fucking guys up it up.
How are you having your legs?
I've seen you.
I've seen you lift weights
or senior do dead lifts,
all these things you're doing,
what are you building?
You're building up your core, your,
your, your, your whole column,
but you're also building up
your SAP bottoms. Ridiculous.
And then our Paul Barman is launching
bones and your opponent just launching,
but bones
launching shin bones.
Like if there's one bone you wouldn't
want to get hit in the fucking face with.
It's the shinbone number one
terrible blade of a bone.
That's the one bonus shaped like a weapon.
All of these other ones
are covered up with meat.
Even an elbow like you got to catch a
motherfucker on the point of an elbow to
otherwise you're hitting him with a
forearm smash and there's a lot of meat
involved in the forum smashed when
you shinned someone to the dome.
That's up fucking, that's
a weird edged bone, man.
This is a weird feeling to
that fucking comes at you.
Six miles an hour on your head.
WOMP womp womp.
Spain from such an intense grumpy fuck.
Who really knows how to kick hard,
dude, man. Oh,
some scary fucker.
Just throwing these laser
beam through your head.
I'm telling you,
anybody who doubts me,
you just needed to see Pedro
his own in his prime. Brian,
where'd you get those golden
pickles from there? They're good,
right?
Many, many jars in there. Grillo's
pickles are very generous.
He sent me a giant fucking case of them.
They're the best pickles of all. Tada.
So real quick is the latest I've
stayed up in Oh, about 10 years, dude,
you're going to be since
college. Oh yeah, I'll be fine.
It's only two o'clock in the morning.
I know she got training tomorrow.
We're in California. God did double
today to make up. If you were in Hawaii,
we'd only be 11:00 PM that's how
you got to look at Shit, man.
We should all be in Hawaii right
through that door. There's a curtain.
Pull that back and go to the, there
you go. We should all be in Hawaii.
Let's be realistic.
If we could all make a choice to bail and
go to one place and bring our families.
Everybody exists. It probably be like
the big island. I'd be wanting to.
I want to be Bj Penn's neighbor. I
love it. Just all hang out together.
Maybe we do during the
day just hanging out. No,
can't do that shit. Said wives.
We're married. We're kidding.
What I think we would do is have a good
time by the water. Be With our families.
Did you guys collide
by the way he that
rumor a Brennan.
There's a rumor that when he does
the title Udo fucking Hawaii.
That's what I'm saying.
Know we had due to some, ah,
we won't do that.
What are you saying?
You guys can put mask on and watch me how
I was there a few months
ago. Shit. Oh Miles Jones.
Oh Shit.
This uh,
this dude was telling me that he got to
go there like in March or April to the
big island.
He said that's when the whales,
they're either breeding or giving birth.
I don't remember which,
but he said they're everywhere.
You said it's almost dangerous
to be out in your boat. Wow.
Cause you were out in the boat and the
whales will breach like 20 yards from you.
Blues guy was killed. My shell both that
way. Killed on a sale book. I was a pussy.
I would have saw the way, I wouldn't
have panicked when a dove in the water,
the shore
holding,
nobody yelled help because their ears
are really good and they would have come
by. Here's the trivia question.
We've already asked them.
How much has a blue whales heart way?
Same as my dad.
He put my Dick next to a
blue whales close on a scale.
It would balance out blue owls.
Heart weighs 1500 pounds.
That's about what my Dick was close.
That's about all my dick is made out of
dark matter. Call me fought Nick Diaz,
right? Yeah. Yeah. You fought Nate,
Nate and nick.
Both of them lit him up.
Nate, Nate, Nate lit him up with strikes.
Then I believe Carmen and arm bar and
a nick caught him with a Google. Duh.
How big of a star was go me back in the
nic test. It's so high for marijuana.
They believe he might've been high
while he was fighting. Oh No. Oh yes.
He Won. You know, people
were arguing like, oh,
you know that the pain that he got
when he got hit with those shots,
he didn't feel it because
he was high on marijuana.
That's the one thing that
you have to argue like, well,
marijuana is prescribed for
pain. I mean, it is true,
right? I mean, I would imagine it
would help you or does it absorb pain?
You guys still the manage
knows the Mary Jane,
but I was borrowing when
I was doing kickboxing. I
wasn't smoking weed back then.
I didn't, I didn't. I've never felt was
true. Everybody. It'd be high fight,
but they can't. They get
tested, everybody gets tested.
That doesn't make any sense but getting
punched in the face hard with a right.
I don't think he's going to help you
with that. It helps if you nick Diaz.
I Bet Nick Diaz gets in there lit up.
I bet he doesn't give a fuck.
Fuck anyway,
they wouldn't be fighting but on the off
Nick Diaz Eat your jab sober or high.
A lot of guys don't like to
train technique high though.
It's kind of interesting.
They say they don't learn things is good
high like when someone's trying to show
you like a stutter step and an attack.
Like sometimes I get a little bit twisted
up but when they can just flow with
what they know once it's in the DNA,
that's where the weed comes in because
when you're high muscle memory work on
instincts way you flow,
but when you're not high it's there's,
there's glitches here and there because
you have so too much shit on your mind.
You're thinking about some bits. When
I smoked some weed and drank some wine.
I actually say 10 years ago
I came up with some bits.
Are you saying that as
if it's a new thing?
That's how you do comedy and you go on
stage. Do you come up with new shit?
You're ridiculous. That's
hilarious. Hey Bro,
I was just saying, because I'm
about to, I'm not this Sunday.
What happened this Sunday? I'm doing
my one hour. Come on down. When he's,
when he survived him for, he said
he was high bacon, new stuff.
I said was that 10 years ago? Are you
saying no? Right? Being mean to you
like somebody to stand up,
stand up about 60 times.
Yeah.
I'm saying if I come down to Irvine
on Sunday and I see old Gato, he shot,
got to do. First of all, don't kill my
friends confidence. It's about to go.
I can't kill my second. Don't bring up.
Don't bring up the nature of his bits,
which we'll fucking ruined them for the
thousands of people that listen to this
podcast, so let's not just
that either. You're working,
working thematically. So my one
hour you'll see completed new stuff.
Told him to be there then
you'd be there.
Just makes my dick hard.
I feel conflict between you two guys does
this because of the [inaudible] invite
me to dinner tonight. What?
Didn't you have a sense that bro,
you told me how to set man.
You live in Phoenix and 11 bro.
I don't get calls anymore. You guys
still friends? I'm in camp though. Yeah,
but my fields. Oh, now he's in camp. He
isn't camp though. You can't get needy.
These are the guys I know. It's
weird. When he gets in camp,
we asked to be the end of it.
I know. He knows I'm, I'm,
I'm really not in camp. Yep,
we can. You do though. You, they
tell you, you got to find anyone the,
and a hard time for chewing on Mike
and Allen wants too. And I'm like,
Oh yeah. It was like a fucking job
was giving him the hardest time,
but he was chewing right into that
fucking my like 35 years old. Yes, he is.
I deep throated these hot ass
pickles are delicious. They are.
I'm not into that. You want to
pickle those tastes like cock.
We're out. Almost tastes like Cutco.
Yeah, we're out. These are writing.
I'm not a fan of these. These are the
sea salt. Pop pop's, those pickles,
heaven. Those pickles are the
best ever. I don't they good cone.
You know what though?
When you chew on a pickle though,
the mix is going to pick it up.
They're so fucking crunchy and fresh
like you should go in the other room.
I can be. I can hear that shit. I wish
we had some of them. Sriracha cashews.
God dammit right now. I
could go for it. Ron Pickles,
those kinds of warrior bar here. I'm
that getting rid of shit. No Man.
All we have
pickles and Stevia.
I mean door to a pizza. I
wouldn't, I wouldn't yell at you.
I don't think the pizzas are going to
deliver at two o'clock in the morning,
brother, where we live in in New
York City. We're in the valley.
Sun Shit's shuts down.
I live in Venice son.
There's two in the morning or your
studio is kind of scary looking.
Of course it is charged. Scared is
a werewolf in there. Open the door.
You imagine you deliver a fucking pizza.
You opened the door. See that thing? Yup.
I'm yawning. Yachting. He's working over
everyone. Snacks in this bitch. Well,
I got a new nature box coming this week,
naturebox.
Do you guys worry the bars tastes like
a sweet or what? No, no, no, no. Well,
it's cranberry and buffalo dude.
It's super healthy for you.
140 tastes like it tastes good.
It tastes like a beef jerky type bar.
But if church
more fresh, there's,
there's no artificial. Um,
it's like there's no
artificial preservatives.
There's no artificial sweeteners.
No, no, no. There's nothing.
There's nothing artificial in
it. And it's brand new. Right.
We've had it for a couple months.
They would look and tell you exactly
what's in it, but there's no cranberries.
The bill, they sent me 10 of them in
a box. I hate him in two days. Yeah.
I felt sick. I felt sick. Eight
10, 14, 14 grams of protein,
140 calories. Jamie, go grab another
bottle of them. Brent get one man.
They're um,
they're really,
or bars or something really good
for you to only two grams of fat,
140 calories, 14 grams protein.
Just super healthy. And they,
that's how they used to preserve them.
I guess.
They used to use cranberries and sea salt
when they used to have to get sea salt.
Man,
these to have to take salt water from the
ocean and Cecil and actual fucking sea
salt. That's what do they do now? But
they still call it sea salt, right?
I mean some of it is sea salt.
Some of it is I. Dot. I mean,
some of it is made in the lab,
I guess.
I don't know how the fuck they make
salt as a stone. I know the Himalayan,
oh, miles. Jury, he's fucked. He's,
Oh, it's all, it's all, it's over.
Damn miles jury with a big
good man with a big win.
It hasn't lost yet. The kid keeps getting
better too. He's putting in the work,
man. He's putting the work. He drinks
down there. Had a alliance and San Diego,
Huh? Yeah. That's a big Kale. He has
a Jiu Jitsu gym too and San Diego.
Mild jury does phone shit.
No Shit. What happened there?
The black belt in Jujitsu? Yeah. Oh
yeah. Yeah. Just was his strong point.
He's just a nasty as Stryker to Damion.
He's a tall kid. Look at this lead,
this good move. Very
smart fighter. Bang. Oh,
that was why it's right hand.
Oh. Oh, you can do well,
go me as this weird kind of striker.
He's a knockout puncher, but he's like,
everything is home runs.
It's all home runs and it just doesn't
seem like he's setting things up in any
way by a little bit.
Let's be honest.
But is it the game passing by or is he
not as fired up as he was when he was
younger? He doesn't have the body
that he had when he was younger.
Two
armored cars.
Grub fucking
pickles are in town.
The hot ones too.
Do y'all like the hut?
They got like hub and arrows and shit
and if you've got balls eat those.
I have to eat the pickles, digging.
They're powerful miles. Jury.
The kids really impressed me.
Undefeated. Me Too. Super impressive.
He's gonna be tough to beat.
Yes. Just is really good at it.
Oh Damn.
11 first round fitness.
It's inquiry.
These pimples are not easy to
get into line to be honest.
He wants the English tough.
I forget
he was, no, no, no, no. He's just a
beast from San Diego. From Cali Kid.
Yeah.
Stimulus.
No.
Oh Shit.
You confusing him with Dan
Hardee cause they're both sexy
and I had one. The fucker right there.
Fuck Yeah Dude. Look at this movement man.
Very nice. Look at this setup for this.
She's is moving. It's Diego Sanchez.
We did good. I am good ground and
pound him. That was his first big win.
The Diego San Doz,
he put,
he's putting a lot of weight behind those
punches to a lot of length and a lot
of weight. Diego was his first
big win. He outclass Diego.
It's a good fight, man. Practice.
I am crucified. I don't,
you shouldn't be giving this
up on the air. Oh, okay.
Trash brand can text me if he wants.
Look,
it's really the only thing to get like
go counter act that ground and pound from
the horse stance position.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. What we do, you gotta be,
you gotta be really good. Yeah.
That's the perfect spot for him to
avoid submissions and be able to throw
punches and say stay standing on your
feet and squats cause you could reach the
face and right there there's
no submissions. But the only,
the only thing you got to
worry about is I up kicks. Yup.
Cause you're in a perfect
spot for an upkick. So you,
you would think that most MMA fighters
would work on that? Yeah, we do.
There's levels man.
Cause you know as I,
I still haven't seen anybody throw kicks
off their back as hard as hoists and
I'll tell you what man, Harry
Crow cops, fricking nasty.
Adam hit me with a UPC cake to my knee
and to the face. It was like boom, boom.
You would think a kickboxer
would be the best at them. Right?
It was literally like that movie a
rush hour. Which one are off kicked me.
It was like,
oh well you know who the first guy was
to kick really good off of his back?
The one of the most impressive
early today. Henzel Gracie
gets all tech tar off.
Remember him,
he k owed him for his back and then stood
up and blasted him in the face of the
punch and broke his hand.
Do you remember the story in that part?
That was bare knuckle.
The story was nobody like Hanzo actually
practiced up kicks to get really good
at them and move Bustamante Bustamante
thought cause I guess there were clothes.
Thought it was a waste of time. You're
not son until, oh, pulled it off.
March person had strikes. Dude,
is that to your head? No, no.
That's delivering son to him.
I'm 300 attempts.
Not a big deal. It's whatever. Not
bad brother. We got work to do.
My man's in shape. I'll
go train right now, son.
I got from her bell share.
Don't tempt to brother.
I'm all hyped up on fucking bulletproof
coffee and a bait about 17 hot pickles.
I'm either going to shit my pants
and get a workout in the bowl.
You picked gentlemen,
both. Both make you sweat.
He says nights here and an
archery target we can take.
That dude is you get in the bows
and arrows or what not. Hey,
I thought you were gonna make fun
of me when we went to your house.
I got someone went to your house
and you release those chickens.
I'll scare the shit, the
chickens. I told my brother,
I told my brother and my prayer, my
friend club was like, fuck man, a
brilliant elisos chickens. I was scared
as fuck, but I was trying to act tough.
I'm not, I'm not used to
like wild animals released.
Those chickens are scared as fuck,
man. I'm starting to develop a farm.
That's my first step. My first
step is having all these chickens.
I got like 24 chickens. I think it'd
be nice. I want to do it personally,
but I think ultimately the best move
would be, and I said this before,
the best move would be if like friends,
you know Uriah Faber, he lives,
he lives on a corner. All these
houses, they own the whole corner,
the whole neighborhood.
It's like you a neighborhood.
So dope move you and your homeys.
If,
if someone could figure out how we
could all do something like that.
You write on paper all of this family,
well Uriah Faber has his own house but
Chad Mendez lives right next to them and
you ride owns a few mounts it to all
of them. It's all his training camp.
Holbys in his friends live in the same,
they call it the block.
It's a brilliant idea.
So they have like this whole area where
they're all like they'd go grilling
together,
they have parties,
they have people come over
and this super friendly dudes.
So it's like a real warm,
fun environment and all this comradery.
They all live together like that.
And I've always felt like that would be
the best thing if like all of our yards
board each other. And then you
fucking grow vegetables together.
That would be dope. When I
was a kid, when I was a kid,
when I was a kid, my dad was in this
thing, my stepfather was in this,
um oh it was like a cooperative thing
in school and they would grow plants
together and they would all work.
It was a in the university and they
would all grow like a bunch of different
plans. I remember going there and thinking
this is what a great idea this is.
Like everybody would
contribute like some days.
I keep brought me down there on like a
Tuesday and I remember it very clearly
because it's goat attacked
me is fucking male goat.
Like I was hanging out with little man
and it was like seven years old and it's
fucking gold starts headbutting me and
I'm grabbing the goat and I'm freaking
out. And then he came over and Jack
to goat and like get the fuck up,
bitch pushed the female go
started attacking me when
I was holding onto the mail
go cause she decided I was the enemy.
I've been nearly as fucking cunt.
I had been feeding her just a few
minutes ago. Yeah, I remember.
So I remember it very clearly
that I remember this thing like,
like what a great idea to have
like a bunch of vegetables
like grown right there.
And if you do that and
you've got chickens, just
vegetables and chickens. Joe,
you got days of food? Yeah, I'm, I'm, I'm,
I'm done for the chickens and vegetables.
All that shit. How about we just get a
bunch of bad ass cars. We like share cars.
We get girls as girls.
There's drugs.
There's also someone's already retired.
That's when wait till you retire
as they say, but not in Calabasas.
Will the steward,
when did Michael Bernard deejaying
argue what I'm thinking right now.
So does she forget your own hair?
Fucking slick.
Dj tide mark over look shots.
He looks good on the tables that Pakistan.
What is that?
The Mgm Mike's head.
He looks like he was taking a nap.
Dare you? I'm just saying head phones.
He doesn't have the luxury of the shape.
A color a DJ now I can't say not sweet.
Got there yet.
[inaudible] guys like Michael,
cause a sweetie.
Oh he's a good guy. We were talking
about, we talked about this before.
Yeah we were,
it was weren't on air.
We were talking about Mark Hunt Big
foot and the difference between what the
kind of punishment that big foot
was able to take in that fight,
which is incredible.
And then his last fight with her Lawsky
two shots and he's down or are you
talking about when he's off to you
or to yeah. Oh yeah. It's crazy.
Crazy advantage.
It gives guys,
is that the case or is it just the case
of the standard thing of seeing guys
just have Daniel Cormier, he knocked him
out. You know, there's a bunch of fights.
He's taken a lot of damage in fights.
Cain Velasquez fucked him up in his
last fight. I'm just saying man,
when when you're on TRT and fighting
down in Australia and you're eating right
and left hamstring Mark Hunt and then you
fight in Brazil off tot he get knocked
out. One Punch. God, it's a good
argument man. It's not saying it is,
but it's a fucking good argument
kind of. But isn't it also, look,
the are lost face several times during
feel shit. You know what I'm saying?
But big foot's been taking punishment
before. It's weird men. Right,
but isn't it true though
that like sometimes you get
punched in the face and you
just getting punched like on the
cheek? Sure. Egan, he punched here.
It's placement man.
You can get one tank like across the tip
of the Chin and that the legs just go.
It's not even the chance.
Most of the time it's behind the ear on
the side of the head or behind the ear
that's observed. Marshall got tagged
tonight. She got hit in the year.
Marshall got hit there
when DC fought big foot.
He tagged behind the Cain Velasquez
got hit behind the air against jds.
I got him behind the air
against a big or big country.
It's all about placement,
man. Big countries.
Really good at that looping right hand
and land's best casting style. Right?
I Lens and a lot of different ways.
If I was a betting man and I had,
you made me pick,
I would say Roy is going to
land that he's going to wobble,
hunt that he's going to take them down.
Tkl Wow, that's crazy. The second round,
do you remember when Roy was just
a grappler? It was a long time ago.
Wouldn't any and I first
met a long time ago at, no,
really doesn't use it anymore.
It's crazy.
It's crazy because the dude didn't
even start striking into 2009 when I
interviewed him in the boom.
I got fucking hard. He hits.
Oh God. When I interviewed
mentality, he's not ferocious.
His Chin is iron granite chin.
The only time he's been stopped
as our Lawsky Scott stomped him.
I think that's the only time,
and that was a ridiculous
situation because he had
our Lawsky down immerse site
control and they smelled him up.
It was ridiculous. It was pathetic.
But see, he didn't even start striking
till 2009 I mean, think of that.
He's knocked out. No Garren knocked
out mitre own, you see knocked out
Dave Herman there. There's
took, should that mean though?
That was a those Congo boom. Look
at that right hand. Boom, left hook,
boom dude. This is the,
now he's also a smart fight.
So when the going gets rough in this
fight and they're trading bombs,
hunt has to keep trading. What's I'm
going to do? Take them down. Nope. We,
Roy can't take them now was going
to say fuck this. Abandoned ship.
Emergency Brake. Boom, I'm
taking you down. Right.
I can win the fight but just says,
Nah, you gotta keep throwing you far.
What's the difference? He the hardest
hitter you've ever fought. No.
Well it's tough be Shane's the
hardest you've ever been hit us.
Roy hit me behind the ear. Roy landed
three right hands to or straight on.
I didn't feel anything like we
said, plays in, hit me here.
Hit me here than the one I turned on.
The Jab hit me behind the ear
and that was the ending shot.
So I really didn't feel it. He's so
good at. But if you look case by case,
Roy has to be the hardest hitter. You
know what I'm saying? It's amazing.
It's amazing. Leverage is the leverage.
And the way throws that right hand,
just reckless is shit and all the power
and also this fucking confidence in his
chin.
I mean junior dos Santos hit him with
everything but the fucking kitchen,
Sam Dume dude, he thought he was
doing fine. Eaten those knees.
He was like, that guy never
hurt me and he's a fucking
tough though. [inaudible] everyone
here loves Roy at some point.
That crazy durability chin.
It could be this fight,
it could be 10 fights from now. It
just goes away. It's like Oh shit.
Or he is just that country motherfucker
that you hear about that lives up in the
mountain and chops wood with his face
and doesn't give a fuck one 70 I think I
want to know like that though is their
faith. You think feto would be that guy,
right? He can fight. He can fight one
70 if not all. Not caring. I mean Sally,
but I mean he's got,
he's got a lot of weight on him.
Well he's weighing about like what is,
he went in to two CC to 60 is it possible
that beard could absorbs punishment?
No. No. Is it possible otherwise
Kimbo slice to be the channel.
You know what I'm saying?
I'll do that
train with my like guilty. I'm like,
ugh. Jheri curl over your hand.
I mean he has got that.
There's no reason Kimbo slice had the
best look of all time and nicest fighter.
I know the greatest
guy says my sweetheart.
You know what I'm having on my podcast,
man, can you see Alexander art?
You have a kid cutting. I'm having
kid Cuddy and huge. Me and my brother,
huge kid Cuddy fence. He's and he
sits down. He say big brown loves Ya.
I'm going to tell him, you know I
even walked out to one of his songs.
If he's cool, Ooh, I'll tell him, tell
him. I'll tell him I'm around a shadow.
I'll walk out to one of the
song. I'll tell him on Monday,
man, it's God. He's good.
Yeah, he's good, but I'm going
to get Houston Alexander on too.
He's another motherfucker.
God get some power.
Are talking about styles make slight.
How about when Houston Kimbo slot,
everyone was like, oh shit, this
will be the fight of the century.
What are the fall by you? Actually
this was, it was a tough fight.
It was so boring and they bought no
one committee because they both have
knockout. Power is weird. How about when
you used to Alexander? Fuck Keith Jardeen.
Nobody knew who he was.
Oh, I know cod. Ooh,
Zander can got mark Hunt's a scary dude,
man.
And he's familiar in Japan.
Listen, he's a star in Japan.
[inaudible] champion. He's fought some
of the best of the best of all time.
If you have a tattoo on your neck,
do not talk shit to again,
it looks like in the next chapter. House
slept good crowds. It's a good point.
That's a good,
that's a legit point.
There's a lot of guys in
Venice with dirty feet,
neck tattoos and like fucking all skinny.
I'm just saying mark on his
and gnarliest head. He's just,
I think that's his son's name,
whatever.
I'm pretty sure that's his son's name
that he had written in Kanji on his neck.
You don't mean I'm always coming
up with schemes or you know,
something to get a guy to fight me.
I want this big fight. And with hunt,
we're talking shit back
and forth. I said, fuck it.
Let's put our fight purses online. I
when I get all your money, you win.
You get all mine thinking he'd
be like, Nah. He was like, cool,
cool man. Uh, we'll ask Dana.
No. You know, knowing damn
well Dan's, we'll ask Dana.
We'll see how it goes. You know,
he shut that shit down. Well,
didn't have gangs. Just offer that to
Luke. Rockhold stole paid to shops.
Book Gay did. Yeah, me and busy and
talked about that. Yeah. Bisping,
he was being really funny about it too.
Since since I get paid about five
times more true. Able to me, bro.
Let's talk about this though.
Mark. I'm really excited.
I can't wait for this fight. Let's
talk about marketing real quick though.
Just a couple of years ago,
if you remember, he got
taken down by Krista usher.
He lost a McCorkell by some economists,
emotional calmness,
McCargo economist submission.
He went to that weird fight
in Denver with Rothwell were,
they call it the worst heavyweight
fight of all time. So you're like, damn,
Mark Hunt is not doing well. Look
at this mother fucking now. Yup.
Killing the game, right. Killing the game.
Well that Rothwell fight man was in
Denver and if you don't live in Denver,
good luck fighting in Denver.
She weighed 260 pounds. Listen,
if you're not in shape in New Zealand,
when you get to Denver,
you're also not going to be in shape.
If you're not in shape in California,
when you fly to Florida,
your fat ass still ain't in shape.
I used to fly train partners in and
they'd be crazy out of shape bra.
This altitude, not your fetish
shit bro. No, it doesn't matter.
Where'd you come from? Jacksonville.
Yeah, you're fat and Jacksonville.
You know what I'm saying?
Drive me nuts.
Is how disappointing must that be for
professional athletes like they come in
professional athletes to work with
you and their shape, like the kind of,
we would send them home the next day.
What'd you beat it? Nerd. Go kick rocks.
Get eat it nerd.
So don't they say that the best to do it
is to sleep at sea level and trained it
out too? They say like no living in East
San Bernandino. Yes, that's what I meant.
Yeah. Train, train it where there's
no altitude and then sleep. Why?
Because your body, you get the
harder work rate in at sea level.
Plenty oxygen reps, the more energy
exerted because you're not, you know,
you're not struggling but
there is a benefit to living
end training up there but
it's not as much of a benefit as
sleeping up there. But training is you.
I used to train it awfully high
altitude and live at high altitude.
I feel 10 times better
living in California.
I get better training in my body.
Recovers Better. I do eat better.
Do you out [inaudible] in La Roxanne,
how are you getting?
Very sorry man. They'll
sprinkles. Got me crunk shit.
I'm also going to shit my pants
and he said it's also the,
there's a Hob and arrows and I know I
drank seven cups of coffee. Do you like?
If you were going to fight in Denver,
would you go to Denver and prepare?
Kind of have to, right.
You know what? But Joe, uh,
Joe Silva said he's never going to put
heavy weights on debit card again because
of the thanks Rothwell and
Hon. Thanks. Thank you sir.
It's hard it man, if you're fucking not
mark nine and eight number six in the,
that's a fucking gangster man.
Nine eight five 10 to 64 [inaudible]
that a fellow and you throw nine
touchdowns, eight interceptions. You
don't have a job. I'm just saying. Yeah,
but this isn't the NFL.
This is Mark Hunt. I agree.
It's k one grumpy champion and knocked
out check Congo k one grumpy champion.
Who was the shortest fighter ever?
Like the difference between dot.
This is a good fight and
they look exactly the same.
His fight and Stephan struve site,
it was the most disparity in
size ever in a heavyweight fight.
And Hunt landed a leaping left
hook that destroyed strips, drawl.
And so I'm playing against Caramel.
This is an interesting fight, man.
Very interesting. Hunt. Certainly,
certainly is more weapons, but he's,
he's also disagree.
Disagree.
I don't think coming to stand
up and not saying overall,
I'm saying as a MMA fight. Oh No,
he definitely doesn't. Overall,
he's got more weapons standing up by 100%
but Roy arguably has more power in his
one weapon. That one weapon known
as a, as a good wrestler. He,
he has see his trips.
Yeah,
but Mark Hunt has been working
on as a takedown defense dude.
Mark Cook is from fucking out of space.
Oh, shut. He just, he just tagged Nelson.
Can you imagine it is the first fiber.
See Roy gets stopped like it might be.
He might not be able to take
more cut down. I think Roy's
to smart man. Very good.
It's slipping in and out of shit too.
He's really good at that check hook. Oh,
Roy goes for the take
down early to tell you.
I told my brother on the way down and
I said boys and choose to was a Roy.
He's smart man. Oh, you cut all that
weight. You take them down early in,
they exhaust him. He's not going to
have the same power. Not only that.
Hunt is a very skillful striker.
He's not going to just stand right in
front of you like you see when Roy went to
throw that right hand, Hans slides
right out of the range of shit.
Just out of the range
went up to the worst.
The fight stopped an eye poke in
solid wood in Japan right now.
This entire night would be
ruined. Yeah. Isn't that sad?
At least no one would've gotten hurt.
I fucking hate.
I hate the glove situation, man. I feel
like there's gotta be a way to not.
Oh yeah. He poked him right in the
fucking house till he goes. Sorry.
He said enjoy your victim. One
fucking Huh. It's so disappointing,
man. I mean, nobody means to do it.
You try. That's a Moy Tai thing too.
You know,
they train that with the glove on.
He's all right. He's all right. He's
gonna keep going. Beautiful. Beautiful.
They need to come up with a solution.
Big Brown. What's the solution?
Is it something that covers the
fingertips? Oven Mitts, right.
Condoms of, it's obviously
not. No gloves. No gloves,
no solution at all for that. You have to
have the fingers out, man for grappling.
Yeah, I know. Yeah, but is
it low left kick to the body?
God Damn. He puts some fucking pop
in that when it comes to school.
Oh, he gets angry. Remember Huntsman
code before by Melvin manner?
Yeah, he did do an 18 seconds.
Melvin Manhoef is a motherfucker
straight up. Scary. Meanwhile,
we got a fight with Robbie Lawler so
much faster than he should have been.
He's beaten the show. Rob
Lewis, that leg kick, man,
that's you just get kicked by a
telephone pole. That's not a normal knee.
What kind of knee is that?
The size of that need some serious shit.
He is nice,
but you know what?
If hunts smart and he keeps sliding
towards his right after he lands shots,
he takes away some of the right hand
slide to the right because Roy very rarely
throws lefse. He does. His
left is a measuring device. Me,
he'll throw it like a left
to get you thinking about it,
but that right hand is the bomb with me.
He threw a double jab.
See there's the right, a double jab to
a huge right hand. That's his thing.
He goes, pop, pop, shakes
it, and then big right here.
See the thing about a striker like hunt,
like look how slick he is for a slick.
He's basically 300 pounds right now to
move in like a fucking ballerina. Oh,
and there's a clean right hand he landed.
See that there's a disparity in
technical advantages when hyper tactical
advantage that Marchmont his
movement to his movement is,
but that's also a blue advantage.
Yeah,
100% he knows exactly where he's coming
and look if he avoids the right hand.
See it's just avoiding
the right hand though.
He doesn't have to
worry about knees kicks.
He's just worried about
that right in at his level.
If they go all this guy's a right
hand, he's going go, oh cool.
It's a totally different animal. You're
dealing with a k one grand Prix champion,
but, but now you're talking
about a guy very who
can stick in there and has
better cardio than you maybe.
Who knows who's got better cardio so far,
but right now you just deal with mark.
I mean,
Mark Hyatt was fat,
but it doesn't mean he's out of
shape just because he's 290 pounds.
He could have been starting off at three
40 and gotten really good shape at two
90 and had to cut down to two 65 and
still be able to kick some fucking ass for
three rounds. Fiber apparently. You're
right, it's five rounds. I'm very excited.
When I found out was, I knew it was five
rounds, but I forgot for a second. Oh,
that's what I wanted to talk to you
about water. I Dunno if this is true,
but if it is true. Oh, dumb. Roy got
him with a left hook to the fuck.
Yeah, he did. I'll have someone
said that junior dos Santos,
the steep Emile chick fight.
She requested a three round fight for it.
I hear that. Is that true? I body shot.
Roy heard he wants a three round fight.
Why do you think that is? I don't,
maybe those two fights with Kane,
those fucking horrible five round wars,
man.
Maybe he doesn't want to do that to
his body. If I'm steep am saying nope.
Five rounds.
The other thing that hunt is good
at is rolling with Shit Diff,
but it looks a little tired, not to
me. He doesn't get stiff with stuff.
He roles like when things are coming at
him, he rolls away from things. Yeah.
He takes a lot of the power off of
those punches when he does that.
And for someone who's not used to
a guy that says look like that,
it also Uber Royal, the
leg kicks, spun him around.
It also,
uh,
makes you very tired because you're
decelerating your own punches instead of
hitting something. Yeah. Missing a punch.
It makes you more tired than
actually hidden. So on. Yeah.
When you're fighting to get, let's why
Ali would where guys out so well, yeah.
Cause he would just be
standing in front of them.
They were just be fucking
eaten air sandwiches. Look
at that beautiful movement.
You know what that is,
man, that's just knowledge.
Just knowing where the countries are.
Common sense man.
Okay.
Oh Roylex hold his head. His
head's always in the right spot.
Yeah. Well it's sort of tough if, if
he knows that you have to weapons,
right?
I mean royal,
he hit him with one pretty good leg
kick is pretty good leg kick though. Uh,
not game changing. No, but pretty good.
Now here's a company landed a great left
Hook right hand. That was the, yeah,
there's a nice right hand
and right to the eyeball.
Boom and look slides away.
Boom.
There's one over the top that tag
tomatoes are rolled with it though.
You rolled with the left hook,
but there's a good leg kick,
but then he rolled with that too. Then
you roll around with this, went with it,
but it's like when Roy mixes it up,
anytime a fighter mixes it up,
he opens up all these other possibilities
because he's creates new variables.
If you introduce new variables.
That's why GSP was so good.
He never knew what the
fuck he was going to do.
So that extra half of a second when
you're thinking what is he going to do?
Then he executes something.
Is that an extra half of a second?
It's such an advantage that along with
the comfort level that a guy like GSP had
from all those championship
fights was one of the reasons
that led him to be one of
the great fighters of all
time is that he was so good
at being unpredicted.
You didn't know if he was going to strike
or try to grapple and guys would be
thinking, what's he gonna do? Fuck,
you already did it and then you're
always playing catch up. Yeah.
I talked to Nate Marquardt about that,
who is his main training
partner and he would always say,
you didn't know if he was
to shoot a double leg on
backwards bess levels all four.
It gets them, oh, hi.
They're thick. Look at how
his legs up. Roy is very good.
Oh, it is on my side. He's out.
Oh my goodness. Oh my goodness.
Hunts out and Roy auto adjusts
his knee pad. That's interesting.
What's that about? I think
it was uncomfortable. Yeah,
but I mean, what's up?
What do you think? He's got
a knee injury. Oh, back fist.
That's a big, big moment for hunt,
right? Yeah. Getting up like that.
There's the fact that he could,
he was able to escape, dude.
He's tough to keep down now.
It's, it's all he's training.
It looks like so fucking
strong to look at the back on.
That fucking takes a while to get it all
together. Some people would have quit.
He just kept going and now he's finally,
he's hard to take down and he's got a
little bit of Jujitsu and he's to 90 and
five 10 that helps. Helps
us set up, did it get,
so we're fine for a little bit.
Shit for about 10 minutes.
So we had to cut the two
65 pounds in one day.
They said he lost 19 pounds in one
day. So he's at least, you know,
a solid two 84 solid too.
That's so ridiculous.
It's so ridiculous.
If he got down at two oh five but
meanwhile he fucking moves good.
He moves good. But you know what, Mike
Daltrey made some really good points.
He was talking about Cain Velasquez. He
was like, yeah, he's the best of all time.
Yeah, he's awesome and fade or, yeah,
he was fucking amazing in his prime.
And probably Oh nice,
right hand. But he goes,
he would have been even better if he
lost that. But I disagree. I disagree.
I think you need some body fat.
It listen. And like I said,
we all love Mike Dolce. It's not
a bodybuilding competition. If,
if fate or Cain Velasquez
had both had six packs,
they wouldn't have the same cardio.
That's interesting.
I think you need some of that
fat halfs on that cardio.
But when you're trying to cut weight,
uh, Dan heavyweights on 35 heavyweights.
Yeah, for sure. So why don't
we tango, wait a second.
I have the best card in the game. Let
me change my diet and get the six pack.
Cause Dolce thinks I
need to be less or fat.
Plus he's going to alienate a lot of
people that love Roy Nelson because Roy
Nelson looks at the average American,
oh shit.
Oh boy.
Like that mark.
Oh Roy Nelson fires back.
This is what Roy wants, man.
Man. If you didn't know Roy Nelson
was a UFC fighter and you saw that
Dubai, a swearing pool, and
you talk shit to him, Bro,
fucking colossal mistake. That
would be a huge, instead of,
Oh my God,
a bad
mother.
Oh my God,
I've never seen that. Never Seen Ryan
else and take a shower. Holy Shit.
Wow. No, that's fucking scary.
What do you mean? Oh No,
you hate mar hunt. No, I'm just
saying. Wow. That was crazy. He said,
no,
no, no. Mark Hump walks away
to halo. How he does that,
that walk away. He's done that to
three dudes. Now how expansive this,
Ooh.
Cheers.
Mark Hunt is the king of the walkaway.
Kao He tripped right there looking at it,
but that's the referee gotten to watch it
again. The referee pushed him. Bullshit.
Watches the fucking referee.
Sowhat hey,
we should have blocked the rough,
but a foreign minister and the
referee room. Beautiful.
Crazy, beautiful walk off.
K got caught right in the chin.
Well,
he got caught by one of the best
strikers in MMA period. Hardest by far,
the serious heavyweight fighters.
Nobody moves.
I can with the scissors or juniors
junior harder than cane.
100% but he moves so smooth.
He moves like a big black
guy. Right? Oh Wow. Wow.
Yeah. That's all you Doug cream. No,
but you know what I'm talking about
talking about green. No money.
Roy's no professionally,
professionally,
but he moved like a brother.
Well, I think what Samoans,
you know have one of the
things that they like.
There's so many guys like
David [inaudible], Mark Hunt,
they have incredible ability to generate
power beast like David to do you
remember David too? When he's
his primary John Ruiz. Jesus.
Fuck Louisa's.
He had this Jesus,
Louise,
and no one has a bigger fucking jaw,
like who's got like a wider
mount Rushmore jaw and Mark Hunt.
He takes a tremendous bomb.
How old is he?
I think he's like 38 or 39 or
something like that. Every bit of it.
38 thank you.
Jesus.
He looks 29
is that Chinese tomorrow or next week?
He's in his fucking prime. That's,
that's a fact.
Top 10 opponent is hurting
heavyweight out there.
You got your sights set on that.
You'd like to fight back.
It's about Ya'll.
My little buddy,
he's a great guy.
I hung out with them in the airport,
him and his training partner.
He's a sweetheart, really,
really fun guy to hang out with
and talk to him. Very friendly.
It's so common there. You know what
you were saying earlier about him,
about his career being in.
Here's one further.
When he first got signed by the UFC,
like they had a strike force contract.
They didn't want to honor it,
and he did his pride contract.
They didn't want to honor
his pride contract and not,
not that they didn't want to honor it,
but they didn't want him to fight.
They wanted to pay him off and
he said, no, I want to fight.
Not that they want to honor. Of course
they would honor any contract, but he did.
They didn't think that. He was like, you
know, UFC material. What's happening?
What's going on? They didn't think he
was UFC material. We thought, you know,
he'd lost a few guys and he said,
look, I want to prove it to you.
And then he loses his first fight and
fuck and they give them a second chance
and then man on a row. Super
impressive. That was insane.
He lost how many straight?
Well,
he lost to McCorkell and then he loves
to tell that to junior dos Santos,
is that the next loss or
was there a loss in Magento?
He lost to McCorkell than he did.
He lose that decision in Denver.
That's a good question. Did he
beat Brendan Schaub? I mean, not,
not burning sharp. He's right here.
Ben Rothwell, Ben Rothwell in Denver.
I forget. I knows a decision. Let
me pull it up. Mark Hunt. That damn,
I've never seen really get taken out like
that. Fuck. That was beautiful, man. Dude.
That shit was beautiful. Dope ass
picture on Wikipedia. You guys,
have you guys seen Josh Barnett and
a hand out do a scene from Brokeback
mountain? No, of course. I haven't
seen it. Have you seen it? No.
Oh my God.
Did go hand out the [inaudible] show
episode for Josh Barnett and out the load
Anja doing a scene from Brokeback
mountain. It's branding.
What did I say?
I said we need to restart reenacting.
The Silva fight was a draw, but wasn't
that fight changed because of the,
the drug thing then like
they disqualify who draw.
So there's no, there's no winter
though. Is that what it was?
His draw big money and bonus
money for the fight of the night.
So he lost junior scientists before that.
He'd beat Stephan's true check Congo,
Ben Rothwell and tuck shirts.
So there's McCorkle was the last,
just the one that won for neuro and then
he fought Dosantos and then he had the
war with bigfoot shitload. Right?
Get that [inaudible]
two, three, four, five.
He lost six in a row to the
gets submitted by Musashi.
We get the guys who was filed by a
man who get the guys who was fighting.
Josh Barnett fader was an
interesting fight, man.
Remember when he had fade
or in an arm lock? Remember
that? I forget and I'm like,
you're Kamora, but he couldn't finish
it. Those are some and Josh Barnett,
those early days though, he's a
pure striker, no nothing. You know,
they didn't know what he was doing.
He was learning,
but he beat Mirko Cro cop in his
prime t Vandelay Silva man. He,
he,
you know,
a lot of people think he was the guy that
ruined Vandelay cause Vandelay fought
him as a heavyweight and at
Vandelay was the 203 pound champion.
He was fucking everybody up at two
oh three and went up and fought.
And he actually thinks, I
believe, if I remember correctly,
he was light when he fought, um, hunt.
I think he was only like one 99
and he fought hunt white for him.
Like when he fought cro cop, he
was super heavy. He was like,
he was heavier than Cro cop,
if I remember correctly,
Vandelay was like two 18
and cro cop was two 14. Wow.
Vandelay was just said the cro cop is
the strongest guy you ever felt, right?
Yeah.
What did you weigh when you fought
him to 21 or something like that too?
Maybe that way he was he to 40
[inaudible] stronger than you are? Uh,
just like, just like so like, like
a rock couldn't move. I'm like, no.
You know some guys you move and
the like tilt, like kind of budge.
Do you think it's like, it's
like a statue. The legs,
like he hit the guy has giant, has a
good base. I just think he was like,
there's no fat on them. Just like that
grown man strength when I fought him,
you know? Yeah. You know,
you're talking about a guy who'd been
kickboxing for so fucking long and the,
I think I would imagine that a guy who's
like a really strong kickboxer like a
hunt or like a cro cop.
Those guys had developed those monster
as legs and they have good balance from
throwing kicks and once he teach those
guys take down, take down defense,
it becomes very difficult. She's, they're
dealing with such a ridiculous base.
Like Cro cop has some
giant ass fucking legs.
You want to talk about a guy with
a ridiculous highlight reel stud.
So tired.
Tired.
I've just had such a long day.
Six Oh, shooting the Goldbergs.
I'm so cute as you shoot it today.
Yeah. Yeah. That's the fun part.
Do you like sucking the Dick Television?
Still do like playing
with television show.
I have to say I really liked
what network is it for ABC?
I play at the gym teacher from the
Eighties Oh my God. I can imagine.
It's so funny. I drink this protein
shake. I had to drink. I it's,
it's actually was one of the best
things I've ever done. That's hilarious.
What's the name of the
Shell? Uh, the Goldbergs.
It's such a funny Jeff Glennan who was
in a wedding bridesmaids and it's really
funny show. I heard bride is a fun part
of the shock. Yeah, it was. It really fun.
Great movie. It's on youtube. Classic.
What's called the Goldbergs.
Okay. Time. No, never saw it.
It's supposed to be really funny.
It's pretty funny movie. Amazing
movie. It tells me it's really fun.
It's a classic American classic.
It's fine.
Know who else aren't seen bridesmaids?
Al Qaeda.
Isis fucking seen bridesmaids,
man.
[inaudible] American don't
see fucking bridesmaids.
No, it in, it's been about three
years ago. You live in America.
It's bridesmaids was a huge hit.
Huge,
huge terrorist. It's a great,
it's actually a really good movie.
I liked the winter soldier,
Captain America.
I saw it recently know the last funny
movie that I saw was, was this at the end?
Pretty fucking hilarious and
funny. How funny. The fucking,
what's the dude from eastbound and down?
Have you seen that this character did
awesome.
I love the amazing
spoiler alert. It's been out for
six years plus a spoiler alert.
Spoiler alert. It's a million
o'clock. Nobody's out.
People get mad at me for
fucking spoilers for fights.
It happened like the day
before. I'll say, oh,
I just finally got around to
watching blank fight. Wow.
What a fucking huge wind.
Through
your online shithead.
You're online. You're reading the Twitter,
fucking MMA common data for the UFC.
What did you think was coming your way?
Stupid.
You're looking for
flower arrangement tips.
I'm going to talk about why you
want my fucking Twitter feed.
Do you go on MMA weekly, Twitter
feed to and go, Whoa, spoiler alert.
You know what has to hurt
people's feelings when?
When I see you talk shit
to one 20 you'll dummy. Oh,
that's something you and I talked about
long time ago or like that's the most
thing. That was my, remember this sound
nice when you call somebody a simple name.
I almost cut this guy off and be that guy
who this huge guys looking at me and I
and I and I, and I pull up next to him
and he goes, you got a fucking problem.
And he was this really big giant guy,
fat. Really me. I looked at him, he goes,
and I go, what? And he goes, you got
our fucking problem, man. And I go,
you're fat.
He goes,
I just drove away like little car,
little insults like that.
There's dumb or you're fat.
I would just start Lauer.
Those are flat pulled up to someone and
said, hey man, you got a fucking problem.
He goes, you're fat. I'd be like, ah,
you fuck. But it hurt my feelings.
If they're like, you're a fucking dummy,
dummy, dummy. You fuck you did that.
This girl was talking, man.
Some people are dummies.
I did do it to a girl's talking to show.
Yup. Heckler. You went no, no, no, no, no.
Your dog.
That's more than once.
I'm not sure what
your dog,
your dog.
That was a real problem with fucking
doing standup at the comedy store.
There's nobody, nobody does the
crowd. Nobody takes care of the crowd.
So you were constantly comic.
Shouldn't have to deal with that shit.
That shit should all be
done by like bouncers.
They should have any improv you
go to that never gets out of hand.
They squash that shit like that.
They know what they're doing.
I think I can tell the
story. What happened tonight.
Tonight. What happened? Yeah.
Uh,
I was at,
I was at the laugh factory and there was
a dude in the front row talking like an
asshole and to the point where I, I, I
kicked his leg a little bit. I went, hey,
you got to shut up in the middle of my
set. And I go, hey, you got to shut up.
And he goes, oh, sorry, sorry. And then
he kept talking. I went to, I said,
it was fine.
It went well and Dane,
Dane Cook follows me and I'm watching
Dane and the guy is doing the same thing
and Dane literally at literally in
the middle of it went like this.
He just and tweet, if I'm
exaggerating, Dang goes,
you shut the fuck up right fucking
now or I will knock you the fuck out.
You say one more fucking word.
I'm going to knock you out and
send you the fuck out of here.
Like right and cooks when do it some
time back the fucking show you asshole.
Yeah. And the whole place started clapping
the whole, cause the guy was so great.
Would it be if the guy stood
up and whoop, Dang. I was like,
I was like Dane in front of
everybody was ready to go.
That guy was a plant put by
Jamie Masada. He's like, Dan,
cookie's going to be on a one to two
warm up with blind Kalin. You Go,
you tell a joke, you talk
to good, you speak on phone.
And then when Dane Cook come
on, he be so mad. He's like,
this fucking guy heckled me.
I'm Dane Cook.
And then we get on TMZ,
10 guys and the bad zoom
Assata uploading it to youtube.
I'm sure somebody videotaped Brian.
Do me a favor.
Tell them the dream you had that you
told me. I tell them the dream thing.
It's you telling me if this is normal,
I think it's appropriate. Okay. I had,
this is my business partner and listened
to this dream. I had a boyfriend. Okay,
that's not Martin Luther King
and what were you doing?
And they'll listen to this shit.
Any fucking me get a dream. He was having
sex with a man. Well, I'm glad you,
you told me this after I told Steve
Rinella that I don't want to share a tent
with you because he asked me. He goes,
is it okay if you're sure Taylor, Brian,
fuck yeah, I do. I still like a werewolf
or anybody. You look like a snooze.
I'm assuming you don't know. I have
an irregular NASA. Craziest, craziest,
loudest snore. I thought
you recall that. Mouthpiece.
Mouthpiece of a new mouth
when we went hunting
third or fourth version
up fitting, right, man,
I kept falling off. Yeah, I kept
falling out, but the new one is,
it's uncomfortable, but it fits great
and it keeps my tongue in place.
Makes no sound. It looks like I sleep
like a baby. I make no sound. Right.
And then finish your gay story though.
I see. I'm sorry about scoring.
And I was like, and I was
like, I'm straight man,
and I have a boyfriend
and this guy keeps fucking
crazy shit and this guy's fucking
me and I got to keep this a secret.
I'm not sure how to make sense of this.
That's a bit
dead serious. When he told me this and
I literally just looking at what it is,
bro, next hour, it's gallery, right?
Write it down,
write down,
these are endless with this drain
can go wherever. Have you guys
ever in my life, dude. I was
like, and I was like the guy,
but he had a back on them and I
was like, damn man. And I remember
I didn't say this party cocktails,
we're having cocktails and I was looking
at Raga, I fucked this guy again.
I
slide.
Yeah,
Fuck Shit.
It was crazy straight,
man. I'm fucking straight
disturbing how many jokes you
have like arguing your sexuality.
I know like a big part of your
act as arguing your sexuality.
I was like 50% gain.
I issue
you got Brody Stevens up
to 84% started the podcast.
It's was probably 10% gay but outcast.
He told me he was 84% Thailand's.
He said 15% after that dream.
I said full 50% you think you're gay?
No, a little bit and now I wish her well,
we went on when we went,
when we went hunting,
we were gone for six the first time
we were gone for six days in Montana.
Second time we were gone for five days in
Wisconsin. That's 11 days at gay jokes.
I mean, the kid is relentless.
It never stops coming.
It's a storm of locusts that there's,
there's no end.
It shows up on satellite satellite.
It's like
crops die.
Rivers show the fucking,
the rivers get choked
leaving like there's no,
no one ever get tired of farmlands.
Crops dry up there actually
something with that,
you know who is actually more
obsessed with male beauty.
Then Brian Count as big shit here. Akiyama
well, yeah. I mean that's my boyfriend,
but big brown, big brown. Big Brown is,
don't try and push it on me. Yeah, but
you're,
you're a track
your dream. You had sex with a man. No
one else has that shit here. That's weird.
Brian,
why are you saying that
he's attracted to men?
Because you're attracted to men too. Are
you attractive? You're attractive, right?
I would imagine you're attractive guy.
I'm a cutie pie. You're beautiful men,
not that right now.
He looks like that's a good mood.
I've never seen you look so tired.
This is how guys are like,
Brendan gave me his cold. I was
around is called. I had to go.
I was sick as shit or two weeks.
It's crazy.
I had a performance San Antonio
and I'm dying. I'm like,
I'm just slogging through and I
call him. I go, Bro. I go. He goes,
how are you doing? I go, I'm not doing
well, man. I'm sick and I got to,
I got two shows tonight and you gave me
your call and this is what I hear on the
other end. The phone [inaudible]
I mean, you were dying.
We told you guys get acute cold. I got
in his fucking chicks think that's funny.
No it guys love it. Then I got in his
fucking Prius. I get in there and he goes,
I'm sick of shininess. I'm
never sick. Spray céline
solution his nose. And he goes,
this is why. Two days later, two
days later, he's sick as fuck.
Kept telling me this for weeks. All
I heard from him was, there's a wait.
You never get sick. I don't get sick
anymore. I spray the sailing solution.
Yeah, he got time. They got my
cold. So four days later I go, yeah,
throat starting to hurt now moving down
to your chest. He goes, yeah. I said,
enjoy that for about another eight days.
I was sick. I wasn't sleeping. That's why
your immune system so superior to the
average man. Thank you for saying that.
It's dear crush, crush all
disease. Well, you know,
eats a lot of heartbreak and I meditate,
eat factory farmed fish,
nothing from the ocean.
I'm God's favorite too.
That helps even even as even as Brazilian
character is it gay Brazilian carrot
here. That was one of the most
hilarious moments of our life.
You got to write that down.
Take that sheet of paper off the top
and that I had a dream that I had a
boyfriend and he wants and he was
fucking me for Joe. Joe Rogan,
my snog of her. Thanks for the
idea. I had a dream. I had a boy.
Fucking good. Fold that up.
The best part when you go,
I gotta fuck this guy later.
I know you guys to get fuck.
You must tell them.
Just go hit a back. I remember his
back was very wide and he's fucked.
She throughout the dream
and there's nothing he could do because
it gives me like running and sometimes
you do run but you're like in
slow motion like it in the drain.
I'm trying to shoot straight. It
should pull. It goes really slow.
Your rabbit gun and you shoot
the gun falls upon the slow
sample is like everyone likes never work.
You know when you see a movie that's
really scary and you feel that,
that chill up your spine where
you're like, fuck, this is scary.
Like you're so uncomfortable and scared.
Sex with the guy felt the same way.
I was like this fucking song,
but God do it.
All of us are dreaming.
Running brides like yeah,
you have that junior jack and a guy off
super slow and it just never ends in
every now and then. Throwing that you
tried to escape when you had the gun.
They represented the,
the mistakes of my go.
You're in your underwear like
wherever you go. It's freezing cold,
but we had a cuddle this
gay shit naked. I was treating
his frostbite while he was fucking
mosquitoes and hard on,
oh my God, listen, we ran out of time.
We're three hours in shit pop on some
powerful Mark Hunt. Congratulations.
Mark Hunt. Yeah. That
was fucking phenomenal.
Materializing, right? Kind
of saw it materializing.
So how smooth he was the only guy in
this room who has to actually contemplate
fight.
That guy is breading shrouds
these deep 40, she'll
Maddie, if I'm talking,
I'm sure if I be Travis brown he could
be next. Let's get through Travis.
That's crazy job. You have crazy.
Do they want to be a fighter? Oh,
there's only a couple
of more minutes to go.
But if you had to think of like this
Travis Brown situation where he leaves
Jackson's and now he's
treated with Edmond,
is that a good thing or do you think
that that shows any sign of like,
you know, sometimes people were
in a state of turmoil, you know,
they feel like they need to change,
they lose a little bit of confidence
and they try to switch things up.
Is it good to switch things up?
I can be good list and I moved to La
and switch things up. Um, obviously,
uh, my know Rhonda very well
and I know that camp pretty
well, I would say. And, uh,
I'm not going to go into detail,
but I think it's a great thing
for me that he's trading there.
I'll put it like that without going
into detail. Did you just say,
can you
think for him?
That's what he said. Whoa.
He would say that though.
Even if he didn't even mean it.
Not, I promise I went, I would say,
I just want to say Shit, I'm 100% dead.
Seriously? Do I have no reason. You know?
You know what?
They made a mistake by going 100% whoa.
What if he hears us and changes
his mind? Don't give a fuck. Wow.
Brendan. Brendan, I'm not worried about
Aurora. I'm not worried about him. Yeah.
Did you used to train?
There were no where he's training.
He never trained with note what he's
doing? Nope. Never trained with the admin.
But you did do country might have,
like you might have someone telling you
how they're training because you know,
not at all. Not at all. Not
You mean? Nope, not even
close. I would never do that.
So you know what the training is like
at Jackson's? You know, it's like,
it's a pretty high level training and he
decided to leave that Jacqueline's has
traded partners for days.
Can I just speculate?
Can you speculate?
Do you think there was any issue with
the fact that Overeem came into the camp?
No, not at all. Not at all. No. Travis
beat him. We'll never find them again.
I don't think that anything to do
with it easily find them again though.
That could happen. Nah, you don't think
so? No. Never. They would never do it.
Number three, let's say.
Yeah, no. Well, I'm a man.
There's a chance. Yes.
Rankings don't mean shit. Yes.
But the chance of them finding again,
them doing rematches or not good,
unless you're at a very high level or
here's my opinion. I completely disagree.
And one of the reasons I completely
disagree is that the delivery with the
vision, the depth of the
heavyweight division is not
that there's not that broad.
I mean there's not that many trains
with Andre Arlovski. Yeah, it's true.
So you think he was just like,
fuck it, I'm out of here, but look,
because our Lawsky stays in our
lost keys fighting over him,
or lambskin Overeem are in the same camp.
Just because they're both heavy weights.
It doesn't mean to,
Travis Browne agrees with that.
So Travis Browne could have been the
situation where he felt like he was one of
the top heavyweights in camp. He beat
Overeem, then all sudden ovary moves in.
And then on top of that he
loses the fight with VRE doom.
He doesn't like how he felt in that fight.
Feels like you need to add
some things to his game.
And one of the things that he said,
he said he didn't know how to fight.
He said he knew how to go
out there and fuck guys up,
but he didn't know how to fight like
the technical aspects of fighting,
which is kind of, you know, it's
interesting saying that when he's like,
you're dealing with Mike Winkeljohn,
you know there's like an
outstanding striking coach.
Like one of the best
in the world we called.
I've seen Winkeljohn cause the monster.
So wizard.
So Travis is working with him and then
he goes from that saying that he really
didn't know how to fight. And Edmund
is teaching them how to fight. I mean,
it's interesting. Well, look what
Edmonds done for Rhonda. He's,
she wasn't negative,
a striker and the Tam and all of a sudden,
all of a sudden Rhonda can, it took her
a while because I was even doubting.
I was even thinking, damn, she ever
gonna be a serious threat on her feet.
She's becoming a serious threat.
Fuck can at the rate she's going another
couple of years, two or three years,
Rhonda might just stay standing
for a while longer. You know,
that's that chocolate dealt type thing.
You know, if you can't take her down,
what the fuck are you going to do?
If she could knock you out in the feed
when Rhonda blasted Sarah McMahon,
would that need of the body? That sense?
That was a big fucking message. You know,
that was a big message. Samak last
time we were here you said you didn't,
you didn't feel that Rhonda
Cyborg was a good, uh, uh,
like you weren't happy about
that potential matchup.
Have you changed since then because of
all of that? Has there been anything?
I just don't,
I just don't think you would be good
for the UFC with Cyborg history,
with steroids and, and, and Ronda
being very pretty and being in movies,
it's not going to be good if she were to
lose to Cyborg. That's all I'm saying.
I think Cyborg is a great fighter.
I don't think as a marketing standpoint
and for the future of the UFC.
Cyborg is your champ is a good thing.
Do you think that she should
be out forever because of
the fact that she did? Uh,
she keeps winning.
She keeps winning and I'd give her a shot.
She's got to have a shout.
The time everyone
see how she feels almost got fucking shot.
Cyborg is zeroed in on
Rhonda. That's all. What else?
Fucking but every fight. Every girl seems
like it's an evitable. Come on, Gina.
Carano they're like, no, it's
fine. Why don't we bring you back.
You tap out in like a minute or so and
we'll do all this marketing and then you
get out.
Everyone wants to fight Ronda.
They know they're not going to win
the market and they get from it,
but saying the fight that
most MMA fans want to see MMA,
not mainstream, but it would be,
it would be beautiful mainstream.
All the regular. They'd be probably
behind Rhonda because cyborgs.
Yeah. Everyone would be
behind Ronnie. We a Cyborg.
She had some steroid abuse before
and all that stuff, but still,
that's what makes it an amazing fighters.
You have chickens,
you super yolked crazy looking sheet.
Cyborg is the perfect nickname for
against Ronda. That pretty judo girl.
I think that is going to be the
fight of the millennium sidebar.
I don't want that anymore. She doesn't
look like that anymore. She does.
She looks like a strong woman now.
Yeah.
She just does not look like
she used to live. Well.
Still still stood up as far as,
as far as women's MMA,
that is probably the biggest money fight
right there. Yeah, that would be huge.
Moneywise I don't think so. Cause
more. The mainstream knows Gina.
The mainstream doesn't know
Cyborg and they're like, oh,
I don't want to see one eye on
cyber of countdown and that's over.
You know what I mean? It's
totally sellable. It's a
terrifying fight and it's,
I think it's completely sellable,
not only damn thing, it's sellable.
I think if she keeps winning, it's a
must. It's a must have fight. I mean,
I don't know if it's ever going to
take place, but if she, if Cyborg,
if you go back and watch the
fucking video of her beaten up,
Gina Carano beaten up. I talk too
much. When she found Gina, you're like,
what are we doing? It was like bully
beat down. You know what I'm saying?
What are we doing?
Do you want to be your champ?
You think that inspires other little
girls when they see bully, beat downs,
styles, sideboard, Regina, if you know,
if you're looking at it as a promoters
of the promoters point of view. Yes.
So quick. That's all. As far
as the fans, the fans go,
I think cyborg biggest
MMA fight of all time.
Now we're out of time.
Turn into a Pumpkin is three hours
in eastern. It's gonna cut off.
Thanks everybody. Brian,
count B, r y a n C A, l l, e,
n on Twitter.
Come see me on Sunday.
Brown Aka Brendan Schaub on Twitter,
S C H,
A.
U B son.
Come see him on Sunday at the Irvine
Improv running through this hour that he's
going to be filming soon. And
then edge it. Bra e d d, I e.
B r a v O 10th planet j j.com
represent respect and recognize it.
Just be soon.
Much love everybody.
Anybody got anything important
to plug just her in the kid, son
Podcast,
Eddie Bravo radio.
PODCASTS is coming up
on it's official now.
Edi to, uh, we'll be, uh, at,
at the Florentine Gardens.
Friday, October 10th. Ebi One is
on Youtube. Search. Eddie Bravo,
invitational Ebi one.
That's about it. Can I.