Hello Freak bitches.
Yeah,
I know a lot of cops,
man,
they,
they see the,
one of the problems is you're a cop.
You see a lot of shit.
I see a lot of shit all the
time and you lose your patience.
You lose,
you lose your patients and you,
you know,
you,
you become more attuned to the kinds of
the world then you would like to be and
you don't want to hear any
fucking bullshit anymore.
So very,
very fucking tricky job.
My,
my pain.
Your humanity.
My question is this,
now you're always seeing the worst in
people being did I know that there are
people out there who
really do risk their lives.
Like if someone's house
is getting robbed or,
well,
how about this guy?
The fucking,
this guy in Denver,
man,
they had it.
Someone had to go in there and stop him.
You know,
this isn't,
this isn't something that you,
you know,
the community can just rally together.
No one had guns.
But my question is the,
the police that break the law,
should they be held more
accountable because they know
the law that much better?
Like in other words,
if you had killed somebody to
ever or should you get time
minimize?
For example,
there's a case in in New York where a guy,
he got like a a year of probation or
something or was it a year in one year in
jail is because he killed a guy
while he was drunk driving and he's,
he's his family is apparently
connected with the NYP ds.
This is my question though.
If if you're a caption should be held
accountable to the law even more so
because you knew it was wrong
to be drunk and driving.
You arrested people probably a hundred
times for doing the same thing.
You don't think that it's ever been
shown that to put people in a situation
where it's whatever they're doing
that's wrong has more of a consequence.
I don't think that's
ever been shown to them.
It have any effect on their actions.
I think people do shit cause they think
they're going to get away with it.
They don't do shit because they
measure the consequences and go,
all right,
I might do a year in jail.
Fuck it,
let's ride.
They don't do it like that there.
It's,
it's more of an impulsive
sort of a thing when,
when people make mistakes,
but if people know,
listen,
there's no way that I'm really going to
catch it that much heat for this because
who the fuck is,
right?
If I'm drunk and somebody pulls me over
and we both play for the same team,
you're going to bring me in.
Do you know what's going to
happen in you after that?
What's really crazy is how many cops
turned out to be corrupt back in the days
before the Internet.
I mean,
I think it's very difficult
to be corrupt today,
but I think back in the day it
was probably pretty fucking easy.
I miss,
I think it's slightly less
difficult to be corrupt.
I mean,
I think you can if,
if there's money in it for you,
you know,
and I think there's levels of corruption,
there's harmful levels,
and then there's simple stuff like,
you know what?
I'll fix it.
Tickets for you.
You know,
we're good friends.
That's corruption.
Whether or not it's,
it's bad.
Those kids are dying.
Someone shouldn't have the
ability to do that and they say,
you know what,
you're connected with me.
I'll give you the card
when you have a problem,
you call me and I'd take care of it.
I know people that benefit from that.
I know people that had been in situations
where they may not be 100% right and
they have a specific card or something
like that and I'm not denigrating thing.
I'm just saying that at some point,
you know,
are you more responsible
for your corruption because
you know the law 10 times
better and you're enforcing
it and forcing it.
In other words,
if you get caught for murder and then
you're off all of a sudden in five years,
that's only because you knew the law
better and then you still broke it.
Well,
he was selling drugs to pick.
I said,
I don't think that you can,
you make people more responsive
when you going to change.
Thank you.
Might make people feel better
because you're punishing them more,
but I don't think you're necessarily
going to change behavior by offering a
bigger consequence.
I think the only way to change
behaviors to change thinking,
and what I try to tell people
is it sounds ridiculous,
but this is something that
came to me on a boat once,
is that you got to treat everybody as
if it's you living in another life.
We could all do that.
If we could all picture ev,
any person,
regardless of what the fuck
they're going through in your life,
think about what it would be like to live
that person's life from birth to death
with their situation,
their economic situation,
their biological situation there,
their life experiences.
Would you be any different
than that person?
If you were that man,
if you were that woman,
would you be any different?
Are you them?
You know,
if that person was born you,
would they be you?
And Are we all the same like that?
And is that what life really is all about
is figuring out that each one of us is
exactly the same.
We're just living through at
different biological circumstance.
And the more you can
treat everyone you meet,
like there,
you living another life,
the happier you'll be.
And that's the only way we're ever going
to sort this thing out is everyone has
to do things based on
that ideal everyone had,
whether it's business or personal shit.
Whatever you do,
you always have to think that this person
that you're dealing with is you living
another life and you can't
let them boss you around.
Can't let them talk shit to you.
Can't let them fuck up your life.
You know you do your best
to keep them on track,
but your ethic and your resolve and your,
your intent should always be to treat
them as if it was you living a whole
nother life.
Okay.