Silver worked real good experience by
request of Dr.
Rhonda.
Patrick.
You want it to have that music.
So there you go.
Now that's how we do it for you.
I appreciate you out.
How about that?
Because of you will do it from here on
out.
Like you know,
there's something about it that makes
you feel good.
It gets a little opening or something.
Little something.
Something.
Has there ever been a study on what
exactly music does to the mind?
Like an inspirational song when you're
on a treadmill that makes you keep
going?
Oh man,
it makes all the difference for me.
All the difference.
I don't know.
I don't know if they've done that exact
study,
but I'm sure there's been studies that
have been done looking at how music
affects the brain.
Yeah.
I just don't know.
Yeah,
there's something going on.
It's 100 percent.
Right.
I mean when,
when a song is,
it has to be.
It has to work with,
you know what if it's a song that was
your song,
like flash dance,
but that's good.
I really liked him and out to the
stones.
I really liked the.
Rolling Stones.
Yeah.
And I also like it when it's like,
you know,
maybe some ACDC like okay,
I need some motivation to like push past
that.
Yeah,
that's what I listened to in the,
in the a cryogenic chamber.
I listened to back in black because it
just seems like a good song for that
dude.
This morning I,
after I did a workout I get a cold
shower and I was like singing in the
cold shower because it's so cold.
It was like me singing and I was like,
yeah,
no,
we're hoping to fit in my brand.
And like Dan was like trying to record
video but like audio,
he was like trying to record it for
snapchat but he failed miserably and um,
but I stayed in for five minutes and the
singing was like,
yeah,
it helped me push past that.
This is cold as fuck.
So you did it just for the
norepinephrine just for the.
Did I say that right?
Yes,
you did.
Thank you.
I did,
I did it.
I did that.
Plus I try,
I tried doing high intensity workout so
I was trying to sprint faster than I
usually do,
so I like to do a lot of aerobic.
I do aerobics and I like to mix it up
with some resistance training for
different reasons.
In the same day.
I usually do mix it up,
but not always.
It depends.
I like to like,
you know,
sometimes I'll start off with Iran and I
don't,
I don't do like long long runs.
It's like two miles,
you know enough to like get some brain
drive neurotrophic factor growing,
which is a growth factor that helps you
grow new neurons.
That's been shown to happen with more of
aerobic type of exercise,
but then the high intensity interval
training like sprinting or I'll do
bodies,
body weight squats or push ups or you
know,
these backward types of pushups.
Then whatever it's going to like,
get me doing that high intensity sort of
thing where you're,
you're actually producing lactate
because your body is using glucose since
you can't get oxygen to your muscles
quick enough for how quick you're like,
you know,
applying for us and putting this
energetic,
energetic demand,
use glucose and you don't use it inside
the Mitochondria.
I mean you don't,
you don't need oxygen,
so you do it without oxygen and you make
lactate is a byproduct.
Will lactate's been shown to increase
dramatically a lactate uptake into the,
into the brain.
It increases dramatically upon I'm that
type of exercise and it's lactate that's
fueling norepinephrine released.
So like you're making more lactate to
make more norepinephrine and your brain.
So,
and norepinephrine is,
it has an immediate effect of making the
connections between your neurons
stronger so that you remember things
better.
Um,
and so that you learn better and you
remember better.
It's called longterm potentiation.
So I was like,
I need my brain to work today.
I'm going to do that stuff.
Yeah.
Whereas the Abramovic type of exercise
has more of a longterm effect because
you're making more neurons,
uh,
but those,
those neurons take two weeks to mature.
So like the aerobic training that I did,
those effects will come two weeks from
now when I'm,
I have more neurons,
but you know,
so the immediate effect of the lactate
and making an effort and it's happening
right now because right now the
connections between my neurons are
stronger.
So and plus it also makes you feel good.
Um,
it,
that's crazy though.
There's a physical effect like that.
There's a physical effect of your brain
actually functioning better.
Like there's a direct mechanism involved
in your brain functioning better because
of exercise.
It's so.
I have been so obsessed with this lately
like this and I know that I have like
probably we've talked about this before
and I talk to people probably get sick
of me talking about it,
but this concept of stressing your body
stressing exercise.
Most people think exercise is good
because the exercise itself is good.
No,
the exercise of this exact exercise
itself is not good.
It's actually very stressful on your
body.
And what's good is the stress response,
the body.
We've got a hard wired genetic program
that is conserved in plants,
insects,
bacteria,
primates,
humans,
you know,
we're,
we're all,
we all have this response to stress.
And that response is to try to survive.
I need,
I need to stay alive past on my genes.
Obviously the stress response is much
stronger.
I'm younger when you're younger or the
earlier in life because your body knows
you're not old enough to reproduce for
whatever,
you know,
hormones and things like that.
They're not being produced.
But um,
so the stress response,
which is like exercise causes stress,
thermal stress,
like heat cold.
And then there's all these compounds in
plants that are a stressful to us that
can induce this.
But it's almost like the brain is
preparing for the next time it's going
to encounter stress.
It's like,
okay,
this is war.
I got to gather up the troops,
I gotta get this army.
We got to assemble this army because
that stress is going to happen again.
I got to pray for war.
So it kind of makes sense that you're,
you're going to have a very profound and
positive effect in your brain and also
in other parts of the body.
I'm,
you know,
the exercise itself.
Um,
it's funny because a lot of people do it
to lose weight or to mostly to lose
weight or you know,
become sexually attractive muscle mass,
which has other very important
physiological effects,
but people do it because they want to
look good.
Um,
and honestly,
a lot of,
there are a lot of people that say,
well,
exercise doesn't really play an
important role in losing weight.
It's nutrition.
You know what the right,
but exercise has a very important role
and that role is to,
to cause your body stress so that you
activate all these really good and
awesome jeans that are helping you deal
with stress.
And guess what?
Stress is happening right now.
Every time you breathe in oxygen,
your making stress,
you're,
you're generating byproducts that are
very dangerous.
So,
so exercise is good
with definitely good.
I just get freaked out when people that
are really smart don't get into
exercise.
And I just,
I always feel like that's just,
they have a blind spot,
you know,
there's,
there's a blind spot where they don't
want to discipline themselves to
actually do the work.
They just find that troublesome.
Or maybe they connected with jocks or
people that were assholes when they were
in school.
You know,
there's,
sometimes there's that connection
option.
Yeah.
They probably don't realize the,
the anti anxiety effects they have.
I mean it's,
some of the Anti.
I really also do it because I've got
some kind of like hyperactive stress
response,
stress,
hyper,
hypothalamus,
pituitary axis where you know,
I'm,
I'm prone to be like,
oh,
there's a tiger does lie.
I'm like,
you know,
it's always kind of like,
I'm ready.
I'm ready to fight.
You know,
something's coming to get me.
Sometimes when I'm really stressed I'll
get night terrors.
So like I'll wake up screaming.
It scared the crap out of Dan.
Jesus really not used to be a lot.
Like when I was in graduate school and I
was really,
really stressed.
I would wake up and I just scream.
I thought there was like someone coming
to get me and you know,
there was times where I actually injured
myself too because I flew across the
room because.
Because I thought that there was someone
coming to get me so,
so that more than once.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I hurt my wrist hurt like my,
like some tendon back here.
I broke them near Jesus.
Yeah,
like once a month.
Once a week.
Well now a days.
It's like almost nonexistent.
I would say it happens once every,
maybe four months.
But there was a time not too long ago,
like three years ago where I was doing
it at least a couple times a week.
Once,
once a week for sure.
That's so weird.
I've
always associated people that are like
really paranoid about fear,
about danger,
whether with intelligence,
because it's like if you actually pay
attention to the world around you,
you realize how vulnerable you are and
how many random things can happen.
Random accidents,
bizarre occurrences,
run into the wrong people.
The wrong place at the wrong time,
you know?
And we're so easily damaged.
Take that as a compliment.
But you know,
I think there,
you know,
there's definitely something,
it's kind of an ocd loop sometimes
tonight and I'll get that where it just
and it's so bad like you just get going.
I think I haven't even talked about on
the podcast before,
like there was a time when I was scared
to drive like,
and even now I,
I drive but I feel most comfortable
driving in a place that I'm very
familiar with.
But if I start to let my brain think
about it,
it's like driving scary.
Yeah.
Well it should be.
You look around and all these people
that are texting to so few people are
giving 100 percent of their attention to
the road these days.
There's so much going on.
Self driving cars.
I'm actually looking forward to that.
But they have them now.
Well they're not,
they're not ubiquitous or not.
They're not.
You know,
people aren't using them.
Well my friend has one and no,
he drives with the new Tesla.
You press two buttons on it and it
literally drives on the highway.
It turns.
Yup.
He sits back.
He doesn't even put his fucking hands on
the wheel.
He's like,
it's the craziest shit you've ever seen
in your life.
He,
Tom,
Papa,
papa has to.
It was were the new teslas.
We're only allowing to let you park.
I didn't realize you could actually
drive on the highway.
The newest versions of them drive on the
highway.
I have two friends that have them and
you pray.
I guess there's a button,
that navigation button.
You Punch in the information and then
you press it twice and this sucker will
drive you to where you need to go.
That's pretty cool.
It doesn't work on Shitty old roads
though.
Like Tom Papa was talking about Laurel
Canyon.
Laurel Canyon has got kind of like it
goes by computer sensors that are
detecting the lines based on the cameras
that the car has.
So the car has these external cameras,
they see the lines and then they adjust
accordingly.
But when the lines are really wonky,
like if you.
We're going to over Laurel Canyon,
I don't think I have.
It's really shitty.
Le Rose kind of bumpy.
A lot of potholes and the lines are
really blurry.
They're worn out.
Yeah.
So on that.
Yeah,
I'm sure you have,
but on a really good road it works
great.
Like it just drives.
I'm,
I mean sign me up.
Yeah.
I mean I want everyone else to be in
because I'm actually afraid of everyone
else that's even like coming into La.
Like we drive into La.
I don't know.
People here are crazy drivers.
People swerving.
I mean just constantly swerving.
I don't know if people are just really
aggressive because there's so many
people and you have to.
I don't know.
That's exactly noticed it.
There was a study,
there's an episode of radio lab about
this or they did a study on volume of
people in cities and what affect the
volume of people has on a how many
syllables per minute they say and how
many steps per minute they take and
there's a direct correlation worldwide
between higher populations and like you
can literally guess if you.
If you set up a camera on a street and
you record all the people walking by and
you get a good number of people when you
calculate how fast are walking and then
you record them talking just from those
two pieces of data.
You can tell how many people are in the
city like
so,
but let's see if I can guess so.
If there's more people in the city,
do you walk faster and talk less?
No.
You Walk Faster,
you talk faster,
talk faster,
and you walk faster.
Both of those things.
But if there's a direct correlation
there,
looking at the speed of how you talk,
not how frequent you talk.
Exactly,
exactly how fast you talk,
how quickly walk,
because I feel like the faster you walk,
the more you're like,
got to go,
go,
go.
The less likely you're going to stop and
talk to someone.
Do you know what I mean?
So it's kind of like,
it's just like,
you know,
hey man,
I got to go,
you know,
we're going to do to go get a fucking go
downtown and there's a lot of shit going
on.
See it,
buy this.
Whereas if you go to the middle of rural
Tennessee will.
Hello,
what's your name?
Dr.
Rhonda will.
Very nice to meet you.
Dr Rhonda,
what kind of Doctor Are you?
I guess that could be why there's sort
of a,
a stereotype that people in the south or
a little friendlier.
Maybe they just,
maybe that's why there's less people.
They have more time,
more time.
I know I get in this loop or it's like
I'm so busy.
I know you're super busy where it's just
like,
dude,
I don't have time.
I gotta go,
I got this,
I got.
I'm trying to get out of that.
Yeah,
I think it's a good balance.
You need a balance,
you know there's,
you need that drive,
that motivation.
It's good to like,
you're obviously doing something
productive that's contributing to
society.
You,
you're fulfilling,
you feel like you're fulfilling
something.
But also then did life just goes.
It's like it goes quick,
quick.
It goes quick and you know,
I'm almost 50,
48,
I'll be 49 in August and then like this
is my body works great now,
but for how long,
you know,
nobody's body works great at 70,
it just doesn't,
they're all shitty.
They're all show.
Everybody's holding their back and
they're fucking knees hurt.
When you hit 80,
who's an athlete at 80?
Who's doing cartwheels at 80 and,
and you know,
and doing chin ups in a row,
it's just not happening.
I used to surf with a guy back when I
was in college.
Who was,
he was a surgeon,
who's Dr we called him doc and uh,
he was pushing 90,
I don't remember,
like 88,
89 or he was,
you know,
we rounded up and is like,
he's 90,
but he was out there surfing,
catching waves.
Now I'm sure it wasn't like competing,
um,
but I,
I do think that the more physically fit
you are and the more,
you know,
throughout your life and the better you
eat,
these things are all going to affect the
way you age.
They're all going to affect,
you know,
how much pain you're in,
all that stuff.
And obviously losing muscle mass as big
thing starting in mid middle,
starting at 40 humans start to lose like
point five to one percent or something
like that.
Muscle mass per year,
uh,
just without,
without doing anything.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
I think that that's probably one of the
more difficult things to gain as you get
older.
So if you can maintain it,
you know,
you're way better off because if you
just,
if you're out of shape your whole life
and then also in your pushing 60 and
you're like,
you know what,
I need to get to the gym.
Well it's so hard to make gains.
It's so hard to do,
you know,
any sort of like real resistance
training on a regular basis and you're
going to be so sore,
it's going to be so hard to build a
base.
So it's a much more difficult route.
It's difficult now.
And you know that resistance training,
it's something,
I don't know a lot about this but it's a
topic that I'm interested in,
you know,
because I'm convinced that maintaining
muscle mass is very important as you
age.
And specifically I think that the type,
the type two type of muscle fibers that
you're,
that you do get when you're doing more
resistance training,
those are the kind of fast twitch.
I think those actually play a role in
like stability,
being able to like quickly,
like lose your balance or which is
important as you start to get older and
you become more frail and falling down
and breaking your hip can.
That can take you out.
Like that's a big problem.
That's another thing that bone density
gets increased by muscle resistance
training,
weight training,
squats,
dead lifts,
things along those lines.
That has a pretty profound effect on
bone density.
There's a,
there's a hormone that's actually
released,
I think from muscle tissue called Iris
and that is released when you're doing
resistance training and uh,
possibly also during a robot,
I'm not sure,
but it does.
It plays a role in helping maintain
your,
your bone density as well as
osteocalcin.
Osteocalcin released osteocalcin then
gets into your bloodstream at pulls
calcium out of your bloodstream and
brings it back to the bone.
So,
you know,
the thing is,
is that most of the calcium that we
store in our body is in our bone or
teeth and bones and muscle,
but I'm calcium plays a very important
role in the bloodstream as well.
So anytime we're not getting enough
calcium,
and I think something like 38 percent of
the US population doesn't get enough
calcium like so there's.
There's a huge percentage of the
population doesn't get enough calcium
and whenever you don't get enough,
your body actually pulls it out of the
bone and brings it to bloodstream so
that it can play an important role in
endothelial cells and making sure they
don't get to step.
And so that's where osteoporosis come
saying yeah,
because as you age,
if you imagine a lifetime of chronic
calcium,
quote unquote inadequacy,
so you're,
you're never,
you're never getting enough of the
calcium every day.
Eventually that's going to start to
build up and you're gonna keep pulling
it out of your bone.
You're gonna.
Keep pulling it out of bone.
You know there's a,
there's a couple of things that regulate
that.
That's one,
just obviously just not getting enough
calcium so you keep pulling it out of
your bone and the other thing is not
getting enough of the so doing,
doing the types of exercises that you
need to do to make sure you're releasing
these hormones that are bringing calcium
to the bone that are,
you know,
doing that.
Um,
and also certain dietary factors can
play a role in that.
So making sure that you're getting
enough vitaminK ,
two,
vitaminK ,
one is found in green plants.
It plays a role in blood coagulation
when you have enough of it for that
blood coagulation.
Then some vitaminK stays around the
bloodstream and activates osteocalcin
and other genes that are able to pull
the calcium to the bone.
Vitamin K two never really goes to the
liver and that's um,
something that's found in fermented sort
of a bacteria make it so like you can
find vitamin K two in the western diet,
like cheeses,
bleu cheese is fermented.
Cheeses have a higher amount.
There's some in organ meats like liver,
but Natto fermented soybeans are the
highest fermented soybeans,
not toe to toe.
Yeah,
they've got like,
if you're comparing like cheese or even
organ meat to Natto,
looking at k two levels,
there's no comparison.
Not toes got a huge amount.
I've never even heard of that stuff.
It's pretty big in the health community.
Um,
it's also high in something else called
Spermatozoa,
which,
um,
is able to clear away damaged cells in
your body.
And it's called drip process called a
topic Ge.
So we're always getting damaged cells
and anytime we have a salt that's
damaged,
damaged cells occur,
um,
you know,
just just from normal metabolism.
But as our telomeres get shorter,
um,
the team always take the hit.
So tila mirrors are those tiny caps on
the end of your chromosomes and they
always are like sacrificing themselves
because they don't want your dna to get
the damage because if your dna gets
damaged,
it could lead to cancer.
So they take the hit and as they start
to get shorter,
it accelerates their shortening because
they already get shorter each year.
Then what happens is the cell becomes
what's called senescent.
And what that means is the cell just
sits around in your bloodstream or in
your kidney or your liver or whatever
organ we're talking about,
and it's not really alive.
So it's not mel metabolic,
but it doesn't like go away.
It's not dead.
So what does it just sits there and it
starts to secrete I'm pro inflammatory
cytokines,
which then activate nearby immune cells
to like fire away nasty chemicals in
damage,
more cells.
So what happens is you start to damage
nearby cells.
You can think about like,
have you ever noticed like when you get
a gray hair,
so gray hair,
you'll get senescent Malana sites,
which are the cells that produce the
pigment.
You'll get one that senescence.
So it's just kind of sitting there and
it causes a hair follicle and her hair
gray.
And then all the other hairstyles around
nearby.
You always get them near each other.
And part of that has to do with the fact
that these senescent mental Melana site
in this case,
which is,
you know,
in the hair follicle,
is to creating all this nasty stuff that
then damages other nearby,
um,
hair soft.
Wow,
that's fascinating.
So,
oh,
so anyways,
back to the spermatids,
the spermatids actually clears away it,
it activates this whole genetic system
we have in our body called autophagy,
which is like self eating.
So we start to like eat this cell and
cleared away.
And recently,
like within the last month a study came
out where scientists actually engineered
mice,
uh,
using crispr technology to clear away
all the,
every time they had a senescent cell.
You and I are getting senescent cells
right now,
but right now,
sorry Jamie,
it's happening.
It's like it's happening all the time.
Um,
but,
but the researchers did this brilliant
experiment where they designed,
um,
they were like,
okay,
it's an essence cell,
has a certain marker on it.
And so they then said,
okay,
when this marker gets expressed,
I want you to have the,
you have the,
these immune cells go and cleared away
and eat it.
And so every time there's a senescent
cell,
the immune system cleared it out and the
mice ended up living 30 percent longer
than their normal lifespan.
Pretty cool topic.
It's called.
It's pretty cool.
And there are other things that actually
increase it resveratrol.
Brisbane was very trial from,
it's,
it's a one of those plant compounds
that's the spin,
a recent obsession of mine.
But plants make like natural
insecticides and you know,
for millions of years,
plants have been figuring out a way to
like ward off insects and fungus and you
know,
because they also want to stay alive
just like we do and they don't actually
make enough of this camp like these
chemicals to kill the insect.
It's Kinda like just go away.
So they often affect their nervous
system,
um,
and just kind of make them go away.
But what's really cool is that these
compounds in plants and there's so many
different ones actually have a hormetic
effect on us.
So that hormetic effect being in small
doses,
it activates our whole stress response
pathway,
like exercise does.
And so I'm raspberry trolley is actually
made in grape skins.
And also blueberries make to a much less
degree,
but it's made to ward off fungus.
And resveratrol has been shown,
at least if it's in a high dose,
like was milligrams a day to clear away,
it activates,
it actually activates this whole genetic
pathway that gets activated when you're
fasting.
Fasting is another type of hormetic
stress.
So when you're fasting,
you cause damage cells to clear away.
You also basically start to turn on all
these genes that help you deal with
stress because your body's like,
oh my God,
I can't,
I don't have food.
I,
you know,
I need to deal with this.
So you activate all these really good,
you know,
genetic pathways where you're making
more antioxidants are making more
antiinflammatories,
you're making more brain cells,
you're preparing,
um,
just everything good.
Um,
so it was a virtual kind of his thought
of it,
like a mimetic of fasting in a way
because it activates like one of these
pathways that get activated and it
changes gene expression.
I've been very skeptical.
There was virtual literature for quite
some time back in 2003 or so when it was
a first first kind of came into the
aging world.
I was very skeptical of it mostly
because a lot of the studies that had
been done in animals where they feed
animals,
Rivera trawl,
they feed them such large amounts that
are just like not relevant to humans.
So I was like,
well,
so what,
you know,
but the more I've been reading about it
recently,
the more I've become a little more
convinced that there actually may be
something to,
to this reserve or trial.
It's activating this pathway called
[inaudible] one,
which is globally changing gene
expression,
epigenetics.
It's,
it's,
it's activating all these good things
and deactivating bad things.
And so,
um,
there's really,
it's really interesting.
There was a study that was published not
long ago,
a couple of years ago that was done in
monkeys were monkeys were given a high
sugar diet and a high sugar high fat,
which is a bad combo.
And it gave him a spiritual,
you know,
either gave them a spiritual or didn't.
And the monkeys,
I did not get resveratrol.
Their arteries were like really stiffed
the,
caused their arteries to stiff by like
40 percent.
But there was very raspberry trial
completely negated that.
So I was like,
wow,
maybe I should start looking into the
rivera trial again because it's a
little,
it's a little interesting.
But,
um,
there's so many other plant.
There's a book that was written by an
Indian scientists called plant an Antifa
dense and it's a very dry.
I mean,
it's a textbook,
so it's not like something people like
read,
like for it.
It's a textbook really.
But what it,
what it does,
what he does in this book is there's
over 900 different chemical compounds in
like a variety of plants.
He's a plant in a PR specialist.
So he,
that's his specialty.
And he categorizes like over 900 of
these compounds were these,
these compounds are,
you know,
potentially going to induce a hormetic
response.
And so I know several scientists are
actually using some of these compounds
that are at least listed in this book to
study their effects in mice and
eventually in humans.
But like some of them,
like I'm plumage in plumage ins and
black walnuts and it's bench.
It actually causes a slight stress in
our brain.
And um,
it has been shown in mice to protect
against ischemic stroke because it's
like,
it activates all these good things.
It protects against this ischemic
stroke.
Um,
there's another one called galantamine,
which is in snowdrop flowers,
galantamine is it also stressful in the
brain?
Like I said,
these,
these plant compounds are designed to
target and sick nervous system.
So it's no surprise that are affecting
the nervous system of,
of mammals.
And in fact,
in this case,
humans swell,
galantamine increases acetylcholine
production in the brain and
acetylcholine plays a role in learning
and memory and it's actually given to
Alzheimer's patients,
galantamine to help them remember
things,
to help them with their,
to improve their memory.
But it's,
it's,
it's just one of those natural
insecticides on alcohol.
Ian is a nootropic.
A lot of people take acetylcholine just
from memory.
Well,
the thing I like about the getting it
from,
I'm getting it from getting it from a
hormetic type of response versus like
let's say someone designed a drug to,
um,
to activate the subtle colon receptor,
is that you always have these biological
feedback mechanisms when you're.
When you start to activate a receptor in
the brain,
pharmacologically,
your brain,
your brain knows your brain's like,
oh,
I'm getting a lot of this stuff that I
don't usually get a lot of.
I'm going to stop making as much of the
receptor.
The receptor is what's necessary to have
the physiological response.
So your brain's like,
oh,
I'm just going to stop making as much of
this receptor.
But then what happens is if you don't
give it that signal,
if you don't take that drug,
then you've got less of that receptor
and so you're going to have massive,
like withdrawal.
It's going to be like crazy because now
whatever acetylcholine you do make,
it's not going to have much in effect
because there's less of that receptor
there to actually bind to it.
Whereas when you have something like
galantamine something that's a hormetic
inducer,
what's happening is you're actually,
you're not actually doing anything to
acetylcholine neurons or to,
to,
uh,
the,
the receptor or anything directly.
It's slightly slightly toxic and part of
the way your brain deals with the type
of stress that it induces is it goes,
oh,
this is the kind of stress I need to
make.
I need a seal calling for this for
whatever reason,
whatever,
you know,
these plants are doing different things.
For whatever reason,
the galantamine is like the one that
says,
okay,
Acetylcholine,
so your body is,
it's a response to something kind of
like triggering it,
you know?
And so you're not going to have that
feedback mechanism where it's like.
So if you take it into pharmacological,
former pharmaceutical forum.
Yeah,
I'm just saying a lot of,
you know,
I mean the classic example would be a
opioids opioid painkillers.
So when you're taking an opioid
painkiller,
what's happening is there's a couple of
different opioid receptors in the brain
and the opioid painkillers,
kinda like a morphine derivative,
which is sort of like endorphin.
It binds to something called the new
opioid receptor,
which is what endorphins bind to.
And that's endorphins make you feel
good.
That's also part of the reason why you
exercise while you,
you know,
you're,
you're wanting that endorphin release.
Um,
well what happens when you start to like
make a drug like morphine derivative
type of drug that goes and directly
activates that receptor,
binds to it is that receptor,
the new opioid receptor,
and you start to make less of it.
And that's been shown when you,
when you give morphine drugs,
you downregulate,
you make less of the receptors.
So now what happens is when you don't
have that opioid drug,
you know,
let's say you had this much receptor,
you started taking the drug,
right?
And now your receptors going down here,
And so now if you don't have the drug
are down here,
and so any endorphin you make isn't
gonna do much.
Like,
Oh man,
I need more of that.
And so you keep having just to get back
up to baseline,
just to get back up to normal,
which is why you can have addiction.
Addiction can be very common with those
types of painkillers because of the
effect on the receptor new opioid
receptor.
So that's,
you know,
that's one of the problems.
And interestingly enough,
there's another type of opioid receptor
called the Kappa opioid receptor,
which,
um,
I've,
I think I've discussed with you before,
and one of the podcasts,
because a cap opioid receptors,
sort of the opposite of the new opioid
receptor because it actually,
when you make something in your body
called dynorphins it,
it's responsible for a dysphoric
feeling.
Whereas new opioids,
euphoric,
you feel good.
Dysphoric feeling is the Kappa opioid
you make dynorphins because it cools
your body.
So when you're hot,
when you're,
when you exercise,
when you elevate your core,
but when you sweat,
that's a good sign.
When you're sweating,
you're making dynorphins.
When you sit in the sauna,
you're making dynorphins and you know
when you're working out hard enough that
you're sweating,
you're physically,
you're uncomfortable,
right?
You're like,
damn,
this sucks.
You feel uncomfortable.
And the same goes when you're sitting in
a,
in a hot sauna and you're sweating and
getting really hot.
Man,
you're just like this.
You feel dysphoric,
like that's,
that's what's happening is dynorphins is
binding to the kappa opioid receptor
will.
The really cool thing about this whole
pathway,
again come to coming back to feedback.
Your biology is so smart.
It always figures out a way when you
start to add,
when you start to activate that cap
opioid receptor,
your body's like,
Whoa,
I'm getting a lot of this bad stuff.
I need to like make more of these
receptors because I've got too much of
this dysphoric.
So it actually causes more than caused
your body to make more new opioid
receptors and it makes them sensitive.
So then the next time you release
Endorphin,
you know your workout,
boom,
it feels even better and it lasts.
You know?
So that's part of the reason why I know
that there are certain drugs that are
used to treat opioid addiction,
uh,
activate the capital you would receptor
pathway exercise.
Some people use Sauna.
I don't think they understand the
mechanism,
but because anything that's going to
help you with dynorphins because people
that are taking opioids,
opioids,
opioid painkillers,
there are new opioid receptors are
already like down,
down,
down.
You want it back up and dynorphins
activating that cap,
opioid receptor will do that.
It's been shown in multiple studies.
You know,
so kinda went on a little rant there,
but it's.
I wanted to ask you,
I didn't want to stop you.
I'm the first one.
Go back to resveratrol and black walnut
and all these different things.
Do these things work synergistically or
do they cancel each other out or is
there any problems and combining them?
Yeah.
Great.
That's such like,
you know,
so the question is synergistically would
mean,
can you,
can you then combine two things and have
an even more powerful response?
Right.
Well the thing is is that because these
compounds are targeting different
pathways there,
you're going to have some overlap which
will have a synergistic effect,
but you're also going to have a diverse.
There's going to be diversity.
So you know you're going to have the
plumage and,
and the black walnuts,
galantamine,
and then you get your apogen and from
celery,
you know,
apogen and causes your brain to make
more neural neurons,
neuro stem cells,
and you get the reserve tra,
which is like clearing away damaged
cells.
It's also anti-inflammatory.
And then you go and eat your Kale and
Broccoli.
That makes something called
isothiocyanates.
I isothiocyanates are um,
very potent anticancer.
So they actually change genes.
They change.
We have genes in our body that are able
to convert a pro carcinogen into a
carcinogen and I'm isolated
isothiocyanates stop that from
happening.
And we also have genes in our body that
can deactivate anything that could
potentially become a carcinogen that
when we're exposed to all sorts of stuff
like everyday.
So activating those genes is like super
awesome.
In fact,
it's been shown in mice if you like,
if you give mice a really high dose of
isothiocyanates and then you would
knock,
collate them,
you inject them with tumor cells,
they will not form tumors.
Whereas the mice that are injected.
Yes.
And there's another study that was done
in humans and men,
men that took around the eight,
a 250 grams of Broccoli or Brussel
sprouts.
So isothiocyanates or in the cruciferous
family of vegetables,
Kale,
Broccoli,
cabbage,
Brussel sprouts,
Bok Choy,
cauliflower,
yeah.
All that stuff.
BRASSICA.
Those are all.
They all have isothiocyanates in them.
I'm actually the isothiocyanates are
formed.
They're stored in something and the
plant called glide,
glide costs and rolaids.
And in order to release the
isothiocyanates that the plants have an
enzyme called myrosinase,
which we have a little bit of it,
a little bit in our saliva,
a little bit in our gut bacteria,
but not much.
Um,
and myrosinase is heat sensitive.
So when you heat your,
your cruciferous,
you're inactivating about 50 percent of
it.
And it's still good to cook vegetables.
I mean,
it's good to get both,
but the raw,
the raw kale that you put in your
smoothie or the raw broccoli or eating
the raw broccoli,
Broccoli sprouts have seven times more
because they're a young plant.
Young again comes back to that when
you're younger,
the stress response is more potent
because nature wants you to survive.
So Broccoli sprouts,
isothiocyanates or made to ward off,
you know,
creatures from eating them.
So the younger the plant is,
the more they make of it.
And so.
And so,
Broccoli sprouts,
I used to actually sprout them.
Um,
have you ever tried Broccoli sprouts
before?
I have.
They're pretty pungent.
Let never made them though.
It's really easy.
Like you can order some cds on Amazon
and then get like this,
like this mesh bag and you put the seeds
in and then you wet the bag and you just
keep at every day.
And after about five days you'll have
broccoli sprouts.
So really good on solids.
I'm not so good in smoothie.
I used to put them in my smoothie and
it's like,
it makes me want to Barf,
like it's so gross.
I mean it's really good for you,
but it's just like,
it's so better.
But then again,
you know,
at that when I was doing,
I've gone through so many different.
I'd make different smoothies all the
time.
These are disgusting.
My smoothies,
you'd probably Barf,
you have no idea.
I have done like Broccoli sprouts,
mustard greens,
garlic,
and then you know,
carrots and upset.
But that.
But that right there,
like the.
Have you ever tried mustard greens?
I have had mustard greens.
Have no trust in this smoothie bar.
It'll be like,
you'll think you're drinking hot chili
peppers,
put giant chunks of ginger and four
cloves of garlic for large cloves of
garlic for that is crazy.
So garlic.
Alright,
let's finish the isothiocyanates,
but that it all has to do with these
hormones in the back of my mind.
I still have another question on top of
that.
Keep going.
Go,
go dude.
I am.
This is my recent obsession.
Is the plant this plant,
insecticides.
I really think we don't even know what's
in these plants,
but it's like,
you know these isothiocyanates men that
ate 200,
250 grams a bit.
They actually in their urine,
you can have,
there's a biomarker of a compound that
inactivates like a certain carcinogen
that could be potential carcinogen.
And they increase that by 10 percent.
Meaning that they are doing good stuff.
Basically know the isothiocyanates are
really good for the brain to.
It makes something called a type of
isothiocyanate.
His soul for fame,
which is in the Broccoli sprouts.
It's been shown to like help with
autism.
I mean because it induces a stress
response in the brain and your brain
does all this good stuff and then
there's like apogen and and the celery.
There's a garlic.
The Allison Allison is in garlic and
alice scene is in order to activate
allison,
you have to chop or blend or two garlic.
So if you just throw alice,
scene itself is not sensitive to heat,
but if you don't,
if you don't chop up the garlic,
the enzymes in the garlic allison won't,
won't get activated and won't release
the allison to swallow a whole clove.
Is that what you're meaning?
If you swallow a whole club or some
people cook with whole clothes,
they don't chop them.
So if you want to,
if you're cooking with garlic,
chopped the garlic and let it sit for
like five to 10 minutes before putting
it in the heat.
Really out on a cutting board.
Exactly that because that you'll get
them,
you'll harvest the most.
Allison from allison is another one.
These plant natural plant insecticides,
it accentuates as time goes on.
Um,
so it just takes a little while for the
enzyme to release it.
So you,
it takes a few minutes.
The enzyme release,
is it,
even though this plant was picked like
maybe a week ago or a month ago or
whatever has to break the rules of the
garlic for the alice and a's to get
released,
but more of it releases over time.
That seems so strange.
No,
it's not that more of it releases.
It's just that you're,
you have to give it time to like for the
enzymes,
get activated and release it.
It doesn't take that long.
I mean honestly if you were to wait like
five minutes,
you'd be fine probably,
but I'm just on the cautious side,
you know,
I like to wait like five or 10 minutes.
But yes,
if you just,
if you just chop the garlic and
immediately it's the enzymes have to get
activated and then they chop it up and
then the is released.
So that just,
that takes a couple of minutes and just
seems odd to me that there's a process
once it's been picked and it's sitting
there,
it's obviously not alive anymore,
you know,
it's sitting in like a little bowl.
Yeah.
But the enzymes not active until you
break the garlic's been picked,
but it's in like a club thing,
right?
You have to open it out,
you have to get it out of the club and
cut the cell wall to activate these
enzymes.
When I don't feel good,
I chew a whole clove of garlic taste to
do that.
Yeah,
it is.
It's,
it's antimicrobial.
They have very,
very potent antimicrobial activities.
It kills a wide variety of bacteria.
When you talked about that mercer case
that you had,
and I related that to everybody because
my friend denny had a really bad case of
Murcia and I told him about your,
your situation.
He had it actually after you had been on
the podcast last time.
And I um,
I told him that his photos insane.
He's got a photo that I put on my
instagram page of his knee.
I mean,
his,
his knee got within a couple of days.
It went from being like mildly infected,
like what's going on too.
He was in the hospital for weeks.
Massive,
you know,
I intravenous antibiotics.
The whole deal.
Yeah.
Awful.
I told him about what you had done with
a grape seed extract was.
It was.
I should probably clarify.
I'm not exactly sure it was mrs because
it wasn't actually cultured,
I assume it was because it came back
like three times,
but.
So I probably one way or another.
And so I,
I took a very,
I was taking garlic pills like every
hour,
grapefruit seed extract,
every app I tend to get enough is the
garlic extract from a pill.
So yeah,
the question is,
um,
there's,
there's aged garlic and then there's
just regular garlic pills and then
there's fresh garlic.
Um,
it all depends if some,
some of the garlic that is aged has
allison in it,
but it doesn't have other mcap in it.
There's other mcap tens that are doing
other things.
Um,
what does the more competent mcap 10.
It's a,
it's a,
it's another byproduct of these plant.
You know,
insecticides and recap attends our
first,
they,
they bind mercury very well,
so they will bind mercury and like help
you excrete it,
so they bind mercury that's in your
system and you excrete it and they also,
um,
they,
uh,
do something in your brain so that they
can actually cross over the blood brain
barrier,
get into your brain and they're potent
antioxidant in the cell membrane,
which is,
it's kind of technical,
but it's hard to find antioxidants that
are in the cell membrane itself,
most of the time they're soluble in
itself,
so it's actually very good for your
brain.
Um,
but so I was taking the garlic oil,
garlic oil would have it,
should have both,
both of those.
And I was also rubbing it on my sore
topically says rubbing it on there and
taking it orally.
Grapes,
Grapefruit seed extract.
I've taken Ginkgo,
Ginkgo Biloba because that was also
shown to be,
um,
to kill a different staphylococcus
strains and vitamin C.
and I was taking this stuff like every
hour,
every hour just overloading your sister
like garlic was.
It was like massive garlic.
Um,
but the,
the,
the garlic itself,
you know,
it's antimicrobial,
but also there was a study that was
recently published,
men that had like Atherosclerosis,
they were given two point four grams of
garlic a day and it actually slowed the
accumulation of plaques in their
arteries by like 80 percent because
allison is a very potent anti
inflammatory and it helps the
endothelial cells,
helps reduce inflammation that
endothelial cells.
It's good,
it's really good.
So Allison,
it just goes on and on.
I don't even know.
There's so many different compounds,
but these are just ones we know of,
you know,
they're just,
they're doing really,
really positive and potent things.
Curcumin is one that I've been obsessed
with.
We going to talk about that later.
I took a lot of curcumin.
I take that every day.
Um,
I have been obsessed with a certain form
of it,
this formulation of it.
So I know we've talked about this before
on the podcast,
but could human,
there's a couple of problems with the
bioavailability of it.
The first is I like your stomach acid
and your intestines,
like you just can't get past that very
well.
So it doesn't actually get absorbed and
whatever does get absorbed,
it's like immediately cleared because
your body's like a toxic no go away.
Um,
so taking,
taking curcumin,
which is in Tumeric,
right?
It's in the tumor at plant,
um,
that is,
you can be taking it but not getting a
lot.
It's not doing a lot.
So.
So,
um,
there's this new formulation,
I don't know how new it is,
new to my mind knew to Rhonda a where
they take the curcumin and it's put in a
fight his own,
which is sort of like a Lyposomal,
um,
but it's a little different to liposomes
contain a chemical compound like in the
middle of it.
So they have like a phospho lipid kind
of complex that contains a compound and
it's supposed to increase
bioavailability because it gets past the
intestinal system.
And also it can just fuse with your cell
membrane and just deliver the contents
of the cell so it can bypass
transporters and all this other stuff.
Fight.
His homes are very similar.
They also have this would like this
possible lipid complex.
In this case,
they use phosphatidylcholine,
but it also disperses the compound
throughout and supposedly it like it's
supposed to be more bioavailable.
I don't know if that's really true,
but I have been reading some published
studies using this certain formulation
of curcumin in the,
in a fight his own,
which is phosphatidylcholine and the
formulation is got,
pat did a name,
it's called Meriva,
but you know,
if there is curcumin and in,
in a liposome is probably working the
same way.
I just doubt that dispersing the
molecules like within the actual
lyposomal makes that big of a
difference.
It's more about getting past.
So what this does is it gets you past
the absorption issue and it also gets
passed it because it fuses with the
cells quickly.
It gets past some of the other,
you know,
getting rid of it quickly issue.
But I've been taking it like I've been
taking at least a gram a day gram a day
of it.
And uh,
what got me really hooked on it was a
couple of studies that came out,
clinical studies that were done.
Well.
First,
there was one that showed,
um,
people that were running downhill,
like exercise,
some sort of running downhill that
caused delayed onset muscle soreness to
happen.
So whatever it was about the running
downhill caused sounding deceleration.
Is that what it is?
Rough.
You were to run a pill on your body,
on your body than running downhill is.
I don't know about your brain though.
Your brain's like,
oh no.
It's like,
no,
I'm done.
Yeah.
Um,
but it's,
it was shown to reduce the,
um,
the delayed onset muscle soreness by
like twofold,
taking one gram,
one gram twice a day.
Isn't that kind of subjective though?
When you say look,
reducing soreness,
it's so hard to gauge.
It is absolutely.
That absolutely is subjective.
And same with the other.
There's another publication where people
were given.
There's not,
there's a more quantitative quantified
publication,
but um,
this was,
that was done in people that had like
osteoarthritis arthritis.
They were given one gram.
Um,
I think it was just one grant a day,
not two grams.
Think it was one gram a day and it,
it actually reduced their inflammatory
markers by like 68 percent.
It reduced their symptoms of course,
but also there it increase their
mobility.
So they checked their mobility,
increase their mobility,
blake fourfold,
so they were actually moving more,
you know,
and so that's the reason maybe because
of the influence anti-inflammation
properties.
Curcumin is very,
very potent antiinflammatory way more,
you know,
it acts very different than a typical
antiinflammatories do,
but there was a study done in mice were
mice were given like a very high dose of
not this formulation,
just regular curcumin.
They're given like 100 milligrams per
kilogram body weight,
which is like insane.
It's like eight,
eight grams for 180 pound male,
which is a lot.
I mean it's a lot of curcumin.
What does that look like in your hand?
Big Pile probably to bowl.
I did see because I was kinda concerned
about toxicity.
I did see one study that was done on
people that had cancer.
They were given eight grams of curcumin
a day for three weeks and there was no
side effects.
I don't know.
It's a lot,
it's a lot.
Uh,
I personally think the
phosphatidylcholine complex is a better
approach because there's only one
proprietary formulation of that.
I think there's an Maria Eva and there's
another one someone recently shared with
me.
Lung,
Lung Jebediah.
So would you recommend the standardized
stuff that you get at a regular vitamin
store or.
No,
I actually think the phosphatidylcholine
complex is um,
is superior because of the bio
availability issues and because it is
fusing with your cell membrane and
getting just the biology.
I'll make sense.
Plus there's actual studies showing that
it works and you know,
there was another study,
so this mouse study where they gave them
eight grams.
What the whole point of this study was,
was they injured the mice.
They like,
they did some sort of force so far they
put forest.
It was so messed up.
Now you have no idea how many of my
killed like my,
my,
my scientific career,
I don't do it anymore.
I used to,
I'd killed hundreds of mice in the
vegans will come.
It's for Madison harvest that I would
have killed her.
You're a speciesist was so awful.
Joe,
like the awful part about this is like,
so I used to go and kill mice to get the
organs,
so I would get their livers,
which is one reason why I have a hard
time cooking liver because I'm like,
Oh God,
I wrote in liver.
Oh no,
because the consistency is like the same
as beef liver.
Um,
I get their livers and thymus and
spleen.
But with the sad part was,
is that I had gas them so I'd go to them
and uh,
as I was doing this like everyday it was
like,
fine and give me some ice.
I'm going to guess.
And you know,
I just,
I didn't care.
I mean I was one of those,
I don't know but call it,
but the thing that stirs,
here's the scary thing.
First of all,
when I first started doing it,
it was really hard and I felt really,
really bad.
Like tears.
Like I was sad.
I was,
I was like,
I can't do this.
Like,
you know,
you're not going to get your phd.
I'm like,
okay,
I'll do it.
So it was hard for me at first,
I totally got used to it where it was
like nothing,
like I didn't even think twice.
I just take a handful of them,
put them in the little box and had
gasoline.
I mean it was so fucked up.
It is.
But,
and here's the other scary part is that
then I would have long periods of time.
I'm a very empathetic person that people
to like I really am just that have long
periods of time when I didn't kill the
mice and then I'd have to go back there.
So like months would go by and then I
have to go back and do it and all of a
sudden I was like I can't do this.
And I couldn't watch them.
They'd start breathing,
you know,
and trying to gasp for air and I just
felt awful and so I'm just glad I don't
do that anymore.
I moved onto humans,
take their blood,
but the,
it's better for them that way.
It's better.
Yeah.
You're helping them.
So,
you know,
the,
the mouse stuff,
man,
it was,
there was you like when you have to do
something and you know,
I was medical science doing cancer
research.
I wasn't just doing it for fun,
but it was definitely um,
is strange feeling to like feel that
desensitized sensitizer I'm like,
Whoa,
wait,
and I've been doing this for like four
years.
Why am I all and caring about this
again?
Just take a little break.
Yeah.
Because I was doing other experiments
that didn't require that I had to kill,
kill mice and get their liver.
But.
So would you recommend taking regular
curcumin that you get from a regular
vitamin store or do you think there's
some benefit of it?
Yeah,
absolutely.
But it's just not as much as much
because first of all,
you're not going to absorb as much of
it.
And second of all you're going to,
you know,
clear it away quickly.
Um,
but what is there a better formula of
resveratrol?
Resveratrol?
Supposedly there's some of it in wine
which they were trying to correlate with
the positive health benefits of drinking
glass of wine a day.
But as far as I understand,
it's a small amount.
Yeah.
So if five ounce glass of wine has about
two milligrams of Risperdal,
which if you're talking about this study
I talked about in monkeys,
they were given like 480 milligrams.
That's,
you know,
you're not gonna like monkey.
You're not gonna yeah.
For a monkey and you're not going to
like.
So you're not going to like have that
same effect.
And like I said,
they're a thousand milligrams was for
the clearing of the topic,
clearing away damaged cells.
But you know,
these are,
these are a little chemical,
these are chemical compounds that are
triggering something in our body and
whether it's two milligrams or 400
milligrams,
it's doing a little bit of something.
And so,
you know,
I wouldn't just throw my nose up.
I mean you're not going to like live 30
percent longer because of it,
because you drink wine,
you know,
but it's still,
you're still getting some,
you know.
So there's something to that.
There is,
there is something,
but it's not
grocery store.
He was drinking a box of one.
He drank a box of wine at night,
which they think is like eight bottles.
How did he not like die of alcohol?
Some people have like a weird.
They have a variation in their gene
where they're able to actually convert
the alcohol to acetone and Acetate,
which is ketone.
So they actually get benefits from.
It's really interesting.
Yeah.
Whoa.
I don't know.
I know.
Well clearly he's got something if you
can drink that much wine and not.
When he was telling us he was chocking
it off like it was no big deal and we're
all like,
wait,
what,
what the fuck?
Like a whole box.
Like even Brian was like a box,
a box,
a box of wine,
like a box of wine.
It's for like a large family gathering,
you know,
alcohol in high,
high doses like that.
It's not good.
You can know it.
You're going to start killing neurons
here.
It's not good.
You shouldn't do the binge where you're
taking so much of it.
But having a five ounce glass of wine
with,
you know,
two milligrams and resveratrol may not
be as bad it,
it's probably probably
some health benefit as well to this.
The mood altering shift of the relaxing,
of having a glass of wine.
I've always felt like that's something
that we shouldn't really look past.
Like having a drink relaxes you and just
whatever negative,
negative impact that alcohol has on your
liver or the toxicity,
isn't it kind of balanced out at least
on in low doses by the positive benefit
that you get from it being a social
lubricant,
relaxing you,
things along those lines.
It makes sense to me.
I mean there,
there are so many different conflicting
studies out there with alcohol that's
good for you.
It's bad,
it's good,
you know,
and,
and I think it has a lot to do with
genetics and just binge or what else are
you eating and just all these other
things.
But yeah,
if,
if someone drinks a glass of wine,
let's say they're like wound up all the
time.
It's like we were talking about before
the podcast,
but they're always like the lions coming
to get me,
you know,
it's like,
the lions coming to get me.
I gotta run.
I gotta fight off this beast.
I mean that's the stress response,
right?
That's the,
you're activating your sympathetic
nervous system,
but you know,
which is good if you're actually out in
Africa and there's a line,
but if you're not having that active all
the time is actually it,
it,
it prevents some of the feedback loops
that happen in your brain.
So when you have chronic stress like
that,
then you start to,
you start to keep making it.
Usually when you're making,
when you make stress hormone,
your body's like,
oh,
I made this.
That's enough.
It shuts it off so that stuff that goes
away so you no longer shut it off and it
just keeps going.
And that can cause you to either be
super anxious where you're like lions
there all the time or the opposite end
of the spectrum where you're like,
totally,
you just don't care about anything.
You know,
and,
and you can be like depressed.
Where it's like nothing excites you,
you know,
you're just,
you're indifferent.
So having a glass of wine,
if that chills you out and you're not
saying,
you know,
I,
I think that seems like,
you know,
okay,
if you're having a glass of wine to
chill out and yeah,
it seems like she'll announce good,
but exercise would probably be a better
way to do it.
Yeah.
What about the,
is there any benefit to stressing your
body through alcohol?
Like as you were talking about these
pesticides that plants produce,
their stress,
your body,
you have this response from exercise,
things along those lines.
Is there a risk?
When I was young I was really dumb.
I thought that smoking cigarettes might
have a good effect on your lungs because
it's like lifting way through your lungs
because your lungs would be like,
ah,
I got to process this stuff and it would
make your lungs stronger.
Like,
wasn't that.
I think that was like what doctors
believed,
like,
yeah.
Well at one point in time,
I mean I know that it was in that movie,
the aviator,
the Leonardo Dicaprio moving.
That's good.
No,
no,
no.
That's not the one I'm thinking about.
I'm thinking of the one where he was a
can.
No,
no,
no where he played.
Um,
I'm the asshole that,
that ran the FBI,
the guy who wore dresses over.
Yeah.
Your hoover when he played j Edgar
Hoover when he was young.
Only Rod Caprio,
uh,
in the scene was with his mom and his
mom was telling him,
you know,
that you're frail and you should listen
to the doctrine,
smoke cigarettes.
Like that was the thing
that they used to doctors prescribed
cigarettes to people to like increase
their vitality.
Well,
I don't know about.
I mean,
I don't know what their explanation was,
but we'll do contain nicotine.
I don't,
I know you want to,
I don't want to interrupt,
but there is one thing that absolutely
does happen from smoking cigarettes that
does benefit a certain population of
people because when you,
when you put nicotine in your body,
um,
it,
it totally normalizes something called
sensory gating,
which is what your brain does.
Your sensory gating is your brain
filtering out all this other information
information that's happening all the
time.
Like Jamie's sitting over there,
he's doing,
God knows what,
but I don't care.
I'm not paying attention because I'm
talking to you,
you know,
there's noises out here,
there's smells,
there's,
so it's like your brain is able to focus
in and not like keep all these inputs
coming at once.
Well there are people that have,
you know,
problems in sensory gating and it's
genetically related.
It's also,
there's certain dietary factors that can
play a role where they cannot do that.
And so they're getting all this input
all the time from everywhere.
So if they like walk into a room with
like a bunch of people,
they flip out.
It's like,
because it's just so they can hear all
the conversation.
It's all coming in at once.
It's like sensory overload.
So a cigarette can negate nicotine
negates it for 15 minutes,
which is why some people probably are
chronically smoking because after 15
minutes,
man,
they got to get that hit again.
Or you know,
it's coming.
A lot of people that are,
um,
schizophrenia have a sensory gating
issue.
And so a lot of schizophrenia is
actually,
I think,
I think I'm,
this is me totally just throwing this
out there.
I think that's likely why a lot of
schizophrenia,
expert chainsmokers because they're self
medicating.
That makes sense.
But I don't know,
I'm just,
that's,
that's my point.
We're talking about nicotine though.
You're not talking about the actual act
of smoking.
Nicotine.
You could take that and other forums and
nicotine is prescribe.
It wasn't prescribed a certain heart
patients.
So he doesn't have some sort of a
benefit.
I don't know the heart function.
I don't know.
I feel like it does.
I feel like there's some sort of a
medicinal benefit to nicotine itself.
Obviously not in a cigarette for him.
See if he could find that health
benefits of nicotine.
Yeah.
But Mike dumb idea was that it was like
it would stress out your lungs,
it would make your lungs stronger.
Definitely stress them out.
But is there any benefit like that with
alcohol?
Like is there any like stressing out
your body from drinking?
Is there any robustness that would be a
side effect of that.
So here's the thing with anything that's
Hormetic,
so anything that is a,
the dose is very important.
You know,
when you have something that is
stressful on the body.
If you were to be running,
if you were to run all the time,
all day,
every day,
you didn't recover,
you die.
You know,
if you're a,
if you were to sit in the sauna or a
cold or you know,
so if you were to take like two
kilograms of Bok Choy,
you know,
you'd have some problems.
It's too much.
The things that are hormetic,
two kilograms of Bok Choy would fuck you
up.
There's like woman pounds of Bok Choy,
two kilograms is kilograms.
That's a lot of
Bok Choy.
Yeah.
What does that look like?
That a lot?
Well,
a kilogram is one point two pounds.
Is that what it is?
I don't know.
Jamie.
Good goal.
I think it's one point.
Two pounds.
It sounds familiar.
So two kilograms,
two kilograms says it's about a box box,
box box box of what?
Above?
Like a big box.
I started looking at,
well that's a,
that's not a real measurement.
I don't know what a box to box you in
this room that doesn't make any sense,
but what does a kilogram.
A kilogram is one point,
two pounds,
right?
Or two point two pounds.
Is it two point two,
two point two,
two point two pounds per.
So four kilograms.
Eight point was at a point eight,
nine pounds of Bok Choy.
What is just google that?
What does that look like?
Yeah.
Google four kilograms kilograms to
pounds,
four kilograms or pounds people in
Europe.
You fucking idiot.
You don't even know the metric system.
You don't even know what the rest of
them.
You know what this is my response.
Is that Google for things like that?
Yeah.
It's hard to get even with my stupid
brain.
So that will kill you.
I'll kill you,
but it might give you greater goiter
like,
like it because,
um,
what does goiter?
It could basically cause hyperthyroid.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Really?
Yes.
That's crazy.
Well,
the thing about the isothiocyanates,
which are in Bok Choy,
is that they're anticancer.
They're good when you're,
when you're getting,
when you're eating your Kale.
And I'm talking to kilograms again,
it took two.
That's a lot.
Massive amount,
massive.
Nobody in their right mind would ever
eat that much kale or Broccoli or
whatever.
Bok Choy a day.
But if you did,
the thing is,
is that isothiocyanates can compete with
iodine transport into the thyroid.
And so if all you're eating all day,
everyday is Bok Choy,
guess what?
Your iodine.
It's not going to be getting into your
thyroid.
And so you could have some thyroid
problems,
right?
So you need,
that's just overwhelming the amount.
And this is,
and this is with anything hormetic I am
going to answer your question,
but the point that I'm trying to make is
that a lot of these compounds that are
hormetic fasting exercise,
you know,
doing cold stress,
heat stress,
these plant insecticides you need the,
the key is the dose.
So like you don't want to over it.
You don't want to have a huge,
huge dose of it,
you know.
And with the plants it's really hard to
get a huge dose.
But with exercise,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not sure that running 50 miles is
actually that good.
It's pretty,
it's pretty stressful.
It's not good.
Yeah.
So you know,
you get the point.
But with alcohol it has been shown that
in small doses it can have a slight
hormetic effect in small doses.
Well it depends.
Like,
I don't know if these studies have been
done in humans yet,
but like probably like,
you know,
like a,
like a small glass of wine,
there is a slightly hormetic effect now.
Now keep in mind there are other things
that can regulate that,
you know,
people are different.
We all have different genes and so for
example,
I cannot recover from a large dose of
alcohol like Dan Ken because my,
I have a certain gene variation and a
gene that does not repair damage from
two neurons very well,
you know,
so there are other things to keep in
mind,
but yes,
that has been shown in small doses,
at least in animal models like flies,
more arms that small dose of alcohol can
actually have a hormetic effect.
And that's with any class to actually
define a chemical compound as hormetic.
The,
the,
the in science,
the definition is like there's this,
there's a u shaped curve,
so when you have just enough of it,
you get a positive effect,
but when you go over that threshold you
start to have a negative effect and
that's,
that's with,
that's what stress,
when we're talking about good stress,
we're talking about,
we're not talking about exercising all
day,
every day.
We're talking about exercising,
you know,
getting,
pushing past and in getting some of that
huge issue with martial artists,
with the fighters because they always
feel like if they do more they will have
more endurance and there'll be able to
perform better inside the octagon or
inside the ring or whatever they're
wrestling mat,
whatever the competing on and it becomes
a real issue with people because
overtraining is a giant factor in
preparation because they get to the
point where the body can't recover from
the work that it's done and their mind
and their,
their actual,
their mental toughness and their
discipline has actually ruined them
because they've,
they've gone too far.
They started getting chronic injuries to
big issue right now.
So there's that tipping point we have to
realize like what is the right amount of
work for and the right amount of
recovery versus people who they feel
like,
well,
if you just push yourself further,
your body will respond.
If you put.
There's.
There's a lot of people that have had
that attitude that if you can just,
it'll be hard.
You might feel overtrained the
beginning,
but your body will compensate.
You.
Body will eventually upregulate and get
ready.
Get ready for this increased workload.
The manning on it.
Yeah,
prepare for war.
Well,
I mean there's some truth to that.
You know,
you do want to push yourself and your
body will,
you will have a strong stress response,
but you have to recover.
You can't,
you can't,
you can't.
If you.
The dose is very important.
So if you push yourself beyond,
it's just like you're not going to have
a recovery period,
like you're not going to be able to.
Isn't it
important than to build your base over a
long period of time then?
Because you would build your endurance
slowly where you slowly increase the
base.
You make sure that your recovery is
consistent and then just keep doing it,
monitoring it over a long period of
time.
Then once you have a very high base,
then really ramp it up and then go
through like a
training camp.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
Nobody does that though.
That makes sense.
I mean,
that would,
that makes logical,
that makes sense.
And,
and,
and even for some of these,
these uh,
plant,
you know,
compounds to like in that Rivera trial
setting,
the monkeys,
the first year those monkeys were
actually given us a smaller dose.
They're giving 80 milligrams for the
first year and the second year they were
given $400.
Very interesting.
Right?
They started and,
and back to your resveratrol.
I don't,
I don't like I have to.
There's so many compounds.
There's so many brands out there that
are just utter crap.
They have like filler and you know,
you think you're getting Akinesia but
you're not,
you're getting some,
some kind of magnesium steroids or
something.
So I'm,
I'm,
I'm interested in the,
is virtual.
I'm interested in a lot of these other
plant compounds.
I like to get,
it's one of the reasons why I like to
eat a wide variety of plants.
You know,
celery,
Parsley,
you know there's,
oh,
there's stuff in like apple peels and in
green tomatoes,
so ursolic acid in apple,
skin and tomato dean and green tomatoes.
They actually inhibited gene in your
skeletal muscle called atf four.
That gene actually starts.
It prevents protein synthesis from
happening,
so it stops your muscle cells for making
proteins.
So inhibiting that means more protein
synthesis and that's been shown in mice,
like if they're giving really high dose,
like point two,
seven percent are solocasts and point
zero,
five percent tomatoes and they can grow
that,
increase our muscle growth by 30 percent
over what they would do if they didn't
have it.
That's insane.
Yeah,
but they were giving them a huge dose
still.
That's amazing.
It's amazing.
Thirty percent is like,
that's.
Steroids can do that.
Yeah.
Well there's these,
these are now out in the market as,
as far,
you know,
foreign nutraceuticals,
I guess you'd call them muscle builders.
They're all into it,
but the,
you know,
but you can eat.
I like to eat apples.
I like to,
I like to make,
um,
actually I don't make it.
I buy it already made,
but it's to tomatillo sauce.
Have you ever tried that?
It's really good on eggs and put them on
eggs and every time I'm drunk I'm eating
it.
I'm like,
ah,
missiles,
muscles.
How bizarre.
Um,
is rose virtual something you should
take with food?
Empty stomach.
How should you take that?
You know,
because I've been so skeptical of the
field for so long,
I've not supplemented with it.
I mean,
I did for a little while.
Um,
I'm looking back into it just because
now I'm interested.
Now I'm very interested.
I,
there's,
there's also someone pointed out to me
because I,
um,
I did a post on this and they said that
was vera trawl was shown to negate some
of the high intensity interval training
gains or something.
I didn't read the study.
I don't know exactly what that means,
but I'm.
Brisbane all has been shown to actually
cause a mitochondrial biogenesis and
shift muscle fibers to type one which
are more endurance.
The thing is that Raspberry Charles,
not like an antioxidant,
it's not like taking vitamin E,
the difference between taking an
antioxidant or to even taking like
Ibuprofen,
like if you do these studies,
studies have been done where they've
shown that taking like Ibuprofen or
taking supplemental vitamin A,
you know,
after a workout or while you're working
out can blend some of the positive
benefits from it.
And the reason is because when you
exercise you are,
you know,
you're causing stress.
Like we were talked about,
talked about you're causing
inflammation,
you're causing,
you know,
reactive oxygen species to form and this
is very important for the stress
response.
That's,
that's why you have a positive effect.
But if you're taking something like
vitamin D,
vitamin e actually like it's like a
sponge it like goes around and stuff and
he's like,
oh,
here's a reactive oxygen species or an
inflammatory that just stops.
It sucks it up.
And ensades,
you know,
they,
they stopped the inflammatory mediators
from being produced,
revere,
trawl,
curcumin,
you know,
these plant insecticides,
they don't work that way.
They actually are stressful themselves
and so they activate these anti
inflammatory genes,
antioxidant genes,
all this good stuff.
So it's a very different,
you know,
then then taking,
um,
an and an antioxidant or an anti
inflammatory and implement those nsaids
or they're not really good news in my
opinion,
they're,
they've been shown to increase heart
attack,
heart attack and has been shown and say
it's.
And so if there's an FDA warning label
on every Ibuprofen bottle and all that,
you can buy in the market.
So that's bad for you.
So,
well,
it's nonsteroidal,
anti inflammatory,
right?
Yeah,
it's Ibuprofen.
Yeah.
The thing,
the thing with some of these,
it depends on the type of,
of um,
and said,
but with,
with Ibuprofen and other ones.
So ibuprofen targets.
The way it's an antiinflammatory is it
targets one of these enzymes called Cox
two and it stops Cox two makes inflammed
it makes leukotrienes,
and excuse me,
trump thromboxanes,
which caused platelets to aggregate.
They also cause inflammation.
It makes this other chemical that's
involved in pain.
So when you stop that enzyme from doing
that,
then you're going to have less
inflammation.
You're going to have an inflammation
causes pain,
right?
So,
so you're going to have an anti pain
believing that you're going to have a
pain relieving effect.
The problem is,
is that when you inhibit,
again,
we get back to biology and feedback
loops and you know,
our,
our biology,
we've,
even though this enzyme,
Cox two causes inflammation,
it's also an anti inflammatory at the
same time,
Cox to also,
it's important for making sure platelets
don't aggregate too much.
So at the same time it's doing something
that's making them migrate.
It's also like,
okay,
let's keep this in check and let's make
sure it doesn't go overboard and it also
makes something else,
um,
that's important for relaxing,
smooth,
smooth the smooth muscle cells in your
blood vessels.
Um,
and also it releases nitric oxide.
So when you spoke that enzyme to
blocking the inflammation and pain,
but then the,
um,
the smooth muscle cells become stiff and
you make less nitrogen oxide.
So,
which is important to relax the blood
vessels.
And that can be bad.
If you are a stiffening your vessels a
lot and you have plaques,
the plaques can then,
you know,
kind of come off and get clogged and you
have a friend who takes that shit every
morning.
He'd runs a lot,
he runs a lot and he takes it every
morning and he'll take it before he
runs.
So he probably,
oh,
that's not.
First of all,
I'll send you this study where at
blended the gains from exercise.
Like it really is new.
Cameron hanes get off that shit.
I mean women.
So there was like eight different
clinical trials that were done and this
is what made the FDA put a warning label
on all ibuprofen bottles is because
chronic use increased the risk of stroke
and heart attack twofold.
And the,
and the Mecca,
there was a study that was published a
few months ago,
um,
that was done in animals that showed the
mechanisms.
So it showed exactly what was wrong with
inhibiting Cox to,
um,
I've been very concerned because I know
that like almost every female that I
know takes it once a month,
they'll take it once a month is a,
if you're chronically taking it every
month,
you're taking it for a week,
one week out of every month and you're
taking it every month.
So really it should be reserved for a
pretty significant injury where you are
in real pain in my opinion.
Look,
I don't know,
maybe taking it one week out of them it
chronic use in this wasn't,
this was done in,
you know,
there's eight different clinical
studies.
Chronic use.
To me,
chronic use is taking it every month.
So once a month would be.
I mean it.
So if you get so drunk that you're
fucked up and you're hung over and
wrecked once a month,
that's chronic use.
Then people take that for hangover.
Yeah.
I don't know if you're,
if you're,
if you're getting ripped,
if you're drinking a lot of alcohol
going,
would you consider that chronic use?
So most people wouldn't.
Most people think chronic users like
every weekend,
so once a month is enough that you don't
have enough time to recover from the
damage,
is that what you're saying?
I think that once a month if you going
overboard like that to me.
Um,
I,
you know,
I don't really have any evidence that
once a month.
In fact,
I know there have been some studies that
have to look into that.
I would think that going out and binge
drinking once a month is probably not
the best thing.
You know,
you can handle it more when you're
younger,
but especially as you get older are our
capacities to handle that type of stress
or decreased,
you know.
So to me,
especially as you're getting older,
you're probably not,
you're probably doing more damage by
doing that.
What I was getting at,
would you be as concerned with someone
taking your Ibuprofen once a month as
you would be someone binge drinking once
a month?
I am concerned about Ibuprofen but,
but I don't know.
I don't.
I don't know actually.
I've never heard anybody talk about
negative effects of Ibuprofen,
Ibuprofen.
I'm the selective Cox two inhibitors or
even worse,
which are,
I don't know the brand names for them.
Cox,
Ibuprofen targets Cox two,
but it also targets Cox one,
so it's not as bad as the selective cox
to only inhibitors,
but um,
that,
this was big news.
It's like,
you know,
the fact that the,
even the FDA,
even finally it was like,
wait a minute,
something's going on here.
We got to at least put a warning label
on these ibuprofen volumes.
They started doing the,
I'm probably like eight months ago,
seven or eight months ago.
Wow.
That's very recent.
We consider this would have been taking
Ibuprofen.
Yes.
And I've been very concerned about my
mom.
I actually got my mom this,
this Maria.
Here it is FDA drug study after.
Wow.
This July strengthens warning that non
aspirin,
nonsteroidal,
anti inflammatory can cause heart
attacks or strokes.
You.
So you're so used to saying things like
ensades.
Most people are like,
what the fuck?
I haven't started me.
No worries.
The US Food and Drug Administration is
strengthening existing label warnings
that non aspirin,
nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs
increase the chance of heart attack or
stroke.
Wow.
Based on our comprehensive review of
safety information,
we're requiring updates to drug labels
of all prescription nonsteroidal anti
time fly.
Now this says prescription prescription,
but if you.
But ibuprofen is Ibuprofen.
So if you take a regular pill that has
200 milligrams you by prescription,
it's 800 milligrams.
I always take four.
So four is 800.
Anyway.
So if you take for advils,
it's the same as a prescription.
Nonsteroidal anti inflammatory.
If I ever take it,
which I rarely do.
I always just,
I'm a dummy.
I always just go for the full dose did
I've been.
So I got my mom.
It seems to be a big problem for women
because like I said,
they take it for menstrual pain,
so they're,
they're prone to like rely on that.
And like every woman I know relies on
it.
Like for,
it's like you know what a little bit of
pain is.
Okay.
And you actually,
like,
I haven't had,
I haven't taken ibuprofen except with
the exception of like if I have,
if there's some like surgery or
something where I'm like,
Ugh,
they're required to take it,
but I haven't taken it in six years.
Like I avoid it and I just,
I deal with pain,
menstrual pain,
but,
and other pain,
I just like,
I just don't,
it's not,
it's not that big of a deal,
you start to get used to it.
Um,
but I got my mom this,
this Meriva,
this curcumin and phosphatidylcholine
complex.
And I told her I was like,
take four of these a day,
which is two grams because she's got
arthritis and all sorts of chronic pain
and I have to,
it's hard for her.
I'm trying to like get her on the right
diet and all that.
But compliance is an issue.
But if she starts to notice some changes
with something easy and it's like,
oh,
I do see this kind of working,
you know,
so that's Kinda my goal.
But she said it's been helping with her
with her pain.
And also,
um,
she's like,
she's more mobile and stuff,
so I'm from the catechumen.
I'm,
I'm actually like,
I'm thinking that it's the,
it's the.
So there was a study that I did,
I tell,
did I talk about the study that was done
that compared it to Ibuprofen.
So this clinical study that compared
people that took the Maria va curcumin
in the foster pedal,
colon complex,
um,
they took two grams a day and it was
comparable.
The anti pain relief is comparable to
800 milligrams of Ibuprofen or thousand
milligrams of Acetaminophen.
Acetaminophen can be bad for the liver
and cause liver toxicity.
That's pretty awesome that it was
comparable?
Yes.
And comparable as far as the results
through subjective.
I'm like,
what was the,
how they measure it?
I don't remember.
Is that inflammatory markers or was it
like a subjective?
I don't think so.
I don't think other other ones have
measured inflammatory markers with that
curcumin and phosphatidylcholine.
But I don't think this a particular
study did.
I think it was subjective,
but they didn't know what they were
getting.
It was control.
It was like double blind controlled.
So they were there getting something
right.
So it's just a matter of like them on a
one to 10.
How much relief did you get?
That kind of thing.
I don't know.
I have to look back at the study.
I don't remember it.
It's most likely subjective though.
It's nice.
I have a hard time believing you don't
remember anything if so much shit stored
up in your brain.
Come flying out.
What do you have room for?
Like friends' names and birthdays and
stuff.
Was it even in the calendar?
Um,
the other question that I wanted to make
sure that I asked you,
because we talked about this through
email was I know that you've done a lot
of work on the benefits of Sauna and the
heat shock proteins from sauna and I was
asking you because I recently,
not recently,
but over the last year really got
heavily into hot yoga and I'm like,
I wonder if that's what's going on here
because I leave those classes and I
swear to God a fucking asteroid could
hit my car and I'd be like,
well I guess I don't have a car anymore.
Sot Nom nom I stay like you.
You get so chilled out from doing that
there.
There's some,
there's,
there's something going on that's akin
to some sort of a drug response.
I think I talked about this before
because when you're hot,
when you're working,
when you're doing hot yoga,
you're releasing dynorphins and the
reason you released I norfund is because
it cools the body and your body's like
when you're,
when you're heating the body,
your body tries to cool itself.
When you're cooling the body,
the body tries to heat itself,
right?
So,
so this is what's happening.
When you're doing,
when you're doing the hot yoga,
you're making dynorphins dynorphins.
So while you're doing it,
it's kind of like physically
uncomfortable.
You're holding these poses and you're
like,
ah,
you know,
when you get out,
because of the whole effect on the new
opioid receptor,
you have more of them.
That endorphin that you released or that
endorphin you're going to release an
hour later when you see your kids or
whatever good thing happens,
man,
it's going to be like awesome.
It's going to feel really good.
No,
it's incredible.
It's incredible.
That's what I,
that's what got me into the sauna and
the first place when I was in graduate
school because was me waking up once a
week and screaming and like flying
across the room,
punching mirrors and I literally broke.
I broke a mirror with my.
But while I was injured I was injured
for.
Wait a minute.
Where was the mirror?
It was one of those mirrors that you
like buy at target and it's like you can
stick a full body mirror to see jumped
out of the bed and like throw yourself
at it.
Well we had it like against the wall,
but it wasn't hung on the wall so it was
like cleaning cars cheap and whatever.
Just busy.
Whatever it does,
it's serving a function.
I can see myself.
So I like,
it was kind of close to the bed so I
like flew off the bed and like hit the
mirror with my butt and broke it.
And I was injured for like,
there was like two months I couldn't
run.
I couldn't do,
I couldn't do squats,
I couldn't.
I was like,
if I didn't have the sauna in the
mirror,
is that what you're saying?
But you know,
I like muscle tendon.
I don't know.
I have no idea what I did all from
sleep.
From anxiety,
yes.
So crazy.
But you can see why.
Like when I discovered the sauna I was
like,
wow,
this is.
Because I would go,
I would go to the sauna.
I lived across the street from the MCA
and so the YMC has a sauna and I would
wake up in the morning and I'd go work
out or do the sauna both,
you know.
So I'd go and I sit in the sauna for
like 30 to 45 minutes.
I mean I was pushing it and I was
miserable.
It was hot and,
and there are times when I would stay in
there for 45 minutes.
I'm not recommending people do this,
I'm just telling you what I have
experienced and I'd get out for five
minutes and then I go back in,
you know.
So I was like,
I just pushed it and that would go into
the lab and it didn't matter who was
stressing me out.
He was telling me what to do,
what or if my experiments were failing
and I was like,
oh my God,
six months of work down the drain,
you know,
like,
I didn't care.
I was like,
oh,
okay,
I'll have to start over after we think
this.
Like,
wow,
it was.
So I was like,
that's when I looked and I was like,
something's going on,
something's going on.
I got to figure it out.
I want to know.
And that's when I like started just
going into the brain effects on the
sauna.
Everyone always focuses on the
detoxification and all that.
I was like,
dude,
something's happened in my brain.
I don't know what I'm saying,
dude.
All the time.
It's like a nervous thing to do.
Not usually do that.
I'm not really.
Not all the time I'll say dude,
but not like,
not like you're wired,
you fired up.
Um.
So do you think that a similar effect is
happening when you're doing hot yoga?
Even though it's not as hot as a,
the sauna,
it's 90 minutes at 104 degrees and
you're doing physical activity,
you're straining.
Anything that's causing you to sweat is
gonna cause you to release the endorphin
because you're,
you're,
you're overheating,
right?
That's the way your sweat is supposed to
help you.
Cool.
So you're also releasing dynorphins.
There hasn't been a study on hot yoga.
I get this question a lot.
There hasn't been a study on steam
rooms.
There hasn't been a study will.
There hasn't.
There's been a couple of studies on hot
baths are a Jacuzzi's,
but not looking at the brain,
looking at other things.
I'm personally,
if you just think about the mechanisms,
I think that it's very likely and if
you're gonna,
if you're pushing yourself to sweat,
if you feel uncomfortable,
then you're,
you're,
you're doing the right thing,
you're releasing dynorphins and you're
getting the heat shock proteins.
You're getting all that good stuff.
So it makes sense.
Yeah.
So it's in it.
It is very addicting.
It's also part of the reason why
exercise can become addicting.
People always,
always attributed to the endorphin
release.
I actually think it has a lot to do.
Also with the dynorphins,
the pain you experienced,
the discomfort you experience is very
important,
uh,
because you're actually then having that
response that hormetic you can almost
think of it as a hormetic response
because the discomfort is what's causing
you to make more of the new opioid
receptors that you're more sensitive to
the endorphin and more sensitive to
that.
Um,
feel good stuff.
It's funny because that's one of the
main things that people try to avoid in
life is discomfort.
That is probably,
if you,
if you looked at especially lazy people,
you looked at the primary thing,
they try to avoid the turn.
Avoid Discomfort.
Yep.
Like this,
this morning I woke up and I was like,
I have to go to gym,
have to go and have to,
like,
I got to like push it and I was running.
I was doing sprinting on the treadmill.
Usually I,
I,
uh,
usually a sprint,
like the last end of my run,
but I was just spreading and I was like,
so I was doing it.
I was like,
oh,
this sucks,
but I have to do it because I'm,
my brain is going to help me.
The dynorphins and also the
norepinephrine norepinephrine,
which is um,
you release when you exercise,
release a lot of it in the cold.
I took a cold shower to cold shower was
like a pretty good as well because the
cold also norepinephrine released nor
nor epinephrin when you're exposed to
cold because norepinephrine causes
vasodilation.
And so when you have vasodilation,
you actually are losing less heat.
I always take cold showers after hot
yoga.
It's amazing in the winter because in
the winter there was actually cold
because of water here is not really that
cold because it's California.
If it gets cold out it's like 50,
but when it's 50 the water's actually
cold.
So like after a hot yoga you get in
there.
It's really uncomfortable.
It's hard to breathe,
you know.
But when I lived in Boston,
there was a guy named Bob a roller that
I used to do taekwondo with this guy in
the middle of January.
We take cold showers and he'd say that
it's good for the spirit and he was
like,
the only guy that would do it,
everybody would just stand there and
watch them.
Bob's going to go in the shower and he
go in the shower by himself and to
obviously by himself.
We're like,
we're going in the shower with him,
but this guy would take these cold
showers and I just.
I couldn't imagine why anybody would put
themselves through something like that,
but I guess he kind of knew even back
then there was some sort of a benefit to
standing in that freezing cold water and
just not just mentally as far as like
your discipline and your self control to
be able to stand there and force
yourself to do something like that,
to have that sort of autonomy over your
body like that,
but also because there's,
there's all these different releases,
these powerful endorphin releases that
you're getting from that.
Yeah,
it feels good.
It feels really good.
Is there any danger in going from say,
a hot yoga class to cryotherapy?
I would love to know the answer to that,
so I've.
I've recently experienced,
um,
I've,
I've gone from a really hot sauna,
like crazy hot.
I mean it was like 180 degrees
Fahrenheit.
Yeah.
I had to wear one of those hats.
It was crazy hot,
like the hottest I've ever experienced.
So I went and I was with an acquaintance
of mine,
um,
and then I went directly into an ice
bath and I did four rounds of this,
like for,
and it,
like the experience itself was amazing.
Like I felt really,
really good,
like euphoric entering.
Well I was in the cold.
Well,
once you go in the ice bath and you go
back into the sauna,
like,
and you're in 180 degree Fahrenheit
Sauna,
it actually feels like room temperature
and it's kind of like,
whoa,
this is something kind of cool about it.
Like you just,
you feel really,
really good.
Um,
I,
there were points when I started to get
a little light headed and spinny so
spinny and it was maybe low blood
pressure,
low blood glucose.
I hadn't,
you know,
I don't know,
something like that.
But I'm,
I'm,
I'm really wanting to know and I have to
look into the literature,
you know,
I put,
I just recently put out a report and a
podcast on cryotherapy and the benefits
of cold,
but I really was hoping to find more on
going from hot to cold because mostly
one I felt so good.
And the other thing it does it reset my
circadian rhythm completely.
Like I just,
I went to bed at like 9:30
and I slept like a baby.
It was like,
how do you think it did that?
I don't know.
I think that there's something,
I don't know if it was the hot cold or
just the cold,
um,
ics.
So I,
so I did this around 6:00
so it was like right before bedtime,
but I'm cold.
Does,
you know there is a circuit,
there is a regulation of when your body
starts to cool itself and it cools
itself right before sleep.
Melatonin plays a role in that.
When you make Melatonin,
it actually starts to cool the body a
little bit as well.
I really don't know,
Joe.
I was trying to figure it out,
people aren't doing studies on it,
but it was very real and I experienced
it.
Is there a difference between doing cold
before you go to the bed and doing a
song before you go to bed?
As far as the results I'm doing,
the sauna sometimes can actually like
immediately keep you up,
but also it's.
It affects rem sleep and that's been
shown and piglets as well and Dan swears
that he would have all sorts of lucid
dreams.
I don't remember.
I don't really remember that aspect of
it,
but it does seem to affect sleep,
so lucid dreams from like the heat or
something.
Probably not.
Maybe.
Maybe something else going on in the
brain.
You also do release norepinephrine from,
from anything.
That's when you,
when you're stressing your body,
when you're doing your workout,
good enough.
Like any sort of stress.
Also a stimulation like novelty
releases,
norepinephrine and that,
you know,
maybe Acetylcholine is being released.
I don't know.
You know,
they're,
they're calling.
It does have some sort of a positive
effect on,
on dreaming,
right?
Yeah.
People report really intense lucid
dreams from taking a lot of different
nootropics,
but particularly Coleen,
someone was telling me about galantamine
because I was talking about it before
and someone was like,
Oh,
this causes lucid dreams.
I wouldn't have known that,
but there's some.
Yeah,
there's some,
some aspect.
Five htp as well.
Five htp may be beneficial to lucid
dreaming.
Something about
that's strange because Serotonin in the
brain gets you out of it.
It takes you out of rem sleep.
Serotonin
takes you out.
So if you were going to take five htp
should take it in the morning,
then
I don't know what the whole half life
and all that.
I mean it has to like five htp has to
then get into your brain and then be
converted to Serotonin and
I don't know,
so it might actually be good to take it
at night and then by the morning rolls
around,
it's done converting it.
No.
Okay.
Sorry.
Um,
the,
what would it take to do some sort of a
study like the study that has been done
on the sauna for something like hot
yoga?
What would you do that,
let's see,
it depends on what you want to measure.
So I think if you want to look at heat
shock proteins,
um,
you could look at them in blood cells,
so you can measure them in blood cells.
You could look at,
you could measure norepinephrine from.
There's actually a biomarker of
norepinephrine that is called salivary
Alpha amylase and it's released in
saliva.
And actually it would actually be
really,
that would be a marker,
like if your workout,
if you're pushing your workout hard
enough,
you'll release more of that Alpha
amylase,
some more,
more norepinephrine,
so you can measure that.
And then hsps.
So you just have to have volunteers and
then sauna,
then you'd have to have a lot of people
that are gonna,
you know,
take the blood,
you have to have physicians involved and
then you have to have people that are
gonna,
you know,
isolate and look at the protein.
Maybe even looking at gene expression
would be cheaper.
I'm doing something similar but not with
sauna.
I've been involved in a clinical trial
with blueberries.
Actually another one of those plant
hormetic compounds.
There's another one in blueberries
called Anthocyanins,
which is really,
really,
blueberries contain a small amount of
territory.
They contain very late,
about 10 percent of a grape skin has.
So the blueberries,
what,
what's really good.
And blueberries is called anthocyanins.
Anthocyanins are produced as a response,
you know,
they're,
they're a plant insecticide.
Uh,
they actually like they bind to a
certain gene,
the Anthocyanin itself recognizes like a
little sequence of DNA and turn and bind
to the street and like turns it on.
And this gene is called NRF two and it's
like a master regulator of all these,
like really good repairing DNA repair
enzymes.
I'm antioxidant enzymes,
anti-inflammatory,
all these good things.
Um,
and so I've been involved in a clinical
trial for the past two,
maybe even two and a half years now
where,
um,
my colleagues and I,
we've been looking,
we've been taking blood from people that
are,
they're obese.
Their BMI is about 28 or above.
They're obese.
Their insulin 28 is,
he is obese.
Well,
they also measure BMI is 30 is actually
obese.
We moved it,
we moved the BMI down to 28 because it
was like we weren't getting enough
people.
A 30 is technically considered obese.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean a lot of people were 30,
right.
You have to consider BMI is not a really
good measure of obesity because people
that are very muscular and short may
also have a high BMI.
So you have to also look at waist
circumference and other factors which,
which they are doing.
Um,
but,
but there are a lot of obese people.
There are,
there are a lot of obese people and
we're looking at a certain percentage of
them that are right on the border of
becoming type two diabetics.
So they're insulin resistant so their
body is not responding to insulin but
they're not type two diabetic clinically
yet.
Um,
and so we're,
we're,
we're getting rid recruiting these
people and we've gotten 50 of them and
half of them are getting a freeze dried
blueberry powder that's equivalent to
two cups of blueberries and it's got
lots of anthocyanins and all this other
stuff that's in the blueberries.
And the other half is getting a placebo
drink,
which is blue looking and they put sugar
in it,
which is.
But yeah,
you gotta you can't give someone a
placebo and not.
And not taste like blueberry.
Right.
Is there any benefit to eating actual
blueberries versus the freeze dried
powders?
Yeah.
You're getting the fiber,
you know,
you're,
you're getting probably that's the main
thing,
that fiber and who knows what other
compounds that may be not maybe
destroyed somewhat by the freeze.
Dry.
I don't really,
that's what I would be confused about
them.
I've always been confused about that.
And when you see the various freeze
dried,
you know,
anything or any,
any sort of dried,
powdered anything,
I always wonder like how much of that
are you actually giving?
Like what,
what,
what's,
how much of the actual benefit is lost
in this turn?
Turning it into a pill.
Yeah.
So there's definitely some,
some things that are lost,
but the specific things that I'm
interested in,
like the anthocyanins are there.
Um,
but so what I've been looking at it,
there's other people that I'm working
with are looking at,
um,
you know,
markers of inflammation,
glucose response,
like all the metabolic parameters.
I'm specifically looking at people's
damage to their DNA.
So like we get white blood cells and the
frozen down and then I look at the DNA
and the white blood cells and see how
much damage there is.
I do it at baseline.
So before they start the blueberry
powders and these people have a lot of
damage because they're obese.
Obesity accelerates,
damage to DNA,
damage to DNA causes all sorts of
problems.
But eventually it leads to cancer.
And people that are obese have a twofold
increased risk of multiple cancers.
Ridiculous article that I read were
talking about the positive benefits of
being overweight and were
where people were trying to justify
being overweight and they were.
I'm talking about there's a certain
illnesses that people recover from
better if they're overweight.
And they were very few very strange
examples they were using.
They try to justify being overweight.
And um,
and it was also the article was also
impartially in response to quote unquote
fat shaming,
you know,
and I'm like,
boy,
this is just such a weird justification.
It's so bizarre that your,
your very biology,
very the thing that gets you through
life,
that people are so intent on receiving
mouth pleasure,
which is all it is.
I mean,
that's what you're doing when you're
shoveling food in your mouth,
you're getting mouth pleasure and then
you're getting the response,
the,
the physical response to whatever sugars
or anything that you,
you,
you know,
your,
your body and your gut bacteria craving.
But so,
so much into that you're broadcasting it
in the form of this is like really
misleading article that was just
designed to make you feel better for
being overweight and to justify these
choices that you've made,
which are terrible,
terrible choices.
Like there's no benefit whatsoever to
being overweight,
right?
No,
I mean,
being overweight,
being overweight is linked to increased
risk for cardiovascular disease,
increased risk for type two diabetes,
increased risk for cancer,
increased risk of stroke in prison.
You know,
it's,
it's increased rate of Alzheimer's
disease.
It's yeah,
so I mean having an increased risk for
all of those age related diseases is not
good to them.
Articles written about the positive
benefits being overweight.
I haven't seen those.
You see if you can find some of that
Jamie,
people that are fat that are just trying
to use confirmation bias and locked into
whatever small,
weird statistic might exist in regards
to like maybe they'd get over like a
cold better or something.
It's like it's really dumb.
Actually.
Obesity starts to cause I'm
immunosenescence because and and
problems with your immune system because
people that are overweight or obese,
they,
they have a lot more inflammation in
their body and inflammation takes a lot
of energy.
Here it is.
Five surprising health benefits of being
overweight.
Being overweight carries a reduced Chris
Rheumatoid arthritis.
It's because your joints are all greased
up.
I'd like to see the references on that.
Being overweight means
you're less likely to develop dementia.
Being overweight can make a stronger
immune system.
Yeah.
See,
that's one of the things that I had
read,
like what?
Hold on.
Is it possibly to be fit healthy and
fat,
to be fats to Farian?
What does that mean?
Frat staffy in what does that.
What does that word to protect your body
from possible harm.
Rendering potential problems.
Harmless even before incursion to
explain on a slightly more plain level,
the cytologists are proposing that
you're extra bulk works like a blubbery
barrier.
Indeed,
the big men,
Danny Ross who was stabbed,
all that's different that someone was
stabbed.
Somebody fell 20 feet and Lawrence Bell
Hus,
Blah Blah Blah Blah,
or po,
po portly poster boys for the defensive
qualities of flat,
but that's ridiculous.
That's like,
that's like wearing armor.
You know you're talking about someone
like.
Yeah,
physically,
if you're that something that around
police,
if you physically,
if you have like all this extra fat on
your body and something hits you.
Yeah.
You've got like a wall between you,
your actual organs and your,
your bones and this.
This impact that's so stupid though.
Being overweight is linked to increase
longevity and recovery time.
What know?
Now it's not.
Scroll down.
I'm not saying is it okay to,
to fat shame overweight men.
Make that larger police kitten oaks,
that fat tissue as well as hormones it
releases,
improves bodily defense mechanisms by
providing vital energy reserves and anti
inflammatory agents.
As a result,
despite overweight individuals being
more susceptible to serious health
issues to begin with,
they are less likely to die from them
than those who are underweight or even
with healthy BMI is heart disease,
for example,
is four times more likely to claim the
life of somebody with a healthy Bmi than
an individual considered overweight.
This is horseshit.
It is.
This is not absolutely opposite.
No studies that the onion.
Is this a forest?
No.
What is the.
What is the website?
The Telegraph.
Whether articles too is just the one I
figured would have the scroll.
Scroll down a little further and being
overweight can mean you're better in the
bedroom.
Oh,
shut the fuck up.
This is a fat guy.
Fat Guy wrote this hormones,
found in abdominal fat,
allow men to last longer in the bedroom
bowl.
I'd like to see the references for any
of these statements because actually
it's quite the opposite.
Being overweight or being obese,
it's associated with seven years off
your life span,
extremely obese is 14 years off your
life span.
Um,
obesity is the number one risk factor
for heart disease and type two diabetes.
Um,
it also is associated with massive
inflammation.
What's this?
The Journal of sexual medicine inside on
pathogenesis.
Genesis of lifelong premature
ejaculation.
Inverse relationship between lifelong
premature ejaculation and obesity.
Yeah,
but you know what,
that's because of the obese guys aren't
getting laid and they probably jerk off
so much.
They can last forever.
This is a stupid study.
That's it.
This is an association.
There's some premature ejaculation.
Has to do with anxiety,
has to do a lot.
There's a lot of factors involved and
premature ejaculation and what exactly
is premature?
I mean it's a completely relative and
subjective term because if you come and
you enjoyed it,
it was perfectly timed.
It's not premature.
I mean it's just like you didn't hold
on.
I mean the whole idea of holding on as
long as a cultural construct holding on
as long as you can.
I mean that's just,
we've decided that that's a good thing.
I mean obviously for mutually
mutually beneficial pleasurable
experience for your partner.
Yeah,
it's probably last longer than you know,
that's what woman would like,
but.
But what is pr?
It's not premature.
The,
the,
the end goal is to try to breed.
It's try to procreate,
right?
Is if you get it in there and as long as
you get it in there,
it's not premature.
Like biologically speaking,
it sounds like it's pretty subjective
there.
Their definition of premature.
I mean what does that mean?
Let the idea that you can connect all
those things and say that there's some
sort of a positive benefit to being fat.
That's click bait bullshit.
That's what that is.
There's,
there's very
strong evidence of everything.
The opposite of what you just read.
Yeah.
Like I just don't even.
I,
I really just don't even know where they
came from.
Maybe some crappy associative studies
that were done,
but I mean the large body of,
of the literature shows the opposite,
but isn't that way confusing when you
see things like that,
like in the Telegraph that probably got
read by a million plus people or more
worldwide?
Probably even more than that.
It's irritating.
It's crazy.
Yeah,
but those are the kinds of articles that
people will use to justify their poor
life choices and this was this same kind
of thing.
Not that article in particular is what
I'd read about when someone was talking
about fat shaming.
I'm like,
come on,
man.
There's no such thing as fat shaming.
Look,
it's.
It's rude to be mean to people.
Yeah.
It's rude to like pointed someone laugh
because they're fat,
but to suggest that someone being
overweight is bad for the health is not
fat shaming.
It's just fact.
Yeah,
and it's also,
you're,
you're trying to help someone you want
to say,
look,
you know,
there,
there have we know mechanism.
We know there's been studies that show
that being overweight causes
inflammation.
It's your immune system's constantly
being active and not get crosses into
the brain and causes depression.
It causes anxiety,
it causes learning and memory problems.
So you may not be working and that's
been shown.
You may not be working at your optimum,
you know,
being overweight,
you could feel better,
you know,
so it's,
it's kind of ridiculous.
I think I agree with you and I have
friends that are overweight and I've
always been the person that I'm all,
I feel like I'm lecturing,
you know,
because it's always,
I'm always like all these benefits and I
rattle off all this stuff and all this
information and then there's a certain
point it's like this person probably has
gets defensive and doesn't want to hear
it,
but I care about them and that's
actually part of the reason I started
making videos and doing what I do
without my fitness actually because I
was constantly doing this to friends and
family members,
people I cared about where it was like
at least if you put something out there,
like if you put a video out there or an
article or a podcast or something,
they don't feel like you're targeting
them.
So then you can just go,
oh yeah,
I talked about that.
You should go check it out.
You know,
and you know what it does.
It seems because people would get less
defensive.
Well,
it seems to me that there's a certain
amount of information just won't get
through some people's wall.
They have a wall,
this is what I like to do.
I like to eat cake.
That's it.
And then you know,
like,
Hey,
KC has sugar and sugar is bad and being
obese is bad and cancer and blood
pressure and uh,
sorry it's not getting in.
I'm going home.
I'll have some fucking cake.
It's kind of a rule like that mouth
pleasure that they get from shoving that
cake and oh,
they just can't wait.
And then the craving,
you know,
we had talked quite a bit about gut
bacteria because of your experience with
probiotics and also your experience with
antibiotics from recovering from staph
infection and how devastating was to
your immune system.
I started going down the rabbit hole
with a gut bacteria after that because I
just found it so fascinating how long it
took you to recover and how a common
that experiences from large doses of
antibiotics,
how devastating it is to the immune
system to overall health wellness per
the way you feel the way you like,
your mood,
your mood.
So many different effects.
One of the things that I've found when I
was eating a lot of bread and pasta is
that I would have a good meal,
like say I would have like chicken with
maybe some vegetables or something like
that,
a nice big healthy meal and I would
still be hungry afterwards for sugar.
I would like my body.
I was stuffed like I ate like half a
chicken.
I'll eat a half a chicken and my body
was like,
we need a cookie.
I need a cookie.
Come on man.
Give me a cookie.
Like I need some ice cream.
There was,
there was,
there was some gut bacteria craving and
that's what it seemed like.
It seemed like some bizarre craving.
It wasn't a craving like I needed more
calories.
Where were you eating these?
Like was this.
Would you typically eat something that's
refined sugar?
Yes.
Oh,
okay.
Well,
yeah.
something.
This is an interesting effect and sorry
if I cut you off,
but something that does happen when you
eat refined sugars,
like something,
not a piece of fruit which has the fiber
matrix and all these polyphenols.
By the way,
polyphenols are plant insecticides.
It's all we were talking about has all
this other good stuff.
When you take the refined sugar away
from that,
what happens is when your your gut,
so your gut digest it and it refined
sugar usually is like a glucose mol.
It's 50 percent glucose and 50 percent
fructose,
and that's sucrose and that's what's in
table.
Sugar is what's in a lot of refined
sugars and what happens is that when you
cleave the sucrose in the end,
you cleaned the sucrose to this glucose
and the fructose,
the fruit toast itself doesn't get
absorbed by all the cells.
It only gets metabolized in the liver
and it does something.
It's called ATP trapping.
So what it does is it traps ATP,
which is the source of energy,
and it does this because it's trying to
like do this whole other complicated
enzymatic reaction,
blah,
blah.
Right?
But what it does is trap the ATP and
this sends a signal through the vagal
nerve to your brain.
I don't have energy,
and so you don't get satiated.
And so when you eat refined sugars,
and this is independent from the gut
bacteria craving stuff you're talking
about,
I'm not exactly sure how all that works,
but what I'm talking about is real.
It's ATP trapping and it's.
It's,
it's,
it's something that is known to be a
cause of y.
You can eat a bunch of fructose and
refined sugar and not be satiated,
and so you have to eat more because your
body,
your brain thinks you haven't been fed
because the APP has been trapped.
It's called ATP trapping.
That's one possibility that could be,
could have been happening.
It's really,
it's also why a lot of people that eat a
lot of refined sugars with sucrose or
high fructose corn syrup is the worst
when they eat that.
Why is high fructose Corn Syrup to
worse?
Because then so when your gut,
so the way your gut.
Okay,
let's just.
Let's compare table sugar.
Sucrose or high fructose corn syrup.
Both are bad,
but when you compare the two,
because sucrose is got,
it's got glucose.
I mean it's got glucose and fructose,
high fructose corn syrup does to you.
It has more fructose,
but the thing is,
is that,
um,
when it,
when the sucrose sees your gut,
your gut has something in it called sue
crazes,
which clique,
which it takes,
basically it's,
it's slower to cleave and digest the
sugar,
so it's not like a big bolus at your gut
sees,
so it's not as irritating on the gut
because it has the first,
the suit crazes have to cleave the suit
gross and so like all this stuff is
happening.
Whereas when you get the high fructose
corn syrup,
that doesn't happen.
It's a big bolus and it's like,
it literally like causes a breakdown in
your gut barrier.
It's like irritant.
It's an irritant.
The same thing can happen if you take
too much of,
um,
I mean there's lots of other things that
happen,
but if you take too much like magnesium
or something,
people can get gut irritation.
It's a big bolus on the gut and it's
irritant and that's what high fructose
corn syrup does.
And there's also then the whole atp
trapping thing is like exponential with
high fructose corn syrup,
fructose.
It's compounded.
There's a bunch of different factors.
Of course,
the fructose is very different in fruit
because the matrix,
the fiber,
it's digested differently.
It's.
It's completely different than taking a
table sugar or high fructose corn syrup.
Who's the monster that extracted that
stuff?
I mean,
it's so bad windows that done.
When do they figure out how to do that?
I mean they used to do cane sugar rose.
I don't know.
I know there's people that are super
into to all that stuff,
but yeah,
it's cheaper.
That's why it's cheaper and it's hidden.
It's in everything.
If you go out and go to a Chili's and
think they're going to eat healthy,
you order a salad and there's like 60
grams of sugar in there.
Waldorf Salad because it's all in the
dressing.
High Fructose Corn Syrup.
That's insane.
Okay.
Here it is.
The 1970.
It was first introduced to food and
beverage industry of high fructose corn
Syrup was first introduced to the food
and beverage industry in the 19
seventies.
That's amazing that that stuff from 1970
until today,
so in the the last 40 plus years has
become a massive part of our diets.
The average this was published and it
was like the Health Organization and
somewhere in the UK and whatever they
call that.
There were some health organization and
UK that that did a press release and
said that the average five-year-old
consumes 50 grams of sugar a day.
Oh my God.
Sorry.
Yeah,
50 grams to 50 grams a day or that 50
grand a year and two grams a day.
That's 50 grams a day.
Which was their weight.
It was okay.
Now I'm remembering it was.
Yeah,
it would be awesome.
It was 50 grams a day,
which was the average of their entire
body weight.
Have a five year old a year,
a year,
so if you have a bag of sugar the size
of a five year old,
five year old eat that in the year.
Exactly.
She's and I did some calculations that
comes out to like a pumpkin spice latte
at starbucks which has like 64 grams of
sugar.
It's,
it's crazy and everything.
There's a particular type of gut
bacteria,
they crave sugar and that thrives on
sugar though,
isn't there?
Um,
you know,
yeast are surviving on sugar,
but they're not gut bacteria.
You're,
there was like a,
a documentary,
an online thing that I watched on the
various documentary on different gut
bacteria,
so that attracted to,
so I don't,
maybe this is,
I know that so that your gut bacteria
with what they eat is fiber and they're
mostly in your colon.
And so when you're,
when you eat fiber deficient diet,
um,
proteins,
lipids,
sugars are all absorbed in the upper
intestine,
but your,
your bacteria in your gut starve and in
order to stop themselves from starving,
they start to cannibalize the gut
barrier that they live on because it's
got carbohydrates.
And so low fiber diet can cause massive
gut barrier breakdown.
It's actually the most in terms of
magnitude,
the most potent thing that regulates gut
health is fiber.
So is that like irritable bowel
syndrome,
things along those lines?
Well,
that can,
that can happen,
but you don't have to have irritable
bowel syndrome to have your gut barrier
breaking down.
You know,
you can have a low level of
inflammation,
not know it,
but there are certain types of bacteria
that can thrive in the condition.
Now maybe that maybe let's say you have
a low fiber diet,
meaning you're eating a lot of refined
sugar,
so it's Kinda like the same,
right?
You're eating a bunch of refined sugar
and in place of plants and fiber rich
foods,
there's a certain type of bacteria that
can thrive on low fiber and it's a type
of bacteria,
I don't know the name of,
but they have little flagella things
that like move,
you know,
sperm sperm it.
Yeah,
exactly like that.
And so they'll like swim up.
So your bacteria are supposed to be in
the colon,
let very,
very end of your intestines.
Right?
They're not supposed to be.
You're not supposed to have a bunch of
bacteria in your small intestine will.
They'll swim up to the small intestine
because that's where the food,
that's where the and the sugars and the
lipids are all getting absorbed.
They'll swim up there and this is often
referred to as bacterial overgrowth.
Small intestine bacterial overgrowth is
what the technical term is,
bacterial overgrowth is actually when
your bacteria are starting to grow in
your small intestine and what happens is
when you have bacteria in your small
intestine,
it releases something called Zonulin and
this work has all been done by Eliseo
Fasano and he's,
I think he's at like Massachusetts
Children Hospital and he discovered this
so you know,
he's a rockstar for figuring this stuff
out,
but so when you have this,
this intestinal overgrowth released
something called Zonulin.
Zonulin is also,
which are released when gluten,
when your body sees gluten Zonulin,
um,
it literally,
like you have the gut barrier and
there's like these junctions with the
barrier,
it opens up the junctions,
the tight junctions,
and then people that don't have like
Celiac or they don't have a really,
really poor gut health.
It closed.
It's like a transients like open,
close,
open,
close.
And so when they open,
your inflammatory cells can see the
bacteria that's there.
Usually the barrier separates them
because what did,
what do immune cells do when they see
bacteria fire away?
More so the small intestinal bacterial
overgrowth does that and so does,
so gluten gluten also causes Zonulin to
be released,
but um,
so that would cause like bloating and
inflammation,
you know,
things like that.
Wow.
God,
it's just so.
It's so crazy how much your diet
actually affects your overall health and
how few people really consider it when
they're thinking about what they're
eating and the consequences of what
they're eating and your brain,
what tastes good and your brand.
If it's,
you know,
having low inflammation is key for your
brain.
All these different factors that are
playing on inside your body.
Like all this stuff.
I know.
Yeah.
No,
I'm eating a diet that's high in fiber.
That's one of the reasons why I
actually,
I eat a lot of wide diversity because
there's lots of different types of
fiber.
There's you fibers,
not just like one nutrient,
you know,
people always treat at me,
oh,
can I take Pectin,
can I,
can I take insulin and you know,
which is a type of fiber.
And it's like,
well yeah you can,
but you know,
these different types of bacteria.
So many different types of bacteria and
they are,
they're eating different types of fiber
and we don't even know all what each of
them are eating.
We just,
we know the best thing we can do right
now is to get a broad spectrum,
you know,
so there's fiber in the implants,
there's fiber that are called leggins
and cellulose.
I'm in fruits,
there's pectins like apple,
a citrus appeal,
have pectins,
Beta glucans are and mushrooms.
They're an oats,
I'm resistant starches in legumes,
beans.
There's inulin which is in plants and
off like onions,
artichokes,
garlic,
and all these different types of fiber
feeding,
different types of factor.
And that best thing you want is a
diverse bacteria set.
So feeding them all different types of
fibers.
Good.
Plus you're getting all the plant
hormetic compounds and then you're
getting all the micronutrients,
magnesium,
vitaminK ,
I'm fully,
you know,
these are things that people are in,
are deficient in.
So I,
I,
I try to do that and then I eat meat.
I think there was a,
uh,
it was,
now that I'm thinking about it,
I think it was kind of like an
infomercial,
what you're talking about.
I'm talking about the candida videos.
Yes,
that's exactly what they're selling a
product,
but I don't think I made it that far.
It was long.
Five minutes.
Yeah,
it was really long and it was
disturbing.
You know,
you're talking about Candida growth in
your stomach and how your,
your,
your gut is responding to all this sugar
by this massive production of or
massive.
Here it is.
So that's what happened.
Sugar,
the cause of Candida,
Candida cause of cancer.
And sugar has been shown,
right,
to accelerate cancer growth.
Yes.
In fact that there was a study that was
just published recently were like caused
breast cancer cells to grow like four
times faster.
Whoa.
Four times faster from sugar.
Refined sugar.
Not from my wife's mom.
She's a lovely lady,
but she loves sugar.
She puts sugar in everything.
She makes Kale Salad and you eat it.
You'll like,
you're eating candy,
like everything has sugar.
Like,
you know,
it's like from her era,
that's what they did.
They put sugar in their cornflakes,
everybody would sugar and everything and
they felt like it just made things taste
good.
Like you're eating healthy food and
skittles,
sugar on it,
you know,
spoonful of sugar helps the medicine go
down.
Remember that?
Yes.
You know,
and it's just,
it's so disturbing that people grow up
thinking that this is the way to eat and
it just.
Nobody told them,
nobody warned them and you know,
she's in her sixties now and that's just
how it goes to the autonomous.
It's hard to God,
it's fucking
people.
Yeah.
I've got,
I've got loved member,
loved ones that I care about that are
also addicted to sugar and I try try
hard.
It's,
it's,
it is hard.
Especially the older you get when you're
stuck in your ways,
your brain's not as able to kind of
change as easily,
you know?
So we'll see.
So you
don't have a lot of willpower.
Some people just not good at like
saying,
okay,
this is what,
I'm not doing this anymore,
you know,
like this,
I'm done doing that.
Boom,
you know,
I don't know how other people's brains
work,
so I don't.
I don't know what the pull is,
but I know for me when when I try to
quit something like I'm going to quit
sugar,
I'm there.
Boy,
that fucking first week or so.
It was hard because the pole,
it's like there's this desire to cheap
go.
Come on man,
one cookies,
not going to fuck anything up.
It's not going to be that big a deal.
Like there's this poll to have sugar and
when I kicked sugar for,
I've done it twice now,
but the first time I did it,
one of the most disturbing things,
it was like the headaches,
like two or three days in I was getting
these headaches.
I was like,
Oh my God,
I'm getting sugar detox headaches.
Like that's what it was.
It had to be.
There was the only thing that was
different.
I was eating all the same normal things,
but I wasn't taking any sugar.
Anything that has sugar,
I wouldn't take it and I was getting
headaches it on most people if you don't
get,
if you don't have a rock solid
determined mentality for this type of
stuff,
it's really hard.
Like if you're wishy washy on your diet.
Well I'm just going to try to eat
healthy.
Like my friends have told me that before
they try to lose weight.
What are you doing?
I'm just going to try to eat healthier.
You Ain't gonna do shit.
Like you have to have like a rigid set
of rules.
You can't say I'm just going to eat
healthy because then you'll decide
you're eating healthy back fucking
cupcake's not gonna hurt anybody and
then you'll eat that cupcake and that'll
kill all your hard work.
I had no idea that you were eating
refined sugar like this whole time.
I thought you were.
You're always like vegetables.
Meat.
Yeah.
I would occasionally I would dive in.
I mean,
it wasn't like a real problem,
but it was enough that see if you eat
protein bars like the ones that Jamie
was eating over there,
what does that have it?
I love those goddamn things.
These things are great.
They taste awesome.
They're called pro bars.
I first found out about these suckers
one-on-one.
A hunting.
Oh,
come on.
Is that real?
This fucker is 21 grams of sugar in it.
This is crazy.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
It's everywhere.
It's hidden everywhere.
That is.
God damn crazy.
This is 21 grams.
You're always supposed to have 25 in a
day.
Yep,
exactly.
A whole day.
One yummy bar fucker is Alex your added
sugar fighting two or three of those in
a setting.
Like after I worked out,
I would eat two of those.
Like if I was going to in the morning,
if I was headed over here and uh,
I didn't have time to eat,
I'd throw to those down and a Kombucha.
So the Kombucha,
John Ten 10?
Yeah.
For grape grape cappuccinos.
10 plane has five.
So,
uh,
I prefer plane,
but sometimes the grape was all.
I had left,
so I'd throw it out a grape that's 10 a
throw down,
two of those.
That's 41 or 42.
Jesus Christ,
I mean 50 grams of sugar on the way over
here,
which is twice what you're supposed to
have in a day.
And then I might have a piece of cake,
you know,
I'm to eat real healthy and say I'm
eating real healthy and you know,
oh you want some apple pie folk?
Do you want ice cream on it?
Why not?
And then what's that?
It's probably another 30,
40,
50,
60,
70.
So you're winding up with 100 plus grams
of sugar in a day,
right?
Yeah.
And this,
this,
this stuff is causing inflammation in
your gut.
It's the more,
at least with you,
you were still getting some of the good
stuff though.
It's not like you were eating a fiber
deficient diet.
Yeah.
No,
I was eating healthy on top of that,
but even better than.
Yeah.
Than most people that are eating that
stuff.
This is crazy.
It's crazy.
There's a thing called a Lara bar.
You ever heard lar?
A.
They're so yummy,
they're so good,
but it makes it look like you're eating
something healthy.
It's like the wrappings earth toned.
It's like woo.
I'm like,
I'm doing yoga in a bar.
This is.
Most of those bars are really candy
bars,
you know.
I think quest nutrition
is probably like,
if I were to say that there's anyone
that makes,
makes a bar that's not a candy bar.
Quest quest has some decent ones.
Well,
um,
primal kitchens has a really good one.
It's a nut bar with dark chocolate and
it has a tiny amount of honey in it.
It's less than four grams.
I'm pretty sure less than four grams of
sugar per bar,
but it's mostly almonds and dark
chocolate.
Like a little bit of honey.
Those are really good.
They're not,
it's not sweet at all.
Those I liked those and a lot of times
I'll eat like a meat bars.
Like there's some bars.
What are the ones we have back there?
Those.
Yeah.
One of those ones we have in the back.
Jamie,
what are those things?
Quite.
Yeah.
Well,
not just the ones that we sell it on it
with.
Those other ones that I bought about
some other ones that are really good,
but even some of those have fucking
sugar in them.
It's just amazing how sneaky they are.
That God damn sure
didn't condiments.
It's in hot sauces.
Yeah.
These things right here.
So these fuckers,
this is so,
this.
I got these
damn things.
He's Paleo.
Simplified them like all go paleo bar
bullshit.
It's got a lot of God damn sugar in all
these fucking things of 15 or 19 or.
Yeah.
This one is 20 Jesus Christ.
The uh,
the lab that I was doing my postdoc in,
they,
I've talked about this before.
They,
they,
they made it,
they designed a bard intentionally to
try and fill new micro nutrient gaps in
people that are like obese.
So like it has,
it has vitamin D in it,
you know,
it has magnesium,
vitaminK has Dha,
Omega three,
it has all these good micronutrients in
it and then they try to put some dark
chocolate so that doesn't taste like
crap.
Um,
and sprinkle a little bit.
There's very little sugar in it,
but you know people don't like them
because they don't taste good.
This little fucker as 22,
this little crazy you shouldn't eat.
That disappears in my hand.
This little tiny thing is 22.
Imagine how many people are eating this
stuff.
Sugar just fucks.
I think the best thing you can do is eat
whole foods.
You can eat vegetables,
you know,
fruits are not that bad.
You can eat a pear and apple.
You can eat berries,
strawberries,
all these things they have.
They have a variety of different good
polyphenols.
These plant insecticides,
they've got fiber,
they've got some micronutrients and they
taste really good.
They taste good like a peach,
a really good peach.
Oh my God.
They're delicious and it's something
that we've gotten,
so we.
We've just gotten so used to it.
We'll take it for granted.
You know,
if you had a desert and it tastes like a
delicious peach,
you'd be like,
Ooh,
this is a wonderful dessert because it's
a peach,
like it's good for you.
Yeah.
It's almost like we want that bad for
you.
Rush.
It's like were naughty on top of the
fact that we're,
we're eating something,
we're getting like the mouth pleasure
from it and we're also getting the
naughtiness like,
Ooo,
the cake.
How much of that is a learned response
as well?
You know,
my,
my postdoc advisor or Bruce Ames,
he's 87 years old,
going on 88 and I've been to many
different dinner parties at his house
and he's American and his wife is
Italian so she immigrated here from
Italy.
But every single time I go to a dinner
party the dessert is always fresh fruit.
I mean it's just like super normal,
like it's,
it's always fresh.
Some sort of fresh fruit medley.
She'll cut up and sometimes she'll put
some little bit of some alcohol or
something on there.
I'm like,
I'm moretto or you know,
but it's always fresh fruit and that's
like,
they've been doing this for 50 years.
That's been their dessert.
Fresh fruit,
you know.
So that was good though.
He's good.
Chocolate cake is better.
Dark,
dark chocolate.
Dark chocolate has a lot of good stuff
in it,
you know?
So that the dark,
dark chocolates.
One,
I think that people that are really
craving that can can feel good because
there's,
there's ecg and dark chocolate,
which is what's in green tea.
UGC is one of those normal plant
compounds that are doing a a hormetic
response.
It's been shown to cause brain cells to
grow.
It's anti cancer,
it kills cancer cells.
It also is really good for your skin,
prevents your skin.
Collagen is being broken down and it has
a really high reading of antioxidants.
Right?
Well that's what I'm talking about.
These,
they're not.
People get confused antioxidants.
There are antioxidants in fruits and
vegetables,
but in dark chocolate,
the antioxidants are the hormetic
compounds that are causing your
antioxidant genes to be expressed is a
big difference and there's really like,
there's no comparison.
Like if you're,
you know,
you need a certain amount of vitamin E
which has antioxidant,
you need a certain amount of vitamin C
which is an antioxidant and a cofactor.
You need it to make Collagen,
but in just like the antioxidant form,
it pales in comparison to like
glutathione related enzymes.
We have super oxide dismutase.
All these systems that we have in our
body that are designed to prevent these
things called oxidation or oxidative
stress,
stress from happening.
So when you're taking,
in fact some people,
um,
they have a uh,
so we have this gene that can use
glutathione in our body,
takes the glutathione that we make in
our body and it puts it to like prevent
damage from happening to ourselves.
There are people that have more.
I'm more active version of this,
that if they take vitamin D
supplemental,
that it actually does them harm.
Really?
Yeah.
Because that,
because what happens is the body goes,
oh,
I've got this vitamin E,
it's doing that job.
And so the enzyme doesn't get active
when you have the stress there,
the enzymes not active.
This is a certain gene polymorphism in
the GSTP one gene.
So how would someone find that out
there?
What they have to have 23 and me 23 and
me,
um,
is a genetic test that tests for a
variety of these polymorphisms.
And um,
there's the,
they give a,
a report that's kind of,
they don't tell you about that gene.
You have to like,
um,
you can,
I don't know if promethium promethium
is,
is a tool that's like it costs $5.
I've talked about it before in your
podcast and you can run your 23 and me
data through it and it tells you all
these polymorphisms,
but that what you have and what they
mean.
But I also have a tool that's out today
actually,
right?
That's a,
it's a,
it's the Beta version of it,
so it's,
it's basic functionality,
but that genes on there,
the GSTP one glitter found one is on
there.
So,
um,
this tool that I've got out is free so
people can use it for free and I'm going
to add a bunch more genes to it,
but right now there's a,
there's a basic set of genes that are
interested in genes that are involved in
making vitamin D.
can you convert the vitamin D three?
You're taking into the steroid hormone
or vitamin D three you get from the sun.
Some people have a polymorphism where
they don't do that as well.
There it is right there,
there it is.
Rhonda is genetic report and this.com
forward slash genetics.
It's amazing to me that every time you
come on the podcast there's new shit
that I have to remember and it seems
like you're constantly learning things.
That's what's crazy is that you've been
studying this for so long,
but it's just you're at the tip of the
iceberg.
It seems like there's no end of this.
There's no end and we need crispr so
that I can keep learning.
It's like infinite amount.
I mean I have
crispr for people don't know what that
means.
It's a relatively new method of,
of altering genetic.
I'm going to give the thousand mile
summary of it where it's basically a way
to to go and fix a gene that may be
like,
let's say you've got some gene that you
can't repair,
you know the alcohol damage induced
damage as well,
which also increases the risk for
traumatic brain injury by like tenfold.
It's bad.
So you say,
I don't want that apoe e four gene
because it's gonna lead to Alzheimer's
disease.
It's going to make my traumatic brain
injury lead to Alzheimer's disease.
You know,
it's so and also does other things.
Well,
crispr is a technology that can go and
recognize the gene you want so it
recognize it's just a small sequence of
DNA that you put on it.
So you put this little sequence of Dna
because you know what the sequence of
the gene is and it recognizes it's
complimentary pair and it goes in and it
cuts it out and it replaces it with what
you actually put there,
which is the right version of it.
So it can like go cut out a bad thing
and put the right thing in.
So it's a way of going instead of gene
engineering up until Crispr,
the way it was done was basically you
would put a gene in and it will just go
anywhere and it wouldn't replace the bad
one necessarily.
So this is Kinda like a whole new field.
It's just like,
it's like.
So anyways.
Yeah.
And there's a radiolab podcast on that
as well.
It's spelled C,
R I s P,
R.
Right.
And if you're interested in listening to
Radiolab podcast,
because it's amazing and it's also
interviews of people who discovered it.
And.
Right.
Jennifer,
do you see Berkeley?
Yeah,
I listened to some of that.
It's
good.
I think the job really good job
explaining it to people so that they can
understand.
Um,
I want to talk for a little bit about
the cryotherapy because this is
something that I emailed you when there
was a disturbing article that was sort
of Poo pooing the benefits cryotherapy
in the article was I thought it was
really poorly,
poorly done,
poorly researched.
And it was also,
it was studied really subjective things
like how sore you felt after exercise
and whether or not a benefited for them
from that.
But yeah,
but there are real positive benefits of
Cryo therapy that are measurable.
Yes.
And that happened as well,
first of all,
that article that you're referring to
from that whatever website it was,
but the article was Steven Novella is a
guy and I think what he did is he rushed
to put this article out because that
woman died in Las Vegas from Cryo
therapy and it was a really tragic
incident.
She was by herself.
There's two different types of cryo
therapy.
One of the things we should point out,
first of all,
I don't have any because I've been
accused of this.
I was just say right now I don't have
any vested interest in cryotherapy.
I don't own any of it.
I don't.
I don't make any money from it.
Nothing.
I enjoy the benefits of it and I use it,
but this woman who did it,
she did the type.
There's two kinds.
One of them,
it goes from the neck down.
So you stand in this booth.
Your head is above breathing and normal
oxygen,
but below you is liquid nitrogen.
You can't read that stuff in.
That's why your head is not under.
If you do breathe that stuff in,
you don't have any oxygen.
You'll black out and that's what
happened to her.
She did it by herself.
It was poorly set up and apparently she
was quite short so her head was kind of
below the,
the,
the limit where you're supposed to be
with.
So she was breathing in the liquid
nitrogen and she fell asleep and blacked
out.
So I thought she was full on.
No,
no,
no.
The full on ones are much rarer.
And what the full on ones do is they
super cool the air with the nitrogen.
So the air itself is pumped in really
cool.
I did.
Yes.
That's what you did.
And that's what we're going to do today
too,
if you have the time to.
Okay,
let's get that one.
You can breathe in.
It's just fucking unbelievably cold.
Okay.
So the one that she did was she set up
by herself,
which you're never supposed to do.
You're always supposed to have
supervision.
So it wasn't whether or not.
I mean she's the only person I've ever
heard of this died from this.
And it's a horrible,
tragic committing suicide.
No,
no.
She was just worried there.
And sometimes women will,
um,
they'll put their face under it because
they want the effects of a cryo facial
because cryo facial has been shown to
improve Collagen and flattens your
therapy,
actually prevents it star,
it inhibits enzymes that break down and
called college and aces.
And that's actually part of the reason
it helps with arthritis.
Arthro college and a's is break down
collagen and they break down like,
you know,
the tendons college and around the
tendons and stuff.
And it can cause arthritis,
arthritic pain.
So doing it would make sense why you'd
want to do something because it would
have an effect on your skin.
Yeah.
Women love it when they get their face
down.
Apparently they get or vein men to or
any man,
hello,
you don't have to be vain to college.
But the point being that article came
out and all these people were saying,
Oh see,
I told Ya,
cryotherapy was bullshit.
I'm like,
oh my God,
what a Piss poor article.
And it was all talking about soreness.
And one of the things that he said that
really drove me crazy was you,
you'd get just as much benefit from a
cool down and stretch after a workout.
I'm like,
tell that to these fucking people that I
see that go there all the time,
that do it twice a day because they have
severe arthritis and it's the only thing
that's given them any form of,
of,
of freedom,
of movement of their hands.
Like I know a bunch of people that go
there that have had some really
debilitating arthritis and this has
given them a relief where nothing else
was given it to them other than like
pretty severe pharmaceutical drugs or
Ibuprofen at high levels or what you
were talking about.
Like there's a lady that goes to my
thing,
but she was raving about how she can
finally stretch your hands out.
Like her hands had been like locked in
this position for years.
Yeah,
it has.
I mean the cold itself as a paramedic
stressor that is activating a variety of
antiinflammatory pathways,
antioxidant pathways.
You know,
and it's also last time I think on the
podcast we talked about,
it increases norepinephrine,
epinephrine itself.
It can,
so cryotherapy and cold water immersion
are two forms of of cold exposure.
Cryotherapy just two minutes at like a
minus 180 Fahrenheit can increase
norepinephrine.
Twofold.
That's twofold over what you were before
you went in and nor epinephrin.
In addition to the brain benefits we
were talking about how it makes you feel
good,
how it helps with learning.
It also is a very potent antifa
inflammatory,
so it inhibits the production of TNF
Alpha,
which is very.
It's kind of like in arthritis,
tnf Alpha is kinda like going haywire.
You're making too much tnf Alpha,
and what happens is tnf alpha is a
signaling molecule to or your immune
cells that says,
hey,
there's an infection here because that's
normally what happens when you release
Tnf Alpha is because there's some
bacteria or some something that you need
to kill and so your immune cells,
all they see is the signal.
They don't know what's causing it.
They don't know that it's because your
gut cells and your immune cells in your
gut are seeing bacteria because of your
poor diet or whatever,
and so that's getting into the
bloodstream and causing chronic
inflammation.
It doesn't know that it.
All it knows is that this means there's
a threat and so they start to increase
the production of your immune cells make
hypochlorite,
which is like bleach.
So you're making bleach in your body to
kill things and that's happening
chronically.
That's going to cause some tissue damage
is going to cause pain.
It also,
they also make hydrogen peroxide.
You make that.
Your immune cells will make that so
cryotherapy inhibits the signaling
molecule so that your immune cells quiet
down because now they're not seeing that
signal that says,
come on,
hey,
fire up,
fire up.
It's not there.
So that's a good thing to inhibit tnf
alpha.
And like I said,
with the college as well.
Um,
but there are so many.
I did,
you know,
I just spent two weeks just researching
and reading.
I've been doing some cold exposures,
you know,
like cold shower and also jumping in the
ocean ice bath and I really liked the
cryo therapy that I did last time we
were here and uh,
you know,
so I've been very interested in it,
like understanding why you feel so good.
And so I did some reading on it and
there's so many different positive
hormetic benefits from doing
cryotherapy.
So you have,
you know,
the,
the anti-inflammatory part and this,
and this also,
it's been shown that doing like 10
sessions of cryotherapy in a row,
it increases the expression of
glutathione reductase by two fold and
another glue of the fly on related
enzyme glutathione peroxidase by like 68
percent.
And these are these enzymes like you can
be taking all the lyposomal glutathione
you want,
like it's not going to matter if you
don't have the enzyme's active to use
it.
So you could take lyposomal glutathione
and that's great.
You're increasing your,
you make glutathione inside of
yourselves.
But,
um,
we,
we can't make as much of it as we get
older,
but if you take it and you don't have
the enzymes that use it to actually do
the good stuff active,
that it doesn't matter.
So cryotherapy was shown to activate to
different glutathione related enzymes,
which is pretty awesome.
So it would enhance your body's ability
to absorb glutosiome no,
it doesn't enhance your body's ability
to absorb it.
It enhances your body's ability to use
it.
So if you fight off bad,
good violin and then you're using
cryotherapy,
it would enhance it.
Um,
so what I'm saying is that the lyposomal
glutathione that you take,
all that does is increase glutathione
inside of yourselves.
Glutathione inside of your cells does
nothing without enzymes that use it to,
uh,
to basically sequester damaging
inflammatory things.
And the cryotherapy increased activates
the enzymes that use it.
So it's like,
great,
I have all this gludethyon sitting
around on myself that I've been taking.
And I also now have the enzymes that use
it to do good stuff.
Now are being turned on that.
What was very interesting is that it
took like multiple sessions before,
before those got like 10 to 2010 and one
at least 10 and you have and then the
other side he was 20,
so it was it consecutively at day,
10 days in a row.
Yeah,
But the first day I didn't do it.
So that,
that was also very interesting.
So it's almost like your body is saying,
okay,
this crazy fuck of some response.
Yep.
Yeah.
Your body is preparing for war.
It's like it's stressful,
you know?
It's a stressful response.
The other thing that's really cool that
we didn't talk about last minute podcast
is the thermogenic effect when you,
when you release nor norepinephrine.
So that's.
I keep going back to that because it's
like you can't refute that.
Steve Novella,
no one know debunker skeptic.
No,
I don't care who you are.
You can't.
It's just,
it's consistent in every type of cold
exposure period.
It's,
it's,
it's consensus.
You release norepinephrine.
Well,
there always seems to be some sort of a
rationalization with a lot of the
debunking,
like whether it's the benefits of
exercise,
whether it's a benefits of Cryo therapy.
That's almost like a rationalization for
not doing it.
It's like you're looking for an excuse
to not do it and not really very
objective.
Yes.
That was,
which was disturbing about.
It's like this is like you're poopooing
people grape.
Yeah.
I,
it was clear.
I mean after especially especially after
the two weeks of research,
I mean,
I think there's a kind of mentality when
you're.
Sometimes people like to think I'm a
debunker and I'm not,
I am,
I am intentionally.
Like,
because if you get in this mentality of
always debunking something,
you're,
it's like the spiral and you can't see
the good.
Like you can't keep an open mind to like
get past.
You're like,
what's in your box that you know,
and that's very dangerous.
I think that,
and I think a lot of blind spots it is
and,
and there are a lot of scientists that I
know they're very smart,
extremely smart,
but they are in that loop where it's
like just they have to debunk and
criticized and it's like,
you know,
at some point huge discoveries are made
by like connecting the dots and getting
past that.
Like,
I mean you have to be critical.
Being critical is very important,
but you also like,
I think there's a certain threshold
where you just start to like,
you know,
you get to the spiral.
Well it was also was infuriating about
this is the data's out there.
This is not like it's not,
there's no data.
It's like he made a cursory examination
of the evidence and what he chose to
focus on was it was so subjective.
It was focused on a study that tested
muscle soreness,
posts,
exercise with cryotherapy.
No,
actually the study that he referred to
as a Meta analysis and it was
subjective,
but it actually came to the conclusion
that there were benefits.
However,
it said more studies and that needed to
be done because there wasn't large
enough sample sizes and the quality of
data was poor because there were not
double blinded placebo controlled
clinical trials and I have to say to you
so that,
so they're actually what he resided in
that article.
There was a positive effect of the cow.
But the problem is,
is that because they followed that up
with,
oh,
well,
it's poor quality,
basically poor science.
The reality is,
is that you can't do a double blinded
placebo control controlled trial with
cryotherapy.
Like you're,
you're going to be cold and you're going
to be putting this chamber where there's
like cold or you're not,
and you're going to know if you're cool,
you know?
So anyways,
I thought that was ridiculous.
I just like whatever.
I'm in Oregon.
I'm going to read about this stuff
because I know I've experienced that.
There's definitely something going on.
Um,
and one of the things that happens is
the norepinephrine.
And when he released,
when you released that norepinephrine,
it activates a pathway in,
inside of your cells that basically are
causes your energy metabolism,
metabolism to ramp up because you're
trying to generate heat,
you want basically your wants to.
Your body is saying,
I don't want to die,
I need to make heat.
And so a couple of ways it can do that.
One,
it can shiver and shivering is when your
muscles start to contract and that it
requires energy for your muscles to like
twitch.
It's very,
um,
it's not very thermodynamically
favorable.
So you,
it's not a good way to generate heat but
you generate heat because you have to
like ramp up to twitch.
But then what happens after you've been
exposed?
And actually this happens to me because
we did the crowd twice.
The first time I did it,
I was shivering like the entire time I
was shivering it was really crazy
because I've never shivered like that in
my life.
But the second time I went in I did not
shiver.
And after reading about it,
what happens is your body quickly adapt.
So you adapt.
And what happens is non shivering
thermogenesis,
so the nor epinephrin causes your
Mitochondria,
which are the energy producing little
organelles inside of yourselves,
well,
it causes them in your,
in your adipose tissue to get activated.
And it does this by increasing the
expression of a gene called UCP,
one which basically freaks your
mitochondria out because your
mitochondria are kind of like batteries.
They're charged,
they have a negative charge on the
inside and a positive charge on the
outside.
Will ucp one totally uncouples that so
that there's no more charge.
And that charge is very important
because when that charges is there,
your body knows,
okay,
I've been making energy because the way
you make the charge is by making energy.
So when the charge goes away,
your body's like,
Oh my God,
I've got no energy.
So it just starts to ramp up fat
metabolism.
So it does that,
and you start to make more mitochondria.
So you're,
you're making more mitochondria in your
fat cells.
And this is often called Brown fat,
so you can actually.
The reason it's called Brown fat is
because when you look at a fat cell
under the microscope,
if it has more mitochondria than it
looks Brown,
so you actually start to burn fat and
you have this thermogenic because you're
burning fat.
It's creating heat as a byproduct so
you're warming your body,
but it has this nice side effect of
burning fat,
which people like.
And the more you expose yourself to the
cold,
the more you're browning your fat,
the more you're increasing those
mitochondria,
your fats,
which means the next time you're in the
cold,
you can tolerate it longer.
So people that have been exposing
themselves to cold like yourself when
you're doing the Cryo,
you know,
often you actually can tolerate the
colder for longer periods of time
because you have more mitochondria in
your fat cells.
And this allows you to then generate
more heat.
So,
and this has been shown in people,
people that have been exposed to a cold,
that they have been shown to increase
their,
um,
Brown adipose tissue by like 38 percent.
If they're exposed to 10 days of 50
degree air,
like outside air.
Just regular air,
50 degrees all,
all day,
10 days,
so like six hours a day out in like,
you know,
New York in the,
I don't know,
pretty winter or fall,
something like that being out there for
six hours for 10 days in a row.
Men were able to increase their brown
adipose tissue by like 38 percent or
something like that.
So people from the east coast or from
the northeast,
the move to California and then they go
back during the winter,
they go home,
my blood got too thin.
Was really is there really is like a
physical factor of your body not being
accustomed to dealing with colby.
You adapt,
you adapt.
And that's what Brown adipose tissue.
And that's really one cold.
How cold got really popular.
Popularized because people wanted to use
it as a hack to lose weight,
you know?
So they were like,
Oh,
if I do these cold showers,
I use it for the brain benefits because
I noticed I feel really good and also
more focused.
So I like that.
And a lot of people I've talked to have
felt the same way.
Um,
but then I think the other part of this
article was the,
the effects of it blunting some of the
strength training and you know,
I talk about this in this report that I
wrote or the in the podcasts that I
released on and it's so complicated I
had to like sit there and literally just
read for like two weeks to try to figure
it out because you know,
the problem is,
is that exercise is a hormetic stress.
Cold is a hormetic stress.
So exercise itself,
you need some of the inflammation,
you need the bad stuff to get the good
stuff.
That's how it works.
But you know,
the inflammation that's happening
happens while you're exercising and up
to one hour after,
one hour after.
That's when the whole hormetic response
kicks in.
And this has been shown in multiple
studies.
One hour seems to be when the anti
inflammatory response kicks in.
So you've generated the implementation
and then now you've got the
antiinflammatory effects.
If you do a cold exposure within that
hour after exercising,
it's possible.
You may blunt some of the inflammatory
effects that the exercise is inducing
because the cold is activating anti
inflammatory genes too early.
Now,
I don't know that for certain,
but I do know that this,
this study that showed there was one
study that showed strength training.
If you did it,
there were,
if you did cryotherapy immediately,
like mediafly after a Cold War,
it was actually cold water immersion,
which is not the same as the Cryo cryo
chamber that it blended some of the
anabolic signaling.
And so there was like some of the muscle
mass was,
was not gained,
but you know,
there's other studies that have been
done that have shown for some reason.
All the endurance guys,
they always wait an hour.
It's kind of weird.
So what I'm wondering is if people that
are doing this research like sit down,
take a step back,
you know,
people are always in this.
I got to Polish it.
How to publish,
you know,
there's a real big publisher parish
mentality and science where it's like
your bread and butter depends on your
publishing and so you're just constantly
trying to get that data out there,
but you really,
I think things are so complicated just
to sit down and take a look at
everything that's out there and start to
go wait a minute.
There's lots of little details that need
to be considered to design this trial
correctly.
So I'm hoping that at least for those
people doing strength training that
they'll do one where they actually wait
until an hour because there's been other
studies where that strength to strength
training in combination with cryotherapy
done much later.
Even the next day there were actually
benefits,
performance benefits.
Like they able to do more of those leg
curl things.
I don't know what they called leg
extensions.
Those,
you know.
So,
you know,
I don't really know what's going on,
but what I do know is that it seems as
though it's very likely that during the
crowd therapy,
like immediately after and now.
Then again,
if you're,
if you're talking about someone that's
doing,
um,
like there's been studies that have been
published showing that people that are
doing two bouts of exercise,
so they're like riding a bike and then
they,
they're waiting whatever,
30 minutes and then they go and run or
something.
If they do cold water immersion in
between those,
they actually have performance
enhancements.
You know,
if they,
if they wait,
I'm sorry,
I have to do it between two bouts of
exercise.
Some of that's due to the fact that
cold,
the cold water,
it seems to improve heart rate
variability.
It x has been shown to improve it by
like two to three fold.
So heart rate variability is the change
in oscillation between heartbeats and
it's also,
um,
people,
people judge a,
the heart recovery from a workout.
So as soon as you're done with an
intense workout,
the ability of your heart rate to lower
immediately within minutes,
that's like a marker of heart rate
variability.
And it's supposed to be good because
your parts able to deal with these
stressful changes,
you know,
because when you're making cortisol or
something,
your heart starts racing more or some of
these other stress hormones,
uh,
so it's been shown to improve that and
having her being able to have your heart
rate slower right after a workout and
then you're immediately going to do a
workout again.
You can imagine there would be an
performance enhancement with,
with that.
So there's also,
there's a difference in the
physiological response between cold
water immersion and Cryo therapy,
right?
Well,
it depends,
um,
you know,
if there,
there are differences in the ability for
those two different modalities to
extract heat from the body,
you know,
if we're talking about submerging
ourselves and cold water up to our
shoulders,
um,
water or ice is a much better.
It's much better at extracting heat from
the body,
then error.
Um,
but surface area also plays a role and,
and the temperature change.
So if you're sitting in cold water
that's 57 degrees,
that's not as cold as going into a minus
180 or whatever crowd chamber.
But you can also sit in the cold water
for a lot longer,
so I do it for 15 minutes.
I think that there has been a study that
compared the norepinephrine release,
20 seconds at 40 degree water up to the
shoulders is comparable to two minutes
at a minus standard,
something one 80 minus one 84,
no norepinephrine,
but a lot of the effects are mediated
from nor norepinephrine,
but listened to 20 seconds at 40 to
reverse those two minutes.
So imagine,
imagine staying in the water for five
minutes in that.
And this has been shown.
So if you have someone that stays in
water 57 degree water for an hour,
they increased their norepinephrine by
fivefold instead of twofold.
So you have a more robust response.
So it could be good,
but it could be bad if you're talking
about doing it right after a strength
training session and jump into cold
water for five minutes.
That could.
That could have some very potent
antiinflammatory effects.
So the best way to handle it would be to
wait at least an hour,
I think.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
What about a anti inflammatory markers
in the blood?
So there have been studies that have
shown that cryotherapy lower c reactive
protein,
which would be an inflammatory marker,
and then the glutathione related enzymes
going up and also superoxide dismutase,
that would be a marker for inflammation
because there's also a decrease
inflammation when you have more of
those.
So,
so cryotherapy does.
And then also,
um,
there's been mark measurements of TNF
Alpha going down.
Like I said,
I'm also another marker that macrophages
release macrophage inhibitory protein or
something,
some inflammatory,
you know,
a molecule that's made,
there's less of it when you,
when Cold War,
I can't remember if as cold water
immersion or cryotherapy,
but it's cold exposure.
So.
And that was mediated through norb and
ignore epinephrin mediates a lot of
stuff.
It's,
it's mediating the brain effects.
It's mediating the thermogenesis.
It's antiinflammatory,
it's anti pain.
People get injected with norepinephrine
and their spine to alleviate a pain.
Yes,
because it's anti inflammatory.
Wow.
Jesus.
There's probably other things going on
as well.
So science just science,
just the hard science.
There's plenty of evidence that there's
benefits to grow therapy.
Oh yeah,
so why would I write an article like
that?
I'm like,
I said there's the,
there's the bad article that was the
anabolic blunting effects which was done
immediately after exercise,
which made a huge splash because it's
like,
Whoa,
you're right,
your gains.
Um,
and then you have the,
the,
the hardcore are very skeptical people
that are like,
well,
the quality of data,
you know.
Well,
the thing is,
is that there's a large body of data and
sometimes if you can't have a double
blinded placebo controlled trial,
then you have to look at mechanism.
You have to look at animal studies
combined with human studies.
You have to understand what's going on.
You can't refute the norepinephrine.
We know that norepinephrine is doing all
these things,
you know.
So I think you just have to be very
comprehensive,
especially when the,
when you know,
there's the argument that the,
there's no placebo controlled trials or
you know,
it's too subjective,
but there's lots of ways that it's not
subjective.
And this has been measured in people.
People have measured the direct approach
and they've measured these enzyme
activities.
They've measured these inflammatory
molecules.
And people also in animals,
you know,
so there's,
I,
I'm confident when I say that there are
absolutely health benefits from doing
cold exposure for your brain,
anti-inflammatory,
for,
for thermogenesis,
you know,
being able to your,
if you can,
this is actually a,
a,
a target a lot.
I know a lot of researchers that are
working on this,
they're trying to um,
find a way to pharmacologically brown
fat because it increases fat burning and
weight loss.
So we will,
of course,
it always,
people always try to do that with,
I prefer the,
the,
the cold exposure.
But other things do at fish oil was
shown to recently do that to increase a
brown Brown adipose tissue.
So a plant based Omega six and three's.
No,
no,
no.
That's um,
so the,
so the fish or it was two grams of EPA
and one gram of EPA,
Dha.
And it was,
it increased fat burning by like 27
percent or something during exercise.
And then at resting and increased it by
something in the teens,
17 or 13 percent.
And that was just at rest fat burning.
And the way it was shown,
the way it did,
it was by increasing UCP,
one,
uncoupling the Mitochondria and causing
your basically causing your fat to make
more Mitochondria and Brown fat.
Super Cool.
I've been taking high doses official,
but yeah,
to answer your question that the plant
version,
and this is always a problem with a.
I get this question a lot from,
from people that are Vegan or
vegetarian,
you know,
they're like,
well I get my Omega three from the plant
version,
Alpha linolenic acid.
And actually,
um,
there's,
there's a lot of important things to
consider.
One is that Alpha linolenic acid is
poorly converted.
All these are.
These are,
these are long chain polyunsaturated
fatty acids,
Alpha linolenic acids.
18 EPA is 20 eicosapentaenoic acid,
which is found in fish.
And then Dha is 22.
So you basically,
your body will take the Alpha Linolenic,
which is implants,
flax seeds,
walnuts,
and it will start adding carbons on to
make the other ones because you need the
other one's 30 percent of your brain is
made of Dha.
Dha is very important.
But the thing is,
is that most men actually only convert
about eight percent of Alpha linolenic
acid into,
um,
into EPA and only four percent into Dha,
not very much now estrogen and actually
can increase that production.
It can increase the gene that converts
those because women are the ones that
are,
you know,
carrying the child and Dha is very
important for the developing brain,
very,
very important.
So it makes sense that nature would make
a way to be able to do that with the
plant version.
But the thing is,
is that there's been a study that showed
that people that take preformed Ala
Alpha linolenic acid have to take 33
point five times more than preformed Dha
or EPA to get the same amount of Dha and
EPA in the brain.
So a lot.
There's a lot.
So there,
there are ways around,
um,
there are Vegan or vegetarian friendly
sources which would be micro algae oil.
I think that I personally think that
vegans and vegetarians should take my
gradual.
If I was a Vegan,
which I can't ever see myself becoming
one,
but I would absolutely take that.
Why do you not see yourself ever
becoming one?
Because there are important
micronutrients and neat that are,
that are important for a variety of
physiological functions,
including the brain,
red blood cells.
You can supplement with some stuff,
but I just,
I haven't convinced myself not to to eat
meat.
So I think with,
with Vegans,
well,
vegans,
what they're trying to do is come up
with a sort of an ethical work around
they're trying to figure out what's,
how can you be healthy and live a vegan
diet and is it healthy enough and most
of them,
at least the hardcore proselytizing ones
seem to think yes and they want
everybody else to do it too.
There are a lot of benefits.
There are a lot of positive factors to
eating a more begun like diet,
all the fiber you're getting begins.
I mean I do know there are some begins
at a lot of processed junk so they're
all,
you know,
not everyone that's vegans healthy,
but not everyone that's omnivores.
Helping the ones that are eating
healthy,
they're getting a lot of.
They're getting a watt wide broad
spectrum of plants.
They're getting the different fibers
that getting into the micro,
they're getting the good micronutrients,
implants,
the magnesium,
the vitaminK ,
the full late a vitamin C,
and they're getting all the.
The hormetic compounds in the plant,
so those.
Those are really good things,
but the problem is is that they're,
they're more nutritionally deficient and
things that most people in the western
world or not because the problem with
the,
like the United States in general isn't
that we eat enough meat here.
Most people,
unless you're Vegan or vegetarian,
people are eating enough meat there.
Problem is people aren't eating enough
of their Greens and so I usually focus
on micronutrients that are found in
Greens because that's what people are
not getting enough of,
but there are important micronutrients
that are in meat that vegans and
vegetarians are more subject to being
deficient in like be 12.
So 12 and iron are are two really,
really important ones.
Both of these are very,
so b.
12 is very important for the production
of neurotransmitters and Myelin in the
brain,
both iron and B,
12 hour.
Most people think of iron as being
important for your blood cells,
and it is,
it's,
it's bound to something called team,
which is a,
um,
a protein inside hemoglobin.
It's important for transporting oxygen
to your tissues because you need oxygen
to make energy.
So,
but the other thing that iron iron is
doing is it's also important for making
Myelin in the brain.
Myelin is what surrounds the axons of
your neurons and allow it allows them to
communicate quickly.
It allows electrical signals,
signals to be trans,
ported quickly.
So that's important.
And then make neurotransmitters like you
need iron to make Serotonin in your
brain.
And it's one of the reasons why during
pregnancy irons very,
like if you have iron deficiency during
pregnancy,
can cause abnormal brain structure or
can cause birth defects because it
shapes the structure and the wiring of
the brain.
Um,
so that's,
you know,
obviously here in the United States we
have supplements,
we have access to supplements and you
know,
you can take a sublingual,
b 12,
you know,
it's,
it's a little bit of a different world
than it is somewhere in like a
developing country.
But B12,
it's animal base.
So how are they getting a plant base be
12?
Is there a plant that has [inaudible] in
it,
in large numbers?
Um,
so b 12 is actually made a buy back
certain strains of bacteria.
And the reason to tie in me is because
it gets me,
you know,
animals are predators and so it gets
concentrated in their muscle,
gets concentrated in,
in animal tissue.
But what about animals that are
herbivores?
I mean,
is it still predators?
Because they're,
they're eating,
they're eating a variety of,
of things that have the,
the bacteria,
like there's certain strains of
mushrooms that have it in order to,
if you're a Vegan or vegetarian,
you're just eating those mushrooms.
You'd have to eat an enormous amount to
get the RDA,
but it's more concentrated in animal
meat which are constantly eating it.
So it gets concentrated in their tissues
because they are b.
12 is required as a cofactor for a lot
of enzymes in multiple organs,
including their muscles.
So their muscles,
you know,
every time they're eating,
whatever has the be 12 on it,
they're concentrating it.
So there are certain types of bacteria
that make be 12,
but I don't think vegans or vegetarians
can just get it from that.
They have to eat a lot of it,
like,
like one of those crazy.
So the argument that have Vegan can get
enough v12 from just a standard Vegan
diet without supplementing.
You don't buy that?
No,
I don't.
So there's,
there was a study that was done in
Tanzania,
so there's a few researchers.
Ucla actually is where I think one of
them just retired,
but there's some researchers at Ucla
that we're studying the effects of b 12
and iron deficiency on cognition,
on,
you know,
learning cognition behavior.
And there was a bunch of studies that
were associative studies like that
crappy premature ejaculation,
obesity where it's like,
you know,
these two things are associated but we
don't know if it's causing.
And so there was an association with low
B,
Twelve low iron and poor Iq,
lower Iq,
poor cognition,
poor behavior.
But there was no real causal,
you know,
roll identified.
And so these,
there's a couple of researchers at ucla
that did two different clinical trials
where,
um,
there was 12 different schools in
Tanzania that were selected and these
clinical trials lasted two years and
there was two of them.
The first trial was 575 kids are around
600 and the other one was like 370
something so closer to 400.
So total we're talking a total of about
a thousand children.
School children,
like these were elementary school
children.
And the typical thing they eat in
Tanzania is,
um,
it's like a porridge,
I forgot the name of it,
but it's a porridge and it has
vegetables,
it has beans and it has corn and that's
their standard porch.
And so what the trial was designed with
the school kids,
we're going to give it.
They were given a snack every single day
for two years,
either the porridge or they got the
porch with a glass of milk or they got
the porridge with meat.
And every three to six months there were
arithmetic and reading tests done.
So they were looking,
trying to measure cognitive performance.
And there was,
um,
they measured physical performance and
muscle mass.
Um,
and,
and what the results were of this study
was that the porridge with the meat.
So the school children that were eating
the meat with the porridge scored better
on math,
arithmetic.
They scored better on reading tests.
They had larger,
they have more muscle mass and they grew
more than the other school children that
did not get the meat.
And they also.
So that's all quantitative.
Um,
they also,
they were more likely to exhibit
leadership qualities out in the
playground.
That's a little more subjective,
subjective,
but still interesting.
So the bottom line here is that,
you know,
obviously in Tanzania they're not,
they're not supplementing or not,
you know,
taking b,
12 iron and they're also,
there's also essential amino acids that
are present neat,
which our bodies can't make,
which are found in some.
You can find some plant sources of it,
like keen water or hempseed has it,
but they're not supplementing with that
stuff over in Tanzania.
So if you don't have access to those
things and you're just eating vegetables
and beans and corn,
then you will have nutritional
deficiencies.
Now the question is,
if those children were given a,
b,
12 supplement or iron,
would that have made a difference?
Probably,
it probably would have.
I mean,
there's been studies in the United
States that have been done on school
children that have been deficient in
certain micronutrients and they were
given a multivitamin and an Omega three
supplement,
fish oil and they only the ones that
were deficient to begin with improved,
like did better on reading and
arithmetic test.
So there's definitely an argument to be
made there.
But I think,
you know,
I think for Vegetarians,
um,
you know,
we live in a very different time.
Obviously there's,
there's protein powders and keenwah on
hemp seed and be 12 sublingual.
And what are they getting [inaudible]
from?
If it's a Vegan based,
I don't.
Oh,
is that like,
I think possible.
I thought it was just like methyl
cobalamin.
So I don't,
I don't think that there's,
it's not me,
it's just,
it's just synthetic be 12.
How would they synthesizing it?
I don't know.
You're going beyond my knowledge base,
but so there it is possible to get both
iron and b 12 from.
So,
so b,
12 is,
I mean,
not a lot of vegetarians supplement with
b 12.
I mean they know and sublinguals
important because there's also gene
polymorphisms that affect the way your
gut absorbs be 12.
So people have to,
uh,
to bypass that.
You can put it onto your soul
sublinguals the optimal way to take it.
Yeah.
I think for anyone,
if someone's a Vegan,
what are the,
what are the supplements that they
should take?
You think b12 iron wood.
Okay.
Well with the iron is kind of tricky.
I just want to mention,
because you know,
iron,
a lot of vegans think that they can get
their iron from their diet because iron
is also found in beans.
It's,
it's in plants,
it's in Spanish,
but the way it's bound,
it's bound in something called phytate,
which we cannot digest.
And so the bioavailability of iron is
one point eight times less in plant form
than in meet me.
It's bound to something called Heme,
which gives,
it gives blood cells that are red color,
which is why red meat has more of it,
but um,
people that are,
uh,
that are vegetarian that think they're
getting enough iron,
I really think they should get their
levels measured.
So women lose a lot of iron during
menstruation.
So the,
so the RDA for iron for men is eight
milligrams a day for women.
It's 18 went,
so already on top of that,
if you're a vegetarian or Vegan,
multiplying by one point eight is
already important if you're just getting
it from food because the bioavailability
of iron is almost two fold less than
from me.
So that's one thing to consider.
And,
and the other thing is also an athletes.
So when you're like an endurance
athlete,
you actually,
a hemo lysis occurs.
Red Blood cells lice when you're doing
like very intense endurance training and
so you lose iron there too because
you'll lose losing red blood cells.
Iron is tricky because you don't want
too much of it.
It's like if you're supplementing like
it's not.
There's no guesswork here.
There's no guesswork with iron.
Having so having too much,
when you take too much free,
like supplemental iron,
it can cause,
you know,
free iron inside yourselves and that is
like dynamite.
That's like,
like it reacts with enzymes in your body
and it screws up energy production.
It causes lots of damage.
So it's really,
really bad,
really bad to get to my drug.
This is supplemental iron from actual
sources.
Notes tightly regulated,
but when you start to do supplemental
iron,
yeah.
So I think that,
um,
and then there's Jane Pauley,
some people like Dan has one,
I,
I've,
I've seen lots of people's DNA where
they have a,
there's a variation in a gene that can
lead to too much iron overload.
Um,
it's called hematic,
Chroma,
hemochromatosis,
and,
and it's very,
it is very common.
And if you,
if you're,
if you have one of those jeans and
you're taking supplemental iron,
you have even more free irons.
It's very bad,
very bad.
So I think that people should
definitely,
I don't know what all the blood levels,
there's different markers that you can
measure,
your physician will know,
but getting iron levels measured is
important.
If you're gonna start supplementing and
when you do supplement with Arne,
is it important to take it with food,
with,
uh,
with fats like what is,
what is the absorption?
Vitamin C,
I'm dramatically increases the
absorption of non heme iron.
So hire an iron that's not found in
meat.
So even actually people vegetarians that
are eating a bunch of beans,
legumes,
um,
first of all they needed to get one one
point eight times more than they would
have meat,
but they also,
if they eat it with a citrus fruit or
have some berries or Broccoli's high in
vitamin C habit with your beans,
that would,
that would make a,
make a difference in increasing the
bioavailability of iron.
So that would be important.
That's a fascinating aspect of food
supplementary or supplementation is
eating it with the right foods and
making sure that,
you know,
some things you don't want to eat with
any food at all and some things you want
to have on a full stomach or you want
fat.
The fat soluble vitamins,
carotinoids,
even vitamin D.
um,
the,
the vitamins that are soluble in fat are
the bioavailability is increased when
you take it with fat.
And so that would be another one
actually a lot of vegetarians probably
think they're getting enough vitamin a
because Beta carotene,
which is in plants,
can be converted into vitamin A.
Vitamin a gets is actually,
um,
it actually becomes a hormone and it
works much like Vitamin d not quite the
same,
but it does change,
it activates genes,
turns genes off,
does all this stuff.
So it's very important for immune
function,
for your eye,
for vision,
but there are,
um,
you have to,
the bioavailability of Beta carotene is
very low.
We don't absorb it very well.
That increases that bioavailability.
So taken with that because they are fat
soluble,
the carotenoids,
Beta carotenes,
fat soluble,
and also,
um,
there are gene polymorphisms that people
have so they don't convert Beta carotene
into vitamin a very well.
Like my brother in law has one where he
doesn't at all very well.
So he has to actually get vitamin a from
an animal source or you can get retinal
acetate.
I don't know,
I think it's synthetic,
but that's something that some
vegetarians may consider,
not,
not all of them,
but some just considering whether or not
they have that gene polymorphism.
I think the main ones are iron B,
12,
Omega three and vitamin D there,
you know,
70 percent of the population doesn't get
enough vitamin D,
but vegetarians often think they're
getting enough vitamin D because you
make it from the sun.
But you know,
the problem is,
is that so many factors regulate that
because a uvb radiation has to hit your
skin to make it.
And so if your wearing sunscreen or you
have um,
a lot of melanin,
so if you're,
you've got like dark pigmentation that
blocks it out latitude where you live.
So uvb rays,
like don't hit the atmosphere certain
times of the year in certain regions.
So you know,
you're only three or four months out of
the year can make Vitamin d from the sun
and then age,
you know,
as you get older,
a 70 year old makes only 25 percent of
the vitamin D that they made when they
were 20 years old.
Wow.
Yeah.
So all these factors play a role and
there is a vitamin.
I know I was talking to Rachel about
this because vitamin D supplements d
three,
the plant form is [inaudible].
It's made by mushrooms.
Mushrooms also make vitamin D when
they're exposed to sun.
The plant form doesn't get converted
into the hormone very well.
And also there's been two recent studies
that have shown that [inaudible] may
actually inhibit a [inaudible] function
and muscle.
So it actually has negative effects in
muscle tissue.
Taking too much do too.
Yeah.
So [inaudible] is the,
is the best supplement form and most of
the [inaudible] on the markets from
lanolin which is secreted from sheep
skin or something.
I don't know.
I don't think that's Vegan friendly.
But there is.
There is a type of algae Lichen Lichen
that that's a,
that makes vitamin D and lincolns and
algae.
I don't know what it is.
White plant.
Is it weird funky stuff that grows
fungus?
Alaska?
Yeah.
It's like a moss almost.
Let me pull that up.
Liking.
Yeah.
So it's something that,
uh,
I know Caribou eat a lot of black tail
deer,
so it's like a white,
tasteless sort of a grass that they
exist or not a grasp,
like a,
almost like a,
it's weird.
It's weird plant here.
That's what it looks like.
What does that,
that was kind of weird looking.
It's weird stuff.
Yeah.
You find it all over the place on Prince
Edward Island in Alaska was the first
place I came in contact with it and I
was like,
what is this?
And then we'll this black tail deer eat
a lot of,
some kind of a plant so you can get
three from that because the company that
makes teeth.
So there are vegan friendly sources of
it.
So if,
if they do want to eat Vegan,
it is possible to get a fully balanced
diet and protein would be the other way.
The other thing,
right?
The essential amino acids are typically
found in animal protein.
So getting,
um,
so those are like leucine,
leucine,
Tryptophan,
penal,
Alanine,
I don't know,
there's nine of them,
but just exist some really low doses.
And in most plant based proteins,
is that what the problem is?
I know the very,
very,
very low doses,
but you can get some that have higher
doses.
It's hemp seed and then chemo.
So those are the only two now I'm sure
there's more than enough.
Right?
But they have like really a full amino
acid profile and they have the essential
ones that you need.
And keep in mind the essential proteins.
That's what's the branch chain amino
acids.
That's what that actually taken up into
muscle cells.
So.
And there's been studies that have been
done just getting,
doing plant protein without the
essential amino acids.
Does not do not.
You can't gain muscle mass after doing
strength training like you can if you
take in the essential amino acids
because that's.
You need those to be taken up into
muscle to build proteins.
Well there's some of the weird Vegan
arguments that they repeat almost as if
it's fact,
but that's not.
And one of them was that saturated fats
and saturated fats are somehow or
another bad for you.
Yeah.
So that's a very confusing literature.
I think I'm saturated fats in and of
themselves aren't necessarily bad unless
you have.
There are certain gene polymorphisms in
um,
so PPR,
Alpha,
Ppr,
Gamma fto genes,
if you have a gene polymorphism in one
of these three genes because in order
to,
um,
when you eat diet,
saturated fat and it needs to be
metabolized,
transported to the right place,
you know,
you don't want it just sitting around in
a,
as fatty acids in bloodstream.
Will.
Those jeans that I just mentioned,
they play a role in doing that.
Some people don't activate them very
well,
and so if they have a high saturated fat
and a low poly or mono unsaturated fat
intake,
they can actually have increased type
two diabetes.
They can have poor glucose response
because fatty acids are sitting around
in their bloodstream and antagonizing
the insulin receptor I'm doing,
doing all sorts of things,
but if they have a higher
polyunsaturated fat,
which is found in fish or nuts or mono
unsaturated fat,
so abakada autos,
nuts,
olive oil.
If they have a higher ratio of those,
then it activates those genes more and
so they don't actually have those
negative effects,
so that's one thing.
That's the smaller thing.
The real problem with saturated fat is
actually sugar.
Yeah.
The,
the.
There's.
The problem is is that saturated fat
increases the production of ldl
cholesterol,
which isn't necessarily bad unless you
have massive inflammation from eating
refined carbohydrates and specifically
from eating sucrose or fructose corn
syrup,
and this has been shown actually a
colleague of mine,
Ron Kraus,
he's a brilliant cardio cardiologist and
he's actually one of the guys that he
discovered a a test to measure what
really the bad part of cholesterol,
which isn't just ldl.
It's actually a small dense particle and
that small dense particles formed only
when you have have the saturated fat
plus the high fructose corn syrup or the
refined sugar because it's causing
inflammation.
So I did a podcast with him.
It's a little technical,
but like my mother in law,
she,
she watched the video and she had done a
liquid panel where the her physician had
measured her ldl particle,
measuring particle size,
measured triglycerides,
all of these things wanting to get her
on stands because she had really high
cholesterol.
It turns out I knew why she had high
She has high cholesterol because she has
gene polymorphism in April.
We for which prevents cholesterol from
being recycled,
so it's not.
That's why she has high cholesterol,
so she watched this video and she like
learned all about the particle size and
that it's the small dense ones that are
really an indicator of cardiovascular
disease and her small dense were like,
she had none.
It was all the good kind of all the ldl
cholesterol is important because anytime
you make a new cell,
you need cholesterol.
Cholesterol is made of cell membranes.
Every time you're making a new kidney,
your liver cell,
you need cholesterol.
When you have damage,
when you hit yourself or you're doing
your workout and your muscles get a
little damaged,
you need cholesterol there to build,
to repair that damage so you need it.
If you don't have it,
you're in trouble.
But anyways,
the point is is that the saturated fat
can.
That's why there's so much confusion is
because one gene polymorphisms to people
are now starting to tease apart that
it's actually the combination of eating
refined carbohydrates and saturated fat.
If you just have the saturated fat you
don't have and you're eating vegetables
and good things as well,
then you're not going to have all that
inflammation.
You're not going to make small dense ldl
particles,
which I talked about this with you last
time.
That's what makes the small dense ldls
inflammation.
So when you have the small dense,
because a certain protein gets obscured,
it causes it to like stick to the,
um,
to the walls of your blood vessels very
easy.
So that's kind of the danger because
then you start to accumulate a plaque
there.
So there's totally makes sense when you
talk about the amount of heart disease
that exists in people that have this
typical American diet which is high in
saturated fat,
but also high in high fructose corn
syrup process.
Sugars in vegetables.
Yeah.
I mean,
here's the thing.
This is the problem with all those
studies,
those studies that are correlations is
that you're looking at people that are
eating.
Yes,
they're eating meat,
yes,
they're eating saturated fat,
but they're also not eating vegetables.
They're also eating cake and crackers
and chips and hamburger bonds and you
know,
all that stuff and her lifestyle,
sedentary lifestyle,
all those things.
So you know that these studies like you
have to really take it with a grain of
salt and especially for healthy
omnivores,
you know,
like I said,
there are vegetarians that are
unhealthy.
They eat a bunch of process.
There's also very healthy vegetarians
and vegans out there.
Well,
there's a lot of unhealthy omnivores.
I mean if you were to go to like the DMV
where like someplace to everyone has to
go and like take a survey.
How many of them eat me?
Will it probably like 95 percent of them
are going to eat meat and then you ask
them like what's their vegetable intake?
You know,
what's your refining?
How many refined carbohydrates do you
take in how many,
you know,
they're all going to be not eating
vegetables and they're going to be
eating their cake and chips and you
know,
there's their,
their hot dog buns and sort of blame it
all on these.
The blame it all on saturated fats is
wrong.
It is.
You know,
some people can have a problem with
saturate when they have too high of a
saturated fat intake,
even if they're eating healthy.
Other healthy stuff,
like I said,
because the gene that that's activated
that helps metabolize the fat,
break it up,
transports it to where it goes isn't
getting turned on.
Well,
we'll get those genes get turned on by
polyunsaturated fatty acids.
And so if you eat a ratio,
if you're eating saturated fat,
which is dairy,
you know some pork,
I don't know,
red meat mostly.
Like if you get a lean cut,
it's not even actually that high in
saturated fat compared to dairy or
cheese or butter.
So much misinformation,
so many people spout out this
misinformation as fact too.
It's just.
It's so frustrating.
It is frustrating.
The other thing is that people actually
will notice there's a problem in there.
If they're eating a lot of saturated fat
and they have one of these
polymorphisms,
they start to gain weight.
They start to have bad lipid profile.
They start to end.
They're like,
they know like what I've been doing this
I measured,
I know it's bad.
Well,
they don't realize it's possibly because
they have one of those gene
polymorphisms.
If they increase their,
their poly unsaturated mono and
saturated fat may actually not be a
problem,
but in cholesterol in and of itself is
not a bad thing.
It's not no cholesterol.
You need cholesterol.
You need it.
Like I said,
your own body's production of it,
but you also need to take some in.
Yes,
exactly.
Well,
taking in dietary cholesterol doesn't
even raise your body's cholesterol.
Saturated fat will raise your body's
cholesterol.
Dietary cholesterol from eggs doesn't
like.
It's like nothing.
It doesn't do anything wrong.
Michael Shermer bond crash showed that,
so yeah.
No,
it was taking in dietary cholesterol
doesn't even like move the dial for
your.
Your body's cholesterol production.
It's so funny because so many people
think it does.
You know what really moves it?
Stress stress dramatically increases
cholesterol production.
You know why?
Because when you're stressed,
your body makes your stress.
Your body starts to make cholesterol and
LDL lipoproteins which have cholesterol
in them because it stops up.
It stops up what's called endotoxin,
which is released when you're stressed
or inflamed and you want your.
You want to stop it up because it can
cause lots of damage.
So you start to make cholesterol and
what ends up happening is when you're
inflamed,
your body will turn off the production.
It basically starts making something
called [inaudible],
which is important to make these.
You know,
these are very low dense particle ally
proteins I was talking about,
but what it also does is it inhibits
your body from being able to metabolize
fat with the exception of medium chain
triglycerides because it inhibits the
transporter.
This transporter on Mitochondria called
cpt.
That is inhibited when your body's
inflamed because it's making that Melano
Kobe and when that transporter is
inhibited,
your polyunsaturated,
you're saturated all like 99 percent of
the dietary fat you take in is not
getting used,
so it gets stored or it starts.
It's like you have fatty acids into your
bloodstream and can raise triglycerides
and things so it can be really bad,
but MCTs bypass that.
Mcts don't need that transporter.
We just blew through three hours again.
That's awesome.
Lou,
through it feels like it was 20 minutes.
It's crazy.
It's really crazy.
Yeah.
These are ridiculous conversations.
Thank you very much.
You're awesome.
Thanks Joe.
As always,
I'm going to have to go over this 50
times with a notebook to try to get half
of it.
Found my fitness.com,
found my fitness on twitter.
What else?
Yeah,
the genetic tool.
I've got people can check that out,
found my fitness.com
forward slash genetics,
and then I've got a podcast on itunes,
did the cryotherapy.
I talk all about that.
I've got some.
How do they get to that?
What is it on itunes?
What's it called?
Found my fitness.
Good.
Sticking with one brand.
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
You're awesome.
Can't say enough things.
So those are the best conversations.
I look forward to them and I'm really,
really appreciative that you do these.
Thank you so much.
Bye everybody.
Yes.