Don't forget to turn your volume off.
Meow.
Is that meow means we're going, yes.
Okay. My, my volume. Totally off.
Everybody settle down.
Settle down.
There's no way to say the same shit
every goddamn time and not get bored with
it. I wish I had something new to say
about the flashlight, but I don't,
you know what it is. There are
spots. What the fuck is that Brian?
Oh, that's somebody from sinister props.
Our friend over there send us another,
a thing today.
Wow. That is dope. And that's the same
guy that made the um, exorcist one. Yep.
Exorcism. This one has a, this
is a Zombie. Hitler. Well,
Nazis, his Ma's. He's not allowed to sell
it with a mustache for legal reasons.
So I have to put something on there
cause he can't sell dummies with the
mustache. I, I'm just, I'm
just joking. I don't know.
It's without a mustache.
He could just be a random Nazi dude.
Some other scary Nazi dude.
Yeah. And then he moves.
He does this like creepy thing
when it's hung up. Right.
Where he's just like moves down.
Oh Wow. Like it's kind of weird.
Yeah. And his eyes turn on and off.
Yeah. That would be the
worst. A Nazi Zombie.
Like it was a cunt in life. You know,
what is it going to be like in death?
You know the Nazis easier. The country
is humans have ever lived, right? Yeah.
If someone's being a con, what do you
say to him? What do you a fucking Nazi.
You say that? Yeah, like that is the
thing that you say when someone's just a,
an utter cunt.
And that along with being,
the only thing that can be
worse is if they were gay.
Rapist zombies, right? Not just gay.
Just gave rapist sons.
There's nothing wrong with being gay.
I mean it would probably be your best
quality if you're a Zombie and a Nazi and
gay. He'd be like, well gaze. The only
part that, it's not even a problem,
but if it was a rapist
Zombie and it was gay,
that would be like the worst.
If it was a Nazi rapists,
like if it fucked you and just said
horrible antisemetic shit. Well,
that's why you better obey the first
rule. Zombie land. What is the first rule?
Zombieland cardio. Oh, that's right,
that's right. That movie, you're a fatty.
You're going to get hit by one of those
guys first. Yeah. That was a smart movie.
That was a great, that was a
fun movie. That was our, like,
it's, it's I, I was like,
somebody told me to see and I was like,
come on man,
I can't see another Zombie movie. I
can't, I just don't have the interest.
I know whoever I'm watching the beginning
is going to be there at the end.
You know, they might lose a few friends
along the way, blah, blah, blah.
I can't watch it. They usually lose a
few of the Douchey ones. Right? Yeah.
Get wiped out. Of course. Yeah.
As soon as someone shows any
unfavorable characteristics, you know,
there's Zombie Bait.
Yeah.
But that was a great example of what
is still possible with the Sharia law.
No,
I brought the wife to that one and she
normally would never go to see that shit.
And she actually at the end, it was like,
that was actually not, not bad. Yeah.
That was a good movie. That was fun. You
know, it wasn't a good movie. Abe Lincoln,
vampire hunter. Oh Jesus. Hey,
you're saving the money of going,
how dare you?
It was fun for a little while.
It was fun for like the first
hour and then I was like, okay,
it's getting ridiculous, man. What?
They started going through history
and fight for alcohol care. Come on.
It's just silly. This is commercials.
We haven't even gotten to the podcast.
Adam score. Gee, I'm really stoned. Yeah,
you might be the germ Rogan experience
podcast. As I was saying before,
I got so rudely interrupted
with my own shenanigans. Uh,
w we are brought to you by the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net,
click on the link for the fleshlight.
Enter in the code name Brogan.
He will save yourself 15% off the
number one sex toy for men. Oh,
people have been asking us, are we
sponsored by alien? Where there was a,
like a thread where people were
saying that like, you know,
you say you only have two sponsors,
but it seems like you have three now.
Alien ware Alienware is not our sponsor.
Alienware hooked us up and, um, the,
our sponsor is sucker punch entertainment.
So the,
um,
the story behind it is I wanted to
switch to Alienware computers because
Alienware computers are,
uh,
they're supporting a lot of MMA fighters
is a lot of guys that are getting
sponsored by Alienware.
And I think that's awesome that a huge
company like Dell has the balls to do
something like that. And so, uh, I,
I looked for a way to do a
deal with Alienware computers,
but the way we're doing it is I'm
doing a deal through sucker punch
entertainment. So that is
the answer, that question.
And it's primarily to support a
company that supports MMA fighters.
And I think that's a
good thing for all of us.
And if it takes me an extra 15
seconds on a podcast to do that,
uh,
I would like to do that.
Cause I think it's one of the coolest
things that we can do as consumers is a
support companies that support,
you know, the things that we enjoy,
the things that we like, especially
companies that take a chance on MMA,
which of course is a, a very
big passion of mine. Um,
so that's the answer to that question.
We are also sponsored by on
it on it.com if you go there,
you can check out the new kettle bells
that we have in. We just got them.
They're fucking awesome. They're the
best cattle. But you can buy these,
your kettle bells,
they're the shit. They're,
they're really bad ass
and they're heavy as fuck.
So you have to send these
things through the mail.
The whole thing is up very
to find process. I mean, if
you can't imagine you're,
you're sending cannon balls essentially
cast iron cannonballs through the mail.
I mean, so socks for the ups lady. I
mean it's fucking, you get one of those,
fill up the ass for that too. Oh
yeah. Yeah. It's brutal. But you know,
they're the best we can. The best we can
sell. At the lowest price we can sell.
And um, there you get them and they
last for the rest of your life.
And I swear you don't need anything
else to get a workout. My best workouts,
I use a chin up bar and three
kettle bells and that's,
I don't need to do anything else. I can
do everything with these fucking things.
And when you, when you do kettle bells
you get like a functional strength that I,
I never felt that I got from regular
lifting for regularly lifting.
Like when you isolate things like
isolate triceps and isolate biceps,
a lot of times that can lead to injury,
especially bicep tears happens on a lot
of guys who used to do a lot of curls
because you stress out the muscle from
that weightlifting like that, you know,
the isolating one particular body part
and it's an unnatural thing to do.
And then when you go in box
and actually use your arms,
that's where guys were blowing
out their biceps tendon.
I hadn't done my bicep but
my shoulders of Clayton,
the last cause I for awhile when I was
in New York and I had started my career
in modeling,
then went to film school and sexy bitch,
you sexy bitch that dad now, but how
dare you? I did a lot of just you know,
training just to make the physique and
then went back to boxing because I used
to box and I was younger. I was like
western Canadian champ when I was younger,
but so now my shoulders would click right.
I had to go get prolotherapy. Oh yeah.
Have you heard about that?
I've had that.
I've had that on my wrist for your
great work. Fantastic. Amazing.
Yet that's considered like if you don't,
yeah folks, if you don't know what it is,
well is it considered a hogwash?
Is that what you were saying? Well,
every time I mentioned like my natural
path is a good buddy of mine from high
school and I'll mention him
to regular doctors like,
oh my natural pass said this and they
like my real doctor. We'll stop. Right.
And be like, you shouldn't
listen to what they have to say.
Yeah. That is a tricky thing, right?
Like doctors don't want to listen to any
herbal talk. Like you show your herbs,
herbal, whole natural physician or
whatever the fuck you calling yourself.
You know, cause it's too much
of it that it's just fuckery.
That's why a lot of it might
only be legit. There's,
there's probably a lot in
herbal medicine that is legit.
This is a lot of fuckery going on
with that too though. No Man, they
natural paths.
What from our sun?
It seems like it should be an
honorable occupation. You know,
get people to live their life in a
healthy way and we'll eat healthy vitamins
and take healthy nutrients.
And you know,
that's what my buddy told me is he
said, you know, when you go that way,
you have to come halfway. Right. Half
of it is you living right. Eating right,
looking after yourself. But you know, my,
my natural path also does prescriptions,
right? So he's not like he's got his,
you know, he's like, when you get an,
when you get sick you need an antibiotic.
Right.
I tried to make it so your body doesn't
get there. Right? Like my mind is smart.
Right. Why is it seem
like fuckery? Break it up.
I mean, I, I'm not, I'm trying
so hard to not be judgmental,
but when if someone says
natural path, I'm like, okay,
maybe he's one of the good guys, you
know? I mean it's like anything else,
like when you get into astrology or any,
anytime you go down weird street,
there's just too many people
that are shitting in the alleys.
I'm sure a few people down
weird street have a point.
I'm not saying they don't, I'm definitely
not saying they don't, but God damn,
a lot of them seem to, yeah,
you get seems to be crazy. Yeah.
You get the credit and then they
ruin it for all everybody else.
But you had the prolo done. I mean, I had
it done in my shoulder like mine were.
I would just pick up a milk jug out of
the fridge quick and it slipped a little
bit.
Right.
For people who don't know
what prolotherapy is, if you
have a ligament problems,
a lot of people recommend this
thing called prolotherapy,
which they inject like a glucose solution
directly into your ligaments and your
tendons and it actually forces them to
swell and grow and they strengthened by
as much as 30 to 40% you know,
that's pretty sure that's been proven
yet. I mean, and the way that it started,
my uh,
my natural father was telling me that
the way that he got into is in the United
States when you'd have to go,
you get approved for insurance to go get
shoulder surgery and they estimated 60
grand. They would try to put you on
the prolo first. They're like, well,
this is only five grand, so why
don't we try the prolotherapy first?
Then if that doesn't work then we'll
book you in. So you said some of this,
some of the, some of
the mistakes, you know,
in the industry can actually turn out to
have positives and other ways where now
that stuff, I mean, I'm not saying for
everybody, there's not the way you put it.
To me, that made so much sense. He
said, listen at him. He was like,
before you go get surgery and they hack
and shop and they take stuff out that
you can't get back. Try
my process. He's like,
I've had former NHL players and stuff
that have had it done. If had, you know,
wicked, wicked results. If mine doesn't
work, then go get your shoulder chop.
Because once it, well,
what exactly was wrong?
What you're to out of these
commercials real quick.
These commercials are fucking gigantic.
Is this still a commercial?
What is it? Is it really a commercial?
Goddammit, it's a fucking show.
And in the show, this is the beginning
part. Okay. And then the beginning part,
we do commercials, but sometimes
we talk to, it's okay. It doesn't,
I like to take a serious,
yeah.
Well this would be just the
Internet's mystery. Okay. Uh,
on a.com kettle bells.
They're awesome. Uh, my,
my point before all that was just that
isolated muscle groups is kind of an
unnatural thing.
And the,
the natural way to work out with
weights is to use your whole body.
And that's what the benefit of kettle
bells, the exercises allow you to use,
like your momentum and explosive energy.
And it's like, it's all like, you know,
they're like real power lifting exercises
like cleans and snatches and today's I
snatches. Yes, I did squats and
you know, and, and, and you know,
and alternating cleans is,
there's so many bad ass Turkish getups
are so many bad ass exercises you can do
with kettlebells. And uh, go check them
out there for sale on at.com. Oh, and,
and it also get yourself some
Alpha brain or you'll sound stupid.
It's my new approach.
What's Alpha brain offended that you
didn't give me the new Alpha Brain Joe?
I thought I did. No, it,
the new one has like a sticker on it
that says now with something else.
And I might not have that yet.
Do you guys have any of that here but
not in an Ami. Tried it and it's like I,
some of my car
Brett tried it, said he loved it. Yeah.
Whereas writing, yeah, he liked it.
So it's legit. There's look
that's very controversial. Uh,
I can't talk about this any
other way other than this way.
So even though it sounds very repetitive,
some people,
this might be the first podcast they've
ever heard, so please forgive me, but uh,
what they are is nutrients that have
been shown to have a positive effect on
the,
your brain's ability to
produce neurotransmitters
that your brain's ability to
work in a smooth fashion of those.
You want some gummy bears? No,
those are scary as fuck.
I know what those are.
Those are those dangerous gummy
bears. Careful out Corgi. Yeah.
Don't throw those over there.
If you have any questions about
the nutrients or anything,
the research on the nutrients,
if you go to [inaudible] dot com
all the information is up online.
It's all explained in as scientific
a manner as we are capable of doing.
If you try it and you don't like it,
we have a hundred percent money back
guarantee on your first order of 30 pills.
Do you know,
just say this wasn't for me.
You don't even have to return the product.
You get your money back.
We just don't want anybody to feel ripped
off, but it's good shit and I use it.
Holla at your boy. Go to the website.
Enter in the code name Rogan.
I'll save yourself 10% off any and all
orders. Get yourself some brain pills.
You dirty bitches. All right, Adam,
score gies here ladies and gentlemen,
get down to business.
Okay,
well good experience.
Train by day. Joe Rogan podcast show
what's going on? People getting mad at me
from my fucking commercials. What? Ben?
I liked the way you do your commercials
cause they actually get into the eye
listening to your podcast. I'll, I'll
get lost in your car. I'm like, Oh shit.
They're still in a commercial.
They got to bring it back yet.
Not very professional,
but it is what it is folks.
I think it's better way to let
it fucking fly. Who gives a shit?
I think it's a better way of
doing it. Yes, I agree. Hollow.
Adam scored you ladies and gentlemen, my
friend from another country. Yeah. No,
I'm not too far. He's from up
north. Are Our cousin to the north.
Is that we are we brothers and sisters?
Are we cousins? Cause that's fucked up.
Who lived right next to her?
We can't be brothers and sisters.
I think we gotta be brothers and sisters.
Then you've got to let the Mexicans
into that means hate me. You know what?
Honestly, without skins, fuck your sister.
How hard I have to work on my yard.
We were all going to not trying to be,
I mean how rude.
How dare you suggest it.
Mexicans work on Howard's men.
The ones down from my parents in Texas,
they do magical job and
they're 40 bucks a week.
Like they cut out sod
and replace it like I,
you couldn't get someone to do what they
do for 500 bucks. A lot of fucking work,
man.
Being a gardener,
God damn think how hard it is to be a
goddamn Gardner that she has brutal.
I digging ditches all day out in La.
Holy Shit Man.
La.
Kind of a crazy place
to live.
If you really stop and think about it.
We got a lot of people here
and there's no fucking water.
We have to steal the water from the
Colorado River and we call it the l.
We would call our thing the La River.
That is the most hilarious river ever.
And it is like the perfect example
of what's wrong with La. It's cement.
The La River literally is a cement
tube and they call it the La River.
Like that is not a fucking river.
You assholes.
That's a fake river.
And you know what?
You guys get power from Canada actually
from dams, not far from where I live.
We steal it or do we buy
it? No, we use by miss who?
Dangerous weapons in
Canada. Next thing. Who you,
how do you guys make the power through
big hydroelectric dams on in the
mountains. Wow. So then you
sell it to the United States.
What parts of the United States?
California is wine,
and we brought it up in a union
member like mayor mayor of Vancouver,
Larry Campbell. He says,
he's like, I don't think the
trades would stop. He's like,
do you want la in the dark and thirsty
because we ship water to right. Wow.
So that's incredible.
So the dams make so much
electricity that you can power La.
Yeah, the world. I don't
think it powers the whole,
I don't even know how they
ship it or how it works,
but we sell it to even understand
electricity. Yeah. I under, no, I don't.
I do know that it's,
I don't,
I have no idea how they save in some mind.
Fuck.
Our fucking houses are at
every moment electrocuted.
There's fucking cords and if you lik
dumb, your head would explode. All right?
It's just shooting the shit that powers
up TVs and air conditioning and you
didn't even think about it.
You just plug in your,
plug it into the nuttiest fucking
thing you could ever possibly imagine.
There's some sort of an electrical pulse
and electrical field and electrical.
There's a wire and it's connected somehow
down the river to sell fucking nuclear
explosion.
Yeah.
It's 12 fucking nuclear power
plant and it's in your house.
There's a direct line from that thing
down into some fucking son in the middle
of downtown San Diego.
Wherever the fuck that power plan is now,
you always get people thinking deep too.
That's a terrifying thought. Well, that's,
I was trying to think how do they ship it?
Like how do you store it?
Do you put it in a can obviously has to
come through a line and then goes into
it. I didn't even understand
it a little tiny bit.
There was a crow in the Starbucks
of the day in line and uh,
you know,
um,
I was getting my coffee and she was
talking to her boyfriend and she was like,
what if it was fucking total chaos?
Like if the power never came back on. And
I was like, wow, isn't that incredible?
That what we think of is total chaos
is the grid that if we lost this crazy
thing that we've constructed,
there's no way we could live without it.
That's a weird fucking combination of
human and machine and technology and
relying on at all all the time and just
being terrified of the idea of being
forced to live off the land.
Use tools,
catch your food. You know what I'm saying?
You said it is skynet. Isn't that crazy?
What a weird thing that we've
become that we haven't even noticed.
It sort of snuck up on us
and we became like a hybrid.
We're like park people and
fucking part technology.
We're constantly on the
tit of technology all day.
Paul Day.
Oh Fuck Day.
How do you do with your Joe?
You're pretty good with your Twitter.
Getting back to everybody. I mean, I can't
get back to everybody. It's impossible.
I mean, I would get nothing done if I
did, I would like, you know what I mean?
I mean, I try to, I get back to
people occasionally, but I don't,
I can't commit to doing it to everybody.
It's a system,
but I think you do a pretty
good job. Like, you know,
I'm always able to hit you up there
and you get back to me and you,
I think you do a pretty good job,
man. I mean, I'm looking at mine.
I only have like 11,000 followers and
I'm finding it hard to just try to be,
it can get pretty nutty one. How?
Dude Luck Justin Timberlake rocks.
It doesn't even have, I think they just
have guys running. Oh, that's so sad.
That's what I don't like.
People like that.
That just seems like it's their
generic tweet where they're like,
my show is here. I'm playing
here. Tickets at like,
there's none of them just saying, Oh shit.
I just saw the craze. Like you're like,
okay, let's just someone running
it on a generic program anymore.
They just give it the handed over to
the publicist. Some people do. Yeah.
That's unfortunate. You know, cause
I like, like Kevin Smith's tweets.
I know Kevin Smith's writing those tweets.
You know what I mean?
Like a Jim Norton. I love Jim Norton's
tweets, so I know he's writing them. No.
And that same I, I'd stopped following
the people that I don't think's writing.
And when it's just these great quotes
all the time and stuff like will Smith's
or quotes every day. And I'm like,
okay. I like, that's I think Joel,
I think that's what I was
talking to Brian earlier,
like the community you guys built is
because you guys are like interactive way
and you do do it yourself.
You're not having a publicists like
checking everything you tweet and saying
shouldn't do this and
shouldn't and doing it for you.
But we should all totally have.
It's really done that.
Brian wants an intervention.
Someone saved me from myself.
Well maybe I missed it, but you haven't
done a tweet. That's so bad. No, look,
we're nice people.
I'm fast deleting the,
but the bottom line is if we're nice
people, you gotta be a nice person, man.
It's like, you know,
life can throw you some,
some situations that could go one way
if you choose to be a nice person or
it could go horribly wrong if you
choose to be a Douche bag or choose to,
you know, be weird about it
or not be considered about
another person's feelings.
You know, it's real. It's a,
these little like moments where we
like decide who we are. Like it,
it happens and you know,
you can go down the wrong road.
It doesn't mean you're a bad person,
you know, like made a mistake.
You might have overreacted, you might've
been stressed out about something.
That doesn't mean you still can't be a
good person and he's just got to reset
and realize you're not the past.
Okay. You're not all your fuck ups.
You're what you've learned.
You're now, you're, you're,
you're the you now that
gets it some move forward,
move forward and let that shit
go. Well, I have to, you know,
bring it up for the people listening,
Joe.
I mean like how cool you were when
we first came to do the union, right?
Todd called you.
We needed someone that we knew we needed
someone that knew the subject matter,
that was a celebrity punch. And you know,
three guys from Canada, you said, yeah,
no problem. We come to your house. I've
been, it's still, if you were like,
what was the first time you met? Joe was
like, we came to the house and he's like,
how long has set up the lighting? And
we're like, Oh, 20 minutes. He's like, oh,
the kitchen's over there and I'll be
right back. I'm just going on my computer.
Then I was like,
man,
we're just three random guys from
Canada and your Todd Todd is a very good
friend and uh, you know, he's,
uh, he's done a lot for the whole,
uh, legalization process and the,
Oh, I shouldn't even say that.
I should say the awareness process.
You know,
he's got a great book on how to grow hemp.
He's a brilliant guy when it comes to
the history of it and it's helped him
personally through cancer. So He's,
he's very passionate about it.
So when he brought it up to me, I
was just like, okay, let's do it.
It was awesome man.
Cause I mean you're the number one asked
for guy to interview for the next one.
Like that's how everyone's like Joe, Joe,
Joe, Joe, Joe was like, oh that's cool.
I was like, I'll talk to him. I was like,
they're like you've got to have a muse.
And I mean Joe,
I mean I had to watch the film 1000 times,
but when I'd go to sold out theaters and
every time you think like I could count,
we knew the spots where
people are laughing like okay
cheeseburger thing coming
up here.
Let's Nerf the world.
And I just literally go up some of
my watching cloud, the laugh now.
And they do it every time man. It was
to see that reaction I think. And,
and when we did the union,
it came out,
I don't think a lot of people
had seen you in that context.
They knew as a UFC guy,
not a lot of people need from news
radio unless they were a die hard fan.
And then they need from fear factor.
Right. So they didn't see it. Like,
cause I remember a lot of people are
in like fear factor guy smokes weed.
Like they were so shocked when
you said that in the opening part.
We have you saying like I realized when
I was 30 years old that I'd be fucking
trek. You gotta be fucking kidding
me. Well that's really what it is. Um,
I was just being honest about it,
you know, I didn't think it was, uh,
I, I didn't think doing it was, uh,
anything other than what I had to do.
You know, I think, I think you have to,
when you know something about something,
like when you have an experience,
especially in experience about
something that has such a tainted name,
like marijuana, you know,
he just like, oh, Meryl Won.
What if, what is he a loser?
Just lists,
lists and no spine and no motivation.
It's just got this terrible
connotation and connection to it.
And I bought it hook,
line and sinker until I was 30 years old.
And, uh, Eddie Bravo got me high. Yeah,
I remember what you brought Eddie
over that day. The first time we met.
But I mean I was the same
way when we did the union.
I think that's why the union turned out so
good is that we weren't activists or
anything in the beginning. We just,
you weren't a pot smoker it on. That's
what I tell people. They're like, oh,
what does he like? Is he a stoner? No.
Easy like clean cut and Kirk
Looking Barbie motherfucker.
Martin, what's his name?
Ken. Thanks. I'll tell
you. Why am I saying Kirk?
Kirk? Kirk, I don't know how you got Kurt
is there's been a black Barbie guy. Yeah.
Should be. What the fuck man?
It has her. They're scared.
So scared.
So scared of a black man has to.
I bet they're probably have. I mean
there's a bar. There must be. He's got a,
Ken must have a friend. I bet he
has a really white features though.
Let's see what his features look like.
Let's see if there's any black men.
I think I remember some of
the Black Barbie friends,
but I mean there wasn't my
toy by Black Barbie thing.
Must have blackboard that they do and
it's not as, it looks pretty crazy.
How does that work? That's pretty
cool. That's like Tyrese. No.
Or Tyson Beckford. Yeah,
that's a handsome black look.
You just got to accept that
that girl meets that guy.
He's going to fuck her representative in
doll form of what would really happen.
Yeah.
Look at his body.
He's a super athlete and wonder if
the white has got a body like that.
Put pull up a white Ken.
See if they only came the black eye.
A body like that because that would be
hilarious because if that was a human
being, I think that one's just a
spoof one that someone may stop. Stop
fucking with you.
That's a title.
That's a Dyson cinnamon. I,
I apologize. I've been trolled. He
got Brian. That was pretty good.
Son of a bitch.
Are Boys supposed to have the Kendall?
Is that what what it is?
Or a girls by the boy? No, boy. I
thought they tried to sell it as that,
but I don't think you'd ever think it was.
I think I would think I'd
never was four guys at all.
Oh a few dudes wants to bought it and
been like, what the fuck did I do?
I did GI Joe fucking Barbie.
I was going to say,
am I the only guy that every time I go
over to my cousin's and there'd be Barbie
and Ken,
I'd strip them down and put them in a
sexual position when I was like seven.
So you only new missionary, right?
It just always be guy on top. But
yeah,
Barbie Ken,
I would buy like like hulk
dolls and shit like that.
Why is that an, because it's 10 it's the
hall you and saw vendors over was event.
If you had a Ken doll, it'd be like
that's how you get into the Barbie party.
Like if all those little girls
are hanging out and partying,
do you want to party with them?
You got to get a Ken doll.
It's like your car and I definitely go
for getting into the little girl party.
I would have tried more of the approach
of just hulk smash his way in there.
And you can't do that when you're 12 man,
that's a,
I just don't think I would have
been that slick actually about the
the hook line to get into the place.
That's ridiculous.
Cause 12 year old boys are not
playing Barbie. I wouldn't have,
I wouldn't have been that slick. Right.
Like they usually still insult each.
Is that when they like each
other at that age. Yeah,
but I'm just saying 12
years old is way too old.
Like they gave up on Barbie when I
think kids give up on Barbie real early.
I think we now hold,
especially now with technology.
I mean so any boy who buys a Barbie
doll is probably just being tricked.
If he buys a Ken doll,
he's been tricked by my thing.
He's only been tracked because marketers
have gotten, that's what it is.
I mean I collected Gi
Joes, masters, all those.
I had all the marvel superheroes.
I had all of them too.
I was a big Wolverine Junkie.
I had his first 50 comics and men are
dorks somewhere along the line though.
You feel real guilty about that?
Like I got rid of my comic book collection
when I was poor and I needed money.
I sold my entire comic book collection.
It was just one of those desperation.
I need food moves and uh, I, I've,
there was a part of me that was like,
this is good because you
really have to grow up. Like,
what are you doing reading comic books?
You're in your twenties now and you
have to, you know, you're, you're,
you're struggling out here.
You can barely feed yourself your
role in nickels to eat, you know,
like finding change in your house, get
the, get rid of the comic book pitch.
Then once I got rid of him, like, man,
did you guys ever experimented with
a visionaries? Excuse me, this toy,
it was like right after Gi Joe and they,
they were like a beefier Gi Joe,
but they had like holograms all over him,
like a hologram up a
wolf and it looked like
I only went once they stopped and Gi Joes,
I was pissed.
I was about when I grew out of it and it
was just video games after that and in
sports,
I was a huge comic book fan for a long
time when I wanted to be a comic book
illustrator at one point. So I was
always like, yeah, yeah, yeah I could.
I used to draw a real
good when I was young. Um,
but I had a really douchey high school
art teacher that kind of turned me off.
He was like, he kept emphasizing
that yet, well you're,
you're gonna if you want
to be an illustrator,
you're going to have to draw things.
You don't want to draw. Okay,
you're going to have to draw diaper ads.
And he's like,
diaper ads was like the one thing
that he kept bringing it up.
Like you're a professional artists. You,
he might have to work and do a diaper,
add a, I was like, this guy is just
so negative. Like fuck artists,
you know, it was just, he was
a really, really dour dude.
It sucks when you had those
kinds of teachers in high school,
whether it's art class or whatever that
you look back now and realize how they
really shouldn't have been there
and didn't put in the time.
And then he was gross man.
Like even if you drew like what?
Like your interpretation of something,
like a weird sort of interpretation
of something. He would be like,
if they want you to draw
something for an advertisement,
you draw what they ask you to draw. I'm
like, dude, you're gross. This is gross.
You're like,
you're,
you're putting this weird fucking
spin on what is and isn't cool to dry.
I like comic bitch
and they're telling me there's
something wrong with that. Look,
she hadn't looked at comic industry like,
Oh,
they're all transferring video
game industry, which is huge.
So those people that were telling them
not to do that silly bitches stupid.
But then you get that,
you get that like one good teacher that
actually takes a little bit of time and
gives you an, you're like, whoa.
Like I can learn so much when I
just get that little bit of respect.
I remember I had an English
teacher and it wasn't,
it was in like the 10th grade and I
didn't know how to write essays properly
because I didn't pay attention to my other
classes and instead of just giving me
c minus or d, She came up to me
after class. She's like, Adam's,
anyone ever told you that you
write like your opening statement?
Then your argument of like how to do
it. And I was like, no. And she's like,
oh my God. Right. She's like,
okay, well I'll help you
with that. And then I'd like,
but I thought that was so simple.
That was the first teacher just asked
like instead of just give me a flunking
grades and be like, do you know how
to do this? Yeah. I had a really,
really cool English teacher though.
Everybody tried to get into her
class when they got in their class,
they was psyched because she was
really generous with the grades,
but she was just the sweetest,
nicest lady. And when you
would go into her class,
it would be a completely different
vibe than all the other classes.
Everybody was happy.
They were all relaxed because
there was no like authoritarian.
But she was such a nice person. He would
never want to get her upset with you.
Like if if she like had to quiet you
down because you were talking in the back
of the room.
Somebody that you would feel genuinely
bad like you know you'd apologize because
she was a sweet, sweet person.
She was so inspirational.
There's One lady teacher and I had
one Spanish teacher that was a bad
motherfucker as well but right. He
was like he, he wasn't letting it.
I think he was a fairly young guy and
he was handsome and like the girls were
like all over him man.
And the dude like I know we had a dodge
like a lot of 17 year old girls cause
cause he was a really handsome guy.
I don't think he was any older than
like 23 or 24 it was a scary situation.
Interesting man.
Because he was not much older than us.
I remember that feeling like he was so
much closer to us than all these other
teachers.
Like the math teacher was like in her
fifties and if this guy was still alive,
I'm still pulses.
All the rest of their dead dude.
There were some dead people teaching
high school. Man. I know we had some,
I mean I wasn't, I wasn't the greatest
in high school. Uh, it's just, it's hard.
It's doesn't pay well that their kids
aren't behaved. The kids are like me.
I wasn't, I wasn't not behaved.
I was an idiot. Oh, I was too.
And I mean I used to get in fights all
the time because I was insecure and so I
was always getting in trouble for that.
But I'll tell you that
like teachers would,
they told me later on is that they used
to hear so many bad things about me in
the staff room that they were
terrified to have me in their class.
But the teachers that were cool,
like I never ever, like you said,
like if I had a teacher that showed
me respect from the beginning,
like if she asked me, I would feel guilty
like you said. Or he like, I be like, oh,
I let them down because this guy like
treats me like he's really teaching me and
he treats me as an adult. Right.
And is trying to get to instead
of like you said, like coming in like
a dictator and slashing you down.
Like a never responded well
with those teachers, you know,
I don't like anybody that to Douche bag.
I don't want to be them when I grow
up, you know? That's how I would feel.
I would be in their class.
I'd be like, shut down, boom.
It's not paying attention. Barely
squeaked through. That was my strategy for
mine too. I barely, it was
funny cause one of the teachers,
my buddy works at a bank and they're
getting a loan and she brought up,
she's like,
where's that Adam's Gorgie kid?
Is he in jail or is he with the bikers
now? And then my buddies like, no,
actually he's uh, going to be on TV this
week. And he's in and they're like, what?
And even her husband grabbed her.
It's kind of like, yeah, he's,
he's doing well and she's so people
thought you were going to grow up to be a
psycho? Yeah, cause I mean, I grew
up in a different, like, I mean my,
my dad owned a strip club when I was
going through high school and just after
high school, while I was up
nightclub first and a strip club.
And then that was the madness that I
inherited when he passed away in 2003
Jesus, that's when we did. Yeah. So, and
I had been away. And how old were you?
I was 23 Jesus Christ.
And you have to take over this crazy
strip club in Vancouver. Is that where no.
Colona Colona. Yeah. And it was,
I mean that was biker gangs
rolling through there and shit. Oh,
well you see most of the agencies that
send the girls and BC are owned by EMC
clubs. Holy Shit. Right. So
my dad had worked in, yeah,
when I took over it was,
we've been trying to put
together a screenplay for
years. It was, it was, you know,
23 years old. I'm thrown into this. I
was living in New York for four years,
came back, hadn't been in that environment
forever. What is that environment like?
Like it's Vancouver just have a lot of
motorcycle gangs. Is that like a real,
they're the number one. There's an article
in the Mcclain's at the Ha were it,
it was his rich and powerful and BC some
of the richest out of they. There's not,
they don't have as many rivals.
It's smaller.
I mean there's more people in the state
of California then the entire country of
Canada. Right. It's just smaller.
So there's less competition and
they are the number one. Wow.
So that's like the organized
sort of situation up there.
How dangerous is it?
Well,
I mean I know some of them like you know
that I went growing up through the bar
that I knew that are great and you
know, I'm friends with them. I,
I said is it accepted part of
the culture of super accepted.
Like actually when you look at them as
a young guy and you're like, oh my God.
Like when they say crime doesn't pay,
and you see these guys that are well
built in shape, beautiful girlfriends,
they have $60,000 Harley, $6,000 boats.
They're in their 20s and you're like,
damn right. Like they're the Rock
Stars of Colona. Like when you,
when you go to my hometown, it's
like, that's, that's the guys,
I mean like they'll have a
boatload of beautiful women.
And is it possible to get in trouble for
talking about this? Like if you, you're,
you're talking about that, you know,
that's why I said the actual name. Yeah.
Yeah. He can't say to
you guys, it's like a,
it's like when Vegas ran the mob.
Yeah. Or was it rather the, uh,
the mob Ran Vegas? Yeah. I mean,
they're big part of, I mean there's,
there in Colona where I live, there's
150,000 people and there's three MC clubs.
Now.
Do they have like shootouts and shit?
Are they genuinely get
along or all wheeze?
Just bcs had a lot of shootings in general
with the drug trade coming up right
now. There's been, she's
been all couldn't be avoided.
You saw that?
Uh,
I mean I think it made national news
where there was that shooting downtown
Vancouver and the hotel and there was
like a women's national soccer team
staying amps. It was broad daylight
raid in the restaurant, five star,
four star hotel rate in the lobby,
man makeovers getting back.
Is it about,
of course it's all the drug trade hits.
They put a hit on somebody or something.
Something to do with that. Yeah.
It was so scary,
man.
That's a scary culture to be criss
crossing with, you know, and,
and your d and then you put booze in
that mix and you're running and you're
dealing with this ticking
time bomb. Right. That's just,
it, it, it was a real task.
I mean, my, my wife and with now,
I mean she's stuck there with me
and helped me through, you know,
all of those headaches when we
were going through the place. And,
I mean all this happened,
like I had a bat,
I did a bad deal with a
childhood friend on the club,
so I didn't get paid 23 and all of a
sudden you've taken over this crazy little
situation, sharks just everywhere.
Right. And even some that don't,
they don't realize they're
going to be a shark.
Some friends that because of the club
and what that kind of brought for them,
they were like, Oh Adam, you should
never sell. It's your dad's legacy.
And you know,
cause I want to just go back to New York
and continue with my film career. Right?
Like I wanted, I had already was starting
to do well there and I wanted nothing.
And then I'd be like, oh it's tell him.
Then I get convinced to stay, keep it.
Cause my dad left it,
but,
and so the end of the day I didn't get
half of what I was supposed to get out of
it.
And I was shooting the union.
I was planning on using
the rest of that to finish.
So I had to go back to my stepfather
like two or three more times to get the
financing we needed to finish and
it was, you know, my first film.
So people are starting to think I'm kind
of crazy like they astronaut farmer,
right? Like you've been working on
this film for a year and a half.
You've sunk everything into it.
You sold your house to make this film.
Like it was a really well done movie.
You did a really good job of editing it.
It was very entertaining.
It's like I've seen a bunch of cannabis
documentaries and I think yours is the
best. I really do. It's,
it's a really well done piece and show
you showed so many points and so many
sides of it that are just irrefutable
and it's all just laid out there and
people can choose to make
their own decisions of what
they should and shouldn't
do with their body. But if you think
that that cannabis should be illegal,
you're insane. You're compliance.
How bout, how bout that?
Like the film was done so
well in parliaments eyes.
I just got invited to Parliament Hill
and Canada. That's Canada's White House.
For those who out there,
don't know.
I got invited by the Liberals to help
show the other mps the pros and cons of
cannabis prohibition with the,
they heard in the war, the,
the way it happened is Aaron Kotler,
who is the former to Irwin Cotler,
former attorney general of
Canada under John Crutches.
He had originally looked
to put a decriminalization
bill in when crutching was
ending his term. Um, but then it didn't
go through and his son are in color.
Son was actually like really
pissed off and it was like, man,
I can't believe you do that. It gets kids
addicted. What are you thinking about?
So then when it came up recently that
they're now the liberals and Canada,
we're looking at putting what they call
the most comprehensive legalization bill
that's been tried to be
passed in Canada. They, his,
his dad mentioned this in an interview
in a son called in and was like that,
you know, and he's like, hey,
why'd you say that? I was so
against it. And he's like,
well, that's what you told
me last time. He's like, no,
I watched this movie called the Union.
I've totally changed my perspective
and I want you and mum to see it.
So these nps kept hearing about it and
they kept getting letters from people
saying like from this and you
should watch it, you said.
So they sent me an email and
say, hey, can you come out?
I thought it was getting punked at first.
Like,
so think about the top of my head been,
could you see that happening
here in the u s Oh,
the White House would like to this,
this fucking corrupt cunt farm.
Well that's like,
there's pictures of me and Brett and
we're both just standing there going like
really? Like you really invited us
here. That's incredible. Yeah, it's,
what was it like? We're in
this all oh, dress like, oh,
I put on a suit. I want to,
you know, I went to go be professional and
brightness, full business attire, suit.
I've got some pictures, uh, Brian
if you want to pull them up.
But it's like me sitting with the em,
they did a cool way of doing a screening
is they had a square table and they had
TVs on the inside. They were like this.
So no matter what side you sat on,
you could see them. And then on the
tables there's also the big screen.
So everybody's sitting there with their
mix and they can all look like they're
sitting in the thing looking forward.
And then what about the Bolo tie? That
shit's ridiculous. Which one's a Bolo.
Bolo tie. That little string tie
that oh no, no, not for a while.
They tried to remember that the Polo,
they tried to try to pass it off as
a tie though. Yeah, it's a bolo tie.
Like you can even sneak it in a lot of
restaurants that you're supposed to have
a tie on with a Bolo.
Brett Brett got nailed at the Parliament
Hill restaurant cause we went to go
there and he just wears a dress shirt
and like dress pants. But they're like,
oh no tie.
So they had this drawer and I swear they
got the ugliest highs ever made just to
be like, don't you ever forget your tie
when you come in here. They were hideous,
silly.
Come on.
How silly is it to say to
someone you're not done.
You don't have your full outfit on.
You don't have your full outfit.
You have a shirt, you have a jacket.
No, he didn't have the jacket. No,
he just had the dress shirt and like
just a dress shirt and dress pants.
I came in the full suits.
Not Enough. That's not enough
to have this extra thing,
this extra piece of cloth.
So I know that you're a gentleman
because only a gentleman wears his extra
formal piece of cloth.
Man,
I don't expect you with your tie clip
to be calling anybody a cunt or telling
people to go fuck themselves.
You know what I'm saying?
That's when they know they can trust
you.
There's a lot of stuff when you go in
there and you're looking at like the old
chairs that they sit in where the queen,
if she comes in and he kind of
look at all this and like really?
Does that matter? Like, well,
what about in the olden days
when they wore those crazy wigs?
I think in Canada things,
powdered wigs.
What was that about? Like when they
were in court and shit, they were crazy.
Wigs sexy.
When you really think of that,
it's like how much it
must've sucked dick to live.
Back then it might've been cool to
have wigs on fuck outta here to live.
It's hot ass holes with wigs on are
deciding your future and fucking knock and
sticks on the ground.
Everyone would look so weird
and mysterious. He die of
the flu. How about that?
Yeah, but is log out much better
now? Like maybe there's not the show,
but I mean it's a game when you get home
and certainly a game lost confusing man.
It's like God, who is this benefiting
the half? So God damn many of them.
Even lawyers. I mean folks, let's
just, we need balance. We need balance.
We can't, it can't have people
just struggling to try to soupy.
But we needed some balance in this.
Well that,
that was the other thing is after I had
dealt with all this shit with my dad's
club and took over,
then my half sister sued me for the estate
because my dad had left. Everything's,
when shit gets crafty. I couldn't even
believe, you know, go on that end.
Like we hadn't talked in years and I had,
you know,
really reached out and I bought her a
car and done things to try like, oh,
you know, maybe out of this tragedy we
can build a relationship. And all, man,
it just went 40 wanted people were,
you know,
people look at other people sometimes like
a lottery, you know, just, they don't,
they don't think they're ever going
to be able to make money on their own.
And this is a certain amount of people
and they have this sort of like,
it's almost like a victim's rights
mentality that life is a fuck them so hard
that though they're going to, they're
going to go after you Ken. Man, I felt,
oh I felt that in the,
in the,
in the club scene he just put out a lot
thought into your health and breaks,
know very specific things. Is that what
you felt like? Well how a sumptuous of me,
sorry. No, no, because when,
when I had the club, there's
a lot of people, you know,
when I was running it that felt that,
well if you could fuck the customer,
good for us, right. We're making
money and I'm just like, man,
that's a bad Karma situation,
man. You can, you can.
I've met people that are real nice people.
Like how about Bob,
the owner of the Ice House.
Perfect example, right? Super Nice,
Super Nice person owns this club. It's
so he's putting out good Karma, you know,
real nice to people. Always very
friendly, very generous guy.
Just a cool guy. So in and
out of that comes, comes good.
You know, you control your environment,
you know totally what that was when,
you know, when my dad ran the club, it
did well because my dad was the owner.
There'd be out there shaking everybody's
hand and he was like, he had resentment.
No,
there's an energy you don't over.
Well here's what is there is a ton of
cocaine being sold all through my place.
So when I took over,
you know I
eyes had been, you know, people are
turning a blind eye for awhile. I did.
I look like the King Pin. Right.
Everybody's working their move in and hey,
I know people did what they
have to do to do in the club.
So I said that stops in the club and
then all my staff, all my staff laughs.
Oh Shit. Cocaine operation.
No it, yeah. Wow.
I heard it from, I mean you inherited
a cocaine operation. Oh yeah.
I inherited a mess dated 2123
and I was producing the union.
My first film, like that was my
only chance to get out of the hole.
How old were you when I'm at IU?
I was 24 or 25 25 well for Todd to
have that much faith in you guys,
it showed, it showed, well it
showed, you know once I met you,
but it certainly showed with your final
work where, where his head was at.
Cause it's, it's really good man. It's
very, very entertaining. No moves.
Well well if we,
I always said if people could
see the story of what it
took to put that together,
that would be a more entertaining
doc. Nah, maybe just to you
making, if you're fucking movie cause be
as entertaining as the reason why pot is
illegal. No way dude. Get serious.
It might be to you. Well
No. Well that's why we're,
it might be like a wedding video.
It's something that's awesome
to you but nobody else wants.
It's definitely not man. It's, it's,
it's an honor to see the impact it's had.
Like it,
I mean my Stepdad was the one that lent
me the money to do it and for me it was
really cool.
One day we were down at pf Chang's in
Houston and we were eating and I had my
union shirt on in this though. The
waiter comes over and he's like, man,
that movie is fucking awesome.
He's like, I Netflix that.
I got 10 friends coming over,
I'm going to show it to all them
like and I was like, oh cool, thanks.
And cause I had my hat and glass and he
was like thanks. Then he's like, wait,
he's, he get a fucking guy. That's it.
Like you do wasn't swearing
but he's like you're the guy.
Oh so he thought he was
just saying it was cool.
Yeah cause he saw the logo right
on my shirt and then you know,
I'd had that before and it was
really, it's always flattering. I,
I can't believe anybody, you
know, knows my work that well.
But then for my dad to see, right. Cause
he took this huge gamble on us. Right.
Give us $200,000 cap. My
God, he did. Holy Shit.
Brought 200 grand from your
dad to go shoot it. Whew.
That's some pressure son on.
I had to go back two or three
times because when I got
screwed over at the club,
I was anticipating to have money
from that that I didn't get.
And now the film was the
only thing I could use to pay
back. Like I'm like, well,
if I'm ever going to pay him back,
I have to get the film finished.
Otherwise I'll never get out of it.
So I had to keep going back and
back and only now, recently.
That's why it's funny some people,
but that's really,
how much have you made off the union?
I was like,
I still owe my family some money.
Do you really? Yeah. Wow. That's,
so that movie's still hasn't
gotten to the black. Well it did.
The distributors made money.
Right. But you know, they,
there's the marketing shipping and
then it's at the end of the day,
we have not seen any,
like I've been able to pay off my dad
a majority of his stuff. Thank God.
Right in. There's still residual
checks coming. They're pretty small,
but it's, it didn't make like, it didn't
do millions of dollars or you know,
these numbers that some
people might think,
I think a lot of people might have stole
your shit online if we got a quarter
for every like pirate bay and stuff
we did in the green. Yeah. You know,
it's funny because people
go, yeah, well you know,
he's not losing any money because
I wasn't going to download.
I mean I wasn't going to buy it anyway,
so I would have never bought it.
So it's not like he's losing any money,
but it was okay.
I know it's, it's, it's
tricky. It's tricky. But then
at the same time, you know,
a lot of people did see
it because that the viral,
like Facebook and social media is the
main, cause we had no money for marketing.
Yes.
That's what made it go 100% super viral.
So for a first film that was,
you know,
it to get the exposure is great
and we weren't that, you know,
as long as we could pay our families off
where we're happy with seeing a bunch
of memes from that documentary.
Oh now like those Internet memes where
he quotes somebody and there's a photo of
them.
Oh there's tons and there's tons of where
they've just cut your clips where it's
just the Joe Rogan clips from the
union and then it's like quotes,
like they'll have pictures of you that
it'll say like let's nerf the world and
all your caught me and my most
indignant moment too, because when,
when we did that,
it was when I really had just
started smoking on a reg.
What year? What did we do this
2005 we would have interviewed you.
So I had only been smoking for
like five years. So I was, I was,
I was like gearing up with like my
frustration with the whole situation.
It was like,
it was really like you caught it at
the exact right time where I was having
these conversations with people where
they would say there's something wrong
with pot and this and that. I don't
think it should be legal. I'm like,
what are you even yapping about?
Like what are you talking about?
You saying that it should be illegal to
have a beer because do you know how that
worked out? Did you ever hear
about that prohibition thing?
I went fucking crazy and organized crime
got a foothold in our society and I go,
and guess what? That's exactly what's
going on right now. It's exact same thing.
It's just with marijuana and it's with
a bunch of other different substances
that are somehow or another still
getting sold everywhere all the time.
They're going to legalize everything.
It's, it's, it's crazy. That's,
you can't eat. You can't, I mean,
you got to let people know exactly
what everything does to you.
You got to take a massive amount
of taxes from the sale of anything,
whether it's marijuana or whether it's,
you know,
I don't know if you should be able
to sell the hard shit, you know,
but I think you should be
able to sell mushrooms.
I don't think you should be able to sell
like dangerous narcotics that we know
are devastating to actual
life and towards society.
But if you can prove that something has
a history of human use, like mushrooms,
and you can prove this is a massive
amount of anecdotal evidence,
people have like changed their lives.
John Hopkins University
had this longterm study.
People did one mushroom trip
and 20 years later, they're,
they're fucking still like they're a
better person because of the experience.
It's like that kind of shit.
You hear those kinds of stories over
and over and over and over again,
and you're not. No one's dying. So
you feel like it. It's okay for this.
In this instance,
the argument's ridiculous.
It's ridiculous that you would try to
make this obviously massively beneficial
thing illegal. There's gotta be
something going on. Oh, you gotta,
you gotta see what we have
in store for the next one.
Brett wants take it to a whole new level.
It's talking about some of the think
tanks of like why we get into this.
Like are we least effective when
caught up in group mentality. Right.
Because even when we
were in Parliament Hill,
we're talking to some of
the guys there and like,
like Brett was asking some questions,
key questions. Like he's like, you know,
cause they said they had to put a bill
through the day before and it was a
thousand pages and he was like,
how often is it that sometimes things
just get missed and they get passed and
the guy was like more often than
you'd think. Well I'll just,
because people don't want to read like
it's at the end of the week and they're
like, oh there's a thousand
page bill that you want to read.
You go and you go through it.
And then that's the stuff where the smear
campaigns come up years later. Right.
And they're like, he signed this thing
10 years ago and he was working for like,
whether it's the conservatives
and they were like, okay,
we're all signing and like,
like he's going to go home and
after all the work he's done,
16 hour day at the hill,
go home and read a thousand page.
Boring is language ever
too, right? Like not,
we're not talking to any God and then try
to make sure that you understand every
line before you put your signature on it.
It's really a thousand pages.
That was the one that had
just been passed. Yeah.
How many days did this guy have
to work on that? Like they'd have,
they'd have a decision at the end
of the week. He was saying like,
and then they have a four hour vote. Like
it had been worked on for a long time,
but by the time it got to
that stage and it's like they,
so did they have to read the whole 1000
well that said a lot of the times it
depends on who's dealing with it,
but who would ever expect
someone to be able to do this?
That's what I was looking like. It just,
the workload they have, like they were,
we were leaving at six and they were
going into a four hour vote for that.
And I was just like, oh my God.
I was like, I couldn't shit.
And they almost like we went to look
through and the, and the guy's like, oh,
if you come through here,
you have to stay through the whole thing.
So if you come past this point, then you
cannot leave because it's in session.
I was like, well, I'm not going near
there. Four hours, Jesus Christ die.
That will be the,
wow.
Did you see that recent video of the
woman from the DEA fielding questions
about, from posted on the gentleman
from Colorado who was, uh, asking,
uh,
if marijuana was less dangerous than
heroin and she's her bad and she wouldn't
respond, she was just like, well, we feel
that all illegal drugs are bad. It was,
have you seen it Brian? Oh my
God. Pull it up because it's,
it's preposterous what we move. What
would you Google? What would be the word?
I'd just put DEA,
DEA agent.
I'm stumped marijuana.
It was a lady with particularly sad eyes.
She really did. And she had
particularly sad eyes like I didn't,
I don't think there's any joy in that job.
And you,
when you know that you're just,
all you're doing is trying to keep people
from smoking pot because that's what
they're telling you to do.
And there's no joy in that man.
That lady had no joy in her art.
We'll look at,
even though it wasn't eat
bleach as members of the team,
she's just doing her job. That's it.
Yeah, that's her. Yeah. I just hold up,
but just check by the dopey
i's a hilariously enough.
What does this gentleman's name?
Cause he's a bad motherfucker.
Re w what is his name then? Marijuana.
He's from Colorado. Let's give him props.
All illegal drugs are,
is methamphetamine worse for
somebody's health and marijuana?
I don't think any illegal
drugs. Heroin, a worse, uh,
for someone's health than
marijuana. Again, all, I mean,
I know that you can look this up.
You should know this is the
chief administrator for the
Drug Enforcement Agency.
I'm asking you a very straight forward
question. Is Heroin, Jared Polis,
mother Fucker, marijuana. We got to look
at getting him for the culture. Drugs are,
are bad. Just mean you don't know.
Heroin causes an addiction. Okay.
It causes, uh, causes many
problems is very hard to,
uh,
to what does that mean?
That the health impact of
heroin is worse than marijuana?
Is that what you're telling me?
I think,
I think you're asking is the objective
question. No, it's objective. Uh,
just looking at the science, this is
your area of expertise. I'm a lay person,
but I've read,
read some of the home aware of it.
I'm just asking you as an
expert in the subject area,
is heroin worse for someone's
health and marijuana? You know,
I'm answering as a police officer and
as a DEA agent that these drugs are
illegal because they are dangerous
because they are addictive because they,
they do hurt a person's house. So heroin
is more addictive than marijuana. Heroin,
more dick of the marijuana.
I your experience generally
the properties of heroin.
Yes. It's more addictive.
It's methamphetamine. More
addictive than marijuana.
Okay.
Well,
both are addictive ways.
Is Methamphetamine more highly
addictive than marijuana.
I think some people become addicted to
marijuana and some people become addicted
to methamphetamine. You mentioned that
the top, and uh, your top priority,
I believe you indicated to us is abuse
of prescription drugs is one of the main
classifications of prescription drugs,
painkillers that you're concerned about.
That's correct. And are those
painkillers a addictive? Yes,
they are very addictive. Uh, are those
painkillers more addictive than marijuana?
All illegal drugs are in
schedule one or addictive.
Oh my God.
It's amazing that that person in charge
of anything that has anything to do with
the legality of marijuana.
Well, see that's where we
want to show in the culture.
High ride is there seems to be this global
cultural shift in the way people are
looking at cannabis laws and the people
that are coming out now are more and
stuff than ever.
You're seeing some big names like several
members of the DEA that are now part
of leap that are talking out against
the big time. Well, it's a, it's a,
it's a crime. It's a criminal
thing. What they're doing,
what they're doing is
they're somehow or another,
they are being forced into a situation
where they're ignoring the science and
ignoring the, the, the, um,
health benefits and ignoring the
medicinal benefits and just the fact that
people enjoy it and joy and,
and,
and the fact that there's virtually no
one has ever died from it ever. Really.
Realistically, no one has ever
die from it. Just that, just that,
that anybody keeping you from that,
anybody that keeping you from that,
that's not your friend, that's
not your friend. That's craziness.
It's craziness that they think they
can keep you from an experience because
that's really at the end of the day,
what it really is,
you're still responsible for your actions.
You shouldn't be driving.
We baked out of your fucking head and
forget which way to turn the middle of an
intersection cause we'll fucking dark man.
I shouldn't ask you much nyquil.
Exactly.
But you should be responsible for your
actions and that that is what being a
human being should be all about.
Carry your own weight,
take responsibility for the
sh the shit that you fuck up.
If you fuck up something
because you're high,
like you'd go and smash a
window if it's not the high you.
A lot of people could have been high in,
they walk right by that window and
didn't want to break it at all.
You are an asshole man and you should
have to pay for that fucking window.
But there's nothing to
do with weed. Joe, come,
come run a nightclub and you want to
see a ticking time bomb. Oh my God,
I couldn't.
Then there's people on booze where I've,
I've had this conversation a million
times and I used to work the door and you
have to escort them l cause
they're too drunk. Right core.
And then the mood when mean this
is a board and I'm like, yeah,
where you're allowed to drink but
you can't get wasted. Right. So then,
but then this goes around in
a circle and a big fine, fine.
They get out the door and then
they forget and to come up.
So when they get kicked, Oh man, cause
you're too drunk, dude. It's a board.
I'm like, I just went through this
wreck. Like, I honestly can't understand.
I'm like, are you that like
is it really just goes in,
it goes blank and then goes blank and
keeps coming and then they start getting
as you keep being nice and you're
like, listen, you're done for tonight.
Come back tomorrow. I'll even, I'll even
pay your cover tomorrow if you come back.
But tonight you're done. That's very
generous of, you know, and that's,
that was always the offer.
Be like,
I'll help you get a cab and a wave
your coverage to come back tomorrow,
but tonight you're done.
And then they take your kindness
Renin and they start being like, yeah,
well then fucking and the
boost or like it just,
you see them morph into this person
you like and I bet when he was sober he
would just be a nice guy.
But then there will suddenly,
it's like he gets too drunk,
he wants to be an ass.
You start off as polite as you can and
they'll be polite and then their emotions
shift.
And those any get dumbest thing to do
too is when you're out and you're drunk
and you'd be a Douche bag to a bouncer.
It's such a bad move.
I'm such a bad move.
I've worked the door and I never got
that logic where someone's like, oh,
well you make 10 books now where
you're trying to get the gold star.
Some people are just assholes.
You know, we, you Kinda,
I have a, uh, I mean,
it sounds ridiculous,
but I have great respect for cops and
great respect for people who are working,
you know, a security in a club or a
nightclub or something like that. Like,
that's a, that's a difficult position.
It's a, it's a dangerous Bishan.
Thank you very much. That's how I
feel about it. Like, so when I, if,
if ever I'm in a situation, if I ever
was, I'm never are, but if I was,
I'll be very polite. But no, sir. Uh,
you know, none, none, no craziness,
no wanting to fight the cop,
you know, like Jesus Christ.
Those people are assholes. It's, you know,
you can't blame alcohol for those people.
I don't know what it is.
I don't know what causes it.
But you can't blame alcohol when a guy
tries to punch a cop. You know those guys,
like some people damages that.
It's like that's the thing you're serving.
They see in colonial area,
there's a lot and a lot of growers.
That's how I knew so much about
the details of the union. Right.
How it all broke down.
I looked at getting into it when my dad
first died and he passed away like as to
supplement me to go to film school.
Right.
I looked at being the Latin
landowner that would buy the house,
have people that would grow for me,
I'd come back every three months,
but the cash 50 50 but then
dangerous. Is that dangerous? Right.
Canada is much more lenient
than it is in the u s for sure.
But I, I didn't do it and that was
originally the beginning of the union.
We cut my story out because we
thought at the end of the day,
the union is so much bigger than my
story. It's not care. So we cut it out.
But that's what got us into that.
And originally when we
were going to do the union,
we're just going to do an expo,
say the BC industry. Right.
And how it's so evolved and how like
there's a mortgage broker that'll help you
cause you got bad credit and they'll
send you to this banker to help put it
through and that you've got to realtor.
Like they all know, like even my,
one of my friends worked at
a car dealership and they
went to their discretion
whether or not things could flag. Is that
how that works? Well you know the banks,
it's, why am I asking this? So
Am I going into organized crime?
So nosy mill,
it's interesting and it's one that some
people's favorite part of the union,
right?
But you can,
that was where I felt guilty is that a
lot of these guys would come in in the
wintertime.
Colona's Dad,
it's a summer town and they would come
in and they got the most disposable
income because they've got some cash
that they of always put into things.
So then they come in and spend two or
three grand and that's awesome for us.
Right? Like I'm like, yeah, and then but
I'm like, okay, who's the bad guy here?
Like a lot of people say he's bad,
he's a drug dealer,
he's growing but then I know what he
does and I'm gladly taking his money to
serve another drug. Right. So then I
was like, how am I any better? Right.
He's not a drug dealer.
He was selling weed or if
that is a completely different
connection than someone
who will, who will sell you
something that's fucked up.
True are dudes who are real drug
casual about it.
Get people hooked.
There's people that are
like real clever about it.
I've known the guys that have sold coke
and stuff. I owned a club through that.
But it's, the problem is, is that
while it's still like the way it is,
well a lot of them are controlled or
they get ripped off by gangs and fray.
That's where it seems like
now in Canada you can
get a federal license.
That's the way a lot of guys are going.
If they don't have a criminal record,
they can get a federal license.
So there's no like here that you have
a state license and the feds come in,
like you get a federal license and you
can grow. Why he does no reasons. Yeah.
Okay.
But don't you have like a dispute in
certain parts of Canada where there's far
more conservative? They don't feel the
same way about marijuana and they do,
but that's,
that is a federal license that they're
looking now to try to shut down,
but it's to grow because there's people
whose looking to try shows down. Oh,
the government's looking to change it,
change it back to make it not available.
I'm not sure of all that.
We have to dive into that one
as we get into the research.
But they're trying to pull it back.
But it was interesting.
I just went into a huge grow op.
It just outside of my town,
there was a total legal one and it had
like 19 permits for like they could do
the clones, they could store
for others, they could do huge,
huge operational show you pictures on
my phone. It was like, I think they,
I think they said they had 150 lights.
So if you,
and they were getting high times,
they're doing an article cause they
were getting 2.2 pounds of light.
So they're getting like 150 pounds,
170 pounds every but completely legal.
Like they had cameras when I was there,
the cops were coming through it with
them and this thing was so clean,
Joe Bryant, they had offered music,
they had opera music playing in the,
in the thing because planting in it
enhances their growth cycle. My God,
I want to move to Canada,
I want to move to Canada.
So they wanted me to come cause I was
a union guy. They're like, ah yeah,
you can fill them anything you want
in here. And, and it was beautiful.
I'll show you guys some pictures.
I got them on the phone is too
fucking stupid to let that happen.
But that would be of great benefit
to people. It would provide jobs,
it would change the economy,
and once marijuana became legal
than hemp could would become legal.
Then we'll have legal in Canada too, which
I know. Yeah, we were selling I'd on it.
We're going to start selling this hemp
protein powder. It's fucking awesome, man.
I've been, there's a dark chocolate,
I forget the the company's name,
but I've been drinking this stuff really
steady for like a couple months now.
It's like hemp, hemp protein
doesn't give me like terrible gas.
It doesn't fuck with me.
It feels like really healthy.
It's like a really easily digestible plant
protein for me. I really love it man.
It really been getting into it,
but we can't get any fucking hemp hearts.
It's really hard. You can
only get 50 pounds a day.
That's the most you can order.
So it's like the hemp part is just so
bizarre to me because that makes just 0
million cents. So you can, like we
explained in the movie like super, yeah,
you can use it manufacturer to ship at
everything but grow it here in the u s so
stupid because when people don't
even understand is like hemp is not
psychoactive. Like you can't even
get high from it. It's, it's a,
it's like a cousin plant to the
psychoactive version of marijuana.
Although you could use marijuana as well.
You could use the stems and the sticks.
I mean it's the same shit.
It's hemp.
It's just that the flowers of the
marijuana plants are the ones that get you
high.
So it's not whether or not people could,
I guess someone could pretend
like, oh, booth was Joseph. None,
but I have beautiful flowers,
flowers. What would you say? Oh,
what happened here? This is a mistake.
Oh, how did this, how did this lie?
Oh, well let me pull this
out. This is the devil.
But the rest of them just for
making underwear and paper. Well,
I think it, once it happened,
the thing is though,
once it gets impregnated
then the whole crop,
like you can't keep just the one or two
like that. You don't know enough about,
I don't know enough about the botany
of how it grows, but I don't know.
But I think a lot of people think too
is they don't realize like have you seen
some of the products it's being used for
like in the new Bugattis and stuff like
that. The interiors she, that
Lotus that they made out of him,
they made a of this Badass Lotus and
it's like part of it was like just the
actual fiber, not even colored.
The actual fiber of bright.
See if he could pull up a picture
of that cause it really is dope.
Like Lotus handle car. Did you know
that Henry Ford's is that you're moving,
you're moving.
Well that's not mine,
but there's a little clip
like that that there's,
I know about Henry Ford stopped.
It was in the union. No,
we do have an opening bit that talks big
about hemp, not Henry for his videos.
Just that little clip that's up there
on its own. For folks who don't know,
Henry Ford's first car
was made out of hemp,
like he made him body panels that you see
that Lotus for folks who are following
us on Ustream, if you're not
just just Google, uh, hemp Lotus.
There's a couple other
pictures of this thing, um,
that maybe you could see
it a little clearer, Brian.
But what it is is they
made a car instead of like,
like Corvettes are made out of fiberglass,
you know,
and like a really expensive cars. A lot
of them are made out of carbon fiber.
Well this car is made out of hemp
and it's stronger than fiberglass.
It's, it's a natural pride
or two lighter. They just,
there's a car in Canada, bill called
the crestal, that's an electric car.
That's an all the interior and the
majority of the body home brown strip down
the front. That's exactly,
that's the actual hemp color.
That's the actual fiber.
It's so bad ass man.
And it's really fucking durable.
It's a crazy plant.
It's like you could get a stock and it's
really thick and it's light as fuck.
Like you pick it up and like it feels
like nothing, but it's so dense,
like it's really weird
if no one has ever seen.
If you've never seen a hemp stalk
before, it really does feel like, okay,
maybe this is an alien plant.
Like wait,
maybe this is not like any plant
I've ever come in contact before.
If you pick up an oak log, you know the
thickness and the would that would it?
That feels like it's heavy
as shit. Right? Well,
the hemp stocks feel like
the hardness of an oak log,
but it's like really light.
It's weird.
It's like where the fuck did this thing
come from? It's, it's crazy. I mean we, I,
we knew,
I knew nothing about pot
and when I started in the
Union now they wanted to do,
that's hilarious. I just wanted to do,
like I said, the x was a to BC industry.
Then when we discovered all these things,
that's why some people that really knew
everything in there was like, well,
like a lot of the activists, like I knew
everything in the union. It was like,
yeah, but oh, how dare you.
Me and like 99% of other people don't.
So there's a lot of weeks that know they
think that everybody should catch up.
Yeah, I knew all that stuff will and,
and here's the Kudos that I even,
I didn't really,
I,
it really clicked with me when we were
parliament hill is that how entertained
they were. Right. And there's four
of them that weren't going to stay.
They're going to be there for 15 minutes
and they were going to leave and they
stayed throughout the whole film.
And at the end they were saying that like,
I didn't know it'd be that funny and I
didn't know what a B and Brett was like,
well that's the key to getting you to
absorb information is it still has to be,
it's still a movie.
It has to be entertaining.
If it was just a blurb and it was like,
here we are at or sometimes people
forget that most people don't know that
information.
Most people don't and it you cannot
tell the story without giving that
information. If you want things to
be reached by a giant gang of people,
you cannot assume that they already
have this information. It's too potent.
It's too important. It's too
significant. And the story,
well that's why we're diving into
the second one. We're going all out.
What is the second one going to
get involved with the culture?
I we're looking much more global this
time and like I sold looking at the
cultural shift that's starting to happen
with regards to the way people look at.
What do you accredit that
you, do you think the Internet
is responsible for that?
Is that we, yes. The distribution
of the truth about marijuana.
That's exactly, that's actually a
part in it. We want to interview,
you know Sean Parker and some of those
people like to talk about how the
Internet, even the playing field,
like remembering the union.
We have Ronald Reagan saying,
you know,
and I'm surprised the scientists haven't
brought out this new information that
says that marijuana,
it could be the most dangerous drug
that is in use in our society today.
When he said that in the 80s like
unless you're going to go call a medical
facility and polar old records,
like you're like, hey man,
that's, that's present.
He's,
he must know he is a team that's giving
them that information and he's got it
right. But now you can go on
Google and you can look at,
and of course you get
the good with the bad.
There's a lot of fake and hate it when
people going back and forth for saying
this.
But you know,
you can pick or choose through 10
10 or more articles and that's it.
We did in the union,
we put all the links and stuff up there.
So like if you didn't believe what we
said and like, hey, we're filmmakers,
there's one or two little mistakes
and there that we made. Absolutely.
But if it got you to research
it and start doing it,
that's a great movie because
you're thinking about it
after you've watched with
a factual mistakes that you missed
all their very, very slight.
It was like with the original
declaration of independence,
it was actually the first two drafts,
not the one that's in the museum,
the one that's in the
museum's made with high.
But the first two drafts
were written on hemp.
So it was a lot of his like clever were,
and then you know,
same with the 30 days of marijuana
being in your system. Lester Grinspoon,
the First Ivy League doctor to
come out and talk about, um, the,
the real medical findings
that he discovered. He said,
it's not always 30 days,
like if you smoke all the time
and it's in your fat cells,
but it can be if you just
smoke once in the first time,
there's a good chance in two weeks
we're going to be in your system. So,
so when you hear about
a guy like Nick Diaz,
kitten popped and he's got like
the non psychoactive metabolites,
what does that mean?
Does that mean he's like, he's like
really gotten any weakness system, right?
Barely. Barely, barely. I
think that uh, you know, if,
if they're gonna I mean those guys go
through so much pain and you've seen a lot
of tragedy with the painkillers.
Now. Like, I mean, a friend of mine,
Derek Boogaard who was, you know, an Nhl
enforcer, uh, for the New York Rangers,
you know, how to, uh,
accidental mix and I, you,
you'd wished that there would be that
alternative for pain. So maybe Nick Diaz,
his knuckles are sore. He hits people,
he hits dudes a lot of times in a fight,
like more than anybody else. They
just don't stop. Right. So, you know,
maybe as he's got arthritis in
his hands are from training.
That's what he wanted to
use. Like at how, by it,
whatever the fuck reason he wants to use
it. But I'm saying even if that's my,
my take on it now at this
point, it's like, yeah,
of course he should be
able to use it for anxiety.
Of course he should be able
to use it for insomnia.
Of course he should be able to use it,
but he really,
he should be able to use it for whatever
the fuck he wants to use it for.
And this idea that there's any reason
why it should be illegal is just crazy
talk. It's crazy talk. It makes
you a nicer person. It does.
It might make some people a
little dope here, but guess what?
That probably means you need
to get their shit together.
They're probably thinking a bunch of
dumb stupid shit when they're sober and
when they're high,
there's not much to spin around in there.
Maybe it's good for them to feel stupid.
Well think, think about it for the pain.
I'm sure you know fighters,
Joe,
that if taken like the hard painkillers
and then a lot of notes that I need to
realize their whole careers
because of that stuff.
And they don't even know how addictive
it is. Right? The doctor says,
take this for pain. They get
hooked to it. So, I mean,
just that when I've seen in athletes,
like they have to go through a lot
of pain and these constant man,
I know a dude who was a s a
really like completely clean guy.
He didn't smoke cigarettes,
he rarely ever drank.
He was a really healthy,
and he was a professional pool player.
He hurt his back and he got hooked on
pain pills and became a complete total
mess and then died. I mean they,
they literally took this dude's life.
This dude got swamped up in that world
of pills and he's younger than me and now
he's gone. You know? And I, I knew him,
I knew him when he was totally healthy
and I knew him when he was gone.
And that's crazy. It's crazy. It's a
sad thing. He was like proud, proud guy.
And he would like fall asleep
in a plate of mashed potatoes,
like that kind of shit.
And that's lead.
See how many people I saw like that in
the Bardo. Like you'd see those, how many,
you see these beautiful girls come in
and then like four years later they're
like, hey, and you're like, it's and a
lot of the dancers and you're like, Hey,
oh my God. Like you look like you've
died and come back to life already sad.
Those kind of drugs are so
terrible. They're so sad.
And your body, it's just a,
it's a Shitty, I wouldn't recommend
owning a nightclub if someone,
if someone said to me like,
Hey, I'll do like hi, just,
I don't ever want to be in that business
again. Our business is rough man.
You know?
So I'd rather,
I'd rather be a challenge like a
struggling filmmaker that's, you know,
working three jobs like I am then
go back to that. Yeah. Well you,
you dealing with groups of
drunks on a regular basis,
it's like and seeing and then you know,
seeing the sad stories like that or seeing
like times when a guy just got out of
line and bumped into the wrong person
and got smashed. Yeah, that sucks too.
I watched a guy get hit in the face
with a bottle once. It never, you know,
I never expected this to
happen the way it happened,
the way the guy hit the guy in the face,
it was like there's no way he just did
that for that reason. It was like nothing.
And this kind of smashed him in the face,
cut his face.
And I remember thinking now like always
be aware that it's possible that someone
out there is so fucking crazy that they
would do that for no reason like that.
Oh,
that's why when I worked the door,
I never let someone get to the odd side
of me or anything like that. Right.
And a lot of the times it's some ways
aggressive in their hands. Clench.
You don't see it. I mean we would, I
always tell them, I was like, listen,
you're not supposed to strike and hit
guys, but if, if you're really threatened,
right.
And some guy you're in a corner,
like you do what you got to do
to look after yourself. Right.
We'll try to get there as fast as we can.
But I mean we had a doorman stabbed,
oh shit,
he got stabbed three times and probably
the only time in your life you like to
hear this,
they told them they're like,
it's a good thing you're
overweight because if you
would have been an inch thick
inch thinner it would appears major.
Cause the guy that got Dave through these
guys out with the guys went out to the
car,
came back and then they went at the
Dorman and one of our dorm and knocked the
first one out.
Then he went with the other one.
He was tussling with him and he said he
put him down and then when he put them
down and he saw the blade hit the
ground and blood all over it and then he
punched in the side and then
he looked and he was like holy.
It was just pouring out and uni.
And then I remember him telling the story
that really scared me as he sat down
and he went to our other dorm and
just being like, if I pass out,
please make sure I get to the hospital.
Cause you don't know what's
going to happen if your
body's going to shut down or
like, you know, you might just faint
out, but you're, you know, so it's, it's,
it's shitty. I, I'd never want to let
another nightclub. Fuck that. Yeah.
There's just too many douche bags.
They can't keep it together.
It's too many people out there really
at the roadhouse pay hurts really at the
heart of it, at the bottom at all. It's,
it's really people doing a
shitty job of raising people,
people doing a shitty job of having
a community and doing a shitty job of
raising people. And what do you
make? You make shit kids. No Shit.
Kids grow up to be gigantic fucking
problems. And if you run a nightclub,
congratulations, you're the new
babysitter. Well you're a new,
the new babysitter for the drunken Douche
bag and then anything that they do,
like they're not held responsible.
Like if they, that's where,
going back to the responsibility thing,
you were saying,
people should just be held
to their actions where what
you get for nightclub and
you can get sued then they go out,
not just that.
They go and fight or hurt someone or they
attack our bouncers and then they get
hurt on the way out. And yes, of
course there's other sides that were,
sometimes the doormen are excessive,
but there's times where guys so drunk,
they like, you carry him out,
you don't, you go to let him go.
And he stumbles and smashes his face on
the concrete and caves his cheekbone.
And right, like I worked as a
security guard at great woods, uh,
center for the performing art. It's like,
it's like in Mansfield or something,
Massachusetts. I think that's where
it's at. And it's, um, it's um,
this outside performance
area. So it's, it's a part
of it is inside and part
of it is like covered,
but then there's a back area that's
open that's like a lawn area.
And I was security there and we did it
for a whole summer. And I tell you, man,
after a while you really develop
this us versus them mentality.
And it's really stupid. But
I was 19. I was an idiot.
I shouldn't have been in that
sort of a job in the first place.
And the guy that I was working for
was carets. He aggressive. I mean,
oh my God,
I saw him on the first day.
I worked there Taqa guy and beat him with
a walkie talkie because the guy stole
their golf cart. They had a golf
cart, they would drive around the,
the great woods width.
So these guys tackle them and they
beat the shit out of this guy with a,
with a walkie talkie. That dude was a
classic. His name was alley cat. And uh,
he wanted to open up this bar.
He had this dream, you know,
he was the head security guy with a dream
and his dream was to open up this bar
alley cats, libations and victuals. And
I remember it was the title. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Because marketing,
those are the victuals is,
was like a cool name for food.
And libations is like a cool
old name for liquors and drink.
And so that was his, that was his
dream. And he was a crazy motherfucker.
And he ran, he ran the security thing and
it was me and a friend of mine who was,
uh, we were, um, on the same competition
teams, same taekwondo competition team.
He got a job there and they said,
do you have any,
any of the other guys that are
martial arts guys that want a job?
And so they essentially hired all the
top martial arts guys from this Jay Kim
Taekwondo Institute. And they were all
the security for this place. But I was,
I was like,
this is the craziest idea ever.
He was like seven or
eight people you know,
that have like the security jackets
on and it was like fucking thousand.
Oh yeah.
Thousands of crazy assholes.
And I will always wear a
jacket over my security jacket.
Like I would just try to blend
in as much as possible. I'm like,
I'm way too short for this
too. I'm only five, eight.
I can't be around like big giant
dudes with a security jacket on.
That shit's ridiculous.
You know,
I want to have to fucking punch and kick
my way out of this. Oh well that was,
I remember there'd be slow nights,
right,
where you'd have a big rowdy
like sports team come in, right.
And it'd be like the bartender
and you'd have one dorm and on,
cause it's a slow night or
two and then you'd literally,
they begin rowdy and
starting to smash glasses.
And then literally we'd have to
think like, okay, like be ready,
like Gba ready to jump over the
bar if you have to help. Right.
If these guys get to a point where they
really want to cause something that you
say,
it can be so weird that you just politely
ask them to do something and then they
get super aggressive. Well
I then, and then they,
then they just really look at
size where they're like, fuck,
there's like nine of us and we're all
in good shape and there's only two or
three of them. Like why do I
have to respect this guy? Yeah,
it can get bad.
But what a lot of people didn't know it
was in a small town is a lot of like the
people hanging out.
We're really good friends with the staff.
They come there all the time.
So the odd times that that
happened when I was doing it,
you'd have people jump in from outside.
Right?
Cause they was like serve as
the community more or less you,
you'd have friends that just the common,
you know when their regular you treat
them good and then they'd come in and I'll
tell you the one time my dad was friends
with a lot of the big Mc guys and when
they used to come in there was never a
problem in the bar because everyone was
worried about bumping into,
one of them are like,
you know some idiots wrestling
and they fall into a table.
So like it was weird on those nights it
would be is usually the young like just
starting to slang little gang bangers
that think that they're all that and they
have something to prove and they,
they're doing something for somebody
else where they've got some kind of
connections are nutty Gig for you man.
And to be only 23 years of age and having
a handle all that. Oh Man. My, my wife.
That's, that's, I mean why I married
her. She was a trooper through that too.
Did it last before you got
rid of it? Oh, I had to get,
my dad passed away in 2003 and we were
out of there by 2005 so for two years you
got to run that mother.
If I had to get proper books because
my dad didn't do proper books. Oh.
And so to sell to a legit buyer, they
wanted to use two or three years of books.
Right. I talk to my friend Bobby. Yeah,
well that was over the situation. Well,
trust me, there was lots of
bad Bobby's coming around.
But my thing was like, okay,
if I took it is only one bad. Bobby, you
don't know bad by, I mean, I mean bad,
but guys that would come
with a cash offer. Right?
And then if there's a cash offer that
sounds like bad Bobby. Well, but then,
but then in three years, if it doesn't
do the numbers they think and they say,
well, I don't think I overpaid. I
want some back. Right. So that's like,
that's why I was like, okay, I
don't want to go that option.
So tried to work it out with like a
childhood friend and then you know,
didn't do that right either because
we didn't put everything on paper.
So I got screwed and had to start for,
I remember when my wife was eight months
pregnant with Riley and my daughter and,
and uh,
we had negative $400 in our account and
I needed $45,000 to finish the union and
I didn't know where I was going to get it.
Suck that Dixon to just think
about it. No, fuck about us.
You can find a rich guy and
suck his dick for a million.
I was in New York and worked around those
guys would be no way. Yeah. Would if,
you know, like for whatever reason you
got flown to John Travolta's house.
No, no, no man, I got bad stories
about those lists and you know, man,
I did that stuff in New York.
I lived in a model house in New York.
Not that I don't want to get you in
anything. You don't want to talk about it,
but, no, no, no, no. Me a nod to gay.
Never for the record. Never did any
gain shit shorty. I'm sure. But uh, no.
I lived in a model house
cause I used to work for men.
Thank you for it not getting upset.
Oh, I know. I wouldn't get upset.
I've listened to your show. I've
listened since you guys had snowflakes.
I know that the shows that well. Yeah.
Well we've hung out a bunch of time span.
It was fun.
The UFC a up in Vancouver,
but right now I don't think they can
come back. I think, I don't know.
I think there's some problem
with the regulatory, well,
I want to try to come see me in Calgary.
There was some sort of a ruling against
a MMA of Vancouver. I'm come on,
really trying to remember what the actual
ease, no problem was. Yeah, let me,
let me Google this real
quick. I don't know man.
You know, it's like friends,
like it's a fucking problem
all over the world, dude.
People Successful Shows York that want
to see the UFC and somehow or another
it's been um, uh, what am I going to do?
They still sell players cigarettes in
Canada. Oh, you bet. Wow. That's great.
What am I Google it again? Jesus Christ.
UFC. Now going back to Vancouver.
Vancouver, right. You guys
are coming to Calgary soon.
That's not far from where I am. Well,
eight hour drive. I got so upset.
I was the all I can think of as Bob Riley,
I start thinking about New York.
I completely spaced on Vancouver because
the New York thing drives me fucking
crazy. So illogical and it's
so corrupted. It's so gross.
The people of New York would make a
lot of fucking money if they came.
If the UFC came to Madison Square Garden,
it would be fucking huge.
How about this John Jones versus Anderson
Silva or Anderson Silva versus George
Saint Pierre,
something like that.
Inside Madison fucking square garden
and I'm like a kid in Canada. I would,
that's our cots are keeping that from
happening. That could fucking happen.
What's the hole back there?
Some,
I don't even want to name names,
political bullshit, nonsense, culinary,
union, fucking whatever, whatever.
A lot of corruption as people
are getting greased, the,
the desire of the people is
getting ignored. People want
to have it in the state.
It generates money. The amount of fans
that they have in New York City alone,
it's fucking through the roof.
Everywhere you look,
there's a Jujitsu school in New
York does MMA, gyms, boxing gyms.
People are allowed to enjoy it and for
some asshole politician with some fucking
backing by whatever creepy organization
that's trying to keep this shit out,
it's ridiculous because it
violates the will of the people.
Anybody that does that is a shit
politician. That's a sad statement.
That's an anti American thing to do.
You're trying to keep something away from
people that want it and you're trying
to block a business and you're trying to
do it because you're in cahoots with a
different business. That should be
illegal, but shit, that's corruption.
I can picture.
I did.
It's not a mirror would be a mistake
within our come back to Vancouver.
It's not American.
You're leaving Vancouver for Calgary.
Yeah. You guys are coming to Calgary.
That's all good.
I don't know man.
I feel still watch NBC,
but okay,
here's the latest legislation opens
door for ultimate fighting championship.
You okay? So this sounds
good. Maybe I read that wrong.
I can't pay attention everything folks.
The fucking,
I know people always go with me.
Some people try to come up with the
toughest questions about marijuana and be
like, what do you think about this law
that was passed in Missouri two weeks ago?
And I'm like, man, sorry. I do my best
to try to stay up to date on everything,
but I, it is physically impossible. I
don't know what's going on in Missouri.
So they did stop it.
They,
there was an introduction of a provincial
law designed to break the directed a,
the deadlock over regularly regulation
and supervision of Combat Sports.
So originally they stopped it and now
they're trying to figure out the correct
way to regulate what's going on.
Now it seems like they're opening the door
to it. Coming back. I think people do,
you know, ultimately the
here, the will of the people,
especially today so popular in Canada,
people don't even understand.
It's hugely popular in America.
Way more popular in Canada. No,
it's like in Canada. It's not like
when there's a UFC, it's not like,
are you watching the fights? It's like,
where are you going to watch the fights?
Like dude,
we were at the fucking watchers arena.
That gigantic Roger Center,
whatever it is. What is it called?
Is it the Roger Center? The things
crazy building that's, it's so big.
There's a hotel inside of it.
There's a hotel inside of it and
they used to play baseball indoors.
That's how big this place is. And
it was filled for the, I mean,
I don't know if they could do that
in America. I mean, maybe they could.
It was George Saint
Pierre and Anderson Silva.
I guarantee you they could do
that in America. But that's
a big goddamn crowd. No,
it's Canada's nutty for it. We, it
has less people. Yeah, we're, we're,
but I think that comes a lot
with the hockey culture, right?
There's been fighting in the
hockey culture for years,
which is like our national sport.
I hate to say this,
but I think there's more fucking manly
men per capita in Canada or more condoms.
I just think, you know, I
think they, I think you come
from a country, first of all,
that has to survive the cold. Right? And
I think that's good for your character.
You know, I've always compared, uh,
people that have it soft to people that
had it tough and you always see the
people that have had like
the most interesting people
that I know are all people
that had it tough. You know, when
you have, it's soft, it's easy,
just come out fucking useless.
When they got it, they got those,
those battle scars, even if
they're not physical ones. Right.
The wounds of going through that.
That's a lot of times people said,
I have an old soul for,
that's one of the gas thing someone can
ever say to you and you need to get away
from him. Probably trying to fuck you.
Right. If it's a dude, especially,
it was a woman who she's
definitely trying to fuck you.
Look at your handsome ambassador.
No,
I was at a restaurant once and I actually
heard that hack line, that old soul,
a guy was like reading a book.
It was the weirdest thing, man.
He's an actor that was in, um, I
don't even want to say his name,
just some weird old actor that was in a
bunch of movies and then they probably
went crazy.
So he's sitting by himself with a book,
which is what you do at a restaurant
if you go to a nice place.
And so there's this couple next to
me just starts introducing himself.
Would you do, sorry, sorry.
Glitch. Yeah. He just,
he starts introducing himself into
their conversation and talking to them.
And then he's like telling this, uh, this
man that he has an old soul that's lame.
And I'm like, not now you're making me
feel that I use that choice of words. No,
it's, I mean it's look you, you,
you said what you mean, you know,
it's not nothing wrong with it,
but I had a funny old soul story so yeah,
I did just have a funny, a funny
image. He like wore a Bandana.
He's one of those assholes sit by himself
eating dinner with a Bandana on his
head. Okay. What the
fuck are you doing? Reading
a book? We used to get those
guys in the nightclub to,
they'd come in and sit in the corner,
read a book. It's like really?
This probably the loudest,
most annoying place to read it.
You're better off just to have a drink
and stare at the girls cause that's what
you really would like that though.
You know,
it's like some people
like to work at Starbucks,
they want to hear people
come in and come out.
That I could understand but a nightclub
like we can't even hear yourself think
like that shit man. People are weird.
You know, he pulled a weird dude.
I don't have to tell you.
You were running a god Damn Strip Club,
Strip club connection at 23 years of age.
How did you avoid getting sucked into
the clutches of organized crime? I just,
well I left originally when I was younger
and went to New York and I wanted to
get into the film industry and
stuff like that. So I, I, I just,
I don't know,
when I came back I never,
it wasn't much of a big drinker and
wasn't into the party scene. So I was,
luckily I didn't fall into that.
That trap.
It was union was like the first
thing you ever did. Really? Yeah.
The first thing I'd ever produced. Yes.
Did such a fucking bang up job of it, man.
And you, you went to some
real creepy places like you,
you were like sort of an investigative
reporter in, you know, in that movie.
Like when you went to those places where
you went to those drain tiles. Yeah, man,
explain that cause that's of crazy.
Well we knew the people that were
busted in there and obviously,
and explain what the situation.
Okay.
Well there is for the
people listening at home,
didn't know there was 20 full size,
like those square,
they're not actual train cards,
but they're the cargo carts that they
put on the trains and they'd actually
buried them and connected them together
so that if you were to look at them that
it'd be five rows with two each way. So
like, or no, 10 rows with two each way.
So like 20 full sized train cars buried
underground and they had a giant grow up
under there and it was 10 miles in the
mountain where there isn't a neighbor.
You can hear the craziest part joke.
The guy that got that busted actually
snuck in there and took pictures one night
to show the cops so they can go,
oh my God.
Balls and way up in the
Bush like way the fuck out.
They're balls of adamant
Tanium oh man. But yeah, that,
that had 287 lights.
What is Wolverine's bones?
Adamantium but that's
how I always said and
she's a soccer balls to 287 lights and
they were both going to make just the
growers that I knew in there. We're
going to make half a million in one year.
And so what happens now, because
it's not lake, they got routed.
So we got very lucky. One of them
got nothing. Got It. Totally wiped.
The lawyer got her off and the other guy
just got house arrest and had to pay a
big fine. Whoa. Yeah.
Canada is going at it. Gangster
style. I like it because it's,
they also have a lot of money
to fight it in court right now.
Don't wait that man.
I think Canada is probably,
it's very obviously being influenced
by the policies of the United States.
Definitely the, the United
States has like, you know,
they have set parameters for Canada
and told them very specifically,
they don't want them making marijuana
illegal or making illegal rather,
I mean this has been this, it's been
held up by your carrot, you know,
and whenever you know,
discussions, we have diplomacy me,
we'll kind of diplomacy that we have when
we're, we'll let completely connected,
you know, I mean are, we will never,
you know, Canada in the United States,
it's so weird that we're two
separate countries. Really. It is,
cause we're connected.
You can drive there everywhere you get.
The whole thing is drivable.
Well that's,
that's why I see where may not really
this woods, you know, we're, we're,
we're Kalona is clone is rate on a border
there and I'm the lake and there's a
lake in a serious, that's got half of
it as in the u s and half it is Canada.
So you can drive your boat out.
Right. And then you're like,
and they're there and they're
there. Yeah. The marine guys,
my verve or all day long. That's so
gross. That's so fucking North Korea, man.
And it's, yeah, it's bizarre
when you think about it,
but there was guys I knew from
Colona that were smuggling,
they'd get these one body submarines and
go underneath it so they could get into
the, it's so eggs, submarines,
Jesus Christ. It's, it's literally, if
you see Colona it's late. It's, it looks,
they're the rock stars.
Like if they're doing well,
especially in the late nineties when the
US dollar was like nine 55 cents on the
Canadian dollar and they were getting
like 4,500 us a pound and then that was
transferring to like 6,000 Canadian.
Wow. They were making a killing.
It's amazing man. And in,
in Colona like NBC a lot.
Like we sadly,
it's like one in seven is
what the economists said of
like living dwelling units
or one in 100 it has it.
And then the grow ops,
like when you say they're in
the almost one in 100 has,
it has a potential grow up in it.
So every hundred houses
there's one house to grow up.
And what is the one in seven,
the one in seven in certain blocks in
like outer small towns of where there's
grow ops in these farms and it's one
in seven in those areas. Oh my God.
There's been small towns that they've
done articles on that literally the town
had nothing. Everything was dry. Then
some guys came off there, the big grow up,
they're paying all the guys
to do construction, good cash.
And of course that's the whole
thing of why this union evolved.
Because like the guys building the shed
or the electrician setting up the lights,
that's not illegal. Right? As long
as you're not stealing the power.
So if he gets come to wire it
all and the guy's like, oh, here,
here's six grand cash, call
it even. Well of course,
even the electricians like sweet not
thinking to declare all that, right.
So there's a like a love hate relationship
that's built around the business of
it, right? Which we break down in the
union. I'm rattling on about that.
It's a real strange sort of
situation because uh, it's a much,
much more illegal in
certain parts of America.
Like if you had to try to run
an operation like that in Texas,
they'll fucking get you, man. They'll
come and get you. Don't mess with Texas.
I lived in Texas a shame.
I fucking love Texas, man.
Texas is one of my favorite
places to visit. I,
I did my first CD in Houston.
I did my first where I lived and he
used to be my first DVD and Austin.
I mean I fucking love taxes,
but make no mistake about it there.
There's some curve.
That's a really fucking
suppressive situation that
you have there when it comes
to marijuana in Texas.
Yeah, I'll give you get
caught with medical marijuana.
If you're like some dude
with the prescription, you
could still get in trouble.
They're like,
they don't respect how you want to be
builders recommendation or of nonsense.
Like you got some drugs on you boy on
a year and over faggotry about your
fucking prescription union, you
know, prescription here in Texas.
I in that. It's great. Meanwhile,
everybody could use some wheat if,
if all of Texas. It's the irony of it
all is that if all of Texas had weed,
the cops jobs we way fucking easier,
way easier.
That's a fact, man. The
people would chill out.
They would get all paranoid and shit
and they do less crime because of that.
And then they would also just be,
you know,
be a little bit more sensitive to
what the fuck is actually going on.
And what are the repercussions of your,
your evil actions out there?
Robbing people. Settle the
fuck down, dude. For Real.
They've already proven that it's had a
decline in automobile accidents in places
where marijuana, medical
marijuana is legal. I can't,
I can't wait to dive into the call.
Like for me,
I may or may not be true
because you know what,
I did no research on that
whatsoever. I read it on low.
That does. So I can't wait.
Caution,
a study done by Dr Rogan
absolutely doesn't mean that
I'm endorsing smoking pot
and drive it cause some people
can't handle life. Okay. So I'm not,
I would never say that everybody is
the same when it comes to tolerance of
aspirin. Alcohol causes, seen
it with alcohol, everything.
You can never tell anybody to do anything
because some people can't do shit.
But some people are binge eaters.
You give them one little piece of sugary
something and they'll go crazy and you,
it's a veracious thing.
I've watched people polished down like
ice cream Sundaes that she shouldn't have
had an ice cream Sundae. And it's
like, wow, like it's our gas make.
Like this guy is like fulfilling some
just deep hole inside of them with this.
This is like sexual,
almost like he's fucking this ice cream.
You know what I mean? Well it's tough
like when you look at junk, like I wish,
you know,
when you go look at some of that for me,
I'm a pastry guy cause my grandmother
was Italian. Right. So like I,
when I see that stuff I'm like, oh, I
can just eat a tray of it. Right? Like,
and then it's like, what is your shit?
Do you like, um, all those, the polio,
Ian's man, you know, the three
layers with the chocolate top.
That was one of my favorite from
my grandmother. Oh, those were my,
I just called them the three layer cookie.
Those I used to eat those things.
So that was the only time I grab him get
mad is when she'd save them for the big
Christmas parties and I go in and raid
them and go to lay at the tray spread for
all the family and there'd
be like six left. All those,
my grandmother used to make
these other ones that had like a,
a black licorice kid.
They were like a little biscuit that had
like an icing that was slightly black
leaders that in niece or whatever
or whatever. Those are, you know,
it's someone fucked up and forgot to
bring to the west coast when good rice
pudding. See I always have a bad thought
of all right. I haven't had good right.
I lived in New York.
We used to go to a like little
diners you'd like to eat.
Like if I was doing standup or something,
it stopped at a diner.
Like these little,
they all had a cheeseburger deluxe and
the cheeseburger deluxe was usually two
patties and they would give you some
coleslaw with and for dessert if you want
it to that a little glass thing
with like that cake looks good.
What's that over there? You guys got
any, you got any rice pudding? Yeah,
we've got some rice pudding,
rice pudding and whipped cream and
it's fucking ridiculously delicious.
It's so good.
And he can't find it on here.
It's real rare that you see rice pudding
were so common on the east coast. Yeah,
I don't, that's not, mine
has always been a pastry.
So my grandmother made
everything homemade, homemade
grad, homemade jam. You,
you're healthy dude. Do you watch
what g I try now I'm getting back out.
I just started in the Isogenix actually
to get back in shape here. So gen x,
it's like the protein shakes.
Scientology now? No, no, no,
no, no, no. It's the,
the weight loss things.
Cause I got up to two 24
at six foot and I'm like,
I'd be fighting Cain Velasquez
right now. I'm like hell. Not that.
Like my ideal weight that I want to get
down to just one 90 not that that would
be much better because it'd be
Anderson Silva, but the way,
the way I really think like that,
like who you guess what?
You don't have to fight any of those guys.
The weight wouldn't matter what you see.
What I think with the Anderson is Elisa,
just be like a a Ninja
finish, right? Like just bang.
You'd finish me before
I could breathe Cain,
I just picture the savage brutalizing
before it'd be like a slam and a crunch
and like it just never gets tired.
I'd be a mangled pretzel,
like his dismantling of
big foot Silva was real.
It was disturbing because everybody
knew before Cain ever came to the UFC,
everybody in the know knew about this kid,
but former Arizona state wrestler who
they were saying was tearing it up at Aki.
They're like, this guy is a beast. I mean,
I heard a bunch of guys talking about
a shale son and who is a, you know,
pretty fucking honest with praise or
criticism when it comes to fighters. Said,
everybody knows the best heavyweight
in the world is Cain Velasquez.
This is before he ever
fought Brock for the title.
And so when he mauled Brock people that
people in the know were like, wow, yeah,
that guy's for real,
which makes junior dos Santos is fight
and victory over human. The first round,
even more staggering. Junior is such
a bad mother fucker, man. For Real.
It's just so exciting now with all the
great guys that are there. Like I get,
I could watch every weekend. I'm so
pissed off. The ream fight didn't happen.
I wanted to,
that would be a really fantastic five
because that would be one of the first
fights where a guy wants to
stand up with him. Yeah. No,
and that's where it gets really crazy
because guess what junior could take guys
down to man. He took, um, he took
Shane Carwyn down. Well that's a,
that's what I,
I,
it'd be interesting to see what happens
if the sand has gets taken out just
cause we, yeah, I know he's
trained, but I haven't seen
him yet. Yeah. You know, he's,
he's such a fucking great athlete, man.
Junior has some amazing hand speed.
Amazing.
It's really,
really going to be hard for a lot of guys
to deal with because he has, uh, he has,
uh,
an advantage over almost everybody when
it comes to the thing that's the easiest
to land, which is your hands, you know,
it's hard to kick somebody, you know,
it's real hard when you worried about
God's taking you down to, you know,
it's especially hard if the
guy's a real good wrestler.
It's hard to get those kicks off,
but you know,
when you're nervous and you're not
sure with your footing yet, you're not,
you don't have your timing
down yet. You're not going
to throw, we'll kick. Okay.
You're going to show it. If you're going
to throw a jab, you can throw a jab. Well,
Juniors Jab is like you getting caught
in the end of a telephone pole and he
throws that shit perfect.
Riding your face and he pops you a couple
of times on the chin with that shit
and you're, you know, you're,
you're still in the fight,
but you're significantly diminished.
I was there for the car when fight.
That was in Vancouver. Right. I watched
that. That was just like bang, Bang,
like amazing. Like amazing, amazing.
Kerwin's face stayed together.
Colin is up beast dude,
that guy is so fucking tough and that
if that didn't convince everybody,
he could have quit in between rounds.
His face was smashed up.
They could have called that fight.
They could've called that fight.
I thought it was, I thought they
were going to call it earlier.
You know and he's close.
He's just so fucking tough man.
He is just so fucking tough.
He's an animal man. He's a tough,
tough dude and a nice
fucking guy to Shane Collins.
One of the nicest people you'd ever meet.
Super friendly,
genuinely nice to everybody.
He meets.
What I've heard you talk in the podcast
show, it's, it seems right to cause,
I mean I had a boxing background
and you know when you go in there,
even the best guys have
taken a lick and right.
And they know what that feeling's like
and to get challenged in there and you
can get caught on any given night that
you are more humble because you go work
it out and you've been through there.
And I like to go like I went to go try
a Jujitsu for my first time a few months
ago and you know,
cause I did boxing and fought and stuff
when I was younger and I wanted to,
I'm like I'm so enthralled by,
I watch these young kids on youtube
now that are doing jujitsu moves and
slamming guys.
Have you seen the head button knockout
of the kid on the one I've seen
everything.
Every
fight that's ever been,
I've got a problem.
Do a little Ninja kick UK.
You've seen this when the guy has a shirt
type W into my browser worldstar hip
hop comes up. Okay. That's
how many fights I've seen it.
That's the first thing. Google chrome
says all bitch, I know where you're going.
What's your first Twitter?
Cause mine's like,
for some reason it's like something
I used to tweet a long time ago,
but I haven't been on
that for a long time.
But for some reason that's
always the first one. If I
hit t, it comes up Twitter.
But it's like backslash something I
don't, I shouldn't. Oh really? So like,
like it'll come up like weird.
Like a,
a page that you'd never
visited before who had no, I,
that early visit I used
to visit all the time.
And Ex girlfriends happens sometimes,
right? Yeah, it's an ex girlfriend and,
but so, but every time I pressed tea,
it's the first one that comes up. Jesus.
Because you're,
you're a stalker.
You don't realize it in the backyard with
the cloud. I think it's in the cloud.
And you know what I mean? It's cause I
used safari or something. I don't know.
Oh yeah. Probably just
safari take it's, um,
cookies from the cloud to
know, fuck knows. I don't know.
I don't understand that. You
can ask me, don't ask me this.
Is this what we gotta do?
You gotta all be nice to each
other cause we're getting absorbed.
We're all going to be one thing.
It's happening saboteur right
now and we've got to learn.
It'd be nice to each other.
Learn to do your fucking part here.
Pull your own goddamn weights
because we are one crazy thing and that's,
that shit is slowly being
brought to light technologically.
Oh Man. Look at the connect. Funny story
today. Not maybe I just fucking got high.
I made that shit up and
it's why I got all excited.
I think I was on getting on the
plane today from Vancouver. Um,
what's her name? Uh, she was
Kelly Taylor and nine oh two.
I know the Blonde Janine Garth or Jenny
Garden Jennie Garth has looking at was
like, I think that's her.
And then I looked and I went
online. Right. And I'm like,
what does she look like now? And
while my phone, I'm right. Okay.
And I look and then,
and then I saw on her Twitter it said
that she just wrapped filming a movie in
Canada. So I was like, okay, that's her.
So then I said, oh, I tweeted like, oh,
it's like I'm in,
I'm in a Yvr and I see this blonde.
I think I know I looks familiar
and to find out it's her. Oh,
she still looks beautiful for her age
and then, oh, I just say the age part,
you could have got it. So no, I
didn't say age. I just said beautiful.
Actually I just said beautiful.
It's, it's still looks beautiful.
No age didn't fit. You can check
my Twitter, but yeah, no, no,
because I tweeted her in and then she
tweeted mother fucker them yet. No,
you can check it's there forever. I
believe you. I believe you. Right.
Fuck my own quotes up all the time.
And then she yet, but then I see our,
I had put her in it and then she was like,
Oh hey,
you must have been on my
flight. Huh. Thank you. Like,
and I was thinking about that
like weird. Like, you know,
you never had that connectivity
like right there, you know, if you,
you may contact with a star if you were
a big fan of nine oh two oh that would,
could have made your year just by
going through. Have you followed up
freak you out man. Married
two kids. There's not feel
like you. Of course you are.
We're just chugging along with going
to the olive garden. For some reason I
felt like she had a talk show
that maybe I was going to be on.
I don't know if I did it,
but I did.
The Donny and Marie show does get a lot
of shows. Man. When I was on news radio,
we would do as many shows that they
would ask us to do because our show was,
you know,
not doing that well in the ratings.
So I wound up doing the Donny
and Marie show. I did it twice.
I did it with the chastity Bono before
she became chiles. Really? Yeah.
Then I'd love to hear stories like what's
up before, after which one felt best.
I didn't see her. I never met her
after, but it was fascinating.
It was listening to him now
talk about the effect that uh,
turning hormonally into a man has had
on what he likes and doesn't like.
It was really interesting.
Yeah, really fascinating.
And that mindless babble became
incredibly irritating to him,
whereas he enjoyed it when he was female,
but as,
as he made the, so it's not
just to stereotype, you're
saying, oh, what's C'mon man.
It's to, it's silly. It's real.
It's real clear in almost all primate
cultures that men and women are different.
You know? It's just you've got to
accept whoever the fuck we are.
Just don't try to change each other
except the fact that we're absolutely
completely different things and just be
nice to each other. That's not always,
it's fucking hard.
That's the hard thing. It's like you're
aware. We have to admit, first of all,
we're in a corrupt system,
so we have to figure out how to fix that
without arresting every single fucking
he would bang.
It's in power in every facet of government
that could be responsible and corrupt.
We have to figure out a way to
make this system make more sense.
Like this is not like
the right kind of system.
Like this seems like too complicated, this
whole representative government thing.
I mean, I don't know how you guys rock
it up in Canada. How you, uh, you know,
how you feel about a special interest
groups. I mean, do you have this? No,
you can't. You can't, uh, uh,
in politics in Canada you can't have big
business give them money like they can
in the US,
you can't do that.
It's like the maximum they can
take from one company is like,
I don't know the numbers correctly,
so if I get ugly, but it's,
it's not very much don't make a mother
fucker moved to Canada do because it just
keeps, I know you're kind of,
then you bring it up. It's
the best country, man. It's,
I, I, when I go there, I always tell
people it's like 20% less douche bags.
So like I never understand why people
can't be that cool in America. You know,
what era?
One of the big differences I see like now
like living in the u s and then coming
here is there seems to be a bit more
care in Catholic. I hear lots in the US.
It's like, well, if he didn't
make it, well fuck him,
it's years and it's my right and you
know what? Instead of being like, yeah,
but if everybody's not doing well and
your name, you're like fuck your neighbor.
Well you know, if you run out of power
and shit hits the fan, they need help.
Well is it going to be fuck your neighbor
then no one's gonna be like, Hey,
can we help each other out soon?
Man, ambition is very good.
But ambition without compassion is empty.
It's nonsense.
That's ridiculous.
That's like not,
that's not the proper use of your
karmic resources because you know,
you gotta,
you gotta have like a nice community.
You got to be happy when you know,
when you're doing well and when he's
doing well and everybody enjoys each
other's company and that's why you,
you know, you create a community.
That's the whole idea is
that we could all do that.
If we accepted every one of us as if
it was us leading another life. It's,
you know all that shit. That's why we do
legal man. Start thinking like that. Joe,
we'll start.
I'll tell you from listening to your
guys' show from the beginning and seeing
what you guys have built up,
you and Brian,
I mean this amazing community
that supports each other.
The other comedians when people are on
you let them pull plugs for their stuff
like and it just,
you see how well you guys are doing.
I've seen when you guys had your first
one it was snowy screen and now in the
kind of people like I
genuinely look forward.
It's like when you had Ricky Ross on here.
Yeah he was talking to us.
It was fascinating and like I can't
wait to see Graham Hancock. You old man.
That's one of my favorite one 42 I
know it off by heart. I'm always like,
oh how dare you crazy.
Have you been paying attention to this
object and the bottom of the ball? Got It.
Cause of you, right. I
fall through like your,
your tweets are the ones I
looked at by most of portal, sir,
because people deliver it to me first.
I just,
they know if they send me something
weird, it gets out there. But that's,
I mean through your podcast
so people know, right?
They know that you're doing that kind
of stuff. It's the power that you have.
I mean, even just the first couple times
you retweeted me when I was building my
Twitter's like up a couple
thousand followers. It's like boom,
that people are like, oh, it's a union guy
eating. And then it goes, that's awesome.
Take the first time you retweeted me
cause I'm like, check out this article.
And you're like, yeah, it's retreat and
my phone all day. It was like, Dang.
I was like, what's wrong?
I'm like, Twitter. That's
when I finally got into it,
I was like, oh, I see how this works
now. And started going through.
You can create a little community.
Like, I mean for the most part,
and this is not bullshit and almost
all the tweets I get are positive.
You do get a lot of positive.
They're really nice people and you,
you sort of can kind of cultivate that.
I mean,
you're going to run across the
occasional, yeah, well we, we,
we ageable grumpy pants on a smaller
level. We did that for the union. I mean,
we got,
we built this Facebook page with no money
or anything like the studios have the,
has like 40,000 people that follow
it. That's nice. And you know,
they always like when you know, right now
we're doing, there's a real mean to it.
Oh,
excuse me.
Are you should fear it's going out dressed
like a crazy person just walking in
on a podcast. What's up brother?
Come have a seat, man. Jump in.
Don't Hawaii Buddy came out.
What the hell is up?
But [inaudible] ladies and gentlemen,
I went, the hell is that my man,
my man or we met in Vancouver.
All right. Hey, what's up dude?
We this podcast over what the fuck's
going on? Yeah, well it's nine 15. Yeah,
we usually start at nine 30. Okay,
that's cool. Let's, uh, all right.
Sit down and join us, man. So you have
a Kickstarter for your new film? Yeah.
Just the culture high and they can find
it at [inaudible] calm and a is this
trailer worth checking out?
Yeah, the trailer is really
good. We worked hard on it.
How could you say, is it
worth checking out? Oh,
I didn't know if it was like a very
long and you know [inaudible] like four
minutes, right? Silly.
Yeah.
Thank you.
It is a system which has conscripted vast
human and material resources into the
building of a tightly knit,
highly efficient machine
that combines military,
diplomatic intelligence,
economic,
scientific and political operations.
Its preparations are concealed,
not published. Mistakes are buried,
not headlined. It's to set
as a silenced, not praised.
No expenditure is question. No rumor
is printed. No secret is revealed.
In 2007 a small independent documentary
on bailing the breakdown of marijuana
prohibition entered the North American
Film Festival circuit. The unit,
the business behind getting high
would find itself accepted into 33
international film festivals.
In the span of a year.
The film went on to win numerous awards
in Gardner critical acclaim across the
globe with little to no
support from big studios.
That union stormed the Internet realm
reaching out to millions of witnessing
this overwhelming response.
The filmmakers took it upon themselves
to evolve the documentary from a simple
motion picture into the
beginnings of a movement.
And so the union social networking
Facebook page was worn quickly growing to
serve over 35,000 active users arm with
groundbreaking numbers on with many had
said to be a dead topic.
Distributors and broadcasters were
forced to take notice five years after
conception that you need in the issue of
cannabis prohibition was launched into
the mainstream.
As the film is released into video stores,
universities and media outlets across
the world with new found exposure at the
film went on to claim the attention of
Canada's highest level of government as
it was chosen to be screened on Parliament
Hill in order to educate senators and
members
parliament on the ramifications
in marijuana prohibition.
The rest is history.
Now in the twilight of a
public shift of awareness,
the unions makers have set into motion
plans to create what they hope to be the
most prolific and relevant
marijuana documentary. To date,
the followup film to the Union
entitled the Culture High.
Having had six years to grow to
adopt new stories, new heroes,
new villains,
and an entirely evolved insight and
just society and who we are as a human
species.
The culture high,
we'll break down the boundaries that
prevent marijuana prohibition from being
stripped down to its very core.
Are we at least effective when lost in
the emotion of group mentality as the
emergence of the Internet equalize
that political playing field,
the culture high,
we'll raise the stakes with some of
today's biggest celebrities gain access to
previously unattainable
footage and revealing
incredibly moving testimonies
from both sides of the spectrum,
the culture high as the documentary that
will tear into the very fiber of the
longest fought war more time.
But in order to make this documentary
come to fruition, we need your support.
By August 1st we must raise $190,000
to kickstart the remaining funding
necessary to produce this film.
What we seek from you is not charity but
the pre pledge support of your copy of
the film.
It's that simple.
You prepurchase your DVD copy of the
culture high for $35 and by doing so you
will give the film the ability
to be made in the first place.
That's brilliant equation.
Then you pretty bad.
The film started saying it alone is like
the way to go for it
for all these projects.
This is a great way to do it because you
have a great track record. Like I said,
your first piece, if you haven't seen it,
folks go out and get it and if you can,
if you're not, if you're not
fucking starving, please pay for it.
Cause a Adam's good dude and it's a
really well done piece and it took a long
time. I know you, it was a labor
of love for a long time. You know,
I never thought about it,
man.
We did it and then it was a while after
that before it actually got released.
Like how long was it? Two years. We
are done in 2007 but it didn't come out
till 2009 because we couldn't
get a distribution deal.
We didn't know how. Right.
It was our first time.
Now this time with the culture high,
we already have a theatrical deal in
place where we have to pay for it.
That's what the gap and you're going
to be in the movie movies? Yeah. Yeah.
Like in America or
Canada? No, no. America.
We feel phase four films that picked
up Kevin Smith's red state. So Ocean,
Abraham, Lincoln, vampire
hunter. You could go see the
culture, how you won't get,
we'll get only two days unless it
sells out and then it will stay a week.
But are you going to be able to go to
like those mainstream cinemas that like
play?
Will they distribute like it'll be with
like say whoever it's AMC or whatever
and then they'll pick their certain
locations. Does that work though? I mean,
if you have a crazy
controversial documentary like
dark, does that get censored?
Nope.
Doesn't get censored.
I mean without the hard part
is getting your money's worth.
I'm saying does it get
it censored? Um, it,
does it keep you from being in
certain like malls? Oh definitely.
There's a certain countries that wouldn't
even touch my thing because of its
subject. Certain territories are just
like, no, it's about that and Canada. No,
not in Canada but in certain like there's
certain markets like it would never be
on Air Canada's flights. Right. I saw you.
I wasn't sure if you said counties or
countries. No, countries and territories.
Right.
Like if you sell certain parts of Europe,
that's where I saw when the
distribution game, I'm like wow,
so they're going to be certain types of
films that just don't get out there so
that culture won't see it. Like they
know if it's an action or whatever.
Certain ones they just not allowed.
They won't certainly was like,
don't even tell me that.
I'm looking at it in like an
AMC multiplex cinema in America.
Yes. All the regular movies like
the Avengers and right next to her,
the colors might be one of the small,
like say there's two MC GMCS,
it'll probably be the smaller one and
one and one of them smells like feet and
that's the one.
Yeah,
all those fuck hill for a
doc that's so hard to do. So,
but if you do them like this,
we're like what you guys have done,
where you build this community
that follows and you make
sure that the few dates
that they come out are targeted in
targeted areas and the people go see them,
then it makes sense.
Well you know,
this is also a community that would
want to support something like this.
So you know them being able to see
that video and say, hey man, I would,
I would love to get a copy of that and
you know, have the pride and the, it's a,
it's a nice feeling to know that you know,
you purchased something that you actually
want and you allow something to get
made because of the fact that he purchased
it in advance. You gave like, you know,
a, a vote of trust that just, you know,
I mean, you're an honorable man. It's,
it's a, it's a worthy investment. I know
you're going to put out a good product,
so it's cool the way you're doing it.
I like it. I like it. You know, it's a,
it's a good sentiment. Well,
in our first eight days,
we've raised 58,000 bucks and the
town days. That's amazing. Oh,
this support has been phenomenal.
Like even, it shocked everyone.
Even Todd was like, dude, he's
like everybody in the marijuana.
How much do you need to make total
one 91 90 and you're already a,
we've got 35 days to go. We're 50
almost 57,000 there it is right there.
You have an arbitrary number of
days to go on. This thing is,
I wouldn't start or makes it,
you have to do it because then you can
just always be kind of accepting money
from. Right, right. And then it's
all or nothing. Right. We have
to hit the whole goal. Right?
Or are we getting nothing? When you
get the one I didn't. You stop. Pardon?
When you get to one nine d no,
you can go over, which is great.
If we go over then we can put
it into more theaters. Right.
Their laws now on begging
for money on the Internet.
Do they have like very specific laws?
Like you're not allowed to, you know,
to fuck people over too much.
I ask him for money on the Internet.
Probably can't do fraud people for one
thing and then just go to go to Vegas.
You can't probably the fraud.
Well that's the thing is kickstart as a
good way that they have to approve your
project and improving. You don't
just get to put it up there. Well,
you could also make a kickstart though.
Fund my lifestyle for a year.
I want to live. If you did a good
enough video and people want it to do,
there's not just for docs.
There's people that are creating like
video games or they have a new watch and
you pre buy the watch when you get it.
Or I have a kickstart to make a new
Kickstarter type kind of website.
How long before, how you, how dare you,
how long before these Google lenses,
these Google goggles will
be a subscription service
where you can pay to look
through someone's eyes.
Hopefully soon.
That's going to have
technology keeps happening.
How much would it be worth to look
through Tom Cruise's eyes for a day?
I would pay $1,000 you know some celebrity
with sell that for sure this is a gay
porn cause I would take a chance,
take a chance.
At the day I tune is a day he decided to
just break his fast and suck her cock.
I would do, would it be nice
if he could just come out?
Wouldn't it be beautiful? That's
what I love to be. Think he's gay.
I'll bore at made funny when he was like,
oh,
I realized all these major
guys are straight. Right.
And it showed guys that clearly have
reputations for plus. So weird man,
I'm going to rock.
Hudson was gay.
It was like devastating to people and
then afterwards it was like, oh yeah,
of course.
Tell you if Tom Cruise is not gay,
that he is the victim of the worst
fucking horrendous smear campaign ever.
Him and Travolta. You've just become
a part of that. Yeah, it's so, well,
I'm denying that part right now and
I'm apologizing for my ignorance.
How do I know what the fuck he does a
great joke about it, about Travolta,
reaching out and grabbing that guy's cock.
What he says,
he fondled his balls because
at first he touched my ball.
Then he reached out and grabbed
my name and then what do
you tap? No, no, no, no, no,
no, no. And then minutes later,
yeah, that's what he said.
And then minutes later and then
it's the fuck you talking about.
Minutes later you're still in the room.
You asshole.
Can I just grab your Dick
Norton was on the last podcast.
He was fucking amazing to
listen to what he said it was.
I'm so happy that Norton exists.
He's one of those guys.
I'm so happy there's a Norton.
He was so funny when he was going over
his different perversions. I was crying,
laughing.
He's so entertaining to me.
Like the way he's so honest
about it and a blood,
the way he like relish isn't like you're,
you're getting to experience
it through him. You know,
like how he liked girls as it just a
little stinky. Just a little, not at,
not a terrible smell. Just a little smell.
A little smell. I like a little smell.
He was like, he's so funny. I
like, I like underarms. He like,
he likes a little feet smell. He likes
when girl's feet smell a little bit.
Love Adrian. He's a crazy
guy, man. I love him.
It's so nice that there's a
guy like Jim Norton, you know?
Where would you be without comedians?
Harsh. A female comedians. Yeah.
If you were forced to hang
out with the average folk, oh,
you know, if you didn't have a
guy like Jim Norton and your life,
if I have a guy like Joey
d s and your life, or, uh,
I don't know, I would just be
bored. You really ever stopped.
I realized this recently. I've talked to
this yesterday. I think what it was like,
I don't really have any friends
that aren't comedians. Wow.
I gotta to make some friend friends.
I've Jujitsu friends.
I have a quite a few friends that aren't
comedians and I hang out with them or
just attribute to oh well attributes.
Well,
some of them are hanging out with them
and then uh, I have uh, some um, uh,
pool friends put it just the fuck is I
though. Oh, the Nazi's looking at you man.
I'd see Nazi zombies zoned
in on our Jewish friends. Oh,
you should fear how rude with the Nazis.
Zombie.
This is creepy man.
Imagine if that shit was real life.
Imagine if that was what you had
to deal with out in the streets.
Just this Nazi zombies. It's fucking
Nazi zombies everywhere, man.
Trying to eat you. We're so lucky.
We're so soft to grow or where we go.
We just drive around in our cars
listening to satellite radio complaint
complaint. If our Internet is not
fast enough on her phone, whoa.
We could be living in that.
That movie.
What's that TV show where
the walking dead. Oh, dead.
That could be real man as it could
have happened 10 minutes ago.
We just don't know it yet. They keep
seeing, you know, do you know, I'm sorry?
Do you know him? Yeah, we met once
at a restaurant. Vancouver. Okay.
When you guys feed Yack, Yack at that
time. Yeah. That place is awesome.
What did she call it now? They need just
to sell it the fuck out. It's great.
It's called comedy mix. What happened to
your heart's fear? Pummeled that place.
You have a chaplain? She's looking
sexy. Always feels looking sexy.
That's what happened. Zombie
Hitler here. That's what happened.
The fabulous are we should fear. You're
fabulous. It's fuck dude, look at you.
You're rocking it. I love it. I
like what you doing? It's perfect.
Just go straight to nothing. I'm not
fucking around for three days. Yeah.
Do we need to hang out at Starbucks
and just sit there and read?
Have you been doing some road gigs,
man? Yeah, I'm going to Ottawa.
Where that you just showed in your,
uh, your documentary. I'll be nice.
It's beautiful.
Then in the summer and get harsh.
Fear will also be with me and
Duncan Trussell in Calgary
and I think that is was
that July 20th July.
It's July 20th is the date and then
that the next day starts true fast,
2012 snap those IEPs,
Calgary and shroom tech together,
bringing it back to shut.
Those will give you very different
performance enhancements there.
I expect everyone in the
UFC to be on my show.
Every fighter must test
positive or you're queer.
Can you imagine if there was like a day
that you had to do it as much of the
fight, no matter what, but everything
you do, the whole culture just agrees.
There's only one way to get through this
as a hundred percent of us have to do
mushrooms on this day.
That way nobody's vulnerable.
Nobody drives around from the period of
12 noon to 8:00 PM there is no fucking
activity done.
Get everything you have to get done
before 12 noon than everybody in the whole
fucking city takes mushrooms.
Wow. That would be amazing.
A beam of light would just go
straight up to heaven. Yeah, we would.
We would all evolve a hundred
years in one day, a hundred years.
You remember how nice people were after
nine 11 I like everybody was like,
especially in New York, people were
super friendly. They like jolted a,
a bolt of humanity into people
if they want it to be kind.
They wanted to appreciate each other
cause they really did realize that, wow,
we really are at war and fucked up.
Things can happen at any moment right now.
Just hug somebody and say you love
them and be nice and be friendly.
And this would be like disability the
nation for a while. A did for sure.
The mushroom day would be like
that times a million. Yeah.
It would be like that times and I'm not
bullshitting if people who haven't in
people who don't agree with me.
The only reason why you don't agree
with me as if you never done mushrooms,
because if you did do mushrooms and you
thought about it and you thought of how
crazy it experience it was and how much
it is a shared experience when you do it
with other people that do mushrooms,
drink shared experience. No, no drink.
I just realize that you are doing the
mushroom duck. Any mushroom talk at all.
It's true.
I know that everyone needs to do mushrooms
drank I think together one day it was
not going to hurt anybody. That would
be the greatest holiday of all time.
One day. The whole population does
mushrooms in the meantime. Yeah.
2012 July 21st 22nd or 23rd Shizam so
the Mayan calendar was off by several
months.
Bitches.
The porter will be open July
21st where will you be? Oh,
we're doing a shrimp festival in
Montreal. Oh Jesus Christ. Suntrust.
What are you doing?
Yeah,
my Charles Cool city for materials shows
Ari that weekend and then a bunch of
other people do the mushrooms,
the Canada ones. Um,
I've got a couple more coming up too.
If you want to do any more than I look
in the other ones. You want to do a go,
go back to, um, I'm going
to be there at the same.
Sure.
So as Tom and Brenda, so you have a show
at the same day that I have my show.
I think they were around the same time.
Do you think you could bolt over from
one to the other and do both places?
Probably.
Would they get mad at you?
Long as they don't announce it?
Hey. Oops. Anyway, nobody heard it.
Um, either way I will drag,
can't get Joey up there,
but I'll get to come regardless the
hangout. Yeah. It should be amazing man.
That a Massey hall is the fucking coolest
old building too, man. It's like a,
it really historical place in Toronto.
It's a,
it's one of those places where you find
out other people that have played day.
Like wow.
It's just like,
I don't even feel like I should be
allowed to walk around here, man.
Forget about actually go on stage.
This is like a historical monument.
That's how I fell the Parliament Hill.
Like I thought it was a joke.
I thought at any time they're going to
come out and say, okay, we punked Ya.
Did they laugh at my shit man?
They loved it. They didn't laugh.
They laugh and I was talking to
yesterday leaving all my bad words,
everything you played the Union for
parliament in Parliament Hill and nick and
the clip there were in a
square room scored. There was,
you're a bad mother fucker.
What's amazing?
Me and Brett were just waiting
to get attacked and then like,
you know when we start talking about
politicians and kind of the corruption,
how it works, like Ooh,
how are they going to,
but they were giggling
and laughing and they bow.
They were probably all in the throat.
Now Irwin Cotler probably all high as
fuck outside there and I got real nervous.
That's hilarious. Trust me,
the building when you walk in,
the security was worse than the airport.
Like you actually picked up the titanium
in my jaw. Wow. Right. So they were like,
oh, BP to pickup the stealing your
balls. No, didn't pick that up. That's,
that's a new and a
Menttium shit undetectable.
We had some drop that amazing
that you pulled that off man.
It's amazing that seeing that and seeing
those people sitting there watching
that video,
it's really bizarre to me.
You see my face on that screen is really
strange. This does a strange thing.
Trust me for us two sitting there like
right next. I had an MP right next to me,
three conservatives over here,
senator art and cause I'm going
to be honest with you, man,
when you came over my house, you're
friends with Todd. I'm like, Yo,
who's the fuck's gonna Watch this. The,
yeah, yeah, I'll do your documentary.
It'd be just like all the other
documentaries I did that nobody saw
like 20 of those things.
I probably said the same fucking thing.
There's probably some dude he copies in
circulation shit on the cutting floor
somewhere from some other
shitty documentary that I
did where I said the exact
same shit. I'm so repetitive. It's
ridiculous and it kills that subject.
That's why you need to do mushrooms. If
the world bitch it also, it also come,
you know, it clicks. It's all in how
you edit it too, right? Yeah. No,
you did a brilliant job. Amazing job. You
really got to put it together. Perfect.
Listen, fuck heads. I love you guys.
I don't really mean to call you. Fuck.
I say that like I treat
you like a treat us. Um,
this thing's got to end at some time and
then now is that time. So Adam score,
you will see you sir are the shit.
He did a fucking tremendous job.
You took the ball and you ran with
it. You did an amazing job. Pot.
That's a good idea.
Are you should fear.
You did a really incredible documentary
and I can't wait to see this culture
high. It's going to be bad ass.
Fuck yeah, it goes to that.
I ask him what we should do
something from here. We'll do it.
We'll do it a about the podcast. We'll do
it. We'll, we'll, there's an interject.
We will interject some podcasts footage
in it and we'll promote it through the
podcast too. I'll help you out, man.
You're all spread the word buddy.
Spread the word man. You're doing
an awesome job of just doing that,
getting that real information out there.
The truth out there,
and you know it's not about hippies folks,
it's spelled fucking personal liberties
and we've been co opted by. Shit.
Corporations and Dunkin really give a
fuck about you and we need to recognize
that it's not patriotic to support
that it's unpatriotic. It's,
it's tough sometimes to buck up
and say the situation is fucked,
but the people that are going to benefit,
it's not just going to be people
like us that want to smoke weed.
It's going to be those people that
are suppressing people too because it
shouldn't be within the law to
allow them to suppress people.
It is in fact an injustice.
It's a terrible thing where people are
allowed to tell other people what they
can and can't do.
That doesn't hurt anybody else.
And when you're doing anything because
you have some sort of a financial gain
that you're allowed to make some sort of
a loophole judgment and make money from
that,
that's wrong.
You know it's wrong and I know it's
wrong and the sooner we get you off this
evil tit,
the better your own personal life would
be because I guarantee you if you're
running around out there making money off
of keeping weed illegal, you're a con,
you live a cunt life and
you hate yourself. Okay?
Cause you realize you're doing
something really creepy and you're,
you're stopping progress.
And if you in fact stopped doing that
and instead embrace the psychedelic
experience instead,
take a fucking yoga class,
go work out before you opened your
mouth in the morning. All right,
get your shit together, bitch. It's
not our fault that we can handle it.
All right?
Step the fuck up and fall out of
score you on Twitter. It's got a,
it's his real name as s, c, O, r. G. I. E.
But he thinks you're retarded.
So he spells it different.
He goes s, c, O, r, e
and then a big G. Yeah.
Just to emphasize,
you are brilliant.
You did it phonetically
Gorgie productions, right? So
that's your production company
production makes it slightly less clever.
Not because I'm a g, but just also
it's it. It's only Twitter handle.
I could get the other one I'd used on
the union one by accident so I had to use
that one. Oh, so, but you still
have the union on Twitter as well.
Can they follow that as well?
They follow that as well.
And then also the culture is on there
already and nice. Nice. And when,
when he planted on getting this ball
fully rolling with this culture high fall
August versus when the deadline
ends for the Kickstarter run.
And then we'd go into production in
September, our full production in some,
well Brian and I hope to be a
part of this, correct Brian,
are we down hundred percent bitch and
you guys already should fear powerful.
Ari Shaffir please follow him.
Smokes smuggles we'd all over the country.
How dare you.
We're not going to tell you all about me.
And Ari does edit a new day to the
San Diego shadows. How dare you.
What Day is this? This
Thursday. So Thursday, Friday.
I will be there on Friday.
I do not know if I'll be there on Saturday
right now it doesn't look like it,
but I'll be there on Friday.
Going to be there. I'm sorry.
What'd you that American comedy company
thing. I'm going to go see the comicon.
Never been to comic con man. It's like
Mecca. I got to go there before I die.
Before the Mayans.
Correct.
Correctly predict because you got rid
of the bureaus and your presence in our
atmosphere. Do you believe
in a, on an Aki? I,
I've heard your theories about
it and I got no theories son.
I got to know the area.
You see Prometheans yes I
did. It was good. Hey Man,
I did not think it was good. You
didn't like, no, I did not like a man.
People are split on that thing and I like,
I thought it was a brilliant and moments
in a thoroughly enjoyed it for long
chunks,
but ultimately as a whole I felt like
you got to way too many cuts of shit
scenes for me. Fuck me with the fucking
spaceship landing on the chicken cheese.
Okay. Sorry. Spoiler
spoiler, spoiler, spoiler.
But I would see it again because I'm a
retard and I love Scifi movies and Ridley
Scott is still God. Yeah.
That's so fucking Dork to say.
Someone who's got really Mazi is God.
You know Ridley Scott is God,
it's amazing director. Oh, I'd
love to talk to them about how,
how he fucks a fleshlight.
How'd that, how'd that,
how'd that guy would love to be cuddled
by the inside wall of the flashlight?
Because Ladies and gentlemen,
there is no better feeling.
The love of your friends is
number one family right up there.
And then there's a flashlight folks.
It's like the best vagina
you really could ever invent.
And if it just moves on its own,
it would be too perfect.
And that's all you would do all day.
You should be lucky that it's a manual
thing is the lazy cunt that I know you
are.
You know,
you're going to give it a couple of
thrust and then you gotta throw it in the
corner of pass out probably without even
pulling your pants up. You sick. Fuck.
What if I had a fleshlight that you know
that the cousin and that would do that,
like crawl over to you and oh yeah,
that would be fabulous.
Be found. Again, you'd have guys
never leave right next morning would,
but you would start feeling jealous or,
or rather a,
you'd start feeling guilty that you are
doing this and this is no way to live
your life.
Just getting sucked off everyday by a
robot and you'd go out and you try to find
like the most religious girl possible.
They'd probably completely ruined your
actual real sex life because you will
completely disassociate sex
from being like a physical need.
And instead it will become like this
really heavy duty emotional thing.
Fuck this shit.
Like some chickens in the 50
shades of gray and you'll find her.
And then together you guys could just
slow kiss and you never come ever again.
And then thanked the flashlight.
You go to Joe rogan.net. Yeah.
And even the code date Brogan and you
save yourself 15% off the number one sex
toy from Matt.
Yeah,
I'm doing it all luck,
boy. Now go to [inaudible] Dot Com O. N.
N. I. T. Get yourself some battle ropes.
Battle ropes is the latest thing,
the fucking latest goddamn fitness craze.
Crazy 40 foot long ropes that you swing
around like a fucking savage pirate type
character from a thousand years back.
And get yourself some kettlebells too,
so you can be a manly man and stop. Stop
doing your bicep curls. You little bitch.
Let's do a pushup. At least do
some pushups. Do you know? Well,
you don't have to do anything really.
I mean,
some of my best friends
don't work out at all.
Do whatever the fuck you want to do.
That's all I'm saying.
If you want to get down
with the kettle bells,
go to [inaudible] dot com did the
best possible construction the there,
they will last you a lifetime
archeologist. 5,000 years from now,
we'll try to figure out what the fuck
these things were in your basement. Okay.
Cause they're going to still be here
and he's like, it's hard to ship.
Use the cool car. Oh, Alpha brain. You
go buy some Alpha Bank to, what is that?
I go to [inaudible] dot com and he
all your answers will be solved.
Thanks to punch drunk entertainment,
sucker punch. What am I
sacrifice? Is this sucker punch? I Dunno.
I'm just, I'll call it punch tracking.
That's nice.
Chunk of my scores.
Nobody's pushed me for
years and I'm still stupid.
This is the end of this podcast.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we want to thank you very much. If you
are podcast starved and you're like,
God damn it,
I wonder what those guys talked about.
Right after that podcast is over,
we got another fucking podcast.
It starts any second now and it is
called the ice house chronicles and it is
only available on death squad.
If you go to iTunes and subscribe to desk
squad or go to death squad.tv and you
can find the Vimeo links and you
can find all that good juicy shit.
And if you want to watch it live,
it will be on the same channel.
ustream.tv Ford Slash Joe Rogan.
Holla at your boy.
So the icehouse chronicles or you should
fear will be here. Brian Read Ben.
We'll jump into the fray. Gloves. So
here's the radio. Tiana, Brendan Walsh.
Oh my man,
Maria Shahada.
Randy Lik he's here to talk to the lift
he wants to talk to. It was a smack me.
I heard this might be the end. This
might be like a doors song. All right.
We love you guys.
Thank you for everything and we
will see you as soon as possible
next week sometime.
Hm?