I can't be wearing a headset.
No.
Are you going to wear your hat?
You got to be looked.
Looks Weird.
Well,
it looks weird if it's only one headset.
Are we live?
We fucking live,
man.
What's going on brother?
Chelan look at you.
Look at me filling out the tanks.
Budweiser.
Cheers.
We got it.
We cannot have a podcast with cowboy
without America.
America,
America.
Yeah.
So not have a good one.
Hmm.
So tell me about the tanks.
He sent me a picture today,
gail,
didn't I?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
And go and dive into Catalina.
Holy Shit.
Home with the home of the sharks.
Makos right?
The MAACO.
Yeah.
I was watching a TV show the other day
where people are fishing for them out
there.
So we got a filled up,
a couple of doubles.
My buddy rob from always sunny in
Philadelphia taking me this weekend
camping.
So they're going to die,
but they all die of singles.
So I like to go deeper longer with
singles.
Wasn't going to single tank.
Got Aluminum.
80 Oh,
single tank.
The tank.
Yeah.
So me and my girl or dive in doubles,
which everyone says doubled means double
trouble,
but whatever.
So what does that mean?
Like how deep can you go with the
double?
Oh,
you can go as deep until you run out of
air,
but we'll probably go and the 200 range,
two 20 to 200 feet down,
200 feet down and home.
That's one of those weird ones where
when you come up you got to come up
slow.
Right.
She didn't get the Benz.
Uh,
yeah,
absolutely.
Um,
you get the bends.
Yeah.
Uh,
decompress and you know,
um,
the process did to diving in and I've
been diving series,
he's like a lot of wreck diving and a
lot of like tech,
you should say diving over the last two
years,
man,
I ran some guys in Las Vegas,
but he traveled and he,
uh,
kind of schooled me on their,
on their way of,
of,
of diving.
And I love it man.
And the reason I go to Las Vegas and
they meet all the time that you got,
I die with guys.
They died 200,
300 feet every day.
Every week,
you know,
so getting around the people that die of
it regularly and know their shit,
you know,
is it to teach me the way,
you know.
So I think,
thanks travis,
I appreciate you.
Show me.
They'll show me the light brother.
Now when you come up,
like from,
how do you know like when you're going
down to my algorithm,
it's all in your dive computers and you,
so your plan,
plan,
plan.
Then you recheck and Lindsey,
she,
she does the same thing and we check
each other's work and make sure it's
all,
all our gases are mapped out for how I'm
like,
let's just say we're going to go 150
feet for ma.
There's a cool,
there's a cool ship down there.
We want to check out.
We want to be there for 35 minutes,
right?
So I put the algorithm and these apps in
our computer or we write it all out and
it'll tell us exactly how long the
bottom time we can have the stops that
we with the make and the gases that we
have to switch to decompress amount of
nitrogen.
In our blood.
I make her way to the surface.
What's the science behind it?
Like what?
Why does nitrogen getting your blood?
So because Oh,
from Earth's surface to the atmosphere
is,
is one atmosphere,
right?
Every 33 feet is another atmosphere.
So every time we go down 33 we add
another atmosphere that much more
pressure.
So right now you're breathing 21%
oxygen,
78%
78% little bit of like Argon,
other shit.
And then the natural air,
right?
A lot of nitrogen to,
yeah.
So 78% of the area right now is
nitrogen.
21% of the oxygen.
Most of you don't know that if that
you're just breathing oxygen.
No,
you're on,
you're reading 21% oxygen.
So,
but you off gas it through your tissues
because there's no pressure on you,
right?
So like right now you're taking a breath
and then you breathe out and the
nitrogen just off gasses will,
as soon as we start going under the
water,
the amount of pressure holds that in
our,
into our system.
Like if we can't,
we can't off gas it.
So it becomes turned into liquid and
goes into our blood,
which is what the Benz is with.
The guys would be working and then these
come up cause they had,
they didn't know.
No one knew until,
you know.
Right.
I mean we didn't know there wasn't a
moon God until all of a sudden we know
now.
Like I know.
So um,
yeah.
So they would force the lit the liquid
out of and do a back into a gas by
coming up fast.
So which goes into your joints and cause
the bends and because it makes you her
bend over hurt your back.
Cause that's what they call it,
the bank.
So the guys were like,
Oh fuck,
I'm fucked up.
Right.
I got yes.
That's where the term national can kill
you,
right?
Oh yeah.
Well you can encourage them and your
brain blood clot,
you know,
all kinds of crazy kill you instantly.
Whoa.
So we,
so 150 feet,
all of a sudden,
25 minutes is up.
Now we're going to start our ascent and
our computer says it right at 70 feet.
We got to do a minute.
At 60 feet.
We got two minutes,
we're going to switch gases.
Never my switch to 50% oxygen.
Right?
So increase the amount of oxygen to
which decreases the amount of nitrogen
that we're breathing.
So we're going to speed the offgassing
process cause we're coming up.
So the pressure's coming off this,
our body's able to off gas it.
Um,
so we just have to do like stages and
it's all through algorithm.
And the navy dive system been through
years of hundreds of millions of dives.
You know,
figuring out the timetables of the
correct amount of time.
You have to be at each dept to off gas,
the amount of nitrogen your body's built
up.
And then when you go deeper than that
and you start adding in a tri mix,
we had helium and helium,
helium.
So yes,
we had helium into the mix.
And uh,
I mean it's so fun,
but the fear of,
you know,
could I die?
Yeah.
Hell yeah.
That's what I love it.
I'm crazy.
I fucking love it.
And we were talking earlier about
sharks.
I swim after the sharks,
like I want to get him on the Gopro
there like swimming away from the
sharks.
Don't they don't just eat divers.
They don't need to sweat along a fucking
great white come attack you.
They're like scary to you man.
You're like a big black breeding.
I'll fucking bubbles and shiny,
you know.
So they want nothing to do with you and
I'm always trying to chase him down.
So most of the shark attack,
so like surface right.
Cause they think it's a cscl up top.
Yeah.
And where would you rather,
we were just,
we were just watching it before you got
here.
Some footage of the shark attacks on on
Youtube and where would you rather be?
I'd rather fight the fucking shark under
the water.
I'd rather be under,
under instead of on top.
Like if,
is this the video I posted yesterday on
the sharp gnawing on the case.
This right.
Fuck everything about this.
This is insane.
This great white shark is trying to get
these people,
he's biting his cage,
trying to get what's inside.
What do you do?
You just grab his dorsal fin to go for a
ride,
baby,
he can't bind you up behind him.
Rides Back Monta Leo,
have you seen a great way to underwater?
I never have.
No,
I've never,
I haven't been down,
you know,
in the waters where they're at,
Australia and stuff like that.
So no,
I never,
I've never seen a great white,
I've seen plenty of hammerheads and you
know,
Maaco and,
but never like a giant great hammerheads
are so bizarre.
It looks like an Avatar creature.
They don't even look real.
I poles with a couple of hammerhead
women,
you know,
like what are them titties doing honey
get,
that's what a girl with a cup tries to
go straight d right away.
It can't be done.
And they lay next to her on the bed.
Define Science.
He got an evil knievel canyon between
your two ties.
So I love diving.
You know,
I got,
I got a great dive partner and my,
my girl Lindsay.
And um,
that's the biggest thing having,
you know,
having the companionship in trust if
someone with your life,
right?
So,
you know,
carrying all the tanks.
I,
she'll be diving and she'll have a pair
of devils on her back in two tanks in
the region in ours.
We've got four tanks on the water.
I heard 200 fishing is the shit.
I love it.
Yeah,
I'm gonna eat it.
I want to just,
I'm just killed.
Kill.
But yeah,
so,
yeah,
absolutely.
Because it's like a hunting but fishing.
Yeah,
it's,
yeah,
it fly easier than you think.
You know,
they don't know what the fuck's going
on.
No idea what's going on.
They don't know what you are.
You're like,
what the fuck?
Oh fucking God knows it attached to a
rope.
The SATCHEL,
like a fishing line you could down at
you cause you shoot it.
It depends if you're using a gun or they
have like slings that go on your arm,
you can shoot him like a little luck.
Spiderman and not so much.
Just a little like a slingshot type
thing he's put on your wrist and let go
of it,
you know?
Wow.
But you're the spear guns.
I'll go far and they have like little
reel.
You can reel it in like how far AH,
50 feet.
Yeah.
Haunted me.
Wow.
Yeah,
they slowed down considerably though.
Report the first few feet.
Wow.
Right on it.
And you and your depth perception is so
different underwater.
So it's kind of,
you got to aim above them.
It's weird.
Like a bright right?
There were fractions.
Yeah.
That's the same when you shooting down
when they go hunting boat.
Yeah.
They both fish in the water.
You got to like aim six inches under
where you think it's going to be.
Exactly.
Those are now when you're,
when you're diving,
I like how long have you been doing
this?
First of all?
Well I got certified in high school.
High School.
Damn.
So you've been doing this for a long
time.
It was just like going 30 40 feet
recreational diving,
you know,
go and see some stupid,
I shouldn't say stupid,
but like that's like the,
the,
the recreation they do is go see a reef
but one read,
it looks like every reef.
Right?
I don't know.
So I kind of got over that.
I said,
I met with these guys and doing the shit
that only 5% of the world do.
You know,
my goal was to go 500 feet.
So I've been,
I've been just shy of 300 and yeah,
there's just a lot of planning and crazy
shit that goes involved with me and your
dad.
Pretty much anything goes wrong.
But uh,
how long does it take you to get up from
the 300 at from 300 it's about a 50
minute decaux time back of the surface.
So five zero.
Yeah.
So it's about a three hour dive
completely.
Holy Shit.
Now if something goes wrong,
like if you're cord gets cut when you're
down there and just heard,
but we'll,
if you bleed in oxygen,
right?
You shut one off and go to your cell.
You always carry enough getting,
no one's ever died because you have too
much gas.
Right.
So,
okay.
And carry it with you.
Right.
So a lot of the mixtures we bring with
us,
like my back gas,
I'll just be regular,
either try and mix gas or regular air
and then I'll have a 36% oxygen,
which is to about a hundred feet.
So if anything were to go on my back as
I can haul ass to a hundred feet and
then start my depo,
you know?
And really there's like protocol and all
kinds of different,
plus I'm driving with a buddy,
which would be you and you have all the
gas in new too,
so,
and you would be,
you know,
arms length away from me.
Some shit went down.
I could give you my gowns here.
Yeah.
Oh Wow.
Give you regulator and take,
you have one that hangs on your neck and
one that you're using.
Right.
You'd give me yours and put yours in and
we'd figure it out.
Oh,
okay.
Like if I was off screwing off and doing
something I shouldn't be,
which I'm fucking 99% doing,
then I got to rely on,
never rely on myself.
Whoa.
No,
we can't talk.
So talk,
you have to say.
So me,
me and Lindsay were in,
in,
in Florida dive dive in the Spiegel
Grove,
which is a giant,
like a shoot ship and,
and,
and uh,
the key west and we kind of ship.
Was it,
I don't know if it,
the Spiegel Grove is aircraft carrier or
if that's the vandy,
I can't,
I'm getting confused.
But one's like a giant aircraft carrier
and one's a like a destroyer.
Oh Wow.
500 feet.
Yeah.
They're natural reefs.
So the,
the government song,
Camino cut a bunch of holes in for
idiots like me to go solve this song,
come on.
Purpose.
So they take all the fluids out of them.
They a sink.
I'm going to make them artificial reefs.
Wow.
And so they do this because the
decommission the ship and they don't
know what to do with them.
So,
so this is a good move?
Yes.
Make it,
it just put less,
let us fish and wildlife hang out and
then they make money off guys like me.
Like,
Hey,
let's go fucking explore this thing.
You have to pay to go there.
No,
you just pay for the gas in there.
But the thriving boat captain that needs
to feed his family,
he charges you 180 bucks.
Take you out to gps and tell you good
luck.
Wow.
So a b and Lindsey are out there.
Well of course I'm seeing cool shit
going down in the engine room.
Fucking do whenever I want.
And she gets tangled up and has like a
freak out episode and then I come back
to like,
what the fuck?
He like,
like gave her like,
where are You ben?
And she's like,
well the fucker like all mad at me.
It was all caught up in things.
But when we got up,
Whoa,
back up to surface.
I got my ass tore up.
I was like,
well you made it,
you're good.
All the rags we did get off.
Walk it off.
Shit.
You ever gone like on treasure hunting
dives?
No,
I,
I mean foe.
So first of all,
I need to live near the ocean,
which I don't.
And second,
I need to know someone who has a boat
and you know that you hear stories like
all these boat.
Know of all the good
fishing cause where the good fishing is
usually there's a structure down there,
right?
So that's how you like run it.
You find that the old boat captain and
know like uh,
uh,
a structure that's not on any wells,
the gps,
then maybe you could dive down there and
check it out,
but you need,
it was a 250,
300 feet.
So you need some guys that you trust
that fucking go deep with you.
Yeah.
So,
but now I have it and I would love to,
that'd be something that would fucking
love to do.
I was watching the show,
I don't remember what ocean they were,
uh,
pulling the,
the rec from.
But these guys were professional
treasure hunters and they found some
insane amount of goals,
like some,
some Roman ship that sank.
Could you imagine?
Yeah.
And they were trying to figure out who
gets the gold and who claims it in.
Me Too.
It'd be,
it'd be fucking go time.
But you have to be like really careful
about like giving out the location and
other treasure hunters would find it.
Like is a big business in that shit.
Well,
so like let's just say me and you go
treasure hunting and the captain takes
the spot.
We find it.
We jumped down also and we find all this
golden,
this treasure.
We only have enough gas for,
who knows,
20 minutes down there.
So we got to come back up.
We couldn't even bring the fucking gold
this trip.
And we want it to,
right now we're back in the belt.
You know,
I know the boat.
CAPP knows who else is with us.
So now we've got to figure out who do we
tell and do we tell us,
spoke at it.
Oh,
you're coming with us for the next,
can we figure this shit out?
Because I'm not gonna let you go to
whoever you.
Yeah.
So it gets really,
really tricky.
You have to kill the captain.
You would have to,
you'd have throat.
Do you know how to use a gps?
You know,
like marketing drop a pin.
Pin.
Yeah,
yeah.
You'd have to drop a pin on and you'd
have to kill that guy and drop him where
the pin is or don't kill him.
You got to cut him in.
He's got to get a third something.
Yeah.
Or Yeah.
How much money he gets a third for.
Oh,
you're talking probably millions of
dollars,
but if you don't give them a third,
he's going to fucking a rat and you
know,
fuck yeah.
Yeah.
You have to give him a third because
you've got to think,
if he didn't take you there,
you'd never got it.
And it's a shitload of money.
It's free.
And so he says half,
then what do you do?
Fuck you.
Then you kick his ass like you don't let
them get half.
You got to be generous.
But if he tries to fuck you on your
generosity,
that's when you kill them.
How many people have probably been
killed over shipwrecks and pirate shit?
Yeah.
That goes back a lot though.
Shitty ass wouldn't boats.
How many of those fucking things must
have crashed?
Plus those greedy bitches,
they loaded him up with gold.
Try to make it across the ocean.
Yeah.
Plus if I was a pirate I'd be no one
when you're loading your is up and I'd
just go fucking take yours over and take
offs and I got all my shit plus all your
shit.
Right.
Cause we found another one on the list.
Now I'm tripled up big heavy belt.
Well this documentary that I was
watching,
this guy who was doing it,
it was a professional treasure hunter.
That's what he does.
And you know he has to get investors
involved because it costs hundreds of
thousands of dollars to make millions of
dollars treasure hunting and then you've
got to be able to find them.
A lot of them apparently around Florida
shirt.
Well that's so like key west.
There's so many like rec shifts because
that was like the port,
you know that was the,
so yeah,
I could only,
I mean I went to it,
they have like a wreck ship museum and I
went there and talked to all the guys in
there and they're saying that men,
there's thousands and thousands of boats
that are all,
because that's the port where they would
do all the tradies thousands.
Wow.
It's a whole nother fucking world down
there,
man.
It really sent a little mermaid.
It's a whole new world.
But,
uh,
look,
I have kids,
men,
I've heard that fucking toy.
Yeah,
we all,
and we were just at the Seattle aquarium
and I was looking at these octopus's
they had this,
uh,
octopus exhibit and they were doing this
thing on octopuses with this lady was
explaining they have three hearts and
it's insane.
And the brands around their neck and
underwater.
It's fucking,
yeah.
If you're a scuba diver and you haven't
in a night dive cause there's a whole
nother world at night.
Uh,
like the,
the what are the [inaudible] for the,
when you move luminescent and that's
crazy.
Yeah.
You can move on to water and everything
close.
And the octopus,
how fast they change colors and move.
When you move under water,
you glow.
Yeah.
If you shut all your lights off and you
just like move your arms and draw,
he could write joe.
Oh,
going to spell out in the,
out in the,
so,
cool.
Why is that?
Why can you see it?
What is it?
I think the shrimp phytoplankton I've
seen as the plankton.
Oh,
that's insane.
I mean that might be a little bit
digitally fixed,
but uh,
it's fucking cool.
Wow.
What area of the world is this stuff?
But we do it and Co's and Mel,
whenever I go down to Mexico,
so I'm sure it's know they have in
Puerto Rico at.
That's right.
I've seen it.
Unbelievable.
So you go down there,
Shit your lights up and you can just
play in the water and kick up and make,
they just glow.
It's write your name.
That's like space ships is space.
And then you have these crazy octopus is
that can change colors.
I don't even know how many different
colors they can change,
but you just see him fucking crawl on
all across the ground saying,
cool.
Wow.
That is so bizarre to end these
thousands of ships that they like.
One day they're going to figure out
technology to go and find those things.
They're gonna be able to locate all of
them.
But right now when they're willing so
there wouldn't,
so the rotting away.
So,
I mean there's,
there's not much left of them.
Right.
The metal ships are,
are,
are the only thing that I've,
I've done one wouldn't,
and it was,
it was shit,
it was like all fallen apart.
You know,
they don't find much.
But what's left is like the pottery and
the goals and the coins and things along
those lines to find some certain metal
things.
But like swords,
swords right away.
We're not dimensioned dead bodies.
I mean if you're finding a ship that no
one's ever seen does probably cook right
now,
you'll find some fucking dead body type
shit.
Some haunted shit.
Yeah.
Type of about putting your heartbeat
through the roof,
going,
opening the hatch and just seeing a
skeleton head fall in your lap that
both,
that they found that was adrift and
there was a dude who had turned into a,
essentially he had turned into a mummy.
He had been mummified by the sea air and
dried out,
slumped over the table.
Like he had a table in the galley.
He slumped over the table and he's dead.
There he is.
That's how they found that dude,
because I feel like that's,
that's the same movement anyone's going
to do when you're on your last leg and
you're in a boat that's fucking sick and
that's,
that's the move we're going to do.
It says mommy found on boat missing
since 2009 one leg out,
pour one leg out posted.
He's like,
I guess this is it.
I wonder if another person would have
made it.
I wonder if he was a pussy one if he
gave out.
I mean,
you know,
we've got tired of fishing boats.
Probably the,
it's the fresh water that gets Ya.
Yeah.
Like I'm sure you can eat fish.
You know,
it'd be the,
it'd be the water that would get you
out.
So how long,
how long have you changed personally?
No,
I could go a week without water from my
cuts and one 55 so I know I could do a
week.
Yeah.
And that'd be after that.
I'm on my,
I'm on my death bed.
Yeah,
dude,
let's talk about that.
Don't do that anymore.
That,
I know you keep talking about like
fighting Eddie Alvarez cause you already
beat him and now he's the champ.
But God damn,
you're looking good at one 70.
Yeah.
So you say,
I didn't look good if 55 I've sensation
with 55,
nine 10 70 or my last run world beater
man.
It's not just that you look good,
it's just the way you look.
It's like you,
you,
you hit a whole new level.
And I always wonder like is it because
obviously you keep training,
obviously you keep getting better.
Obviously you work hard,
all those things,
uh,
learning from experience,
all those things are a factor.
But on top of that,
there's also the factor of you not
having a cut that fucking wait man.
So this last fight against rick story
against Rick Story.
It looked like you were in the fucking
matrix.
That was some Anderson Silva's shit.
I ate five guys three nights that we
were in Vegas.
Five guys.
Burgers,
hamburgers,
bevels.
I'm a food bacon and of those
[inaudible] and he was on the,
of course,
yeah.
You get the Jalapeno,
get the season,
the season fries.
Of course.
See my all healthy.
My trainers are happier.
Yeah.
I mean I think I had six pounds of cut.
It was an easy no brainer.
Yeah.
But when I saw you before the fight,
before that you were a one 76 when you
were at the comedy store.
Yeah.
That's nothing.
Nothing.
Yeah.
Look how good you look at this way.
I feel good.
That's for damn sure.
But isn't that a factor?
I mean look how fast you are.
Like the [inaudible] fight dude,
you were on fire.
You're on fire at that weight.
Yeah,
I dunno.
What's the thought process one do one 55
right?
You can do it.
You have shown it's like 60 or 65 or 65
weeks class that be capital,
but it's just that last five pounds.
His death for me.
Fucking brutal.
You know,
from 60 to 55 I just feel like I got
nothing left man.
I don't know if that carries over.
Like,
like I want to ask,
you see pedis slipped a little tired.
Deneen his last fight.
I don't know if the 45 cut,
if that has something to do with that.
Oh for sure.
If it tastes the of your gas tank a
little hundred percent,
hundred percent,
it has to.
It has to,
right?
Yeah.
I feel great out there.
That's what I'm fucking love fighting.
And it's like my favorite thing in the
whole world to do a
in the whole world.
Like I wish a motherfucker when I leave
here,
pulls up in the parking lot and tried to
give me shit like that to me is I,
you know,
and this is the way,
it's the craziest thing to me.
People tell me like I,
I posted version of me flipping people
off,
right?
So they're like,
gobble,
you're a fucking role model.
How dare you.
Like,
no,
I'm not.
I'm a,
I'm a bar junkie that fights all the
time and you guys just now on TV and,
and you and you think is cool.
So you,
I'm,
I'm your favorite fire and you know,
but had you not be in the UFC,
I'd be the asshole trying to take your
girlfriend if fight you at the bar just
as you know.
You know,
that's who I would be just so you know.
But you say that but you're a very nice
guy.
I've seen you out there in public and
part of it's,
cause you're dealing with people that
are fans and they come up to you.
They're nice.
I'm just saying I love fighting man.
I was like well you love it also because
you're really good at it.
I mean if he kept getting your ass
kicked he'd be like,
man,
I've got to find some other,
like when I was in high school and like
figuring out who I was,
I got my ass kicked a lot cause I was
that guy and that guy was,
they didn't ever take much to for me to
jump,
you know,
and I'd strike and then I'd get my
fault.
Can I ask mom by three dudes,
two dudes.
One didn't matter.
I would just get beat up.
And that's what got you in mma?
No,
I started off kickboxing.
A buddy,
a buddy of mine just told me,
you think your telecom tries kickbox and
shit.
And I went down and fell in love with it
and two weeks to train,
first way to try,
um,
commerce,
city rec center in Commerce city,
Denver.
It's like in the,
it was this rec center that offered
Taekwondo Tuesdays and Thursday nights.
And I'd go in there and we'd spar and
sparring is all I did.
Like that's what I used to do.
I thought that was getting ready for a
fight would be just be fucking throwing
down.
Now I don't spar at all.
And uh,
all I do is drill because drilling is
the most important that you do.
Right.
But uh,
it's what we would do a spa.
So you don't spar at all?
No.
Really interesting.
No,
I,
and I tell my training partners and
everyone that tried to,
you know,
try to get me so far,
but now they're okay with me just
drilling.
But I feel like the little guy at the
Walmart in click and every time you take
a hit your head,
he pushes the button.
How many,
how many people go in Walmart for it's
full?
I don't know.
You know,
I have no idea.
How many more do I got?
I think it was a very good point.
Fucking brawls to me and Leonard Garcia
have in the training room.
I don't know.
Right.
So like I'll get in there and move
around with Andre and,
and,
and move around with the all the
heavyweights,
like light mma,
sparring,
you know,
heavy takedowns and grappling real like
striking,
you know?
Uh,
but the days of putting the big loads on
the thrown down,
hell no.
I just did it with Joe Sheila and the
other day,
so I can't really say Hell No.
But him and I had a good,
good tempo and it wasn't anything crazy.
You know,
I've watched videos that you guys
sparring.
It seemed very controlled,
very controlled,
so that if you,
if I'm sparring with someone that's very
controlled and doesn't try and kill me
and cool,
but man going in with some of those guys
that are trying to make a name at the
gym,
just want to crank you,
then I got to fuck him up.
You know what I mean?
Now we're fighting and you know,
that's a funny contradiction.
It's like I love to fight.
I don't want to spar.
I love if I don't want to get hit
anymore.
Is there any way we could do that?
These beer say America.
You see America,
as I said,
that's the new thing.
Is this a new thing?
America?
That's interesting.
Yeah.
How do you not buy those if you see,
and I don't want to have,
what if a course comes along?
Goes America?
Fuck yeah.
We don't even talk about coolers.
We talked about ice cold.
Refreshing.
Budweisers that's what we know.
That's it.
That's all you're talking to your
sponsor.
Yeah.
It's like on it.
We don't talk about musclepharm
products.
We were talking about,
we take him on to talk about muscle farm
products.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm the least competitive competitive
guy ever.
I hear it.
My it,
I'm a supporter.
She,
I love fighting man.
I mean sophie you don't spar.
I think that's very wise now when
you're,
when you're doing drills like explain to
me how you're doing them.
You are,
you setting everything up.
Um,
from a,
a striking standpoint where like you
work in combinations and then counter.
So those combinations and then
possibilities of all the different
things that could happen somewhere with
brandon gives me now,
you know,
he's fucking great tactician or man,
big fan of that guy.
Yeah,
he breaks his break.
So I don't ever watch tape and people
think that's so crazy,
but I don't,
I just don't.
But they do.
So my coaches do,
so he'll come and he'll be like this,
we're working on this because I think
this is what story is going to do.
You know,
we knew he was gonna come with big over
hands and the needs of the body,
we're going to be there.
So everything we drill is,
you know,
when he does this,
make it reactionary,
you know,
and I feel like that's all good and
great,
but the good thing is I know how to
fucking fight like deep down in my soul,
so everything,
all of that doesn't work.
I can just fucking bite down and give
her,
well,
you know,
Jeremy Stephens had a very similar
sentiment.
He said,
I already know how to fight.
Yeah.
He goes,
it's all about just getting prepared,
working on my cardio,
working on my fitness,
working on my drills and my techniques.
Yeah.
And that I'm a thousand.
I mean,
I,
I don't ever take days off like today of
course,
taken out and drink a beer with you.
But,
uh,
I mean for the most part,
I trained fry five days a week and a lot
of people think that all I do is fuck
off.
Like he just drinks beer and parties and
no,
I just don't post pictures of me
training because I fucking hate that.
I hate,
like I see everyone else's vote.
He's like them in the gym.
Then six posts a day of them were like,
no one gives a fuck.
You Swim,
you strength conditioning,
you spike,
whatever.
So I just do cool shit and throw that on
the Instagram,
you know.
But I train all the time.
It's like my job,
you know.
So people are always thinking about
their fucking off.
But I mean I,
I take this very serious and I train
hard and there's no way you can be as
good as you are without having to have a
gym in my back yard.
So some days I'll go play at the lake
all day,
but we come home and then we trained
him.
My coach is like,
fuck,
now it's 2:00
AM and we had the train.
So I mean it's just,
but I love it.
When did you make the decision to stop
sparring?
Probably four fights ago.
Four fights ago.
After which fight?
After I got my ass whipped by a Alvarez
or by a heel.
Sandro.
Sonia's.
Yeah.
We didn't part of that camp much at all.
But uh,
yeah,
I don't know.
I talked to Aubrey is how and you,
and it's how I got hooked up with on it,
man.
I,
I started thinking something was fucked
up with my brain.
So I start brushing
my teeth.
One morning I fall over and I hit the
wall.
Like I literally fell over and like hit
my shoulder on my wall and I was like,
what the fuck?
And I close on on,
I fell over,
hit the other wall and I was like,
Oh man,
something's wrong.
You know,
like something seriously wrong with my
brain.
And I started freaking out.
So I go get a cat scan and go get an
MRI.
And A,
I'm convinced that I'm God,
I'm concussed and that I've taken too
many shots and I'm,
I,
it's because it's a w what,
what,
let me back the story of a little bit.
Why I think this is because my buddy
Scott Parker,
he's the enforcer for the,
for the Colorado Avalanche,
just,
he can no longer take,
he has like a problem with his
brainstem.
He took too many punches.
If he takes talks,
if it takes one more,
it's going to kill him.
Right.
So I'm like talking to him about this
and now he's like got it in my mind that
I had the same thing.
Like I'm thinking like I fall over,
like literally fall over,
hit the wall.
I'm like,
oh fuck,
something's really fucked up with me.
Anyways,
I go and get all these tests,
go see uh,
uh,
ear,
nose and throat doctor and it turns out
my sign and my septum so deviated that I
have like a sinus infection and that it
can't drain because my is deviated.
So I have like this series infection in
my left cheek and I had to get this,
I had to get on medication and get it
cleared up,
but that's why I fuck my equilibrium up.
I was like,
so it was getting in your ear?
Yeah,
it like they're all connected by any
infections somehow through my,
I have no idea.
I know how to put this.
I put this,
I still have to do it every day.
I got to put this thing in my nose and
like bro blows like a buck,
a nasal spray and my nose fixed I to I
got my,
and then I had to stop fighting for a
little while.
Not that long.
Not that long man.
I'm telling you,
it turns out I'm not mentally retarded.
I have a infection that I got cleared
up.
Butch is what I contacted you and I told
the rebel and at the cmt oils and um,
you know the mct,
sorry,
mct oils and the Alpha brain and started
trying to,
cause this is the point where I thought
I was fucking freaking out.
Right.
We started taking care of your health
and supplement.
Then I feel fucking great man.
Yeah,
there's a big difference between
supplementing and nuts and I've never,
I've never taken anything.
I'd just never,
everyone always,
I literally budweiser fruit roll ups,
you know.
And I know we talked about it and now I
fucking take these onnit pack day and
night,
sometimes two a day.
I feel fucking,
you know what?
I feel like a fucking cage gorilla
that's 15 year old and I don't know if
it has testosterone or not,
but I feel like I,
like my poor girl just gets ravaged now
go like on Cape beats to me.
I'm sure she's happy.
She's very happy.
So,
uh,
you know,
and I don't,
I don't,
I don't know if it's cause it's equaled
out my body or,
or what.
But man,
I feel my,
my coverage was great and I'm taking,
pumping on it,
you know,
I'm like,
I'm,
see I'm never taking something and I
feel so fucking good.
And I wrote and I walked out,
I said,
hey man,
you got any Alpha brain here?
I could fuck a pop,
you know?
And so we have,
so there's out,
dammit.
Dammit.
But I have some in my bag.
So yeah,
I,
it's,
it's unbelievable,
man.
How,
how good I feel and how you don't till,
you know.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
That's the key,
man.
The key is a lot of people walk around
and they don't take anything and they
think they don't need anything and
they're like,
ah,
I'm fine.
Well,
you're fine.
You'll exist,
but there's a big difference between
having your body optimized and not be an
optimized,
healthy food.
You got to get off the candy son,
Candy Habits,
eat candy anymore.
Ever since I've been taking these pills,
it's like it filled a void.
Literally.
I don't,
I don't crave like the sweets like I
used to.
Um,
it's,
it's unbelievable,
man.
I,
I can honestly say I've,
I've,
I've ditched the candy.
I'm like,
oh,
I eat a snickers bar every now and then,
but I don't take handfuls of milk duds
and skittles like I used to every day
ash.
Right?
Yeah.
And I feel like that's why I eat the
candy to try and like come back,
come back up.
But yeah,
definitely.
I'm sure.
Are you taking probiotics now?
You've taken the gut,
gut,
gut health,
total gut because your gut health
determines a lot of times what you
crave.
And one of the things that people find
is when they get off sugar and they get
off gluten and they get off like a
simple carbohydrates,
breads and pastas and stuff makes me
crave it.
The Pussy.
Is that the,
that's natural.
Au Natural.
That's your body's going equaled out.
Okay.
I got same park that makes you want to
fight and makes you want to fuck.
Gotcha.
It's a part of the whole gorilla DNA,
right?
Yeah.
No,
there's,
well are you taking a t plus?
Do you take that optimizes your
hormones?
That's a big one.
Um,
there's Alpha brain,
which one of the good things about Alpha
brain is mental fatigue.
One of the things that helps you in your
workouts is like a lot of times like
physical fatigue is one factor,
but mental fatigue is a factor too.
Like when you step up,
even if your body's tired,
if your mind feels good,
you could find out that you can force
your body to go through the motions.
You can force your body to do it because
your mind still feels energetic.
But when my mind feels shitty,
like for me,
the hardest workouts by far,
or when I'm hung over I'm like,
yeah,
cause my mind is tired.
It's like,
it's not even like my body can't lift
the weight.
It's like my body's like,
oh,
but my mind is like,
I can't muster it.
So Alpha brain post drinking is
fantastic.
It's one of the best things for
hangovers because a lot of things that
are going on,
you're dehydrated.
That's a big factor.
But also like all your electrolytes are
all fucked up and all your
neurotransmitter levels are all fucked
up.
You could Jack those backup with Alpha
brain and knew mood knew mood's a big
one too because it brings up your
serotonin levels and that's what I have
each team that comes into the night pack
for sleeping,
right?
Yeah.
Perfect.
And I tell people who are trying to
steal off thing,
but listen to me,
please don't buy it.
Please don't buy it.
Find out what the ingredients are.
Go buy your own shit.
Go by it.
That the best form you can buy.
That's the most important thing.
By the purest best version of it,
you can find.
Use all those things.
Use Coleen.
He has all these different ingredients.
You're going to find an Alpha brain and
all the different ingredients.
You're going to find a new mood.
You're going to have results,
but if you want to get it made for you
in the best possible form,
that's what we sell.
That's what we're trying to do it on it.
We're just trying to,
every everything that I use,
everything that arbor uses,
everything that all the pro athletes
use,
guys like you use,
we just find that what's the best shit?
Yeah.
What's the best fee?
I mean,
I literally feel the Best I've felt in
my life and I,
I don't know if it has to do with solely
take it on or just reinventing myself,
man.
You know,
uh,
you got to sometimes just fucking step
back and reset and figure out what works
for you.
Right.
Does big,
real big.
And I,
and it,
it,
it took a lady Francesca Parker,
Scott's wife did set me down and fucking
tell me,
cowboy,
what,
what's the bad in your life?
I've got to get that shit.
We gotta get the energy vampires off
you.
And we got,
and you got it.
You got to hone in and figure out what
works for you again,
man.
And,
and I did.
And I feel fucking great man.
Was Aubrey taking you into the room in
his house for the,
the,
the launching into space now.
The psychedelic journey room.
No,
I ain't ready for that.
I'm ready for that.
Are you ready for that?
I'm ready for that too.
I need to do it this year.
I'm about a year off of,
I've done it.
I was,
I did about a year ago.
I'm a,
I'm feeling like right about now.
I'm ready to get back in there.
Let's do it together.
Okay,
let's do it.
Let's,
let's hook up with Aubrey.
We'll figure out a time you got to go
meet the,
meet the overlords telling you,
man,
I'm all this shit that you say that.
It's crazy.
I believe it's crazy,
but it ain't crazy like dmt is crazy.
GMT is some next level.
Let's go do some drugs and hang out.
I'm telling you.
Is this you saw to approved?
Yes.
Perfect.
It is.
All right.
Well,
you can't test for it and it exists in
your own brain.
It's like tested you for saliva.
All right?
Literally,
it's like testing you for blood.
Oh Man.
Cowboy test.
Positive for red platelets.
Amen.
We're going to get in there.
I'm totally,
and we're going.
Do you feel like dmt or what is the tea
that people take?
The the where we get the Sharmane and
you go and you drink Iowasca that's dmt
too.
If we just ate a fucking handful of
mushrooms,
we could have the same psychedelic trip.
DMT is mushrooms times a million plus
aliens.
Huh?
That's the way I describe it.
I've done mushrooms and mushrooms are
awesome.
You gotta take a shit load of mushrooms.
You have an amazing trip.
But there's something about dmt that
just blows all the other ones out of the
water.
It's the most potent of all
psychedelics.
Most transcendent of all psychedelics.
She,
I feel like you're a,
you're a black belt and psychedelics.
I'm,
uh,
my first day white belt.
Doesn't matter man.
You can,
you can,
you could do it.
Everybody can do it.
I'm sure I could do go from a white belt
to a black belt.
Literally your first class you go,
oh shit.
And you come back and by the way,
you never really a black girl even when
you do it.
I've done it.
I don't know how many times now,
but every time I do it I'm like,
oh fuck.
Here I go.
I get nervous.
I'm white knuckling.
Before you take that hand of the pipe,
you go,
okay,
it just takes one.
Here we go.
Three hits,
three heads,
three minutes is what I recommend.
Deep on.
Blow it out.
Go in again.
I can't just do one.
You don't want to get to the door.
You don't want to get you to do.
It's like,
you know you play Ding Dong,
ditch,
bring someone's doorbell,
runaway.
You can't do that.
You gotta you gotta you gotta open up
the door and you got to get into the
house.
Yeah,
it's,
it's amazing.
How does it make you shit yourself?
Until I'm like,
no,
like the tea.
The problem with the t is that your body
rejects your purging the bad.
That's my argument.
You like,
no,
you're just throwing up and shitting
yourself because you had the shit.
You shouldn't have eight to del Taco
before he fucking took it.
Well,
you definitely are supposed to alter
your diet.
You definitely suppose to have an
alkaline diet before you.
A sense that you're going to fucking
blow your backside out because they're
like,
you need a fast before you come into
this.
Yeah,
that's not,
you purge it now.
Bad energy that's you fucking purge out.
Just the shit.
Yeah.
Eight.
Well,
this is like hippy dippy,
new age way of talking where people go,
oh,
it's the toxins.
You're getting rid of the toxins,
the toxins,
like they do that and yoga all the time.
When you're in this position,
this position releases toxins.
It,
it clears your body of all the emotions.
No,
you're stretching.
Shut the fuck up.
And with this dot,
this is d.
You're not purging,
you sweating.
If you're sweating,
your body's getting rid of some fluid.
There's definitely so a cleansing
process involved in that.
There's no fucking toxins like,
come on,
stop with the toxins.
At least we're on the same page.
It's just do drugs and have fun.
Yes.
Okay.
Well,
I WASCO is dmt.
But what it is,
it's a,
it's an orally active version of dnt.
I'll give you the quick breakdown.
Your body produces,
your gut produces something called model
aiming oxidase and you,
it,
what it is is it breaks down dmt.
So if you eat like grass,
like there's certain types of grasses
and lettuce and a bunch of different
plans,
like thousands of different plants have
dmt in them,
but you don't trip when you eat him.
The reason why is because your stomach
produces something called Monell amy and
oxidase.
Well,
these indigenous people in the Amazon,
they figured out how to combine one
plant,
which has dmt in it,
and then another plant which has an Mao
inhibitor.
So this Mao inhibitor inhibits your
body's production of monoamine oxidase.
And so the DMT naturally absorbs in your
body,
but you're eating these fucked up plants
that tastes like shit.
It tastes like a total dick.
Right?
And you just,
you're just throwing up and shitting
yourself.
Um,
it's supposed to be an incredible
spiritual experience.
I haven't done it.
I've only done the the way stronger
version of it,
which you smoke,
which doesn't give you any throwing up
any diarrhea and which sounds way
better.
It's way better.
It's gotta be,
I think the other ones really amazing
too.
But the thing about the DMT thing,
they called the businessman's trip cause
you're in and out in 15 minutes.
It's perfect,
but I amazing.
So you're not
no hung over.
You're good transient drugs ever
exhibited or ever observed in the human
body.
Your body brings you back to baseline
really quickly.
So you're high as a fucking car.
You,
you're in the center of the universe.
You're,
you're talking to dee geometric patterns
that are made out of love and
understanding and know everything about
everything you've ever done your whole
life and recognize your bullshit and
dissolve your ego right in front of you.
Show you your life in,
in,
in like these hieroglyphs and show you
these insane images that are made out of
like neon with no borders.
And then 15 minutes later your cowboy
again,
but you're,
you're renewed.
It's like resetting your whole
experience.
Man's planet,
man sold me.
It's going to be your friend.
You explain that?
I wish I could explain my diving that
good cause I was just like,
oh you fucking go in and break some
other gas.
And I think he did a great job.
It,
I think you did a great job explaining
it.
But I think there's a lot,
a bunch of factors going on.
I think like with your life,
like all the good things that are
happening is I think first of all,
a decision to go to one 70 is a very
good one.
So here I'm uh,
I'm uh,
I get upset.
I think the number one problem we have
in fighting today,
the number one problem is weight
cutting.
Yeah.
I fucking with you man.
And I,
the whole time I was at 55,
I'd always,
and I,
you know how I like to fight.
So I'd call,
Hey,
I want 70 pound or fell out.
I'll take that fight with Joe.
And Daniel would tell me,
well cowboy,
you're 55 of those guys are fucking
monsters.
I guess they were wrong,
weren't they?
So then,
so now me I would have told you to do is
hug nomis no offense,
but you don't have the fucking,
the stamp.
They gave me the fight.
No,
I need to get a stamp.
So now I'm like 70 and I want to fight a
55 and they say no,
you're fucking so great.
It's 70 you don't want to go down to 55
like God damn.
Well you guys make up your fucking mind.
What I can do,
you can't listen to those dudes only
listen to me.
Okay,
I'll go through you.
I'll be your manager from now on.
I'm going to handle,
you can contact me,
I'll contact them.
Have speaking for cowboy Bam.
Done.
But they may have,
when I walked in I seen you had a
wheeler album out front.
Wheeler Walker.
So man,
so I was getting ready in the,
in the locker room was doesn't I put
kicking ass need pussy and it's Kinda
tough.
It starts,
I've jamming and we get there kind of,
you know,
a little bit earlier.
And so we still had all the,
I think I had six people in my,
in my uh,
locker room and I have like a big ass
speaker,
like a big jukebox.
Right.
And I just tell you take over like
everyone go with Kaji.
Okay good.
I'll see you anyways.
So I started playing and then when I
start warming up that's what I throw on.
And mother fucker people were like whole
well how about when it goes to sucking
Dick?
He called man.
Right.
So yeah I just,
I noticed that when I walked in I was
like Oh okay.
Yeah he's a buddy of mine.
I love that dude.
He's hilarious.
He's fucking,
if you ever seen the video for that,
that song,
no the video for that song.
It's hilarious cause they did it at like
this like real country western and the
people
in the audience had no idea he was going
to be there and they had no idea what he
did.
And so they played it for like these
regular country music people
can play.
Cause we was a buddy of mine,
man.
We could.
I'm sure we can begin to hear this right
here.
No,
here's the video.
Let's watch the video.
Put your headphones on.
Do I stop this one?
Yeah.
Dot Mine.
You put yours on
Friday night work because he had did an
acoustic version of it too is kind of
Jammy.
That's why I kicked his ass and kicking
out the same people on the train.
You were with me.
They were like an eye out.
He's probably listening to both see and
kicking it.
We'll see in the morning.
Was He in the night?
Get into a fight.
Right for you.
It's perfect song and it's perfect.
I loved it.
Yeah.
It was just quiet in the change room.
We're be like,
what the fuck?
It was good man.
That's awesome.
I think to UFC and MMA in general should
make a concerted effort to stop weight
cutting.
Just stop it,
stop it dead.
Say No more and and just eliminate it
completely and I think it can be done.
I think it can be done if you have just
set up good fights between guys that are
the same size.
This,
I think this,
this whole obsession with like
championship belts on them with you.
It's all great and everything.
But like,
here's the perfect example,
conor and nate diaz biggest fucking
fight in the history of the sport.
No belt on the lot.
That just,
just throwing down,
nobody gave a fuck.
Nobody said where's the gold?
Where's the strap?
Right.
Where's the leather?
But he feels like EOC is going more
towards big fights in his championship
fights.
I hope that's what they did.
I hope so.
Till they just take the guys that want
to on a seat.
Can you announce that fight that fight?
The no,
dammit.
I can't.
It's not 100% yet,
but it's going to be fucking ruined.
Ruined.
And it's a good,
hopefully today we get the,
we get the double thumbs up.
I mean I sent last night,
last night we got the half the thumb.
So you gotta have to have,
you already have them up like a pose
down,
a photo or two of you guys together.
Shit.
That's going to be a good fight and that
could potentially be mad.
So,
yeah,
I mean that's,
that's what I'm fucking,
I they didn't put me on 200 and they
fucked me on that,
but I really wanted to be,
but I would want to be on the Madison
Square Garden.
Man.
The 200 was great because she was better
I think it was.
Yes,
it was better to watch.
The 200 was great because it was a
celebration.
But two O two was a better car.
Yes,
absolutely.
The Brian as her thing was kind of a
freak show.
Like Holy Shit,
brock Lesnar's back and you know,
uh,
Amanda Nunez and [inaudible] was a hell
of a fight.
Amanda Nunez,
no jokes on me.
No joke.
And yeah,
for some next level women out there,
now they're found Tina,
chef chanko chick,
holy shit.
And Holly Holm and,
and there's just so many high level
chicks now and fucking Yolanda,
you and Jay check is just a straight up
assassin.
Yes.
I trained with her a little bit of
muscle farm scam visited and it's fun.
She's a Badass bitch.
Yeah,
she'll do respect all,
do respect.
All do respect.
Now I'll do her,
I can't say fish calls I got before I
came on here.
Did there should be an advisory sticker
on this for what words I can and cannot
say who said that to apple?
What had,
you know,
some people from the PR team at UFC and
my management team.
So,
uh,
I have a tendency to say bad words.
Hilarious.
It is,
it is and I don't mean it and I get to
draw in a derogatory or I just how I
talk,
you know,
and well,
you should talk how you talk.
I'm telling you cowboy,
I gotta be your fucking manage.
It's all these suits in the way of that
is the fruit of the sponsors,
man.
The sponsors.
I need another beer.
A worked up.
It's the sponsors man.
They,
they can't,
they can't take it.
They can't,
they need to take it,
I think to God damn it think you're
popular for,
they think you popular for wearing a bow
tie and talking about,
uh,
being wide open.
Right.
Hey man,
look at this.
This is,
uh,
the Colorado Springs Fire Department,
Dad's captain,
the fire department.
I was just down there.
They sent some shirts for you.
Oh,
beautiful.
Yeah,
they're,
they're listening.
They're like your biggest fucking,
if they wanted,
they wanted you to have those brought
him bearing come bearing gifts.
So station 12.
Uh,
thank you.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.
Yeah,
no worries.
I was just over there and they,
they,
they let they,
everyone I fucking talk to you.
He loves you man.
So I'll just give you a shout out man.
That's good.
They say,
uh,
how much you've changed their life.
Just talking about diet,
talking about good times and you know,
so it's awesome.
Beautiful.
It's good to know that you can,
ah,
more beer.
Look at Q.
Yes sir.
Look at us.
We're crushing him.
Jb was,
ought to be talking about some good
shit.
Hell back.
And we gotta we gotta get to the point.
We'll fuck the PR team.
Fuck man.
Are you hiring?
Are you hiring the UFC has gotta be in a
weird position with this show because
they know we talked like if he wants the
last one,
me and Eddie Bravo.
Edna Bravo was so fucking drunk.
He barely knew what he was talking about
15 seconds ago and he was going on about
how he doesn't believe the rovers on
Mars are real.
He doesn't know why the water sticks to
the earth because the earth is round.
What does the water just roll off the
earth?
How do you know that the Earth is
spinning?
It just got so bizarre.
So they can't worry about that though,
man.
Everybody worries about you being you.
You like people like someone who is
actually themselves because it's so
fucking rare today.
And I feel like I've been myself the
whole journey and,
and that's I,
to my grandma's credit,
you know,
she always tells me,
don't fucking paint yourself in a
corner.
No matter what you do,
don't pay.
You should be you through and through.
And I always have,
you know,
and I probably always will be.
So I,
I told my manager,
I'm probably going to say some fucked up
shit and you're going to have to put out
the fires.
It's not fucked up.
It's what you really think.
Right.
You know,
goddammit.
It's just as nothing wrong with it,
man.
They got to understand like this is what
they do.
They market things,
but they somehow in their mind they
think that,
oh,
the best way to market things to not
piss anybody off.
That's not true.
The best way to market things is to have
a guy like you who's out there dive in
300 fucking feet playing with sharks and
shit,
riding jet skis and doing all kinds of
bananas.
Shit,
you're fucking mad,
man.
You're a a genuine madman and they want
to take you and they want to turn you
into some fucking cookie cutter like a
person that they could sell.
It's bullshit.
It is bullshit.
You can't sell that.
I'm with you who are out of that.
They want you to to be Luke Bryan.
They want you to have genes that are
already ripped.
They wanted to give you those fucking
pre ripped jeans.
Look,
we scuffed up your boots for you.
Fuck you.
Fuck you with it.
I'm with Ya.
Fuck them.
Fuck them all hooked to this beer says
America on it.
Now you're a fan.
I'm a big fan.
I can get a couple of cases dropped off
anytime you want.
You let me know.
Let me,
she just like you send me on it.
I'll send you budweiser does a flag with
a,
it was,
it just fucking gives beer.
Just a jar at flag.
Fill a flag up with a big gigantic sack
of beer.
Yeah.
You talking about loose.
That's what I can't wait.
We'll get you about two or three more in
and you're going to loose money.
Ready to try to spark up a joint and
we're going to call it good time.
Since I got that fear factor money,
I got loose.
That's your fucking about him.
It makes you lose that.
You'll see big money to come in.
It's coming.
It's got to come.
Now.
Did,
did you sign a new contract?
Did you,
did you happy?
Yeah.
There's a pause there.
I don't like it is,
I'm happy.
The pause,
I mean am as happy as I'd liked to be
na.
Am I,
am I skipping?
No,
but let me tell you something,
man.
I googled.
I had to take a photo today,
put it on my instagram and I googled
donald and it went trump.
And then I put in the word see,
and it was instantly serone you're
famous motherfucker.
Hell yeah.
We need to get you paid.
I need to be a fucking manager.
Do on it.
You're going to be on the team.
I just don't want to get paid for it.
I want to be like,
I'm just the guy who calls,
just call me if shit gets weird.
Well your answer is going to be the same
as mine.
Fuck it.
Shit.
I feel like a guy like you honestly
should be completely insulated from
anybody's advice.
I feel like a guy like you,
it should be like your friends and your
family and people you love and everybody
else has to shut the fuck up and just
let you go.
Oh,
that's
a,
I feel every day.
So yeah.
And then I get phone calls saying,
you can't say that cat.
Well you can't do that cal,
but you have to do this.
It's wild.
Yeah.
I mean they have to understand like
people talk a certain way and they
express themselves a certain way and
it's,
there's an honesty in what you do that
you're not going to find in that many
people.
There's an honesty and expressing
yourself that is being lost.
If beans,
squash is the way I'm geared,
I,
I'm with you,
man.
I wish.
I wish things were different.
I really do.
I wish that,
I wish I,
you don't have to listen.
Oh,
I do.
Fuck that.
I do this.
This company we're drinking right here.
They don't allow me to say certain
things.
I'm Tom Wiser America,
Budweiser.
We've got a problem now you write
America on you,
your Budweiser,
but I'm just saying this.
I'm like,
well,
we're not at all that.
Paul spoke and talk and a pot smoking is
American.
All this is American beers.
They go hand in hand.
It's not one of them's not bad.
One of them is not good.
I tried to explain to people like,
you can't get a bobcat and your backyard
and not think he's going to fucking
attack you.
Exactly.
That's how I feel with me too.
Like I'm a wild motherfucker.
Like you can't,
you can't take the leash off me.
You can't put the leash on me and take
me kiss handshake babies.
Then let the leash off and let me and
say,
oh,
he's going to be all right.
Exactly.
He's not,
they can't turn you into some fucking
Sitcom Dad.
Okay,
who were the wife comes home and yells
at you like,
well her throwing her took the trash
out.
Ooh,
look,
look.
That's what they want to do.
They want to figure out how to extract
money out of you.
So when a guy like you starts talking
crazy shit,
they're like,
oh,
they're gonna protest.
Oh look out the transgender women,
but new little lesbian slash animal
rights community that doesn't like you
diving.
Yeah.
God,
I don't know what I do if I couldn't sky
diver.
You have a,
you have a problem with a serious
problem.
You have a problem with your brain where
you're thrilled.
Meter gets low and you panic and then
you've got a juice up bitch back up and
you gets low and you got to juice to a
big,
and that's why you're great fighter.
And when we're on DMT or are we going
to,
am I going to face these demons?
You think?
Oh for sure.
Okay.
But you'd be fine.
You with Dmt is going to tell you,
I would imagine.
I don't know what they're going to tell
you.
I'm sorry for even suggesting it because
then what?
I go into it next time they're going to
go,
oh,
you know,
no,
we're going to say today.
I think your life experiences is a
wonderful journey.
Here's what I feel.
I believe,
honestly,
I think what you're doing by fighting at
this extremely high level and by
entertaining millions of people
worldwide is you're providing people
with incredible thrills.
You know how many people sent me and the
animated Gif of that final combination
you landed on rick stories.
Talk about
that.
Oh good Lord.
Lets throw that bitch up on the screen.
Well let's,
let's talk.
So everyone says how great this convoys,
oh it's beautiful.
Okay,
here it is.
All crack.
That's the end of it.
We'll wash it from the beginning.
We,
you know what I love about it,
man,
what I love,
I love technique.
Look at this.
This is what I love.
Pop to the body,
to the head.
Boom.
You know what I love about it?
Not a single one of those techniques is
wound up.
full power.
But look how you doing this pop bank,
crack blind.
So for everyone is listening.
All that is the Jab,
cross,
Hook,
kick.
Yeah,
but it's not,
because here's the thing about it.
The way you throw in all these things is
the way everybody should throw every
punch,
your,
there's no windup.
Everything is perfect technique.
The execution,
the timing,
the,
the accuracy.
Look how beautiful this is,
man.
See,
this is you.
So I bet it's hard for you to
appreciate.
But for me as a person who calls MMA as
a person who watches fights do,
when I was calling that fight,
I was like this.
I was like,
Oh,
oh,
oh look at this.
Oh,
this is perfect.
Geno's upset.
I missed the triangle I am with myself.
Oh my God,
he's a tough guy.
He's good.
But get good submission defense.
So last time we talked,
we talk about Calvin [inaudible]
himself.
Like I'm playing a video game.
I was in the mode for sure.
Yeah,
for sure.
That's a matrix.
Shit.
I mean this to me is more impressive
than when Anderson Silva knocked out
forrest griffin.
Cause when Anderson Silva knocked out
forrest Griffin,
what I know about forest was at forest
was compromised going into that fight.
He had been knocked out twice in
training camp.
He had a real hard time taking shots and
probably shouldn't have been in there in
the first place.
And so he had a lot of doubts and he was
having a real hard time.
This is a big powerful rick story.
Who's a nasty motherfucker.
He throws vicious body shots.
He's a hard wrestler.
He's the guy who was the first loss that
Johnny Hendricks got.
People don't know Rick Story.
Rick story's a tough dude.
And for you to tee off on him like this
in this perfect way.
Not with big wound up fucking heavy
shots like he throws with Rick.
Story likes to do is you pressures guys
and he fucking digs in or I'm wound to
the body,
takes you down,
beats you up.
He's a tough,
tough dude and what you did is you just
use perfect technique.
That angle when you throw that left,
you throw the LE,
you throw the Left,
the Jab,
you throw the right hand to the body and
then you take that Washes Jab.
Well he bought that way.
I like taking it.
He did.
Boom.
That was all like you adjusted,
you adjusted perfectly with that left.
He tried to be nice,
tried to be nice about yourself.
Look at,
it's a beautiful combination.
That's a matrix shit and I feel like a
big part of that is you not depleting
your body.
Absolutely.
Another big part of his is one 70
pounders.
Don't think you can just come take my
body shots anymore because I don't like
I let them more biscuit now.
Yeah,
right.
You don't,
you don't have to gas body Jesus.
What did your body feel like when you
fought one 55 like when you compare
yourself to a normal training session,
like say you're several months in
between fights.
I walk around one s I used to walk
around and bout one 74 right.
That was like my deep training camp and
I noticed when I started to cut I'd get
down to one 6,870
but I had nothing in the gas tank man.
I would always be like,
it would all mental at that point,
you know?
And I didn't have like my body felt real
thin and brittle and one 70 I feel good.
I don't feel the,
I got the,
I got the extra tank,
you know?
I don't feel like it's a big part of it.
Oh my God.
Is it big part of it man.
Now you spitting into that thing.
What's going on here?
We've got one.
I'm drinking Copenhagen.
No,
what is that shit?
Yeah,
Copenhagen.
What's the deal with that?
Explain that to me.
What does that do for you?
I've never been involved.
I have no experience in this.
I should get back on once when I was a
kid cause I read huckleberry Finn.
Did they give you,
did they give you a head?
It gave you a head high.
Threw up.
Yeah,
I sorry.
Extra salivating and it felt like shit.
I don't know.
It was a good,
I like it.
Let me try some of that.
Give it a go.
What do you do with it?
Just take a little bump.
Put under your lip bump.
Little Pinch.
Like a cocaine style bump.
Now we've never done that either.
I'd go less is less than what you has
plenty for you.
Is that too much?
That's good.
Okay.
Where do you put it?
Any way you put any lift you want.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's going to start to burn a little
bit.
Get cancer immediately.
I don't think so.
I mean now you shouldn't,
that doesn't taste bad.
No,
it's like wintergreen done in the right
one.
It's been the right one,
but you do not.
I repeat.
Do not want to drink juice bit.
That is a fucking day gone bad.
Well,
one of the guys who worked at UFC who
was a,
uh,
Jimmy's laughing cause of chewing.
It looks ridiculous.
Why does it look ridiculous?
You're going to get a supervisee high.
It's going to be great.
One of the guys that was a stunt man for
the UFC or not the UFC fear factor.
Yeah.
Um,
he worked on so many movie sets where
couldn't spit that he wound up swallow
and spit.
So he got used to chewing and swallowing
it.
I got my,
I got it spread out all over my lower
gum.
Yeah.
You gotta use your tongue and a ball up
together.
There you go.
Now.
So I'm not addicted to,
to,
I can go to the pot either.
Yeah.
I can get from dad,
go weeks without the pussy.
Now I don't have an addictive
personality at all.
I can know literally.
I mean I can,
I usually just shoot them on the boat
and out and I don't know,
whenever I drank,
I chew what I drink.
This is like a cigar times five.
Oh yeah.
You're going to get buzzing.
Yeah.
Oh,
I get it.
It's just fun.
I don't know.
It's probably bad.
Probably a terrible role model and move,
which are bad for you.
Oh No,
it says right here the warning.
Great for you.
Uh,
I don't know.
They put that on the can,
but I feel like all the people who can
sit and get cancer from this are
pussies.
Is that right?
No.
It's another thing.
You're not supposed to say.
W we'll Copenhagen sponsor you or in the
UFC and left the house.
Shit.
Well,
the UFC let them,
why wouldn't they?
I don't see why,
uh,
maybe cause this is tobacco butt,
but what about alcohol?
Yeah,
I mean,
talk about kills a lot of people that
they don't talk about.
Sure.
But,
but I mean bud light and anheuser busch
is a giant sponsor,
UFC,
so,
yeah.
Yeah,
I know.
I have them.
See why they wouldn't,
I don't know if the,
you'll voc Copenhagen right in the
middle of the octagon.
Yeah.
So man,
people already get mad.
I think it's hilarious.
And people get mad that Nate Diaz was
smoking a vape pen after his fight.
I'm like,
you just watched him get punched in the
fucking head for 25 minutes and you
think it's bad that he's smoking a vape
pen.
You want to hear the problem with it
though?
What's the problem?
Well,
there's no problem,
but you sought a contest up to 42 hours
after we fight.
Right.
So it might be a bad call on him because
just because,
only that would be the only bad downfall
I think.
I mean,
he's totally doing it publicly.
He could probably get tested immediately
right after.
I don't know.
The thing is that the one he was taken
with cbd oil,
which is not psychoactive,
which I'm a totally,
totally fan of.
That's all I take.
Do you take cbd with Tom?
I'd put the patches.
I used the rub.
Yeah,
because he said there's no
hallucinogenic effects.
You just did the healing,
the medicinal side of the marijuana.
Right.
So,
uh,
yeah,
whenever I go to Colorado,
I load up on another cbd oils and I use
them all the time for my knees and my
elbows.
You can use in a bath,
man,
I have some ointment.
You put it in the sauce.
Yeah,
it's bath,
but it's really a bath salts for real.
What is this?
The size of that joint parties with
snoop and the biggest joint ever.
That is not the biggest joint ever.
That is propaganda.
I've seen the biggest joint ever.
It's far bigger than that.
I'm a big supporter of both of those
gentlemen,
but I don't like lying.
That's a pretty big joint.
That floor me,
that's not the biggest joint over looked
in this audit box right here.
Now was in there creeping around
earlier.
Oh look,
we'd how weird.
So now you're smoking.
Chewing I'm drinking is to see what
happens when you combine the two of them
together.
The three of them,
the three of them.
I'm a fucking American.
I'm a grown man.
A middle aged.
I have children.
I have a wife.
I pay taxes.
I got a lot of good pr things on my
side.
I'm telling you,
change lives,
man.
You wouldn't be the people that listen
to this.
I mean,
this might be a terrible episode for
people to tell them to model their life
after,
but typically you talk about,
you talk about good health and eating
correctly and just people that sit
around and do nothing with their lives.
You know,
just getting up on a Sunday and going
for a hike and getting out there.
You know,
you talked about these things,
so they enjoy it.
I get messages every day from people
that lost a hundred pounds right there
feeling healthy.
The problem is we're dealing with
propaganda and you could do one or two
things.
You could either just say,
well,
you know this is this,
this,
I think I swallowed all that tobacco.
Yeah,
it's all gone.
Yeah.
I was wondering why I'm so hot.
You got to bag Glonek it's gone.
Yeah.
Swallowed it.
I had a boy.
I don't know what I'm doing right,
too and drank and so,
all right.
We're fine.
Eating Pussy and kicking ass.
What happens if you swallow it?
New Rule.
Jb pulls up something immediately.
New lives enforced by the food and Drug
Administration will prevent cigarettes
and smokeless tobacco sponsorships in
sporting events that smoking tobacco.
I think that's the vape pens or are
they,
is that talking about chewing tobacco?
That's chewing tobacco.
I swallowed it,
but there was a couple of years ago,
this was like 2010 find it.
No,
you're fine.
You're going to be all right.
Serious head rush though.
This is good.
I'm enjoying this.
I might,
I might incorporate this in my diet.
What did we start selling on it?
Tobacco pills.
They'd be like snaps packets that you
put in a little packet.
Well,
that's one thing that you do get when
you smoke a cigar.
You get this weird kind of different
kind of hot,
absolutely weird kind of head rush.
Silly,
happy.
Hi.
You know I didn't spit once.
I never said I was falling it.
I love it.
That might be the best way to go.
Fucking,
hey rose.
The thing,
we're,
we're here for a hundred years if we're
lucky.
Lucky.
And along the way,
we're having a deal with decades and
decades of propaganda,
which are lies.
It's just lives we were dealing with
lies by all these different people that
profited off of demonization,
of marijuana,
and having people think that there's
something bad about consuming these
psychedelic drugs.
These things have made me more
sensitive.
They may be nicer.
They made me more aware of my impact on
the people that are in my life.
More kind and more appreciative of the
people that are in my life.
More appreciative and more thankful for
all the lucky things that have happened
to me.
All the fortune that I've had to meet.
Good dudes like you and Jamie,
and,
and to be able to do something like this
podcast when I smoke weed sometimes.
You know what I think?
I think how fortunate I am and I think,
I think how much I love my children.
I think about how much I love my
friends.
I call it my Joey Diaz will call me up
high in the middle of the day at any
given moment ago.
I'm just calling to tell you I love your
dog.
I fucking love you.
I know he's high as fuck right now.
I'm so high.
I think I'm on.
I'm on not even on this planet.
I'm calling you from Jupiter,
but it's not.
These are not bad things folks.
They're not bad things.
You know,
you know when you see nate Dina's
smoking a little weed,
he should be able to smoke a fucking
joint.
It should be at that press conference.
They should have a one of those oxygen
things with sucks the air out.
A little vent right above him.
Let him smoke a joint.
You just fought for millions of people,
you know.
That's what I think.
Cowboy,
I'm with you man.
I'm,
I'm totally,
I think this is the part where budweiser
cancers,
they're like,
we're done.
We're done.
We're done with this.
You're out of here.
Well,
sponsorships are hard man.
I understand.
I understand it from their perspective.
You know,
it's hard cause you're kind of
outsourcing credibility,
right?
This is all a friend of mine,
my friend Jason Harrison,
he owns this company called [inaudible],
which is a,
um,
big time,
uh,
hunting apparel company.
And they've been in here before because
they're fascinating guys.
He's,
oh,
super smart genius dude who makes like
the,
the best clothes for a mountaineering
and for hunting.
And he does it because it's his passion.
He likes to do.
So this guy like goes to Japan,
finds all the best fabrics,
and we were talking about,
I don't know if you know about what's
going on under armour.
Do you see the thing with a dude killed
a bear with a spear?
Fuck yeah.
Yeah.
See that's how you feel.
And he killed a bear with a spear and a
bunch of people got mad and a bunch of
people protest it,
which is really ironic because one of
the things,
we're going to kill a bear,
any Predator,
I'm not a Predator,
a hunter,
but if you're going to kill a predator,
fucking get down and dirty with it.
Well,
he got down and dirty.
So you had to be,
what,
five feet from it with a spear?
I think he was,
well,
he's a huge dude.
His name's Josh bonior.
I'll just give him a shout out and a,
this is what happened.
Josh bowmore killed his bear with a
spear and they put the video online like
did he,
did he treat it first or no,
no,
no.
It was at a bait site in Alberta.
He was there the week before I was
there.
I was their hunting the week afterward.
Okay.
Um,
and he got within 16 feet of this bear
and fuck,
maybe 16 yards.
He got closest fucked to this bear and
he,
but he is like a competitive javelin
thrower.
He's a huge dude.
He's a bodybuilder.
Sure.
He chucks,
his spear hits the bear,
the bear run 60 yards and dies.
Okay.
But there's a video of it and the bears
guts are hanging out.
You know,
it's like hunting scenes or graphic,
just like,
you know,
everybody likes to have those five guys
burgers but nobody wants to go to the
fucking slaughterhouse and watch them
get hit in the head with a piston then
gutted and hung by their ankles and
twitching and spraying all over the
place.
But that's the reality of the world we
live in in,
right?
Sure.
I'm not 100% you know,
saying that the v I don't think putting
the video up is a good idea because if
you're going to put a video like that
up,
there's a lot you got explain for hours.
Your position on a whole lot of things
for anybody is going to accept that
video.
Anyway,
under armor,
which was a sponsor,
they sponsored his wife,
they canceled her sponsorship cause she
was filming the hunt and then they're
getting this huge backlash from all of
these hunters who were like,
well this is a legal hunt because it was
legal to do that in Alberta.
And everybody always says like if they
talk about hunters,
Oh,
you pussy,
you think you're fucking man,
go kill him with the spirit or knife.
This guy did it.
Fucking killed a seven foot bear with a
spear.
I wouldn't do it.
I'm not saying there's a couple of
problems with it as far as like a
regular person,
like first of all,
you gotta be strong as fuck to throw a
spear hard enough to kill a bear or if
you're not you to be close enough.
Yeah.
A couple of those things are those,
those are both huge factors.
You're taking a tremendous risk doing
something like that,
so it gets out of the realm in a lot of
people's eyes of like hunting for meat,
which is really the only thing that
people respect.
If the average person doesn't hunt,
they do not respect trophy animals.
The trophy hunting,
rather if you say,
oh,
I want a,
I want a zebra rug,
so I'm going to shoot a zebra.
People who get fucking pissed at u of o
is wanting to see a stuffed giraffe in
my backyard.
People will get fucking really mad at
you if you kill an animal for its skin.
Sure.
If you kill an animal for the sole
purpose of eating it and you'd do it in
an ethical way,
people they,
they go,
okay,
I get it because I eat meat myself and I
buy fish from the store and there's 95%
of the planet does that.
But this guy who got it,
there's a huge controversy with armour
and one of the things that Jason
Harrison from quill,
you said,
he goes,
we don't outsource our credibility.
Our company is dependent upon us.
We don't have any athletes that we
sponsor.
There's nothing,
there's no one out there that represents
our brand that we have to make sure you
don't say this.
Don't say that.
All they do is just make great shit.
And I think that's the thing about a
company like Budweiser.
I love that a company like budweiser
gets behind a guy like you,
but they can't.
They got to accept you for you.
God accept you for you dirty words and
all the words and not,
you know.
I said,
we all know you're a meat eater.
What would your last meal,
your death row meal,
the choice B l can Jalapenos.
That's how I do so many fucking pissed.
I missed out on that too.
He tells me the next time you hear I
have you over the house.
I'll cook for you.
I seen you cooking it last night.
I know you're only here for short time.
Next time my friend was planned.
Is that,
let's train.
Let's get together.
Let's get a little workout in.
Grill for you.
We'll I'll bring it on.
Yeah,
we could roll.
we do whatever you want.
I want to,
I want to see how you set up some of
your shit too.
I want to watch because you know what I
really love that you do,
man,
that need of the body that checked me
the body.
God Damn.
You'd do that better than anybody in
this sport.
You and you do it out of nowhere.
You,
you have a a beautiful way of delivering
that when you don't know it's common.
I think that's a really,
I mean there's a lot of guys that do it,
don't get me wrong,
but I think that you probably do it as
better as good as anybody in mma right
now.
I like to see how you set that up.
I like to talk to you about that shit
anytime.
Yeah.
I just got my black belt and pretty
excited about that Jujitsu,
longtime km,
long time companies being overtrain 15
year just putting on the gay.
I don't get into it that much.
So problematic.
The geese problematic.
Totally caught me off,
gotten into,
had no idea it was coming to and I was
like,
Oh wow,
cool.
Look,
it's so hung up on that.
Goddamn.
Gee,
I'm a big fan of the Geek.
I don't.
I have a black belt in the G.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with the gay,
but I think people are too fucking
connected to an article of clothing and
they're doing it for one reason.
One reason does the only reason into
that tradition because the guys with the
Geeky know how to use that fucking Geek
guy you to hold those collars.
They don't know how to grab those
sleeves.
They not a control your ass in a way
they cannot do when you're slippery.
So if you guys go in there mma style and
you're wearing shorts and he's wearing
shorts,
it is a completely different ballgame
and no one wants to admit that I do.
Every time I go wrong.
And again,
I said,
hey man,
if you want to take a college,
oh go ahead.
You can have it.
I don't even know how to defend himself.
That's if you want to win by that to go
ahead and you can,
you can go ahead and seek,
you'll the shit.
Okay.
However you want to do.
Listen,
it's great if you get in a fight with a
dude with a winter coat,
you know like Jimmy Pedro was probably
the last guy in the world.
You didn't want to get in a fight with.
If you have a winter coat,
you know,
Olympic gold medalist,
judo dude's going to fucking drop you on
your head.
That's the word.
But so funny story,
you're talking about Olympic gold medal
judo.
My best friend Eric Boni camp and I,
this is before I start a fight and got
into a street fight down in Colorado
Springs,
Jesus and the guy had his judo jacket
on,
right?
And we were like,
yeah,
whatever.
Fucking we started a fight with them.
This mother Fucker,
I don't know is the Uchi Mata though
with it when they throw you,
this is a couple of those,
holy shit.
He threw my buddy through the fucking
plate glass window.
Oh Shit.
Did the mic drop and walked off and I,
I just had a standard like holy fuck.
Threw him through a plate glass plate
down downtown Colorado Springs,
Colorado.
Like we are in the down in the bar
district fight started.
Not even,
the dude just was like whatever.
My buddy came at him and he just grabbed
me and fucking threw him through the
window and I was like,
you win.
Well,
you know,
one of the things that we're really
early on MMA is there's certain guys,
there's just giant levels of Shit,
right?
Like we're seeing that with Damien Maia,
We saw the Damien Maia fight with Carlos
condit.
There's levels of this Jujitsu and
Damien Maia has got that Hixon gracie
style Jujitsu and it's just perfect.
Technically just perfect.
Everything he does is perfect.
Well,
there's like,
like when Kyra Prezi and first fought in
the UFC,
I remember going,
oh,
okay,
I just haven't seen this level yet.
Right?
Like this motherfucker's tossing people.
He would get that cow breezy in his
early days.
We'll get that over hook.
He would get that over hook and he would
bump you and in launching send you
flying and everybody went flying cargo
through everybody.
He came down Jackson and he threw me,
he throws everybody talk about like a
morale killer.
You get thrown in front of millions of
people.
You're like,
oh fuck.
And he throws you perfect.
Yeah.
You know,
he is a gene labelle gokarn conviction.
it's like that whole,
uh,
that whole fucking lineage of Jew of
judo is very strong.
That highest on grappling.
That's very,
very strong lineage of judo.
They have strong judo mat and you know,
and that's where Ronda came from.
She spent a lot of her time there as
well under judo,
judo,
gene judo.
Jeans is like always at our fights.
You know,
is she coming back?
You've got to talk to her brother.
I'm talking to her.
I haven't either.
I don't,
I don't have the drive time.
Rhonda.
I always feel weird like when someone
loses a fight,
like if I reach out to them,
I just always feel weird,
you know?
I always feel like I don't want to,
if I want to,
I want,
if I see someone put y'all four to one
on you buddy,
come on evenings the one bro.
Keep your motherfucking game.
My brother.
Yeah,
but the eight tobacco and smoke weed
probably really close.
This one's done.
Gone in like levels of uh,
like,
you know,
you see levels of everything in sport
and I think that's one of the things
you're showing,
man.
I think you're showing a level of
kickboxing.
There's a very fucking,
when you,
you're hitting those kinds of
combinations.
Now I believe in my wrestling.
I think that's the big key in the coat.
A fight.
And in the rick story fight,
you took both those guys down and I
think they were probably like,
what?
Yeah,
what the fuck.
But I mean,
I just,
the competence in my takedown defense is
allowing me to really open up and
believing in myself is really,
like I said,
when I reinvented myself,
you know,
I just started like,
when someone comes into the gym,
I'm fucking you up.
Right?
You come down Jackson,
I'm beating your motherfucking ass.
Like I understand.
So it's just accept the fact you're not
sparring.
Yeah.
Anymore.
Back in the day when you come in,
you come in and we do mma rounds,
I'm fucking you up.
Right?
Yeah.
And uh,
I see it like somehow figured out how do
I translate that into fight night
because so many emotions,
this last fight I was the worst I've
ever felt in my whole life.
You know,
I talked about that with Megan after the
fight.
I had the worst headache and was looking
Jimmy really sick all day before this
last fight.
And you,
you know,
Greg Jackson's like,
cowboy,
this is what you train for every day.
This has to be somebody on your worst
is,
is what you had to be prepared for it,
you know,
and Ah,
fuck.
It was just warming up.
I didn't feel it.
It wasn't until we started walking out
that I was like,
fucking Kelvin this,
find the mother fucking gear.
Let's go.
You know,
and had just had to get it this,
I think there's,
uh,
there's a legit question that I asked
you in the last podcast.
I said,
um,
Div,
you ever talked to a mental coach?
You ever work with a mental coach?
And you're like,
fuck no,
I just go out there and kick some ass.
He blows it.
He buzzy and kicking ass it.
Um,
which I think is very admirable and it's
fun,
but I think you're,
you're at this,
this,
there's this,
there's this crust of the elite of the
elite right now,
and you're at that crust.
And I think in that,
that top echelon,
when you get up there with the best of
the best,
I don't think there's any room for
potential.
I think it all should be played out.
You should,
you should have realized your potential
as much as possible by the time you got
there.
And I think a factor in that is mindset.
And I don't think it's just being tough
and going out there and kicking ass
because you've already got that down to
a science.
That's you.
I think there are some strategies and
there,
there are also some tools that you can
use in terms of mental management that
keep you in the proper channels and
don't allow your mind to wander so you
don't have to bring your mind back.
Yeah.
And say,
ah,
I don't think about that.
Let's just,
we're here for,
this is what we came for.
You don't need that pep talk.
Okay.
Because you never go down that bad
channel.
You're always staying in these positive
channels.
And the thoughts come in like they do
with anybody.
Like when I meditate,
when I get in a tank,
people think you just go in there and
use zen out.
No,
I start thinking about stupid shit.
I thought I started thinking about God,
I gotta clean my fucking office.
I'm such a Slob.
You know,
like,
uh,
a little things.
You start thinking dumb shit and put it
down and take them back in and uh,
and mental coat.
I'm going to connect you to vinny
shoreman.
Vinny shoreman is the guy that works
with Joe Schilling.
He works with,
uh,
Ian Mccall.
I've done two sessions with him.
He's a hypnotist.
Okay.
These all total,
he's also a Moitai commentator and a
coach and he knows his shit,
especially when it comes to striking and
I think you would get along with him
just because of that.
Right?
But he's got some really,
I've done two podcasts with him too.
You can listen to the podcast he's got,
he makes some real legitimate points.
So when it comes to understanding how
the mind works,
the tricks you can play on you and how
bad decisions from the past can fuck
with you in,
in terms of like bad things sort of
define you and you've got to figure out
a way to alleviate yourself from an,
he responds to my meeting with him
before or after the BMT trip before,
before we got to get ready,
get ready,
get ready.
When those astronauts go into space,
Bro,
they fucking,
they don't just do I apres the Sharman.
He's the one who's going to put on the
whole thing.
He plays the music,
he plays these South American
[inaudible] that were recorded by him in
the jungle.
It goes deep.
Fuck.
But what I think,
I think you know,
and I think you're already coaching
yourself by this,
like reinventing yourself,
right?
Right.
Reevaluating your diet,
starting to add supplementation,
taking care of yourself better,
approaching things in a more
professional way,
cutting out the sparring,
working entirely on drilling,
and you were seeing all these results.
Choosing to go to one 70 and be
healthier when you're fighting,
you're seeing all these results.
All of these results are like this.
Gravitation towards improvement and
advancement.
And I think that there's a thing that
men have and I'm guilty of it.
We all are,
well,
we don't want help.
That's why women rise.
Like men don't want direction.
I know where I'm gone.
Don't worry about it.
I mean,
it's classic.
My wife does it all the time and I know
where I'm going sometimes.
I'm not even exactly sure,
sure.
But what I know is I don't want to hear
her tell me where I'm going because if I
was just driving on my own,
I'd figure it out.
Like it would be no problem.
But when someone doesn't think you're
fee,
it's like men have a real issue with um,
with being coached on things that could
be potentially thought of his
weaknesses.
Sure.
Like men don't want to go to like a
couple's counseling and have some other
dude tell,
tell you how to communicate better with
your woman or your man,
you know,
whatever your,
your man,
I can't guys go to cal can't go down
that path.
That's what it was like.
I got a peek and I drank too much
American house.
Go ahead cause I'm glad you left.
I don't know what the fuck I was saying.
I was going,
I was killing out about something
completely preposterous.
What was I saying?
Oh,
we have a men have a do have a problem.
Um,
a lot of us do with,
I'm thinking that you are miss your
mistakes.
You are your fault and you are your
weaknesses.
So they,
they,
they get branded into your system and
once he seems get brandon into your
system,
they're really difficult to shake cause
you sort of define yourself not by the
lessons you've learned from those
experiences.
And uh,
you being this conscious entity that is
existing right now,
not in a state of mistakes and have
errors but of life.
You're living right now with information
based on your past and you can go
forward from that and be like really
positive and like go,
wow,
I'm glad I went through all those awful
things cause I know that I could be a
real twat or I could be really retarded
or it could be really foolish or
impulsive and I could mess my whole life
up.
But I am this guy right now.
If you don't log,
learn that,
then you can go through this life going,
hey,
I don't give a fuck.
This is me,
this is who I am and I don't want to,
I don't want to any coaching,
oh I don't want any advice.
But there's a bunch of other people that
have gone through similar experiences
and you can call them coaches or just
call them human beings with information.
And there's people that have gone
through a bunch of experiences that are
real similar to the ones that you're
going to go through or I'm going to go
through.
And these people were talking about
learning from other men that like
learning shit about like weaknesses,
but like emotions and about like,
uh,
fears and,
and it just your own mortality,
you know,
all those things are real issues.
Men Don't like learn them from other
men.
So you're like,
I don't need that shit.
You know what I'm talking about?
And I was talking about you got to get
back in the back,
bro.
You took the lead.
I can only reset where he sat and,
and other news.
Yesterday I outfitted for a new movie.
I'm doing western.
You're doing a western.
How weird.
It's actually not a movie.
It's a netflix series.
I've got six episodes.
Holy Shit.
Cool.
Right?
That's gigantic.
I got to do cowboy shit.
What is it?
It's a,
it's called godless.
It's,
uh,
it's,
I'm part of a gang,
the train robbery gang.
Holy Shit.
And I'm fucking pumped,
man.
I'm excited.
Wow.
That's amazing.
And how I was starting not on the 12th
have you ever acted before?
Well,
I did the always sunny in Philadelphia,
but I played me,
here's what I think.
I think you're going to kill it right
out of the box and we're going to show
the world how fucking easy acting as
God.
Damn.
People think that shit is hard and I'm
not,
I'm not a good actor,
by the way.
I should just say that right off the
bat.
But I know a lot of people can go right
from other shit and become actors.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm more excited about fucking shooting
guns and riding horses and shit.
I bet you are.
He should be.
That's real.
Yeah.
I mean,
yeah.
You don't want him to get too pumped up,
up fake shit.
It's going to be do some fake shit.
Oh Dude.
You get to wear makeup outside of his
beard.
They tell me,
they tell me,
Kevin,
we need you to grow your beard,
all your hair out.
And I said,
well,
this is a little bit of a problem on the
top here,
but uh,
I'll try.
I'll go ahead and give them,
why you to grow your hair long and tell
me to get me a wig.
Like Kevin Costner was.
They said Wiki.
I said,
wigs are uncomfortable that they want to
a grunge.
Look out in this at hard.
I can do grunge.
Can't you just be a,
a cowboy with a shaved head?
Did they have buzz cuts back then?
I mean,
where would you buzz your head?
You'd shave it all and you'd let it grow
back.
Little Buck knife,
not one of them.
Nice straight razors.
You use those a western deep,
tight places that people go to all her
Walworth,
raping and pillaging across the
countryside.
You can't fire lit mere cut.
That's what they would do.
And they would,
uh,
sharpen it with a strop sharpen with
that leather thing.
Never understood that,
oh fuck this lab leather.
Sharpen a razor blade.
Do you understand?
I do not.
I,
I buy a new razor every time.
Here's a rabbit hole that I've gone down
recently.
I've been going on these instagram pages
of custom knife makers.
Who these dudes,
are you the person that likes all those?
Is that why keep coming up on my,
uh,
probably my like feet.
I like that shit.
Who likes to these big juicy but girls
and all these fucking nights.
This guy,
this guy,
these guys there.
Well,
I'm sure there's some girls out there
too,
but I've only followed guys that are
there.
They have their own forging facilities
and they made the shoes and everything
after I seen it.
They're clanging the fucking metal and
putting in the fire and making handmade
knives and shit.
Dude,
I'm obsessed with this.
I've,
you forced me to creep just because
they're on the,
on the whatever,
the whatever that microscope.
Yeah.
What does that fucking thing?
A search search search page.
It might be because we follow each other
and the,
I'm going to those sites all the time.
We've been fascinated by it.
Man.
I don't know what my original point was.
It's the cool shit.
It's a lot of people making cool shit
out there,
but that's the rabbit hole.
I've gone down this whole idea that
someone is good at making that and how
good you are speaking to people's souls.
See,
but this is easy.
This is just talk.
No,
it's not though.
It's not easy.
What you do is not easy.
You could not,
I couldn't just go get somebody off the
street,
put them here and be like,
all right,
I need you to interview somebody for
three to five hours and keep it
entertaining and have no dead time and
know what the fuck you're talking about.
See,
that's where you're wrong.
I don't not know what the fuck I'm
talking about.
What I'm talking about,
what you're getting into your dmt speech
was he had me,
you had me wrapping my arm rate for a
main line drag,
so I'm ready for it given that one
before.
I know that one real good.
It's like asking you to throw your and
how it could be hammered.
Does that piss you off when you're at
the shows?
I've been to a lot of your shows and
everyone's always like,
do you do,
when you ask people,
what do you want to type in there?
I was like,
dude,
you're like fuck you dude.
I do
that.
So that's,
I just tell them,
go on youtube.
Yeah,
go on Youtube.
I can't talk about any more and there's
nothing funny I could say about it
either and it's definitely not something
you'd see in front of a giant crowd of
people where they're going to
understand.
I try to explain Doug's stand old paddle
whole bit once cause I got him high on
DMT and blew his mind and he went and
did a whole bit about,
about me and him doing dmt in my house.
I thought he was dead.
He was moaning and foaming like
legitimately foaming at the mouth.
He was aligned down,
gone for 15 minutes.
No,
it was a solid three of moaning with a
point where I'm going,
oh boy.
He was,
maybe he was just purging.
Well I just started thinking,
what did I do?
Like I made doug do what I do,
right.
So I'm thinking,
Hey,
he'll be fine.
That's why I'm not doing what you do.
You say three giant hits,
I'm going to do what you want and a
half.
Here's my point.
You fucking healthy.
Doug.
Stan hope smokes two packs of cigarettes
a day.
He gets up,
starts drinking,
stops when he falls asleep.
So now it matters of your,
your physical,
well,
I just think what was going on and I
wasn't bad for him.
He came back,
he was fine.
It's a natural drug that is in the human
body.
You don't overdose from it.
No one's ever died from smoking.
DMT done dmt.
I mean when a lot,
how can we,
how can we have there now that for your
pumps,
we don't have a very big audience of
people that can pull it.
They're like,
yeah,
there's,
you've definitely oded on lsd or on
alcohol.
This is what I think without being
irresponsible.
I think that if you have any
psychological issues,
you probably shouldn't do anything that
perturbs your,
your,
your state,
your stuff.
So I should not do it.
I'm fucking crazy batshit crazy.
But I think that saying that,
just saying that getting out of the way,
it could benefit a whole lot of people.
There's a whole lot of people that could
benefit from it.
That's what I'm saying.
All right.
But I think just for me,
I'm going in as a way to do it through
Kundalini Yoga.
Apparently you do,
you know,
Denny,
uh,
proper coast.
He's one a 80 bravo's black belts,
maybe seen him with me a bunch of times.
He works for the UFC sometimes.
He,
um,
uh,
Kinda does what Eddie used to do where
he recognizes what they do is like,
they're filming a certain positions.
Like when Damien Maia finished Carlos
Condit,
right?
Like,
we need to be marked Ella grotto when
telegraph tase out,
um,
d uh,
denny will fill in the place.
So he understands the transitions.
So he'll pull that clip up for the
replays.
And,
um,
denny is a,
a big proponent of Kundalini Yoga and
he's also,
he's done dmt.
And when he does Quinn Delaney,
he can achieve those states.
How?
I don't know,
I don't understand.
Kundolini I've never done it,
but it's a fungus.
Coon Dalene Eenie Rimini is a series of
exercises and meditations and yoga that
are widely purported to achieve
psychedelic states.
There's other ways to do it to this
hollow holotropic breathing.
There's like a psychedelic breathing
method that you can do that can see DMT
is produced the human body.
So you just got to get your body to make
it.
And so there's this sense that somehow
there's,
there's ways that people have figured
out where you can stimulate your body's
production of his natural psychedelic
chemical.
So not just through taking it
exogenously like smoking it or,
or drinking it when you're taken Iowasca
but to make your home body produce it.
And the,
and the reason behind it is for near
death experience.
Right.
Does that make you feel okay?
I don't know.
What's the reason behind it?
I feel like I've experienced what you're
talking about.
When I almost died,
everything I was seeing,
the most pain I've ever been in.
I tipped the Garney over,
fucking threw a ball,
his blood,
and they put me back and then all of a
sudden it's like overwhelming film
feeling just overtook me.
And everything was just okay.
Like I was okay to die.
It was craziest feeling I've ever had.
Like everything was,
I had neck,
no,
no fear and I had no worries in the
world.
Everything.
It was just like,
okay,
like everything was just like a giant
ease.
It lifted off me.
I've heard of that before.
I haven't had that experience but I've
heard that before.
Well don't try and die.
I have a friend almost died in a car
accident and she said the same thing.
She said right after the car hit and she
got smashed by this,
this car slamming it like take got t
boned,
she flew across the other side of the
car.
It's smashed into her friend and there
was this immediate like feeling of
peace.
Okay,
so media is feeling of like everything's
going to be all right in this weird love
sensation.
I didn't see any geographic shapes
telling me,
well you cause you were knocking on the
door so then you kind of go and sneak
out and get it event.
Well that's what the worry is that when
you're doing dmt,
what you're seeing is the afterlife.
And you're seeing that there is some
place that the soul goes and that the
soul is not just a concept that's based
in mysticism and lies and fantasies,
myths and lies.
Oh,
there's a lot of people look at things
that you can't prove.
Absolutely.
It's right.
Yeah.
That's the big word,
right?
Like if you look at something like a
soul,
like you can't prove it.
You're right.
You can't prove it.
Definitely we all agree on that.
But let's examine what the fuck it means
to be a person.
We don't know what it,
what it means to be conscious.
There's all these ways we can define it
and talk about it where it makes sense,
but it does not make sense that you are
looking through your eyes and live in
the life of Donald's Roney and I'm
looking through my eyes and I'm living
the life of Joe Rogan and we've become
pals and we have stories.
We talk and you say things with your
mouth and icon to understand what you're
saying.
And I say things and I hope you
understand what I'm saying.
And we,
we laugh,
we have a good time.
And drink a few budweiser.
It's like this is a fucking bizarre
state to be clinging to a circular ball
like some gigantic,
huge pack of water and dirt and rock
that's hurling through infinity with
scis seven others.
It's so strange.
It's just strange.
It can be life.
Is waste stranger or as strange as
anything you're going to experience on
DMT.
We just used to live.
I like life.
I like life to life
is awesome.
So what,
uh,
let's talk about space.
Let's go there.
Let's do it.
What do you,
what,
what the fuck is out there man?
I mean everything.
So I talked to Bj Penn.
He thinks the world is flying.
I understand this.
How would this crazy,
is that right?
He believes the world is flat and that
when you take off in an airplane,
you just do like a big,
you don't go around the world.
You just kind of do like a boom.
Here's the thing.
Why?
Why would anybody lie about that?
I where's the,
where's the money in line about the
earth being flat?
It's so stupid.
So stupid.
He thinks Columbia Columbus might've
been onto something.
Listen man,
there's a bunch of people making youtube
videos.
Okay.
And these youtube videos confused the
fuck out of people that don't understand
physics like you or me.
I don't understand physics or night
comes down to when you sail around the
world.
Yeah.
You go around the world,
go round little fucking world fall gps.
Yeah,
follow the math.
You're just kind of,
what do you just hit a wall?
Like every image shown by NASA is a
composite of that's exactly actually
right.
So shut the fuck up.
Look that you can go into space station.
You cuts,
you can see it.
There's a video.
Has everybody that's been this space
station lying.
Every Russian,
every American,
they're all a bunch of liars.
And you baby girl Illuminati.
You're not stupid.
That is to think that everyone has been
faking every image of the earth being
round.
Oh and coincidentally the earth is the
only flat thing we've ever found.
The fucking universe.
Cause all the moons,
all the planets,
Jupiter,
all that shit's round as fuck.
What's that?
These are tree stumps by the way.
According to the flat earth theory,
every giant rock were being trolled.
Dude,
this is not real.
This is,
that's a trees down.
How big would that treat is a,
an elaborate four chan host.
There's slowly trolling America.
Oh,
like Pandora size tree does definitely
make sense,
right?
Wow,
that's legit.
And what happened to it?
I got knock,
knock.
I know about the dinosaurs.
Don't think the reality,
the reality of earth and space is crazy
enough.
You dump cunts,
you don't have to fake conspiracies.
The reality of this whole thing is so
fucking Uber Bizarre.
We're in a giant ball that's floating in
the sky.
Above us is something a quarter.
The size of us,
it's floating in the sky and it doesn't
even fucking spin and you need it there
and it regulates the tides and if it was
any further or any closer,
everybody we'd be dead.
That's crazy.
That itself is fucking crazy.
You don't have to pretend you're seeing
trees.
You don't have to pretend the earth is
flat.
You fucking retards.
That doesn't have any faith comes in
like they're saying,
how can all of these things fall?
How can all these things they don't
know.
Jamie,
explain.
I can I,
I took physics like in high school a
little bit in college and one Eddie was
going on rant.
It was,
I
couldn't remember all the things to say
it,
so it wasn't going to break out physics
laws and whatnot to break down each
step.
But if you do physics experiments in
class,
you will easily see all of these steps
and you,
and it blows your mind.
You're like,
oh my God,
it's,
it's amazing how this works.
There's math that's been done over
hundreds of years that full
on all these people that have been
studying this stuff for centuries and
building upon all of the knowledge of
the people before them.
Like when,
when a guy like,
here's a perfect example,
you could relate to martial arts.
Well,
we're,
we're seeing today when you see guys
like yourself or guys like Damien Maia
or guys like wonder boy or any of the
top fighters today are mighty mouse.
You're seeing the highest expression of
martial arts that has ever existed in
the world.
It is a fact.
It's an undeniable fact.
Anybody that tells me that people from
the past were better.
You don't know what the fuck you're
talking about.
There's,
there's no chance in hell.
This is an undeniable fact,
that objective fact,
okay,
well this didn't happen immediately.
It didn't happen because one guy figured
out how to fight.
Like this is one guy in Brooklyn that
has his fucking street fight in class.
It's got this deadly touch of death that
he could do to people and all this other
things you've been to is all bullshit.
They think that chokes work,
chokes don't work.
They don't work on me.
When he chokes don't work,
then you go back to your friend.
Chokes don't work.
The earth is flat.
It's flat.
Are you sure it's flat?
It's fucking bananas.
To think that someone is going to be
able to figure if seeking,
manipulate the league minds so easy.
It's not even the weak minds is the
uninformed mind busy and that watch
youtube videos,
that's what it is.
It's not even that you're weak because a
lot of times when people speak well,
so what they says Lizard people have you
seen,
have you seen that as shit?
Right.
What the fuck is that?
It's all bullshit.
All Bullshit.
These are people that are aliens,
but they,
have you seen the youtube videos?
Have you seen?
I've seen plenty of them,
but that was one of the David Eick
things,
right?
He believed that all of the elites were
reptilians grab tea and that's what it
is.
And he defend that your reptilian and
even,
and even a,
if you defend that you are obtaining
even,
uh,
are you putting it up?
Oh yeah.
Do you see that said he is investigating
a possible extra terrestrial signal from
deep space.
Yeah.
They said this is nuts.
The contact.
Yeah.
Literally.
Literally she's in it too.
Dot.
Movie was dope as fuck.
Yeah.
Well that's the image they're trying to,
but this is a real,
a steady signal that they're
investigating.
It is amazing,
man.
That movie contact was fucking bad ass,
by the way.
I loved that movie.
I mean there has to be,
there has to be something outside of our
realm there.
He's not just something,
here's how infinity is best explained
his.
This is the best definition that I,
I've read.
Not only is the universe infinite,
but what that means is if you exist,
everything that has ever happened on
this earth in the exact same order,
every pebble falling,
the same crevice over and over again.
I mean with no variation at all is not
just happened before.
Every word I've said,
including that pause has taken place in
exactly the same way.
Not just once,
but an infinite number of times where
there is no end.
Why does,
that's what real infinity is.
So we can understand infinity because
we're our brains.
Like if you tell someone,
hey,
we drank six budweisers,
man,
you guys must have got fucked up.
That makes sense.
You get those numbers right.
Do you really understand like when
someone says 6,000
miles,
you go,
okay,
all right,
well the United States is how many
thousand miles you've got to go,
how many thousand miles past that it
gets a little blurry,
right?
Yeah.
And then you go,
all of the moon is 250,000
miles away.
Go,
what?
How far is that?
And you start thinking,
well,
the moon is a,
you know,
how far is the sun?
And that's a million.
Well,
this,
they found this fucking planet.
It's earthlike and it's four light years
away.
What's that?
What's four light years?
How fast is light go?
I'm lost,
right?
30 to a hundred feet a second.
Right?
So we'll,
we have his senses and what we have is
an understanding of our environment
that's immediate to us because we're
basically monkeys that just a few
thousand years ago were worried about
being eaten by shit.
Right?
So finally we reached the stage where we
don't have to worry too much about being
eaten by Shit,
which is why shark videos are so awesome
to us.
Right.
Well,
so now you're on evolution.
This is a,
this is what I'm just saying.
This is a recent state.
What we're trying to understand things
past our immediate area of things that
are going to eat us.
So we don't really have the capacity or
the need,
or we'd never had the need before to try
to understand what the fuck 250 million
miles is,
or 250,000
miles or four light years.
It's too,
it's too confusing to us.
It's hard for us to grasp.
So when someone starts talking about
infinity,
it's impossible to grasp because what
his affinity means is there's no end it
never,
ever,
ever ends.
So everything on this earth that's ever
happened,
like in the universe,
not only is there a cowboy that never
found that rec center and never got into
fighting,
but there's infinite varieties of all
the different lives of cowboy with every
single different step you took and
infinite numbers of each one of those
individual choices with every single
word,
every single phrase,
every single thought,
all in the exact same order taking place
an infinite number of times.
I need dmt to understand this.
You have kid that's not even going to
work.
I don't understand it.
I'm saying I don't understand it because
it's impossible to understand.
The universe has no end.
If the universe has,
this is the,
the main mindblower of the universe
inside every galaxy.
You look up there,
there's hundreds of millions gallon
inside every galaxy is a supermassive
black hole.
That's one half of 1% of the mass.
The galaxy scientists believe it is
entirely possible that you go through
that black hole and you hit
an infinite number of other universes.
That's each one of those is a new
universe.
Like every black hall you go into,
it is a new universe.
And that universe,
there's hundreds of billions of
galaxies.
Each one has a black hole in the center
of it.
Each one of those takes you to another
universe of hundreds of millions and
billions of galaxies,
and each one of them as a black hole.
And it goes on and on and on and on and
on,
and there's no end.
So this infinite universe that we see is
one of infinite universes that we can't
even possibly understand.
There's no way.
There's no end to any of it,
not.
So from this podcast,
we're going to go to the Church of
scientology and learn the truth for $500
we need to know,
I need to put you to an e meter for only
$500 and vermilion I'll,
I'll give you the secret.
Hmm,
right?
Yeah.
You have to blow someone.
Oh,
sorry to hear it again.
And I hate your tobacco.
How much worse is blowing a guy and then
eat and tobacco as well.
How many light years?
Who's a light here?
What are we talking here?
What was his piss?
Now they're talking about blowing man.
Pull that plug out.
There's some fat guy with a gun has been
jealousy you the whole time.
Very upset.
It's ties flopping around.
He's running down the office right now
listening to this.
Have you heard serone but sponsoring
this guy.
Dammit.
They're talking about sucking dicks and
kicking ass in buzzy and kicking ass.
We did talk about that one line where
it's like,
wait,
what?
Wait,
I saw a dude got that tattooed on his
arm sucking Dick and kicking ass.
Yes he did.
It was on instagram.
You can find it.
He sent it to Wheeler Walker Wheeler.
Probably put it on his,
uh,
his instagram wheeler is a different
guy.
It knee will use a different guy before
he was wheeler.
Yeah.
I know.
I know the real him.
I don't,
I don't understand the real,
what do you mean the real hand?
See Eating Pussy Sucking Dick and
kicking ass and in the American colors,
well,
it's not that much of a secret so I can
talk about it.
But Wheeler Walker Jr is a guy named Ben
Hoffman who's a,
he's a comedian from Kentucky.
All right.
He created Wheeler Walker Jr.
Am I supposed to talk about this?
Why not?
It's opts out [inaudible] he knows it
his show and he's been,
but he just rides it into the rocks like
he comes on the podcast is wheeler
Walker keeps the sunglasses.
Eyes get the full beard.
But he's also been on the podcast.
Has Ben Hoffman so when he'd walk or is
he just talking reckless?
He's a wild man.
He's just,
he's saying what he really believes when
it comes to country music because he
really is an absolute country music fan.
What does this fuck is this shit,
man,
when we hear this reboot it,
instagram is weird like that right here
it goes.
Let's hear what he said.
Fuck is this shit man.
Snapchat without the Dicks dumbs down
dude.
And he didn't dicks.
It's funny.
It's just ridiculous and funny man.
I'm a huge fan of what he's doing.
He's uh,
he's wild Bro.
Wow.
See like corporate America would have
never created that and that's how he
exists.
He exists because he came up with this
on his own and the country music world
is freaking the fuck out.
Freaking the fuck is this guy guy's
selling out arenas.
I mean Wheeler Walker Jr since he's been
on our podcast.
I was like,
that was just when he was starting to
catch on.
Like when,
when he came on the podcast,
he was already like getting some
momentum.
It was just starting to catch on and
since then the more of these videos
could share it online.
The more people start laughing their
asses off and they come to his shows are
fucking huge giant places and he's
killing it.
You're plugging them huge again.
They didn't know it was coming,
man.
They didn't know it was coming.
And you know why they didn't know?
Because they're trying to make a Luke
Bryan.
No disrespect Luca,
who?
You're a great guy.
Cameron Hanes,
his friend was too.
I'm not a,
I'm hitting it shouldn't say Luke Bryan
because I actually liked some of his
songs.
Let me think of a guy who was like,
who's this shitty?
Like,
here's one that Wheeler Walker always
talks about the Florida Georgia line.
Okay.
I don't know anything about those guys.
What do you know you gotta do you know
them?
I know them.
Okay,
let's just walk this.
Just drop it.
If you,
are you friends with those dudes?
I don't know about friends.
They wouldn't,
they wouldn't call me and wish me happy
birthday.
That's you're asking Wheeler Walker
calls it rap music for people who are
scared of black folks.
Oh Wow.
He was talking about the throwing their
hands up.
They seem like fine folks.
They seem like great guys,
but what he's talking about on stage and
when he's doing well,
wheeler's doing,
it's something that no corporate entity
or no pr firm would ever allow,
ever allow.
But look how God damn popular it is
because people like crazy.
They like crazy.
Do you know who do you know who a riff
Raff is?
No tear wrapper.
Go ahead,
pull it sounds like a rapper.
He is a white rapper and he,
his raps are like sitting with Joe
Drinking Bud fucking bitch is kicking
ass.
That's like his wrestler.
It's the last seminar.
But I mean he's,
you talk about it sells out millions
guys crazy though.
Crazy.
He made these,
he made his,
his,
his uh,
thing off rock are um,
Geez,
the gents on vh one,
I think it was,
what was his teeth?
Look at him.
He's,
he's out of control.
So I did a monster sign.
He sponsored my monster.
So I did a monster signing with this guy
and he is who was two and a half hours
late and it's going to b e t tattooed on
his neck.
TV.
MTV Bet as well.
Yeah,
he's a,
he was white.
He tell him Kenya,
Kenya,
he's out of control.
So this is the saying only does fbt
right there and just say,
yeah,
I talked about the same thing.
He's,
he's,
he's outlandish man.
Told him my Jordans is,
is,
is one of his songs.
Tip Toeing in my Jordan's.
Yeah,
people hit,
they want something outside the norm and
the a good percentage of the people that
are listening to this right now are
stuck living some life where you have to
pretend all day long that you don't
think certain things.
I liked the way he's dressed.
He's,
he's uh,
he's wild man.
Did you ever Sag your pants like that?
No.
Good for,
you know,
my Dick is big enough to hold his hands
up.
God bless you.
Saggy pants.
It's one of the things that frustrates
me the most about this youth culture.
I would have thought that with the UFC
skinny,
skinny and sagging is a bad combo.
That's a bad combo.
That's confused.
It is.
If that's confused,
but it's the new trend.
I mean everyone wants to be in the
train.
So whatever it is,
it is,
what the fuck is.
Why is sagging jeans,
why is it,
what is that?
It's all comes from prison,
right?
Cause they didn't give her a men of
prison,
so I have no fucking idea.
I think the idea was that you couldn't
get a belt because you would choke
yourself to death.
You can hang yourself with a belt so
that your everyone's pants work sort of
sagging.
So it made you look like you were some
sort of a criminal type character if you
wanted around with no belt on.
Like as if you're pretending that you're
out there in prison.
What your Jordan's on and pretending.
I don't know your underwear hanging out.
I'm a,
I'm a big fan of my jeans where they
fit.
But other gay guys that were in prison
or God's used to fuck guys in prison
that had been interviewed said that that
was how guys would let you know they
were ready to be taken.
They'd have their pants halfway down and
that was,
that was the international sign for take
the booty.
Did you ever see that dude on like one
of those prison shows that called
himself the booty bandit?
No.
Ever seen that guy?
Oh my God.
I'm gonna introduce the band world will
get pulled from youtube if we play this
right.
Well,
yeah,
most likely that is a world of
copyrights today.
Rightly so.
I mean,
they did find the booty bandit.
Anyway,
this fucking dude was on uh,
one of those shows like tlc or something
like that to go into prison and he would
talk about all the different guys.
He fucked.
And that booty was basically like
currency.
Yeah,
that was,
that's the dude.
You've got to listen to this.
I don't give a fuck who he is.
Currency.
Yeah.
You gotta you got this is you got to
listen to what this guy talks about.
Give,
give me some volume.
Young Jamie,
what's manner we're being invaded by the
government.
Budweiser's hack this show did turn it
around enough.
They're talking about [inaudible] now
they're talking about moody is current.
What time suck a dick downtown booties
currency.
No sound on this or see if one of the
other videos play sound weird.
It's the system pump.
Get on that list.
Probably because Jamie's been drooling
over cm punk videos.
We go back to the one you in a zine.
Cm punk was a cm.
Paul was on the side.
Their suggestion there.
Joe Rogan on cm punk.
That's hilarious.
What did you say?
Nothing good.
Oh really?
Nothing bad.
I don't know anything.
No one knows anything.
That's the thing.
I mean they want me to say thing.
Here he is a booty bandit
speaks on it.
This isn't working.
Not,
this is not the same video.
Go to the one.
So we just figured out how to get it to
talk.
Here he goes,
you got two things playing.
Jamie told us about the place and
importance.
That booty.
Somebody put a laugh track.
Oh,
oh.
What?
They put a laugh track on it.
Here's the raw version of it.
It doesn't have sound.
It was just talking about fucking guys
in prison.
It for currency.
Oh Wow.
Oh,
the cm punk thing.
I didn't say anything bad about him.
We,
he can't say anything about it.
I'm like,
do you want me to hype it up?
And like,
it's very interesting.
He did the right thing.
He went to a real good camp.
He uh,
he didn't fight for two whole years.
He'd just been training.
You would have to apparently smokers
there.
There's no way you could learn a decade
of skills in three months.
No.
And that kid he's fighting is good.
The kids fight,
fighting can scrap.
I liked the way it took that dude's
back.
I liked the way he choked him out and
showed real good technique.
He knows how to fight.
Like it's not going to be an easy fight.
No.
I mean in every Samsung it's to fight in
the UFC.
I'm Phil.
Phil.
All right.
Fair enough to his name.
Right.
He's going to be filled.
Brooks.
When he fights,
I think I'm pretty sure they're coming
out of the punk.
Are they really saying cm punk?
Why not?
Because I don't know.
Well they must've made a deal with the
wwe so they could use brock lesnar.
She owns everything.
Talk about Illuminati,
Illuminati,
Illuminati.
They own your likeness for life.
Is that necessary?
I don't think so.
I think when I'm 80 I should be able to
get that back.
Is there another sport that owns your
likeness?
Tell on your legs or life.
Cm punk.
Say they got him a zero.
Zero.
Let's do the only two or no,
but the kids good.
How was he in the UFC?
At and out because just for this fight,
that's how he's in there.
Well that's the wire they get.
You're right.
It's not fair.
But it is because it doesn't matter.
It's not like he's taking a fight away
from somebody.
No.
We got to see somebody.
Look,
if,
if the UFC wants to maximize 85,
one 70.
And that's just a mistake on who's part.
Somebody wrote it in there.
They fuck up all the time.
Somebody's,
you know,
these kids are barely paying attention.
And Sam Hog in the shot does not look
like a wwe wrestler.
No.
Well,
he's natural.
I mean,
that's part of his,
uh,
his whole,
yeah,
well he's always been natural.
Even if you see him,
wwe,
he talked about him and I tagged that.
He's a straight edge,
straight edge.
No booze ever.
No nothing.
No Pot,
no nothing.
No steroids has this take vitamins.
We've had his dog's name is Larry.
We've talked about this.
Yeah.
Good luck with all that dude cause that
live in life sober.
I'm sure you're a great guy to hang
around with.
Oh,
I'm sure the stories and the fun that
come out of unreal.
Definitely not a control freak.
Definitely not like super weird about
like certain subjects.
The fuck out of here.
Huh?
I'm with you man.
We,
we,
we've found alcohol and you know,
losing jags for reason.
Hmm.
Yeah.
How dare you pretend you're smarter than
all the people before you that have
learned how fun it is to party.
It's the finger pointers,
the finger point or you get mad at you,
but they're the same ones drinking it in
their basement by themselves so they
wish some of them don't.
Some of them just keep it,
keep it rigid forever and then one they.
Dot.
Yeah.
I think there's a lot of people that
just,
they cling on to whatever ridiculous
notions they have of this life and they
get some sort of happiness in having
control.
You know,
there's certain,
certain sort of happiness in their
routine,
you know,
like,
uh,
you know some people who only eat,
I only eat for performance.
I don't really care about the taste.
What does that fuck off?
Fuck all the way out.
All the way off.
Like what do you mean you're a Vegan?
What in the fuck are you talking about?
Oh,
some people don't want anybody to die.
Olympic,
um,
power lifter.
Who's a Vegan?
He's a Vegan.
That's pretty impressed.
I just want well,
test that motherfucker.
Well,
well the last two years he's a Vegan.
Oh okay.
So it's still,
it's still very impressive.
He's still can compete and he feels are
there any ever has,
it's amazing.
No,
it's not amazing.
It's,
it's bullshit.
You need fucking medium juicy blood
dripping out stake.
That's how I feel.
But I'm not that dude.
I don't think anybody should tell me
that I can't eat meat and I don't think
I should be able to tell anybody that
they have to eat meat.
I think if you're as dude that has it in
your head that you don't want an animal
to die cause you,
you sync up with all these animals and
you feel like if I can get through this
life without an animal dying on my
behalf,
that's better in this day and age.
Sure.
But let's take away everything and say,
you are just out there on your own.
You're going to have to eat.
You're going to have to fucking happy.
You can only pick so many fucking
berries.
Oh really?
There's only so many berries that grow
seasonally.
It's not enough.
It's not enough calories.
No,
we are made.
I mean,
the vegans talk about gorillas.
They only eat bananas.
They actually like leaves and shit.
I mean,
you don't get bananas at the zoo.
Here's a girl who would have banana in
the wild.
Now they're eating like bamboo stalks
and shit.
I mean,
regardless,
we're not,
we're not saying we're not.
We're omnivores.
We are made to kill gorillas and eat
them.
No,
I don't think people,
they definitely grill us.
Right?
I mean if,
if it was,
if it was eat a bamboo shoot or a
fucking gorilla,
I'm taking the gorilla down.
But I think the grills anyway,
like I know they eat a lot of monkeys.
Like they call it bushmeat.
Bushmeat is like a real issue in some,
a endangered species because a,
they'll shoot like chimps and shit like
that and they'll eat them.
Yeah.
If it's you not eating,
are you eating a champ?
You're eating a chimp buddy of mine was
in Bolivia for the show meter.
He,
uh,
he hosts,
I chose Steven Rinella and they shot a
monkey and they cooked a monkey and he
ate it.
I heard monkey brains.
Amazing.
I'd do it.
I need to fucking suck.
Die Balls.
Budweiser's I called Dana white enough,
suck the eyeballs go.
Oh Shit.
I can make you laugh.
Oh my God.
This is all pre DMT Hella debt.
That's hilarious.
When I come back and be a whole new man,
yeah,
man,
we have a real hard time eating monkeys.
I'm wouldn't be in there.
Kind of have a hard time eating
anything.
You would need a monkey for sure.
Yeah.
If you fucking cooked up a monkey right
now,
I would eat it.
Okay.
Oh neat.
Just about anything g primitive man,
like would you eat it and neanderthal.
So if we're on the movie alive and my
plane crashed and I had eat some ass,
sometimes I eat asked for fun.
Do you know what I mean?
Is,
I mean it's a different kind of ass,
but yeah,
I'm going to go in.
I hope you don't eat that.
That's the wrong you're doing it.
Are you using a spoon?
No,
no,
no.
That movie's not real.
Listen,
if you are a man and you don't need to
ask,
there's something wrong with you and
your wife.
Yeah,
someone's got it.
It's going to be a dude who says,
I really don't give a fuck and he's
going to come along.
I would literally eat,
I mean,
whatever.
Why not?
You want to kill her and alive.
Let's eat it.
Yeah,
she has.
She's not going to stay alive.
I'm not a Vegan obviously,
but taking the point of Vegans,
I could see what would they're trying to
do is they're trying to not contribute
to any animals dying,
but they're put here to die.
Is that a bad thing to say?
Is that more I wa I don't mean it like
that,
but I mean we have to eat and we are the
top of the food chain.
We definitely at the top of the food
chain,
and there's,
this is where I used to describe it,
there's a war going on between all the
animals on this planet and the wars for
survival and we are so far ahead of the
rest of the people competing the war.
We forgot it to war and we forgot that
we have these prison colonies in our
cities.
We call them zoos.
That's a fucking prison.
College shows you,
Oh the,
we have won the battle of these stupid
fucking country alligators.
And then job
people like me that go swimming and
chase sharks and they get eaten and
they're like,
ha,
one for the low column.
Has anybody ever gone like getting eaten
when they were diving?
It's not common.
It's not very common at all.
Really uncommon right there.
I think it's maybe one,
I don't know.
Maybe ever.
Right?
He's probably an asshole.
Probably cut himself.
Yeah,
probably a cut.
Chumming trying to get close to a shark
like,
oh yeah,
you can do that,
right?
You can do that.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I guess I was chum the water a little
bit.
Bring them in once you have a lot of
chum and up,
some sort of pokey stick.
I don't want that with the work.
I think.
I think if a,
once a shark isn't,
I'm eating you mode.
I think you're getting eaten.
All right.
Let's play a little game.
I got a little game for you.
If you could pick any animal that let's,
let's put you in a concrete room.
[inaudible] I don't care the size and
you know that I could fuck up naked.
You have nothing.
You're a squirrel up new funds or with
clothes you can grow would be here.
That'd be your,
your animal.
That'd be the highest you'd got.
Will fuck a squirrel up with confidence.
Bet The house on me.
Bam.
Squirrel,
a three pound squirrel.
Cominak three pounds is big.
I'm talking about a regular squirrel.
Okay.
One and a half pound score wouldn't have
pounds quarrel,
but seriously,
if you ever seen a one and a half pound
rat running at you,
it'll scare the fuck out.
He's got a cat would be.
Oh,
for sure.
Fight Crime.
Fighting for sure.
Yeah,
just buddies and I did I fuck that dog?
And I'm like,
yeah,
I don't know man.
I think if ag dots coming at you in a
vicious way,
I don't know if you can,
if you could take that,
you know,
especially if it's a good size one.
Like any dog over 70 pounds,
like a German shepherd or something like
that.
Even the 35 pound pitbull.
Oh yeah.
Well 35 pound pit bulls would kill a 70
pound German shepherd.
That's a tricky one because those dogs,
that's a different sort of movie about a
shark.
Would it have to be in the water?
I think he would have to be in the
water.
It had to be in the water.
No water?
No.
Like crocodile?
Yeah.
Not,
no.
No.
Nine pound crocodile who?
Nine pound crocodile.
Matt,
you don't want that.
You didn't know what they want the life,
but I think he was talking,
he would get fucked and pound
rattlesnake and I was 10 pound
rattlesnake.
Yes,
I need to post.
I just posted on my instagram.
We were,
we were,
how long was it about as long as me.
He was me,
Bro.
He reminded,
have you guys ever seen the movie rang?
Go with the rattlesnake that runs the
town.
This mother fucker.
This mother motherfucker sat three feet
off the Brown and was like moving and
dancing like literally three feet off
the ground.
I've never seen anything like it.
He was fucking pissed off.
He's the cowboy cerrone of rattlesnakes.
Yeah.
And even more mad.
I kept throwing him in the head with a
little snake catcher thing.
Oh,
you're trying to catch it with one of
those because we got a little hospital.
There he is right there.
Oh my God.
I broke the rattler so he broke the
radler cause when I grabbed his ass,
fuck fucking Anaconda roll up that up.
That,
uh,
stick trying to get me,
he would like roll crazy shit.
Look at the size of a man.
He was a big boy.
He was pissed the fuck off.
So there's a hospital right down the
street that you take them and they milk
them 500 bucks it give you or taking
gate 500 bucks.
It's good move.
Yeah.
So then they,
they,
you know,
but we have this probably like my eighth
or ninth one I've cut this year.
It was crazy a,
so that's how they get to look at.
I'm staking up.
Wow.
We'll put them in the toolbox.
Oh yeah.
So what happens to the rattle and now he
doesn't ever,
they wrote back every time they,
uh,
ruskin or whatever,
the back,
every one of those levels and each one
of those little levels is how you quote
me.
I don't know.
I just know the bigger and badder they
get,
the more buttons they get like each
year.
Right.
They get a new one.
I wish I had the info for that,
but I just know he was a big bitch.
That's a,
that's an old rattlesnake man.
That's a dude has seen some shit.
Shit.
Yeah.
Uh,
my dog just got bit the other day right
in the nose.
Swell up,
and he looked,
yeah.
Swallow all the way up.
I thought I was gonna.
I was calling the girl telling her,
hey man,
I don't have to put this dog down.
Like,
did you uh,
take it to the vet?
No,
I'm not paying $1,500
for nothing.
I got,
I got a three step solution to that.
Oh Man.
Hey,
I love my animals.
He lived,
he shook it off.
You made it right on the nose,
man.
He took it as face wall for about a
week.
Went Down Gun.
It's a pillow.
Senate penicillin.
Gave him a couple of shots and called it
a day.
I had a two different dogs.
Got Bit one dog got bit twice.
I would take him to that.
I had a crazy dog named Francis page
$1,500.
And it worked.
Yeah,
I had to,
I'm with you.
I see the way your bank account and my
bank counter set up.
I don't have that $1,500.
Put It on a dog bill.
You've got to put that aside and stop
buying jet skis now.
No,
cause I'm too busy living life,
having fun,
man.
I understand.
But to me like an animal that I'm taking
care of becomes family.
His family have to take care of them.
So if it was like my kid,
I would spend 1500 bucks.
So if it's like my dog,
I'm still gonna spend that 1500 bucks
dog.
Just a dog.
But a dog can make it a dog.
They make it a little kid.
It's not going to make it very
rattlesnake.
We're so sorry.
Could you fucking imagine that we're so
weak.
Taking a fucking,
so I almost got bit by a rattlesnake.
I was out of the lake walking around.
One struck at my ankle,
barely missed me.
So went and grabbed my gun out of the
truck and I said that I shot this
motherfucker being,
and instead of kering up and running
off,
that fucking snake would just lunge at
me.
I shoot it to get the shot it body.
I just shot everywhere,
everywhere but his head because I'm a
terrible fucking shot so well then shoot
him in the head.
You got to give away love.
So I'm ripping this dude's body apart
and he's like Ha.
Somehow still something that the muscle
to like stay upright and fucking lash at
me.
They're like devil dogs man.
For sure.
We think what they are.
They're like,
when people talk about Reptilians the
people,
what are,
what are they really worried about?
They're not worried about people turning
into panda bears.
They're worried about people being
reptiles.
So people being completely cold and
focused on the at hand with no
emotions.
That's what a reptile is,
man.
That's what people are worried.
That was sticker back here.
Yeah,
it's going good.
We're going down so hopefully you have
something to worry about it,
man.
We'll talk about rattlesnakes.
Gophers and it is kind of weird that
some animals have poison.
Like some,
some creatures that live on this planet
have poison and they could fuck you up
and they live amongst us like this
rattlesnakes all around where we are
right here.
You know in the valley you can go out
and those hillsides anywhere,
like go down to one 18 and go on those
hiking trails.
People find rattlesnakes there all day.
If you have a house and you live
anywhere in the Los Angeles area,
it's entirely possible that if you leave
an area undisturbed long in a huff,
a black widow,
a little nest,
they're entirely possible.
I've seen,
I don't know how many black widows in my
life.
A hundred at least.
Maybe hundreds.
That's all too.
Last week here in this place.
Yes.
That fucking studios haunted or we got
him.
You got him?
I wanted to on that,
uh,
the Seti alien signal thing.
Yeah.
Did you look into that at all?
Did you read their article that came
out?
The the really,
they're really fun title is all I want
to get into.
Okay.
This is why,
because I want to hope that this act,
I don't want to like display alien
signal.
So when you go into it and they explain
the likelihood of it being an alien
signal,
that's super depressing.
Yeah.
I know.
This was the thing I wanted to ask you
about the,
this a,
it's called a dyson shell.
What is this?
No,
they said the,
uh,
the,
one of the hypothesis of if this was
possibly a civilization that it's one of
two types of silver.
I don't remember the,
it's like a,
it's a Russian named a car dash of type
two civilization.
So this is a nice atmosphere.
This is a massive structure.
It's three meters thick.
That would encompass the Earth's orbit,
including the sun and Venus,
harnessing the energy to then shoot out
an Omni directional signal,
which is what got,
which is what they picked up.
Wait a minute.
What?
So it's three meters thick and it covers
the whole solar system.
Yeah.
I'll have the first three levels of it
up into earth.
It would have to be that.
That's what this hypothesis says.
I don't understand the radius of this.
Uh,
uh,
in order to make that sort of energy to
Hump Day yet,
if it's not this,
it's a type one civilization,
which is sort of like what we are.
We can harness our stars,
the sound like we can do solar panels
and then shoot out a directional signal
pointed at Earth,
which is how we picked it up.
He,
but isn't it also possible that some
sort of a galactic event?
I think that's probably more likely that
it's just a blip and they don't know
what the blip is yet.
I think it's too big.
Donald serone so we went to hold things
two bags back to space.
Jamie jumped,
jumped right back in.
He's been waiting love space.
He loves the space to change too.
I wish I could.
Nobody can.
I mean even Neil degrasse Tyson,
he,
Neil degrasse Tyson,
I real fucking good about the
presidential
candidates.
He said there should be an option that's
called none of the above and that when
none of the above wins,
we have to start all over again with new
people.
That is a very fucking smart option.
So while we're touching on religion,
I try one of those again where I don't
swallow it or you're going in again.
What is your outlook on the,
on the presidential election here?
Well,
it's good because it shows how fucking
stupid this whole job is of having this
one person who is a part of a two party
system,
we have to like be a registered
Republican or Democrat to vote in the
primaries that decide who these people
are.
They get to represent this party or that
party and they get to this position and
there's only two of them.
It's preposterous.
It's ridiculous that these are the
people we have to choose from.
Whether you like Donald Trump,
will you like Hillary Clinton?
You have to realize this point.
This is not the smart way to do it.
I'm packing it up tight and ball it up
with your toms before I,
it's like lawn trimmings.
I just dropped it off inside my mouth.
Okay.
Ella,
you're going in for another one.
I'm pumped on it.
Okay,
I get it now.
Now you got it.
I got it all packed in.
There you go.
I hope they'll swallow it.
I hope not.
That's a weird looked on it.
You're good.
You're doing all right.
It doesn't taste bad though.
That's what's interesting.
Wintergreen gum.
Yeah.
Little like wintergreen gun,
which is girls chewing and my high
school.
A lot of girls too.
Yeah.
Those are girls that should move closer
to cities,
sweetie.
There's other options.
Okay.
I know you want to stay.
Do you want people to love?
You tried dmt.
Here you go.
Well,
there's a lot of these gals out there
that a forest,
they go to the outer regions of
civilization.
They're forced to behave like pioneers.
You know,
they've got to go out there.
They've got to make their own fucking
houses.
They've got their own phone that's out
there,
dog.
God,
no gay.
Let's stop that.
Stop that.
They're out there chewing tobacco.
Fucking killing shooting dogs.
When they get bit by a rattlesnake,
you and monkeys,
goddammit.
He sucking the eyeballs out of a monkey.
Suck a dick.
Wow.
We might lose this nurse duty.
This.
It's over.
No podcast is over.
It's been a good run.
840 episodes almost,
right?
What does this one is eight 40 over 40
we closed it down.
We'd locked down with this one.
People are like,
I got a life.
I can't do this.
You can't get,
listen,
I had you on at work on the radio and it
had to turn it off.
What happened?
Let's go.
I want to shout out to all the blue
collar workers out there listening.
Then shout out,
shout out my people and gentlemen.
Yeah,
I'd be laying hardwood floors had I not
pick up by the USA.
Probably are in another universe
somewhere out there.
An infinite number of times.
[inaudible] hard hardwood floors and you
watch it.
Some other dude fight the same fights
that you've fought cheering his ass on.
Maybe maybe mad.
I would probably be mad.
Pissed off.
I feel like I would be mad.
You probably would be mad and he took
the wrong.
Here's what I think.
I think to you are you,
who is you right now is a result of a
lot of these decisions.
So it'd be really interesting to see who
you would be if you didn't make the same
decisions.
Like who are you if you decide to never
go into that rec room and learn how to
fight,
who are you?
If you have a fight and lose,
you never come back.
You never get better.
Who are you?
You know?
I think w who you are right now a lot of
times is decided by a lot of the shit
you've already done and how you feel
about it.
Who I am.
If I didn't walk into that record,
I don't know.
My Dad always telling me whenever I'd
fuck up.
So I was like the worst kid.
Bad.
Definitely not the worst kid I heard he
got killed.
He stabbed his two year old sister.
I didn't do that.
That's the worst I shot my sister and
the head of the slingshot.
Oops.
Pretty close.
A childish mistake.
Child of a shake.
So I feel like it was a rough childhood.
He now and I could only have sex on my
back cause I could only fuck up sell.
I should be the title of your book.
Yeah.
And my dad would say,
if only you could use your powers for
good instead of evil,
you would make yourself out to be
something great.
You know?
And here I am so well telling people to
suck eyeballs out a monkey brains and
everybody,
Andy fucking different everybody.
And for someone who is like you to
pretend to be like your accountant is
just as ridiculous as your accountant
pretending to be you.
Right?
Key to this life is find out who you
are.
And that is the hardest question to
answer because who you are changes every
day.
It's like you gotta be true to whoever
you are at the moment.
Do you believe that who you are is a sum
of the five people you hang out with?
It helps.
It definitely helps.
We feed off each other for sure.
You got to surround yourself as much as
you can with people that care about you
and people that are there,
they have the same sort of ambitions
that you have in terms of like they have
the same,
they have work ethic.
They're not lazy,
they don't fuck up.
They don't,
they don't ruin their life constantly
because those people become like energy
drains,
right.
You know,
it's not like you should totally
abandoned them,
but you got to be real with them.
You've got to let them know.
You've got to say,
listen,
this is what's going on and this is how
everybody's sort of looking at,
well,
you keep doing this.
Don't do this anymore.
Why do you keep doing this?
Because you get attention when you do it
because it's easier than succeeding
because I,
I think especially in your line of work,
I think that self sabotage is a primary,
uh,
escape valve.
That's who is the leader in the self
sabotages man.
I mean,
you go to fighters like old school.
I mean old school fighters like Roberto
Duran,
like Roberto Duran,
right?
Beet sugar ray Leonard and Duran.
And one of the four horsemen man packs
on foods.
So it's eaten like a fucking pig gets
too fat,
doesn't train hard.
Says No moss.
And the rematch,
you know,
Tyson in a lot of ways was a self
saboteurs.
Uh,
Aaron Pryor became a crack addict.
You know,
I got addicted to cocaine,
her crazy stories about
that.
So on a total fucking side note,
you want to hear something really cool?
Yes.
Rick.
Story fight.
I park at the Rv Park,
right?
It's where I find my zen.
I get away from the Strip.
My rv park.
Yeah.
Hang on.
I hang up the RV part.
Another title of your book.
I go to,
I go to the lake.
Guess who my mother fucking neighbor was
who shook nice brother Ron White Ron
night.
Oh,
how crazy is that?
What is that like?
So this guy was big giant black guy
comes walking over to me,
first of all his trailers,
all black with red lights.
And this guy comes over to me and he's
like,
hey man,
what are y'all shit on my porch dead?
Uh,
no,
no shit on your porch.
He said,
yeah,
I think one of your mother fucking dogs
and Shit on my porch.
And I said,
Nah,
man out.
He's like,
I just want to make sure it was an
accident.
And it wasn't anything,
you know,
like malicious,
like you guys,
I need to make sure my,
my,
my area's secure.
And I was like,
Nah,
man,
I don't,
you know,
I don't think so.
That's kind of funny.
And then I look at him and I look at his
rig and I'm like,
hey man,
what do you do?
Because he's in like a $3 million RV,
right?
3 million.
Oh yeah,
his [inaudible].
He's really nice and his extra nice.
So he said,
oh,
I do a little bit of real estate.
And I said,
may don't like really what do you do?
And he's like,
Oh man,
I do a little bit like music stuff,
you know what I'm saying?
Um,
death row records.
And I was like,
Oh shit.
And then he just goes on talking about
these again.
My name is Ron Ron night.
And,
uh,
you know,
I was in there with Shugg and I was
like,
oh,
she has it.
Then of course,
like any high schooler would,
I asked him any questions you could ever
imagine.
What was it like in the early days of
Nwa?
Oh totally.
I was that guy.
Ask him everything.
What was it like how cool,
you know,
what was easy?
He like and he,
you know,
and he's,
he told me that story that they did the
straight a caught,
it was pretty right on man.
I did a real good job and I asked him
about a,
you know,
ice cube and he said that the cube,
he doesn't really go out and party.
He just really do himself and making
money.
It's to add any question you could ever
think of.
I asked for sure.
We shot there,
you know,
for the all the nights leading up to the
fight and he actually stuck around and I
got his number.
Now we're,
we're,
we're pals.
So went from someone shit on his porch.
So we're buds now.
Was it a dog?
That shit on his porch.
You've got no idea.
It wasn't me.
Whatever you have to say.
Who should I does porch wasn't me 1
million hanging out with some shady
characters.
Yeah.
You know,
so dudes make some odd choices,
right?
Well,
I didn't see it.
I have no idea.
I was like,
I don't,
I mean,
I said,
man,
that's a rude thing to do to a person.
Right.
Shit on their porch.
That's about as rude as it gets.
So then we do the fight and was fun.
We have Sunday fun day and I sent that
video.
What was that video you sent me?
That was the park and rec holding me at
gunpoint.
Why?
Because they thought,
let me back the story up.
Let me get everyone plotted in here.
So I have two labs.
Should I send the video to him so we can
play it?
Can we play the video?
I don't know.
I don't,
I mean one is illegal and what we did
was legal.
I mean,
I don't know.
I don't want to get any of those guys in
trouble.
All right,
so let's stop.
Let's not play it.
Okay.
It's pretty outlandish video though it,
yeah,
that wasn't me filling me cause I was
too busy losing my fucking mind.
Just like my buddy Mikey.
So my dogs were at the marina loading
the boat,
another boat rage and isn't of course,
cause that's what I did.
What his boat rage.
It's like road rage but in a boat.
Um,
but I wasn't raging.
My dogs run off.
There's this too.
There's this guy,
he has two pit bulls and my run running
to play with them.
Well this guys are losing his fucking
mind with us.
So it turns out all my guys run over,
they get our dogs.
There was no like compensation or any
kind of fight or anything.
But they grabbed the dogs.
The guy started talking shit.
And when my buddies like fuck you,
the guy calls nine one one and tells him
that we didn't know.
He told him that we had,
we were pulling guns so we pulled the
boat out or wiping down,
cleaning it out.
Well the park and rec comes in hot
thinking that we have weapons.
Right.
So this is the wildest she'd have were
out there.
They're like,
put your fucking hands up,
right?
We're at shirts,
shorts,
no shorts,
have no weapons.
Clearly put our hands up and they start
talking to the Telus,
turn around,
get on the ground.
So they tell us is going to ground these
other two rangers,
pull up hot,
jump out with them.
Sixteens cock and load and point the
guns at us like crazy.
Well at this point I lose my fucking
mind because there is no reason you need
a point.
I loaded them 16 at me like that.
Right.
And uh,
yeah.
So we start yelling and screaming and in
mid between the scream to whoever the
main ranger is kind of takes charge.
It's like,
just talk to me.
Don't worry about what they got going on
over there.
Meanwhile they're pointing [inaudible]
right.
So I'm like,
fuck you motherfucker,
shoot me bitch.
Like look.
Right.
That's the difference to you and me.
Right?
So I start crying.
It's like you fucking coward like you,
you're going to point a gun on me.
I'm going to tee shirt and shorts like
fuck you,
you piece of shit.
And he's like,
so this is what the,
I swear to God,
this is what the ranger says,
look at me.
Focus on me.
Great fight last night.
Uh,
I need you guys to focus on me,
right?
So mid,
mid,
mid me fucking tell him,
dude,
I'm gonna fucking rip off his fucking
throat.
He's,
I said it's great for a fight last
night.
So these guys,
are they all aware of who you are?
I just,
the one guy is at this point,
but how does he know his abilities?
That friends,
this isn't some fucking crazy method,
right?
Like,
and,
and we're out there having a good time.
I'm not drinking for once in my life,
so I'm like sober running the boat.
We're cleaning it at this point,
getting ready to,
and I explained that my dogs got out of
this guys.
And so he says,
well,
they said you have weapons.
So he's like,
cowboy,
do you have guns?
And he true blooded American.
I said,
full,
of course I have guns.
Duh.
It's in my truck.
So now the story on the other guy's part
is looking more realistic.
Right?
I got Dan,
of course,
I have a fucking gun in my truck.
So they get the gun and they run the
gun,
of course not stolen.
I give him my concealed carry and I'm
like,
dude,
we never,
we never wielded the gun.
Like it never got pulled out.
It just,
it just so happens dumb luck that I have
a gun.
And uh,
I mean it all worked itself out in the
end,
but cops are in a tricky position right
there because like,
uh,
in,
in one way,
like they don't know what the fuck is
going on.
They show up.
Yeah.
Who the hell knows who the hell knows
you something you have to show me.
And I didn't know.
They showed up knowing,
thinking that we had done so of course,
so I'm losing my fucking mind.
Like,
hey man,
all this shit in the news.
Like you can just pull up,
pull a fucking gun pointing at me saying
you're going to shoot me.
Like,
so I'm losing my mind and my buddy mike
is totally off the fucking radar if they
had like,
shoot me walking towards these cops.
Oh No.
Yeah,
it was,
uh,
that's not good.
It was wild.
So in,
in the,
in the grand scheme you think thinking,
once they told us,
you know,
the guy called and said you guys pulled
weapons on them.
I see where they're coming from,
but it was just fucking outlandish.
Man worked down though.
That's so common.
People do that shit all the time.
And so he pulled a gun on him.
Like what kind of,
and I always tell him the cubs,
like what kind of,
I mean you can't just do that.
You can just call the cops and say,
Oh,
this guy pulled a gun on me.
Little,
you should get in trouble if you do do
it,
it shouldn't be a free pass.
You shouldn't be able to say,
that guy pulled a gun on me and not go
to jail.
Yeah.
It should be the same.
If I pulled a gun,
get in trouble and he had the got,
you know,
you shouldn't be able to just say,
oh,
this guy pulled a gun on me.
Yeah.
Well it's a conspiracy.
You're conspiring to tell false
narratives so that you can get a guard
in trouble for something he never did.
The other guy winds up going to jail
like you're fucking terrible person when
a guy in jail for something that he
absolutely didn't do in the first place.
I mean I was and that's why I it a
couple of the dude I just fought last
night.
I said,
first of all,
there's eight,
there's 18 of us on the boat.
If 18 of us sitting here like you really
think one guy we're going to pull a gun
with,
there's 18 of us.
Like,
like any scenario you can think of in
your life,
we'd pull a gun like,
come on man.
And that's when the cops were like,
ah,
you have a good point.
They're like,
yeah,
what do you,
what are you even talking about?
Did you get the guy over?
Did they get out?
They wouldn't even bring it up.
So middle isn't that weird too?
Like you can't even just like I have
Amanda man with the person and go,
what are you doing man?
Well,
first of all,
and then you can't even have a man to
man with the cops because you're under
punk status right now.
Of course,
sit down everyone on the fucking curb,
but it's like,
you know,
they just like taking her manitee away,
which enrages me even more of course,
but they have to do it.
They have to.
I understand from their standpoint,
you know,
they have to protect themselves because
there's a lot of idiots out there,
you know?
But Yup.
Yeah.
It's,
it's one of those things where it's,
there's no winner there.
It's terrible position to be in for both
parties.
For them.
They got lied to.
Someone told me you had a gun.
They'd come in and thinking about their
kids,
their wife,
their life,
their fucking mother,
that no one wants to see them dead.
They got to you.
There's someone could shoot them.
This could be who the fuck knows what
they're coming to.
They're coming to a gun.
He's got a gun.
He says Chris Brown shit on the news.
No excuses.
The cops have surrounded Chris Brown's
house.
They won't let him out.
It's been there since three o'clock in
the morning.
The cop showed up three o'clock in the
morning.
They're waiting on a warrant.
Some woman says he pulled a gun on him,
so he's a held up in his mansion.
Helicopters are flying overhead.
I was watching on the news at the gym
today.
I was like,
what the fuck did Chris Brown do?
I don't know if he did anything.
Some woman says he pulled a gun on him,
so through after that happened he threw
a Duffel bag out that had weapons and
drugs in it apparently then.
Well,
that's smart.
Yeah.
Damn.
Well I for one have never thought Chris
Brown to be a guy who makes irrational
decisions.
I look at that gentleman.
I might,
that's the guy that I come to when I'm
confused and I need some guidance and
Nisa guidance like you already fuck.
Maybe he should be a manager.
Maybe.
How old this?
We have many levels of management.
Okay,
you come to me.
I go to Chris Brown and then we figured
work the shit out.
Two duffle bags with guns.
That's hilarious.
I swallowed some of that.
You got to spin it out.
Most of it I got,
Nah,
that's already swelled.
I got most of it still stuck in there.
But it's hard to keep it in there.
I'm not,
I'm a rookie at this.
You're,
you're a white belt by the shores.
Blue Belt.
I'll be a stripe.
I was trying to a belt,
white belt,
blue stripe.
See,
I,
there's nothing,
I have nothing against the armed forces
or I mean at all.
You know,
so I just,
it just,
that was the video I sent to you and
you're just fucking outlandish.
You know?
Crazy.
I recognize,
um,
that it's a hard position to be a cop.
Absolutely.
And uh,
I also suddenly knuckleheads out there.
You never know.
I just basically,
especially everybody carrying weapons,
these dentists.
Wow.
And you know what?
Here's the other thing.
Here's where it's tougher cops.
A lot of cops are second amendment,
uh,
believers.
So they,
they support the right of a citizen to,
to hold arms,
to have guns,
and to use them in a responsible and
legal manner.
All right,
so you want a lot of cops from my theory
on this.
Well,
it's not really my theory on on,
on,
on them,
but it's my theory of how I think they
think.
So if I'm taking you,
let's go back to scuba diving lessons.
You were scuba diving as an example.
If I take you to dive,
yeah,
go cave diving with me.
Right?
We're in a cave.
You run out of air,
right?
So your only source of life is me,
So you have to grab my air out of my
mouth that we now have to share.
But what if you're sucking too much air
and using a mine?
I have to make the decision.
I'm going home to my girlfriend,
my family.
So I feel like that's the same
mentality.
They have to come with any of these
situations.
Like they're fucking coming home to
their wife and their kids.
So no matter rights you get get,
get rid of carole.
I'm writing here so I'm leaving at the
end of that.
That's what I'm saying.
At the end of the day,
you already used your ass mother fucker.
You ain't using it.
Mine,
I undersell.
I said,
I feel like they have to come into these
situations is like,
listen here,
we got called on you,
you pieces of shit.
I don't know the situation,
but in my mind I'm going home.
So whatever,
whatever that means.
Right.
And I'm not mad at him for that.
I'm not either.
I understand that.
I understand the survival instinct and I
understand,
especially if they don't know you,
you know,
if you're,
I assume if a scuba dive when someone,
that's someone who's a really close,
and that'd be a real heart
issue.
It would be.
That'd be,
that'd be way,
way,
way harder.
In fact,
if you show up at some scene and some
dude is supposedly assault with a deadly
weapon and you don't know,
and you're wearing a vest and your guns
drawn,
who knows?
Who knows what the fuck's going to go
down to talk with this stuff in your
lip.
But you do know you're coming home to
your,
your wife and your kids.
Yeah.
A lot of dudes make that decision.
There's a lot of dudes.
I'm sure though that would be in that
scuba diving scenario and say I would
rather die with my friend then let them
die down here.
It's tricky then don't ever come with me
because I don't ever call me cause I'm
going home.
I'm going home.
I know that for sure.
Yeah.
I have gone home.
That is the issue with that cave diving
shit.
I watched this cave diving thing where
they were exploring these ancient Mayan
sites.
Uh,
and the only way to get to them,
it was going through these caves and
they would go to these caves and find
all these ancient Mayan ruins,
but they're going through these case for
like hundreds of yards,
hundreds of yards in a cave under the
ocean.
We breathed out of a fucking mask.
I'm like,
oh Christ,
I can't.
I love it.
I fucking love it.
I know you do.
So I took my bite and my buddies always
ask,
they want to go scuba diving with me and
they want to go k diving.
So I took him up to this.
We have a,
we have a cave in the mountains.
So I just took him in the cave.
Of course you do.
We went in with this,
this is dry.
We walked in,
right?
Walk into the cave with lights.
I made them turn the lights off and find
their way out.
Like,
all right,
you want it let,
let's worst case scenario here.
What the fuck y'all going to do?
And they freak out.
And every,
everyone I've had to turn the light on,
you know,
I'm like,
this cannot happen in the cave diving
because if we're own to the water and we
lose our torch or we lose our air
pandemonium going to fucking break out.
So I was like,
you guys fail.
I'm definitely not going down with you
guys.
But,
uh,
just to give them that little touch of
what it's like,
it's,
you don't,
you really don't know who you are as a
person until you're put in one of those
positions.
Like you can talk big and bold until you
practice [inaudible] been there,
which don't you feel the same way about
fighting know apps a fucking little.
I mean,
like that's one of the weird things
about,
um,
people doing.
Um,
like a writing articles about fighting.
It's one things I've had a real problem
with in the past where I've,
I've even gone overboard like to go
after them because I get real angry when
people write like real disrespectful
things about,
um,
about fighters,
about their performances and like
unnecessarily insulting and not,
it looks like we all sort of agree that
people that put themselves like first
responders,
like firefighters,
people put themselves in,
in the,
the line of,
of,
of danger in the,
in the,
in front of danger for us.
We give them like this,
uh,
extra love and respect they deserve.
Sure.
But when people do dangerous shit for
our entertainment,
you know,
um,
a lot of times people feel the need,
like rightly so.
There's some things that are just
fucking ridiculous.
There's some ridiculous shit that people
do.
You know,
w w w was like,
park core.
People are jumping from building to
building.
You're like,
Oh,
fucking Christ.
By the way,
that guys coming on the podcast at James
Kingston Guy,
can you hook him up with me because I
would love to do that.
Me and this motherfucker been talking,
he scares the shit out of me.
Just looking at his instagram feed.
I can't imagine,
imagine talking to him about stories in
person,
but um,
but with fighters I feel like that's
such a,
it's a fucking scary and a lot of ways
it's a noble pursuit because it's so God
damn,
it's the antithesis of what your
instincts tell you to do.
Fight or flight.
Yeah.
Your instincts are telling you get the
fuck out of this.
Don't do this.
You could get hurt.
This is bad.
We don't know what's going to happen is
this is open ended.
Anything could go wrong and you have to
prepare for this moment,
for months.
In fact,
really for years,
like by the time you get to a point
where you're fighting rick story,
you can't just dive in and fight Rick
Story.
No.
You got to fight all these other people
along the way.
Yeah.
You got to build up the ability,
the skills and the,
you know,
you have,
there's a confident path in your mind
that when shit is going down,
you know how to fight and you know how
to execute and you were confident that
when you get in there and all that
pressure's on you,
you can do it.
Why?
Because you've done it.
So for someone who's on the outside,
I think it's imperative it really in
this sport to,
to,
especially when you consider the fact
that it's so devastating.
Like when a fighter loses,
it can,
it can define their life.
It's very difficult for them to
overcome,
you know,
and are difficult.
It's the,
the lowest low you could ever feel.
What is the worst loss you ever had for
the title?
When dosantos got me this last time,
I wanted to turn my phone off and hide,
man,
it's like the worst.
And then you realize the sun still comes
up and Joe Rogan's still calls me.
He always like the world doesn't end,
but they love you if you lose or if you
win.
And this is no way you can know if
you're going to lose,
you're going to win.
Especially,
you can't say that you're the winning,
honestly,
just a byproduct of performing wes.
Right.
And you can't say you're the baddest
motherfucker on earth until you meet the
baddest motherfucker on earth and
there's the new new bad one coming right
behind him.
There's always,
that's gotta be the weirdest thing.
Right.
Then nipping at your heels,
how many people would call an out
cowboy?
Good Lord.
I love it.
Yeah,
but I more popular.
You get right?
Yeah.
Everyone wants a piece of the pie,
but do they really?
That's my thing.
Come get something.
But do they really?
Are they just big wolf?
And until it comes down to tell Dana
calls them like,
hey,
we heard you wanted to fight.
And they're like,
oh right,
right.
There's a few guys,
you know,
definitely want it.
Like if you call up Matt Brown,
Matt Brow wants it because a few of
those guys like,
and that's one of the reasons why win,
lose or draw.
Matt Brown always gets massive respect.
Sure.
You know,
even though he just lost to ellenberger
props to ellenberger that was,
it was below the knockout.
Right.
Crazy powerful and back against the
wall.
Lost a bunch of fights in Rome.
Ellenberger comes back looking like a
fucking monster.
He had to reinvent himself.
Yeah.
And did a lot of training with nick
curse on too,
you know,
nick curse on,
um,
down at speed of sport,
who works with Joe Schilling,
works with the dose on Joe's.
What a fucking stellar day.
Love that guy.
Cigarette smoke and beer tote and
motherfucker.
Right.
And just as real as fuck him and I,
once we met and hung out where we're
buds man.
I mean,
uh,
yeah.
I mean you feel the same way.
Real,
real son of a bitch.
Right.
And a great guy,
great guy.
He is,
he's funny and they bring him out here
that always fucking,
he's wild son of a bitch.
I love it.
While I was fuck cool to hang with.
And you know what,
he came in after his last loss last.
That's that guy two times in a row by
knockout.
But he was winning the whole fight until
right.
Fair enough.
Yeah.
But you know,
he came in with a great attitude about
it and I think part of the great
attitude about was losing to him by
knockout before.
Yeah.
Well it wasn't like,
uh,
like uh,
I have resigned myself.
I'm not as good as I thought it was.
Yeah.
It was,
hey man,
you fucking lay those chips out.
And sometimes,
I mean he was playing the most dangerous
game.
He was playing just empty gas tank and
attack and be as aggressive as possible.
And he was winning at it.
Yeah.
But he got clipped and,
but he came in with a great attitude
about man.
Great attitude.
I don't think very many people
appreciate what it takes to go out there
and do that.
To not play safe,
to just knock him,
put the gas pedal to the floor.
I don't think you can.
I don't think I can.
I don't think anybody can unless you've
done it.
So you're there watching that.
I think it has to,
I mean that's one of the easiest thing
that someone can do online,
like trolls and people got of them.
Got To love him in some ways.
I get it.
If I was 14,
I'd probably be doing the same shit.
I was 22.
I might've been doing the same shit.
Damn.
Especially if you're anonymous.
I'm net.
Yeah,
with a locked account.
I've never,
uh,
I've never gotten on someone's account
and just talk geranium acts of shit
talking.
That's the problem with talking shit.
It's always done by losers.
And that's something that they don't
understand.
And even guys,
there's a lot of guys that talk shit
that I've actually won some fights.
Right.
And then it,
they've actually had some success,
but they know someone or had,
they're not doing all the right things.
Yeah.
There,
there's,
there's some missing things.
There's diversity and like talking shit
like the way connor does it,
like generating fights and,
and,
but talking shit online.
Come on on your instagram feed that,
come on.
That's ridiculous.
I'm with it.
My next fight.
I have a little bit of a problem with
it.
For one.
I'm a really good friend with him.
Great Guy.
But my fucking girl,
it's her favorite fighter.
Second.
Second Phase,
right?
Yeah.
Better fucking be right.
Oh,
a half fucking wild.
Is that right?
That was pretty wild.
But I wish I could.
I wish I could handle a situation like
that.
There you go.
Spit it out.
It was swollen.
I just tell her how many guys have you
had a fight that you care about?
Ben Henderson for sure.
Great Guy.
Um,
really that's about it to be honest with
you.
Yeah.
I'd like truly care about,
you know,
I,
I showed you a,
were you friends with him before the
first fight?
Yeah,
just because we grew up like on the ring
of fire and the circuit together,
you know,
we knew each other.
Um,
I don't know about friends,
but we've become friendly.
Yeah.
We've become great friends.
You know,
I to give him,
I gave him fucking tickets to the
superbowl man.
That's pretty awesome.
That's pretty good then.
I'm good.
So thank you.
Thank you.
Budweiser first fight that was on that
Wec p a paper view.
That was a,
that was the first fighter called of
viewers.
Yeah.
And then,
um,
then he has a close one eye.
Yeah,
that's some bitch rubber band,
man,
I gave Mary submission that could
possibly think of who's good.
Second one.
He just went out and choked me out in
three seconds.
But uh,
and then the third one and then third
one I won.
A lot of people say I didn't win,
but a super close,
super close fight,
real close fight those fights,
man.
I honestly believe that the scoring
system is ridiculously inadequate and
it's best exam like Joe Lozan versus um,
um,
uh,
Jim Miller.
I'll watch that again today.
I was like,
God damn.
Good luck scoring.
This is a chaotic fight.
You know,
it's like,
there's so much going on.
How much,
how much politics do you think fall into
the scoring?
How?
I mean,
you see the judges and they're kind of
usually elderly.
They're not really young,
young guys.
How much of me?
And I kinda like,
I kinda liked cowboy.
I like his vibe.
I like his energy.
I maybe I'm going to tip the scale a
little bit.
It's a good question.
They could on unquestionably be biased.
Right?
Vans are biased.
I'm biased.
People are biased so we use definitely
biased.
Sometimes I have to watch the fights on
mute just because sometimes you got to
watch the fight on mute and then watch
it with Joe Rogan.
You're like,
wow.
He swayed to tick.
He tipped the scale on that one for
sure.
I tried not to.
I try not to.
I told you before,
man,
I'm bias towards you though.
This is a problem.
Appreciate it.
I'm a legitimate fan,
you know,
and I try to be as objective as
possible,
but the things are happening in a fight.
You get excited.
I think I do my best to do it justice,
but I'm not scoring it right.
You know,
I'm trying to be entertaining,
but being a commentator is a weird job.
How much are you going to do it?
I don't know.
I'm doing it less and I like it more
because I'm doing it less.
So.
How do you pick the ones you want to do?
Paper.
Paper view one's in North America.
No more traveling.
No more Australia.
I need to get on paper view.
Big chose.
Yeah.
Vegas baby.
Kinda easy.
That's a 40 minute flight from me.
I Love Vegas.
Everything's open.
That's the worst thing about traveling
and fighting.
Right?
You fight,
the first thing you want to do is eat
right and they 11 o'clock everything's
closed.
Stake Vegas.
Shit.
11 o'clock come on.
Yeah,
come on in.
We got to fall.
Glob.
We've got rib eyes.
Fuck while they're talking about fuck
why?
But luck.
Really.
Gum Sliver.
Love it.
Yuck.
So you know what I mean?
It's good for you.
No it neither one of those.
It's not good for you and it's not not
good tasting.
It's good.
It's delicious.
Well,
I don't know if it's good for you.
You probably know more than me,
but I just,
it can't,
something that tastes way better than
the sub them oily like a giant booger.
I love it.
It's delicious.
People mad that you,
that
you have to force feed to duck.
You have to force feed the goose to make
um,
uh,
have their liver.
The liver inflates.
It gets larger when they get forced fed.
But I mean why you still kill him?
It's so bizarre.
Like it's okay to kill them and eat
them.
But for a while in California it was
illegal to force feed them.
I fed it,
forced fed a couple of girls goose.
That's not the same budweiser bad guys
running down the hallway.
He's forced feeding girls is goose.
Goddammit.
People get mad.
Oh Man.
Feed at goose.
I didn't know that was the,
here's the thing,
Anthony Bordain told me that I looked it
up.
He said they actually gravitate towards
the feeding pipe.
Like our idea of what a force feeding is
like,
we think it'd be terrible to have
someone dump food down your throat.
Their throats aren't like our throats.
Like they,
they like it doesn't,
it doesn't bother them in a way.
Like there's some is shit that people do
with factory farming,
like making pigs live side by side,
crammed in these cages and cows and
living in their own shit.
But we don't talk about it because we
love Bacon.
Bacon is good and it's hard to get it
from a wild pig.
That's the thing about if you love
Bacon,
you love domesticated pigs folks.
The ones who feed the or to and eat the
bait,
fatten them up.
Yeah,
because if you,
you know,
feral,
beefy,
giant,
muscular pig.
No,
it does not taste like,
well you can get bacon out of it,
but the bacon,
like you see a wild hogs bacon,
which is bacon is like a,
it's like what's attached to the ribs.
It's like the lower rib area on a wild
hog.
That shit is like a quarter of an inch
thick for all of it.
And then if you like,
if you get a side of bacon on a fat
domestic picked out as a fat fucking
slab because he's lays around cut a
feral pig is moving on the move every
day.
Hustling,
hustling.
Yeah.
You remember that old,
the pork.
It's the other white meat.
Remember that?
Yeah.
This is not with wild pigs.
There's nothing white about it.
It's dark.
Like a deer hunter.
Yeah.
I love picking why?
You know what I like about hunting pigs?
Nobody gets mad at you.
You're,
they're like co with a,
with a machine gun out of a helicopter.
If you wish,
please help me.
They don't give a pig slow him down.
He's just fuck they fucking,
they make babies three times a year.
Why is that?
Like you,
you post pictures of machine gunning
pigs down,
but if you machine gun a herd of elk,
all buddy,
man,
right?
I mean,
yeah.
Well Steve Rinella calls them
charismatic megafauna.
There's like this chain of charismatic
large animals and the biggest one is
bears.
Like if you kill a bear,
people will be so fucking mad at you.
But if you kill a pig,
it is a few people that are extremists.
They'd be like,
any loss of life is horrible.
Sure.
But those pigs,
they destroy ground nesting birds.
They just decimate populations of them.
They kill Fonz.
There's a crazy picture.
Like someone was like,
did deers like what do you see that man,
they don't kill deer bull shit.
Wild hogs kill everything.
This is a crazy picture of a wild boar
running off of the font and its mouth
and its a,
it's a sweet picture.
Home.
Domestic.
Yeah.
And they eat my chickens and roosters
all the time.
Oh yeah.
If you get fucking within a pig bite
away like you to see the fucking
chickens eating the feed and the fucking
piggle just grab it by the head and eat
it.
Yeah,
look at that.
Yeah.
That's what my chickens eat in the CAF
all the time.
They eat everything.
People don't understand that as a
fucking eating machine.
That sort of pig is,
they give zero fucks.
Let's talk about how,
so look,
that amazing welder be eating a cheetah.
That's a wild boar eating a cheetah and
then puts out you feed a pig.
Anything in outcomes.
Bacon.
How great is that?
Well you have to get them domesticated
and they change everything about
themselves.
They don't become this sketchy fucking,
there's one running off of the or in his
mouth.
Look at that shit.
We're on this African plains wielder
bees here.
Uh,
is that I feel like,
hmm.
I think that's a pig.
A feral pig.
That's,
that's,
I think that's to pick it might be
Australia.
Visit the page and see what the fuck
that is.
Yeah.
I,
that's how I think.
That's just a wild boar.
Right.
See that's the weird thing about
domestic pigs is in Louisiana.
Yeah.
That's just a wild boar.
Wild boar is they get that real long
snout,
but they don't have the same kind of
tusks that a little dose do.
Well,
not a to bees will to beast is actually
like a,
a an antelope type species.
Right.
We were thinking there's a wart hog
warhol,
the ones that have that swords that come
out of their face.
Those was a giant,
huge tusks.
That's a little bit,
that's like the more extreme version of
this,
but those things that we have over here,
that's a warhol.
There it is.
We'll get that motherfucker.
Jesus Christ.
A hair look.
Get his Mohawk.
Yeah.
My friend Remy went over to Africa and
shot one and he said it tasted just the
eyes.
What are the horns knows something that
keeps up from biting and size fucking
mean.
They called me and that is,
it's like gag reflex.
So when someone tries to eat your eye
that that goes in,
that Dick goes right in their mouth and
they puke up your eyeball.
That's a fucking hard ass animal.
Pretty vicious right there.
Fuck yeah.
It's vicious.
That's a hard ass animal.
You don't grow those kinds of tufts on
your face cause they're pretty,
they attract females.
That's a,
that's an animal that knows it has a
short window to eat as much shit as it
can and hope nothing.
Know that pigs have spiraled dicks.
Yeah.
Type about getting screwed.
That's where it comes from.
Is that what it comes from?
Yeah,
they have.
They like,
they have spiraled it.
So the ducks,
we would,
we reviewed that in the podcast and
apparently I'd say the ducks at three
foot long Dicks,
I was wrong.
This Andrea's Antonopoulos the point of
bird that's only three feet long,
have a three foot.
They have like 13 inch Dick's though.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Oh,
they have giant crazy dicks.
Dot.
Look at it.
That's a duck deck.
So they come in hot coming in hot
because the females have been like
program to try to prevent rape and the
way they've been programmed to try to
prevent rape.
They develop these like labyrinth
pussies.
Like look at that in the upper right
hand corner and Jamie,
there's a female pussy,
female pussy as opposed to what boy
posted it.
That's what I get in jail.
That's a,
that's like the,
the inside of a uh,
a female duck and they have like these
little trap doors where the Dick can't
get through.
So they have to like allow the Dick to
get through and they can actually cut
off the breeding process.
They can choose what male society in a
lot of ways to deal with.
Yeah,
it does.
It does.
It's super important.
Loud.
They don't have a trap door,
but it's,
it might be 10 years,
but all they do is rape each other and
the duck world,
they're just biting each other and
raping each other.
I love hunting ducks.
Probably one of my turkeys.
Turkeys,
pheasants.
Doug has the order of birds.
I love to hunt.
I've heard that Turkey with a bow and
Arrow is the shit.
I love it.
He's able to center punch or you can try
and give the teen it off with them with
those crazy I've tried so you got to get
them really close.
You got to get really close and you've
got to get him when he,
when he's up like cooking,
you know that can fucking cha and
usually when you draw it back he sees
you and they're out of there.
I shot the first one that ever shot last
year and it was delicious,
but it was,
it was a young one.
It was only a year old and Steve
[inaudible] was telling me that a three
year old Turkey is super old and most of
them never lived to be three,
but I was amazed at how big they are.
They're fucking mungus right.
I went,
I just went down.
I got invited to a high on the,
a real tree plantation down in Georgia,
which I felt like was the butterball
form.
Like,
I feel like this let a bunch of turkeys
out of trap doors and we just smelled
them now.
I mean we a hundred for two days before
we got one.
But you thought that going in?
Yeah,
I was like,
great.
This is going to be like so easy.
They can't do that though.
Real trees like an establish hunting
brand.
Everything.
It was fun,
you know?
Uh,
we got the birds and uh,
it was so good.
So good.
It tastes so much better.
I mean,
the same thing with wild pigs.
They taste so much better than
domesticated animals.
When you domesticate animals to just,
you fuck up the whole system,
but you have to like the game.
Do you like lamb?
Are you a lamb?
Lamb is,
you don't like lamb,
lamb chops.
I don't like the game in it.
You don't like gave me food.
I don't think lambs gave me at all.
Fuck.
Yes it is really lamb.
Huh?
Maybe you've had a bad,
I've had all lines,
a restaurant over here in woodland hills
called brandywine.
If you have a rack of lamb from them.
Oh,
game on.
Might Change your mind,
Donald.
All right.
You've got to go with someone who's
preparing it correctly.
If you had an a restaurant before I had
it in a restaurant,
I'd had it at my house everywhere.
Hmm.
Not had to domesticate a lamb.
See,
I don't know what it tastes like to you.
That's the,
I think that's a weird thing about taste
buds.
Like some people weren't a weird chain.
Very good point.
I don't know what the fuck they're
experiencing.
I'm just guessing based on my
experience.
Like I like really hot foods,
Jalapenos and a Habanero peppers.
I like fuck I cooked with hot shit and
you cook them and Piss them off and get
me an hots.
Yeah.
I like em raw too though.
Sometimes I try the Jalapenos Ra,
I found out that just a little bit of
cooking knows the way to do it.
Cause Jalapeno Raul will give you
immediate johnny rocket.
Yeah.
Got a little bit holy fuck.
Three of them last night.
Big Fat boys within [inaudible]
Genetically Modified Jalapenos game on.
Yeah,
they're like a duck dick.
It's a big ass Jalapeno.
But uh,
I like hot food.
But I don't know what hot food tastes
like to other people.
I just know what it tastes like.
Hi.
But I know that some shit that I can't
tolerate.
I,
there was a restaurant that used to be
here in Encino,
but the dude died unfortunately,
but it's called Chili,
my soul.
And it was an all chili restaurant and
you would go there and they had like the
Scoville rankings of the,
which goes up to like 10 which is
impossible to eat,
but they had nines,
they had nines and they gave me a cup of
nines.
And when I say a cop,
I mean like a fucking thimble.
And I was like,
really?
He's like,
yeah,
really?
I go,
okay,
I'll try it.
She went nine.
Yeah.
So he goes,
just a little spoonful gauge and I
couldn't fucking believe how hot it was.
Sweating.
I'm sweating,
pouring sweat,
and like I'm sweating.
Do you sweat when something's hot that
you need?
I don't know man.
I like it though.
That's half.
What I like about it at the Jalapenos,
mass sweating,
it's just pouring.
Like I was in a sauna last night.
It's beautiful that you killed like a
man with a bow,
like a man,
like a man.
The man.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's a freak out man.
That's,
that's probably my number one addiction
right now.
Taking a vacation soon.
Going to Elka,
Andrea.
I'm going on a bunch of them.
I feel like if I was me,
if I wasn't me and I said,
man,
if I was that dude,
I'd go on a bunch of fucking hunting
trips.
I'm going on a bunch of fucking hunting
I give a bunch of meat out to my
friends.
I eat it all myself.
It's all I eat.
I don't,
I don't.
I very,
very,
very rarely buy domestic meet now and if
I do it's because like I need to cook
something.
That night I got some friends coming
over and I didn't defrost anything and I
just got to bang it out quick for the
most part or if somebody wants it,
but I don't feel bad.
I don't feel bad when I eat.
No,
because you domestic meat or a like a a
wild game and you don't to resource in
a,
in a beautiful one hunter.
Yeah.
He just went and cut the head off and
you're like,
oh yeah,
I get men.
Me and Calvin got him.
Yeah,
we got you fucking got this leopard.
I'm going to fuck it to suck his
eyeballs out.
Yeah.
There's something fucked up about
killing things just cause you can kill
them.
But uh,
I want a human,
it depends on how good they taste.
You need to find out what do you think
of healing?
Tastes like?
Probably like pig.
You think that's what they say.
They call him long.
Who's Day people have eaten them.
Cannibals.
They call him,
they call him long pigs.
They've actually,
and you think what we eat like am I,
would I be a little sweeter because I'm
a skittle.
Milko kind of probably delicious.
Marianne.
I'm a beer battered cowboy here.
Your Hams and tastes like white goop.
You beef those fucking cows.
They peed beard to in Japan.
Yeah.
Mandy probably tastes delicious.
Why?
I know that like animals,
they eat certain things.
Like,
here's a perfect example.
Bears of bears eat salmon.
Like a friend of mine,
um,
made a bear ham out of a bear.
They called coastal bear and he said it
tasted like you were eating like smoked
salmon.
They smoked a ham from a bear.
It tasted like smoked salmon.
Looks like beef.
You would have to taste like what you
ate is you're putting it right.
You'd have to,
yeah.
Well that's the other thing is blueberry
bears like bears in the fall that are
stocking up on blueberries are
apparently one of the most delicious
things you could eat ever.
It's supposed to be incredible.
Like guys like purposely hunt only in
the fall and only over blueberry
patches.
Just cause they want to catch a
blueberry bear.
You've never had a blueberry bear.
Never had it.
It's supposed to be amazing.
It's supposed to be like one of the most
delicious things you can eat.
So yeah,
I think,
and when you cut them open,
they smell like blueberries.
Like they're fat,
smells like blueberries is the fattest
purple.
It's like a purple fat.
This is like a video of it.
Like Steve Rinella.
How many bears have you killed?
Three.
Did you like make a cool necklace out of
his cloth or anything?
I have rugs of rugs I made out of them
head still attached.
You know,
heads of time have to write.
You're going to have a bear rug.
You have to have the clause in the head
on,
it's got to do it.
Let's go ahead of me.
People are weirded out by it.
I don't think so.
I think I'd,
that'd be a pretty bad ass thing.
Haven't right in your centerpiece eat m
and a in where I hunt in Alberta,
they have to kill them because they
don't have no natural predators.
So this is,
uh,
this is Steve Rinella doing it on that
show.
Mediator.
But see how the,
the fat has got like a purple hue to it.
Yeah.
He takes that stuff and he,
uh,
makes lard out of it with that purple
fat.
Look at it.
See how weird it looks,
right?
Yeah.
That's,
that's fat from a bear that's been
eating blueberries.
See,
but we have this fucking jungle book
view of animals.
So people look at bears like your
friends,
like your friend bears are all
cannibals.
All of them are eating cubs,
especially the ones that we go after,
which are all the males?
No Kin,
they eat their own cut 100% wow.
They all do.
They'll eat every cub they could get
ahold of.
Why not?
Why wouldn't you just do?
Well,
I think,
I think part of that is because they
don't have a natural predator.
So I think nature balances itself out
and when there's no natural Predator,
I think evil out.
Yeah.
I think what happens is these bears
become predators against themselves and
they,
they eat cubs and they don't want
competition with these young males that
are coming up and they also want the
female to come back into estrus or they
could bleed breed again.
So they just eat cubs and they eat them
for food.
They're finding now that they actually
go actively hunting for him,
it's like his is a terrible video of
this polar bear killing this cup that's
the female there next to him.
Like the females on the right and she's
trying to keep him off and he's killing
her cub right now and eaten it.
It's so common.
It's,
it's 100% of the males cubs.
100%
could you fucking imagine getting mauled
by a polar bear?
Oh Man.
Well they're the most fucked up ones
because they come out of the womb as
predators because they don't eat
anything but meat.
They're the only bear that doesn't eat
grass.
They don't eat anything else.
Cause they look at their environment
there.
They're there to eat seals and other
bears and the way they keep the
population down,
it's by eating each other.
It's fucked up.
And that's,
that's a simplistic description of it on
the shore biologist we mad at me,
but there's definitely merit in what I'm
saying.
There's gotta be nature doesn't do that
with a wolves.
Don't eat each other.
You know,
tigers don't eat each other and have a
predator.
Exactly.
I don't know what t Predator Tigers have
other than people,
but I think maybe tigers have had people
as a Predator for so long that it kind
of balances itself out.
But bears man up there by themselves.
Polar bears eat the shit out of each
other,
and then a lot of the places where bears
are like even black bear,
it's like they're in these dense wooded
areas where nothing other than grizzlies
can kill a black bear other than black
bear.
So they kill each other.
It's,
it's,
it's a dark existence man and circle of
life.
And for hunting populations,
like the people up there that live in
Alberta,
they need moose,
they need deer.
It's like a main staple of these
people's diet.
Like there's a lot of folks that live up
there that don't,
they don't buy meat,
so they have to keep those bear
populations in check because they kill
more than 50% of all the Fonz of all the
Moose calves.
What the population control in hunting,
like you said,
is it has to be done well.
It people think it doesn't have to be
done,
but they don't understand the numbers I
used to be done.
You look at the populations of people in
this country that die every year from
accidents.
With deer.
It's 201.5
million car accidents every year in the
United States alone with deer.
It's no other way.
I mean,
there's one solution they want to
reintroduce cougars,
which is a,
yeah,
I mean that'll work.
That'll definitely keep the numbers
down,
but it's,
uh,
it's very tricky.
You're bringing in an apex Predator and
hacks Predator and you'll only has an,
a finite supply of food.
You're going to have to bring in some
people that are going to have to control
those apex predators.
And that's what we have in California.
There's a bunch of people that are
professional mountain lion hunters that
are employed by the state of California.
And when there's a problem mountain
line,
they go and kill it and it's all hush
hush.
Don't talk about it.
But they kill a hundred of them a year.
Wow.
And they're all filled with cats and
dogs and cats and dogs.
Yeah,
of course.
because that's easy.
Yeah,
it's easy.
Easy going.
They got him in the backyard,
caged up watch.
He's a fucking d right?
He's got some growing out of his head.
You might break a leg chasing after and
I can just pray down.
And this dog on a leash,
stupid fat rottweiler sitting in your
yard with no balls.
Why did you take his balls?
It's really,
it makes it Nicer Jack.
I'm would carry him over the fence.
Like there are a rag doll that's a a
pecs predator.
Wow.
I've never seen a mountain lion in the
real and the real world.
Have they?
How close am I?
Old
Tree fort at my cabin there was one I
crawled up the ladder and he was in
Atlanta,
my blankets.
Ooh.
And then you watched me for about a
week.
Holy Shit.
So you crawled up there.
How old were you?
10 or 12 oh my God.
Oh,
10 or 12 so you crowds a lot of,
you had no idea.
No idea.
He gets to the top.
And what are you looking at?
A big ass cat lane on my blankets.
Is he looking at you and not really.
He was just kind of laid out there and I
was like,
Oh shit.
And just went back down the ladder and
ran to the house.
And then he,
uh,
kind of just sat there for about a week
while we were there and just watched us.
Oh my goodness.
Even the trees all week long.
He didn't move.
He just sat there and watched us took
over your tree for it.
He did a little fucker.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
That's terrifying.
Nothing South Park,
Colorado.
Holy Shit.
And what was he eating while I was
living in your tree for it?
I think he was waiting on me.
Wow.
This all now.
Holy Shit.
When I mean the tree fort,
it wasn't even that high.
I mean,
I bet you eight or 10 ladder rungs.
Whoa,
whoa.
Poetry.
Holy Fuck.
Maybe 200 yards from the house.
I mean,
it was just right there.
And how'd you know when he was gone?
We went home.
I didn't know he was gone and we just
left for the weekend.
That was it.
And family vacation was done.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
we didn't live there.
We just go up there and hang out.
Oh fuck.
God Damn it.
Fucking wild.
Crazy.
I seen where I drove by a fucking
massive bear.
Um,
down the four wheelers trail.
He was standing right there next minute.
Just drove right by and I was like,
Oh shit.
I seen a bear chase a kid on a mountain
bike.
He's just in Colorado on Colorado.
I was on [inaudible],
right?
Yeah.
Black bears.
There's only a few brown bears in
Colorado,
right?
It's not that many.
It was definitely a brock bear,
but I did see a brown bear chase a
fucking kid.
Really Chase the kid.
Was it a color phase?
Black bear might have been a color
phase.
I don't mean he looked Brown and Bill
Young.
Oh my God.
He was chasing a kid.
You're out riding our dirt bikes and
there was a little kid on a little 50,
like a whole range ahead of us.
And you've seen the bear fucking hauling
ass down the mountain after the kid on
the,
on the bike.
It was insane.
Oh fuck that.
Yeah.
Apparently more black bears kill people
then brown bears.
Apparently black bears are much more
likely to be predators on people than
brown bears are.
It's not impossible that a brown bear
would do it,
but it's more likely that a black pair
would do it.
I don't,
I don't know why.
Yeah.
I had a line just,
I've never been attacked by anything
like that and that was a close to your
bed,
but nittany that neither incident graced
a threat to me.
Rinella was telling me about this one
dude that he knows who took a,
someone he knows on a,
the first hunting trip ever in the tent
gets attacked by a 500 pound predatory
black bear to attack.
Some goes in the tent.
I was trying to eat him,
grabs his head.
The Dude's comes
in,
shoots some shoots through the bear,
hits the dude in the wrist.
Oh Shit.
So the bullet passes through the bear
hits.
The guy,
breaks his arm for the bear runs out and
then they have to chase the bear down
and runs into another tent.
I have to shoot the bear first,
first hunting trip ever.
Well,
they got it.
Got It.
Yeah.
I mean,
what a student had a backpack and had a
black bear and her two cubs in our camp.
We woke up in the morning on zip to 10
there was,
I just took my 45 and just unloaded and
in the sky.
Well that's good news is,
is it?
Oh yeah.
And they ran off.
Wow.
Right there.
Right there in our,
in our little area.
Holy Shit.
W The mamas are the most dangerous,
the Mama.
And they say that's the big thing that
happens in like,
like a yosemite or yellowstone rather in
yellowstone when people are,
uh,
tromping around there,
just fuck up near become,
and the mom is like that up.
I can just take care of this real quick.
Yeah.
Just rip you apart.
God,
could you imagine fucking get in a
tussle with a bear?
Oh,
you're not equipped for that?
No.
Do you ever see that video with the
spirit?
I don't even know if you gave me a
spear.
No.
And said in the red core,
right?
I don't know.
I'd be standing there like,
holy fuck.
What is this dude doing with his club?
Keep gotten bears pictures on Google
search.
This was found on Google maps.
A fat Russian dude just beat the shit
out of that bear with a stick that's
could beat dad.
Holy Fuck.
Yeah.
I don't know what I'd do.
I you gave me a spear like you're the
guy who judged by that killed a bear
with a spear is impressive.
Yeah.
What do you do?
Have your one shot and you blow it.
Now that mother fucker's like zoop mad
at you.
Mad at calming and hot.
Did he have a side arm with him?
I don't think he did.
So my question is if I go spear hunting
with a bear and I unload my spear and
the bear mauls me,
can I then shoot the bear with a pistol?
Yes,
you could definitely shoot the bear to
stay alive.
Stay alive,
Berto has an open weapon policy.
Like you can use a rifle,
you can use a shotgun,
you can use a crossbow.
A spirit is the spirit.
You're going to outlaw spears.
Now because of the outrage.
Cause everybody's pissed,
which I think is honestly a good idea
because most people are not going to be
equipped to do it the way that guy does.
At the very least.
I think if you're going to kill a bear
with a spirit,
I have to go through some sort of uh,
um,
spear checking academy.
Yeah.
Well they should be some sort of a
certification course where they know
you're competent with the spear,
you know,
because the spear requires massive
physical skills.
You have to be strong as fuck.
You have to be a person who could throw
a lot of weight.
It's not as easy as like pulling a
trigger.
There's a lot,
there's a lot of physicality involved in
killing someone.
Porter,
I think,
is it gutless think sometimes,
like you shouldn't just be able to pull
the trigger.
You should have to passive hunting.
I think a hunter safety,
you're shooting aspects should be a
little more in depth.
Oh No,
I don't think you should be able to maim
a fucking animal.
Yeah,
right.
Like you should,
you should have to put some groupings
together or something.
Handgun or,
or rifle.
You know you shouldn't be that go gay.
Yup.
It's not loaded.
You fucking know how to put the safety
on and you're 12 go get him.
Yeah,
I completely agree because when you pass
one of those hunter safety courses,
what they are as opposed to 10 I was
fucking 10 they're easy to pass
questions.
You just have to know things and you
have to get 60% of the questions right.
Yeah,
that's it.
It's just going to get a d a d.
Yeah,
and then have fun with your dad and his
hunting buddies.
Yeah.
You don't try and burn.
One of one of them is trying to fucking
this this way.
This is a way to teach people to be
competent first before you allow them to
do it.
I think that's probably the best way,
but then people hear shit like that.
Like you're a fringe and pall mall
rides.
I'll teach my son how to do it.
I hope you do.
I hope you hope we do,
but if we're going to regulate it at
all,
it seems ridiculous to me that you don't
regulate competency.
Like people should have a certain amount
of ability before they go hunting or
before they go and shoot a gun at a
range and he kind of,
yeah,
bearing arms.
Imagine if they just gave you a car,
like a licenses.
Do you like asking what's the green
light?
Yeah,
yeah.
What do you do when you hit a stop sign
and you,
you answer these 60% of these questions,
right?
So they give you a car and that's how
you learn.
You learn by driving out there in the
public,
but that's kind of what you're doing
with guns.
You know,
he just,
someone passes a course and then all of
a sudden they got a gun and they just
wandering around like,
you should,
uh,
you should know how the fuck man,
and he's the hunting and then your dad's
bay is like,
it got them on a,
on a four 10.
Let's give him a 12 gauge.
God dammit.
Right now you're 10 with a 12 gauge.
Yeah.
Having fun or a 300 win mag just fucking
show,
you know,
a 10 year old with 300 win mag boom
full.
You just go flying backwards and land on
your ass.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's,
there's a way to do it.
It's like meeting in the middle.
One of the things about like,
people who are gun rights advocates is
they don't want to give up anything.
And I understand it because they feel
like if you give up any ground,
they'll,
liberals are going to come in and
they're gonna want to take all your
guns.
People who don't have guns don't want
anybody to have guns.
And people who have guns want everybody
to be able to get a gun.
I think,
I don't know how I'm on the fence on
Allen,
but I,
uh,
I carry a weapon everywhere with me.
It's what I do.
I have one in every vehicle all over my
house.
I,
uh,
you and Tim Kennedy should get together.
We do all the time.
We do all this done,
you know,
and uh,
I dunno.
I feel like I've never had a pull my
weapon ever,
but I feel like if I did,
I would kill somebody for sure.
If it pushed me to that point.
If you were in a position where
someone's going to take your life,
which happens all the time,
it would be wonderful if you could talk
someone out of that without having to
shoot them.
But there's a lot of people that don't
want to believe if the scenario does
present itself,
occasionally we got to shoot somebody.
Absolutely.
Yeah,
it does.
It does happens all the time.
He can't control,
there's a giant fucking population on
this planet and amongst those people you
are going to run into the wrong
motherfucker sometimes,
whether it's some Ted Bundy character or
there at some fucking school shooter or
there who knows.
You just don't know.
And this idea that you shouldn't be
prepared and then we should pretend that
those people don't exist.
That's desk just as unhealthy as a
someone thinking that everyone should be
armed everywhere they go.
We should all have guns laying on the
table and that's just as unhealthy.
It's all,
it's all of,
it's crazy.
Like there's,
there's a lot of people here and we
definitely need to work on being nicer
to each other.
Be Nice to her.
And maybe an Abra talked about this.
I think mutual combat should be a thing
that has allowed,
that's in Seattle.
You don't get to watch this game.
Road rage.
I puts me over the edge,
motherfucker.
I will lose my mind.
Do you know why that is?
Why that is?
Yeah.
I road rage exists.
They've actually done like they've made
a scientific explanation that actually
makes sense.
When you're driving in a car,
things are happening in Split seconds,
right?
So you're in that car,
people changing lanes,
you're moving 60 miles an hour,
which I mean,
how many feet a second is that you're
flying by,
right.
And it requires you to be tuned in.
Two senses are very tuned in.
And because of that,
anytime something happens,
you're on red alert.
So you,
or you're engaging with people on red,
Oh fuck you.
Like you're in that car and you're,
you're already so ramped up.
By the time you get out,
you're like ready to go to war.
And people that are like normally calm,
they get in those situations and they're
so fucking ramped up.
So ramped up.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
It's,
it's dealing with bullshit.
Allow it to be done.
It,
I agree.
Motherfucker want to pull you over.
You should pull over and figure it out
and said a pullover and then shoot each
other.
Shoot each other.
Well that there'd be a lot of those
people honking their horn if you got
beat the shit out of somebody.
That's true.
The big all right.
Maybe not.
Go ahead.
Go ahead and cut in.
Talk a lot up until the time the door
shut and they're standing outside.
Yeah.
And then maybe they try to talk to way
out of it or talk to way out,
you know,
out of you and scared.
But um,
there's a state,
Washington state has a law,
a mutual combat law where you could do
it in front of cops.
Do you know that crazy dude,
Phoenix Jones who's an MMA fighter who,
uh,
he,
I don't know.
You don't know who he is.
This is a crazy story.
He's a legit MMA fighter.
Very talented kid.
Um,
is he carlos?
Full doors,
brother Phoenix Jones.
Anyway,
he wears a fucking superhero outfit and
he goes out and fights crime.
Real life.
Yeah.
And there's a video of him was on a
street fight in front of cops because
Washington state,
like you said you want to fight.
Do you want to fight?
Okay.
You guys allowed to fight so you can
smoke pot.
Yeah.
So this is this,
this guy,
he's got this outfit on and this dude's
talking shit to him.
Is this the,
um,
do you have any warrior bars?
I don't,
man.
I don't.
I got some other shit.
So the guy talks a bunch of shit and
then he tries to walk away and the guy
was like,
oh,
you're fucking pussy.
So eventually he wound up fighting.
This guy's in front of cops.
You had the fight.
Do you have to find a cop first?
No.
You get agree upon it,
but the cops won't intervene.
So you can say this is mutual common.
Yeah.
So look at this.
There's a cop car so the cops are
watching.
This is hilarious by the way.
This is real fucking recent.
And this dude,
Phoenix Jones,
whatever his real name.
So no weapons,
no weapons,
no evan mutual combat.
Yeah.
And so the cops let them do it,
see if he can get to the actual fight
itself.
Cause it's hilarious with his mother
fucking ass leg kicks the shit out of it
right off the bat.
And the dude's like,
wait,
what a little bit before that.
Here it goes.
So they go at it,
we go,
Ooh,
fuck you.
He's like,
okay.
Okay.
He's dressed like a superhero,
which is even more humiliating.
They kicked your ass.
So they start going at it.
They're standing there in front of the
cops.
Look at this.
Wow.
Right away.
Oh leg kick.
And then he's bouncing,
moving on him and do,
he was like,
wait,
what wac leg kick again.
Oh Shit.
I got back and he's bounced it around on
him.
He's throwing jabs to the body.
And is that the cop right there to the
right and watching?
Yup.
Why?
Because if it goes to the ground,
it's over.
I don't know,
man.
I think in case the guy quits,
I guess if the guy quits,
the cop has to be there to say,
well then it's a salt.
After that,
it's no longer mutual combat.
Like he's just kicking the shit out of
his leg when we do,
it's moving forward just in a Zombie
state.
Now he doesn't know what the fuck's
going on and then the beating come down
and then the cop step in and separate
it.
I say,
okay,
that's enough.
That's a,
then they're like,
have a good night.
Yeah.
Good night,
sir.
No,
please don't care.
Exactly no paperwork because doing it in
front of the cops,
Washington state as some crazy mutual
combat law,
how do we get that pass across the
board?
It would stop a lot of fucking Jabber,
John.
Oh my God,
would it?
Oh Man,
wait.
It's not a people that say things they
don't really mean.
You know,
and they,
they open up possibilities.
They don't really want to take place
because alcohol,
yeah,
they get froggy.
Exactly.
Jump.
Now all of a sudden they got a jump.
Well that's why pots better,
but because that guy got so froggy,
he actually jumped and he didn't even
know how to jump,
which is the most ridiculous thing in
front of a cop on camera.
At least you could take an ass whipping
description of what happened here is
kind of interesting.
Who wrote this?
Just somebody somewhere.
I think it's whoever shot.
Oh,
he said F u n word and he was going to
walk away and leave and the guy said,
I'll fight you.
Right.
I'll take it to your house.
And then that's when he went to the
Commons.
All right,
we're going to fight them.
At this point,
Phoenix agrees to mutual combat the to
shake hands and the fight commences.
He says,
fuck you,
I'll bring this to your house.
Yeah.
And right before he beats the shit out
of the dude,
the dude says,
you know,
you don't want it up.
None of this.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
Combat.
Well that can only exist in like them
wild west dates.
Like you get that off in Arizona,
maybe New Mexico.
They could pull that off.
Tell him I'll never make it to
California,
California.
Me.
[inaudible] they'd be like,
we have to stop violence and guns.
You have any reasonable sides?
Is it both sides?
Yeah.
We have like a lot of people that came
over here to grow sprouts and I don't
think there's going to be much,
much mutual down in Compton.
No,
no,
no.
The yeah,
they have to learn how to fight first.
If you don't know how to fight,
that's when the guns come out.
It's really,
I wonder if mutual combat allows weapons
if you both have weapons.
No,
I think that's a,
that's not in the rules.
It's murder you.
Have you seen that shit?
They're doing a Russian now.
M ones have a night fights.
Knife fight night.
Like nights you dress up like a knight
armor and swords and Shit.
Fuck it.
Yeah.
I put it on my twitter.
I mean we treat it today.
I'll fucking,
the guy got killed by a sword to the
face,
dude.
You got to see this shit.
They hit each other in the head that
were in armor outfit Blips,
heavy pounds.
They're not moving very well.
I would bet it's heavier than that.
Like,
look at this.
They're jacking each other with these
fucking swords.
They're like modern night.
Gee.
Oh,
and the shield to the face.
Well,
there's some,
uh,
full speed versions of it,
Jamie,
where they look out there whacking each
other,
man.
I mean,
they got a blunt sword,
you think?
I think so.
I think they're probably blunt,
but they're big in the legs.
Behind the legs is not,
oh,
we need ladies in Guardian.
I'd be going for all of this.
You got to take down,
take down.
I mean,
this is real.
this would be real life if that would
happen.
Oh,
shielding him.
Lay down.
Oh my gosh.
She yelled at him in the head.
No,
I guess they stopped it.
He did on his own.
He was like,
okay.
Oh my God,
Dad.
Yeah.
Well,
they've got a good job.
He's trying to tap on the ground.
He's done.
Wow.
Man,
that is crazy.
There's no rule where they're finding
what's awesome too.
Yeah.
They're going to get there in a field.
It looks like a place where people would
fight with swords.
The Shire.
Aw.
Hell yes.
Look it up.
Look at his face to meet up.
Oh yeah,
man.
He took some sorts of the head.
That is a fucked up sport.
That's a tough dude right there.
This is next level shit,
right?
I mean this was,
sign me up.
I don't even know how to yield to soar.
Bell duty.
You.
And if so,
if this starts happening in the United
States,
you're down.
Look,
what the fuck.
Come on.
Five sweat.
Oh my God.
This is the second ax.
Look how big that guy is.
I don't want even want to hear it.
Oh he has.
He has a real life acts.
Well this,
this is the only way to fight it out
with the act.
Grabbed my all.
What?
Oh Shit.
This is instead he killed that dude.
He hit that too.
Fucking x.
What do you look up for this so people
can fucking do this fight.
I am Cf.
I am c f 2015 five on five France versus
New Zealand.
They have night fights.
This is a new day.
Had those guys had axes and macy's and
they hit a hit that dude in the head
with the ax seven times.
Yeah,
right.
He's dead.
What the fuck?
Cowboy man,
he got in trouble there because he's put
the blade,
that dude's throat,
you know,
you know allowed to do that jump kick
and then put it to his throat.
Oh my God,
I can't do that.
He said,
dude,
you can seriously cut his head off.
The referee stopped too violent.
Yeah,
but the guy who long before two dudes
dress up and Samurai outfits with no
fucking armor and go at it.
How?
How can you take an ax to the head six
times?
You can't.
Obviously one guy went down like,
yeah,
but I mean how can is that?
There's no blood.
Look at the cause of his helmet.
I want the mace look.
This is so crazy.
Fighting for points to and says,
God,
you can't stab.
I haven't seen any stabbing going on
because I feel like that'd be my move.
Well,
here's what's unrealistic about it in
the real world and if the two on one
like this,
they would be stabbing each other for
sure.
His fights,
it'd be quicker.
So like there's something about like
using these blunt objects and not being
able to stab each other.
That makes it almost more ridiculously
brutal.
This is a crazy fuck how big that is.
That's the mountain.
This is awesome.
They tackle each other,
I think when you're down,
you're down.
Yeah.
He seems confident.
I wouldn't be confident if I was in the
war.
I'd be,
that guy was to stab me in the Dick.
I got to get up now.
How crazy would warby,
how fucking crazy would old time,
warby old time barbarian style sword,
sword,
macy's.
Like if you're the guy and you're
choosing,
what would you be your weapon?
So I'm like,
oh,
for sure.
For sure.
Sit on the rate.
Yeah.
Imagine being the guy like,
Yep.
Grabbing your macy's just like you.
You walk into the onnit academy in your
life.
10 1220 or the fucking three headed 30
pounder and you're like,
that's mine.
What do you have six good swings out of?
Yeah,
maybe.
Especially if your guy doesn't train and
they weren't really trained in that
month and then you're fatigued and dying
and some dude's cutting your head off
and you get to see that sword right when
it,
when it hits your neck,
but a man went to the actual life.
You're six,
you're six good.
You're,
you're lifting people off their feet.
This Nicholas 21 versus 21 tiny pig pin.
They have men.
So you s is here.
Oh my God.
Battle of the nations.
It's called and I hate to tell you,
but I just don't think the US is going
to do very well now against the
Russians.
Well,
I mean I just don't,
I just don't know of us has much night.
Jesus Christ.
Lynch's dewey.
No,
we don't see when the age of 19 zero
right Arrow,
but does Russia,
they ever lineage and knighting the
Scottish or the English team?
Yeah,
they write braveheart style.
Our style for sure wins every year.
I mean,
when you look at mma and how crazy Emma
May as in comparison to boxing and how
people have embraced it,
this is like if they've figured out a
way to regrow limbs,
if they figured out a way,
like we're 100% if you get your arm cut
off,
they can grow that bitch back.
People are doing this,
man,
you can't regrow your heart back or your
head.
It's true.
It's,
you can't stab in the heart.
Can't cut their head off,
but you can come down.
That'd be like a three point stance.
Yes or no.
No kicks in the Dick.
That'd be,
you can't,
no,
no heart piercing and no head shopping.
Yeah,
that would be the rules.
But you can cut a guy's arm off and they
immediately seal it up real quick and
they rushed him to the hospital.
You won by Kao cut his arm off or can
you still fight?
You grow a new arm.
And a couple of weeks later he's at the
press conference,
a little baby arm.
He's like,
fuck cowboy.
You know,
next time what?
Sue's my arm goes back,
I'm gonna kick his ass right now.
I got a little baby arm.
This motherfucker,
you getting bigger every day.
I'm taking steps on rollback.
You can come back to big or,
yeah,
it's,
I think it's like a sprout.
It's how it has some salad.
It has them girl,
and then it has to stretch out and grow.
Yeah.
That's what I would think along the way.
Like all alligator arm,
like an alligator doesn't just grow a
goal.
The whole thing just just pop out.
They start slowly.
They regrow.
There's,
yeah,
they were grow.
There's no,
she,
I didn't know that Gary asked fuckers
gainers.
There's a scary lizards regrow their
legs.
Wow.
I got a little gators.
I call it those.
My friends,
they call them gators.
Hang out on the boat and eat all the
food,
drink all the alcohol,
and it comes when it comes time to fill
out bitch up,
there's little arms.
Can't reach their wallets.
Oh,
those kinds of,
that's like t rex arms,
the gators.
But you can't make shoes out of them.
But I was cool.
That was cool at all.
The gators day gators.
When I was a kid,
I used to live in Florida.
We lived near a lake.
Alice in Gainesville and uh,
alligators were endangered when I was a
kid.
Yeah.
Like they were telling people not to
feed them because people throw
marshmallows and the water.
Why did you like marshmallows so much?
I don't know.
They love him though.
And the gators would eat the
marshmallow,
but it was cool to do.
We would get marshmallows and throw them
in the water and then they started
telling you can't do it.
They don't digest them well like these
are in danger.
We have to take care of them.
And then from then on they just slowly
but surely overwhelmed to the point
where like,
okay,
you can hunt them,
can shoot 500 of them a year.
Like they have tags were 500 alligators
can get killed by one dude.
500 500 that's some serious hunting.
Yeah.
That's some serious one and a half a
day.
Yeah.
Every day.
Well,
they only have a season,
so they're doing way more than one a
day,
but they do an all bunch of different
ways of doing lines.
They put they date,
they swallow a hook.
Is that what's going on?
And then they're just,
and the thrash around you shoot him in
the head.
Right,
but they're,
they're essentially on a hook in their
belly.
Exactly.
You ever see swamp people?
I do,
but I just didn't ever grasp like the
hook him in the mouth or it's in their
gut.
It's sometimes to the mouth.
It's like fishing sometimes.
I mean if you have a,
a line for a catfish,
you lay out a line.
Like a lot of times you'll catch them
though they're barely hooked.
Sometimes you catch and it's hooked.
They're hooked deep.
So they,
that's the same thing they do.
And then they pull them in and they
shoot them,
but they can shoot 500 of this.
I was watching that swamp people show
and they were,
the guy had a tag limit of 500
alligators.
What is a a gator pay?
It's a good question.
And what do they do with the gator
besides make bitching ass boots for me
then make bitch ass boots for you.
They make a,
I mean to eat gator belt.
Yes.
Apparently it's the highest in protein
[inaudible] Papa dose.
And then you can get an appetizer
alligator,
but you're getting some frozen bullshit,
which you really want to do apparently
according to all the New Mexico,
I think it's fresh alligator.
But my friend John Dudley is the
alligator hunter.
He hunts alligators occasionally and he
shoots with a bow and Arrow and he says,
uh,
that they're delicious.
If you get the,
the gator tail like right after the or
dies,
it's delicious.
It's super lean.
You don't Cook it very long.
It's like one of those things that you
cook it like,
you know,
like you,
uh,
I guess you'd have to cook pork.
I don't know.
I wonder if they get tricker gnosis like
a pig does.
That's a good question.
I'm sure they live in a nasty swamp.
Yeah.
But I wonder if they're like susceptible
to it.
Cause like when they eat it,
I wonder if their body breaks it down in
the same way our body does or a pig's
body does or a or a bear or even a
mountain lion.
That's where all the cases a trick and
osis come from.
But when they,
uh,
they do that,
apparently it's delicious.
We take a,
an alligator freshly killed alligator.
It's supposed to be real and super high
protein higher than even like Moose.
Really higher than Bison.
Higher than anything.
Supposed to be good.
500 a tag.
And how many tags are given out?
I don't know.
It's a good question,
but I to get rid of them.
It's their 10 guys with 500 a piece or
is there,
I mean,
what's the,
it's a good question.
I don't know,
but I know that there's a surplus.
There's too many alligators.
Like they,
they're everywhere.
Whenever I'm down wakeboarding in
Florida,
I see him all the time in the water
with,
it's like God dammit.
Gattard did you see that one video where
that fucking gator walked on the golf
course and it's a 15 footer.
Fucking,
you've seen it.
We can't show it because those fucking
people,
they got my facebook pulled down.
Whoever owns that gators putting that
video on why he claimed it was their
video or saw it didn't link to a youtube
video or something while that's why
they're trying to make money off of it.
We'll look at,
we can see it.
Look at that thing walking across the
golf course.
Look how big that is.
That's the gate of the book.
It's so huge and you get it into
perspective when the guy comes into
focus in a little bit,
cause the guys filming this and a few
minutes to dude walks out and see now
you get,
you understand how big it is when you
see that guy in front.
I understood how big he and literally
walked past the huge sand trap.
Look how tall he is too.
That's what's weird was like how long
their legs are.
He didn't and he hangs out at whole nine
in the fucking in a little pond.
Florida is so fucked up dude.
Look how big he is.
How old are those?
Oh it's gotta be an old alligator.
Wow.
I don't know how old he is,
but he's been eating a lot of dogs.
Wow.
Yeah.
I would eat that.
You need fuck.
Yeah.
How do you kill a gator?
Shoot him in the head.
You got to shoot him in the head.
Head shot.
Yeah.
It's got to literally be,
there's a very small area you're
shooting at too,
like right behind the eyes with a bow
and arrow.
You could do it.
Yeah,
same.
Same.
Yeah.
That one though,
man.
God Damn.
There's another angle on them.
Look how big he is.
His mouth.
Just look at it's fucking tail.
I mean it doesn't even look real.
Like if that was in a movie,
you'd be like,
fuck that.
That's not real.
Lake placid.
That's the little class it alligator.
How much does he need to eat to sustain
that little walk he's doing?
Oh my God.
I would imagine two dogs today.
I imagine they eat a lot of fucking
thought he'd done that.
Was it game over sun and lays out what
the fuck closest guy get up to this
insane people are living right next to
dinosaurs.
That's a fucking dinosaur tail on that
thing.
Mine.
God,
that is an insane animal.
What do you think?
15 feet does it say?
Yeah.
They said it's 1515.
They estimated wow.
Easily 15 feet.
It's an enormous,
that's the high end.
I was like the 1% or of alligators.
Yeah,
that's impressive.
Let's bring this bitch home.
Donald Cowboy cerrone.
So I think we've worked out a few
things.
We have one,
uh,
one 70 stay at 170 pounds.
Uh,
I'm the new manager and then we'll go
straight from me to Chris Brown to DMT
dmt.
That's important.
And a America,
America,
but tell Budweiser,
relax.
Um,
don't eat this any mansion as well.
Definitely don't swallow that.
It's don't be scared of oysters.
Other than that,
I think we covered it.
We got it.
This is fun,
man.
We got to do this more often.
Hey,
how'd a great fucking time,
Donald Cowboy Cerrone,
ladies and gentlemen,
you can catch them on twitter.
Cowboy cerrone,
catch him on Instagram,
cowboy serone and an x five,
two oh five [inaudible] square guard.
Is that what's going to happen?
For sure.
Is that all?
Well,
we'll be able to tonight,
allegedly exactly what it is,
but it's going to be epic,
epic,
epic.
Thank you,
brother.
It was awesome.
I enjoyed it.
We add a here.
Goodnight everybody
[inaudible]
okay.
Hm.