Recording.
We're broadcasting the Joe
Rogan experience podcast
is brought to you by the
fleshlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net and
click on the link for fleshlight,
you, uh, entering the code name
Rogan, and you get 15% off,
would that said Brian Post saying is
here, buckle up bitches. Here we go.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Yeah. I have no excuse for
the order. We do things then.
It seems so official though. It seems
like it's now a real show. Sure.
Before we were just sitting around going,
what is this fucking thing going to
start is the other ones I've gone to are
just bullshit
compared to this
fucking Mark Marin and
Brian Pro San Ladies and gentlemen. Good
to see you, buddy. Good to see you, man.
I've been reading crazy, crazy things
about you and marijuana that you have.
Oh Shit. Yeah. Go like sacred. Yeah.
It's so weird that got out there. Like,
who cares?
Common QuickCare quit pot,
dude. People kids are going
to do now. I got nothing.
Any changes that you make in your
life. Radical changes. People.
There's going to be arguments,
message boards, debates. Uh,
I was really surprised and then uh,
people are mad at me cause I'm
doing a gathering of the Juggalos.
I heard about that as well. I think I lost
a few fans. Why? Wow. People are like,
what the fuck dude, why are you doing?
I thought you were cooler than that.
Like if people are like, that
is so not metal in a, you know,
it's metal getting a nice paycheck so my
kid can go to nursery school next year.
That's, that's pretty much super
metal. Well you know, it's also,
and it's going to be an
experience as you go.
If somebody offered you a nice check
to go, very possibly. Very possibly.
I would think about it. I'm called
God, what the fuck would I say?
What bits would I do where
they gotta to go? You know,
I'd have to like figure out
how to edit it and do it right.
I have to do fine on it.
I have two months to do that.
Like it's in August and so I've got
time to prepare. You know what, man,
there's the cynical in 25 minutes and I'm
falling. Harland Williams who's a yeah,
it'll be fun. Like yeah, he'll get up
there and go uh, you know, platypus.
Vagina and I'll go, okay,
I get to follow that.
What is the concert for people that
don't know? Cause I, I, yes, yes.
The, the gathering of the Juggalos
is all the insane clown posse.
It's all, and it's a fee. It's
to me it's a very fascinating,
fascinating movement
because I kind of look,
it's so easy to poke fun at them.
It's so easy to point a finger,
but it's also like I kinda identify
with disenfranchised people.
Most of them were really given a
shitty fucking hand in life. Yeah.
That's what my,
that's why family is like their big thing
that they say at this thing and these
insane clown posse concerts,
they'll say family, IDL, a family.
Like we're all like together. They
feel like they're a part of something.
And how has that bad,
no, I know that's part of why I said
yes to it. I was like, you know,
in another world I could have
been one of these kids. You know,
cause I was a mutant that sat at home
reading comic books and listening to iron
maiden and didn't have a family,
you know,
didn't have other guys that would
like the same shit as me, you know,
so at least they've got that,
you know?
I mean we can't have been in that
situation. Yeah. And people, yeah.
People in the Internet
really poked fun at them.
Like they do the shitty band there.
And two is so much better
than the insane clown.
Posse says the arctic monkeys
something billion levels above the ICP.
Write something really obscure.
But yeah,
that you can only get at Amoeba and
people were like almost disappointed.
I can tell, you know, when their tweets,
you know you only got 140 characters,
but it's still like, oh dude, why are
you doing that? You know? And it's like,
why do people care what you're doing
first now, if you're still doing,
you're still being you.
You're still doing your am not going to
throw a clown makeup on and go out and
throw my feces at everybody. You know,
why not? As long as he filmed it,
make a youtube video. Yeah.
Fuck it. That's the other thing.
I'm going to do my thing there.
I'm going to see how that goes over and
I'm going to have experienced stuff's
going to happen to me that night when I
fly out there and go to this crazy cause
it's out in the middle of nowhere.
That's the other thing about it.
Like where is it? Uh,
it's out in Illinois,
but like some place I've never heard of.
So this is a national thing.
People fly in from all across the country
and these guys are fucking gigantic
right now, aren't they? Yeah,
they're pretty big. So yeah.
But you never hear their music? No. Nobody
so strange. They played them on MTV,
like in the 90s when they first
broke and then everybody went,
oh these guys suck.
And then they kind of,
those are what I love about
them is they went dick,
they wanted to keep doing it and they
went underground and they went like made
their own label and these guys
have made a fortune, you know, uh,
putting their own stuff out,
which is like, you know,
a lot of comics that we know
that do that thing. You know,
like don't go for comedy central records.
I'm going to go to those other places.
And I kind of respect that,
you know,
that they've been able to build this
crazy fan base out of and most people had
never heard their shit at all.
Right.
Yeah. There's something interesting
about it and like I said,
they obviously appealed to a very certain,
a distinct group that need something,
right. It needs someone, you know,
I mean what we were talking about
earlier about the pot thing about people
freaking out about you quitting pot.
That is also a part of a movement.
And there's a lot of people that like to
think that, hey man, you know, for 20,
you know,
and Bob for 20 on Twitter and they want
to think that they're part of this thing
too.
And then if you leave this thing somehow,
I know that you make it a decision
to do something different with your
consciousness that you're leaving
this group, you're leaving the
Sandman. Well, you know what,
that's a big part of it.
That's a big part of why I quit is I
didn't want to be that guy anymore.
And I get why some people
like to still be that guy,
but for me will the big part,
it wasn't working anymore.
And I just have always been
one of those people that like,
I always hated people that went into Aa
and, or you know, or like I did cut. Okay.
I messed around with coke and I messed
around with crystal meth and dumb shit
like that. He's really, yeah.
Yeah. Well like before I
knew it was really bad. Like,
you know, I moved to Phoenix in
1986 and that's like where uh,
crystal meth was invented
pretty much. Wow. You know,
and a rate at that time and uh, it
wasn't a big deal but, and I did it,
I messed around and then I was
able to just go, this is stupid.
I don't want to do it anymore. So I've
always been that kind of gay and part,
you know,
I smoked for 20 something years and I
was an every day guy and an all day guy
and I just didn't like the way I was
feeling anymore and it just wasn't working
too. Like, do you ever get like that?
Like did you ever take
your tire blunt and it's,
and you don't even feel any different
than you did before you lit up the board?
I'm a huge proponent of marijuana,
but I'm also a big proponent of moderation
and pretty much everything every day.
I don't smoke every day.
This is when I smoked.
I smoked before I know I'm going to fuck
my wife smoke before I get some sex.
I smoked. Sometimes we're going to go
on a date when he gets some good food.
I small global, then I smoked before I
write comedy. I smoked before I do comedy.
I smoked before, do Jujitsu before
movies, before video game, before I moved.
So this is like,
there's a few times where a whole day
will go by and none of those things will
happen. And I want smoke pot
and it doesn't affect me.
Or when I go on vacations,
I go on vacations, I go on vacations
with like five, six days and no pot.
And I never feel bad. I
just feel like me, you know,
I enjoy the feeling of marijuana,
but I also think it's good to know who
the fuck you are outside of the influence
of all these things.
Right.
And for some people have to
go back at some point and uh,
and do it the way you're talking
or maybe not even that much, but,
but do it like when I'm going to see
rush going to see the new eczema could,
but I want to,
I want to give it,
I want to get it out in my
system completely on how
long, right? Three months.
Yeah. And just went cold Turkey. Yeah.
It's easier when you have children too.
And I know you have a,
and that was the big thing.
Like I talked about it on what
the Fuck Marin's thing. But uh,
one of the things is it got,
I don't know about where you smoke here,
but it got delegated to outside
because of the kid. And before he came,
when my wife was pregnant, we have
a smart house. But anyway, I there,
I couldn't smoke in my office anymore
and I couldn't smoke in the living room.
So then I became the outside guy.
And so it felt kind of dirty.
Like I need to have a shed that I was
going out to in the back. But I was,
you know, and it's a nice
place, but I'm out by my pool,
just kind of feeling like a scumbag,
you know, out there by myself.
Just to kind of get day.
I always do it outside just so
my house doesn't smell like weed.
Like we did it inside today
just cause I got this new thing.
It's a hemp wick instead of a lighter,
you light it with a
lighter and then the it,
the hemp is like a wick and
it's made out of hemp rope.
So it lasts a long time as
opposed to, well no, no, no, it's,
it's to light it instead
of using a lighter,
because I do use a lighter and I'd
smoke it out of a pipe, I'd go, Ooh,
I smelled a lighter. I smell that
fluid. I tasted a little bit. Yeah,
that's shit can't be good for now. So
this hemp WIC, I started doing this,
but it wouldn't work outside.
It was windy so we smoked it inside.
But I have an air cleaner in my office
that I had on before the show and I,
but most of the time I'm a joint guy
and most of the time I go outside,
I do it on purpose. But yeah, I've
had the, I just had a debate at home.
I've had that the wife conversation now
does she smoke it all? Not right now.
She did, but then she had two babies
in a row and the first one, you know,
she breastfed for a year
as she did the second one.
And so that was like the baby's born,
the baby lives for a year and
then she's pregnant again.
And then the baby born the
baby breastfeeds for a year.
It's been a long time since she smoked
pot. So you miss it. Do you know?
She's down. She's almost ready
but, but um, the um, you know,
the, the, the effects to me are
important, but like anything else,
they can be abused. Just
like masturbation. I think
masturbation is great,
but I've had points in my life
where I was beaten off three,
four fucking times a day and and
beating off when I wasn't even hard.
I would just keep going. I go
monkey. I think we all have, I mean
comics and it was like combined with the
weed to doing it in a shitty hotel room
most of the time.
So the process does something really
depressing about hotel rooms when you're
high blown it out the window.
Just sitting there with my flacid common
threat I think,
you know,
he's like don't want to watch
just as like seen everything else.
Yeah, like eighties movies. Yeah.
Check from sex and the city was hot.
Remember she played a mannequin
that came to life at the trial.
She was fucking mannequin.
Yeah.
I can see what you were talking
about. You were doing, you were,
you had a pretty extreme pot thing going
on. They all day, everyday pot thing.
Is it
that totally makes it not work.
And I got,
I've had been to that point before and
then I take like three days off and then
the weed works again automatically.
You know,
for years I wasn't awakened bake
guy and then it just became,
if I didn't have a job,
if I didn't have a writing job I was going
to in the morning I wake and bake and
then you know what I'm supposed to be
like trying to write things to sell or,
or work on my own act or you know,
write a book and it's just
fucking impossible when you
start smoking at 10:00 AM
or at least for me.
Yeah, I think everybody's got a
different biochemistry cause for me, man,
I smoke and that's when
I do my best writing.
I smoke and I sit down and I just get
into the groove and I just lose myself and
there's a window for
me. There's a window for jokes.
I mean, I've written, you know,
the last 20 years of my standup,
most of those jokes have been written
high and so that's kind of a challenge for
me now is like to see,
see what happens,
not high to see what the
materials like has it changed?
Have you noticed any change? Shit.
What about your sets on stage?
Uh, they're feeling good
though. They're actually,
I'm way more focused and a faster like
a faster rhythm speak because I'm more
present. Um, my wife's definitely
noticed that just in talking to me.
Like when I walk into the house she's
like, Whoa, you're like, you know,
you're not hey man. Yeah, yeah. That,
what kind of plot did you smoke? Uh,
you know, that's the other thing.
Like I've never been one of those
guys that knows every strain. But uh,
what's the one that puts you to sleep?
Yeah.
Diva. Oh, they're so different, man.
It's really like talking about
two totally different things.
It's almost like talking about
alcohol versus a stimulant. I mean,
there so completely different.
Do you find your self having
problems being around it now?
Like he hung hang out with Doug Benson.
Me Like I can't Damon.
And I don't even know if he
knows. I quote. He texted me,
he texted me right before the show,
make sure you ask Brian about
quitting pot cause you know,
Doug flies that fucking fly high crowd
to him and he's like, what the fuck?
You know, I'm the guy that started
him on that road. Really? Yeah.
It wasn't really a smoker and I bought
him his first pipe first moved down there.
He didn't know. He, you know, he
did. He did occasionally done it, uh,
when he'd come up to San
Francisco and hang out with us.
But I moved down to La and he and I had
a writing gig together for MTV and like
94. And uh, at that point was
not a stoner at all. And uh,
I was already and uh,
you know,
just got Amanda the everyday thing and
then he's one of the biggest donor comics
while you're his sensei area,
since he is kind of,
it was just to be so hard for him.
It must be really weird. Yeah.
Have you seen Doug on that
old curb your enthusiasm?
It doesn't even look like him.
He looks like this clean cut gentlemen.
It's so weird on that. No.
How Caribbean enthusiasm.
But he's only not that old. Yeah.
Five, six years ago. So weird.
It's totally different. Yeah. And like
in what way? What looks different?
She really clean cut back then.
I don't know.
I mean of course it was probably
his character also. But yeah,
I mean he just looked very
different anyway. So He's,
has he contacted you about
it? No, we haven't talked.
Uh, obviously he's concerned.
It's hilarious.
And I'm hanging out with Sarah this week.
Who was another one in my pothead
friends, you know, Sarah Silverman.
So it'll be weird like to be at
the Improv and not go around back.
You know, that uh, that alley where, uh,
we've been smoking for
15 years. Have you? Um,
you got to try it. Well, if you ever
do, you got to try sativas before. If,
if you ever decide, I mean
don't do whatever the fuck
you want to do, but no man,
if you ever decide this is a different
thing, you know who to somebody,
one of my friends was like,
oh, you're taking a sabbatical.
And at first I was like, what a
stoner thing to say. Like, like that,
I'm for sure going to
come back. But, uh, I,
I don't want to be back to what I was.
And so the idea, like I said, yeah,
I'd love to get to the point, I'm going
to see Russia next month or next week.
You have to, and I'm not going to
do it with this next rush show,
but next year when they come back,
you know,
I'd love to then be
able to go and you know,
when they play passage to Bangkok and
you're right on, what's your goal?
Like what's your time wise goal? Do you
have like a milestone a year, you know,
and I'm using the program, which you're
going to the classes. So you be somebody,
you say the program you're doing, you're
doing an alcoholics anonymous. Yes, I am.
Yeah. Yeah. Why did you decide to do that
instead of this club right now? Well, no,
I've taught, Nah, well, here's the
reason I'm going to, you know, this is,
it sounds like a joke, but, and
it will be a joke at some point,
but I'm not big of a map of a
loser to go to Ebay. I think
it's just pot. You know, it's, it's a
couple of hundred bucks a month, you know,
there's gonna be guys like,
you know,
I just told my mom for heroin
and shit like that. You know,
we're where the stories are way more than
Brent material for me. Yeah, no, I know.
Certainly. Well, this is going
to be a huge bit for sure. Yeah.
That's all kind of a fascinating thing,
isn't it? It's true. When the hard drugs,
the really hard ones, man,
those stories are horrific.
That's the dehumanizing drugs.
I just felt like I'd be the biggest
pussy in the ram if I went to an Aa
from, uh, from,
from half baked that happens in that
I wasn't, they had a meeting. Oh no,
no one ever suck cock for pot.
I'll, okay. It was a Bob sad sack.
That's probably a scene. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. Oh, I to watch that again. No,
that'll make me want to get high.
Have you ever thought about doing the Dr
Jury Show? That would be pretty funny.
We get tonight, are you? I'm doing
the regular blah, blah. Any Rehab?
No, no, no. It wasn't.
I don't know what they
showed me the career too.
I actually still work true,
dude. You don't understand.
You're not sort of quote unquote
in the business you do that.
It's over you celebrity basically saying
I suck and I have for a long time.
You don't just say,
you're not just saying be packing
in and that's what you're saying.
You're saying,
I really don't have anywhere to turn
and willing to be in this house for six
weeks because I need a paycheck.
Right.
The only two people that do it or if
you're desperate for attention in some way
or another, you're going to
think you're gonna f fashion.
Some reality show career. Again,
those people are real drug addicts.
Almost everybody except the
weak people. Yeah. Well,
there was only one weed
guy ever, right? No,
I think there was more than one wrapper.
The wrapper was a week to some girl.
Well the worst one was Eric Roberts.
Eric Roberts was there for weed.
The fucking guy.
There's nothing wrong it is that what his,
everyone's shaking and wedding and
it was weed. He's drinking coffee,
reading the newspaper. Not only did he
fucking smoke weed, he used a vaporizer.
So he's doing it healthy. Right.
He's like, I just thought he's,
I think he just want to get the fuck
away from his wife. Just like, honey,
I've gotta be there for six weeks,
six weeks. That wasn't a good dude.
Just died. Didn't need from a
grease. Uh, yes. Yeah. That was sad.
That was a sad part of that show
and I thought, yeah, he was,
he was on my dead pool cause he was,
he was in the class. I really have one,
but a Conaway Jeff Conway.
And he apparently he had
some serious infection.
Didn't know he had the infection
because he was high on time.
He was so messed up on that show.
He was hard to watch. It was hard.
I've only watched a few episodes of
that show. I watched one with, um,
Heidi Fleiss,
which I thought was fascinating and I
watched the recent one with that. Uh,
the old model lady. Oh, he's
really kind of nutty. Yeah.
What's a haggard? Yeah. I don't know,
but it's fascinating because she's got
this young boyfriend. It's really weird.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Fuck that monster. Well,
I think he's probably a
regular guy probably works in
a supermarket or something.
So for him it's like, you know,
it's Janice Dickinson still. Yeah.
But she's horrible to
look at. It's scary. Well,
do you remember getting old?
Having an old person's face is not
nearly as scary as having an old person's
face that's been cut up to try
to appear younger. Yeah. That,
those are surgery in this city,
like terrific. My wife hates it,
but I'll like, I'll whisper to my kid,
you know, and he's only two, but I'll go,
look, there's monsters, monsters,
let's call it, I always call
it monster face. It's, it's,
it's like I was watching a,
I'm one of those Joan Rivers things.
It was on comedy central. I swear
to God, Bro, for 15 minutes.
I didn't absorb a word they said.
I was just concentrating on her face
and how her, how terrifying. It's a cat.
They're turning into cats. It's a
mask. It's what it is. It's not moving.
It's so obvious. It's like filled up
with something. It's going to melt event,
whatever the fuck. It's
so scary. It's not good.
Did you ever see the SQL to escape
from New York escape from la?
Yeah, I did probably, but I
don't remember it. Not Great.
But at one point Bruce Campbell
plays, uh, do you remember this? Yeah.
Bruce Campbell plays a plastic surgeon
that has basically created these monsters
and this 10 years ago before you really
saw these girls flooding around La.
And so that was the one moment of the
movie that kind of works because it's
carpenters saying, look out like
this shit is, you know, it's on.
It's why I'm probably not the
right thing. Yeah, that's,
it didn't really exist back in the day.
They're all like island of Doctor
Moreau who just kind of horrible face
facelifts had been around for a long
time. Right. Pull the face back.
But this is a new error when
they going not slips. Yeah. Yeah.
They do the lips and they
do the cheeks and shit.
There was a hot girl down syndrome,
hot girl down syndrome because all
the girls start to look the same.
Like Down Syndrome. Johnny
Carson to kind of, they all did.
They all have the same look.
You didn't know her Miss Mom Syndrome.
Kids always have that same look in
the eyes and the same. It's horrible.
But it's true. It is true. It
is that, that's monster face.
They get that giant mouth. It looks like
you got to bite your fucking head off.
Yeah. Lisa rented took care of her is
finally cause I think so. How did she,
I don't know. She took, she got a
deflated or something. Some of the,
I know a woman who had it done and then
she had it taken out and it's just, it's,
her lips are terrifying now.
The whole thing is a mass.
Before she had a mind of her feet.
Big Scar too. It was real weird.
Like you'd be talking to her and it was
so obvious that her lips are pumped up.
But it would be also weird because her,
when she would move,
you'd see the scar inside her lips.
The God damn who,
who said that should be legal. That's
craziness. You're fucking with your lips,
man. Looks he kiss him, he
can feel it in the lips.
You can feel like a little fucking hard
gelatin in their lips and you see it in
regular places.
Like if you got a, I've been
shooting this thing out in Ann Arbor,
Michigan and you don't see these girls
walking around. Right? But yeah, here,
here's especially where you, yeah, you
go to the grocery store in Calabasas.
Fuck yeah.
It's all monster faces out here.
60 year old lady trying to look 45
but it's working well. The worst.
Is Newport beach ever going around
there? No, not in. Why that whole area?
That area's really rich and really
like nice and it's like, you know,
everyone's driving Maserati's and everyone
through Irvine Improv, which is close.
Like there's people that make the trek.
Yeah.
You see a lot of monster faces out there.
Poor women.
Poor women talked into
brutalizing their face.
Those husbands let them or paint for it,
I'm guessing. Yeah. Or they just gave in.
I just gave in and he didn't want to
listen anymore. It's just like, all right.
All right. All right. Do you want to
get your fucking lips done? You know,
and surprise it. Do you ever
think maybe they're just, uh,
did you know the worst nuclear disaster
in the world happened in Simi Valley in
1959? Here we were taught they
were just, that's not true.
It sure it's not the worst nuclear
disaster ever. Not even close. Well,
this shit going on in Japan right
now. Yeah, you're wrong, bro.
The shit going on in Japan
right now is unbelievable.
The United States. No, no, no,
no. Three Mile Island. No, this is
240 times more than that accident.
Why that's are you getting, there's this
is like above top secret.com. No, this,
this, this, this happened
in 1959 and they, uh,
it was 240 times more than the accident
at three mile island and they kind of
covered it up and uh,
somebody sent this to me the other day
and there's actually like news stories
all about it.
There's a Wikipedia page all about
this and I never knew about that,
but it was just kind of odd that we lived
for accurate.
So you,
I assume you're talking about is
Rocketdyne him about the Rocketdyne? Yeah,
I don't think they have all
the information about that.
I think a huge amount of what they're
saying about what the damage and all the,
it's all speculation what happened
out there. They did a lot of tests.
Rocket Dyne is where they mean when
they were involved in the space program.
I'll throw the, you know, through the
Vietnam warm and there's all sorts of,
they're there,
you know,
they basically make arms
and fucking spaceship parts
and shit. There's a lot of,
you know,
it's doing a lot of nutty things up there,
but it's not one of the worst
disasters in the world. Do you?
People wouldn't be able to live here.
It'd be fucking six arm babies and
dogs be born with no ears. There's not,
it's not
from what the, the, the,
what I heard is there was a,
something happened there and instead of
like most of these nuclear reactors have
these huge concrete Glo,
uh, Dome's over them.
So if there is a leak or some
kind of radiation, it's covered.
But this was like kind of a test facility.
So they didn't have all these ex,
they didn't have to have all these
extra things and all these extra gauges.
It's 2011. We can't be having
these, what I heard conversations,
I'm looking at it right now. I could
play the audio for you, but I mean,
but what are you looking at the
history channel? history.com. Let me
tell you something about
the history channel.
You know what gets on the history
channel, Ufo shows, go shows, robot shows.
Okay this is, this is what you need
to know about the history channel.
It's a network.
And what they do is they buy programming,
they want ratings and they want things
to, but they don't verify the, you know,
the claims. They don't make sure
that everything is peer reviewed.
The talking about the history channel's
had a bunch of shows, pro and con,
JFK assassination,
pro conspiracy con conspiracy.
So for you know,
just the sake of everybody's brain,
you can't just,
but isn't that weird though to think
that the one of the craziest cities,
you know is Los Angeles and everything
like that and we have these people that
are turning into nick cats,
they look like cat women and we never
even think about like our air pollution is
so bad.
Imagine it being also mixed with toxic
shit cause I guess the rods that are in a
nuclear reactor, I guess when they act
they, something happened and they shut,
shut it down. And then they were
like, okay, I think it's okay.
And they turned it on for two more weeks
and then they shut it off again and
there were like, like, I
forget how many rods I courses
session Brian, because we don't really
know the real story. We can't, you know,
this is,
this is so frustrating.
Call the cops live out there
too, man. See there all the time.
Radioactive fucking Zombie cops. Well
anyways, you got to read about it.
If you just type in,
we would know about that.
I feel like we would know
about that. Where's that big
of a disaster? I mean, maybe
nothing happened,
but it was that big.
I just don't see that you
would avoid the effects of it.
That shit was in the 60s and
the 70s right? Wasn't it?
1950 [inaudible] I just assume we would
know about 59 apparently Japan has a
melt through now cover man,
that's government.
That's way we're hipsters
came from fucking, no,
just radiation has nothing to do
with these cat ladies are hipsters.
These cat ladies are there because they're
trying to hang silver lake douchebags
go weird mustaches somehow. The
rods and the air. Weird Mustache,
fucking skinny pants,
all those broken rides.
The, um, the radiation
is not doing that. Brian,
did you see your big movie
fan or did you see it,
the new super eight movie yet? Not yet.
No. No. You guys are talking about it.
Is it true?
There's rumors.
I heard that you played dungeons and
dragons with a u and a couple of guys like
pat and all that get together and
still play dungeons and dragons.
But, uh, right before we had kids, we did,
we were the only d and d group to ever
stop because three of the guys got their
wives pregnant.
Like,
I don't think that's ever happened before
in the history of d and d don't think
so. You don't think somewhere in
Ohio, some guys had to pull the plug.
They're not fucking,
I used to hear about that and just draw.
So tell me about, tell me about this. What
did you do you get together? Just years?
It was me. Uh, it started
with my buddy Gerry Duggan.
He writes for g four, and he was a, he and
I wrote a comic book together. And, uh,
we were just talking one night
with another friend going, hey man,
we'd love to get a d and d group gone.
And this goes like, I want to be a DM.
He's like, you know, I haven't DM to get,
what is it? The Emory [inaudible] guest?
Yeah, yeah. He's the guy
that runs the show. Right.
And it doesn't, they don't play a,
they basically, uh, you know, right.
The whole adventure for you or use those,
um, you know, use the books and uh,
you know,
basically walk you through the thing.
And so we went to a couple of friends
and it won't want to be in patent as well
and our blend capacity and I'm
sure you know, and then, uh, um,
Chris Hardwick was in our
group for a while too, so,
and it was a lot of fun and it makes
it basically, we called it nerd poker,
I called it nerd poker because it
just became a way of, you know,
when your friends get busy and shit,
and it's like the only way you can kind
of hang out with them is to have like a
ritual, you know what I mean? And that's
what it was. We don't play poker and,
and uh, you know, we had the video game,
like when Halo first started having those
land parties, yeah, we would do that.
And that was like a regular thing too.
But then that kind of went away. You know,
it'd be like 16 of us with four TVS on
for people on four TVs and that was a lot
of fun and a, that kind of
shit. The bed and, and uh,
we got this d and d game going and
that became a way of, hey honey, I,
you know,
I got to go do this.
Then you get to go hang out
with your buddies and you know,
we be there for four hours and we
barely get any of the adventure done.
Cause it would be just pat and going,
you know,
I just played the Shitty
club and me going, hey, have
you seen that stupid movie?
You know, and Imagine
Reporting Idiots, you know?
Yeah. You guys should have a reality
show. Yeah. Dungeons and dragons.
That should be a podcast
that it's not a bad idea,
but the reality show,
like it goes back to doing that
a doctor jury thing, to me,
any reality show is basically saying,
I've got nothing. Right. You know, please,
you know, give me, you know,
well let's not call it a reality show.
How about a dungeons and dragons
show with four comics, right?
Where every week you sit down and
discuss all kinds of crazy shit.
You have subjects you want to bring up
while you're playing dungeons and dragons.
It's actually good.
Yeah,
we've definitely talked about it
over the years and you know, and uh,
but for me,
I always said no to it because I
didn't want to fuck the fun out of it.
It was just this fun thing and
I'm trying to get it going again.
I'd been talking to the DM about,
hey man,
let's,
let's get this going again back
made it a podcast at the same time.
Yeah, that's probably true. I think it
would actually probably be more fun.
You guys would be wearing headsets and
shit and talking to Micah and you would
know that other people are going to be
giggling and enjoying it along with you.
It might be the way to go.
I've never played this game,
so explain to me how it goes.
Uh,
have you ever played anything
similar? Did you ever get
no fantasy games? Although
I was huge on fantasy books.
I was big Robert, he Howard
fan as a kid and I, you know,
love just getting into fantasy football
or fantasy. No. Cause I knew that
different from that because
they don't really, you don't
get together and, but um,
it's basically you create a character.
Will you,
I'm sure you've played like a,
what do they call those games?
The video games that are,
what's that called? More role playing
RPG. Yeah. Never those you never play
play first person
shooters. Yeah, me too. I,
I played and I could cut legends and a
couple of things like that and I just
couldn't get into it because I like
playing role playing with my friends,
but doing the video game, it's, it's
too slow moving. Like I much prefer, uh,
you know, first person shooters around
just [inaudible] and even in vi, even in,
um, dungeons and dragons,
I was always the guy.
Like I played dumb characters and it's
like I'm the guy that runs through the
door first swing in the battle
ax. You know, just kidding.
I'm that guy.
I watched John The guy like,
oh I've got to figure out my spell and
I've got to say this incantation and I've
got to have these runes in my hand and
I've got to do all these things to get
this one thing to work.
I was the guy like I pick up my hammer
and I smashed you in the fucking head.
You know it was that guy.
I sat down with Dunkin once.
When you try to explain to
me the compelling magic of
world of Warcraft and we
went through a little journey and he met
up with some people and I was like sat
over his shoulder. I was like what the
fuck are you doing man? This is so stupid.
Never got it.
I'm like let's go play quick.
I'll show you how many
people I can kill and a time,
the time that this has happened I would
have killed 30 or 40 people or brains
work the same way. I just can't do that.
Yeah. Cause I knew, I knew what it was.
Cause I know it's close to
what I've played with d and d,
But d and d is much more fun for me
because of you've got the camaraderie and
you've got the friends and,
and uh,
did you ever have a landlord? Do you
ever play video games on a landlord?
That's what I was saying. Yeah.
I did the Halo Halo land parties.
I got addicted to video games because
of news radio because the writers,
the writers room where they had a land
party, so that was in there quick to yeah,
they would play quake to fuck.
It was so much fun. It was crazy.
It was so addictive. We would like,
uh, I'd go up there in between scenes,
like say if I didn't have two scenes,
I'd go up there and play
with some of the writers.
We'd be screaming each other talking shit
to each other. And it was so much fun.
After it was over, it on my hands would
be shaking and I'd go back to the set.
Like I was on crank, you know, I
went up there a couple of times. Uh,
who was her friends with that was on
that staff was alley against. Yes. Yes.
Al Higginson,
Joshua [inaudible] and uh,
went there a couple of times and got to
hang out. So what a crazy set that was.
That that was the weirdest writing room.
[inaudible] didn't they start like
at nine o'clock at night they started
whatever the fuck they want
it to. It wasn't, they start
at nine o'clock at night,
sometimes they didn't start
until two o'clock in the morning.
They just want the writing
room works like that. Like,
and it was basically a bunch of guys that
nobody had kids at that you couldn't,
you couldn't.
And people that you know that like had
kids and they knew not to even apply for
the job but get everybody started.
Like they would like sometimes he wouldn't
even start writing until the morning
and we would get there and then like an
hour later it was first Bot would pull
it out his guitar and start dicking
around in his guitar. Right.
Cause they were so they were
brilliant but complete children,
like some of the smartest guys
I've ever met. But we would like,
we would get there,
say it was a nine o'clock table read,
we'd get there at 9:00 AM.
It's usually later than that,
but if it was 9:00 AM we would get there
and we would have to wait 40 minutes
for the first script.
The first script we'll all we would
get as a chapter and so they'd be like
blocked this chapter and the next chapters
will be coming in a couple of hours
and then they would write
the chapters literally,
but they liked the pressure comes don't
work like that. No, of course not.
I did a guest spot on your
Sitcom and just shoot me
and it was remarkably well behaved, but
it was the way they did. It was brilliant.
All had kids.
They were there till eight or nine o'clock
at night and then they went home to
news radio. Guys figured out a way
to force themselves to be funny.
They figured out a way to put themselves
under a lot of pressure and that that
really funny stuff would come with sleep
deprivation and with a lot of pressure.
I mean it's a, it's a method. It's
not the best method. It's a method.
But the funniest shows I ever
worked on it. I just fucking
what? I love to have been there
all the time. Like you, but yeah,
just those two episodes I did.
Yeah, those scripts were
really fun. So much fun.
It was such a pleasure to be on it.
And I got so lucky because I can't write
a show. No, it was on another show.
I went from the worst show possible to
the best show. It's called hardball.
It was a baseball show. Ahh. It should
been funny. It was written by funny guys,
Jeff Martin and Kevin Curran who wrote
from married with children and they wrote
on the Simpsons there was a great
guys. Yes. And uh, when they got on TV,
when the show got picked up, they, they,
fox the network came along and said,
listen, you guys can't run your own show.
You know what the fuck you're doing.
So we're going to bring in
the worst hack we can find.
And they brought in this guy from coach,
I don't remember his fucking name,
but every joke was horrific.
It was terrible. He got fired,
but they couldn't pull it out of the out
of the flames. It was just, it just died.
We eventually had that.
It just shoot me the final season.
We jumped the shark like they changed all
the writers and the new guys that came
in were a total accident. That last
season was miserable. It's the worst.
People don't know how bad it is to do a
bad show. Like everybody comes and says,
oh, woe is me, Charlie sheen make it $2
million a year. It's true. You're right.
He should not be complaining.
No one who makes $2 million
a week should be complaining,
but there's a reason that fucking guy lost
his marbles. I watched that show once,
just recently. The first time
it's unfucking bearably bad.
It's unbelievably unbearably bad.
I like it because of how bad it is. Like
A, and I haven't watched a bunch of them,
but I've watched a handful of them
and it's like, oh, okay, this guy,
all these jokes are about,
he fucks a lot and the other guy's gay,
like that's all the jokes are.
It's him making fun of crier for
being kind of Wimpy, you know?
So it's all these gay jokes.
And then the fat lady walks in and says
other mean gay jokes and jokes about
Charlie Sheen fucking all the time.
That's all it is.
It's one of the worst shows that's
ever existed. I just like the opening,
that transformation or the kid.
That's all. I can never saw that part.
But it's just, it's amazing that it's
so popular. It's fucking incredible.
Is it amazing? Yes. It's still amazing
to me. It's still shocking. But you know,
when I find out that 51% of the country's
still thinks the earth is less than
10,000 years old,
that's like a recent Gallup poll.
When I find out shit
like that, it's, it's,
it's fucking disappointing and it's
confusing. But you're amazed by it. Yeah,
a little bit. Still, it's
still around anymore. I mean,
I'm not surprised in the movies that
are popular in the music that's popular,
you know?
And,
and the fact that the funny smart stuff
doesn't last because people don't care
and people are stupid. You know,
the numbers though are monstrous.
The numbers of stupid people are just so,
but I'm not surprised by that.
I wouldn't say I'm surprised. I
would say I'm shocked. I'm like,
God damn it really. You know? I would
wish that it wouldn't be like right.
You've got to want to shake everybody.
Yeah.
It's just wish it wouldn't be the
way studio is like good stuff.
Well you know what's wrong with you?
It's the big question is to how long
people can stay stupid, you know,
because he's,
technology gets more and more complicated
and more interesting and more,
I mean your,
your life has run connected to technology.
It's pretty easy to be stupid. You Google
anything, you find the answers, you know,
if you don't want to believe reality,
you find a message board of a bunch
of other people that believe the same
bullshit you believe and just
ride it to the apocalypse.
It's easy as fuck to be done today.
Oh for sure. He's here than ever.
So anyway, my, my,
I was in the worst case scenario from
that show and then all the sudden best
case scenario for news radio.
So I've never done it.
So can say like when you showed
up, like did you like, no,
like when did you know
you're on a great show?
Oh I knew it was great when I saw
the pilot, I wasn't in the pilot.
Fortunately I got to watch the pilot.
There was another guy in place,
well Ray Romano was the
original guy who had my part.
He got fired and they brought in another
guy who did the pilot and then don't
get fired cause it can act or, um, I just
think that he was wrong for the part.
I think they just wanted someone
different. They wanted to do it different.
So they decided to get rid of Ray Romano.
And of course Ray Romano,
there's the greatest thing that ever
happened to him cause it goes on.
Does everybody knows and it
makes $1 trillion. But they, um,
they did it and then they brought in
another guy for the pilot and then he got
fired. And then they had some sort of a,
a thing, you know, and open call thing.
And, uh, I had a development deal with
NBC to do my own show. I just got it.
And then they said,
before we even talked to you about that,
and we went to Montreal or something,
or no,
I got it after I did the
hardball thing. Okay. It failed,
but I got to deal somehow or another,
I got good agents,
so you're still doing a ton of stand up.
I kept telling him I was
always doing stand up. Um, so,
and then I went to NBC and they
showed me the pilot and then, uh,
you know, they said, would you be
willing to audition for this? And I said,
fuck yeah. And then I auditioned and I
got it. It was really just stupid luck,
but I knew right away, it was
amazing. You know, right away,
the first day at table read, I'm sitting
next to Phil Hartman. I'm like, Holy Shit.
Like I knew Dave Foley was famous,
but I didn't know of him. I didn't,
but it wasn't really a
true fan. No, I really,
I did see a couple of sketches
that I thought were kind of funny,
but it wasn't like really into it,
but it just sitting next to Phil
Hartman at the table, it was like,
this is fucking bizarre.
And then were you a fan of his from
Simpsons and you know, I'm just seeing,
I mean it was hilarious.
I remember seeing him on TV
and thinking how funny he was.
And then all of a sudden I'm sitting
next to him on a TV show when I had never
taken a fucking acting class in my
life. And it was like six
months from doing this MTV,
half hour comedy hour and then boom,
six months later, somehow or another,
I'm living in La on a sitcom.
It was completely pissed off pretty fast.
Ridiculously fast. I remember meaning
you around then the first time.
I don't know if you remember meeting me
cause I remember you being on the set.
No, no. Before that we did busters. Happy
hour together. Oh Shit. I remember that.
Blau I forgot that buster Poindexter
the guy from Hanson? Yeah,
from New York though. Yes. To this
shitty character, that hot hot, hot song.
I remember, I remember when he
busted. Yeah, it's a made up guy.
How weird that he did that?
What am,
I mean we had this weird that he did
not give a shit about at all. Yeah.
You hosted,
what network was that on?
I just want to say VH one or like how
many TVs? If it was comedy central,
I'd be surprised. I think, well, comedy
central used to be before comedy channel,
maybe Buster's happy hour. Oh
Wow. Dave Raf booked it. Wow.
Yeah. So that's how, who else did it with
us? I feel like it was you, me and Janine,
but I could be wrong.
I don't think so.
I don't think I've ever done anything
with this graph. I don't know. But uh,
she knew what it was.
If there was like,
I think they taped several
episodes in one day.
I remember a couple of people
being behind, uh, or you know,
be in backstage while we were
there. Oh, right, right, right.
And they splice them all together.
And I had never met you before.
I never seen your standup before.
And I was doing like kind
of the alternative thing
and you brought a stool out
and like, dude, you're fucking this
thing. I did the tiger fucking bit.
Is that what it was?
Most of my clothes,
that was the first time he did me.
I don't even think we met
like I think it was just like,
oh that's one of the other
guys I'm doing this show with.
But does that still
fucking guys? Yeah, it's a,
and then we did, uh, I loved the show.
I love news radio and
watch it the whole time.
And I think I probably got brought
on my first one and yeah, no,
they were both near the end.
How many seasons did you do?
Did you do the Phil Hartman Year or low?
Was it? Love it. So I didn't do love.
It's at all I did to
fill episodes. I did, uh,
the one where we were the
acapella singing group. Oh yeah.
He wanted to beat me up cause I kept,
I kept the eyeball and yet that
was so fun. It was fun. It was fun.
They always had the most
ridiculous premises,
like space news radio where
we did the whole news radio,
but it was in space or titanic news radio.
We'll just ship.
Yeah,
it's fucking completely ridiculous.
We were the singing group that tries to
get Dave to come back cause we're all
about to turn 40, I think. But we,
and it was Kirk and me and cross and we
all come on and try to get them to join
this group up with this again to,
it's such a joke.
So yeah, that was, I mean, that's why
I've never done another sitcom sense.
Everything I've looked at since it's like,
that's why I don't write for sketch shows.
Mr Show did that ruin that for me?
Like when you, right,
a good one or you work
on a good job, like one of the best
versions of that kind of thing.
Like why do you ever want to go back,
you know,
have you considered doing a podcast? I
am. Yeah. I'm going to do one with the,
you know, Earwolf uh, it's Scott
Aukerman started it up, uh,
comedy death ray guys and, and
uh, he's a good buddy of mine.
He was mister show writer. So
I just figured I, you know,
now even though I'm more clearheaded,
I'm not that motivated.
Like I need somebody to ha like set it
up for me and for you to have a regular
place to go.
Like for me to do it at my house,
I'd probably never get off
my ass and get it done.
So you can do it man. Look, you took
this huge step in stopping the weeds do,
you could do anything.
Now you know what you need to do.
This is the number one thing to
get things done. Write them down.
I write things down and when,
when I write down a bunch of
shit that I have to get done,
I make sure I do them because otherwise
they're just sort of a thought, you know,
if, if it's concrete, so I'm
a little PC, yellow legal pad.
I have to get all these things on this
list done. This is my day, you know,
you've been doing this now,
writing things down and podcast a year,
a little over a year,
year and a half to do it.
Or just as a goof, I was
depressed because, uh, came back,
I shouldn't say depressed, but I was
bored because I came back from Colorado.
Wa was forced to move back here
because, uh, my wife was pregnant,
she couldn't deal with the
altitude up there, right.
Cause we were like
literally in the mountains.
So we came back and a month later me and
Brian were sitting around and we were
like, let's fucking do what Anthony
Anthony [inaudible] does on the OB.
And Anthony show he gets
is it does a little, uh,
Ustream show live from the compound.
So we sat down with like a Webcam.
That's what it started out when we had
like fucking snowflakes coming down while
we were talking like fake snowflakes.
I was like so stupid
and cheesy and you know,
half of the show was
just us reading Twitter.
Unlistenable if you tried to
listen to in iTunes, it's terrible.
And then somehow or another, everybody's
saying this was awesome, do it again.
We're like, all right fuckers,
we'll see you next Tuesday.
So we just all of a sudden started
doing it on a weekly basis.
We started doing one way and we never
stopped. We just kept it up. You know,
the only time I took any time off of it
over a week and a half was recently I
had to do a movie in Boston for two weeks.
So we took two weeks off.
And how long did it take you to like
decide on a format and that kind of thing?
We didn't decide on anything.
It just sort of evolve and he started
bringing guests in. All that. Yeah.
I mean we always had cats but it
was always like my closest friends.
It was always like,
you know,
Joey Diaz would come over or each fear
would come over here and then, you know,
uh,
as time went on,
we eventually got like real
microphones like we have right now.
And was the guy that shows
his pulse on the, yeah, it's
done. The Manchester. Yeah.
Brian Posehn was there for the ill
fated attempts with demand shows. Well,
you were a faded of good stuff,
but it was still faded for
a couple of reasons. One,
it was I should have never tried to do
something where I didn't have the time to
do it. I just did. Yeah,
you were pretty busy.
I was doing fear factor at the same time.
It was a ridiculous idea.
The idea that I could do to TV
shows it was doing the UFC. No,
sometimes it was signed to Vegas to do
fear factor, but that was pretty rare.
Most of the time it was done
in and around Los Angeles,
but I feel like we barely, we barely
had you in the room. It was too hard.
I would come in and I would only
have two days a week and it was,
and then there was all this infighting
going on him. It was a funny man.
Greg Fitzsimmons. Yes, and time
Janice running in the room.
A couple of other funny guys.
There was a lot of funniness and you and
and a standout brought your own funny
ideas to it.
We had an issue.
First of all in that as we started was
when the Janet Jackson Nipple thing went
down. You remember that shit?
That's when we got gutted.
They came in and said to kind of remember
like we had an abortion monologues.
Yeah, we had an abortion
monologue. It make it less massage.
It didn't mean, no, not just
data, but less shocking.
They gutted it and then there was
also, there was, they had one direct,
we wanted to do a totally different thing
and the network wanted basically the
same. They kind of bullshitted me when
to get it. They said, Oh, do new to dean.
We'll blur it out.
Swear and will be bid out.
It'd be good if we got sued and
he showed his bomb. Yeah, he did,
but meanwhile I had a fight for that.
You know how much I had to fight for that?
Yeah. Zooey was fucking crying,
but Friedman's daughter,
she was crying because she didn't want
it to happen. I just don't see why.
It's funny. I go, there's nothing you can
do in life that's funny than this. I go,
just watch. I go, we'll do two openings,
we'll do one with it and one without it.
So we did and he,
Joey gets out there and the place goes
fucking bananas because he's 350 pounds
and he's got, he looks like he ate
another human being and his stomach.
And it's hard to even see his
balls when he's a big guy.
Well his balls or shit goes down.
There's balls like grapefruits,
there's a lot of charm.
He's a lot of scars and shit,
but his balls are like
grapefruit and it old ladies,
panty hose next to this
uncircumcised monster,
elephant trunk Dick. And he's out there
screaming, let's get this party started.
And he introduces me and Doug and that's
a great way to start off the show.
And I thought what a fun thing would be
to have Joey on the show every week to
start it off. Just like, why is this
funny? I don't understand why. It's funny.
It's funny. It just is funny. You can't
look, you guys are the executives.
I'm sure you have your own tastes,
you have your own hopes and dreams,
but you know, creatively, you
can't second guess artists.
You have to either let them
do it and if it doesn't work,
then you come in and make corrections.
But you can't say it from the
get go that it's not funny.
You gotta you gotta let,
let,
let us play it out in front of an
audience if we think it's funny,
chances are right. The one thing, like
when the writer's strike happened,
the writer's guild strike happened.
I always wished that one of the
things we would have asked for is, um,
we no longer have to take notes from
people that are less funny than us.
You know what I mean? I'm serious. Like
that's the big part that like cribs,
funny thing and hurts funny shows
is the unfunny people going, no,
I don't like, I don't get
that. Why are you doing that?
And I know it happens at other networks,
but I've run into it a lot
of comedy central because
I wound up there a lot over
the years. I did that show.
I did Sarah Silverman.
I've done other things that haven't even
made it on air because there's chimps
that just don't get
what's funny and you know that they
have those job that they're basically
allowed to, you know, be the gatekeepers
are funny and they're not fucking funny.
It's brutal. It's literally
like, and again it's, you know,
guys that get paid to be funny
complaining about, Oh, you know,
I don't get to do this.
Boohoo well,
it's not just that you're
complaining about a roadblock
and the creative process,
a real roadblock where someone
doesn't get the look you stand.
Could you imagine it? So
one of the beautiful things
about standup comedy is a,
you are your own writer, director,
producer, the whole deal.
Could you imagine if you had a run your
material by a group of people before you
went on stage before you even went on
stage with it so it wouldn't even be
proven? Yeah, I've had that
too when I've done special,
when you do specials where it's
like, yeah, I've had that in the,
can you say this instead of that?
And my last special was the best
because I didn't have to do anything.
I did a spike TV when the spike and
comedy central, first of all it's blank.
And then comedy central.
It was the first one ever where they said,
just go ahead and do what you do.
Well,
we're worried about what we can and
can't do after the network season.
My next thing I'm going to do is going
to be for DVD first and then if anybody
wants to buy it and I'm fine,
that's the way to do it.
That's how I did my Netflix when
nobody gives me notes. Yeah. Cause the,
the two comedy central half hours I did
like I had to tweak words and change
where it's completely and if I call
the move jokes and you know, and,
and they wound up being
okay and I'm proud of him.
But it was also such a process and, and,
and uh, as a standup, like you said,
we've never had to go through that.
Like, you know, and if you did,
it would be a design writing jokes for
24 years. And I never had anybody go, no,
you know, don't do this instead of that.
Well what's important about comedy?
One of the, to me when I, when I
go to see a comic, I don't even,
like when I hear the guys have writers
I feel like I feel like I'm getting
ripped off. I feel like I'm getting
lied to. I don't mind, you know,
I mean some big name guys hire
writers and that's all good there.
The good writers and they
write some great beds.
But I really love when I go see a guy
and I know that this is a singular point
of view. This is this guy's point of view.
This is him sitting down and writing.
I like him. I like, I want to see his
whole pack or her or whatever it is.
I want to see their whole
package from them. The one that,
the one guy that does
it right is Chris Rock.
He writes it all himself and then he has
somebody else go with him and you know,
cause he does those long sets and a lot
of it is like he hasn't written it out
first. So we had somebody, uh,
I think God, who's the guy,
the guy that used to show Mario Joiner,
I think it's Mario joining or sitting
in the audience watching and saying this
worked.
That worked.
But it's not him going
Mario. Right. Me Jokes.
It's a consultant. Yeah. Which that works.
But these other guys that have
like a staff, and I won't name,
I want to name names either, but uh, I
knew a couple of guys that you think,
oh yeah, I think it, how's that guy
come up with an hour every year?
Because he's got three fucking
guys writing for them all the time.
But then there's guys like Louis C k
they don't have anybody writing for me.
It still comes up with an hour every year.
That's incredible. He's a monster. Yeah,
he will. You know what it is.
There's something wrong. He's
got momentum behind them right now.
He's in a groove and he's,
he's really and Co completely.
How against how it used to do it.
He used to do the same act for like
the longest time and now he's in this
completely new George
Carlin sort of a thing.
How long does it take
you to write an hour?
I did my last special almost two years
ago and I have about an hour and 30
minutes now, but I been
working a lot, you know,
I jumped right back into it and I had
a bunch of bits that I didn't do in the
special that it was still kind of fucking
around with, so I had a base to start.
The real hard hour is the third hour.
That's the hard hour if you do three
years in a row because the first year
you've probably been working on it for
a few years in the second year. Well,
if you've got a few premises that you
didn't really touch on within that third
year, man, you're starting
from fucking scratch son.
Yeah.
My first record came out six years ago
and then my last record came out last
year and I'm working on
the third one right now.
And that's the one where I
basically started over, uh,
last March when it came out and it's a
year and I maybe have 25 that I love and
I'm still doing stuff from that other,
but I also had other things going on.
And you know, what do you do when you do
the, do the road? Do you do some old shit?
Some new shit? I do. It's,
it's 45 to an hour and it's
like 25 brand new and, and, uh,
some other stuff from the last record,
which I can't wait to get rid of.
Do people ever get bummed out?
Shit online and stuff of people gone,
you know, you're not as prolific
as your friends and it's like,
well then fuck you my friends.
And if that's the worst is when you
get compared to those other guys.
And people compare me to Louis, uh, you
know, like, or bring Louie up of like,
why can't you do what Louis does? And I
don't know, my brain isn't wired like his,
I don't mind if a guy
does a few old jokes.
I like hearing some old bits that I
enjoyed, but I like a lot of new shit too.
I see their point. I've had a peep
places where I go and they'll say, hey,
this guy was here last year and he just
came back and he'd do the same fucking
ag verbatim punchline
like,
and I,
I make it like if I'm going back to
the same market that I was just out of,
here I go,
I go out of my way to write new stuff or,
or let them know. Even like, hey,
here's some stuff you might've
heard and then here's, you
know. Right, right, right.
Yeah. I didn't even say in
the setup like my accident,
a transitional period and this is, you
know, this is what's happening. And Yeah,
I do a lot of, uh, where it used
to at least I do a lot of Q and. A.
I did that for the
first time this weekend.
I did Vancouver now for the first
time this weekend for the first time.
I've ever done a, um, an encore core,
you'll do an encore? No, I don't
think so. Never done that before.
Maybe at a college. I feel it.
Yeah. I did have to come out.
I feel like in Alaska I came out and did
really like another joke that I hadn't
done. What'd you do in Alaska? Uh, it
was a school up there, up in Anchorage.
Wow. What's it like up there? Is it weird?
It's fucking weird. And it wasn't the,
it wasn't the, in the middle of summer,
but it was the beginning of summer,
so it was a, it was
light till midnight. Why?
I flew in in the afternoon
and then flew home at night,
flew home right after my show.
So it got to the airport
around 11 o'clock at night,
just as it's starting to get dark
and it was really trippy. Wow. Yeah.
Alaska freaks me the fuck out,
man.
That's like the place where you go when
you're running from the world. Right.
You know, when you really want to be an
outcast. But yeah, that was the only time.
So you did your first one and
yeah, it was weird. You know,
they just screaming encore,
encore.
I did an hour and hour and something
and then I went out and I did another 40
minutes. But it's all just, mostly I did
some material that I hadn't done before,
but a lot of it was just asking.
They would ask questions,
he's fucking around with the audience.
I used to do a lot of that,
but it became a lot of the same questions.
And I also felt like the
show didn't end it strong.
I like ending on a strong bit,
so I was doing like an hour.
I broke it down to what I feel like is
the best performance and it's like an
hour and 10 minutes going at it. Full
clip and strong. Thank you. Good night.
So I did that and then I came out and I
felt like, okay, this isn't even the show.
This is just fucking around and this
is at least they've seen the full solid
show and now I can fuck around with like
the question and answer thing and it
didn't, I don't feel like I'm
ending on a bad note, I guess. Yeah.
I ended strong luckily.
But when your ad living like that,
you don't really know where the
fuck is going to go and you don't,
you got to trust the crowd, laugh.
Go all right. Yeah, exactly.
And you've got to trust the crowd
and the crowd was fucking hammered.
They were hammered and high as fuck.
And the pot in Vancouver is insane.
It's just as good,
if not better than California. I never
thought I would. I would say that. But we,
we got ahold of some stuff.
This guy messaged me and uh,
we went to a dispensary, they have
dispensary's then and we went and uh,
I'm just like, how good could this
be? We're, we're from California.
We almost got too high to do the show.
Sativa and Indica or sativa. Yeah.
One area still where you can kind of
score on the street to even sort of,
but I think that's dangerous.
I don't know. But the, the,
the whole five of them in
Vancouver. Rob, do you mean?
No,
just a Bot Bot decent stuff.
One day went back to the same guy the
next day and he told her or assaulted me
Schwag. Oh really? Yeah. Wow.
So it wasn't, he ripped off,
he just was shitty quality control. No,
it was barely smokeable. Oh really? Yeah.
And I actually had a guy there once,
the same, uh, same city, uh, where, uh,
he goes,
follow me.
He just came up to me on the street
because you want it by the way. And I go,
yeah, yeah, sure. Wow, that's
a better effect they do.
And I followed him around
the corner and he goes, oh,
I got to go into this household on.
And as it, as it's happening, I'm like,
there goes that 20 bucks.
And I gave him the money and he went
inside and I actually saw him go out the
side door and climb over a
fence, go away. Wow. Yes,
I could see him run away my money and I'm
just laughing at that point. I'm like,
ah, the I deserve it. You know?
Well, they have a, Vancouver has a,
they have a medical thing going on now
will they take recommendations from
California? So if you have a license,
you have a California license,
they'll allow you to get a
prescription card, right? Yeah. Yeah.
I never go up there. He
never did a legal, really,
you're a rebel borough and now why
would you want to go to the dispensary
is amazing. I know. Well, I just smoked
my friend's stuff from dispensary's,
but I always had a weak
guy that came to my house.
Do you have a guy that come
no fucking way? No, no, no,
no, no, no. You, you, you.
That's probably why he stopped smoking
weed. You were getting all that,
that stone or we'd you weren't
getting it a space weed and you know,
I wasn't getting less space. We'd with
space, we space suite is the, the,
the sativa.
It's much more psychedelic.
It's like you want to watch
space documentaries. We want
to go out and do things,
I'm going to make an organic carton.
Right? You get no, you're right.
And I was getting the same stuff cause
the guy always had to say, you know,
he had the same buyer that you know, or
whatever. When you go to a dispensary,
then they educate you on it. That's
the beautiful thing of it. They'll say,
this is a hybrid. This is a little bit
of this. This is 60% indigo, 40% sativa.
This is a pure sativa. This is gonna. You
want to write a book? This is your shit.
Right. You know, it's, it's a different
feeling. Yeah, I gotta check it out.
But when I have that, when
you're done, if you do,
if you decide to ever do it again,
that should be the thing.
But what are the reasons I kept this guy
is he was my friend and I talked to him
a couple of years ago. I swear to God
we're were in my garage, uh, you know,
or the transactions done and we're,
I'm rolling what up, you know,
before he heads back to where he
lives. And, and, uh, I go, uh,
this is one of the economies
first starting to go south.
I go, hey dude, if I,
if I stopped buying from you because
I was thinking about getting a card,
you know, and I'm like, if I stopped
buying from you, would you take a hit?
You know, like, would it hurt
you financially? He's like,
oh, absolutely. He's like,
yeah, you're one of my regulars. And,
and uh, yeah, that would suck him.
So I then I was like, ah, I'm going
to keep the little guy in business.
I got to look out for the small
businessman. Well that's cool.
That's a good reason to, to keep with
that guy then not get a license. That is,
he was my old friend. I mean he was a
guy. I'd been through wrath and, and uh,
we've been,
you know,
I think at that point wrath was getting
weeded somewhere else or, but uh,
I used him anyway, you know, I kept
him for 10 years or so. That's good.
And weird thing is, and I'm going
to write a joke about it. Like,
I haven't told him that I quit yet and
I know it's three months later and he
hasn't gotten a text for
me. Like he hasn't texted me
like, what the fuck can we,
are you? Oh, that's funny. Maybe you heard
about it online and he's just crying.
Just know he's recalculating as bills.
Trying to figure it out,
how he's going to get by when that you're
paid rent and two months now because
the fuck, yeah, it's a,
it's amazing how many people are in
California smoke pot now. You know?
Because it's so,
it's so prevalent.
People in other parts of the country
really haven't, they don't have a clue.
You don't have any idea how bizarre it is.
You know when you go,
if you go to Kansas City and he'd do a
club in Kansas City had tried get in pot,
it's fucking hard and if you get
pods and I'm going to be any good,
it's going to be okay.
When you're in California and you just
drive down the street and you see these
green plus signs everywhere,
you see him all over the place.
There's hundreds of dispensary's. He'd
been to San Francisco later. Oakland? No,
I haven't been to Oakland, but I have
a buddy of mine who grows in Oakland.
It's a while. It's totally allowed
up there. Yeah. You'll stand up,
you know cobb's uh,
the comedy club in San Francisco and
this never was like this when I lived up
there in the 90s were standing in front
of the place and one of the main streets
in San Francisco,
cops drive by,
there's eight people standing
out front smoking pot, you know,
three or four pipes being passed around.
The cops don't even slow down.
And even though Carlos and say,
hey, take it around the corner,
they don't do any of that. They thought
should be last time I was at cabs,
I was smoking in the green room and
I was passing joints out the window.
[inaudible] handed them
joints rather. Yeah. Yeah.
That San Francisco is totally allowed.
But that whole city now is, yeah.
In Oakland and I haven't
told is even more extreme.
Like they called Oaksterdam
that. Yeah. Well,
they also have classes on how
you can grow and you know,
how do you consider your own business?
Yeah,
they have like some fucking
university of weed up there.
I don't even know exactly what this weird,
there's some place in this country or
is it Vancouver where they're actually
selling it at seven 11 south.
What really? Come on. Yeah,
I heard that just recently.
That
one or two places where now it's
allowed like in one store to two K.
Awesome. That's cool. I heard
that seminar could be, this is
what I heard. Yeah, sure. Um,
pulls up nothing for
Google pulls up nothing.
So I'm assuming this is
bullshit. Okay, good.
But I think we're close if that's
happening. But they'd be crazy not to.
Why not man? Just fucking jumped
in. You know, what do you,
what do you know who's getting hurt here?
You're already selling loco for 20
or whatever the fuck that shit is.
What does that four Loko Shit stuff
that people have their heart bursts.
It's like five red bulls and
five shot. It was, it's Tequila.
It's whatever the fuck it is.
Some strong alcohol and like really
strong red bull type energy drinks.
People are dying of it. Yeah.
They sell that. They sell
cigarettes, they sell booze.
You know, you saw everything. They
can kill you. I sell a little weed.
How long do you think that's going to
be before that happens? 10 years. 20.
I don't know.
I think we're closer than that really.
That felt like that last election we
were really close to get sloppy and it's
just the next time somebody
writes the right bill and,
and words that in the right way that
gets even that last people to go, hey,
that's not a bad idea.
The real issue though is federal.
The federal issue is a huge issue
because it federally, it's still very,
very illegal. It's still schedule
one, which is a huge deal. That's a,
that's heroin. That's cocaine.
It's uh, not, not even, excuse me.
Those are scheduled to schedule one
is more illegal than cocaine. Right.
But there are a lot of cities around the
country that are starting to, you know,
yeah. I know. It's basically illegal.
Uh, you know, like I was saying,
it was shooting this thing in Ann
Arbor. It's pretty okay there. Yeah.
And arbors really? Okay. Yeah,
that's pretty legal there.
I think they just approved medical
in Michigan as well. And um,
where was I recently though? It's really,
oh, Denver. Denver is super legal.
Denver is a lot like California.
They call it mainstream. Damn.
They got like one street main street or
broad stir dam and it's all pot shops.
Josh blue.
Like there's yes.
Some comic that Joshua was the guy who
has cerebral palsy. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But um, yeah, it's, it
means starting to happen.
Starting to happen slowly but surely.
And I was listening to rock radio in
Detroit practically every ad on this
regular rock radio station is
either a gro growth, you know,
go new grow store or you know,
an actual medical marijuana store
really like almost every ad. Holy Shit.
That's cool. Wow. But then again, who the
fuck's listening to radio these tests?
That's true.
But I had a rental car and you know,
and they played a thin Lizzy and
Metallica. So Nice was enough for me.
You ever see the documentary wild to
ocean wild ocean? What does, I don't know.
It's, it's as bad as I saw it last
night and it's all about sardines and,
and like they do that thing were birds
do where they all become one group,
like a mob to like a flock of birds
where they move in one unit. Yeah,
it's so bad ass.
But they have it in three d and the
three d TV thing in the past, you know,
like I said,
it's good for here and there and stuff.
This is the most amazing thing
you'll ever see in three d.
It's just this huge mob. Like all
these fish turned into like a monster,
like a boss battle in a video game.
You see these dolphins just trying to
shoot through them and get it and they all
kind of react as one whole.
And then there's the seagull things that
dive down and go through the water like
missiles and it looks like underneath
the water it looks like war.
Like it sounds like war,
like missiles and bombs and an,
it's the most amazing thing.
Everyone's birds do. They dive bomb.
They're are like muscles. Yeah. Must be
crazy in three days. Three body recommend.
It's called wild ocean. It's the ocean.
It's so bad ass. All right Max. Uh,
speaking of, see, I watched
the sativa before, that's it.
Watched a, a, a documentary.
Somebody linked it to me on Twitter
about the Salton Sea. Do you,
do you know anything about the
salt and sea? A little bit.
This is a trippy thing man.
And I was not aware of,
I remember there was an invalid,
I don't know. It's in California.
There was a val Kilmer movie
about salt and sea. It was
like, you know, some crime.
Yeah, yeah, exactly. Well,
what it is is apparently at
the turn of the century they,
um,
there was an engineering mistake and the
Colorado River for two years was just
dumping water into this one part of
California and they thought that it was
going to dry up and they thought
that, well, this is a huge mistake.
It created the biggest manmade lake
in California, the biggest lake,
the biggest bottle of body of water
in California is the salt and sea.
And it filled this whole area up and
they thought it was going to drain out,
eventually dry up,
but it didn't.
And people were putting boats on it and
people started building houses there and
people started fishing in there.
And then they started having tourism
there and they started there.
They're just commercials move to the,
the, the Riviera in California, the end,
you know, the, uh, the, the, you know,
indoor Riviera or the Interior Riviera,
I forget what they were calling it,
but it was,
it was this gigantic artificial body of
water and people were pulling all these
fish out and it looked like a
fucking party. And it was, you know,
it was like photos and video from the
fifties where everybody was like driving
those old cars and they're all smiling.
And the women looked a little Chubby,
you know, it was a whole, the whole,
the whole, that whole era. Well, well,
eventually the runoff from all of these
farms made it into this see and poisoned
everything and got so bad that there
was mass Fishkill offs where there was a
million fish would die in a day.
And the air was so rank with dead
fish that you couldn't breathe.
So it basically became this toxic fucking
cesspool and everyone had to move out.
All the schools shut down.
Everyone moved down to the area.
And there's only like a few like desert
rats that are still living there.
But try it out though, right? No, no,
no, no, no, no, no. Still. Oh yeah.
Now it's saltier than the ocean.
Now it's like impossible
for things to live in it.
I think it was just like the salt flats.
Now it's a dead like butter puddle of
water and it's all like the apocalypse out
there bad because all these houses
that are like being overcome by this C,
they're all rotted out from the salt
water and the air and the fucking,
everything's abandoned. And windows of
Grogan. It's called the s the documentary.
Um, let me find it. It's cause
it's on my, it's on Netflix. Yeah,
it's on,
you can find it on youtube.
Let me find the video on youtube
because it's, it's, it's,
it's fascinating enough to,
people need to see it.
If you just go last night to my Twitter,
if you want to do some searching.
Today is June 13th and you go to the June
13th Twitter cause I'm trying to pull
it up here on 'em online
and it's pulling on
not a documentary. It's kind of,
I think it came out no six but uh,
into the void. Do you ever see it?
Oh yeah. It's amazing. Yeah. Yeah.
At least the first half of it is,
I,
I did you get pissed off with all the
strobe lights and all the fast motion.
We'll do tell everybody with this
documentary as well. Oh wait,
I'm thinking of enter the void. You know,
you're thinking of that movie on Dmt.
Yeah. He's talking about, it's like a
skateboarding movie, right? No, no. It's,
maybe I'm getting the title wrong,
but it's a,
it's the two guys a mountain
climbing, uh, where uh,
one guy breaks his leg
and they're alone and uh,
he basically lets us friend die or he
thinks he like, I won't give it all away.
He lets the guy go and then,
you know,
then it's told like buy them.
And then with the reenactments,
the reenactments are brutal and uh,
it's just really well made.
It's these two British guys that were a
climbing a mountain and a that had never
been, never been done before. It's called
the engine into the void. The void.
Yeah. And I was thinking to enter
the void. Yeah, I remember that.
See I just saw this kind of movies
stress me. Yeah. I, Oh yeah.
It was wondering was I
watched it in two sittings.
I had to walk away and get something else
done cause I was like so stressed out
for these guys. Yeah. But you know that
the fact that they're both talking,
you know how it ends up,
right. So yes, it's still,
it seems like the only
soften the blow a little bit.
I didn't see that movie where they got
cut his arm off either based on that guy
or a hundred, 127 hours. Yeah. Not
really interested in seeing that. Thanks.
That's pretty brutal. That was why I
made too. Yeah. I love Netflix streaming.
I mean,
how great is that nowadays?
You can just stream these
documentaries like instantly
do something particularly scary about
the idea of getting stuck out in the
wilderness and dying out there,
away from civilization cause
you're so unprotected and we're so,
we're so not aware of how
unprotected we really,
are you one of those goals that even
does those things? I lived in Colorado,
in the mountains.
I lived eight miles down a dirt road.
My dog had eaten by a mountain lion.
It's one of the reasons why we
decided to move back. But yeah,
I decided to just throw myself out
into the wilderness and wanted to be,
you know, I wanted to be
somewhere. It was let way, way,
way less people and just
kind of like take it all in,
but you're really fucking vulnerable.
Yeah.
But I would never be mountain climbing
one other data and I w I'd never be like
this movie frozen. I really liked. Did
you see that and haven't seen that.
It's a harm with three
kids on a ski lift and uh,
the ski lift gets shut down
at the end of the night.
And then they're stuck over there for the
weekend. Like I'm just not adventurous.
I wouldn't be that guy.
Like we got to get one last run in I
think. Okay. I Youtube never been that
do on youtube. It's called the
accidental. See and you you have to,
it's really quick too.
It's only like six minutes and 30 seconds.
We're details the whole a thing of the,
the salt and sea.
I said there isn't a full documentary
that I think there might be more than one
out there.
There's a,
there's a couple of the people when I
posted this as a couple of the people a
recommended on Twitter that
were different than this one,
but this pretty much tells the whole
story in six and a half minutes.
It's insane. It's insane.
It's, I mean it's, it's, it
literally looks like Mad Max.
I mean it's, it's the craziest shit
ever. What part of California is it?
Is it someone that desert? Wow. Is it
like on your way out to Phoenix or mm,
that's a good question. I don't know the
exact one we could find out right here.
Hold on. Yeah, off the 10 or the 60 year.
I loved that abandoned kind of like ha,
like neighborhoods and cities that,
that kind of feeling of like,
like post apocalyptic Zombie of any time
you like that in real life, you know.
I do. I like like a cat lives kinda. Yeah.
As a kid we used to break into
the old prison in Columbus, Ohio.
We would break into it and smoke weed
and stuff like that and we were like 14
and that was just so cool to me.
But just the history of the,
there's deteriorating building and
that visitor Detroit is fucking huge.
Those buildings or this thing,
she didn't enjoy the sir. It's,
it's 220 fucking six feet
deep salt and see, wow,
this is crazy. I got to
watch that tonight. Yeah.
The deepest part of the C is five meters
higher or five feet higher than uh,
yeah, five feet higher than the
lowest point of death valley.
See is fed by the new Whitewater and
Alamo rivers. It's still fed. Wow.
It's crazy. They diverted
it. They fucked up.
It was just an engineering mistake and
it created this crazy fucking spot.
But it um,
it occupies the lowest elevations of the
salt and sink and the Colorado desert
of the imperial and Riverside counties
in southern California. Riverside. Okay.
Yeah. I need to go out and check that
out man. We need to make a fucking trip.
We need to do a podcast from out
there. Yeah, that'd be interesting.
It's worth the price
stinks. Like dude, there's,
there's ground up dead bones
from fish that up sand.
Okay.
There's so many difish died that there
is a type of Sam there that is nothing
but ground up fish bones and they were
showing it in this documentary with her.
It looks like Sam,
the guy's reaching into the sand and
pulling it up and it's ground up.
Fishbowls Dan helped spin out there.
It's where drink that water.
It's probably thinking
about buying a trailer,
cargo there for four days in a row,
waiting for the end of time with the
fish sand the giant carton of cigarettes.
If you ever swam with
dolphins, no. Yes you can.
I was,
when I was in the big island of Hawaii,
the dolphins were out near,
uh,
people like people would go out and swim
with them and the dolphins would come
close to him. That's what I want to do.
Yeah, dude, you can go in Hawaii, there's,
there's parts of, uh, different
parts of the world were dolphins,
dolphins love people.
Man.
It's kind of crazy because they're
pretty brutal though. The dolphins,
there's this,
a resort on a Wahoo Kahala where
they actually have dolphins captive,
but you know,
you can,
they take you into the pool
with them and the capital. Yeah.
Which is kind of a bummer.
[inaudible] me out, dude.
That freaks me out what I want. Then
you see how intelligent they are. Yeah,
they are.
We call them a lot of puppies.
Me and my wife there because
they are just like, Doug's,
it really sweet though. They're like
dogs, but they're a lot smarter.
They rape you to
love rape.
Everyone needs to rape a little bit.
If you don't have any hands, you know,
they have flippers.
You can't just rely on someone's kindness.
Is there one rapey dolphin or are they
pretty be like, they're all eager?
Gangbanging couple like one of them
like, Hey, look over there that,
that you look and then the other one
comes in and dolphins are particularly
ruthless when it comes to breeding
females because breeding females,
when they have babies,
they won't mate for a bunch of years
afterwards while the kids growing up.
So male dolphins will kill the babies
to force the women to fuck again.
So one of those, yeah, people
don't tell you about that.
When they tell you how low
dolphins are green, they're eco.
I'll tell you how fucking
ruthless nature is. I mean,
dolphins are not separate from
it. They uh, well, so the,
they'll kill babies to
force the female to breed.
So fucking bite their
heads off to kill him.
They don't use guns right now.
They start to break the name.
Yeah. So they, um, they'll kill the
babies and last they fuck the female.
So because of that, the
females, fuck everyone.
The females try to fuck as many men
as they can in their little pack.
So that way when,
when it all goes down,
you know the guy comes around and goes
down and this might be my fucking kids.
I don't want to kill this chick.
And so they don't,
they don't kill the babies
to force you to read. Yeah.
Fucking loved. I was so stoned last
night. I was like thinking, man,
dolphins seems so intelligent and they
seem like they all like communicate and
stuff like that.
I want to take a dolphin and put it in
a big aquarium and they just take it on
land and show them like the sites
of the land. Cause know dolphins.
Dumb nine maybe it would help them out.
Take a dog in New York City, get
super, super well. They're really,
they're nearly close to being
able to the grove dolphin.
It's really nice out though.
This is silver lake.
They're really close to
being able to decipher.
They're really close to being able to
decipher it. Dolphin language. Right.
You know what I mean? It's something
that we're really unsure of right now.
What they're doing,
what they're saying.
But it's going to come a point where
they're going to have some incredible
supercomputer that's going to be able to
decipher though cause they have a very
clear language and once we figured out
their language then you know this is
going to be like Google, translate,
pray, pray, pray, pray, pray,
pray and a bunch of racist
shit at eight eight Jews.
The first dolphin is the out. That's
his first words. I hate Jews. Fuck man,
we worked so hard for this.
Dolphins are assholes.
Like if you had a killer whale in a fish
tank and he gave him a marker and he
came back in a swat stickers all over
the walls. Like fuck man. Really?
Let's see. I think there should be more
experimentation on animals like that.
Like I showed last night when I was
watching the movie, I showed my cat 3-d,
you know,
I tried to place that that glass is this
cause it's never been done properly.
People don't show their cats 3d
never know. Maybe the cap freak out.
I agree with some experimentation,
but I don't agree with,
I don't agree with any dolphin
captivity that might as well be jail.
Those are slaves and those are
intelligent slaves. That's,
they don't want to be there.
That's gross.
The killer whale thing that's
gross kind of bummed out by the,
by the dolphins at the Nice hotel,
they probably switching at a four
star hotels matter, man. They want to,
they don't,
they don't know what's on their pillows.
The Room Service 24 hours. It's
a nice, nice set up. You know,
we have to be,
this is what we have to think about for
real and it sounds hippy space talk,
but we have to really be concerned with
the way we treat less or animals because
that's exactly what the way
there seems to be an ethic.
It seems to be every fucking
animal that's intelligent.
We'll take the animal
that's least intelligent and
either fuck it or eat it and
that's, that's how it goes. That's
just how it goes with killer whales.
That's how it goes with dolphins.
That's how it goes with people.
We're the top of the food chain.
So we take the things below us,
like killer whales and dolphins. We treat
him like shit. We put them in prison,
we fuck with them,
we killed them in tuna that's accidentally
and nobody goes to jail for that.
And then you think about what whales
or what work is due to whales.
Killer whales are called killer
whales because they kill whales.
They go after whales and you
bite it is fucking horrible.
Video of Orca is biting Wales faces off.
I mean literally just taking,
just swimming and taking huge chunks
out of these poor defenseless, you know,
peaceful whales fingernails.
Yeah. Nerd whales, whales.
And then we know about chimpanzees would,
a chimpanzee is doing,
they find monkeys, they eat them, they
tear monkeys apart and eat him alive.
You know? So that's the intelligent life
that we've documented on this planet.
And every single one of
them either fucks are,
kills everything that it can control
also to away. Exactly. So do we.
So we have to be real careful saying
that I'm really cool with, you know,
animal experimentation. Because if some
new thing fucking lands here from Nibiru,
you know, and it goes, oh,
you guys are stupid as fuck,
you're still using the nuclear power.
Oh you guys have cell phones and retires
just start killing and eating hippies.
Right. When I moved to
Boulder, I saw that point.
That's what I really truly understood
the hate for hippies faces off and rape
them and eat them.
The last south park was so
awkward on if you saw it,
you'd got to watch it though.
It's about getting old and it was
one that was so weird, right? No,
I didn't say it was great.
I'm just saying it was so weird that I
haven't seen south park and have such a
long way to go to south park studios.
Watch the latest one. It's freaky man.
The first couple of the season.
We're not great now.
Felt like, oh, they finally hit on a
really great idea and they executed it.
You want to talk about prolific, who is
more prolific than those guys are insane.
Incredible.
And apparently it's all Trey Parker.
Matt stone is a huge
part of it is as well.
But Trey Parker guys and alien
and they have consultants,
the guys that come in and
basically go, that's awesome.
Do that, you know, like the,
and then they get a paycheck for,
for talent. Trey, how awesome he is.
Yeah. I got to sit in one of
my friend now works there.
He's that main editor guy and I got to
sit down on the couch once and you know,
like hanging out with Matt stone and
talking and stuff. It kind of relax. They,
once Trey came in, it was
just this intense energy
and everybody was just like,
okay, everyone's got to go. And you know,
it's so weird. He's, he's a maniac man.
I mean positive. I mean
I love him, but he's a,
he's really a hard worker and
you think you have to be that guy
day like during season three,
like in the beginning. And uh,
it was really impressed by
just the way that guy runs,
the fact that they were writing episodes,
but you know,
for comedy central and they were allowed
to kind of do anything they wanted
there. And I don't know if a lot of
people that watch the show know that,
but the way they kept so like you know,
ahead of stories as they were
writing shit the day you saw it,
sometimes you know,
they were,
they were rewriting and then it's on
air that night with the animation,
you know, nobody else does.
That's incredible. They are.
That's like how then do
we know when, uh, uh,
Ileane consultants when
that thing happened,
they had an episode that day
about it and then Terry Shave, oh,
there was stuff about it
and it was insane. Like no
other show does that. Well,
especially animation Simpson's you read
a joke and a year later it makes it to
TV, you know? Yeah,
yeah. That's a, they're pretty incredible
man. What done is a, an amazing thing.
And not just what that,
but they're fucking movies and apparently
there are new play isn't saying can we
see it? I'm hearing amazing thing. I
heard it's the same soundtracks out now.
Did you ever see in the more
I'm an episode they did. Yeah.
They did a half hour on the show about
Mormonism. And it was really funny.
He does a lot of more men's
stuff cause I think he's,
he grew up in that movie gas.
They've tackled pretty much every
religion on that show by now. But yeah,
there are more men. So they
grew up in evergreen, Colorado,
which is a pretty religious area.
That's why South Park,
south pus sorta based on evergreen.
I went to evergreen.
I looked at houses up there.
So it's interesting.
It's like a lot of rich people from
Denver. Columbine, is it up there? No,
not quite. It's like near
Golden. Okay. Like that area.
It's a suburb of Denver and
it's really nice up there.
It's beautiful houses and incredible view.
I mean it's just you got to deal
with some snow, but my fucking God,
it's gorgeous up there. Yeah, but there's
a lot of religious people up there.
A lot of churches, a lot of it's
like very different than boulder.
We looked at boulder and boulder was like
all hippies and intellectuals and then
evergreen was more like real right wing
and a lot of Jesus bangers up there,
which is a lot of Colorado, Colorado
Springs. All Jesus bangers like that.
Colorado Springs was hippies near
Colorado springs is a military town.
Colorado Springs is a,
it's a military is like the big industry
out there and that's where Ted Haggard
was from.
The Guy who was the gay Minister II,
which um, you know, it's uh, it's, it's
interesting man. How many people uh,
get in trouble with their dicks
in, in 2011. This, this latest one,
this Anthony Wiener guy.
If you seen the photos of him sending
photos of his dick from the congressional
bathroom or the Congressional Jim, he's
only congressional anymore. Oh yeah, yeah,
yeah. In the, in the bathroom of
the Congressional Jim in the land,
the locker room.
He's taken a camera for cell phone photo
of him naked holding onto his cock.
Nice cock. And his name's
Dina. So it's pretty cool.
Decent kind of take a lot more
pictures of my cock is bigger.
Would you send them randomly
to Twitter people though? Yeah,
I'd probably put them up on my Facebook.
Yeah, we'll look at what he did today.
This guy, I think it's fascinating
that he's not Hancock at the grove.
We would see the x men today.
Here he is.
I think it's cool that he's not
quitting. Yeah. But why shitty? I mean,
everyone fucking, who cares.
Yeah. He's just, he's a freak.
But yeah. How was that affecting
his ability to, you know,
to dictate policy or to do whatever
the fuck he has to do in his job?
You know what I mean? It, it compromises
people's ability to take them seriously,
I guess. But yeah, which ultimately
hurts us, I think. I guess so.
But the only reason why anybody wants
to be a politician in the first place is
because they, they want
power. That's just a fact.
There's so very few of those
people really, truly want
to help anybody. You know?
I think the obligation is so overwhelming
that to really want to do it,
just to help people.
I think people get into it and then
it's just too much and they just fucking
fuck, this is too, too crazy.
There's a few Ron Paul's that I really
believe are actually trying to make
things right,
but for the most part,
so many of the people
that are in that position,
they're just trying to fucking pump
themselves up. But as a Democrat,
when stuff like that happens,
I always feel like, you
know, Chris Rock and the, uh,
whenever a black guy gets in trouble
joke, you know, like, oh great, thanks.
Right. You know what I mean?
As a adding that to us.
Do you really believe in being a democrat?
Do you think that's real?
Do, yeah. I mean, I,
I vote that party yet.
Even though all this fucking Obama
Shit hasn't changed anything.
And in fact he's been more conservative
and I am done more. He's basically Bush,
Bush black, you know, he's almost done
exactly the same thing. Didn't close.
They'd gone down the way that's
gone. But I mean, come on.
He didn't close Guantanamo
Bay. He didn't, you know,
he said that he was going to close the
wars and public and he's sent 30,000 more
people to Afghanistan after he won the
Nobel prize. I mean, it's all insanity.
It's all insanity. It's,
it's the idea that,
that somehow or another Democrats
operate any different than Republicans.
It's all horseshit libertarian.
Well, you know, I voted for Obama,
but I did it just because I thought it
was a historic milestone and I was hoping
socially that it would make a big change
and it would be different. Yeah. I mean,
I guess maybe it has,
but you know,
and this whole fucking Osama bin
Ladin nonsense, they killed him. Not,
but we threw him in the
water. Yeah. It's all done.
Oh yeah. And a week after the, it had
like the lowest point, right? Yeah.
And you know, and he was talking about
that in a speech recently and he said,
you know,
that it's proof that did this,
this administration is on the right track.
You need look no further than the fact
that we got rid of public enemy number
one, Osama bin Laden. And I'm like, wow,
that is the craziest fucking
thing I've ever heard in my life.
Because what does that got done lately?
Oh,
was just a bad guy you were looking for.
You fucked this economy inside out.
It's asshole is prolapsed and hanging out,
bleeding all over the sand.
And you're saying that, you know, and it's
not him, but it's the whole system has,
it has not been repaired.
In fact,
there's millions of dollars and billions
of dollars that they can't account for
in this fucking bail out. They don't know
where the fuck it went. And you know,
there's all sorts of
shenanigans have gone on.
So to have this guy say that that's how
it's proof that it's all back in order
that they've killed this number one
bad guy like Jesus fucking Christ.
What are you think I'm a little
kid? Like that's, you know, I don't,
I don't believe in him anymore than
I believe in any of the other ones.
I don't think he's a bad person.
I just think that is the job you get
there and then they give you a script and
you don't really get much
fucking saying what happens.
I think we have this really a distorted
perception of what a president is and
it's based on like the ideal
of like President Kennedy,
the I the guy who's going to step in and
put this country on the right track and
you know,
and look what happened to him.
And I think that that is the
thing you don't remember.
I think that's what happens
when there's a guy who uh,
some happen to magic TMZ was
around when Kennedy was here.
Awesome. I'm like, God, I want to see
us going to get rid of Twitter updates.
He'd be popping bottles with models every
night like rose sex tape. I'm alone.
Could you imagine how ridiculous of a B?
Cause he would just be partying and
people be pulling out their cell phones.
Put that down.
Please try to keep America free over here.
He just be bitches and champagne and Frank
Sinatra high five and whether fucking
69 and chicks. Awesome. Yeah, it would
be a different world man. You know,
now it's like fucking every week over
the airport you see these dudes just
scanning for someone famous to show up
with cameras. Do you see them? Yeah.
You know, I know when they're
talking to me, times are tough
pulling me, you know, you, you, you,
what do you think of reality shows today?
Ben was, yeah, I have a question.
Is that I think they're awesome.
You watched American idol. So
we think about that guy, man.
The guy didn't go in at all. What's,
what's your favorite housewife show?
I go with New Jersey cause they're
the most savage who are the closest to
animals. I can't watch that shit.
Yeah, you can. If you do it once,
it's all you need one, one, one.
Yeah. I don't think it's the best move.
It's not a good move to get drawn in.
It's some the grand distraction.
Unfortunately. I watch it like
some of them and she hates that when
I walk into the room and I, you know,
I start scoffing or shaking my head like
the other night she made me leave the
room she was watching,
which we'll show in New York and uh,
they were arguing about some girl being
late for dinner and I was just like,
what the fuck? How can you watch
this? You're a smart girl. I'm like,
you're well read.
Did you like good things?
Like why are you watching these
fucking idiots? It's entertaining.
It stimulates some weird part of the
mind and it does provide some sort of a
relief.
And the relief is that you're allowed
to get invested in these people's lives.
We have no stakes whatsoever.
So this fucking bitch is yelling
at her husband and wow that guy.
Well he is a piece of shit and she does
have a point and you get caught up in
these and it's a distraction from your
own real live situation and your real
life problems that you need to
deal with. Yes, that's what it is.
Can't get my head. I would never want
to watch your show to con shopping.
Shopping would be number one on the
fucking the twat network and no time.
Um, I spent a lot of time on the message
boards, man. And I'm, I'm amazed at a,
and I've gotten to know a lot of people
on message boards and I'm amazed at the
energy that people will put into
concocting arguments on the Internet.
And like having like debates and putting
things in quotes and citing exams.
They put so much work into it yet I
know that their life is in a shambles.
Right.
I know cause they're going broke.
I know that that they might
be losing their fucking house.
They might be in the middle of a
divorce, they might be fucking, you know,
losing their job and yet here they
are spending an immense amount of time
arguing a sport or arguing about a
movie or a song or a band and you know,
and fucking with or
talking about you. Do you read, do you
read the critical stuff about you or,
I read some of it, you know, I know
it's really, really negative. I mean,
I see where the comedy just
fucking door in a fire. Okay.
I'm not going to listen to you. This
is silliness, you know, but you can,
I think you can get
some things from people.
I'm a big proponent of reading critical
things because for two reasons. One,
because I think it's like snake venom.
I think if you don't,
if you're not used to it and all sudden
you read some shitty about you, like,
Whoa, that hurts. I feel shitty. But
I see it so much. It's like, you know,
the snake bites here. I'm like, bitch,
I'm not immune to this shit. I mean,
I read that a lot where people say
stuff about me and it's like, really?
You're calling me a Yeti and that
I looked like a child molester.
I say that in my app.
Oh.
And I look like a muppet.
Never heard that. Uh,
fucking think of something new mean to
say about me because I've said every
possible horrible about myself and my act.
When you're a comic,
you can't catch a comic off guard.
Like we know what we look like.
You're not going to get us like that.
But when they'll say like critical shit,
it's always to me like super fascinating.
Like what are you trying to achieve
there and why are you so upset about
someone's art? You know, someone's
comedy, someone's offering.
It's like I have friends that will like,
fuck Larry,
the cable guy's fucking the Axa and I go
blah blah blah blah blah. Who cares man,
do you, does it really affect you? Does
it really bother you? You know, it does.
Like when you did the Carlos thing,
you were,
you were sticking up for a friend that
had been right sticking up for the whole
art form too, where people don't
understand about that whole situation.
It was like creativity was under siege.
We had a terrible situation,
but guy was getting away with
stealing shit left and right.
But I don't give a fuck if he was doing
it as, oh shit. If it wasn't good.
But there's been other guys where people,
like when people were first thrown
Dana under the bus, I was like,
it's not affecting me.
Ryan and I are not going up for the same
auditions and he's not taking food out
of my mouth by him being a fucking unfunny
hack, you know, I can't watch his act,
but it's not hurting me. You
know what I mean? Like, and,
and unless the guy is like,
you know, doing my shtick,
which know that he's doing,
I'm not going to get mad at somebody.
You know what I mean? Like it just,
I don't have the time.
I agree with you.
A hunting or sound or the energy and
some people did. Some of our friends,
people we all know, you know, like
that's how they spend most of their time.
Bad mouthing other comics.
How about your boy Dave Cross and then
fucking huge thing he did about Larry,
the cable guy that it
took hours to write man,
why are you even that guy? Like
fuck your girlfriend, you know,
live your life,
go downtown and get drunk.
For some people there's an underlying
feeling of they haven't achieved enough
success and when anybody else
has success somehow or another,
it draws away from their success.
And if they feel that this a person
who has success is cable guy from David
Cross, he who knows it just,
it's in the public eye.
We didn't almost get arrested development
and you know, you know what I mean?
Like fighting same parts.
But it's not saying that then
you're looking at rationally. Right.
I think we all come from
this really fucked up place.
Every comic comes from some
weird deficits, you know,
and a guy like Dave is not immune
to it and we are an Mri nor are you.
And there's definitely been guys, I've
been mad at petty shit, but you know,
it's because it got personal and it's not
because of, you know, cause they suck.
And I think Dave's point was that he said
that Larry was racist and w the stuff
he was doing was like, it was
like, but racist people love him.
I think you could say that
about it. Right. It's horrible,
horrible fans.
Some of them,
you know that guy fills out stadiums
like football still, Huh? Yeah. Yeah.
Joshua Wolf opened for him in a
football arena, I dunno. Fifth Office.
He's a comic. He does the Chelsea
handler show all the time.
He opened for him for 50,000 people.
Even seeing the 55 dice says according to,
uh,
Ari Shaffir talk to dice about it.
And then what you do is you just play
pretending that your buddies are in the
back of the room and
tried to make them laugh.
That's kind of what Steve Martin said.
You know?
Did you ever read the Steve Martin Book
about why he quit standup or it's about
him born standing up. I have it. He gave
it to me for Christmas two years ago.
I never cracked it out. And
you're on a plane for six
hours. Yeah. Yeah. Seriously.
I do my best. I'll do my best
writing and I do podcasts on planes.
I can't read it. I read the thing and I
think in one sitting and it really is.
Yeah. It bumps you ever into him.
Huge. I love, let's get small. Yeah,
I mean that's what he's one of
the reasons I'm a stand up. Yeah.
Probably the main reason. Yeah. Yeah.
He was the first guy got really,
really into and I would tell those jokes
to my friends and at that point I was
never like,
I'm going to be a stand up.
Cause I had this one kid
in my neighborhood is a
fat kid who thought he was
going to be the next John Belushi and he
was like, you're not funny. I'm funny.
Oh God. He was one of those
guys. Those guys are fucked.
Kind of a bully about being funny. It's
ridiculous. And the guy who runs around,
you're missing the whole fucking point of
it. Right? Almost everybody that I know.
That's really funny.
It didn't think they were funny and you
got to talk them into being funny. Yeah.
Well that's what happened to
me. It was a friend, uh, uh,
was working at a Mcdonald's in
Sacramento and this, you know,
I'm 19 working at a shitty
Mcdonald's and was, but he's like,
you should try stand up. And I was
like, no. He's like, yeah, you should,
you write jokes every day, you know? And
I was writing jokes every day. Why was,
I was making jokes up,
you know,
and making like structuring them and
doing basically what we do with that
without knowing that that's
what I was doing. Holy Shit.
Just bits about the people.
I would write little cartoons and put
them up in the wall and shit. And uh,
you know, but it was basically I
was writing jokes. Wow. That's,
you did that to me too.
And Steve Martin was the reason I got
into when I was in high school, uh,
I was not a class clown. I was
not funny. Like a lot of people,
like when I was in high school, they
found out that I was a comedian there.
Like what the fuck you became a comedian.
But what I did do,
I was an artist and when I did do is
I would draw cartoons of the teachers
that were hilarious.
Like there was a guy named Mr. White.
He was this crazy guy who
got back from Vietnam.
He was whacked and he was really short.
So I'd always draw him standing
on a stool, like everything.
No matter what it was,
he was standing on a stool and it was
always like him going fucking crazy about
nom and hookers and you know,
and so I would do different
cartoons about different teachers.
Like that was the only part of my humor
that that showed itself at all in high
school.
Imagine you had a cell phone back
then you can record this shit. Right.
I had the same guy, he was like a
Vietnam vet and he was just crazy.
And he would say all these terminology
and you're like, what's that mean?
Like you'd be like, don't you get your h
e double x are put you in the kitty bag.
And everyone's like,
what's a kitty bag?
And I guess that's some kind
of bag soldiers you, yeah.
Oh, so he would talk and like IED talk
and so weird and got acronyms are,
that was how I kind of turned it
around in high school. You know,
I was a giant nerd, but by senior year I
was doing radio and I was also doing a,
the school paper and I was writing jokes
and that kind of thing. Really? Yeah.
Being funny in these music reviews.
And there was a teacher who had lost his
shit and he was a nom guy and he killed
a dog. He had, his neighbor's
dog was staying at his house.
And the dog started barking and,
or like incessantly barking.
So he killed the dog.
And uh,
I thought it was funny to bark at that
teachers face and that got around school
that I just did this crazy barking
thing and made the guy kind of have a
meltdown and like turned
everything around for me.
It was one of those things of everybody
going, hey posting's not a retard.
He's kind of funny.
That's fucking crazy.
So you got in this Vietnam veteran
dog kill or space and barked.
What was his reaction to you? Barking? He
peed himself. He wanted to hit me. Whoa.
They turned really red faced and
just had a total meltdown. And uh,
did you feel in danger?
I know cause I had other kids laughing
and I was so like that was so much more
important, you know. So
when you left high school,
you had a direct path, you knew you
were going to be currently no, no,
I was going to junior college
and that's why I was living up.
I got kicked out of the house cause I,
I barely made it out
of high school cause I,
my grades had been really strong in
the beginning when I was a total nerd.
And then when I tried to turn it around,
they got,
it started going south because I
just wanted to be the class clown.
I tried to make people laugh,
I got kicked out of classes and while
they didn't even know you were actually
working towards a future yeah,
when I was, yeah. And then, uh,
just didn't know studying and you were,
you were being literally studying.
Yeah.
And so whether it's an
understudy Wani I actually,
I called a bunch of comedy clubs in
Sacramento and couldn't get into like the
lab and limits, you know,
remember those places.
And I think there's two clubs still
up there now. There's the punchline.
But I tried getting in and couldn't
get in and they said, well,
when you turn 21 and so the week I turned
21 and went in with 10 minutes already
written. And uh, uh, just that was it.
So similar to my story starting out
younger? No, I was 21 too. Oh, you were?
Yeah. So similar to the same story
of uh, telling other people's jokes.
Like for me it was Kennison
and Richard Pryor. I would,
I was delivering newspapers and I would
go to the office and tell people like
these Kennison bits that I saw online
and I was still, you know, in my head,
I could never do it myself.
I just, you know, it was in
my head I was like, this is,
this is like fantasy funded. It
was grammar school for me. Really?
Yeah. With the Steve Martin
and I must've admin. But 77,
six one was he popular? Yeah, I didn't,
I had a totally different career path.
I didn't think until, I didn't even
think about stand up, think about it.
I just thought I loved being funny.
I never thought, like I said,
I never thought I could do it. You were
just inspired by it to love this love.
I love making kids laugh.
And uh, I remember, uh,
as Kate at my school had
never seen the bad news bears.
And a in one day I told him the whole plot
or the bad news bears like started it,
the break and then we'll be getting, you
know, between second period and you know,
like a 10 o'clock in the morning. I
started telling him and then, you know,
we get called the class and then at lunch
I met up with them again and I'm like,
okay, so then this happens and just
told them the whole, all the jokes,
all the funny parts of the,
do you imagine if that kid didn't want
to hear it at all and he was just being
tortured by you all day?
It's like eventually this
mother fucker last shut up.
Laugh. Cause I knew like how to
tell those jokes. I knew how I say,
you know what I mean?
Like how to set them up and
it's, we're, spoiler alert came, was born
one of my parents when I was 13 my
parents took me to see live on the sunset
strip and a wow, that's cool. It was a
crowded, yeah. My parents are hippies.
They're pretty open minded and uh,
it was a crowded theater and
I remember laughing so hard.
I remember there was one point where I
stopped in the middle of it cause I was
just so bewildered and I looked around
the theater, I looked behind me,
I looked to the left and me and people
were like moving up and down and slapping
their legs and everyone was moving and
laughing. They were laughing so hard.
I remember thinking,
this guy is just talking,
this is incredible that he's just up there
talking like I've never seen anything
like this before.
And I thought about all the movies that
I saw that I love like stripes and all
these great comedy movies that was so
funny, but they were never this funny.
I was like, this is a different kind of
funny and it's just this guy talking.
And I remember that stuck with me,
man,
that stuck with me for years now when I
was 13 I still never thought about doing
it until I was like right before I did it.
That's when I thought about doing,
I got talked into doing it
by some friends, but he was
19 2019 and 20 years old.
Yeah. Yeah. Once you get going,
man, then you realize, God,
why would I have ever
wanted to do anything else?
Have you been following this Tracy Morgan?
Shit, I was going to bring that up.
Yeah. Yeah. Tracy Morgan went off
and said that if his son was gay,
he would stab that little nigger and
to death. Yeah. Yeah. Well, you know,
I can picture him saying it,
but it's kind of fun, you know?
Yeah. If he had said that any
place else other than onstage,
I would never give them a pass.
But when people have to
realize is sometimes you say
shit on stage and you don't
know what the fuck you're
saying. You're just, yeah,
you're ad libbing and you're going
down a road and then maybe you'd take a
choice just to be,
and then
you fuck up and you say something really
stupid and you don't know where to go
with it and you try to be funny with it.
And then I don't necessarily think
that is what he believes he might,
I might be wrong, you know, but
it's saying something on stage.
It sounds like a cop out,
but saying something on at saying
something in the real world to me are two
different things.
That's a performance as a character I'm,
it's not really
understanding what you think.
He's kind of doing a character
where it's more exaggerated,
ignorant version of himself.
I think that it's so close to reality.
He's done so much fucked up shit. It's
not like he's this really conservative,
buttoned down guy and it's
like his dice man character.
What I love about him is he kind of
doesn't give a fuck. Like I hear,
I heard stories of when he was at SNL
where he's like saying to women staffers,
you know, like, I'm going to fuck you.
I'm going to put a baby in
that it's like getting pregnant
pregnant.
Like I just feel like he has gotten away
with so much that he probably thinks
like there are no lines in his head
and giggles to his wife. You know,
like I think like, you know how
we are, we're out our friends,
like there's shit that we'll
say around our friends.
We would never fucking say on steam.
Right, right. You know what I,
I call it house humor,
what I meant like I am not racist at all,
but I'll say the most horrible racist
or homophobic things to make my friend
laugh. And I like how he is in his hand
and I think that's what it was. Yeah.
And I think because he
has no lines on his act,
his act has gotten dirtier and
dirtier over the years, you know?
And he's just good people love it.
And he's given this excuse to kind
of push it and push it. It's chaos.
And that's why he's so popular.
And that's why people love him is because
he's also playing that character on 30
rock words. It's basically, yeah,
it's an exaggerated version of him.
Kim, like mixed with
Martin Lawrence like crazy.
This was just a hateful misstep and that's
where the issue lies. And I feel bad.
Yeah. So I mean there's some, there's
certain things that I say ridiculous shit.
Sometimes,
but I would never say anything like that.
Even even in my most racist
joke when no one else is around,
how Schumer type situation wouldn't say
that I was on this truck stop too close
to that as bad as or flag just to
make my wife laugh or make one of my,
whoever's going to get you know back then
or you know, he's in a lot of trouble.
They're going crazy. They're going
crazy after him. Yeah. It's fascinating.
It's fascinating to watch
people get upset. Do they
want to fire out? Yeah, man.
It's stand up though and yeah,
it's a bad joke. It's not funny.
Yeah. He apologized. Look, I think,
you know he's going to have to leave.
Evaluate second. He said it.
He probably went, Oh God.
You know I've definitely done that.
Where I take a joke the wrong way.
Like you were talking. I'm,
most of my stuff is written,
but every once in a while I will go out
on a river, you know, just riffing and Oh,
I've taken some terrible rifts that
cause the rest of the night I'll like,
think of it what I sent them
while you're driving home and like,
just shit. Fuck did I say that? Because
you just, you know, you don't know.
Every now and then you take a chance
and something crazy will come out and
you're like, Whoa, this is a new bit.
And then it'll become seniors to write
it down and then you'll start doing it
and you'll do it on a regular basis.
I have a lot of my bits, you know,
that a lot of my bits are something that
I said on spur of the moment on stage
and the next thing you know,
expand on it.
But every now and then you go down a
dark road and it's so different from the
Michael Richards thing.
I know people were bringing it up,
but Michael Richards isn't a standup
and it was, he was not good at that.
That's why he had that meltdown.
He had fucking no business being at
the laugh factory on a Friday night or
whatever. Right. You know, in
the middle of a pack show. Yeah.
He was basically an open miker who was a
TV star and a lot of people didn't know
that. A lot of people assume that
he had a background in stand up,
but like do you ever seen him do standup?
He was a software guy.
You were there while he was at the
comedy store first and then he went right
over to,
uh,
down the street to the laptop and I saw
some of these stories and ate at the
comedy store. And I mean, honestly,
I thought he was fucked up out of his
mind on something that I thought he was
coked up. Yeah. You and big
called Brent. Yeah. Joe,
that night he called me and
then Brent Ernst came back.
We went to the comedy store. I
missed him. My spot was on after him,
so I came to the comedy
store and then Brent earns,
came over from the comedy store and said,
dude,
I just saw the craziest fucking shit ever.
He goes,
I just saw Michael Richards have a
meltdown and yell at people and call them
niggers in the audience. So he was at
that, he was there and we were like,
get the fuck out of here.
But I thought that would be
the end of it because I mean,
we've heard a million crazy stories.
I mean I've seen how many times you've
seen Joey Diaz whip his dick out at the
comedy store already or
girls put cell phone,
pulled her assets hallsband
back in the day and store.
Brian holds a con the first second go
credit and having to dig himself out of
that hole. I started Saturday night by
the way. Still got it. That dude is, yeah,
I saw him Saturday. Oh, flaring Connie.
He's an an uncharted treasure. Yeah.
Why do people have known about him?
They,
I don't know how to get
him on the podcast. I would
love to have on the podcast,
you know he's like a
meter maid, is he? Yeah,
he's like a meter maid slash
dog catcher. Yeah. Yeah.
He's like a dog catcher slash meter
maid in Manhattan beach. He's,
this is a joke I always quote. He
goes, uh, students that Susan Smith,
she drowned her kids.
I heard those are bad kids.
I heard this sat that close to the TV.
They didn't put the blocks away.
Those kids will not be missed.
And we were sitting the back of the room
and this was like the day after she got
fucking caught drowning your kids.
The first joke,
I saw him dues in San Francisco.
Egos like woke up this morning with a
hairless Filipino boy up my ass. I, uh,
pulled him out. I Fed them
breakfast, set him on his way
to the back of the room.
Good. Who the fuck is this guy
or lady him? Him and Brody
Stevens. There's this, these
characters that really go,
aren't they characters or are they
getting say is a little insane.
And Brian's a little insane too.
They're both of them saying,
but that's why they're
good. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I don't think you get good at comedy
unless you're not at least a little crazy.
Yeah.
I was telling Brody, I saw Bernie
also at the same night. I was like,
I wanted to do a sitcom with you,
Brody and Holtzmann and then you guys
have a dog. But it's like three's company.
You're not allowed to have the
dogs when they were landlords home.
You have to dress the dog up as a
PR person. Why isn't that on it?
How high were you when you came
over to this totally works.
We'll go pitch that to the network is
actually trying to get a show going for
Brody cause he's realized
that people need to see Brody.
What kind of show shark tank
he's been pitching around.
Brian tried to do a podcast with him
but apparently it was just a disaster.
We talked about that at the,
at the Improv I listened to about fun and
the last time I got high in the Improv
parking lot. Oh really? Probably
haven't been back there in a while.
So what a great club that is.
I never realized how great the the
Improv was cause I was always doing the
comedy store.
And then when my whole thing with the
store went down and I started performing
the Improv and like why everyone's
so nice here. Such a nicer place.
Just such a bunch better club. Are you
around this weekend? This weekend? Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. It's brand per se and friends.
Oh really? Friday and Saturday. So yeah.
You should come by fucking sound by,
yeah,
this is one of my first
weekends home for awhile. Uh,
definitely one of the nights I'll talk
to you. I'll call you. Yeah. Yeah.
Well we're going out.
Um,
another thing that I saw that I wanted
to talk about before I forget is that I
watch a fucking, somebody sent me
something about animals killing animals,
which is my Twitter feed is a
fascinating now because I keep retweeting
fascinating things and then
tweeting fascinating things.
Like I'll read some science journal
about black holes or my large Hadron
collider type shit.
And so every day people start tweeting
me these weird fucking links and this guy
tweeted me some shit about animals.
They get fucked up by
like little cute animals,
like animals that you wouldn't
think would be bad asses.
And one of them is the fucking bull frog.
Tude bull frog. Yeah. Yeah. Really?
Oh my God. You got to watch this
video, man. I wanna. I want to fire up.
Fire up this video, Brian.
It's called bull frogs.
Eat everything you got. You got to see
this because it's going to fucking,
they eat scorpions.
They eat the poisonous snakes.
They mice,
they fly through the air and catch birds.
They can jump like a motherfucker
had no idea. I had no idea either.
They have the crazy tongues. They have
the Thomas, they have this giant mouth.
It's bigger than their whole head.
Right out of their mouth.
Opens up a dumpster fucking kill bird to,
there's a fucking video of it,
man. I want you to watch
this cause it's so trippy.
We'll end with this and I just
want to get to your point.
What was that dirty or commercials?
Commercials on these fucking videos.
So, um, yeah, this bird, the
terrain. Angela's Scorpions.
I don't know why they don't die
from these things, but they fucking,
they also eat bull frogs.
Date smaller bowls. The frogs.
Yes. Check this shit out.
You're going to freak out.
Turn it up. Frogs are just a
selective eaters.
Feasting only on flies
and that's what I always thought it was.
Just flies. Yeah. Rock. For example,
spiders,
snakes,
fish,
and just about him. Should I fucking
mouse a mouse in his mouth? That's insane.
But how do they manage to
be such eating machines?
Dave, the Smith Center of using
cross don't have big claws,
sharp beaks or fangs,
giant houses that what have you overcome?
Pinchers poisons and spicy stingers.
Great outdoors.
How fucking crazy that he's just jack
the score piano look up. Biggest Mount,
but God, is he using his hands
to put yes. Yes. Yes. Watch him.
Jack does transfer.
They've been known to swim 20 feet
to shore and additional 20 feet.
Rapamycin or were they always like this
or these Newton bullfrog oh shit we're
putting in. It's Rocketdyne. Yeah. Oh God.
That had been known to stop and
it's like a lion on the proud.
Oh my God.
When?
How fucking crazy is that?
I love for using their hands
like that. Yeah. Really Weird.
Don't even eat each other.
Why not?
Small Bull Frog?
That doesn't watch it step easily.
Look how big this bull frog eating.
Yes, they are quite cannibalistic
young. Both heart muscle
quickly learn one simple, oh no,
eat whatever we had once.
Oh Jesus.
That's like you eating a
10 year old in one bite.
I mean you see how fucking big den is.
How crazy is that in and out?
It's closed.
Are you stat? I used to be in frog jumping
contest as a kid. I was first place.
It was the first time I ever was on TV.
What does that even mean? We used to have,
yeah, jumping frogs from Ohio.
There's not much in Ohio.
I said we get have fraud contest where
you raced frogs against each other and I
won like first place one year and stuff
like that. But I used to have buckets.
You're on frog.
Yeah.
I used to have tons of frogs and I would
like train them and and do all this
crazy shit but those
motherfuckers are crazy. We had,
I had this one frog that would have these
crazy suction cup things on his hands
and he could just jump onto like
a window and then like it was,
I think it was a toad maybe,
but it would jump all over it and it just
climbed it all over the house. It was,
frogs are amazing. I love, I'm
a big fan of frogs and one sec.
That's going to be a
quote online somewhere
now. That's fucking crazy. I've never
seen that. There is so bizarre. It's just,
if they were big, like I say about
everything, if there are big,
we'd be freaking out. You know? If
there were a size of horses, you know,
could you imagine how
terrifying the world would be?
A frogs were as big as horses. You know,
they're, they're creepy at monsters.
They're just little.
So we're lucky.
I think we're some genetic
mutation away from that.
Just like one step away from
having prophecy type animals.
Do you ever see that movie the prophecy?
I remember that bear pig,
whatever at the end, whatever the fuck it
was. Well, why not, man? I mean, they're,
they're, they're so close
to doing all sorts of crazy
genetic engineering. I mean,
they've developed cows that develop a,
that make human breast milk.
Now they're genetically engineered the
identical breast milk, human breast milk,
super injudicious friends, fringe,
fringe. Now I heard it's good. Yeah,
you might like it because it's about that.
It's about us being like close to,
you know, like this other world,
you know. Well, we were, uh,
Brian and I were talking about this
before the show started, the, uh,
the movie transcendent man.
Have you seen that yet? No.
It's Ray Kurzweil who is a
guy who's a new, another name.
He's a futurist and he's a proponent
of technological singularity.
And you've been talking about him online,
right? Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's, it's,
he's very popular.
He's got a bunch of books called,
one of them is the singularity is near,
which is a fucking fascinating one.
And his, his big thing is all about
artificial intelligence. And, uh,
but his documentary, he thinks the robots
are gonna take over or are they all do,
it's not just, yeah, it's not
one person that thinks to us.
It's pretty much every single person that
is involved in artificial intelligence,
whether they call them our deluxe
one guy calls it artilects artificial
intellects. What was the company
called? The terminator. Skynet.
Isn't there actually a real company now
called square? It's called Google. Yeah,
we know. But you don't
remember like an eye robot now.
There actually is a
company called I robot.
Like that just seems like you're fucking
tempting fate when you like take some
horrible thing from Psi Phi and
then make it real. It's like,
what are you thinking?
It's like actually opening a Jurassic
Park and calling it Jurassic Park.
What Brian went bad is gonna happen.
We'll read the book.
You know what Brian and I were talking
about before the show was that this is
all happening while we're just
sitting here relaxing as if there's no
consequences whatsoever. Like
there's no meetings going on. When,
when the first artificial intelligence,
which is conceivably one of the biggest
things to ever happen to humans,
the first sentience,
artificial intelligent life,
it will be switched on without any calls
to the heads of nations without any
vote from the people that, I mean
it's one of the biggest consequences.
Maybe the human race will ever face the
idea that something is going to be not
just more intelligent than us,
but literally within days it will be
millions of times more intelligence and
asking, cause it will be
artificial intelligence and
sentience.
So it will be conscious,
it will be aware and it will be
physically capable of creating
better artificial intelligence.
So right away it will fix all the problems
that it has in its operating system.
All the problems it has. And you know,
whenever problems it has with processors,
I mean we, we will literally
within a year we'll be obsolete,
will be just like little
monkeys that are at the zoo.
I welcome the robot leaders and I'm just
going to be really nice to them from
that
during the robots house. I
don't care. You're dead there.
You're the first guy that are
coming to your house first there.
They're familiar blow jobs. They
want, they want that. Trust me.
We're going to be like,
how are we going to help them see
level comedian to suck their dick?
Is that possible? Yes. That can
save you suck the robot cats.
We can be cats for the robots. Be as
bad as the regular Dick. Yeah. Shiny,
rusty, cold metal. You
can clean it really well.
You know for sure it's clean.
Take off the plastic first. Lysol,
spray it down. You know what you're
getting into. It's inevitable though.
Don't make him wear a condom.
Prostitutes.
I've heard prostitutes make you wear a
condom. I think when you get a blowjob,
something I just read. Let's
read here. If it does happen,
it's going to change the whole world
and it's probably going to happen and
everyone's just sitting back
like it's never going to happen.
I think it's gonna be great.
I think everyone's just looking
at the negative part of it. Okay.
What's the positive? The positive
is that robots are going to come.
Our friends or lovers, they're
going to make better lovers. Fuck,
are you doing fine? Trust me,
we're, we're fucking her lover.
The fleshlight had had
physician soft close.
This is the song you're
going to concoct robot song
could take our,
don't feel like we're super close to it
going south and like we're going to see
it. Yeah, we're going to see him
miss [inaudible] the whole civilization,
you know
down shit. Her Shit is happy.
It we could see we were,
we were definitely at the
apex of where there's,
there's some sort of an event that's
building up to take place and I don't know
how much longer we can continue to
progress until that event comes. Like,
what do you feel about when that rapture
guy a couple months ago or was it last
month?
I just had a stroke.
Did he just had a stroke yesterday
kind of or a couple of days ago.
It was just kind of funny.
Was there a part of you going
right, right. You know, like
I've been going crazy. You know,
like all the shit that happened on an
years where a fish falling from the sky
and all these dead things all around
the country and then the big quakes and
then the fucking Japan and you know, and
New Zealand crazy tornadoes, tornadoes,
like they have a good marketer. You know,
like when I was in high school, you know,
I grew up on metal and, and uh, I
was a Christian kid too. And uh,
and so I was raised, uh, you know, uh,
being aware of the Armageddon and
the rapture and all that stuff.
And I never felt like we were close.
Like that always felt like far away but,
but things now, you know, where,
you know, basically, you know, they,
they picture like the Sodom and Gomorrah,
like go to Vegas, you know, like
it's fucking about, you know, there is,
if there is a vengeful God, he's looking
at a Vegas, you know what I mean?
Like I know it sounds crazy,
but I know we're fucking close to that.
I don't think Vegas is the issue of Vegas.
Human depravity exists now. That didn't
exist in 1984 when I read those things,
you know, where things weren't
that bad. And when you're,
when you're talking
about Sodom and Gomorrah,
you need to go biblical scripture
and all that stuff that said,
that's nothing compared to what's going
on in Afghanistan or I write or the
millions of innocent people that died
because of the bombings and all the other
bullshit that's happened that,
but there were tiny but, but you,
you kind of see when a crazy Christian
pulls that kind of stuff, you're like,
sure, I sort of get where
he's coming. Well there's you,
there's clearly an argument that can be
made that things are accelerating. Yeah.
No, I mean tornadoes, we've never had this
many tornadoes before and would never,
I don't remember ever seen a tornado
that destroyed three quarters of a town
before the Joplin Missouri town.
Yeah. I mean in Tuscaloosa, Alabama,
I believe it was too fucking
like in a matter of seconds.
And you're talking about things that
are like a mile wide and wider and they
just destroying everything in their path.
I mean if there's,
I don't remember that before and then
the numbers are higher than ever,
but you know what,
we're dealing with such a limited amount
of years that we have a database on as
far as like my courtroom recording,
uh, weather and you know,
we know that things change
radically. We know that, you know,
the ice ages come and go and we know that,
you know,
a bunch of Shit's happened that over the,
over the course of a,
there's been like six major extinction
events that have happened over the course
of the earth life. So I don't think
we have a full handle on right.
But I think unquestionably the scariest
thing to me or the most profound thing
to me is what humans are doing is not
just what the earth is doing because even
though all those things happened,
the earthquake in Japan and the tsunami
and the tornadoes and all that stuff
right here where you and I are, nothing's
happened. You know what I'm saying?
But we're technology is developing,
developing and growing.
That's still going on while all
these events are taking place.
The large Hadron collider is still going
off. Why all this shit is going down.
All the different experiments that are
happening in robotics and artificial
intelligence and nano technology
and genetic engineering,
those are all still constantly taking
place and constantly moving further and
further and they're going to go somewhere.
They're never going to end.
It's never going to stop. They have,
they didn't stop with the atomic bomb.
They didn't stop with
mapping out the human genome.
They're not stopping with anything.
Yeah,
so it's kind of like up in the air
like are we going to have a biblical
apocalypse or assign a Saifai apocalypse?
I'm leaning towards Scifi,
but then you look at something like the
salt and sea thing that I was talking
about. I mean fuck man, the apocalypse,
hit salt and see if that was
the only world that we lived in.
If that was our only water and this
was the only tribe of people of Earth,
was there a little small place. It was
only like a few hundred miles in diameter.
Fuck man. That would be the apocalypse.
They're going, we would be dead.
There'd be no water. It would
be all poisoned. I mean,
that's the end in that spot,
the apocalypse hit. And that's, I
think what the apocalypse really is.
When people wrote the Bible,
theoretically,
at least they didn't
have mass communication,
they didn't have the
ability to send emails.
So the apocalypse was what experience,
what they experienced in their area.
Yeah. So Atlantis, that was the
apocalypse for them. You know,
anything that that took place that was,
that was real, that was the for them.
But meanwhile, on the other side
of the world in New Zealand,
people were eating coconuts and partying
and getting their dick sucked and there
was nothing, there was nothing.
There's no, nothing going wrong there.
So I think so in that sense, the
apocalypse is here, it's happened.
It's just not right here. Right. You know,
and it may not ever get here. It might,
it might rotate, it might move
around. It might be cyclical.
Just like everything else.
There might be places that are
good at places that are bad.
Tell yourself when you have a
young kid too. That's true too.
You start telling yourself all
kinds of weird shit with young kids.
You feel that? Yeah, for sure. You feel
like much more protective of things.
Holy Shit. Worried about your own
mortality, you know? Yeah. Yeah.
Worried about living in a big earthquake
tidal wave that's going to get it.
Hopefully were nine at comic book
shopper in like a grocery store instead.
We have to my first,
after the first baby.
That's the reason why we decided to move
to Colorado or so. I wanted to let go.
Why don't go where there's less people,
people,
things are more relaxed and you know,
everything's like a little more chill or
just a little bit more outside so that
when Shit, if shit does happen that
we're not stuck in this impossible.
The headstart city to get out.
Yeah.
You want to be in the valley when you
want to get on the freeway and being stuck
on the other side of that.
Well that's also one of the
reasons why I moved out here.
When I first moved to Hollywood,
I lived in North Hollywood and my car
got broken into and they stole my radio.
And then I lived in Encino
for a little bit and uh, um,
my yard got broken into and then I'm,
and I started slowly moving
further if those ones,
I had frank the pitbulls and somebody
broke in the yard and the dogs are there
and they fucking ran out. But then
I had, I think it was my gardener,
I think my gardener was
setting me up. Really? Yeah,
he's was asking me weird questions.
One day. It was really creepy.
I got a new dog and my gardener goes,
it was the way he asked me. He goes, uh,
he goes, uh, is that you're gone, your
dog or your girlfriend's dog? I go,
what girlfriend? Man? I go, what are you
talking about? He goes, do you live alone?
I go, what the fuck kind of question is
that man. And so I asked him flat out,
I go, you're trying to find out when I'm
home, dude. I need that. No Man, no man.
It was like this weird answer
that he had to it, but I was like,
the way you asked me was just so,
it was like like a really clumsy
guy trying to trick you like yeah,
it was like I could tell that he was
like prying for information and I wasn't
famous or anything. You know? I need to
get some bull frogs, Joe. I know. Right.
Giant ones to protect my property and
get them mixed up games with a bull
bullfrog so then I slowly moved further
and further out and I'm going to move
further out still. If I stay
in California, I'm going
to get a place in big bear.
I think. I'm just thinking
about that lately. Have you
done any at all? Yeah, man.
There's too many people down
there that's just like this.
This we were talking about with the
monster faces, the Newport beach,
you know those areas. I
like San Diego, but dude,
if the shit goes down and then everybody
abandons the border there by a bunch of
reactors down there too. Yes, exactly.
For these places we're going to get hit
if we ever get into a war with somebody.
True. And if we get a hit by an
earthquake and those reactors go nutty,
then the shit goes down and everybody
abandons that area. And guess what?
That's when you're really fucked
because Mexico's right there.
And if the door to Mexico just comes
down and there's a nuclear apocalypse all
in the same area.
Fuck.
But we also have the bit of the biggest
military bases down there. Yeah, Dude.
Do you think they're going to stick
there when there's a nuclear meltdown?
Listen man,
protecting our borders,
they're going to be protecting from
the air in led frisbees and there'll be
dropping bombs on people running
with bags of groceries from Vons.
La Jolla will be green. You'll be able
to see it from space. It'll be glowing.
Get a Zombie apocalypse or
an alien apocalypse. The fun
kind. Yeah, I went alien.
Yeah.
I have a feeling that we all unite
together like all our enemies.
It feels to me that it's too easy
with my Persian neighbor, you know,
fighting off floating a psalmist like
will Smith movie. Yeah, yeah, sure.
I think that, uh, the,
the idea of alien life,
like some sort of a physical alien life,
it's so hokey and so that to me it just
seems like that's not going to be the
way it happens. I mean, I might be wrong,
but I think that the idea of some
physical thing that comes here and starts
walking amongst us and shoot and ray guns,
I'm like,
that's like some 1950s
a super eight is right.
Yeah. Kind of. I don't want to
give it away, but yeah. Robots,
I think I can see that.
I can see c three Po,
some shit like that from another land
that's going to be the last guy on the
planet. Well that's why Battlestar
Galactica was so fucking bad ass.
That was it. Did you ever get
into that? The series a remake,
the fucking bad ass people don't know
if you've never seen him go get the DVD.
I'm telling you, seize
joy, the shit out of it.
It'll then a couple of a mini series
where there was one little mini season.
It's fucking good, man. It's so good.
Well written, cool special effects.
And even though it was on
the Psi Phi Network, the are,
you can do pretty bad ass fucking special
effects in 2009 or whatever it was.
And they made it.
Tricia Helfer the Cyborg.
He could jerk it off to the hot.
She's hot as fuck too.
Woo. Oh my God. Yeah.
And the cylons were bad ass.
There's different forms of cylons.
There was the one that looked like humans
and you could and people fell in love
with them or were fucking him and shit.
And then they have a cylon
baby that someone, a man,
what the fuck? That's a
great one, Brian Post saying,
where are you going to be next coming up?
Where can people see?
I got the Improv on Melrose,
so this weekend is Friday and
Saturday and then a man, uh, Detroit,
I'm off for a couple of weeks,
but Detroit magic bag, uh,
July 9th magic bag. Where's that?
Uh, downtown Detroit somewhere.
Is it a club? Was it, yeah. Yeah. And then
a gathering of the Juggalos and August.
Wow. In Seattle and Spokane in July
also. So nice practice saying that come.
Yeah. And [inaudible] is
spelled p. O. S. E. H. N. Yeah.
So it's the Brian Post saying
that's again, that's P o. S. E. H.
N for you I F two Twitter. Yeah.
Just to write that shit down.
And you have a website? Yeah,
Brian per st com. Powerful and a,
I'm going to be in Philadelphia
Known Pittsburgh the 25th of June.
Some tickets are still available,
but they're going quick. It's,
we're going to be at
the Carnegie Music Hall.
Me and Joey Diaz that
Saturday night in Pittsburgh.
So get on that bitch. Like that poster
I made for you. I haven't seen yet.
I'll check it out. I'm sure it's
ridiculous. You fool. And then, uh,
we're at Mandalay Bay theater. Do you want
to go to Vegas? That one July 1st? Uh,
sure. Okay. Mandalay Bay fee theater,
uh, July 1st and either grab Bryan,
give them no, used to get them
ahead. Headlocks and shit.
The people that are asking me
questions about fear factor.
I do not know what's happening. Um,
they just gave me the first offer,
so they want me to do it,
so we'll see what happens.
But I don't know if I'm gonna do it again.
So that's [inaudible]
song that come with them.
It's fine on dollar house
up in big bear. Yeah. Yeah.
Well I make a lot of money
with the UFC now, so it's all,
it's almost like it would be,
it'd be tricky. It's almost,
I'm almost like I wouldn't be making
any more money. It's very tricky.
I don't know what I'm going to do. It
help everything. Everything's good.
It's all good folks. We'll be back
tomorrow with somebody. I'm not sure who,
we got a couple ideas and we might even
be back on Wednesday were fucking crazy.
That's how we roll. So, uh, we'll see you.
Thank you very much Brian pro
saying I'm awesome. As always.
Anytime you wanna come back man,
for sure.
If you got anything you want to promote,
Brian Post sans a cool motherfucker.
Folks, follow him on Twitter
again. Thank you all and, uh,
subscribe to the desk squad on iTunes.
It's a cool series of podcasts that
Brian's running and we had cliff,
you'd be back in after a [inaudible] to
do a post talk. Oh, did you have yours?
Yeah. Okay, cool. Which
who's, who's, uh, cliff,
he and his girl and just sat around
and talked to her, whatever it was.
That one number is that it's going to be,
I'm going to release it tonight
on death squad dot. Okay, cool.
And you can find there's iTunes one.
There's Tom [inaudible] has
a really good one. And um,
Ari Shaffir has a really good one.
Sam triplink does.
And I know you were talking
about Brian Cowen doing one,
so maybe that'll happen too sometime,
right? Who knows? All right.
Love you bitches and we'll see
you tomorrow. Thank you very much.
And don't forget about the staff
flashlight. That's right. Oh,
if you go to Joe rogan.net. No, thank
you to our sponsor. The fleshlight. Yes.
You're digging it. It's real. A
fuck. You want one of those? Alright.
You shook your head and you're like,
I have a flashlight right down. Yeah,
it was good. I got a whole bit
about it. I've worked this out.
I know what I'm doing.
An Alien Flexco do a Joe rogan.net and
click on the link for the fleshlight
entering the code name,
Rogan,
and you'll get 15% off the number
one sex toy for men. All right.
Thanks to everybody.
Love you guys. Thank you.
Right.