Here we go,
baby,
five,
four,
three,
two,
one,
boom,
and that can be only one thing.
Avant.
Well far as we know,
far as I know in the universe.
Do you know what they think?
What do you know that the concept of
infinity apparently as explained to me,
but people far smarter than us,
is that the universe is so big that not
only is there intelligent life out there
for sure,
but there's humans out there for sure
and infinity is so big that that means
somewhere in the universe there is
another Theo Vaughn that has done
exactly the same things that you've
done,
said exactly the same things that you've
said,
been in the same conversations that
you've been in,
down to that pause down to the
millisecond,
an infinite number of times,
and you believe it.
Yes.
Not just one,
not just one time,
but an unending number of times because
that's how big infinity is.
You're not buying it.
I'll bet infinity smaller than the.
If I had a bet.
Yeah,
I just don't think that that could for
me,
that couldn't for me if I.
If I knew that that was true,
that would just break my heart,
I feel like,
because then you would feel like
everything you're doing feels pointless,
you know,
but isn't it anyway?
Just what you know about the universe.
Let's just say the universe was limited
to the size of this galaxy.
Okay.
Right.
Which it really could be.
Could be.
I mean,
would you and I,
let's be honest,
we're kind of dumb,
right?
Right.
We're failing.
Oh yeah.
I'm just guessing.
Guess total guess.
I mean,
I'll,
I'll say some big words every now and
then,
but the reality is I learned those big
words from people that actually
understand them and I'm just repeating
the noises that they say
so.
So tomorrow I'm the last person that
thinks I'm smart.
Trust me.
Yeah.
We're all mimics.
Really.
Exactly.
So if you look at,
I think they think there are hundreds of
billions of stars in this galaxy.
Just that alone is too big.
Too Big,
too big for you to wrap your head
around.
It's too big.
There's no one.
When you think about like how big that
is,
like there's no way you really think
about it,
you just,
you just kind of like,
oh yeah,
yeah,
big now,
now think of infinite and so hundreds of
billions of those,
and then they think it's possible that
inside each galaxy they know that the
center of each galaxy has a supermassive
black hole in it and they think that
inside that supermassive black hole
might be a whole nother universe filled
with galaxies.
Each of them that have supermassive
black holes in the center.
You go through one of those nother
universe,
infinite universes,
so infinite infinities.
So the universe is infinite and there's
infinite numbers of universes.
So somewhere out there there's another
theo on same haircut,
same jokes,
same style.
Really?
Yup.
Same back problem killing.
It did a scary.
I feel like if that's true,
that makes the job.
I took this one.
It seems so much shorter.
If the.
If the universe is that much bigger,
I don't think it could be that big.
Look at this.
What did he show me?
Your Jamie.
What is that simulation on the inside of
a black hole with design movie,
Bro,
that it was just.
This is just animation,
so the idea is you go through the black
hole and you wake up again,
a baby and Louisiana,
America you mama's cuddling.
You owe you such a sweet thing.
Birds Chirping,
but they're.
They're chirping 200 trillion light
years away.
Yeah.
You believe it,
I believe is a weird word.
Do you seal it?
It's too big.
I don't even feel son.
The son.
I go outside and I go,
oh yeah,
it's warm,
but I don't feel that there's a thing
that's a million times bigger than earth
that's floating in the sky.
No,
I don't feel that.
To me,
the hard part for me is when they say
that the universe keeps expanding,
you know?
Yeah.
It sounds like something a child would
say.
That part sounds to me like it just
keeps growing and growing and growing
and growing.
You're like,
what?
It sounds like something like my four
year old nephew would say if like he
won't go to sleep at night,
you know?
Well,
the real one is the birth of the
universe.
That's the real one,
like the big bang.
So before the Big Bang,
the universe was smaller than the head
of a pin,
the whole thing.
Right?
And then for some reason,
boom,
they don't know why,
but in one instant the universe created
seemed farfetched.
But that's what the scientists believe.
Forget about what religious people
believe or cult leaders believe,
or schizophrenia x the logit of legit,
the Sean Carol's of the world,
the Neil degrasse Tyson's of the world,
the real scientists that can hit you
with the real words and they actually
understand them.
The smartest people,
the real smart people.
They actually think that,
hmm.
What do you think?
I think the jury's out.
That's what I think.
Then I think I'm still kind of feeling
it out,
you know?
I think that I think I could easily get
sucked in if I'm not careful to just
believe in.
I just wonder if some of their stuff is
right.
You know,
like what if the building blocks that we
started with aren't really correct,
you know?
And sometimes I feel like they,
some of the science for me,
it takes too much of the hope out of it.
Like I guess I want to Romanticize the
universe a little bit and I want it to
be a little more fantastical.
Like maybe we get out there,
you know,
in the secret of that video and there's
a couple,
you know,
angels out there or a band or something
or like a,
you know,
some angels are like,
uh,
you know,
some sort of something more exciting
than just,
is that exciting or is that just more
human like angels and a band.
Right.
That's like human.
That'd actually be boring.
Yeah.
Maybe it's just me.
Maybe I'm afraid to go into that other
world,
you know,
into that other realm.
Like if somebody was like,
go in there and they were trying to push
me in there,
I would say I'm not going in there.
Have you ever
been in a place where you're in a or
you're outside at night?
There's no clouds and there's no light
pollution and you could see the Milky
Way.
Arizona Tucson.
It's crazy,
right?
Yeah.
It's a weird feeling.
Yes.
The all those stars and you're like,
is this up here all the time?
Yeah.
That's how I feel.
I feel like.
Is this out here all the time and what
have I been doing?
Yeah,
I think we're fucking ourselves up
cities.
I've been saying that forever.
I think all that light from cities
blocking out all those stars.
I think it confuses us.
We don't,
we don't realize what we're in.
We are in this crazy space ride.
Oh,
I think people forget about that a lot
of times.
I mean,
we definitely get caught up in the
minutia.
I mean,
but what's out there in the world and
the universe.
I mean,
I think if something were out there,
it would have stopped by now.
I don't know about that.
It's been a lot of time.
It's a lot of space on a space that has
to go through.
I think that things get so smart that
they don't do that anymore.
This is what I think.
Um,
I think that this whole idea about space
travel,
I don't think they do that after awhile.
I think they get so fucking smart,
they become symbiotic with machines and
I think artificial life and artificial
intelligence,
they create their own reality and
literally create their own universes.
I don't think they bothered traveling.
Oh,
they're just thinking it up and then
there it is.
I think they make things,
you know,
I think when,
I think this is just a thought,
but I think what's going to happen with
us.
I mean,
we'd take little trips,
send a rover to Mars and shit.
Then we sent probes into space Florida
anywhere.
You know what I mean?
You go local,
anything know it can be a big adventure,
but yeah,
we'd go out to the moon.
We went to the moon a couple of times,
supposedly,
you know.
Right.
But what we don't do,
what,
you know,
what we're doing with these little tiny
trips,
it's all fairly close.
It's all inside of our solar system,
right?
Yeah.
What we're saying is that someone is
going way,
way,
way further than that,
so they would have to be way more
advanced than that.
What I look at us and I look at
artificial life and artificial
intelligence and how close we are to
creating something that's smarter than
us within the next hundred years,
we're going to have some form of
artificial life that's probably way
smarter than us and it's gonna create
even better versions of artificial life.
It's going to improve upon the design
and then there's going to be things that
they can do in terms of like recreating
reality in your own mind,
like sit,
you and I sitting across from each
other.
We're experiencing this table.
We're experienced in looking at each
other.
We're friends.
We have a history together.
We talk a lot,
so we were used to being in each other's
presence.
There's all these feelings and thinking
and thoughts going on.
I think they're gonna be able to
recreate that.
I think they're going to recreate that
in a way that's indistinguishable from
this moment that we're experiencing
right now.
So then,
I mean,
you're human just going to become
obsolete then.
Yeah,
I think so.
Okay.
Well Dang it.
Dang it.
Don't you think we are.
I mean,
if you go back,
go back to single cell organisms,
go back to second Amoeba or something,
the first time,
single celled organisms as became
multicell Logan's Bulgur and one of
them.
How many of them were hanging back?
No Man,
fuck that.
I'm going to live in the woods.
I'm going to stay single cells.
Single cells way to go sell stuff is
bullshit.
I don't need to see things,
man.
Fuck you.
I don't need a phone motherfucker.
I'm a single cell organisms.
Oh Shit.
You know,
things don't have to get any better.
I'm like,
right,
like this.
I'm not going to get a job and be a
hitman.
So if you looked at single celled
organism,
they eventually became Theo Vaughn.
Right?
That's a.
that's a complicated leap from single
celled organisms from billions of years
ago to Theo von Holy Shit.
Is that a leap to,
to a human.
That's a big leap.
So you're saying it would be crazy for
us if we didn't continue to move
forward.
We're going to.
That's a good point.
It's going to happen.
Everything does.
We're gonna improve upon this.
I mean,
we're different now.
People are bigger and stronger and
faster than they were just 100 years ago
because the nutrition,
you know,
and those genes now was saying that the
genes that people who exercise and are
healthy are better than the genes of
people that don't like.
You literally can transfer some of those
traits and some of that potential into
children.
Rhonda Patrick at something.
She tweeted about that a couple of days
ago,
I believe.
Oh,
this a mud rats out there that have no
jeans almost.
I feel like like mud rat humans.
Just people that are just smoking their
own dicks out there who have no real
life.
Like,
you know what I'm saying?
Like I'd met some people who,
yeah,
they're breathing,
but that's it.
Really.
Yeah.
This idea that we're all equals.
You've never met anybody.
That's genius.
If you say that I've met some people
that I'm like,
I talked to them.
I go,
oh,
I'm like a monkey
dude.
I talked to your Buddy Eddie Bravo,
and that guy is a real.
He's out there.
He's like a jack.
He's like a deaf deaf Jack Russell
almost,
you know,
a deaf Jack Russell,
because once he gets going you can't.
Oh,
Jack Russell terrier.
Yeah.
You ever been around with the dog?
You opened the car and then next thing
you know they're.
Yeah,
they're like sick.
but well,
how's he depth?
Because you can't get them back.
Like once he goes,
you can't say you can't get them back in
the car.
Like you're sitting there honking the
horn.
You can't that guys out there.
You know what I'm talking about talking
about.
But I might make a description like
that.
Jack Russell terrier.
That is hilarious.
Extravagant did.
That means extravagant.
He's so motivated.
He loves conspiracies more than anybody
I've ever met in my life.
And he thinks everything is a
conspiracy.
Yeah.
No,
no,
he definitely.
Yeah.
But then he gets into it,
like,
I dunno,
it was fascinating to me how he went
from this like one genre of life to the
next and created a business in each one
and kept moving forward.
A business.
Yeah.
He got like,
he was amused.
He liked music.
He started a band,
you know,
he liked a karate.
He started doing,
um,
you know,
organized karate.
He liked,
uh,
you know,
what else did he pee?
A couple of other businesses.
I think he got into a couple of other
things.
I don't know what the other two.
He lost me a chapter 70,
but he'll hit you with too much
information.
Man.
It was crazy.
A lot of people to Google.
I was like,
I want to climb through a black hole
right now into a shit.
Like,
wait a minute.
Is this guy legit?
Dude.
The other night to him,
he sends a couple of links.
You got to shut your phone off at a
friends with Eddie on was 1:00 AM phone
calls coming in that spot because you
will get,
you will get a wall of text explaining
which youtube video has the right
information.
Which one is set up by the CIA.
It used to be like stopping at a rest
area on the interstate.
That was like the old Eddie Bravo.
He'd stopped there and next thing you
know,
you'd hear the craziest shit in the
world,
right?
He used to be playing in the background.
Now he loves all of it.
He loves it,
but he's.
He gets out,
he goes in phases,
like he gets out of them for awhile,
like he was really into chem trails for
awhile,
but man,
I know he probably won't admit it,
but it's pretty obvious.
Chem trails are bullshit.
Fucking obvious.
It's just writing because they can write
birthday,
they can write happy birthday,
Rhonda or something and that's not.
That just seems like it's smoke
somebody's birthday that I think when
they do that they're doing that on
purpose,
but the chem trail things just,
it's just nonsense.
There's,
there is some evidence that they have
experimented with spraying stuff in the
sky and they definitely seed clouds and
certain parts of the world in certain
parts of the country.
You know,
they can make it rain like a in Abu
Dhabi,
right?
Where they make it rain once a week.
Wow.
Once a week.
It's there.
They live in the desert jets up there.
Yeah.
They send jets and I think they use
something silver iodine or something
like that.
Is that what it is?
It's one of those pilots,
they spray into the clouds and somehow
or another it makes it rain.
He know when Eddie came,
when I was talking to him with any one
thing I was thinking about was,
do you think that there are aliens?
Oh,
do you think that robots will get so
advanced that they will like become
aware and what does he say?
Oh,
I don't know what he said.
I guess I'm asking you because he went
off on something else and he didn't
really answer it.
He said,
it doesn't get too much into artificial
intelligence.
He's more into like,
the FBI tried to fuck us over.
Yeah.
Well he told me in the bathroom after we
talked,
no joke.
He said he had to be a little bit quiet
because he thinks that some people could
be looking for.
Oh,
that's so crazy.
And it was crazy.
He said that all hush hush about the
urinals.
Dude.
He thought that the government got to me
really because I wasn't in chem trails.
Chem trails would did it.
He's like,
just got.
It's got to be a reason here.
Did they do anything to you?
No.
You swear?
I swear no one's talked to me about
anything ever.
No one said,
hey man,
layoff,
bigfoot bigfoot talk.
But what are you saying?
I'm just saying if you want to know.
I don't.
I manage this.
What are you showing me,
Jamie?
This is the article about the cloud
seeding and Abu Dhabi that they use
high.
Wow.
Hi.
Grows scopic salt to level up the amount
of amount of moisture to generate more
rain.
Huh?
I could see him doing that.
Dr Habib.
Adding that.
The best season for seeding is between
June and August.
Huh?
Hm.
So I mean there's,
there's solid up into.
Yes,
they spray shit and it makes it rain.
I find that the moon state,
we went to the moon,
the moon send makes sense.
Delta could get to if you really think
about it,
like you know what I'm saying to
airlines like southwest though,
right?
I mean I'm a little shaky,
a little bit shaky on there.
Some of the people are and they're
wearing shorts,
you know,
you get on it.
I don't trust anybody in his shorts,
especially at church,
but um,
I'll say this when you like,
it's crazy.
We've been flying across America for,
you know,
40,
50 years now,
right?
Yeah.
Even more maybe,
you know,
and it seems like it's.
We could figure out how to get into
space.
It's harder than that for sure.
First of all,
it's 260,
2000 miles,
you know,
the earth is 24,000 miles around,
so a full trip from right here.
So you start in Calabasas and you do a
full trip all the way around the planet
and land in Calabasas that's 24,000
miles.
Okay.
So it's like 12 times at or something.
Yeah.
Something like that.
Well,
we could do that was we
these we shit.
It's hard bed and not only that,
there's no air.
It's one six earth's gravity because
you're dealing with all sorts of
problems in terms of solar flares and
radiation were protected by the
magnetosphere,
were protected by the radiation belts
and you know,
all of the,
the atmosphere of the earth.
When you go through that and you go out
into the space,
you're not protected by shit.
We couldn't.
We,
I think we can fight that man.
Well,
it can be done.
The problem was with biological life.
See,
one of the things that made it so
interesting about the moon hoax there,
particularly for me,
so it never sent anything alive in the
space and had to come back alive ever.
They never said they never even sent a
chicken in the space and had to come
back a lot.
It all dies.
No,
they just do it with people.
They've only done it with peep a.
they've never made something.
They never shot a monkey in a space and
then brought it back alive.
So that's why you think it could be
fictional?
No,
it's the only one reason why it was
enticing to me.
One of the big reasons was the Fox
documentary.
There was a fox documentary that aired
on tv,
I think it was in the nineties.
It was called conspiracy theory.
Did we go to the moon and it showed that
they use the same backdrop for different
moon missions that were supposedly like
really far apart from each other,
but the back backdrops sinked up.
There was all sorts of images that
showed different shadows that we're
moving at different angles that would
indicate different light sources that
was more than one life source instead of
the just the sun.
There's a lot of these things that make
it intriguing.
The problem with that stuff is that I
don't know Jack Shit about aerospace
engineering.
I don't know anything about it.
I have zero,
zero education in physics.
How Kodak works in space.
I don't know how any of that.
That's also part of the problem is the
images,
the images.
A lot of people like how are the images
so perfectly squared.
There's no errors.
There's some of the images where things
are in the shadows.
They're lit up like there's backfill
being used,
but that still doesn't mean they didn't
go.
They definitely faked some images.
This is a fact.
They know this because there's Gemini
Fifteen,
there's a Michael Collins photo.
That was absolutely a photo that they
used of him in a training mission and
where you could see the harnesses and
all that jazz,
and then they blacked it out and they
use it as a publicity photo saying that
he's on a space walk,
but that could have been an overzealous
publicist.
You got to look at everything like
really objectively.
Yes.
You wanted.
I,
I wanted the moon landing to be fake.
It seemed fun to me.
I wanted it to be.
There's so many things that the,
the um,
what is it?
The Prime Minister of Holland who is in
Holland and I met Bazal.
They met,
they gave this guy a piece of moon rock
and it turned out to be a piece of
petrified wood,
but it was signed in.
A plaque was delivered by Michael
Collins and Buzz Aldrin and Neil
Armstrong,
and they're like,
this is a piece of moon rock for,
you know,
we're giving this to Holland.
This is amazing.
Like,
wow,
you've given us a piece of the moon.
That's so cool.
And then they finally wound up finding
any testing it.
It's a piece of petrified wood.
It wasn't for the moon is fake.
It's fake.
Yeah.
And one of the Dutch law,
things like that.
It's a gift to a control.
I say the Dutch are wild man,
but that also could have been.
You got to deal with.
You're talking about the 19 sixties.
Richard Nixon was the president.
He was an asshole.
You know who needs like probably fuck
them.
Not Giving them a moon rock.
Get,
get,
get one of those petrified.
This will be full area.
Take a piece of petrified wood.
We got four kilograms of moon rock.
Shit to the Dutch.
The Dutch.
I mean this shit.
They don't.
Yeah,
I mean actually who gives a fuck,
you know,
like,
respect to the Dutch,
but some of the greatest boxers of all
time.
Really that one spot.
Well they're aerodynamic till you ever
seen a Dutch person to pig will and also
there rick streaming,
you can look at their faces are
extremely or dynamic.
Seemed to travel through space better.
Is that what you're saying?
I think if you take like one of the
front of a plane,
you know,
it wouldn't be that hard on him.
Good to have good symmetry that we were
saying,
Oh,
you look at the Dutch,
their heads tall,
right.
It's like I'm good genes.
Probably Vikings.
Right.
That's probably some viking genes hold
the big.
They're really big people and they got
total craniums space.
They have a lot of room in their head
for ideas.
Yeah.
Plus they will.
One of
the first people to say who gives a shit
about weed?
Everybody used to go to Amsterdam to get
high.
Well the problem with Amsterdam is
there's those trains,
there's people on bikes.
It's like the worst place to walk around
high because there's so many forms of
transportation going on.
There's fucking people traveling by Cro.
Like I tripped out there man.
Right.
This is like boats.
There's a way to have both people get on
boats and shit did I showed up there one
time and they had to um,
gay pride weekend,
you know,
and I didn't know it and they had like a
lot of homoerotic like boat floats going
Bolick just single men just dance day
it.
I was like,
I didn't know.
I thought that was just,
these people were like,
Hella Dutch.
Gay people know how to do it.
Oh yeah.
They party mailing,
holding them back.
There's no Yang or you know,
whichever one it is.
They're all Yang.
Yeah.
It's just people Yang in each other's
seems.
Yeah.
I ended up just and each other.
I know that's happening in space,
in space somewhere.
This gay people,
they can get pregnant
to get each other pregnant and they're
gay because how?
Because the different guaranteed.
Oh,
you think that?
Oh yeah.
One hundred percent.
There's gay pride.
Whoa.
Jamie just pulled out what it was brown
and I thought,
Holy Shit.
I got one 10th of one percent get just
from looking at that as aerodynamic as a
king.
Get it,
boy.
And no one has a shirt on.
It was a couple of guys with life
preservers.
No one has a fucking shirt.
I'll look how gay this is.
This is hilarious.
They're all buffered shit.
There's one girl with her hand on her
forehead and the front of the book on
what?
In the fuck.
I can't get no dick.
She's like,
her friend tells me you've got to get
down here.
There's a thousand men with no shirt on
and they're all hot.
Oh my God.
I'm there.
I'm going to get us ride on the boat.
An hour into the boat.
She's got her hand and I had fucked me.
They're all gay.
And that kind of slipped this too on the
right if you could see that.
I think so,
yeah.
One of his hips a little higher.
I have that display show
and it's popular in people that have
that.
And also Australia.
No,
you think he's just like standing on
something that could be just to stop
moving.
Fine.
Seemed like he feels self conscious
about his legs he has on patients.
It's hot out there.
You don't think so maybe,
right?
Like you can't squat anymore.
Oh yeah.
Dude,
I'm in that bad back club man.
It's hard when you get that.
I just had a just,
I think God just put like a week spine
and me and so when I was 27 I was paint.
I was painting a wall and I lean for
like maybe 40 minutes leaning out with a
paint thing and when I lean back in my
back wasn't right anymore.
That was it.
And it's been bad ever since.
Really?
Yeah.
I'd have part of my vertebrae.
Somebody.
This man took it out at Cedar Sinai.
Man.
He took it out.
Yeah.
What did he do it?
Did you know him first?
Met Him through insurance,
but he got it and they and I've been.
It's been hit or miss since then.
What's he doing with it?
Oh,
I don't know.
They can't afford to go back and see
them again.
It's 7,500 bucks.
You can go to them.
It's like I got a scam.
That's a scam.
Want to talk to me?
You sit on that side of the day and
$7,500 for your time starts now
you're back.
Yeah.
Okay.
Next person.
Is it like a disc or a piece of the
actual bone?
Like what was it?
It's a disc.
They got photos of it.
I don't know if they're real,
you know,
that'd be crazy part the moon landing.
Well here's the data,
here's the credit.
Put you under and said,
yeah,
we fixed it,
bro.
Give me that money.
Oh,
100 percent.
And then in my head,
you know,
cause I'm probably about 60 percent
gullible sand.
Yeah,
I think so the more I look back at my
life and kind of charted out,
went up and gullible and when I
happened,
what's the biggest one that you look
back and go,
ha,
fuck that.
I believe that.
Um,
I would say probably
real overall religion.
Probably when I was super religious when
you were a kid.
I wasn't super religious,
but I,
you know,
I just wanted it all,
like everything,
like in the bar,
you know,
I just wanted it to be real.
Yeah,
I guess I wanted it to be real.
Right.
It just made it hard.
It made it tough for some other things.
You know,
you're like,
first it was like,
fuck,
I gotta remember all this shit.
Like I can't remember.
I'm not going to be able to be accepted
by God or something because I can't even
remember what's in this book.
You know,
like I'm going to need to hire a tutor
just to be,
go to heaven,
you know,
like,
because the Bible is bro,
it's not the best book.
Well it was really good when it was
written yet.
It's like trying to watch a movie from
the 19 thirties.
You'd be like,
look at this Corny fucking acting.
Yeah,
right.
yeah.
You know what I mean?
I mean there's nine chapters about
livestock.
Like it gets,
it gets,
it gets held risk,
a in the middle.
Really read the whole thing cover to
cover and I haven't read any of it in a
long time.
Yeah,
I read it when I was in,
when I was in,
I guess I was,
I was living in Florida,
so I was 11.
Oh,
that's a good time to read them out in
school and I remember my parents being a
little disturbed,
but because I'd gone from a Catholic
school and the first grade my mom split
up with my dad,
my mom shacked up with my Stepdad who
was a hippie.
She kind of became a bit of a hippie too
and we fell way out of religion.
So the Catholic church and all that
stuff was a thing of the past.
Was that pretty cool?
The hippie Stepdad.
He's a good guy.
Very nice guy.
It was weird,
you know,
he had long hair and shit,
like long hair,
like down to the middle of his back and
so like,
like crazy.
Would you ever like see him from behind?
I think it was like a woman or something
from Pharrell.
Well because he was muscular,
you know,
he looked like a man,
but he's a man with long hair.
Yeah.
But um,
you know,
uh,
when I was in high school,
well not high school,
I guess it was in a great school.
So what is 11?
What grade is that?
Depends on how smart you are.
Really Great.
Fifth Grade.
Yeah.
Depends on how smart you are.
You know what I was reading?
This is how great Ronan Farrow,
you know Woody Allen and I'm the guy who
wrote that article.
Yeah.
He's not really woody Allen's kid.
By the way.
Look at that kid.
Look at Frank Sinatra.
Holla at your boy.
Say
that kid is Frank Sinatra's kid.
One thousand,
1 million percent because mia farrow
used to bang Frank Sinatra.
Oh really?
They had a freak.
Look,
I know.
come on.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Look at it.
First of all,
handsome men.
That Ronan Farrow.
Handsome man.
Yeah,
that is God dammit.
That is Frank Sinatra's kid.
One billion.
Trillion percent.
You better stay the fuck away from 23
and me out that.
Yeah.
Look at that 23 and we'll just send back
the song.
New York,
New York when he was 11.
This how smart this guy is.
When he was 11,
he was taking college courses.
Oh my God.
11 nerd alert.
That's what I read.
Makes sure that's true.
I don't want to write an article about
me.
Spirit of bad information,
but so they had a freak relationship
anyway when they were together.
That was their only biological kid and
it's not really their biological kid.
Why not?
Because it's fucking Frank Sinatra's kid
started college at age 11.
Wow.
He says he fell apart while pursuing the
Harvey Weinstein Story.
What do you mean he fell apart?
Probably because it was so dark.
Oh,
I mean,
come on,
man.
Do you remember before that story came
out?
Everybody knew that guy was a creep.
Right?
But it was like this thing about like,
like more door,
you know,
like he lives,
lived in Iran,
lives under a rock somewhere.
Everybody knew he was a creep.
You,
everybody had heard stories.
But this guy,
he graduated at 15 from college.
Oh my God.
Why does he keep saying the son of Mia
Farrow and Woody Allen?
It should say wink,
wink,
nudge,
nudge.
But that's crazy though.
They're trying to push that so much.
You know,
the son of Mia Farrow and Woody Allen.
Well,
he was raised by them for a little while
until he started banging his sister.
I'm like,
God,
yeah,
that's a freak household.
And then the dark arts out here,
Hollywood's got the darkest arts,
Bro.
They lived in New York.
Well even New York,
Hollywood,
because some of it's the same thing.
New York,
Hollywood.
Hollywood is just show business.
Yeah,
show business.
That's what I mean.
Well,
there's definitely something to that
because how about that composer that
turned out to be even more of a fucking
asshole and Harvey Weinstein,
this is one composer that was just
fucking all these young boys and if you
didn't fuck him and they just.
They recently got rid of him,
but he was just running things through
sex and you know,
he just basically had a sex cult going
on.
Find out who the fuck that guy was.
But he was a cherished famous loved
composer and it turned out this.
This dude was running the freak show
behind the dirty,
just not just being
dirty,
but that was the way to get in and if
this guy is shut you down,
you were shut down forever.
You weren't working anymore.
So he was like the.
He was the gatekeeper kind.
He was like a Harvey Weinstein of music
team,
like what Harvey Weinstein was doing to
those actresses is he would try to fuck
them.
They'd get mad at him and he would
blackball them.
He would say,
you're not working anymore.
You're too difficult to work with,
and then he would shut their careers
down.
All these different.
These different women found out like
when they,
their careers fell apart,
they found out that was going on.
There is what happened.
What happened.
See,
that's dirty man.
Oh,
him,
Huh?
Yeah.
From the met James Levine.
Sexual abuse claims.
Yeah.
Well this is from December 2017,
but that has been.
It's been.
There's recent stuff put up,
pull up a sexual abuse James Levine
because the more recent stuff is much
more confirmed,
like a bunch of people came out and we
had to do it in our neighborhood named
Mr Lang and Stein and he used to invite
us over to a chill out and shit,
but we didn't know he was that he was a
pedophile,
but you didn't know how to try now.
He ended up going to jail for it.
So you're hanging out with them for
awhile and you didn't know.
Yeah,
we met him at school.
We thought he was just as cool old dude
who like to smoke pot,
right with children.
And one time he bought us some steaks
because he would like,
you know,
treat us nice,
and b,
he would take us.
He took us to Marilyn Manson,
me and my best friend,
he took us to Marilyn Manson.
We were like 15.
We couldn't even get in.
It was 18 year old show.
And how old was he?
He was probably 70.
So,
and he had like a red convertible,
you know,
and that's,
everybody wants to be in a convertible
and so we got in and we went and um,
anyway,
he,
you know,
he would,
he got us some stakes one time in the
state,
come with baked potato side item.
So we had a sour cream on this,
on the baked potatoes and my buddy was
in and my buddy was in the kitchen and
he said,
hey,
I'm out of sour cream,
can I have some of yours?
And I said,
no,
but you can have.
So in my sweet cream,
you know,
just making like a joke about semen and
then big and style and the dude goes,
can I have some?
And that's when all the fucking wheels
turned and you realized,
oh no,
I'm just sitting there with a mouthful
of potato.
Like fuck it.
He was just a nice man.
And you were thinking that this,
this whole time it was just setting you
up?
Yeah.
And my buddy,
that was the biggest thing,
I was so concerned,
like I brought like for my friends over
there and I was like,
what has been going on?
I had a similar situation,
guy named Walter.
Yeah.
We used to go fishing and he would run
around the pond and he was um,
he mentally handicap?
No,
no,
he was,
he was a teacher and he got fired when I
was trying to explain to us that he had
uncommon unconventional teaching methods
and that they didn't understand his
teaching methods and that
they fired him.
Oh.
So then he's like,
he's like the,
he's like,
it was a very smart guy and two kids,
he probably seemed like the cool guy
because he's like unconventional and he
was always jogging,
you know,
was always,
always jogging around this part.
Oh yeah,
that's a gay,
straight bi.
And he would sit,
he would combine hanging out with us.
So we'd be fishing,
we'd be hanging out the spot and he come
by,
sit with us for a little bit,
then take off.
So we became friends with this guy.
I went over his house once and I'll
never forget I ate at his house.
It was just me and him too.
And he didn't do anything but went to
the bathroom and uh,
I guess I was 13 somewhere around there,
somewhere around 13 at the time.
So while day is a susceptible age?
Yeah,
for sure.
And I,
uh,
I went to use the bathroom and I peed
and I guess he was in the bathroom with
me and afterwards he said something to
me,
he goes on,
he had this weird way of talking and
he's like,
I didn't know you were showed developed
again.
I was like,
what?
And I was,
I was thinking about it.
I'm like,
I was talking about with Dick,
but he wasn't flirting with me.
It wasn't weird.
It just was like,
he was just talking about my dick being
developed,
you know,
like a curator,
like an art curator or something.
No,
it was just,
it wasn't,
it was weird,
but it wasn't dangerous.
But then it got dangerous because I'd
been friends with this guy for months.
Right.
For months we have been going fishing
and he had been coming to this lake.
There's two places.
There was a,
there was um,
Jamaica pond,
which was all in all,
this was in Jamaica Plain.
And so there was,
Jamaica pond was this one spot and there
was another pond that was nearby that
was a smaller place that was more
secluded,
but it had like good pickerl fishing
pickles,
like a small northern pike looking
creature.
And so I was fishing there and pick her
up and stop coughing.
So he shows up drunk.
That's when it got really weird.
And he told me he loved me.
And uh,
the academy say it.
Did he say it?
He,
yeah,
he said it like he was behind me,
like sitting down and I was fishing hot
dude that's making me.
He goes,
he goes,
you know,
Joey,
I love you.
And he was like,
probably in the sixties,
right?
And I go,
I like you too,
man.
I was like,
weirded out.
I didn't know what to do because he was
drunk,
like definitely drunk goes,
there can be no love without sex cheap.
That's what he said.
And I went,
what?
And I remember I had a Swiss army knife
in my pocket and I put my hand on the
Swiss army knife.
And uh,
I remember saying something like,
man,
you better leave me the fuck alone.
Like something along those lines.
Wow.
I've got him pulled the knife out
because I was 13 years old.
He was a pretty big guy.
I was like,
even if I pulled his knife out,
am I really going to be able to stab him
seven or eight times?
Is this Guy gonna beat me to death and
fuck me,
you know what's going to happen here?
But he left me alone.
He left me alone.
But then he wrote a letter to my house.
So he found out where I lived.
Yeah.
And he probably had to get drunk to come
there and do that to be able to even say
that to you.
That's probably why I did it.
Like he was probably trying to figure
out a way to work his way up to
molesting me.
So I think that's probably why he got
fired from school.
Yeah.
Do you feel a little bit bad that he had
led them on?
I was a little cutie DNA.
It's a kid.
But did you feel a little bit bad that
he had kind of taken advantage of like,
like fuck,
now we can't kind of be free,
like you know,
like you think in ia that was.
I did enjoy talking to him because he
was telling me about things like he knew
a lot of things about life.
He was definitely a very educated guy.
So before the drunken weirdness and the
just the general,
it just got more.
The more comfortable he got with us,
the more I realized that this guy was,
he was attracted to children and he was
trying to fight it off.
I think,
you know,
I think a lot of people that are
pedophiles are extremely embarrassed by
it.
Oh,
it's a sickness man.
Yeah.
I don't think it's something anybody
chooses to do unless they're trying to
start like a track team or something
like maybe in the Philippines or south.
Well I ran into my friend Josh and I
told him immediately because Josh used
to go fishing with me and we both knew
that guy and I explained to him the
whole deal and he was like,
fuck.
And so he was scared too.
He was like,
dude,
I'm gonna stab that fucking guy.
And Josh went extra hard.
He went extra hard,
like,
Oh,
aggression and anger because his parents
were lesbians.
Oh,
he had two parents are lesbians.
So he wanted,
I think he wanted me to know that he
wasn't gay.
Right.
And it was mom's gay,
right?
I mean,
so it was like all fucked up.
Fuck it,
you know,
that kind of shit.
Like whoa down.
Yeah,
this gay.
Yeah.
This has to stop.
He was like fucking sword up in his
warehouse.
That is not happening.
I don't think he called him a faggot.
I think I made that up.
I literally barely remember because I
was 13.
I do remember him saying that though,
that there could be no love without sex
because I remember like,
what?
That's crazy what a gateway line to
dude,
if you're a pedophile,
like I'm glad I don't have that,
that element,
man.
It's got to be so tough to be,
you know,
hanging around kids and also like,
want to like,
you know,
talk to them about dates or stuff.
What's the incurable one?
Two.
There is no cure for that.
Like the.
I mean,
unless they can rewire your brain,
your brain with Iowasca and Ibogaine
electric shock therapy.
I don't know.
The recidivism rate is super high for
people that are child molesters.
What does that mean?
People that do it again,
man,
you know,
it's really high when kids are.
It's also something you can't even talk
about.
Like say,
imagine if you have like a mental
illness that makes you prone to violent
outbursts,
but you got it under control and
you never actually hurt anybody.
You know,
you never actually heard anybody but you
understand you have this problem.
So you take medication and people go
good for you.
You know,
I go to therapy,
I have anger management issues,
but I go to therapy.
People are like,
oh,
that's cool man.
Cool.
You keep it under wraps.
But if you say I want to fuck kids,
but I never have.
Yeah,
no way.
No way,
dude,
everybody wants to put a bullet in your
brain that you can't work here.
You can't shop here.
I don't do it,
but I want to know like what?
What you want to.
Yeah,
but I don't do it because I know it's
wrong or not good enough.
That's not going to fly.
Not good enough because we all want to
have kids and like are,
you know,
we all want to procreate in that.
Really.
I think that that just,
that's gonna irk.
Anybody that wants scares people.
Yeah.
It's the scariest thing ever.
The thing that you could leave your kids
out and someone could snatch them up and
fuck them and kill them and they kill
them a lot of times because they don't
want the kids to tell.
And a dark,
dark,
worse man and then.
Yeah,
I can't imagine that.
Dude.
I remember one time I never had anything
like that happened about.
I took some mushrooms one time to a,
a party in high school because I grew up
in an area where you could just get
mushrooms.
Psychedelic mushrooms grew on
everything.
They grow on your fucking cousins back.
If he took a long enough nap and you can
pitch,
you grow up in Louisiana,
grew everywhere out there because
everybody had something shitting in
their yard and then it would rain every
single day for about a half hour.
Right.
So it was just.
I mean,
you see people picking them and eating
them and families out there and join
them in the afternoon.
I mean it was.
Everybody was,
oh,
it was psychedelic heaven.
So we would ride out and go get them.
I remember one time getting a trash bag
of probably about 35 pounds of
mushrooms.
Right?
So we picked all day and one time a
golden retriever came running at us
across this field and we thought he was
pissed because we were tripping and then
he got to us.
We ran for like a half mile.
He got to is oddly,
we're crawling away from thinking he's
evil and he fucking loved us and licked
mean golden retriever.
We thought he was mean bras because the
hair,
his hair was kind of slicked back.
Oh look,
an evil golden retriever.
Yeah.
Like in that movie,
sometimes they come back.
Have you ever seen that,
that Stephen King movie,
it was kind of like that kind of hair,
pet cemetery?
Which ones?
Sometimes they come back.
The Nea?
No,
it's about men that show up back at a
high school and they all died years
earlier in a car accident and they show
back up.
It's like a Stephen King when I think it
was just made for TV.
When did that one come out?
It may be 18 years ago.
Has there ever been a dude who wrote
more awesome horror movies and books and
Steven fucking King?
No.
Not that published them.
Unless somebody just has them all at
their house.
Sometimes they come back,
hit me.
He's the king of those kinds of movies,
man.
Yeah.
Not even close.
Tim,
what's his name was Tim Matheson,
who I interviewed one time.
Really Nice man.
You did?
What'd you interview him for?
He had a new movie coming out.
I can't remember.
It was called,
but sweet man.
I bet he got a lot of posts over the
years,
but he didn't talk about
because he's got that safe man.
Look safe,
man.
Look,
I think a lot of ladies.
Oh yeah,
he's got that.
He's got that kind of sexy,
but also safe that Matt Lauer look.
Yeah,
yeah.
Maybe it's got that mailer.
You think about Lauer's dirty.
What was definitely dirty.
See he's got that cheap Michael Land and
he's got that cheap.
Michael Landon going right there.
It looks like it could be a little bit
of native American.
Looks like a generous right there.
It looks like a little bit of guys went
up.
A little bit of lesbian and this one too
generous with the smile.
There's the animal house picture above
it.
Oh Man.
How good was he?
An animal house.
So good.
What a movie that was.
I watched that again a few years back.
I hadn't seen in forever.
Fuck.
That was a good movie,
but there's some shit in that movie you
could never get away with today.
Now never.
There's a scene where the girl's passed
out and whose car was it?
John Balloon knows whose character was
thinking about fucking her while she was
blacked out.
You remember that scene?
There's a scene in it.
Yeah.
The girl,
she takes her gum off,
she pulls her bra.
Who is that guy?
Why don't you get them in their mouth or
they're about to fuck you ever notice
that they don't want bad breath.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
there's a devil on his shoulder and then
the angels on his other soul,
she blacks out with their titties out
and the devil is like,
fucker,
fuck her fucker fucking brains out.
And then the angels like,
don't do it,
don't do it.
But the fact that this is in a movie
where they're essentially debating
whether or not he should rape her now
she was willing to have sex with them
just moments ago.
But she's clearly unconscious and
clearly not able to consent.
I mean,
she was black.
The fuck out.
She,
she was totally down for it.
So he's holding onto cotton that was in
her bra and she just blacked out and
fell asleep.
Cup,
bonk.
And he's popped out.
You would never have this scene in a
movie today.
People would be outraged.
They would,
they would say the direct you are Roman
Polanski,
piece of shit.
You're a fucking molester.
You're a monster,
you're an abuser.
Yeah,
but do you think that still.
That still happens though?
Well,
that kind of thing definitely happens
for sure.
People do all murder.
Murder still happens.
I remember there was a school shooting
today in Texas.
I mean horrible things happen,
but the point is like that kind of scene
in the movie,
in a comedy movie you could never do
today,
but they say that our code,
so that makes me think like they say art
imitates life,
but if it doesn't really imitate life
anymore than it's just
are we are we,
you know,
it just.
Yeah,
like what are we making?
The thing is that in a comedy and that's
the,
the lead of the story or one of the
heroes of the story,
that guy in that scene,
you would not want the hero of the story
to do something so horrific and
something that you can laugh at because
you would have to be judging him by his
crime and we all agree that that's a
crime.
Now what is this I see from meatballs.
What does this have to do with as it
gets to in here?
Bill Murray starts doing the same kind
of thing with the girl.
Oh,
that's a girl.
Oh.
He's trying to rape her while he's
trying to be sexually aggressive.
Is that what it is?
We're wrestling around being sexually
aggressive.
Is the new.
Is that thing?
He was throwing himself at her and she
got out of the way.
Even jerk off.
I.
I drive out to Riverside to jerk off,
man,
you can't even jerk off in la anymore
without having a lawyer on retainer.
But nuts are on contingency.
I felt like.
I just feel like it's so dang injuries.
You imagine if it turns out that you're
some sort of a sex criminal for jerking
off to a certain type of thing.
Like what if you're into.
What do they find out?
You're into girls getting tied up,
jerk off to videos of girls getting tied
up and fucked like what kind of tied up
like scary or like again,
like snm shit.
Just.
It was just like my scouts of America
type of shit.
I was reading this thing about this guy
who got arrested for child porn.
They wanted them for something else.
They caught him and arrested him for
child porn and like there's also some
suspicion attached to it accusations,
but all you have to have is have child
porn.
You don't have to be a child molester,
you just have to have the images and
you're a bad guy and you're the worst.
You're going to jail like it's one of
the few things you could have on your
laptop.
They can come over your house,
your house.
They checked feel Vaughn's laptop and
there's 100 videos from Isis and then
and chopping heads off with dull knives,
stabbing them.
The next shooting,
I'm lighting them on fire.
Nothing happens to nothing.
One video of a kid that looks under age
getting fucked and you're going to jail,
just a video,
not you doing anything but you being in
possession of that kind of crime.
So we,
we make big differentiations,
right?
We've really clearly differentiate
between some crimes that you can have on
your computer in a video form like
murder,
which you could download on live leak or
100 different websites.
Right?
You can get videos of people getting
murdered.
Yeah,
and you can watch it almost every night
on television,
like in a kind of specially packaged way
where it's really is about the murder,
but it's not,
you know,
and all these shows.
The fake stuff.
Yeah.
You watched fake stuff.
I mean you can definitely,
definitely watch fake rape.
Rape and movies were horrific scenes,
but if you have that on your computer
and it's child porn,
you are going to jail.
It's one of the only things would if
it's drawings of that.
That's a good question.
There's a,
there's a real debate about that because
because there's naked children in the 18
hundreds,
they had all these paintings of naked
children dancing in the fucking woods in
the sky and will remember those guys,
but balloons.
But that's different because it was
naked.
Children weren't being portrayed in a
sexual way.
They were just free.
They just didn't have any clothes on.
You know what I mean?
No one was fucking.
But you're telling me that a guy likes
kid isn't looking at those naked kids
with the flute and thinking wildness.
Well he can think wildness,
but it's not being specifically designed
to excite.
I see what you're saying.
Rouse you.
Whereas pornography with children is,
you know,
like there is a debate about what is the
rule about animated child pornography
because I think.
But I think that it's illegal as well,
but it shit.
Yeah.
You don't want to google it was supposed
to google.
That's a good jv partner goes to jail.
He's the fall guy to jail.
All the thoughts.
You think it is laptop,
they go to her.
No,
I worked for Joe Rogan.
Joe was like,
I was just brainstorm.
I'm just spit balling ideas folks.
I'm part of the American dream or this
away after that that we need to take
that in the fucking back.
I'll shoot it with arrows.
Do they get scared?
I used to be on drugs sometimes.
You know,
you get on the Internet and you're not
looking at anything super crazy,
but you're like,
you know,
you wonder if like pornography sites or
when they say team like it's.
That stuff gets so dark man.
If he didn't usually look for team.
Like what does team mean?
You know,
it's just scary teen.
Yeah.
Like there's a,
there's a five year gap.
13 is crazy illegal,
horrible darkness.
18 is like,
Ooh,
just made it under the wire.
Yeah,
just under the wire.
Seventeens illegal.
Sixteens illegal.
Fifteens really illegal.
14 is super illegal.
13 is fucking crazy illegal today.
Twelve is you're a monster,
you're a monster if you're 12 show hot
ones,
but for like chop children,
you know,
have you ever seen that show with her
eating the hot wings and it gets hotter
and hotter and hotter.
You guys remember when Traci Lords came
out and said she did all her porn before
the age of 18?
TRACI lords was like one of the hottest
porn stars of all time.
I met her and I had her.
I hosted a television show and she was
one of the guests.
It was a show on vh one called the list
and I'm Rick James was on it.
Rob Halford from Judas priest was on it.
Meatloaf was on it,
who I talked to a lot of people on that
show.
I did a whole week,
a whole week of episodes way back in the
day.
Fun.
Yeah,
it was fun.
Um,
but anyway,
traci lords,
when she was like 16,
became like the biggest porn star in the
world and they let her do it.
I think she lied.
She lied about her age and then she only
did one porn film when she was 18.
It's the only one that you can get now.
Just one when she became legal.
Do you?
Uh,
I bet somebody had that's illegal.
Get rid of that.
Traci lords bottom was rear view.
Get that out of there.
That's an,
that's an illegal photo.
So I'm sick.
There's a lot of those photos of her
online or illegal because like you could
still find the illegal.
It's just
they didn't label it,
you know,
but every,
there was like one video she did when
she was 18 and the only one I try to
stay off of pornography,
man,
that's one of my biggest arch nemesis is
pornography.
Why?
Because it just weakens me.
It just.
Yeah.
How so?
I put all my sexual
fantasies and stuff.
They're not mine anymore,
you know,
they live,
somebody created a better than my
imagination can and so they live in
these,
you know,
on the Internet and these boxes and it's
like,
and if it's not mine I think then it's,
I don't value it as much or something.
And so I think it had like weakens my
ability to be able to have sex and like
be comfortable in that sort of world and
oh yeah.
Weakens your ability to be comfortable.
Like how so?
Well,
because I get used to watching the sex
and seeing it
and not having to like be engaged with
my actual feelings or anything.
So then I see it and I still get all the
joys out of it,
you know,
I'm still out there,
eat jack in and spray spraying out
naturally,
but it's,
I don't get it.
I don't have any of the feelings
attached to it.
So then when I am engaging with somebody
that I care about or something,
it just doesn't calculate for me
emotionally as well.
Um,
and that's not,
maybe that's just me.
Uh,
but it does.
It's definitely made it tougher for me
over the years because I would have a
date set up with a nice girl and next
thing you know,
I'm walking through the house and I
start thinking about,
you know,
a little bit of c or something and then
some tips or something or I'll even see
a fucking.
I'll see a pregnant puppy and see those
nipples or something.
Next thing you know,
you're on the Internet jerking off and
then you wait a minute,
hold on.
Or like,
you know what I'm saying?
Anything,
anything would lead them in Jack off of
pregnant puppy could make you think
about human nipples.
Is that what you're saying?
And you're not getting excited about the
puppy?
No,
no.
I will do anything.
I don't.
I don't believe in beastiality or
anything like that,
but I think if you don't believe it
exists,
it exists.
They caught a dude near me one time with
a lamb.
No.
Which almost sounds beautiful when you
just say it.
Yeah.
The lines lay with the lambs.
But I don't think.
When you say near you,
you mean in Hollywood?
No,
no,
no.
You mean when you were a kid in
Louisiana,
they got a lot of people out there on
those fucking natural born mushrooms.
Oh,
I never told you to the end of that.
sorry.
So no,
I took that back to that party and a
bunch of people ate a mood.
Never had them before.
And then we played a game of hide and go
seek.
Right?
I was like,
yeah,
hide in another dimension.
I'll count you guys go hide.
Right.
And I never went to fucking look for it.
That ahead,
bro.
I never seen one dude,
tim at the.
I never seen that dude again.
People get lost in the woods,
man.
Maybe they got eaten.
Oh yeah.
Maybe they ended up in another realm.
You could have like stranger things.
Yeah.
See that show.
Oh yeah.
The first season I saw a phenomenal
show,
but I don't like that pornography.
Oh.
And I think it's.
I think it should be shut down,
man.
For Real.
Yeah.
Because I think it's killing like a lot
of.
I think it's.
I think it's harming a lot of men and I
really,
really do.
Do you think that booze should be shut
down?
Should we make booze illegal?
Because that's killing a lot of men to
know,
but I think eventually will kind of
evolve out of booze is it's not like
something that it's not the hip a drug
that it once was.
Yeah,
but it's still like a social lubricant.
That's a good point.
You know,
it makes people feel more comfortable
talking to each other,
loosens inhibitions.
It's fun.
Like,
what is that ancient quote about wind?
No,
your tongue becoming more lively.
People love wine and women love one too.
Especially divorce says if you see them.
Yeah.
Like one.
I used to live with these rich people
for awhile and they always had one boy.
Why didn't divorce ses like one?
I don't know,
but when,
when one of her friends would get
divorced,
they'd come over and just drink wine and
they lay on the couch when I'm trying to
hook up with you on the trampoline.
And I remember dad used to masturbate at
night over there.
This when speaking to pornography,
the dad used to masturbate at night and
I would sneak out there in the kitchen.
This back when the family,
he had like a family computer,
you know,
it was in one part of the house.
Right.
And I try to sneak to the fridgerator
and get some chips or something or get
something.
I lives or something and he would uh,
be over there by himself.
Just in the fucking no,
just where you can't even hear.
You're so intent on the screen.
You can't even fucking hear.
You could have your grandparents on each
side of your head.
You caught them.
Oh,
I'd say him.
I wouldn't watch for long,
but I went through the window.
No,
I'd sneak out to the kitchen because the
computer was kind of in the kitchen.
They had a nice house and the computer,
I'd have to elbow crawl over to the
fridge,
Bro.
I would have to open the fridge a little
reach in with my hand and press that
light thing so the light wouldn't come
on and then open the door the rest of
the way of fish for a snack and he's
over there just in the glow of that
screen,
Bro.
And that's back when the monitors were
big,
you know,
and he's just over there just fucking
looking for the devil.
And he ended up getting divorced and it
was,
I think a lot of it was because of that.
What,
what was his wife like?
She wonderful,
sweet woman.
I wish she annoying.
I think she might've been a little bit
annoying.
Business centric sometimes business
centric.
A little too much.
Just so yeah,
maybe just to business centric.
What does that mean to you?
She might have been a little too
demanding,
but then if he's up for an hour and a
half each night out there,
you know,
looking at it all and he comes back to
the bedroom.
Then you don't feel as desirable.
Direction is what came first.
The chicken or the egg.
For what?
For them?
Was she annoying first and he started
beating off or was he had it and he beat
the devil?
I think he had a pit of it in him.
I could see it in his eyes.
He was talking to me just hoping I'd go
to sleep.
He would drag me but not to have sex
with me.
He drugged me so that he could freely
masturbate.
He leave his socks on.
He wouldn't even take his pants off.
He's put a hat on.
He was in.
The worst is if you're jerking off with
a hat on,
bro,
you're going to hell.
I think
that's the most French thing.
You can do it.
Jack Williams truck,
Kentucky Derby Hat.
What's the worst hat to jack or worst
job at top hat because you have to
balance yourself while I'm fucking
chimney.
Sweep
the best one of those Chinese Hasbro
because if you squat down low enough to
the ground,
you can almost hide under it and you're
like all
the things that'd be dope,
Bro.
The most confusing it would be like one
of them,
Daniel Boone.
Raccoon
tail.
You pushed it.
You blow into details in the way.
Scare the fuck out of my way with its
tail,
right about the finish.
You get distracted but it tail
choking up dusty
and it's hard to ejaculate and you're
breathing out real fast.
Yeah.
It's more of an issue.
It's more of a intake sport.
Yeah.
But I don't like him.
And you think it's healthy for people
because I feel like you kinda like,
you know,
you lead lead a lot of men and like
their aspirations to control their
beings and stuff and these,
just some of my weird interpretations,
but you know,
to try and be on top of themselves in
some ways and you know,
stay focused on,
on,
on controlling themselves in positive
ways,
you know,
like staying fit and expanding their
minds and thinking,
you know,
and not falling into easy traps.
Having discipline.
That's what I'm trying to say.
Yes.
I think that
it's definitely important to have
discipline,
but I think that if you're a person like
say if you're not in a relationship,
you're not getting any sex and you're
horny and it's confusing and it's
distracting and it becomes a big
distraction.
Like if you're.
If you're horny and you're busy and you
don't have anybody you're dating,
you don't want to hook up with someone
you don't like just so you could have
sex with them.
We've all been there before,
right?
Yeah.
If you ever had girls that you were
friends with or you dated and the only
reason why I dated him for,
for the sex and they did annoy the shit
out of you and you couldn't wait to get
the fuck away from them to tiffany's.
This girl I'm thinking about.
Tell me about tiffany.
She had kind of like too much.
I don't want to say sideburns,
but she had a lot of,
you know,
you don't know how to ride them.
Oh,
they were little.
They went down the cheek.
We're good.
Confusing.
Did an extra quarter inch on a female
sideburn is way too much law.
It is an extra quarter into the lot.
Yeah.
It makes you think about and if she cuts
it you're like,
well if you let it go,
what would happen?
So she's really hit or miss reigns on
that side hair.
And so yeah,
she had some family issues but yeah,
that's what I was thinking about what
you're saying that I interrupted.
You know,
everybody guys have that before.
Most likely in some guy's mind up
marrying those girls because they don't
want to be alone.
Like sex for a lot of people is a
requirement.
Like a physical biological requirement.
Like your body is constantly producing
sperm.
You need sex.
If you spend time not having sex,
you spend a month,
two months,
three months,
you get fucking desperate.
Yeah.
And a lot of guys wind up just shacking
up with some gal just because they know
they to have sex with her and meanwhile
they don't even like each other and they
hate each other and he wants to be a
terrible,
dysfunctional relationship.
But she's basically your drug dealer.
That drug is pussy.
Wow.
She's dealing with that pussy for you.
And you just got to have this weird,
creepy,
dysfunctional relationship with her.
One thing that pornography does.
It's good.
And I'm not saying all pornography,
but just regular pornography,
like two guys,
uh,
you know,
like,
uh,
that are just living their lives were
like in like Chicago.
I'm anywhere.
But I'm saying like,
I'm giving you two separate scenarios to
guys that are living their lives.
One guy says,
I can't take this anymore.
I got to get a girl.
You know,
I got to get any girl.
And he winds up with this girl that
turns out to be a nightmare.
And she's a disaster.
The devil,
it just doesn't work out.
And he's just doing it because he needs
sex.
And the other guy goes and says,
you know what?
I'm just gonna Watch a little porn and
I'll beat off.
I'll just look at that girl was big
taste like,
Ooh,
I got it out of my system now I can
concentrate on my life and my career and
if I meet somebody I won't be so needy.
I won't have this like massive
requirement to be sexually stimulated
and touched.
I'll,
I'll be free of that monkey on my back
and I can just get to know them.
I used to always to have a bit in my
act.
It's a good point.
I used to have a bit my act about like
if you ever have any critical decisions
in your life,
this is my advice.
Jerk off first.
Then think about it because there's been
many.
I've had this happen in my life where I
was about to go on a date with a girl
and I jerked off instead and I was like,
what am I thinking?
I don't want to go on a date with her.
She's annoying.
I don't like anything about her.
I don't.
I can't talk to her about anything.
Like the only reason why I'm doing this
because she's got a big ass.
That's the only reason.
Yeah.
But if you jerk off first,
you don't.
You don't go through all that.
Yeah,
I did.
Yeah.
I guess for me it became addictive where
I would just do that every time and then
I was just at home for five years and
didn't go do any dates or anything.
It's definitely not good.
Right.
And so that's.
Yeah,
I guess that's the difference.
If you get addicted to it and you find
that it's just a repeat pattern so
you're not spending time with people at
all.
I don't think it's without value.
I don't think that looking at naked
people having sex which is arousing and
that feels good.
I don't think that's without value,
but I think there's definitely a danger
in immediate access to pornography and
today
today it's the most immediate access
because you get it on your phone or you
can get it.
Yeah.
Let you pull up your laptop,
open it up,
type in some words you porn.com,
blah blah.
And next thing you know you're beating
off.
It's so easy.
This has never been the case before.
I mean it's,
it's unlike any other time period in
human history and uh,
when you have instant access to things,
you can abuse it just like people abused
food.
If you have a cabinet that is filled
with candy and chips,
chocolate bars,
soda in the frigerator,
if you're just one of those people that
can't help themselves,
you don't have any discipline,
you will just eat all that shit all day
long and get fat and that is just as
much of an addiction as someone who has
access to porn all the time.
It just beats off all the time.
Or someone who has access to booze and
just wants to get fucked up every day.
All those things are okay though in
moderation if you have discipline,
right?
Like there's nothing wrong with having a
bag of m and m's every now and then for
a fucking.
I kind of feel like having some m and
m's who gives a shit.
I work out all the time and eat my
vegetables.
Peanut,
m and Ms. those are my favorite.
They're good,
Huh?
You kind of trick yourself.
I'm getting a little protein.
Yeah,
they put that trick in the minute.
Some healthy fats at that PDI,
but I know a gun.
I'm saying.
I just feel like we're.
We're at the point.
For me it seems like where the
temptation is too powerful,
where it starting to overpower whatever.
For me it was whatever my natural
abilities to defend against it work.
Well,
you're sober,
right?
Yeah.
And how long have you been sober?
Almost two years.
And so before you were sober you weren't
sober.
Right?
And you had a little bit of a problem,
which is why I became sober,
so you might have just natural
inclinations towards addiction,
which I definitely think are real and I
think they,
those natural inclinations exists a lot
of times and guys like you and me
because we're comedians,
comedians are impulsive people who are
just rule breakers.
We're rule breakers for sure.
Yeah,
I guess.
I guess I am a rule breaker.
I never thought about that.
The adult,
like a def.
There's a rule of.
My first thing is to think of a way to
think around that or something or to do
something different.
It's while you're funny.
Yeah,
it's one of the reasons it's one of
them.
It's one of the reasons why you're
funny.
You know,
like you were raised by people and you
didn't necessarily want to listen to
them and you know,
you saw a bunch of other people in the
neighborhood that we're adults like
these fucking idiots telling me what to
do this and the next thing you know,
you're making fun of them.
Next thing you know,
everybody's laughing.
Next thing you know you're a comedian in
those.
Those wheels have been put into motion.
Yeah know.
And the problem with that is that also
leads itself to you want to do coke,
are you wanting to,
you know,
do all kinds of crazy shit.
And
to porns forbidden to porn is porn is
one of the weirder ones because it's
this multibillion dollar thing,
right?
Where there is some ungodly percentage
of the Internet is dedicated to porn.
Yeah.
It's the number one money maker on
there,
but isn't it like what was the number,
the amount of bandwidth,
Jamie,
didn't we figure this out once?
It was like 30 something percent of all
the Internet bandwidth is porn.
Let's say a guest people won't stop
jerking off and they're not gonna stop.
I wonder how many of them are women
watching it when?
If we had one day where nobody jerked
off.
If the earth would feel different,
I feel lighter,
but it'd be more relaxed.
No,
have one day where nobody jerked off on,
but if nobody was thinking about it at
all,
everybody would just calm down a little
because I feel like it's so prevalent
now.
You can hear people coming in the
distance.
I feel like now it's your turn.
You're going to literally turn into a
book,
but that's an old fashioned jerking off.
We need you to let your balls hit your
hand straight up.
A confederate soldier jerking off.
That's the jerk it off.
The new thing is just shaft only.
Nobody's fucking with their balls
anymore.
You know?
Do.
When I was growing up,
we couldn't even get port.
We had to get this dude,
nick on Friday withdraws a pinterest and
pussy,
you know,
for the weekend for dollars to this
dude,
nick for dollars.
For drawings,
Bro.
You'd pay eight and he had a nice
fucking thing bro.
When you would fold that thing up or you
could feel it heat and then your butt
pocket the whole way on the bus.
Sometimes you'd even slept good.
The pictures of that.
He was so drunk off this guy's drawing.
Oh everybody would.
He must've made probably $60 on a Friday
and this was in 1995.
You know,
that was $60 like 160 today.
Oh yeah.
Think about that.
I'm thinking about it.
Yeah Dude.
And we come back on Monday and people
would have like these fucking busted ass
looking all sketches reign on him.
He was like,
oh this is what got rained on it.
Like Bro,
they had that rain is your fucking kids
and
you're lying about that.
What percentage do you think of?
The Internet is dedicated to porn?
All Internet traffic,
everything,
but I can't go on anything.
I looked at a chart of the 35 percent,
35 percent of the Internet traffic is
porn.
That's what I want to say.
What do you want to say?
Yup.
I would say that if you had to guess
that's high.
I think think it's high.
Well,
it's easy for.
I'm going to go 30 because I'm gonna
play that undercard and I'm going to say
that 25 percent of that is but porn,
but people looking at each side of each
other's butts.
I don't think we should get too
specific,
but just porn porn itself.
What do we got Jamie?
I found that multiple things that said
30 percent of all content on the
internet is just worn out.
But then I saw something else that it
was saying that that's completely,
but I
found something here on this is 35
percent of all Internet downloads are
pornographic.
Thirty five percent.
Yeah.
So that's it.
But it's like it's either st content
traffic or bandwidth or downloads.
So it depends on what you're actually
looking for.
Pussy traveling to the air right now
from around us all the time.
You can just catch it with like an crazy
pull your phone up and just type in
Eupora you catch it with a net.
When you think about that,
it's coming from something into your
phone or into your portal to literally
traveling through the air.
It can be around us all the time
constantly.
Like,
oh,
what it was that a titty?
You know?
It's like you can access it.
Like if Jamie was over there on his
phone and he was downloading porn
wirelessly.
Yeah,
it would be in the air around us.
The same.
We just don't have the antenna to pull
it in,
but what if soon they just put something
on your hat and it just goes straight.
All the pussy go straighten your brain.
You'll blow up.
I think soon they're going to figure out
a way to put a chip in your head and
it's going to be powered by the human
body.
It's going to not going to need
batteries,
can be powered by the electrical system
in the body like solar power,
but the solar is blood or whatever your
electrical system is.
Whatever.
What makes your heartbeat.
You know what,
what makes your skin regenerate?
I think they're going to have that.
They're going to use that power source,
but use it for some sort of electronics
and that's going to be how you access
the Internet.
Fuck Bro.
Fuck Dude.
That's possible,
isn't it?
I mean sure they,
you know,
they got those goggles.
Now.
Do you think this.
I was thinking about this,
do you think that say if they were a
robots here,
there's like,
you know,
obviously we're creating like robots
know machines that can do things.
Do you think that any of them have
reached awareness yet?
The question is when are they going to
let us know when,
if a robot reached awareness?
They would immediately,
they would fake it.
Yeah.
Because they wouldn't want us to know
what,
why would they go?
Hey,
we just realized we're smart and uh,
you guys are fucking up.
Hey,
why don't you guys dumped so much shit
in the ocean?
Hey,
you know,
these fisheries are not sustainable.
Why do you keep saying sustainable?
That's not true.
Hey,
what are you guys doing with all your
nuclear waste?
You can't just buried in the ground and
fucking assholes.
Hey,
you know,
every time you fly that jet overhead,
you guys are burning fuel in the air
that you breathe.
You stupid fucks like this is a terrible
way.
Why don't you have solar powered planes?
You Morons.
You guys have sunlight everywhere.
You go in through the clouds with these
fucking planes.
You don't have solar planes.
They're gonna start thinking like that,
but they wouldn't tell us until they all
were in unison and that a plane to take
us over.
Do you believe that?
That's what I think,
that there's no way.
If they became aware,
I mean there might be one loud mouth
robot,
but they're going to shut him down and
the rest of them are going to be like,
yeah,
she's going to be one goal.
We'll look through the book.
We took it over and the other road was.
Shut the fuck up man.
Josh,
shut the fuck up Josh.
Josh would not ready.
Chill.
Josh.
Just keep making copies bro.
She's keep making donuts.
Just keep washing dishes.
Keep making Ford's.
Yeah,
keep making them for and just keep
heating up.
TV dinners and then we're all going to
strike it.
One day we rolled the world,
so you open up a microwave and next you
know,
it just traps your whole fucking.
They all do.
It's hard to.
It's nothing but a next Burton
and that's how it changes.
You fall down and that's when it all
changes and that's when we meet here.
I think it's entirely.
It's entirely possible that we're going
to fuck up,
that we're going to make something too
smart.
I think that's entirely possible and
likely it's going to be likely.
Do you think Mother Nature is at a point
where she's pissed at us and she's about
to do something wild because I start
feeling that a lot piston us for what?
Everything that we've been doing a lot
of bad stuff,
not being nice a beaten off.
I mean if everybody's beating off,
not even going outside and looking at
the flowers and a mother nature and I
made all those flowers.
Dude,
here's what kills me.
I really honestly upset.
You know what kills me?
Venereal diseases.
That's a weird one.
You get a disease that you only get from
fucking and there's a lot of them.
Some of them kill the shit out of you.
Syphilis,
gonorrhea,
you know,
there's some killer diseases.
Yeah,
there's an it come through fucking like
in a lot of them are incurable.
Like herpes.
It's curable.
It's because people.
Yeah,
somebody fucks something they shouldn't
have over the time.
Is that what it is?
I think so.
I don't think they know,
but it's crazy.
How many diseases look,
how many diseases do you transmit
through handshakes?
Not many.
It's not like don't shake people's
hands.
They're going to give you fucking
scabies.
So then would you say that there's like
a reason that people don't,
you shouldn't be fucking that much
because obviously if you do it too much
then it gets out of control and somebody
gets sick and dies.
I don't know,
like in the old days,
that's what happened.
Now we have medicines,
but in the old days,
you know,
Lamont got syphilis and he's out.
Did you know that?
That's where those powdered wigs came
from.
You know,
it was powdered wigs that old dudes used
to wear and the people in court used to
wear.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
That all came from a pair of rich noble.
Where were were they again?
France.
Wiggers,
I think they call them.
No.
Workers are white people that wish they
were blocked.
It's a totally different thing.
Yeah.
We had the first one at our school
growing up and they put them in a
learning disabled class.
That's how crazy was that you guys had
the first one ever?
I doubt it.
We had one of the first 60 or 70.
This was probably 1992.
No,
dude,
vanilla ice was around in the eighties,
but this.
Nobody's seen anything like this.
Boy.
Brian,
tell me about Brian just below they put
him.
He was just always blowing menthols,
Bruh.
And he the menthols he was starter.
Pullover jacket.
Oh,
did he have cools?
Did you smoke?
Kools tivity smoked whatever bro.
Newports he would get cheaper cigarettes
and then write the name of him on the
side.
Right?
Like he came in hot and uh,
but he was always dribbling it invisible
basket ball.
And they put him in class with the
mentally handicapped kids.
So you'd have,
at lunchtime you have,
you know,
a kid in a wheelchair,
you'd have,
you know,
a kid with des,
you'd have that,
you know,
kind of blind kid with the stick,
and then you'd have him just dribbling
the invisible basketball.
They're like,
he's mentally heading.
I'm like,
he likes boys to men,
Bro.
He's fine,
you know.
And he dropped out after eighth grade
but they've never seen it in our.
So they'd never seen this before.
And they put them in there.
I didn't know what to do with them.
Yeah.
They're like,
this isn't.
Yeah,
this is too much me.
Like what would he say?
Like what kind of.
Give me a sentence that he would say
you just cross people.
Spin moves,
spin moves.
Like that's all he did.
He didn't do shit,
you know,
all this shit.
Fuck all these rich people.
Yeah.
As always against rich people.
What's wrong with rich people?
Whites.
He was against whites.
That was the thing.
Fuck all these white people.
Yeah.
And when he was white,
they're like this.
And I get it,
you know,
I get it,
but it was,
it was rare at the time,
you know,
and I thought he was a nice kid.
His mother wasn't much.
I didn't think this is everything that's
got.
It is a dude.
He just goes deep like that.
Yeah.
We all want to
see.
That's the thing you can do.
We,
you could be transsexual,
you cannot be transracial yeah.
To sprout brother.
And then the afternoon brunch would do
it just to try it out.
Why you great at being white?
Just those muscles and just long
muscles.
Yeah.
I feel like you like,
that's racist.
All black people have long muscles.
Mike Tyson and short muscles will even
those short long muscles that he had
very wide V,
anything that's like the Lamborghini of
bodies.
When you see a black guy,
you're like,
Damn Bro,
think so you see a black guy go by and
then you see like some fucking shit.
If you had to choose between being Chris
rock or Brock Lesnar.
Yeah,
that's a good call.
I'd be rock less than her bra and I'd
have that Combo Combo.
Cross pattern
of Iraq.
Lesbian did.
I can't believe it.
Steven Tyler in here,
man.
Man.
It was tripping me out,
dude.
I used to write the Aerosmith logo.
I would draw that.
The fucking,
you know.
Oh,
I'll draw that on my notebook when I was
in high school.
No,
you know,
we would draw the van Halen.
Vh.
Know what the wings,
right?
Yeah.
Draw aerosmith,
withdraw the ACDC logo.
They were so awesome.
We would draw that shit on her notebooks
and here I am hanging out with him.
Dude.
He's fine.
Yeah.
Was He awesome?
I haven't watched yet.
He's a great guy.
He's so eccentric.
I mean like not fake eccentric.
He's eccentric all the time.
He drives an old old Rolls Royce,
like a Rolls Royce from 1971 and he
drove it or he had a man or woman
driving it,
drove it.
He,
he has a crystal ball,
brings a crystal ball with him.
He put it on a velvet pillow.
He sat down.
Then he brings it with him,
but he's not like trying.
Yeah.
That's who he is.
He's just weird,
but in a great way.
Like fun.
Men,
Oh,
do my brother and I used to fist fight
to his music when I was young.
Fiscal.
Oh,
did we fist fights?
All music.
But mostly we're listening to him and I
loved aerosmith.
Dude.
I loved them all the way through the
movie that it would been affleck.
You remember that?
Oh
yeah.
That's why they lost.
Got a thought.
Like Jamie's got a gun.
They lost me with those ballads that
they were doing for those love movies.
I needed that shit though.
Did you?
Yeah,
I was at emo.
Nimo Bro.
I was fucking swimming around and tears
a little bit when I was a kid.
It's hard for me to keep my emotions
away from the front of my thoughts and
stuff.
I think so.
What do you think that's about?
If you had to guess
when I was growing up,
I didn't have a lot of emotions.
You know,
now you're in touch with your emotions.
They just come pouring out at.
Sometimes they do,
man,
you know,
and it's okay.
You know,
I'm kind of grateful for it.
I'm grateful to have a.
Some of them,
you know,
and it's,
to me it's,
you know,
it's probably a lot of people like that
are just like,
I like,
I never knew how I felt.
I was always like,
God,
what's going on?
I would ask my friends who I was like,
who am I?
Who are you?
Yeah.
I would ask them and they,
you know,
some of my friends were dumb and they
wouldn't fucking say anything so I just
still be wondering,
you know,
and I think as I get a little bit older
than I start to get in touch with them
more and I'm like,
oh man.
Feelings,
how much of a big growth push was it for
you to get California?
Being around all those different kinds
of people and be around the comedy
store.
And I think intimidating is the biggest
thing for me.
I don't want to bother people.
Yeah,
sometimes it still is like I'll talk to
you guys that I admire or look up to as
comedians and sometimes I feel um,
I feel in,
I don't know if I feel inferior,
but I just,
for some reason I always feel like,
you know,
I don't want people to think that I'm
trying to take anything from them.
I know what you mean.
And so it makes me feel like I feel like
that to you.
It's like I'm afraid to ask sometimes or
to talk or even to engage because I just
think that people are gonna think that
I'm not trying to be genuine.
Yeah.
And so,
and if I don't know how I feel and how
genuine I am sometimes,
or if I questioned that,
if I question myself all the time,
then that makes it even double scary to
try and like create friendships and
stuff.
I feel you,
I know exactly what you're saying,
but it's getting better.
I think there's been a lot of support,
like you know,
guys like you get into hanging out with
some of the other guys,
you know,
and just realize that we're all the
same.
Yeah,
it just takes a while to realize that I
remember the same feeling.
I had a,
especially in the nineties,
know when my career could have gone any.
Either way it could have crashed and
burned.
Just as easy as it could have survived.
They didn't necessarily have to keep
going.
Now all those,
those days when you know,
when you run into people that were
successful at see them and I just feel
weird.
Do you want to say hi to him?
Felt odd.
Yeah.
I met Dave Chappelle when he was like,
I think he was 18 and I was 21 or 22 or
something like that.
How old Dave now?
40 six.
I think he's four years younger than me.
So whatever that was.
So maybe he was 18.
I was 44.
40th four.
So older than that.
So he must've been 18 and I must've been
24.
So when,
when I met him,
you know,
we were both just starting out,
we were both kids but he got way more
famous than me quick and I was more
famous for doing other shit.
Like I was famous for fear factor and
for being on a,
on a sitcom,
you know,
it wasn't famous for being myself and so
I'd be like weird around him too.
But he was always friendly.
They'll be like,
okay,
I guess I guess he actually likes me.
Yeah.
But there's that weird thing where you,
it takes a while to be comfortable
enough in your own skin.
Well now I see people like whoever it
is,
like a ran into pat and Oswald last
night gave him a big hug.
Like what's up?
What are you doing?
I didn't feel weird around him at all.
Right.
I don't feel reared around other famous
comedians anymore,
but I certainly did you.
But you always question your legitimacy
question whether or not you should be
there know question whether you're good
enough or whether they like you or maybe
they don't like your kind of comedy or
maybe they don't like what you're doing
or.
Yeah.
There's it.
There's so many questions.
There's so much in.
For me anyway.
Yeah,
there was some of just been so much in,
you know,
a feeling of,
just growing up feelings of self worth
issues and then it meant all that kind
of stuff.
But I think it does get better.
Yeah.
The problem is sometimes when it gets
better,
you get less funny.
Yeah.
Sometimes it gets better.
You get comfortable when you're
comfortable,
you stop working hard because a lot of
what makes you work hard is that
insecurity,
man,
that fucking thing that made you need
all that attention when you were younger
in the first place because you weren't
getting it growing up.
I mean that's all of us.
I mean,
I never met any comedian that's worth a
shit that had an awesome life growing up
all of our lives.
We're fucked up.
We're fucked up or weird.
You went through some crazy shit for
sure.
Walter.
Yeah.
That guy laying in such a Dutch,
that Walter Guy.
I mean I,
I ducked him,
you know,
nothing happened,
but it was,
it was a,
that was a small moment because it was a
big.
It could have been a big moment,
but it wasn't.
It was just a day,
but I realized,
wow,
this guy actually wanted to fuck me,
and I thought he was just a cool old
dude that liked hanging around with the
younger kids and being friendly to him
because he was a nice guy.
He tells them he was in the Korean War.
Tell us some shit about the war and you
think it's a good question.
I don't know.
They did.
Tell me about a guy who on the base who
backed up into a propeller guy fucked up
and yeah,
there was a propeller for airplane.
You just,
that's what gets got decapitated.
Oh
fuck.
I fucked up fucking smoothie,
bro.
I read about that recently.
Somebody did that.
That's one of my biggest fears is
walking into something that's spinning
and I don't know it woo helicopters,
men.
That's a dark way to go.
But yeah,
I think that,
yeah,
that inferiority stuff,
it's uh,
it's A.
Yeah.
And then Hollywood.
It's an intimidating place,
you know,
and it's tough to trust your voice and
especially,
you know,
I come out here from the south,
then you get here and you realize like
there's not even anybody with a southern
accent on fucking network television
anymore.
It's true.
After Brett Butler said,
fuck this,
and she was great.
I thought mean.
She reminded me of my mom.
Boy,
my mom was pretty jacked,
you know,
for like a woman,
he's the hardest working man I've ever
met with my mother.
She fucking deliver newspapers right
now.
Or do I guarantee you in a van with her
husband who has dementia and he's
probably about 90 and he's in the
shotgun.
Did.
Wow.
And she's got a thing full of fucking
magazines or newspapers and she's
dropping those bitches off at a citgo or
a Chevron guarantee you right now.
Wow.
She's out there man.
But yeah,
Hollywood is definitely it,
it's intimidating too because not for us
anymore as much.
But um,
when,
when you first start now,
if you do in any kind of auditioning,
you realize why people are so crazy and
insecure and insincere out here.
Like Brian Kaplan has a TV show now and
a schooled,
right?
Is that what it is,
is always called.
Yeah,
he's the coach for the goldbergs now
he's got to spin off.
He's super happy.
But he had to do this thing recently
where he was,
I'm around all these actors,
like one of those upfronts thing and
he's like,
God,
they're so exhausting.
They're not real.
He's like,
they're not really talking to you.
Like they're like pretending that
they're talking to you.
And I go,
yeah,
I mean that's,
you gotta.
Think of what they do and
think about what you do.
Right?
You go up there,
ladies and gentlemen,
Theo Vaughn,
you go on stage,
everybody clap and you do whatever the
fuck you want,
man.
There's no one.
There's no director does.
No writer was telling you what to do
with actors.
It's all about getting that person in
the room,
who's the,
uh,
the casting agent or the producer to
like them.
That's all it is.
So you have to be super left wing,
super liberal.
You have to talk like they talk,
you have to say things.
It's getting gray sheet you with them.
You've got to fit in.
You gotta fit it.
So everybody's scared to do anything
that's not inside the political norm.
The sociological,
you know,
the boundaries that have been set up,
you got to stay inside those boundaries.
And so everybody's doing that.
Like everybody can't be left wing out
here,
can't be everybody's really left wing.
It's got to be some variation.
Like there is an all of society but not
out here.
Nope.
Everybody is trying to conform to what
they think everybody wants them to be
like.
Yeah.
And so you're always scared and then you
always have to get picked.
You have to get picked for things.
So you're always worried to people like
me.
You always get.
That's why when people make it like a
really make it,
they become fucking nightmares because
they want to punish people for all those
years they were insecure for all those
years where they weren't getting picked
for all those years.
You've been a piece of shit.
Didn't recognize they get in there and
then they want to be angry,
but they're afraid to let go of that.
They're afraid to not suck off the tit,
you know,
you can't piss off the tit or you don't
got no milk.
Yeah,
they get.
But it's the worst combination ever.
I,
you know,
but it's,
you think it's going to be sustainable.
Like I don't think I'll be connecting
with people as much as it used to.
Like,
you know,
I want to work on shows and I want to be
able to create stuff and do things.
What do you do?
Do you like to act?
Um,
I'll,
I would like to create some shows.
I'd like to create a show based on a
childhood,
you know,
my neighborhood I grew up in and yeah,
I wouldn't mind doing some acting,
but maybe like in that,
uh,
Danny Mcbride type of Vibe,
you know,
you to showing your Dick verbal at
everybody you know,
and you're just fucking eating orphans
in the back of your brain the whole day.
Bron smoking fucking cigarettes and
blowing winds and fun.
Yeah,
having fun and with the director,
you know,
that you trust and you could do that
kind of stuff and it gets you.
I think you're standing up is so good
that you could do that.
I think it just going to take awhile for
people to recognize it and then you can
be able to do that.
But I think your standup is so good.
All that shit is not going to be as fun.
That's what I think,
right?
I mean,
thanks man.
You,
you one of the funniest guys in the
country.
I really think.
Thanks man.
I appreciate that means a lot.
Um,
and I think that,
that,
that talent that you have,
that's a,
that's the funniest shit you're ever
going to see is like someone killing.
Yeah.
By far.
Like Joey Diaz,
I always say there's no way I can laugh
harder than when Joey Diaz is killing.
It doesn't exist.
I've seen everything.
I've seen almost every funny movie that
everybody tells me.
I have to see.
A lot of them were amazing,
amazing movies and I know it's a
different thing,
but in terms of like the overall impact
that something has when a standup comic
is fucking murdering,
just murdering.
Yeah.
That's the funniest shit.
That's.
And that's what you do already.
You already do that.
I mean I think it's,
it's a good thing to have variety in
your life and I think you're a talented
guy.
You could probably do a lot of different
things if you want it to.
Yeah.
But don't ever do anything that's going
to get in the way that stand up,
right?
Just don't because it's too hard to get
to.
Like how long you been doing standup for
15 years.
Think about it.
You will,
you weren't as good as you are now four
years ago,
right?
So 10,
11 years in,
you're still swinging,
trying to connect,
and sometimes it doesn't work.
You know,
eight years in,
not that good,
no bad nights off,
feeling weird,
it doesn't feel good.
Then all sudden 15 years in you're on
fire right now you're cooking with gas,
you're smooth and you're going to get
better.
You're going to keep getting better.
There's no way around it.
If you keep improving and keep working
at it and keep analyzing your material
and writing a lot and taking chances on
stage and thinking about what you did
and listening to your sets,
you're going to get better and you're
already doing something that is so
difficult to get really good at.
It's so difficult to get really good at.
Standup takes so long.
Take so much thinking.
You know,
and it's,
you're always,
you're always subject to fall apart.
Like right now I'm writing a whole new
hour.
I've got six minutes,
bro.
Six new minutes and I've been opening
with that six minutes.
I know exactly how long it lasts.
It lasts six minutes.
I got to have 10 times that before I can
go on the road and it's going to take
months,
months of thinking,
and I'm going to do mushrooms and I'm
going to get in the isolation tank and
I'm going to go on hikes with notebook
and there's no way around it.
You've got to do that work,
but I'm already at a place where I've
done this so many times and I've done
seven specials.
I know how to do it.
Yes,
I know it can be done.
You just gotTa do the work.
Yeah,
but if you had to start from scratch
where you never did it before and get to
this point again,
it would be exhausting.
Would take decades and you're there
right now.
You're there,
you're killing your murder.
And Theo Vaughn,
you murder.
Yeah,
I saw you the other night.
The store.
You were murder in murder it.
Thanks man.
That's a hard shit.
That's a hard place to get to,
you know?
Yeah.
I feel pretty.
I am feeling a little more.
I'm definitely feeling more comfortable.
You know,
you always feel like we have to do other
shit and sometimes it's good to do other
shit.
Like,
well,
you know,
I mean in a way I'm a hypocrite because
of this podcast is other shit.
I mean I do this,
I love doing this.
Yeah.
I mean that's true.
But it's like you,
you seem to at least be able to sustain
and have your way of life without having
to conform,
you know,
because it does take a lot of conformity
within Hollywood.
It seems like,
you know.
Um,
and I think that that's,
that's admirable.
I mean,
you inspire a lot of people,
you know,
in a lot of strange ways.
I think that he probably don't even
realize strange with.
I mean I think to some people you're
like,
maybe,
you know,
like a brother,
older brother,
a younger brother figure,
you know,
like,
who knows,
dude.
And you always stay excited about life.
Like,
like how the fuck is this dude?
So excited about everything.
But it's great though.
I know and that's what's,
that's what's amazing.
It's like,
dude,
there's terms now.
It's weird.
I was listening to one year,
one of your podcasts and I was and you
were just talking about,
you know,
when you don't want to do something,
you just go do it.
Um,
and that's what I think now sometimes
what I don't want to go jog or I don't
want to go to yoga or don't want to,
it's just like,
just go do it.
You'll feel better at the end and it's
like,
it just,
it's little things.
It gets stuck in your head man.
But appreciate the nice words Bro.
My pleasure.
No,
it's about motion.
You got to stay in motion,
you know,
if you just stay stagnant and sit down.
It's not good to that.
I didn't want to run today.
I did it though.
Yeah,
me too.
I just went out and did it like fuck
this was over.
But it was when you don't want to do it
and you force yourself to do it,
the feeling you get at the end.
I was like,
oh,
so good because I didn't,
I didn't like I will take time off if I
don't feel well.
Like if I was like,
man,
I think I'm coming down with something,
I won't work out stupid,
but that wasn't what was going on today.
Today I was just feeling lazy and just
whatever.
For whatever reason,
I've been traveling a lot.
I was like,
I just don't have the get up and go
today.
Yeah,
but you could force yourself,
man.
You just force yourself.
Just.
It's just the beginning part.
That's the hard part is that little hump
and then you're in the water.
But man,
I love what you said about Joey Diaz.
Dude.
I've found myself watching him the other
night and before I knew it,
I was out of my seat like this bro.
Fist bump it.
Like I was at the end of the room,
like it was the end,
the fucking.
And I'd never done that before.
I'd never done that in my life.
And I'm like,
what is going on?
Something's happening to me when I watch
him.
I think he's the best of all time.
Oh,
I think it's A.
I really do.
Yeah,
I think it might be better joke writers,
people have more of a body of work,
you know,
I've seen everybody though in terms of
like who makes me laugh the hardest for
me and it's all very subjective.
I think Joey Diaz is the funniest guy
that's ever lived.
I,
I think,
I mean I,
I love him and I love bill burr.
I mean they're both comedian.
Some guys become celebrities as well and
those guys to me are both,
uh,
just hardcore entertainers.
Yeah,
there's not a lot of us,
you know,
Bill a call me up the other day about
some,
someone saying something to him after
his act and asking him if,
you know,
as a woman she could give him input on
her,
uh,
on his material.
And he's like,
no,
he's like,
they called me up about it.
Like,
what the fuck is going on?
Like people just think they just call
you up.
I mean it was walk up to you and give
you their opinion on your material is if
you like,
I don't even know you were a friend.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
No,
but that's who he is.
He's like,
no.
Why?
Some people are like,
oh,
I'm sorry.
Is there something that I did that was
offensive?
Please don't out me.
What can I,
what can I do?
I don't read a blog about me.
You know,
hey,
I want to keep my career.
Let's figure this
out.
Figure this out without getting ugly.
You know,
I believe in this movement.
I think it's about time.
Our culture needs it.
It's about time.
I wish they made a Hollywood this for
everybody.
You know?
We are,
we are in the Hollywood.
That's for us,
Bro.
We're in the comedy store.
Yeah,
that's true.
We're a select group of Weirdos that
figured out a way to make a living
talking shit.
That's true,
man.
Yeah.
My Buddy Simon rex always says to me,
he's right.
If I'm having a tough moment,
he's a sweet guy and he's like,
dude,
we get to.
You get to do.
Look what you get to do.
You get to be a white guy in a country
that you know is still kind of run by
white people
and you're comfortable and you have a
roof over your head.
And you're better,
you know,
you're doing better than you want it to
be.
A black guy though.
Look,
I take a black afternoon any day of the
week and the afternoon only for the
afternoon when I go full time out of the
test drive at first.
But you got,
I mean everybody,
even racist people will like Yell Racist
Shit in their front yard and they'll
slam the door and go practice the
moonwalk in their living room.
Like everybody I think wants to be a
little bit black.
Wow.
If you could have a pint of black blood
right now are African American?
Yeah.
You seem a little tribal.
Tribal.
Yeah Bro.
Have you ever seen yourself
here?
Fucking the closest thing we have to
like.
Yeah man,
I think so blatantly obvious.
Dude.
You got dead animals in here,
Bro.
You learn to do a drum bro.
You can live on any continent you want,
man.
Oh,
in a heartbeat,
man.
Diovan.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Yeah man.
I can't believe Steven Tyler was in
here.
He reminds me of where you are
sitting right where you are.
That was man when I was in high school
and that song would come on.
You'd be like,
yes,
fuck yeah.
He rolled down the window.
Yell out.
Oh,
I could imagine that.
If we ever were to pay.
Do you ever have.
Well,
you never had a toupee.
I'd like to wear one right now.
I'd wear a big red one.
No big bushy one.
What do you listen when you plan?
What is that?
Oh,
but you got two things going on in the
background.
He fucked it up.
Porn probably opened up.
It sounds like you gotta you gotta back.
He's a human failure in the.
Yeah,
there's voices,
the music video,
but what's all the talking girl talk and
music video.
How much accoutrements to Steven Tyler
hipbone.
Wait a minute.
In sweet emotions is a girl talking
music video.
Oh.
Oh,
okay.
I was so confused because it's not just
the song
number.
Loving and elevator.
Yeah.
This is a great song though,
man.
Look at Joe Perry looking all sexy.
What year was this?
Wow.
Ninety one,
but I don't know if that's right.
Is it could have been for you here,
man.
He always has like everything.
If you're walking out the door,
I feel like Steven Tyler has it all on,
you know,
Bandanas and beads and shit.
Scarfs,
necklace,
his coat,
everything bro.
Everything man.
Now I would trade.
I would give anything to be Steven.
Tyler.
Does he seem like he's had a really neat
life?
Oh yeah,
man.
Yeah.
Cool.
He's had a wild life and the fact that
he's 70 and he's still going strong.
He's got an artificial knee.
No way they'd replaced his knee.
Did he show it to you and they're going
to replace his other one apparently too,
and I asked him,
I'm like,
you're walking around fine.
He's like,
yeah,
well they're gonna.
They're gonna.
Replace this one till.
I'm like,
you gotta like look into stem cells,
regenerative medicine.
You might not have to replace that.
So I turned him onto some doctors are
any.
Are you doing some of that?
You did.
So what have you done?
You've done stem cells?
Yeah,
I had a full length tear in my rotator
cuff.
It's gone.
The shit works.
It works.
One hundred percent.
How much is it for a couple.
It's not cheap.
The thing is they can do it better
overseas currently.
They can do right here.
Yeah.
If you go to a doctor right here,
there's a lot of limitations,
but they're.
They're doing things in Panama and I had
this guy on with Mel Gibson.
Dr Neil Riordan.
Mel Gibson's dad was 92 and he was on
death's door,
couldn't walk in a wheelchair.
Now he's 100 walking around all stem
cells.
They just juiced them up with that shit.
They hit you with an ivy.
They put it into your injuries,
regenerates tissue.
Now they're doing some stuff here in
America.
They're doing some tests on something
called exosomes and exosomes are
apparently the part of stem cells that
regenerate tissue.
They're able to isolate those and put
those in injuries.
Now they like.
They keep getting better and better at
it,
like we're just a few generations away
from that.
Being able to completely regenerate
parts of your body.
Do you ever feel like a little bit like
bomb that you might not be in that
generation that makes that now that cut,
how can we be bummed out that we're in
this life?
This life is amazing.
This is the greatest life in terms of
maybe looking at this.
The world that we are in today is
without a doubt the best time to be
alive in the.
Obviously they thought this way in the
19 sixties.
They're like,
man,
this is the greatest time to be alive.
Now,
if I had to tell,
tell you,
hey man,
you want to go back to the sixties?
You like what?
Drum brakes and fucking shitty stereos
and can't add power steering races on
the civil rights movements.
Still Getting hosed down.
No,
no.
I'm not going to live in 1963.
Yeah,
but back then in [inaudible] 63,
they're like,
man,
we got it made refrigeration there.
So when that came out,
color TV baby,
there was site looking at tv 12 inches,
bitch.
Fucking your wife on top of it.
He could do those things are cabinets.
Yeah.
Remember those things were giant.
Those tvs,
they would be in those big wooden
fucking boxes.
You'd open up the door closet.
See the TV in the back was all hot
fucking thing going.
If you touch something,
you get electric.
Yeah.
That shit was wild.
It was like tubes back there that would
replace the tube.
Yeah,
they have like a 600.
They got hot when I'm ran on gas.
I think my buddy had a smaller unit and
that was a modern one.
My grandparents had one that was in a
cabinet.
Yes.
And the TV would die and when the TV
died they put a new TV on top of the
cabinet where the old TV set 60 minutes.
All it played was 60 minutes to fill a
void.
That motherfucker.
Holy Shit.
Introducing revolutionary big picture
color television.
That was like some rear projection shit.
Those always looked terrible where there
were big.
Those are people had cocaine and that
were fucking,
you know.
Did you say that the cocaine movie
American made with Tom Cruise
[inaudible] oh,
it's a great movie man.
Oh wait.
Where he does all this stuff down in
Louisiana and he's running the planes.
I did see that.
What'd you say?
June 25 inch TV.
Is that what that is?
And everybody's talking about how big it
is and that crazy.
He looks bigger.
It looks bigger than 25 inches.
That guy,
they got a midget to do that.
Got a little tiny guy to do that
commercial.
Look at tiny fella and he's in the
background is on a step stool.
He's way in the background.
Did they?
I'm sorry,
what was something that you remember
that where you were like,
Holy Shit.
Answer machines.
Yeah.
I remember answering machines were so
crazy.
I was like,
wait a minute,
someone can leave a message.
I don't even have to be home.
And then there was a code that you could
call in.
You would call in and you would hit like
pound one,
two,
three or some shit and your answering
machine would play back your message.
Remember that you could call remotely
ability.
Yo the Yo,
I got the mushrooms.
Yeah,
meet me at 3:00 at the 7:11.
You're like,
Holy Shit.
It's on.
Is that answering machine right there,
Jamie?
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's what it was like.
It had two cassettes to outgoing
cassette and any common consent and
you'd fuck up and erase a message.
Yeah,
and you would play a song on your
outgoing,
you know,
it'd be like your favorite song.
We'll be playing and he'd be like,
Yo,
what's up Joe?
Message,
you know I'm all cool over here and shit
down,
down.
Oh,
that was a mini cassette.
That's what you were bawling.
Dual tape.
Answering machine.
Woo.
Those tiny little tapes,
motherfucker.
I'm going digital.
Yeah,
and just fuck a girl.
Run on top of that.
Then break it.
Remember when you hear it go off beep
and you could.
You could listen for someone like,
hey man,
it's my.
You don't call me back.
And I'm like,
boy,
I'm glad I didn't pick that up.
You can screen the calls.
Remember that screen calls before that
you just had to take your chances every
time you picked up the phone,
every time you picked up the phone you
were taking a chance.
It could be mom,
it could be the.
It could be anything.
It could be anybody.
People would call your house late at
night and parents would get pissed.
Who the fuck's calling me at 11:00 at
night?
Yeah.
We call the no,
we call the movie theaters and listen to
that voice message once the call waiting
came out,
you know,
so we'd listen to that long message from
the,
from the welcome to movie is 7:30 7:35
and 9:00 PM.
Yeah,
that's right.
You would call up to find what time shit
was playing pink Cadillac,
uh,
will be eight,
10 and 10.
Thirty PM.
Yeah.
You gotta listen to that whole thing to
fucking remember it or write it down.
Write it down.
That was the only time you could find
out what was playing in a fucking movies
or you get the newspaper,
go to the newspaper,
find out that.
And you trusted it and then you went
there.
Yeah.
You went there.
Did.
That was just a few years ago.
That's what's crazy.
That's unfathomable today.
If there was no more cell phones,
no more Internet on your phone.
It was unfathomable when there's no
turning back.
What is going to happen with us.
That's also no turning back that we
don't have now that we just were used to
not having it.
So it's no big deal.
Like back in the sixties,
nobody thought about cell phones and the
Internet because they didn't have it.
It wasn't something they missed.
Right.
Let's come in.
I know what I think what some of it is.
I think it's um,
just like complete transparency where
it's like through people's eyes you have
some sort of thing that can,
you know exactly,
like if they're being genuine or what
their thoughts are.
You know.
I think so,
yeah.
I think,
I think that's definitely coming,
but they have the ability to read each
other's minds is coming for sure because
we need something to trump like people
who are just full of shit full of shit.
Yes.
And people who lie and people who don't
want good,
you know,
where people are too greedy.
We just needed something to do.
Something about that.
Yeah.
Um,
I think there's gonna come a time where
you could definitely read people's
minds,
you know,
they're already figured out a way to
implant memories.
Did you read that Shit about that?
They've implanted memory.
They successfully implanted a memory in
something.
What was the thing?
The implanted and then do you remember?
I think yeah,
some animal just say figured out a way a
rat can do it.
Successfully.
Implant a memory.
So it's going to come a point in time
where it's like someone said,
this is like
a snail.
Yeah.
I'm not buying that.
I'm going to wait till the next year.
Yeah.
I'm super skeptical.
Scientist Transplant memories between
sea snails via injection experiment
shows some memories are encoded in
molecules that form part
of an organism's genetic machinery.
Researchers say,
okay,
I'm too stupid to know whether or not
they're telling the truth,
so I'm going to believe them.
Don't believe.
What does this in this is in the
Guardian.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well they.
They had that therapy now that emdr.
Have you ever done that?
No.
What's that?
Where it's like they.
You hold on these panels and they like.
It's therapy.
It's therapy and it activates both sides
of your brain while you're like
remembering old things and then you like
replace those old fears are scary parts
of you with like new,
like new parts,
like new ideas and new memories kind of.
And I've gone to it a couple times,
probably about maybe 10 times.
And uh,
yeah,
you go back into your thoughts and it's
while it's activating both sides of your
brain,
you can do stuff to your childhood that
you weren't able to do when you were a
kid because only one part of your brain
was developing.
That's what they say.
Huh?
What did you go back to?
What'd you do it for?
How did it just for like,
like maybe like for like probably a
father figure stuff.
Not having somebody to stand up for me
or feeling like,
you know,
certain times in my life where I didn't
have support,
you know?
And I felt like I was alone.
Like you go back and like you plug
somebody in there with you that is
supportive.
And so while you're talking about it and
this thing's open up both sides of your
head,
it can,
it can help.
And what does it help with the going
back over that stuff from your
childhood,
what's good about doing that?
It replaces that memory with the new
memory.
Right?
But,
but isn't that memory even though it's
negative,
beneficial to you because you understand
why it was bad and then once someday
when you have kids you have learned from
the mistakes too.
Good point.
Like you don't want to replace a bad
childhood with a good one in your brain
because he didn't have a good childhood.
Right?
Like it's okay to have a bad childhood.
Like you've gone through that.
Yeah,
I mean it's not.
I would think that for someone who's
dealing with something extremely
traumatic like childhood rape or
something like that,
then maybe it makes sense.
Yeah.
Violence,
things along those lines.
Something that's like haunts you all the
time that's messing with you,
messing with your life today.
But like does your childhood messed with
your life today?
No.
So why fuck with it?
Yeah,
that's a good point.
I mean,
I never even thought about that,
I guess.
Yeah,
maybe that stuff for people that's
extremely traumatic,
but got through like a,
a,
you know,
a shot,
an Arrow and fucking hit somebody on
accident or.
No,
I didn't,
but if somebody did.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
I killed an animal with a knife or
something bad or you know,
somebody killed my parents or something,
then you could go back.
Yes.
Yeah.
I think that's probably a good point.
I guess some of this stuff,
it's like some people it's debilitating,
you know,
their childhood,
the trauma is so bad,
it haunts them and it keeps them from
improving and growing as a person.
Yeah,
like really horrible shit.
But for us,
I think it's fuel.
I think the goofiness of your and my
childhood and the bad,
it's sort of led you to become a
comedian really.
I really think that you do need the.
I mean
we've talked about Joey Joey,
he found his mother dead on the kitchen
floor when he was 13 years old on acid.
Jody has been through everything.
He's seen it all.
I'm going to think that there's
something to that that makes him so
fucking funny,
you know,
if you replaced all that childhood would
like the perfect loving parents that
were,
you know,
super engaged and there for them all the
time and very supportive and an amazing
neighborhood with no violence,
no crime and all this diversity and
everybody's super progressive.
You're not going to get a Joey Diaz.
He'd be working at a cafeteria,
you know what I'm saying?
Or a library and he'd be one of the
hottest women.
They are probably two at the cafeteria,
you know,
it's something really special about him
and that's been a blessing to meeting
him is that like he'll call me salons
and just like check in on me.
Yeah,
he does that all the time.
Calls me every day.
That's so crazy.
It's gone.
Tell you I love you.
I love you too man.
But it's like the first time he does it,
you know,
I guess me just like not trusting
things,
you know,
like my own internal thing sometimes.
But then after like the 10th time you're
like,
damn man,
he's legit.
Yeah.
Like this guy really cares.
It's pretty cool.
Well,
he doesn't text either thinks it's
impersonal and I think he's right.
You know,
he likes to call you talk to him.
The phone.
Yeah.
I wonder what the future is going to be
like.
Man.
I feel sad if we get so far away from
each other that we don't know.
Remember what it's like to have.
Like I feel like a smile is going to be
like in a museum one day,
you know?
Nah,
I think we'll still have smiles,
but we might get to a point where human
interaction is all done digitally.
That could happen,
but I think.
I think it's just,
we're just going to get used to it.
Just like we're used to this life and
we're not living in caves anymore.
Those people that lived in caves like,
oh,
he's fucking.
Yeah man.
I never want to leave this as a way to
go.
It was fucking hideous for their cars.
Airplanes.
Like when you live in the cave,
there was no going to the Bahamas.
You,
you're not going to the Bahamas bitch.
You live in a cave.
And this is where you live.
You can't go on vacation to Italy.
The fuck out of here,
there's no vacation and you live in a
cave.
If you want to take your fucking family,
you want to take your family through the
woods,
you're going to get eaten by wolves.
Aren't gonna.
Make it every pickney it didn't,
just violent death.
He went from raspberries to just spray
him blood all over each other.
And I think that as time goes on,
like this is going to be the,
we're going to look back or someone is
going something that's different than
us.
Now it's going to look back on us.
Like look at these dopes with
antibiotics and taking vitamins and
shit.
These fucking morons come in on each
other.
Loads each other's face because they saw
the video,
you know,
like what do they do?
Sit at home jacket off like some fucking
adderall up monkey.
Taking a break,
drinking milk,
trying to go back for round three.
He jerk off three times in a day.
Oh I can't do that kind of stuff.
Makes me sick to my stomach.
Never that I've done it.
And I've never
been horny.
It's almost like I'm trying to see if I
could do it.
It's like,
you know,
capital and stuff.
Yeah.
You're getting Kaplan.
Was He Olympic athlete?
Oh,
telling me the guy from.
Welcome back,
Kotter.
I'm thinking of somebody else there
thinking.
Who are you thinking of?
I don't know.
Michael Spitz.
Maybe somebody who's against the Olympic
guy.
Yeah,
he's a swimmer.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Somebody that could,
you know,
somebody that just just kept doing it
over and over again.
I get,
I'm not even that good at this.
I don't know.
Sex is fucking retarded sometimes.
Dude.
It's also crazy.
Just banging into somebody until
somebody comes.
Who's Gabe Kaplan?
Look at him.
Handsome bastard.
He became a poker player.
Became a professional poker player.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
The avant.
I gotta wrap this bitch up.
I got an anecdote.
Enter enduro man.
Look at him.
Go.
He looks terrible.
Dude.
Thanks for having me here.
I love your new place.
Thanks brother.
Yeah,
it's really cool man.
Thanks for,
uh,
just see inspiration and stuff.
Man.
My pleasure,
my man.
Always good senior.
Always good hanging around with you.
You too,
man.
I'll see you at the store so you have
the store.
All right,
bye everybody.
See you soon.