Boom. And we're Lively's gentlemen
who has special guest. Well, Jimmy
didn't think he was going to be here. This
was a total surprise. This is awesome.
Yeah. I'm shooting something tomorrow and
I want it to watch the fights. I'm like,
at this point, I didn't think you'd
be in town. You're always off.
Like every time I call he's like guy, he's
a way, he's hunting, he's unreachable.
Um, and I was just happy that you get back
to me. Yeah, dude was perfect timing. Uh,
you know, we uh, decided a while ago, well
I was supposed to be out of town too. Um,
and then, uh, decided to
come back and make it back in
time for this. I'm like, wow,
we should definitely do a fight
companion. So we decided to, but uh,
Eddie was available,
luckily should be what?
Be watching the UFC.
Oh,
we are going to watch two different
things at the same time, folks,
this should be fucking complete.
The deal is that the Canelo Alvarez fight
is supposed to start at eight o'clock.
That's what they've been pushing. And, uh,
I think they're doing that because they're
trying to get a lot of people in the
east coast to buy it because after
11:00 PM you're like, Jesus Christ,
I want to go to sleep. You know, because
they were doing them a lot of times,
like 9:00 PM nine 30, it's fucking
midnight, New York. It's crazy.
You're tired. Even Saturday people can
do it, but it's like, it's tough to,
when it goes out and 1112
o'clock at night, it's not wise,
especially with boxing
because boxing has weak.
Undercards not necessarily saying
that this is a week fight. Right.
But even if they have a good undercard,
what do they have? Like two fights, right?
I mean, how many fights they have. You
don't want to see more than that. No,
I'm not going to pay per view.
The worst part is when you,
when you watch one of these
fights on the east coast,
by the time you get out the
arena, get your car, it's,
you have time for one drink maybe,
and then they shut down bars. Well,
the good thing is really east coast,
they shut down bars at four
in New York for a year.
You can go back to the hotel room,
take a shower, take a little power nap,
and then you're ready to
go to the after party.
Writes over it like tenish it's
way better. It's way better.
I never watched boxing anymore either.
Like I watched Conor and Floyd just
to watch it, but I never watch. Uh,
but I think I watched the last
triple g fight. That's it.
I watch all of his fights and I watch
it all Canelo's fights and uh, you know,
it's weird. So when you're
watching a guy started slow down,
like I watched him Miguel
Cotto fight and he won.
But he's getting hit more than he used
to get hit. It's like 36 now, you know,
I don't think they have
UFC style testing though.
They don't have like Usada they don't
have a Jeff Novitsky so these guys can get
away with a lot more.
It's a little slippery with like,
I don't think they did steroids in boxing.
That's hilarious.
Illegal Dude. You know
what, you got to see it.
Caerus I don't know how you say it
is an ecourse or oh, you are? Yeah,
but I would say that it's one of those
words that have only read the documentary.
It's fucking amazing.
And it's all on this Russian doctor that
was like one of the top guys over there
for steroids and how,
what,
how much shit they can give you and
you still test negative. Holy Fuck.
These guys are wizards. This is,
they take this guy who's the, uh,
the main person in the
documentary and they,
they just pump them full of steroids.
He's like,
I want you to have a full cc of this
and five of, I mean, shooting like six,
seven things in his past
filling an experiment. Yes. Oh,
can experiment with this
Russian guy who's response.
One of the things they said was
that out of the Russian athletes,
there was some estimate in the
high nineties of percentage
of people that are on
steroids who wasn't on steroids.
Well,
he still like to this day in Rio,
they were actually the Olympics.
We're thinking about banning the
entire Russian team. They'll like,
their anti-doping program is so
sophisticated and so state sanctioned.
Well, can they pass Usada testing
though? Could they pass that lol? No,
I mean it depends because
they see the sought of thing.
They'll show up at your fucking house,
you know,
like you have to give your whereabouts
at all times. Yeah, they'll,
they'll catch you.
And the other thing is they keep your
piss and to keep your blood and they keep
it for a long time.
I think like seven or eight years.
And they actually just busted a guy
who won the Olympics, I think in tooth,
I want to say 2008 and 2012 or
something like that. But uh,
I think it was two guys. I don't know,
maybe Jamie could find it, but they,
they took away their gold metals,
these Russian wrestlers,
they busted them eight years later,
way later that they didn't have a
test for whatever they were doing.
So that's what happens.
It's like these guys are one step ahead,
but then the test catch up,
you know,
and then they find stuff in them and
they retroactively go and grab your shit
from from years ago.
It's like when they saved somebodies head
like Ted Williams hoping they can find
a cure for whatever he died
from and bring him back.
That's why they freeze your body or
freeze your head. Right. That's so crazy.
The freezing the head thing is so bananas.
You're like,
well listen for $5 more we
can keep your body. No Dude,
you know I'm taking a chance
as it is. Let's just go with
the head. Just the head.
Yeah,
just the idea that they're going to just
keep your head frozen and then you need
to get like they don't wake you up
amongst the first people you get woke up
after they figured out how
to reattach heads to bodies.
You get woken up way later.
Like I figured I'd just had a re animate
dead bodies that won't be that big of a
deal, but then attach heads on a new
body like that's a couple more decades.
Lets you talk to Ray Kurzweil. He thinks
we're going to have that in 15 years.
It's very wishful timeline. Is it
possible to be such a famous fighter,
you have s you're rubbing shoulders with
a powerful, the elite. You're so famous.
Is it possible for,
for a fighter and have so much fame that
he has connections to the Illuminati?
No, the people that tell them our
group, the people tends to steroids. It,
he would never get busted. Like it's
totally winky, winky. Certain foods.
Is that possible?
It's totally possible,
but it's just super unlikely because
there's too many pieces involved.
Too many people would know and it's uh,
also there's no benefit to them.
They would have to be getting paid shit.
Tons of money.
It's just so sneaky like that
in order if you have, cause you,
what if someone dies,
you know like what if someone gets a
ship eight out of the winds up dying and
turns out that these people got ahold
of money and that's what allowed them to
not do drug tests on this guy.
And this guy was on Jews and then he
goes in and beat someone to death.
It's Kinda hard to keep anything
electronically. A secret. I mean,
the head of the CIA could make a fucking
email disappear. This the Russians,
no one got buses to returns driven.
Matter of everything gets out.
No one goes to jail.
Please step down.
Now he had to step down
because he would have you,
I'm just saying what you say Jim. I
missed it electronically. You can't,
nothing's a secret anymore.
Like we're not always his name.
The head of the CIA who was cheating and
he got busted that stupid email. Yeah.
Betrayal of trust yet. And he was, you
know, a war hero? Yeah. He ran the a,
the whole, what they call it,
the uh, the theater. He was a,
do you know the story behind him though?
How he got caught?
I think you're investigating
someone else, right? No.
He was hooking up with a chick
and the chick was a little mouthy.
Didn't she write his
book? His biographer? Ah,
I think there was her and I think there
was another one and the other one.
What might have been a part of some freaky
marriage situation where the husband
and wife banging other people
or something. It was, it got,
it got heavy enough where it was weird.
Yeah,
and the one of the ways they got Patraeus
out of there was like through some
sort of adultery clause,
which is hilarious.
It's like a morals clause is one of the
best killers in the military and you're
telling him if you bang on the
chicks we won't let you kill people.
All information that's
coming from the mainstream.
Who knows what really how those guys tell
the truth knows what's going on. Yeah.
Who knows what that is, why they
made him do that. Like what?
What pieces might have fallen into play
Frank Underwood's style that allow that
to happen.
Who they piss off Elliot Spitzer piss
somebody off 10 years ago and they went
and digging and they got him.
Well Spitzer went after the banks Spitz.
It's really a shame about
Spitzer because in any other era,
Eliot Spitzer would have been
probably like a big time hero,
like some sort of a like clean him up cop
type of guy who's like looking out for
the good guy.
The problem is there was some serious or
proxy because it turns out that he was
actually targeting brothels as
well as visiting and which is just,
yeah man, you can't do that.
Like it's just, that's even,
it's one thing if he just got hookers,
sure.
But the fact that the guy was arresting
all of those [inaudible] out of his way
for it. Yeah. He's a real
douche and it's like,
that's why I love to see these guys who
legislate against gay people get busted
and restrooms and stuff because you're
actively trying to fuck somebody life. Oh,
for sure.
And it's always those people.
It's always those people that care so
much, they get angry at gay people.
You know? It's just such a classic
story writing. They're hiding,
hiding their whole life that they're,
they overdo it just so that
no one sniffs them out.
It's such a classic cliche that you
see it. You're like, Oh God. So,
so obvious. Did a great documentary
on politicians who are outed,
like who were anti gay but
got out of there as being gay.
You know what it's like.
It's like that really scrawny type of
male feminists that's always like sticking
up for women and saying like, of course
you are like, it's such a cliche.
It's,
it's almost the same cliche as the gay
guy that's it hates gay marriage and
hates gay people because
he's trying to cover it up.
It's usually these guys that
are like overwhelmed with lust.
The women seem so impossible to,
to get with that.
They,
they morph themselves into this like a
semi real human being that only looks out
for women's issues all the time.
24 seven.
It doesn't see anything
wrong with women ever.
You know that guy where it's like
you're not even real anymore. Yeah.
It gets you to put on
you because then you're,
then you're fucking allowed to walk among
them and be comfortable and they trust
you and they call you an ally.
You're an ally and they fucked the allies.
So everyone wants to be an
Alpha course. Watch the UFC. Ah,
Eddie Brown like boxing, but luck man,
they keep punching each other. Ah,
it is interesting how it becomes
way less interesting. Right? Yeah.
I haven't watched watch anymore a good,
well I watched Mayweather versus a Connor.
She thought that was interesting.
I was in Iceland for that.
It was like five o'clock in the morning.
He was in a bar and it was fun to
watch because of, you know, again,
I wanted to see if cotton would do okay
but Mayweather against anybody else that
have no interesting cause that was fun.
That was lots of fun.
I like watching that guy fight period.
I'm always,
I watched may whether even
if it's a boring ass fight
cause what you're watching
is some guy that just can do things that
other people who are not able to do.
He's, yeah, he's going to be one
step ahead. I just don't enjoy them.
Like I watched the uh, the pack. Y'all
fight in a bar and I was like, Ugh,
what am I you one round from the next?
I look exactly the same and what
channel on to 19 to 19. Thank you sir.
So what we're going to do folks is
just go back and forth from the fight.
So you got that c you're totally hardcore
MMA fan. Would you consider yourself,
I love the podcast. That's
her Matthew, the UFC podcast
fan.
That's like the expert and I'm like the
guy who can do the more humans I use
every UFC or you're going to try to watch
unless you've got something going on.
I watch most of them. I usually
watch them the next day on the uh,
fight pass cause I'm usually doing
gigs Saturday night too. Matt is Great.
I love that too.
He's such a great guy.
He took Eddie and I into his gym
when in like 2001 or some shit.
Remember that he took us to his,
Jimi picked us up at the train station.
We took the train in the long island.
He took us,
picked us up in the train station,
took it to his gym,
showed us his apartment in the basement
where he used to pee in a jug because he
drank so much water he couldn't get out
of bed cause he needed his sleep because
he was fighting.
So he would just carry a jug and put it
right by the bed and just piss in the
jug in the middle of the night. It was
hilarious. Matt Serra is awesome. Yeah.
And he's such a real guy. Like he's
exactly that guy all the time. He's great.
He's great. What a great move
it is to have him on that.
Dana white looking for a fight show
and to have him on your podcast.
Well he had the podcast first
and I think that they asked him,
couple of people and
when he, when Dana brought
up my name, he's like, yeah,
I would love to it because we got a
long while. So it's a fun dynamic.
I mean you could just fun and you guys
got jelled with each other. You know,
you gel. Yeah. But you could see it's
like you guys are friends. It's fun.
That's like a big thing, man. You know?
And I think people underestimate that.
It's one of the reasons why these TV
shows sometimes are so stale and flat.
They're stiff. Yeah, well
they don't like each other.
Then our friends with each other,
you know,
like people like when they see people who
actually like Goldberg and I like when
we used to do broadcast
together Goldberg's my friend,
like I really liked that guy.
And Jon Anik, same thing.
Annex my friend Dominic Cruz, my friend,
like I hanging out with that guy.
He's interesting. Paul Felder. Like
I could hang out with these guys.
That's big man. You know? That's why
people like these kinds of podcasts.
That's why people like,
you know,
anything where people get together and
they can hang out and you feel like a
real camaraderie versus like entertainment
tonight store is back and boy and see
angry. Yes, he is. Mike
Thor's back in the newest,
most amazing version of Thor.
Let's take a look like those people don't,
even if they are friends,
you can't tell. It's,
it's unwatchable and it's
unlistenable and it doesn't feel,
it feels like nothing you can connect to,
so I don't know anybody I
speak to like that. Exactly.
I was going to tell each
other to shut up on that show.
I wonder if w with wonder woman now at
the forefront of sports and technology
and shut the fuck up. Yeah, it's annoying.
They have like these pre scheduled
scheduled promos that they do.
They feel so stale and
everything's just stay.
Well that's why even on TV I go back
and watch old Dick Cavett Shit like
interview bishop prior in 1985 I'd
rather hear a real conversation with dead
moments then like a late night TV show
now where everybody thinks they're on
fire every time the camera's are
on this terrible. Most of them.
These like entertainment shows like
shows on entertainment, like pool.
That's hard to get right will you used
to be that the networks had all the power
and there wasn't ever a PR a content
problem. It wasn't like, damn,
we need content that was slots.
There's Thursday eight 30 Thursday,
nine o'clock they'll slot. There's
just those slots. That's it.
We got plenty of motherfuckers trying to
make pilots and that's never a problem
with content.
Now it's the opposite.
Now they need content so more people
can get their shit out now it used to be
totally controlled. TV has
always suck. You can't watch aid.
We Watch TV shows that we grew up on
because we had no choice. You would.
I would watch TV going, okay, what's
the best of this? These terrible shows.
I'll just watch that.
You're like,
fuck it badly just to love think some of
them were good back then to right now,
the fall guy.
Watch now.
Watch a Paul Guy now I can't
probably doesn't. Hold on TV.
Didn't have to be good. You're right.
He had all the control now. Shit,
it has to be good and now you need
content. The $6 million different world
holds up. The Sasquatch episode
reflect the Big Foot Douchey,
just thing ever on television and I
couldn't wait to watch the fight tomorrow.
Louis Martinez, Sergio, more eyes.
This is a great fucking fight.
Gomar Huisman is a stud wrestler.
Fucking serious athlete and [inaudible]
is one of the best Jujitsu guys in MMA
today for sure. Tapped out chrome
Gracie and its first black belt match.
He's a legit anybody that he's the guy
that set up then mounted triangle. Right.
Nice and slow. Yeah. You know what he
said once about one of his opponents,
he said it would be more likely that
he got me pregnant than submit me.
He was talking about an improvements
in is striking. It's like in striking,
I think I have the advantage and in the
ground it would be more likely that he
got me pregnant and then you submit me.
That's how bad ass that mother fucker is.
But Camaros Huisman is a
stud and he is super legit.
Fantastic wrestler with
really good striking,
very strong guy.
Very dangerous.
Could be future superstar
world champion guy type of guy.
You'd have to take out Leeanne Edwards,
just Edwards actually doing
really well against him.
It seemed like in the first round and
then like you know once he had them on the
ground he was finished.
So see us, he's a savage.
You got to watch a match ISM ground
and pound vicious from wrestler.
He can do everything, man. He
could submit guys, you know he's,
he's a super stud wrestler but he
absolutely can do all that stuff.
What are his best American top team guy?
So he's like a black belt in Jujitsu.
No wonder what he is and Jiu Jitsu.
I wonder like if he's ranked,
but you know like there's a lot of
guys that aren't ranked like Michael
[inaudible].
Michael Kass in my mind is like a
black belt but he's not even ranked.
Should that fight him and stop your
thing? No, definitely not. Never.
You don't stop chokes.
Why would you stop a choke?
You let a guy go to sleep so he's up. He's
actually fit. If the guys unconscious,
he was clearly not unconscious
guys get out of shit.
You've got to give him an
opportunity to get out of shit.
His arms were like this
man. You're right. Stop it.
Cause there's no next move.
Yamasaki stopped it early. Yes.
He should have let him go out. Yes, yes.
But a 100% Yamasaki everybody,
any black belt knows when a guy's
about to go out his before he goes out,
his hands go like this and that's
what happens a lot of times.
If you let go with the choke,
you pop right back up and say you're
all totally correct. But Buddy,
she did let him go to sleep. Shit, let him
go to sleep. And here's the other thing.
This is our absolutely also possible to
some guys when they're getting choked,
they will concentrate just on their neck
and they were tight enough their neck
and they won't do this
and fight around with it.
They would literally put all their
energy and concentration on the neck and
avoiding the choke by just
squeezing and holding on their neck.
If they think they have a
little bit of blood flow,
if they could force a little bit of blood
flow and they think that they can stay
conscious longer than the guy can squeeze,
I don't buy it for the long haul.
I think the on the long haul,
a guy like you know,
someone who someone is a really
good fight, like a Damien Maia Guy,
he's gonna fucking put you to sleep. You
can't, you can't do that on him, right?
The question is can I do it on Kevin?
But even I don't want him to go down.
He's very good.
Even when you're tightening your now,
but he's not limp if he's doing this,
okay, this is, his arms are here, right?
So if he's concentrating on
his neck and his arms are here,
if he really does decide to stop doing
this and just try to just concentrate on
his neck,
it's not a good strategy,
but it might be something you would
use if you thought you were fucked.
If you thought you're fucked,
you in a really bad spot and you really
can't peel his arms off, and he goes,
you know what, I might be able to
just power through and he might not,
he might've had a tap or it might even
want to sleep or he might have gotten out.
We don't fucking know because guys have
gotten out of some crazy shit. In fact,
earlier that night, the
woman who got it right. Yeah.
Who I fuck, I forget that fight.
What was that fight? Find out? Um,
what the card was on the Kevin
Lee Michael Key s a fight.
But the point is it's not dangerous.
It's not like a,
an arm bar or taking
punishment on the ground.
Like when someone takes a couple of
extra shots on the ground that aren't
necessary, that that's bad. But if
someone gets choked out, that's not bad.
It's not bad. You've got to let him get
choked out. You're not preventing anything
damage. Glen. Um, who just, it just a,
that fight that should
have been stopped on the,
I want to say it was one of the
prelims tug. Gavin Tucker. Yeah.
Guaranteed against brick land.
That was bad. I saw Dana tweeting.
I hadn't seen the fight yet.
He's like this referee.
And then when I watched it fight
like this must've been the fight.
He was talking. Well, you
know what the thing is,
is that it was a slow beating work
was giving him a slow beating.
He just kept beating him up. It
was, there was no giant big bombs,
but it was a cumulation of bombs. It
never ended. It just, he was so workman,
like in professionals. Very,
very impressive victories.
Is that why he didn't get,
I thought he should have got like a,
a fight of the night or,
or performance of the night. I mean, I
thought that that was a pretty amazing,
and he didn't get anything for
that, which were the girls that, uh,
almost choked the shit out of each other.
Was it flees, Harrigan, Justine Kush? Yes,
it was.
Was that seen Keshon fleets Herrick?
Is that the fight where she
shit or know who on that? Uh,
I believe police did right? When did that
happen? Yeah. Philly's won last week. No,
that, no, that was a couple of months ago.
I was asked to fight that fight that
Kish had that allegedly she hit herself.
Oh, whatever happened. Yeah.
I Dunno if she did or not.
It's supposedly that can
be grounds to stop a fight.
Now it's like in the rules like if they,
you shit yourself,
it's too dangerous cause there's
all like scratches and shit. Yeah.
If you have cut so you can get like the
worst staph infection known to man and
plus you may make a move
to avoid being put in that.
That's going to put you in other
kinds of danger. Like just you,
you want your face mushed in
that you may do something right.
Your neck and Jennifer is a very good
point. If someone's going 69 on you,
if you're in like north south position,
which is legit position and this dude just
shit himself. That's super rude. Yeah.
Yeah. It's a bad place to be. But hey
man, it's life and death in there.
[inaudible] he would go,
this is a good fucking fight
is like Ooh,
what's going
to happen here? Fight. Okay.
Dan Merkel Yada dance lemon down.
Yeah.
He's the only 500 pounds
now cause gigantic policy.
Huge. He's like at least six five
and he's not like a tall thin guy.
Users at giant for real though.
He's probably 300 pounds easy.
Very interesting.
He's one 74 51 of the first round,
(504) 094-0840 seven if you want to
sync it up with us.
42 41
we're rise is missing a tricep on
his left arm has got one missing.
I know he's got a bicep
misery. What happened? What
happened to the tricep? His uh,
arm tour and he never got surgery on or
if he got surgery it never came back.
But look, you could see it doesn't
really have a tricep on his left arm.
It doesn't start when he got hurt,
he got hurt to the bomb. Oh Shit.
He's in a lot of trouble.
He's a,
he's in a lot of trouble and get on top
of it and the get that he's hurt and
he's on his back and he won't get on
top of it. Yeah, but that's smart.
Like make them stand out with
your team to let off on him.
But he's on his back on his back.
He might have a chance to do something
standing up. He's getting tooled.
I'm agreeing with you,
Joe. I'm just, it's smart.
Mariah's recently. Yeah,
it's smart. I mean,
wouldn't you tell them if you were
Comoros coach, fuck cow. You're like,
don't go in the rounds of sky lit up,
kick kick his calf because not theirs,
isn't it that chance?
He's just gonna wrap his arms around
you and catch his breath. Oh, 100%.
How do don't get any my sweep you,
you might,
you might think he's
more tired than he is.
He might recover quicker than you think.
Next thing you know,
he's got deep half on you
and next thing you know, Ooh,
he's swinging and he might have a better
shot on his back then he does standing.
Hey,
how long before someone
starts doing sidekicks and
front kicks to the calves and
to the, to the shins. How long before
like a Shin Kit comes back like in school?
Remember when that hurt?
Like a motherfucker. Kids
would kick kids in the shins.
Yeah, but I think that
after that, that civil,
I've been fight and get on your toes.
You have done,
if you curl your foot back
in, uh, like a front kick,
oh shit. It's illegal kick,
right? Yeah. I think it's legal.
If you could sidekick the thigh, if you
could, uh, we'll kick the head. How,
how has anything to do like illegal.
It's Hilarious, right? Yeah.
Well in almost mean how many people
that get hit on the back of the head.
That's one thing I was
noticing about boxing tonight.
Guys will complain while they're in the
middle of an exchange of a punch hits
the back of the head. I touched the back
of their head like, hey, you're cheating.
You're hitting me back here
to fucking hit me back here.
It's almost like an excuse
for getting hit at all.
You fucking never see that
in the UFC in stand up.
He never see guys complaining about
getting hit in the back of the head.
You hear about it on the ground.
You know,
like you hear about like sometimes
when a guy is trying to finish someone,
they'll hit him all over the place and
sometimes it'll hit the head whether it's
on purpose or not. They only know,
but standing up you never hear it.
What did you think?
That referee
is? Pretty Tall. He's
out. He's out. Oh Shit.
Wow. That was sensational. I told
you tomorrow Huisman is legit.
That that dude is seriously talented.
Upstanding up was a smart move.
Yeah. He could be the one.
That guy could be a legit world champion.
I believe he's undefeated too.
Here's one loss. Who's
his loss too? He was like,
it was his second fight or something. I
think he's in a long, long winning streak.
Who's his lost to jamming Camaros?
Man,
I'm a problem. I said, oh man. For some
reason I thought it was like Nigerian.
He came when he was young.
I asked him about it that
he's faced. Serious wrestler,
serious athlete.
Siri did get everything so thick
is speed and the thing is man,
he didn't even start out as a
striker. Jose, he wrestled in college.
He got submitted way back in
CFA 11 in a second profile.
Boom to look at the speed on that
shit. What about the shot? Hello?
Take that too.
Is that Dan just giving this guy an
extra second to see if he didn't stop,
stop his eyes rolled back.
I just wanted to see if the
guy was conscious cause if
he rolled and then he was
looking at him and he had his hands
up, he would let it go. Stop it fish.
So you don't think it should have
been stopped before that car?
She had to get that second floor.
You know what one extra punch.
It's a violent sport. They could have
stopped it but he could have recovered.
That was the perfect stop it.
She got to let it play out a
little bit and it's hard to do.
Dan's one of the best in the
business though. He's so good.
He's on t he liked you very rarely
have complaints about Dan Merkel,
Yada fighters hate I'll fighters hate.
Dan stopped early.
You know Jay Gavin Tucker actually said
that he thanked that referee for not
stopping at chance, but that's just
the guy was too tough for his own good.
That's just first lost though. I mean
he's a really tough dude and like he, he,
there was no way he was
going to quit but it isn't.
It's like orbital socket all fucked up.
I mean he's going to have a
lot of things wrong with him.
He got beat up real bad. It was a
bad beating. He took a beating for,
I mean the first round it
took a while before, you know,
it got sort of lopsided.
But then from the second round on it
was pretty obvious that Rick Lynn wasn't
getting tired and you're just pushing
this crazy steady pace and just Gavin
could not keep up with them and Rick was
long and he couldn't get close to him
and Rick just had this very workman Lee
approach just cap on him and the dude
just started breaking.
Just the guy who knows a guy who's been
around for a long time and then the
least the way Frankie Edgar beat up on
y'all, y'all Rodriguez and your guy,
he's been around for a long time.
Who knows how to beat the
hot young guy coming up.
Well Frankie Edgar's on
a totally different level
cause Frankie can keep this
ferocious pace that's so few
people can keep up with like yeah,
he thought he could,
might keep up with it.
He thought like maybe when I get in
there I'll be able scrambled this guy,
I'll be able to keep up with them.
My gout ground games pretty good.
Probably worked on get back up to his
feet, probably thought I'll surprise them.
I'll surprise him and when
we're kicking standing up,
he's not gonna be able
to deal with my shit.
They just realize there's
levels to this thing.
Frankie Edgar is on that
world championship level.
Is that what he's thinking?
Probably is like there's no way
Frankie's didn't get close enough to me.
I'm going to be able to
keep him away from me.
Well or catch him coming in or Frankie
might try to exchange with them on the
feet and he has a chance to land something
or maybe it's takedown defense is
better than you know.
Frankie thinks it is.
There's a lot of thoughts that go into
your head when he tried to pull something
like that off, but it was, if you
are as a manager, there's not,
it's not the fight to make,
it's just not the fight.
It's the one of the worst fights to make.
It's good to find out how you
do against an elite wrestler,
but not the elite wrestler. The guy
who is a lightweight world champion,
now he's coming down to one 45 was the
only guy has been able to beat him as
Aldo. [inaudible] here's the decision
I think, right? Yeah. I mean,
Frankie's Goddamn world class, although
might have his number, I don't know.
But that doesn't mean that
Frankie can't beat a lot of guys.
He fucked up cub Swanson like
easily his world championship level.
But sometimes like guys, just for
whatever reason, can't be another guy.
Like Joe Frazier was always
a world championship level.
Boxer could not be George Foreman.
If they fought a hundred times,
George following would've beat
him a hundred times. Yeah.
And that's got to get into your
head after. I mean, I mean,
John's called me only twice and plus
all this stuff that happened there is
always that one guy that you just
can't do anything against theirs.
There's guys that have a solution to your
style, you know? Do you remember, um,
sugar? Shane Mosley? Sure. Vernon Forrest.
Verna Forrest just had this
solution to sugar. Shane Mosley,
I believe he beat him twice,
you know,
and it was like one of those things
where Vernon didn't look the best rest in
peace. He got shot actually
is a terrible story man.
Cause that someone was trying to rob his
car and he tried to stop someone from
Robin as cotton that shot him.
The gas station in Atlanta.
Is that the guy I'm
thinking of? Yeah. Yeah.
Chase the guys still like he chased him
in a fucking pop them. It was, yeah.
And apparently he was a super nice guy.
It's just a really, really sad store.
But he like,
he could shine against Shane in a way
that he couldn't shine against other
people. Yeah. But then like Ricardo
my org and knocked him out. Remember,
I don't remember if I Believe
Mountain Mel Mayorga knocked him out.
Definitely beat him.
I believe actually my Shane Mosley,
one of my first UFC event,
he was there. It's, I'm,
I want to say it's 2008 2000 I
might in a rampage fight 2009 mm.
It's weird to watch boxers and those
things and how they react. It is weird,
right. But watching Bernard
high, stepping on a behind bug,
Bernard Hopkins and Yale,
he had critical things to save a bunch
of guys rolling around. It looks gay.
And then watching him and his trainers
watch the guys on the ground that they
were there watching the standup,
they were fine,
but what they really got impressed with
was the stuff on the ground because
that's the stuff he can't do.
So it was interesting to watch him kind
of watch his opinion change as he was
there. Right? Yeah. I
mean they have to talk.
The problem is there's like these,
these camps like look at that. Boom,
look at that right hand.
Good Lord. That was clean.
Like you see him shaking his head.
He's totally out of it.
There were the timing on
this. Oh, that's so good.
Uh, but you know, people just get lumped
off into camps. I get what sports better.
That's so silly.
Yeah.
It's so silly because boxing at
its highest level like tonight,
well we're going to watch and just
hopefully like five or 10 minutes they're
walking out now. Oh Shit.
That is a very compelling,
do you know that's one of the
main differences right there.
What you just saw we spend,
that's where the main differences
between UFC in every sport is the,
the way that fighters treat the
fans and interacting with the fans.
You just don't see that in any
other sport. No, it's true. They,
and there was a lot of events
where people get to meet fighters,
they do a lot of events,
a lot of signings and share it and
go meet him and hang out with them,
getting invested in them and
you get connected to them.
So then when they're on the
prelims and the under car,
you still want to watch them fight. Yeah.
Yeah. There's a lot, a lot of good things.
The UFC figured out that boxing had
fucked up and now boxing is kind of take
picked up the slack and a lot of
ways. Rob Font, powerful rob font,
he's a Markdale grottos student.
Very talented guy and they also figured
out giving you the fights that you want
to say. Yup. Let's just give
you the fights. Don't make
it wait five years, like,
which we did with uh, uh, Tyson
Holyfield just put the fight together.
Make it happen. You don't have 10
different promoters working on it. Yeah.
It's hard to do that with
boxing, you know? Sure. I mean,
this Canelo a Gennady Golovkin fight.
This is a unification middleweight
title fight. Let's go to her right now.
It's uh, it's very fucking hard
to get these things to pull off.
Okay.
It's all the behind the scenes people.
Yeah.
Back thing is not working.
Hey, real quick. All right. You
think the bathroom is saved now?
I gave it the mandatory hour. Yeah.
That's a good hour. All right.
Let me try to find this. Jamie. What
did, where am I supposed to point?
This fucking thing? That
side. Okay. Now it's working
big fight for branch.
Huge dude that they
give him Luke Rockhold.
It's kind of crazy.
Is this his first fight in the UFC?
No. No. He used to be in the
UFC a while back and then,
um, I guess I'm going to have to keep
doing that. So to 19 button or something.
Yeah, it's not working. Um,
one 23 maybe. Okay. Hang on a sec.
This is the most boring part of the
podcast ever. What did you just ask me?
David Branch. He fought, I'm
Gerald Harris way back in the day.
Gets slammed and code.
This is like his first fight in the UFC.
He was in a,
Gerald Harris has guard and he
slammed him and knocked him out cold.
So it was a good fight up until
that moment. But he was in,
his guard is trying to his guard
and he got just body slam and
got knocked out from it. Yeah,
he got picked up in the guard like a Rona
rampage. Gerald Harris a stud. He um,
he didn't get picked up that high.
It wasn't like that.
That's the craziest shit of all
time cause that wasn't the guard.
That was a trial bridge.
Think of that. Crazy.
Extra higher. Ooh, that's terrifying.
That's the most terrifying slam of all
times. We watched that the other day.
He did? Yeah. We watched the head.
The head collide as he slammed into
the ground and you see Rampage's head
smashing der Rhona's head dude.
Nobody could spell rampage.
Slam people. All right folks, so
Gennady Golovkin just walked out.
I got all those belts.
Motherfuckers. A lot of belts.
Like a 23 or 24 first round knockout
streak to be something something
preposterous. Not Cruiser
checking account. They're
bull champions. Not Heavier.
The well Gennady Golovkin it's been
fighting at a heavier weight class and a
Canelo fought Floyd Mayweather I think
at one 52 and I think earlier in his
career he fought lighter than
that, I believe. Early way
earlier too though. Fans?
Yes. He was a young guy. When you were,
when you went pro like real young. What?
What's that? He had 23 straight
chaos in the first round.
Gennady Golovkin did, is that what
you're saying? Yeah, 23 straight chaos.
But then he went to, I don't think they
were on the first day. They weren't. No.
Okay.
First.
I'm just adding to his legend for no
reason and how it's making sure most of
them, he would break guys down over
fight all the hype and the Promo.
How it blew him up. He's at like from
that fight. He's like a national hero.
Couldn't hello? Kayla was
already a national hero. Not
Quite as big as he is now.
Yeah.
I guess the main with if I made a big,
but when it just beat the shit out of
Julio Cesar Chavez Jr. That's terrible.
Terrible fight. That
was sad to watch. Yeah.
My mom didn't know who Canelo was
before that. Mayweather fight.
Now she worships him.
I don't love the daddy that it'd be
honest with you as Mexican as it gets.
Isn't it sad to watch a guy like Julio
Cesar Chavez Jr fight a guy like Canelo?
Like you could tell one of them,
oh dude,
this is supposed to be the ones in the
family business. He's not that good.
You get knocked out just now.
You got to heat up that.
He went into a defensive shell.
He just stopped firing back at all.
It was just getting tooled on,
you know,
he reminded me of the kid
and the bad news bears.
Remember the kid when he had you holding
the ball and he's so pissed off at his
father and his father slapped him in the
face and he won't throw the ball home.
That's what he reminded me of jargon.
That fight just like fucking just
kind of stand there letting it happen.
It was hard to watch man. I was like,
this kid doesn't need to be doing this.
Like he doesn't really want to do it.
Didn't it seem like he
didn't want to fight? Yeah,
he definitely didn't want to fight
the head like a panic attack. No.
I just think you realized that there
was just a level of commitment the canal
possesses that he just
doesn't and he knew it in the,
there's like tells in their interviews
like Max Kellerman does a very nice
interview when he sits down with two
fighters and he sits in between of him.
He asked some questions
and Alaskan questions and they have this
like translate thing back and forth.
But you could see like psychologically
Canelo had a big advantage over him.
You know, Canelo was just saying,
look, you know, his, his fight career,
it's been a disgrace. I fought
the best of the best. And uh, he,
his, you know, his father was amazing and
it was an incredible world champion, but,
uh, he's just never lived up to the
hype and you could see like, you know,
he was like, well, we'll know. Yeah, it's
not going on back. I'm going to know.
That's a very poor comeback.
Was He good though?
Was he like before Canelo
he's always been good.
He's always been a fighter. No, he's,
he's, he's lost to some fighters,
like maybe one or two.
I can't remember how many people,
he's one of the best. He's just, and
he just can't, he can't get that belt.
He was better I think a few years ago,
but he was always been,
he's always been a very good fighter.
Like he's not a bad fighter. Like Julio,
Cesar Chavez, Jr knows how to fight for
sure. He's just not at this guy's level.
But do you think it's because
like their fathers are both, well,
I'm thinking about Marvis Frazier
to or your guys whose fathers,
when you grow up with boxing money,
it's a little harder to be motivated
then kind of like that for sure.
You don't have that kind of confidence,
you know, that kind of means streak.
It's not a coincidence that so many
of these guys grow up in impoverished
situations. But here's the thing,
Jon Jones I don't think grew up in,
I mean his family is still together.
I think he had a comfortable financial
childhood. I might be wrong about that,
but I mean his family
is all together so it's,
it's, it doesn't like some guys
are just better at it. Yeah.
But I think there's is
much more the other way.
Then there are guys who
grew up comfortably. There's
some like bill and Bam,
they still lay in bed.
They said grew up pretty comfortable and
wealthy and was still like the biggest
animal on the cool.
Totally happen.
You could have a kid that has
all the money in the world,
but they just have some psychotic drive
where they just want to be the best at
something. They want to prove
they're not pussies. Let me even get,
it could be that or it could just be,
there's people that just
really love testing themselves.
They just really love competing and they
get, you get a few steps ahead, right?
Like you,
you do it for a little bit and then you
really start getting into it and then
you get into it more and then it becomes,
you come to your favorite thing to do,
becomes your identity.
Like even if you grew up with money,
you could still become
obsessed with something. Sure.
And if you could come obsessed by being
the best at anything, it's possible.
It's just not as likely. It's way more
likely when it's a poor kid, they grow up,
you know,
with a sense of urgency.
He grow up with a like this
knowledge in your head that hey man,
it might not always be okay.
Like there could be a real bad time.
And a lot of times your motive for going
after it is different too because you,
you really do remember what it's
like to have absolutely nothing.
So your motive is to avoid that. Again,
it's that, that's a very powerful thing.
It is a very powerful thing and
you can't fake that by like boxing.
It's too much shit in the ring.
There's just too much business happening
and look at all these people and it's
very unnecessary as 30 people in it Kinda,
it's Kinda like that in music too because
the thought is that you have to grow
up and not in the same kind of,
you know,
impoverished or like just a serious,
a broken family,
lack of love. But then you have
Chris Martins, singer from cold play.
He breaks the mold, like
Valedictorian, you know,
brought up with money and a just
a happy lot. You know, he's just,
it's just one like make them, yeah,
exactly. Bayless that's there. By the way,
the referee, I think who was
shitting on Conor and Floyd fighting,
who'd want to see that? It's two
different sports. Kenny Bayless.
I'm pretty sure that's the ref that they,
that they did not want. Oh, that's funny.
Well, you know, a lot of boxing
people want, like I was saying before,
they want to defend boxing. They want,
you know, they want to be on team boxing.
And honestly,
I played apart that a little bit when
I had this thing with Lou Dibella very
good in that, by the way. Well,
it felt like it was pretty easy.
It wasn't making very good argument.
It's terrible argument. The problem,
the other problem is, I mean, you know,
if I really went to war with somebody,
I said, yeah, I got that guy. It was
a terrible argument. And I'm a fan,
like does the dump truck, I'm a fan
of boxing and I probably know a lot.
I bet if he and I sat down and we just
start talking about classic fights,
Hagler Hearns you know, sugar
ray Leonard, Roberta it around,
like he would realize like really quick,
I'm a legit boxing fan.
I fuckin love boxing. How many rounds did
Hagler Hearns go was at three. Yes. Yes.
What did you draw with Third
Hagler? Oh, I don't know.
He had that fight with Mayweather though,
where Mayweather just Mayweather
did a genius thing. First of all,
I made him cut a lot of weight and him
get down to one 52 drained him up a
little bit and then you know,
he caught him before he reached
the level that he's at now.
Like when he fought Amir Khan America,
he fucked Amir Khan up dude with
a haymaker of her right hand.
And you know when you, when he landed
that bomb and put Amir Khan to sleep,
you've got to go. Okay, this
is a guy that's now at the
fucking peak of his game.
So when he fought Mayweather,
Mayweather caught him right when he
was getting into it. You Know Ryan,
when he was coming up and that may where
the fight I think took them over the
top.
When you fight a guy that's a slick
and it's talented fucking fast and the
timing that may whether has, and you
realize like there's levels to this thing.
It's the Lufkin fighting it
the way he normally five.
Oh yeah, this is his weight,
man. He's the king. This guy's a beast.
I know the guys behind him
look exactly like him too.
The good thing about this fight is
what's interesting is Gooden. Golovkin.
Some experts believe that he might be
slipping slightly and Canelo is coming up.
And the idea is that a year ago go,
Lufkin would've fucked Canelo up.
This is what a lot of people believe,
but now Canelo was better and Golovkin
might have faded a little bit.
What's the age difference? I think
Lufkin is, he's older for sure,
but I think he's 35 see if you
could find that young. Jamie.
I want to say he's 35 or 36 yeah.
Oh,
he's still Lufkin is what?
34 I think he's coming Thursday 35
okay. Yeah, so that's like the law is if,
unless he's Jewson that's the last
of the squeeze. Eight years. Yeah.
When you're around.
No,
but I mean when you're around 35 like
that's when the decline happens to almost
everybody. Right? 36 it's
slips. 37 slips more. 39 40.
Very rarely see a 40 year old champion
that's not on the sauce only now.
That's why Randy coture was
such an amazing, I mean,
that's really what Bernard Hopkins
was the most impressed Jesus.
Yet he went into his fifties and he still
was out boxing worldclass fighters and
drop in them. You know, I mean
he got fucked up by Joe Smith,
but Joe Smith is a monster. The final
thought we get knocked to the rain.
How scary. How old is he now? 52 or
53. And he was 50 when he last thought.
If he was 51 or 52 in his brain,
his Pr, I've interviewed him.
He's perfectly coherent. Like
there's the, I don't know how he,
here we go round one, ladies and
gentlemen. Eddie Bravo prediction.
I'm going to go with the Mexican too.
You got to go with your people.
I understand. Um, Norton I got
to go with fuck Lufkin have to.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I feel like either one of these
motherfuckers could shock the orthotics.
Don considered white. Uh, well,
yeah, I mean it's definitely white.
If you go to a black neighborhood
and try to say the n word. Yeah.
That's all you need to know
is are you white? Well,
can you get away with being in a black
neighborhood and using the n word or that
type of credibility or do not.
If you're Wesley snipes dark,
you can get away with using it
anywhere in the world, right? Sure.
So Canelo's white Canelo was actually
Mexican, but he's got red fucking hair.
It's crazy.
It's like holes.
Kazakhstan is considered white then why
wouldn't Canelo be considered white?
But he is white for sure.
I mean he's rushing or you know,
part of the former Soviet Soviet Union,
China and it's right by China. Well,
you know, a lot of these
people have Mongolian and them.
A lot of these people there, well
no, it's like an Asian, but it's um,
that's gangs con. I mean
Gingiss con, they, I think
they said some insane number,
like 5% of all the men in Asia or all
the people in Asia have gang is cons.
Jeans. Jesus is, he's jumping
loads all over the place.
Everybody and killed everyone
killed. Like, you know,
they don't even know how many millions,
but somewhere between 20 and 70 million
people died directly by his hand.
You and his daughter was named.
Which one? Shaka chocolate cones
a fee.
I met her on a falafel place in New York,
being Godfrey chased her down
the street and ran it by me.
God love comes fucking this one
in 200 of the whole population.
The world is directly
descended from Gaviscon.
Look at that. Oh my God.
What years was he a,
was he alive because he was like the
$1,200 a hundred percent of China.
Yeah. Oh Dude, this is a great fight. Huh?
Golovkin just double
jab them.
Ooh,
that's a strong jab.
That might be a big factor.
He's used that jab before on guys and
shocked him and out Jay outboxed him.
Uh,
Lemieux he did that with,
he came out and started popping him
with the jab and a lot of people didn't
expect that he can. Outbox is shit
out of people. He caught him. Yeah.
Oh yeah. Those are blocked though.
Those nothing's happening there.
Those are getting blocked.
The Jab is what you got to keep an eye on.
C in order counter,
right hand of Canelo
triple G. Yeah, he is bigger. He's
taller. We'll see how that keeps landing.
His face is fucked up
and it's the first round.
Okay.
He's getting lit up
with that straight jab.
He's shaking the attitude.
He shaded a lot. Well,
he gets angry at people and starts
talking shit to him and he puts his hands
down and lets them punch him in the face.
When he was breaking this one dude down,
as he was breaking him down,
he put his hands down and started
walking towards them and letting the guy
punched him. Just moving his hands
slightly and then fucking digs in on him.
He's a mean guy man. How blocking. Yeah,
he's seen ecology that amazing though.
When you drop your hands,
a lot of times guys won't react
immediately convinced as a school yard
humiliation of a guy doing
that and you missing.
It's really weird to watch professional
fighters not always just go right in and
when someone's hands are down.
Let me help you out with that.
There's also a reason
when you drop your hands,
you don't know where the punches are
coming from. It's a different thing.
Like it's very tricky.
When someone drops their hands,
you have to be very careful because
things can come from anywhere.
It's one of the reasons why
Tommy Hearns when he jabbed,
he kept his hand down here
and pop it up in your face.
It's do you don't see it as much.
You don't see it. It's quick.
If someone's standing right here and you
see this and you see that you see the
hands a little bit more there, it's a
traditional pattern that you understand.
When someone has their hands
down low and they start moving,
their head shift can come
wild from all over the place.
How many cards has a triple g headline?
Only a few.
He's been mostly like an HBO
fighter be but because his,
his paper views didn't sell well.
Like one of them only Gennady
Golovkin I forget it. We fought,
but he was like 150,000 buys.
It's unfortunate because he's fucking
look marvelous in there. I mean,
his name is Gus guys. He beat Kell
Brook, Kell Brooks. Very good.
And he broke him down. Yeah, no,
he's a black guy from England.
Really bad ass world
champion at a lighter weight.
He was world champion I believe
at welterweight and it came up.
Oh look at this Kennel. I don't like
all that wasted energy right there.
A little too much emotion. He, I mean
he liked rooster them, got behind them.
That's a lot of energy.
Just blew there.
And I find a lot too during
in Connor met with a lot.
I think that was different though.
You know,
these guys are way more identical
in terms of skill and career,
but I'm seeing Golovkin get the better.
These exchanges,
they just showed him both jab at
each other at the same time. Stiff,
you know,
the,
the age could really be a factor.
You know?
Canelo has never really taken a beating.
He only had one fight that he lost and
that was that fight with Mayweather.
And he really didn't get beat up in
that fight. He just got out boxed.
Is that a decision? Yeah. Unanimous. Clear
Mayweather just showed him what's up.
But he didn't knock him out.
You know what I mean?
It's like Canelo's beating the fuck
out of some really good fighters.
He's super dangerous puncher and Golovkin
has been a way more wars than canal
Canelo has. Canelo has figured out a way
to avoid wars and just put it on people.
It's just fucking really
good, man. This is for boxing.
This is like as good as it gets
because Canelo is still getting better,
you know? Ooh, that's a sweet jab. I mean,
he's 27 now and this fight is gonna
make them better too. You know,
he's only 27 Golovkin.
If canal managed to Kale him
and he's 35 could be the end,
you know?
Or at least the beginning of the end.
He's not 25 but Canelo almost is.
And part of the appeal is that he's 37
and now there's something that undefeated
firelight, those three g's on his
belt. That's it. That's dope. Well,
he's undefeated for a reason, man. He's a
fucking master. Gucci should sponsor him.
Nah, it's all right. Just
like we want to have your gs
or the free masons. Just the other
one put over your day. Just put,
put our gs up top and then your g over
the Dick who bloat the watch company
sponsored his Dick. Look, isn't that
funny that people care about that? Like,
yeah,
like that the UFC WWE like didn't
want that lot of people felt,
felt like you guys see too much of that
on boxer shorts. It bothers them. Like,
I don't even notice it.
Okay.
I didn't even help with sales.
Or does it just get into your psyche?
You don't even realize it's in there?
It's a good question.
I remember back in the day, um, cigarette
companies used to sponsor fighters.
Like boxers used to have cigarette
companies and their shorts.
Forget who did that. You know what
it might've been Mayorga did. Ooh,
fuck.
Had a cigarette company sponsored them.
Cigarette company sponsored boxers give
ever see the old way they would sponsors
cartoons and they would
show Fred smokey a Winston.
Like they would have like fucking
a, what's that? I hate that show.
The Flintstones. Do you hate the
font style? It makes me sick.
The spies from why? I don't
know. I just always hated them.
Why? It's a weird one.
I'm not a big cartoon guy,
but that one I particularly at
that left hook the body son. Ooh,
boom. Good love came with
a crisp straight, right.
This is good as it gets for boxing man.
It really is.
You know you got a guy and Golovkin
undefeated 35 and now that blast and
everybody wanting that big fight
and then kill Navajo Alvarez.
This proud superstar steps up.
Wants this fight and just stay the fight.
They both call each other out.
They both want, I mean canal is always
said he wanted to fight the very best.
He's bleeding glove.
It looks like he's
looking at another one behind
it. Wow. God Damn. Go off gins.
Good God damn. He's good.
He landed some shots there,
man.
Whew.
That was an interesting combination
the way through the left hook and then
through it again. It's surprising. Left
Hook. The second left took in particular,
he's forcing this kid to box with them.
I mean the slug with him.
That's his style of fight.
Canelo is a really good counter striker
and what's what's going on here now it's
Golovkin is just really coming to him
and Canelo's this is like a perfect fight
in a lot of ways. This is like
the kind of fight you would hope.
But this Canelo want to stand
there with him and trade punches.
Well he wants to counter strike but it
mean glove is going to come towards him.
So he has his opportunities.
I mean it's,
it's a brilliant fight
like as far as like what,
you know stylistically
it's perfect. Has, uh,
has glock could ever even really been
in trouble in a fight? Not really.
He's been punched a lot though. Never
been dropped? No, I don't believe so.
I've never even seen him like stunned.
He did have a really good
fight in his last fight.
Can you put Golovkin record up
so I can remember homeboy's name.
He's had a couple of very
good fights where, you know,
people are coming to him
very, you know, enthusiastic.
Last Friday for his Sherman was
less, I don't, I Daniel j Dash Jacob.
Daniel Jacobs is the one that's the,
that guy that was a really close fight.
Awesome,
awesome fight.
But it was unanimous decision for Gennady
Golovkin but Daniel Jacobs is fucking
for real white guy, black guy.
He's super good. So it was like,
it was a big win and you know,
everybody could tell watching the fight
that Jacobs is super legit. I mean,
we already knew it coming in,
but so even though he did knock 'em out,
it's still,
he's still one damn Canelo's fierce.
Fierce. Both guys are fierce. Oh, that
left hook to the body. What? Hello?
They're both so good man.
Oh that EPR cut.
Damn. See. And then the other thing,
you've got to think of his age man.
The reality of age 35 with some wars
behind them versus 27 with really no wars.
Just smashing a lot of people.
Okay.
Really good trainers. When the
same trainer, since he was a kid,
what he's showing me, Jamie, what's
going on? Is that the UFC, oh my God,
you're amazing.
How can we can't put it on that TV.
Oh,
we got to fix that.
Who are these guys fighting
arm triangle.
Oh, Craig Gillespie. Jason Jaws.
Okay,
well folks, we are, we should
be on Twitter at the same time.
We should be periscoping.
Yeah.
Hmm.
I don't use any of those live. I want you
to a while ago on Facebook. I just, yeah,
I know it's supposed to help,
but I just can't do it. Yeah,
just it's sometimes it's too much.
He keeps going back to the arm triangle.
He lost it last time you went back to now.
Oh No.
He lost it against like he's
going to under jack it again.
You go right back to it. Easy on us. He
goes right back to it. Look at this shit.
You could tell.
You know.
I knew he was going to do it cause
he's so good at it and at it.
There's no way he's going to,
he's going to wear him out.
He's got to keep them in the
chopping block right there.
He's got to not try to finish them.
Just keep them on the chopping block.
What do you think of that way of
defending? That was a nice way Dan,
when you grab the escrow.
No, that's the thing.
You've done doing it the way he's
doing it. Oh, he's out. He's gone.
It's over tap. What was that? What it
a ghost. Angeles finished off by Neil.
Maggie with uh, yes he did smushed
them round four. Here we go.
This is to add having the UFC
play here too. That was dude.
You turn it on at the perfect
time because you don't,
you rarely see an under Jack
Battle in the UFC like that battle.
He tried it three different times. You
rarely see that. You don't ever see that.
That's Greg or Gillespie. He's a
fucking beast man. Greg Ward Gillespie.
Yeah,
it's a bad mother fucker right there.
He's at least I have some
good mount strategies. He
wasn't trying to beat him up.
He was trying to show shots in the body.
Oh Man.
Can Ella just hit him with a hard
left hook to the body and go,
let's see if they show. These guys
are going at it. Man. This is crazy.
This is a fucking warm man.
I mean you like,
we were watching like an all time
classic boxing war right now.
Ooh. Maybe that jab that hit him. It looks
like I missed him. Did I hit him? Huh?
Popped him fast.
Ooh
hmm.
Eddie Bravo. Would you be watching
this if it wasn't for us? Yes,
because he's Mexican. Ah. Did you
know it was gonna Start at eight?
They always start around eight,
eight 30. We'll hold the money.
Eventually they started like nine. They
decided to start this one early. Okay.
Just to make sure that people in the
east coast, Ooh. Golovkin with that Jab.
You think that was the thinking to like,
let's make sure people in New York and
Jersey and Florida can order this for
sure. That's what I'm, oh dude.
Oo, this is distractible Shit.
All right. That's a good idea first. But
um, he just did that thing by the way. He
dropped his arms a little bit too. Yeah.
It's boxing them up. He shook his head
as soon as they shake their head. No,
that means yes. Yeah. Does that ever
mean guy isn't hurt when he shakes?
Because why would you tell him you
didn't hurt? You're not hurt. Well,
it does kind of look, he ain't got
shit. You could say that a guys,
but the problem is when someone actually
hits you and really dangs you and then
you do it like never. Well,
maybe the Noah's saying, no,
you didn't knock me down.
Not this time. Maybe that's what he
means, baby. It doesn't seem like it.
Almost mostly what? It seems like that
didn't hurt. Like that ain't shit.
You didn't get me. No one ever
says he didn't knock me down. Yeah.
Except in like a Jake lamata movie.
That was exactly it.
Very close up on the rings
trying to Fucking Ooh,
Jab and that counter right together.
These guys are so well matched. Ooh,
look at that tight left hook by
triple g. He's hurt triple gene. No.
Canella you think so?
What makes you say that?
Because it keeps going
backwards into the ropes
body shot that you were talking
about. Right when that landed, he was,
he looked at his eyes, he went, oh shit.
You might be right. Might be right.
I keep forgetting. These are
three men around and know
they're weird, right? Yeah.
You get into it, you're
like, I'll fuck the bell.
You know what's interesting about that?
It's easier to go five minutes boxing
than it is to go three minutes of
wrestling.
You have the shoe fc is like five
minute rounds and boxing is three minute
rounds,
so they just got used to it.
But one thing though is if
you give a short around,
there is a good argument
for a shorter round.
That argument is guys can go faster and
harder in three minutes then they can
and five cause they have to
conserve themselves. Right.
Do you feel like boxing over the last year
is making a comeback or not? For sure,
but I think boxing isn't a
good place. Right? It's making
a little comeback. Yeah,
and it might have something to do with
the fact that there's a rivalry going on
between UFC and boxing. Like
what sport is better? Yeah.
I think it's bringing more attention
to boxing. You know, by the UFC fans,
they're paying attention a boxing
because there's this debate.
Maybe it's a good idea.
We'll could argument maybe
the UFC and boxing up. Well,
it's also boxing in a
real good place right now.
There's so many good fighters
Chanko I mean these two gentlemen,
right? You really do a three
minute round you have to say,
I mean with Jujitsu and all that,
but I was thinking is maybe a
five minute round a box here.
It'd be kind of interesting, but I
think they're doing it right, honestly,
because I think you know,
you could go hard and fast for three
minutes and maybe it will ensure a faster
pace for the majority of the fight.
Then if you made God's
fight five minute rounds,
how often did they get out of ten eight
rounds in boxing when guys get dropped
quite a bit,
it's pretty common.
It was uncommon for a long time and MMA,
but it's more common now.
While that was good head
movement there by Canelo,
that's either the rule changes, right?
Yeah. Canelo avoided most of that.
He's, he's good. Really good
defense there. His defense is tight.
Good movement. Ooh, that's a
good right hand of the body.
It's just like to get to this level.
So it's this,
what's exciting about this fight
is that to get to this level,
there's so much shit
you got to go through.
It's so rare that a guy comes
out this good, you know,
like there's so few of them and it's even
rare that you get two of them finally
fighting. Yeah. Like this. Who else?
Who are the top paper view boxers and
you're looking at it right now, man. This,
yeah. What flooded. Who
else? Voids are tired.
Manny Pacquiao is not drawing the
numbers he used to in his last fight,
he fought and he lost to like
a school teacher. You know,
his time is basically done. Where did
he go to fight? That was a Australia.
What about in heavyweight division?
No paper view there. Well,
Anthony Joshua was a huge star in London
and in England and probably in Europe
and the UK. Uh, in America. He's
a big star with boxing fans,
but sorta like how triple g's
a big star with boxing fans.
Canelo's a huge star with actual
Mexicans like across the board.
And maybe, uh, you could say that
about Anthony Joshua with England. I,
you know, I'm not in England.
Could very well be, oh,
look at that right hand over
the top. He said No. He said No.
Ah,
I dunno about that.
Boxing needs to do to,
to keep the upward. It's
just hard. It's just hard.
He got guys like Terrence Crawford.
He's a bad motherfucker.
He got Loma Chenko. You've,
you've got some good fighters.
You've got Andre Ward is one of the best
in the world. The UFC light or the, uh,
boxing light heavyweight champion who's
also the US gold medalist in boxing.
He's a beast. I think we got to do is
get people the fight that they want,
not make them wait for it for two years.
In three years.
That's easier said than done. It's what
helped the UFC. I think much of that.
And they're shaking the hands at
each other. Oh, this is crazy.
Canelo's weighing some shots.
He's throwing them hard. Mat. Oh.
[inaudible] glove glove gal out a
little bit. Maybe glove again. Glow.
How'd he say it? Come on off.
Kin Calavo again. Colif kin. Ooh,
this is a good fight. Oh, dropped
his hands. You got popular jam.
Cologne in the back of his pants
be June by June or pianos. Yeah,
that's a cologne.
This guy Norman used to wear it in a
department store I worked in and he was
arrested for stealing.
He smelled good.
Oh, that's hilarious. This
smells. Yeah, he smelled great.
I was like, what is that?
He's like, by June, people are weird
with their fucking colognes, right? Yeah.
I have a whole fucking shelf. All
of them to, yeah. Yeah. I just,
I don't know why I liked them until the
compensation I think I used to wear and
your car. Oh God. Yeah. It was
great. That was like fucking,
there was like Guido stuff and like,
like 1988 1990 he thought he
had where it get laid. Yeah.
Girls like CEO's. Yeah. Like it.
For some reason they love it because I
get you got to where it got away with
their like, I don't like a girl to wear
perfume at all. Like I really don't like,
I like natural.
I like the fruity smelling like a,
the the sweet look at this perfumes.
Ooh,
not the ground up his son.
Okay.
Yeah. No, I don't like any of them. I
wanted it to smell like a fucking gorilla.
Hello? Canelo shook his head, but that,
that was a bomb that he got hit with it.
Grazed them.
It's weird. Male perfume. It's weird
that we accept that, you know. Oh,
look at that right hand. Damn
Dude. The Lumpkins porn it on. Oh,
Golovkin is landing some shots,
man. It's only the sixth round.
This is just the six round.
I don't know.
Oh,
Canelo's was fired back.
That's a hard shot to the body. You heard
him to the body. He heard him to live.
Oh, and he went back to it. Golovkin
is in trouble. He's hurt to the body.
He knows it. Yeah, man. He does know it.
He hit him with a right
hand and he's landing.
Oh Shit.
What a turn around.
Okay.
It's so hard to recover from that liver
shot too. You've got to keep moving,
but you're diminished. You've
been hitting the liver. Jim,
I know you've had a lot of guy's
leg kick you and choke you.
I don't think anyone's ever
purposely punched me in the liver.
I've had a lot of things done.
They're all in pleasant,
but they say that's a pretty bad one.
It's horrible and to fact I,
I'm pretty sure that happened just now.
Gennady Golovkin and you could
barely tell watching him fight. Ooh,
get hit in the chest.
They're little high.
Who's a good vibe? It's
so back and forth. Yeah.
I punched the guy in the liver and
the fourth grade didn't do shit. Yeah,
you got to work on new techniques.
On
the fourth grade means you were nine.
How you should actually hit the liver.
Totally, Bro. Crushed it.
It's a horrible thing to kick.
Well, people, do you think it's a bit of
liver need? Deliver might be the worst.
That's one of the worst need to deliver.
As horrifying as a Rhonda
Rousey was so good at that.
She would tie girls up in that judo
clinch and then just need the fuck out of
their body was ruthless because she was
so good at the like upper body control.
She could tie you up so well from Judah.
Oh God.
He Columbia with the
right hand of the body.
She would just get ahold of girls and
then she started fucking Newcome with
knees to the body.
She did that to Sara Mcmann.
God Damn, this is good. Yeah.
This is really so tense, right?
I can't think it happened here. Fortunes
can change the drop of a hat. Okay.
Whew. Canelo is firing them. Huh?
44 49 to 44 power punches.
God dammit. That is so insane.
Favor of Golovkin.
Is Rhonda coming back you think?
I don't think she's going to wrestling.
I think it's over. Yeah, I think so.
I don't think she wants to do it anymore.
You know,
for whatever reason you could break that
down psychologically all day. You know,
Matt Serra had a great line
that, uh, I never forgot.
He said a long ago
that everybody likes to be the hammer.
Oh yeah.
But nobody wants to be the nail.
Yeah. If you, if you're the nail,
can you come back?
Okay.
Yeah.
And there's always going to be fighters
out there that you can't take down.
You're going to be forced to stand.
Sure.
And the level of striking right now
with the girls is at an all time high.
And if you ain't top of on top of your
striking, even if you get really good,
it's still Russian roulette.
These girls are,
are many like chef
Chenko and Amanda Nunez.
So Dane, was he going to do, if you can't
take the person down, you have to strike.
And then it becomes a kickboxing battle.
How good is your kickbox kickboxing
battle where you hope and pray that
something goes wrong and you get it
to the ground. And you know what?
Rhonda has good striking.
It's not terrible,
but even if it was great,
there's a lot of great strikers out there.
So at the end of the day you're going
to be forced to when a kickboxing
tournament at the very top,
it's going to be very hard.
She didn't wrestle her whole life.
She's doing judo at an Olympic level.
She has great takedowns. She was able
to rag doll most of her opponents,
but right now man,
it's going to be very hard for her
to take these girls down right now.
She's going to be forced to strike.
So then it becomes a, you know,
she could win some,
she could lose some.
How many people did she beat that Stryker
is as good as Holly Holm? Ronda Nunez?
None.
No.
None of them were as good as her.
The only one who was closest cats and
Ghana and she caught cat really linearly.
First round, right? Yeah. With an arm bar.
Cat just charged data and got caught in
an arm bar. Yeah. I think Rhonda said,
I think you just catt
deserved better that like she,
she knew that that was
just a kind of a fluke.
You know what cat said that
the reason why she charged out,
I like that it's cause like she took a
furious beating and that Amanda Nunez
fight.
She won the fight but she got fucked up
and that first round like real bad and
she was like, I didn't want to
go through that again. She goes,
I just want to charge at
her and get ahold of her.
Okay.
Imagine of Ronda Rousey decided to on
the girl she couldn't throw or take down.
Plan B is that flying guard pool.
She had the guard for it.
She has an amazing guard,
amazing arm bar from the guard.
Her plan should have been, in my
opinion, to get the fight to the ground,
try to be on top, try to use
your Jido. If that didn't work,
we have to go to Poland.
Guard.
Other option with someone like Amanda
Nunez is that's not going to happen.
You don't think she didn't pull guard on
the [inaudible] as you know on anything,
you're going to get eaten up and punches.
When he tried to get close,
Amanda's got some long got us arms. In
order to pull guard, you've got, uh,
you got to pull off a legit shot to get
them to react, to get them to sprawl.
And that's when you pull guard.
When you're under him and they
sprawl you time and perfect. It's a,
it's a technique.
It's just like a takedown.
Was that the biggest problem
of Rhonda, Rhonda? This game?
Your game was all right.
The guards. Amazing. Just like in
that fight with that Sergio Mri,
he was on his back hurt and,
and his opponent wouldn't
get on top of this.
Let's pay attention to this cause
some shit is happening here.
Golovkin cracked him.
We're,
we're still gonna be able to watch the
Rockhold fight to ou. So exciting. Yeah.
It's only eight 30. This fights nuts, man.
Okay.
He's really impressive. Off the ropes
to Golovkin. I know Alvarez. Oh yeah.
Well he's impressive. Everywhere
they bolt are. I mean,
these are two legit world champions.
That's why this is so exciting.
I haven't seen it off a glove down
on the ropes much at all this fight
because he's been taking it to Canelo
and that's his style and when that's
what's so interesting about this setup
is that everybody knew that Canelo's a
really good counter puncher.
Scott. Real good timing.
He just seems a bit too small.
Canelo yeah,
well that Chad really there's
a size difference man.
There's definitely a size
difference but he's thick, you know?
I just think frame wise,
I think you're right.
But I think the money is where he's at.
You know? I mean I think this fight,
he's a big,
big money fight.
Did I don't know how many good fights
there are for him at 54 what big names
there are. I think he struggles
to make that weight too.
Who Glove given no Canelo I think he
struggles even to make six day and this is
what this is 60 I think one 54 is a real
struggle for him because that's what
may, whether got them down to one
52 mainly with, it's so smart,
like just lose a little bit more weight.
We'll talk a little more way
this little hallway. And uh,
the thing about Connor, like what,
what he did to Connor for a smart too,
which was just make them fight, make
them work, get him, get him tired,
and then start putting it to him to
start piling it up, wiring them out,
piling up, wearing them out. And when you
saw me with her unloading, you're like,
oh yeah, that's right. Yeah. He's
fucking Floyd Mayweather. He's one of,
if not the best box or hour. And Connor
did catch them with a couple of things.
Ooh, look at that. Jab
Son. Oh No. Hbo Paper.
You went blank for a student there.
They all panicked. Can Imagine.
Let's see.
What do you think here?
Definitely losing the
rounds, but he, well,
he's putting up a good fight and
I was losing. Oh yeah, yeah. He's,
he's got like 19 more head
shots for a gloved hand. Yeah.
They have Golovkin ahead. Three to s
three, right? Three point 65 to 68.
But the thing is, it looks like a
Lufkin is trying to put him away.
He's not just content to beat him.
He's putting massive pressure on him here,
you know,
I mean,
and you saw canela take a big deep breath
and as we get into the eight, nine,
10 1112 Canelo fades a little.
He fades a little,
he throws hard power shots and I know he
keeps working hard on his conditioning
and he works harder than anybody, but
it's just, that style is exhausting. Well,
plus Galafi wants to put him away because
he hears people talking about his age
too. I mean, you know, everyone is
saying is he, does he have it anymore?
It's just slowing down. Yeah. That's
a consensus. Oh, shots to the body.
Good shots of the body
by Canelo.
Well,
he might've heard him again.
He might have heard him again to the body.
Go Africans not firing at UPMC.
Ooh,
it's catching his breath. Yeah, you
got it. Rip to the body due to food.
This is such a good fight. This fight.
If every boxing match was like this,
boxing would be huge. The thing
is genius about Mayweather. He's,
he managed to never be in one of these.
Yeah, he really did avoid everything.
Avoided it. All of it.
He never got beat up.
He'll get hit clean like seven times,
eight times his whole career.
He's made the most money made way
more than anybody else combined.
Like double or triple at
least, right? Oh yeah.
And to me he's for sure the
number one money maker ever.
Oh, without a doubt. Yeah.
Close it. Let's put them
into a billionaire, a
category in the neighborhood,
you know, who knows exactly
what the deal is and, but dude,
they got 6.25 something
million paper views.
That's insane. I wonder what he's
saving up for. I wonder what he wants.
And he doesn't quite have enough
modeling is balling out of control.
Does he owe taxes too?
I think he owes money.
He owed a little bit before this fight,
but by basketball teams.
Oh look at that upper
cut. The big thing is, um,
him not going too crazy and spending
it on and blowing it all he does.
He doesn't seem like the, I think they
have one more fight by mansions and shit.
All sorts of Rolls Royces. But, well,
you know, when he got quality cars,
he was like way deep in the
TAC. Oh yeah. Nice Opera Cup.
I can know.
He was definitely like a big tax trouble
before we got bailed out with a fight
in the past. Do you think they rematch? I
think they rematch. They should. Why not?
I think Connor would have to beat somebody
good in a boxing match and he would
also have to have a real training camp,
I think.
I think boxing's over for
Connor. Oh, I don't think so.
That is one more fight like that.
It gives, people will buy it.
That just kind of went to the 10th round.
He got fatigued.
It there's still a motive for people
to buy it. Yeah. I mean, look, he,
he went the very first fight
against the greatest hour.
There's so many lights to bag. You're
right. Yeah, you're right. You're right.
There's that too. But the thing
is if there's a legit big fight,
like say if Canelo Alvarez steps up
and says that he wants to fight Conor
Mcgregor, I don't think Conor, I'll do it.
He might realize,
I think Connor made me realize,
you've got to specialize.
Well actually you can't do both.
Especially the difference
between Canelo and Floyd.
Floyd was just a brilliant boxer.
Canelo is a murderous puncher and
he'll fuck you up, he'll hurt you.
There's also a promotional difference
to Kyron. Floyd are pretty much they,
they're very similar guys and they
both understood what they were doing
promotion wise.
I don't know if Canelo is that God,
while he's not going to promote
it that way, but he's got,
oh look at that upper cut.
That's his genius. It's,
he's got the support of the American
people does love Lufkin vs Mcgregor.
Okay.
Ooh, look at that. Africa. I, um, I don't
know if Mcgregor would take that fight.
No, that sounded good. Fight
for him either. Neither.
Canelo Orga Lufkin's a good fight for him.
It's a terrible fight for him.
Those guys are different.
They're, they're, they're,
they're this, you know, like,
look at what,
the way these guys fight,
especially with this is how
go Lufkin fights every fight
I bring, big drama show.
That's what he calls it.
Dude.
I mean, this is one of those fights
were going to be looking back on Sunday.
Look at those shots of the boss.
This is one of those fights that
we're going to look back on and go,
you remember when we watched that
fucking fight? Holy Shit. Look at it.
He just shook his head on him. Golovkin
is putting tremendous pressure on him.
He's trying to break him.
Yeah.
He's keeping him against the
ropes for 80% of the fire.
It's not just that like it's a pace that
he's fighting and he's trying to make
them wither. He sees something.
You think he sees him Fetty yeah,
he sees him trying to catch some breaks.
He's still super dangerous,
but Golovkin catches.
He's seen Canelo trying to catch his
breath and that seat is splayed out on the
seat in between rounds. His feet were
all out. Yeah. See if I, if I know this,
and I don't know that much about boxing,
I know that Canelo has what people think
of as an endurance problem and it's not,
you know, it's not a big mystery.
He just kind of fades a little bit.
Who we just got tagged. He just kept
tagged. He might get fired. Oh my God,
that was bad. Or the big right hand.
Oof. It's not that he doesn't work hard,
it's just that his style is just so
explosive and he's got so much muscle that
he carries around.
That style requires you to be in fucking
sensational shape. Well it does. It does.
It mean anything that is a counter
puncher cause they're always getting hit
first. So you've got to take a little
bit more to, no, not necessarily.
His defense is outstanding.
Like look at that.
Look how good he ducked under that
right hand. His defense is amazing.
It's just like he's never been hit like
this before and not with a guy like a
Lufkin is just putting it to him.
He's been hit by a guy like Floyd who
just caught them with good clean scoring
shots. Snapped his head back a couple
of times, but nothing like that.
Like a mule kicking you in the face.
This is a different thing because
Golovkin is trying to break him.
He's not just trying to win.
He's putting himself in danger.
He's putting himself in danger
to prove that he's the best.
And that's a different thing.
That's a different kind of person with,
he's not making the kind of money that
these guys are making. He's hungry.
It's fuck. See that upper
cut. Ooh Baby. And again,
he's not making the kind of like
superstar money that he just saw Conor and
Floyd meg and the only way that he can
make it as to being big drama show.
And so he's just coming from for death
once again for this fight. Who knows is,
I think it's probably depending
upon the paper view. Sales. Yeah.
I literally have no scale for what
these guys make. I, I have no clue.
You were gonna make it a couple of
million elements. Millions. Canelo is
a superstar.
He's going to sell.
I mean he would sell fucking
a million paper views.
He was fighting the Uber
driver and I'm not joking.
Ooh,
Ooh.
So he's a bigger draw than GALACTICA.
Oh yeah.
And I was getting five g tripleG is
getting three. Nice. That was amazing.
He's 2 million more to know if you know
how famous he is. It makes sense. Yeah.
He's huge. Right? That guy
goes, Viva Mexico and every,
the fucking roof almost falls off.
Okay.
I'll tell you what, man,
Mexicans and Irish did.
They make you reconsider the idea of
patriotism. Very, very proud of people.
Like when you hear the Irish
people that were in town in Vegas,
when Connor was fighting,
you ever see that video of Mandalay bay,
the whole Mandalay bay? What's the
fight? Wasn't even there. Okay.
The whole Mandalay bay filled,
I mean to where you couldn't walk with
Irish people and they're all singing
together. Yeah. It was insane.
And that wasn't even where
the fight was being held.
We showed him at the garden outside
in November. It was fucking,
I was with Matt Serra was freezing outside
and these maniacs have short sleeve
shirts and tank tops.
Yeah.
Didn't we walk to the garden
together there today about coming,
leaving the guard? It was, it was
freezing that night. Would remember. Yeah,
that's right. There was protest in front
of Trump's apartment. Yeah, that's right.
How Fun was that? Oh, it was awesome.
We had a walk, little Jimmy, uh,
me and a cam and weren't you there young?
Jamie was Tony there to Brendan
mischief maker was there.
Look at that. Oof. Oof.
Oof.
God Damn. Look at those. That left to
the body in that right over the top.
Holy Shit.
What a fight this is.
But we had a walk because there were
so many people protesting Trump.
Oh, he's done. He's got hurt.
He got hurt. He stumbled.
Woo.
Yeah.
Canelo hit him with something. Oh,
look at that jab. Oh my goodness.
Oh, it again. Oh my God.
This isn't your fight back.
This is a fucking fight.
And this is the 10th round kids.
Oh my God. This is amazing. I've hardly
ever has to hold. Yeah, pull them apart.
Oh my God. No. These
guys are going for blood.
Golovkin is a fucking savage man.
Savage.
He's kind of like 82% Genghis Khan
blood. Right? If you've got a gas,
you're right. The rats are good point.
The Ref is not stepping in that much.
He hasn't had a chance. He just
no need to. This is a warm, yeah.
Especially the way Golovkin fights,
man. What a pace he puts on you.
You just don't get a chance to breathe.
He just on you like he stays in
a phone booth no matter what,
and there's no brakes. He pops a jab,
you step back, you're right back on.
You look at this,
he's just right back on him constantly
look at this pressure right hand.
But you've gotta understand
how terrifying this is.
You're fighting a guy like
this that doesn't get tired,
continues to push on you,
and like that's why Canelo
has to take some breaks here.
Then you start just trying
to get out of his way.
He doesn't really want to be
up against the ropes like this.
He has to fight like this.
He really doesn't have the energy to just
meet him in the center and go Kablooey
at each other.
So go,
go Lufkin's pressure and
constant forward movement.
That's a big factor here. He's controlling
where this fight takes place. A weapon.
Yeah,
it's ring generalship.
He's completely controlling where the
fight takes place and he showing much more
desire to win.
He's trying to stop Canelo Canelo's
trying to catch Golovkin as he's trying to
stop them. There's two very
different things happening here.
It doesn't mean that canal can't
still put the lights out on them,
but what's way more impressive
as what Golovkin is doing?
He's just swarming a man and could see
Canelo called grabs him after that.
See that? That's right. He throws
that shot and he grabs them.
It's cause he's wilting lilies. He
has legs. Just give out there dude.
He's wilting. He is.
He's getting fucked up.
He could still come back hard because
he's a fucking animal and he's a world
champion. But the bottom line is he
started to fade. We're in the 10th round.
This shits getting weird.
Look at that.
He's still got some good head movement
though. I'll tell you that. That was nice.
The Cardio is tremendous,
right? Credible, tremendous.
Guloff Kins cardios we'll glove gins
and other big bear guy. Is it? Yes,
he is a big bear guy. Goes to big
bear to train. Same as L. Kukui.
Tony's a savage dude. I've, I've watched
that guy trying for six hours straight.
Tony Ferguson has cardio is fucking
through the roof. Through the roof.
He's an animal. Should see the shit
we're doing up there. Crazy, crazy.
She loved big bear man and said peaceful
up there. It's cool. What do you do?
Love it. It's fun. You could work
out there at a very high altitude,
low oxygen content in the air.
They say Eddie,
honestly the best thing to
do is not to train up there.
They say the best thing to do is
live up there and to train like down,
like to go down to like sea level, like
drive an hour, go down to sea level,
train there and then go do what everything
else up top because your body will
adapt because the altitude,
especially when you're sleeping up
there but you'll have more work output.
You'll get more work in with
your body at a seed level. Yeah.
What do I know? I'm not a scientist
son. Do Tony? Donny more work there.
Tony goes forever. No, I'm sure,
but I mean he could be even better.
It's what I'm saying. I just think that
that's what the science is. I mean,
it doesn't mean anything. Tony's
obviously adapted to big bear. Well fuck,
that's such a good fight, man.
Such a good fight, Kevin Lee.
Kevin is, it is a
serious threat. You know,
he's the one who not taking him lightly.
Very serious threat.
They're both very serious. Look at their
opponents. Tony's been through some,
you know, he fucked up Edson
Barboza, Josh Thompson,
Rafael dos Anjos, those are
big names. Big giant fight.
Dos Swan was very fucking impressive.
Very impressive.
That was an incredibly impressive fight.
And then the other one that was
really impressive to me was a,
the Barboza Phi because Barboza standup
is top of the food chain and Tony was
cracking him and then finished him in
a crazy bloody Doris who was it wasn't
that all bloody and everything
on that Doris. Yup. Yup.
And Edson Barboza is considered probably
top three most dangerous strikers in
the UFC. Oh yeah. That guy will
light you up with wheel kegs head.
Kevin thinks he's so fast.
He's so powerful.
Here's the first wheel
kick Kao in the UFC.
You know in the highlight you could see
a Ra should fear in the background going
like this? Yeah, like as he gets hit
and cracked. Terry, he hits Terry.
Adam with this crazy we'll kick is the
first wheel kick Kayo in the UFC and it
was the perfect one.
Why it all those stock?
It seemed like all though I noticed
it in the Frankie Edgar fight,
it really stopped kicking or throws
a lot less as he oh good question.
It's a very good question.
It could be because he's got injuries
that don't allow them to kick anymore.
It could be that it's easier for guys
to take him down when he kicks. Huh?
You'd have to talk to him.
I'd like to talk to him,
but he didn't use it very much.
A Max Holloway.
But if you go back to like the Uriah Faber
fight, it was like his biggest weapon.
Yeah. But I noticed it against
frank Yeager. I'm like,
he's not throwing a lot of
kids. Yeah. I wondered why.
I thought Frankie was probably try
to time those kicks in. The rematch.
That made total sense to me.
What didn't make sense as how he
didn't use them that much against Max.
But you know, max is a motherfucker man.
When he said he wants to box now Josie.
Although, yeah, yeah, I've heard that.
But that doesn't take away from
the fact that an MMA fight,
his kicks one of the most deadly weapon
weapons in the sport in his prime man.
He was so fucking good. But like everyone,
it's just like they reach a time, oh,
golf can caught him with a right hand.
Ooh,
this is a crazy, crazy fight, man.
Like you usually don't get these fights.
96 95 Golovkin power punches landed. Wow,
that's incredible. These guys are
just bad. The cards Atlanta too. Oh,
the good left hook too.
You know.
[inaudible] I mean a Canelo router is
absolutely a champion and that's the
reason why it keeps firing
back and he won't wilt.
And he keeps using good head movement,
but there's no doubt about Golovkin
is putting it on them. One more round.
So exciting. And then we get to cool
to see David Branch and Luke Rockhold.
How are we? So lucky I'll at this
some Jesus shit going on. Yeah,
I don't know what that is.
That's got, that's got to be,
or else can I ask mom or something.
She was like,
this is got that moment.
Come to Jesus moment.
Okay.
Um, Sandra, it looks so much
better at one seven. He doesn't he,
I missed that five but he did get
an a, I'm trying to, I saw this,
the finish put a smash on
Neil Magni put the smash.
That's how big his legs. Let's a big
giant, massive, yeah. Well he's filled in.
This is what he gives body
supposed to look like.
He was starving himself.
It's terrible idea. I mean,
he was a beast at one 55 from you
smashing guys and running him over.
But he got to a point where he really
could not make the weight anymore. I mean,
he was real in real bad shape.
When you made the wait for Eddie Alvarez,
he's thick man, so thick
dude. And at one 70, I mean,
he's a fucking animal.
He kicked Neil Magnus legs out from
under him and then he got on top of them.
And just put the smush on them.
It was just so high level.
How did he get them down?
A dumbed down with kick kicked his
fucking leg out from under him and then
jumped on him. Yeah, just jumped
on him. It was a, it was a beating.
I mean it was an Ellis golf. He has
to know. I need to knock out. Yeah,
he's got know
12th round.
Okay.
Ooh.
Behind the ear and the clinch.
Ooh, look at that upper cut in the clinch,
pulling the head down, going MMA on him.
That Jab of fucking Golovkin is so slick.
Oh goodness.
Can Nasa with the by how?
Shit combination yellow with the Combo.
Golovkin caught him with a left hook.
Goddamn Golovkin Lufkin has
a chin man tell you that.
An unbelievable chin
show shit. Oh Shit. Oh Shit.
What a crazy fun is on. Oh
my God, this is amazing. Oh,
and Canelo landed her right hand.
This is a crazy fight. Holy
Shit. Look at that top flower.
The Jab and the right hand real tight
in the clinch. It's constant pressure.
Minute 30 to go. Does he
take over? Does he take over?
Does Canelo have enough to sustain
arms down swinging and missing?
Trying to catch some blood in there,
throwing some punches that just don't
have the steam on him anymore and Golovkin
and of it has to know he's a head and
he's still coming after him. Yeah.
He's a fucking spider dude.
He's like a spider trying to suck the
blood out of a fly just on you like almost
like just so predator,
like just constantly look,
it's not backing off.
He's not boxing. This is not a boxing
match. She's trying to fuck him up.
That's the Golovkin style that
makes them so exciting, man.
That's why Mexican fighters love
him. They do, right? Yeah. Yeah.
Mexican fight fans are big triple g
fans to the point where his last fight,
it was a Mooc was grass.
Yes.
He knows man because he fights like
a world class. Top of the food chain,
Mexican boxer and a lot of ways.
Okay.
God Damn, he's good. This
is fucking fantastic. Yeah,
those are just hitting the gloves. Yeah.
Canal was tired, man. He's real tired.
There's still 20 something to go,
but he's still hanging in there. Man.
That's that world champion
heart still swinging.
It doesn't get any better
than this for boxing.
Especially like after the Conor
Mcgregor Floyd Mayweather fight.
This is a fight that like,
hey, this is how it's done.
Yeah, this is the real deal.
I mean obviously Floyd did it
how it's supposed to be done,
but that wasn't two fighters on the
same level. Look at this. This is crazy.
These were absolutely glorious. It's
fine. These are both great moments.
Or boxing though. The, uh, Mayweather
Mcgregor on this ship, both really,
really great for boxing. Brendan
Schaub, I should say this,
before the decision gets announced,
said that if Golovkin didn't win
by some ungodly lopsided beat down,
that he could lose the decision
crew because of corruption. He goes,
cause that's how boxing roles and there's
way more money and Canelo winning.
So that's sad. Now that we know that
[inaudible] sponsor. That's true. Well,
apparently the audiences are like half
Mexican. He's a superstar in Mexico.
Just a super steady talking about Canelo.
Yeah.
So let's see if Brendan shop predicted
this correctly because we think it has to
be Golovkin the rap,
the,
the unofficial scorecard guy had
it for Golovkin by several rounds.
We think it was go Lufkin clearly.
Although Candela fought a great fight,
have there been bad decision
if Canelo wins have there,
what was the last time there was
a decision like that? Tim Bradley,
Manny Pacquiao who won that and
I believe Bradley one, but pack,
y'all should have one. And then came
back and outboxed him. It was worse.
It was worse. If I remember
correctly, I said, what was
the reasoning of that? Boom,
boom, boom. Oh Jesus, they're
shown hello. Oh my goodness.
This is the last round that was Chanel
just tried to put it to him and glove and
he's like, come on, come on, come
on. I'm from Kazakhstan. Boom.
Just boom over the top.
God Damn just war here.
Leave that had just paid back every
punch he took in a combination.
Just sharp jab to his jam.
So snappy. Okay. Turns it.
Give me a guest. Eddie
Bravo for sure. Glove again,
for sure. Right. Unless there's, unless
there's corruption, like Brendan says,
he's not crazy to say that. I doubt
it. They're getting garage pad. We're,
we're saying this, look at this. They
got at one 16 one 12 for Golovkin Hara.
Let him in here. Harold led. They gave
that last, Lufkin ran away with it.
They gave ten nine on that last fight.
I mean that last round to fucking know
Canelo yeah. You know what I really like?
I don't know why they did that.
I like how these girls just stand there
and smile. They're doing really good job.
They're always smiling. It
seems easy, but it's hard.
You got to be frozen and fucking clapping
and it drives me crazy. I hate it.
I love it.
I love the f their focus,
they're focused on not being even
remotely normal. This Adelaide bird,
the job,
their focus,
their job is to stand there and smile in
Assam psychotic way. If they were a guy,
like if they were a guy,
if you were,
if they hired a guy to stand there in a
nice suit and tie and stand there like
this,
could you fucking imagine how crazy
it would be if you hired guys to stand
behind fighters with giant smiles
on their face and just not,
especially if they were in their
underwear. Just imagine that.
Imagine guys in a speedo
standing there like ripped,
like holding it to caught tay sign with
a big giant smile on their face that
happens on Santa Monica Boulevard going,
it doesn't happen during a big
final paper view. Any Bravo,
you silly goose one day when,
hey, let's hear the volume.
Let's here it is this a
split decision to know
told you son.
Oh boy,
they fucking boxing fucking stinks.
Toads,
you son boxing in Shaw.
Apokyn is the sage. Brendan.
Brendan Schaub as a sage fucking stinks.
Why is he mad?
Cause he knows.
He knows he got fucked.
You know Canelo well he's
going to feel terrible now.
He knows he got his ass Catsa
draw. There's no way. That's
how it was that a draw?
No, it's, hold on second,
he's asking to see if he was happy then
that would mean that he thought he lost.
So the fact that he looks pissed
that smart. He's gonna shoot a one.
This is bullshit.
He's tiny notes.
[inaudible] 69 I think he's
mad because he didn't win.
He threw 200 punches. Didn't
win. But he's definitely mad.
Did he got outbox and they made it
a draw? I did 50 more punches. Yeah.
The fuck is that a draw?
It's not even close to that though.
There are punches different though.
There you go. That's the difference too.
Maybe I'll go higher percentage.
Oh, I can't stand it. Yeah,
but it's a higher number. Landed two one
14 and one 10 and total power punches.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, all right. Jab,
weird thing though. When you're looking
at numbers wise, I mean it's one,
it's one way or looking at it,
but like one big shot that's a power
punch and then another power punch.
It doesn't do anything. They're both
power punches. You know what I'm saying?
Like one shot that really fucks you up
and your legs go and you get wobbly.
That's a power punch and another power
punches his shot that lands in the same
spot but doesn't do anything. They're
both powerful. Are these colors mean?
What are the, what is it? You know what
I'm saying? What is the blue ear? Maine.
I don't know. Look at the
number of punches that, uh,
landed on [inaudible] face.
Hundred nine on his right side and a
95 on his left to 10 landed to one 27.
Yeah.
Big Difference in how many landed to
the head getting 40 level or landed way
more he made,
made,
said only four shots were
landed to Canelo's body.
That doesn't make any sense.
Is that what it really what said and
see what he says here. Let's hear this
tonight.
What happened tonight?
Today?
Really Big Mexican day.
All my friends romance about
good move. Go right to the Mexican
fans. Fucking smart move. Oh,
able to neutralize you,
especially early in the fight and have
success late when it looked like you and
started to build the lead.
I want to,
we probably can't play this without
getting yanked off of a youtube,
so we're going to go to the other way.
How?
How is it first of all that I
didn't think that last fight was a,
I mean that last round
was a ten nine Canelo no.
How was he not fucking angry about
this? I mean, why am I angry about it?
Don't we get shit? Big Drama show two
19 if he wins, he retains his belt,
so nothing really changes for
him and he gets all that money.
Now that your record in the
rematch is going to be insane.
The rematch will be insane.
Those dollars
to 19 good job by Brendan Man.
Fucking good call. Yeah, box.
All the fighters were amazing, but
the organizational, it just stinks.
Brendan. Nailed it. Can you hear this?
Are you, are you guys hearing this? What?
No. Okay. What am I hearing? What
he thought? Oh No, no, no. The TV,
you know,
I don't want to hear in here.
He's not saying I got really
lucky that they gave me that draw.
I don't want to hear what he's saying.
If he thinks he wanted his stupid still
owes a great fight. Amazing. I love it.
I don't eat, I mean I do
care, but I don't care.
I do care that I think that I thought
they're going to go off in one,
but I don't care. It's great fight.
I like seeing great fights. I don't,
decisions means less to me as I get older
because I looked at it and like, okay,
what am I doing?
I'm basing like how I feel about something
based on an inaccurate assessment by
people that don't necessarily
know what they're doing.
Like what I take advice on whether or
not an episode of game of Thrones is good
from three people I
thought were knuckleheads.
Like what if there's like three
judges for TV shows? Like,
well the game of Thrones finale, you
know, I gave it an a 100 you know,
let's go to these judges don't we decided
it gets a 40 no fucking way. Right?
And you go to school the next day like,
dude,
you hear fucking game of Thrones
final got a 40 bro. We lost it.
Got a little ridiculous at the end.
Shut your mouth. Oh my gosh. Let's see.
One show. Come on. Okay, let
me ask you a couple questions.
I loved it.
I remember when they first escaped the
white walkers didn't like the water.
Have something to do with it.
Like pick out on a boat and it's for some
reason they can't get in water, right?
That's the thing, right? Right.
But their eyes are you spoiler alert
in the fucking oil or something.
They at something. Don't do
something about the water. Right.
They can't hang it.
There was a few horse when who
the fuck tied chains around
that dragon and dragged it up who went
scuba diving in and tied that dragon up?
You'd probably have to assume who
had the are they that's wrong.
They're not that strong because
those dudes are fucking them up.
They're not that strong.
Who's carrying those gigantic
chains down there underwater?
Tie Up the dragon and drag it up. Who's
doing that? Well, they're all dead,
so they probably don't give a shit
over a kilometer. They couldn't go.
They can't get into water. He's right. So
how did they do a big hole? A big hole?
I'll accept the drag. The
accepted slept. Very good point.
It's a drag and I can accept.
That's a very legitimate happens when
they hit the water that I don't remember.
I don't like water but they don't like it,
but no ties to drag him.
I'm getting to ships, so islands like
a keeping them from going to an island.
That's why these other guys are like,
fuck this, I'm going to an island.
I'm going to wait on the iron island.
Is it possible that just one
of the things down, they,
they cannot get into
water for some reason.
They established that several times
and then all of a sudden they cut.
They don't,
they don't show how they tied this
God damn dragon up with the chain.
It's like one of those chains that
you hold navy ships to port, you know,
and who typed them up.
They just cut to then dragging them out.
Watching that dragon get pulled out.
I can suspend a little bit. I can,
I can live with the inconsistency of the
dead people dragging the dragon out of
the ice water. I can on consistency. I
can live with that. But I'm, I'm with him.
I didn't even notice that when I
was in a show. I didn't need that.
They went in the water and I
love game of Thrones. Ma'Am.
I haven't this shit that just got
me fucked up. Yeah, they fucked up.
It's a big hole. You're right. Big.
Hello. God Damn it. You're right.
Maybe like in the last uh,
episodes,
they'll show how the fuck they tied that
dragon up or maybe we should set up big
ass. Stupid whole. Yeah. And did
anyone catch it? And you know,
what do they say? Fuck
it. Let's do it anyway.
Bothers me is we're led
to believe that these,
these different kingdoms like a
king's landing and all that are like,
like for like countries away.
But man,
they are traveling to damn quick.
They get from one city to the next city
that at the wall and then they meet and
then the snow in The Bahamas walking
over mountains like, dude, this,
this can take months. She
told double. It's like,
it's almost like that whole kingdom
is like, like Redondo Beach,
West Hollywood,
North Hollywood comped in
20 minutes.
This is Mike Perry was supposed to
be Mike Perry versus a Tiago Alvarez.
He could get to Florida.
Right? Is that what he said?
He couldn't get out of Florida
others? Is that what happened? Yeah,
he was stuck in Florida and my
parents that we came up early,
so I don't want to hear that shit.
Is that really what happened?
I believe so, yeah. That's terrible.
Do you ever think like when they showed
the army's walking through like fucking
no man's land, like who's carrying the
fucking food and where? Where's the water?
Hey Bro, you're fucking my high.
What are they taking shirts?
I always think that the budget is taking
shit. That's a good point. Like where,
what kind of sewage system do help
you?
Just walking across deserts and
shot shitting in ancient Rome.
Taking pisses in every
scene in the background.
There was a big issue in ancient Rome,
like they,
people got diseases cause they would shit
in the streets. Let's talk about that.
Let's bring that in. Making
it more realistic. I see
more shit. You're right man.
Like come on.
Like explain how these fuckers are eating.
I'd love to see Khaleesi dropping a deuce
off the side of that fucking castle.
How great would that be?
That'd be great. Oh Man.
Maybe the queen maybe
like she's shots shots,
tight shots where they show Khaleesi
on the tracking. I don't care for that.
Remember the Superman TV show?
She's the mother of dragons.
You don't think she knows
how to ride a dragon?
I was barely going and
she's barely holding on.
Somebody's watching you in a
Jujitsu match like, oh come on man.
He strangle that guy with his legs
now and then she got to fall off the
dragon every now and someone almost too.
I drag. Oh No, that was the
Harry Potter ride fall off.
She's got to fall off one or
to once or twice. Come on, man.
She's just like barely grip.
I hate those shots when they go to her
of riding the Dragon. It drives me nuts.
John Wayne shows are both gay for each
other cause I thought that was the most
awesome. Don't get me
wrong. I love it. I love it.
When she was riding that dragon,
I was standing up cheering cause it looks
green screen it look better without it
kind of weird that all
the rulers are women.
Like what kind of some feminist shit?
Murder.
Just keep that murder coming
and I'm happy. Look at it.
So let's look up fake that Louis.
Dude. Come on man. That's terrible.
Hold it out of that dragon.
Do you know how many spikes would be
inside of her pussy right there? Yeah.
I mean we're here.
Where is it safe to stick your box?
You're going to ride that thing between
bikes. Look at the size of the spikes.
How gross the yard.
Scary and pointy by disease
group strength.
What's credible?
Never show her training
strengths out of this world.
She should have like a rock
climbing wall in her castle.
Maybe she takes one of those spikes
and she puts it down in her posting.
She's lamps hold of it and that's
how she goes the whole time.
She just has a spot she had locked
in like a ball and socket joint.
I was just another really bad one, but
it's called dragon's way bigger than that.
Like yeah,
the dragon's way,
way bigger than hate the way she's
holding on and you're right. Our whole,
when they show the drag and sometimes
it looks tremendous. Huge. Yeah.
This is old episode. That's
like a Moray Eel, right?
It might be smaller than it
might be younger. Oh, that
might've been earlier days.
Oh, you're right. You're right. You're
right. You're right. You're right. Okay,
I'm wrong. Did you have any that she
used it to kill a bunch of people, man.
Some people know some of the last
episodes. Didn't she get out of the chain?
Look got big. It was there. Oh my
God. That's a full grown drag. Okay.
Hold on a second. Look
at that thing. Dude,
that's bad and moving to the dragon is
amazing. I know that motherfucker CGI,
but when that, when that White Walker
through that spear, I was like,
when it missed this the first
time, like, oh cool. I know.
I feel like it's alive.
Leave versus forgot me with the
drag and Johnson versus Borg again.
It was a virus though, right? Did they
kept him out? He's missed weed a lot. Oh,
he's Ms. Wade a lot.
Ray Borg is miss wait several times.
And uh, I don't know if he got
sick while he was cutting weight,
if other people around him, but
it's just, you know, got, you can't,
boy, it's a big opportunity to get
sick for and it can happen for sure.
But yeah, I guess they have
to do it again. They are,
they already trained for it. Oh, well.
Well one of the judges gave it one
18 the one 10 for Canelo Adelaide.
Yeah. Adelaide. Bert Adelai
bird did that. Was it? I mean,
what's that about her record in the UFC?
Terrible one 18 and one 10
for Canelo had they bird.
That's so crazy that a woman or a man,
she's a woman. She's very nice lady.
Wow. There's that fucking bad she's
going to get towards for that. No,
that's terrible.
How she stays offline and they have no,
but they have no accountability.
It doesn't matter. No, it doesn't.
Nothing happens to them. They just
keep right on being fucking horrible.
That that's terrible. Yeah, it's
not good. I better pissed jeans.
There was one woman who got,
she got in serious trouble for several
really bad decisions and she wound up
retiring because it was like
people were threatening our life.
Mike Perry's a bad motherfucker.
He's scary. It's hard.
See that Jake Ellenberger fight if
I dunno,
a casino owner or whoever is running
like the gambling, the guy at the top of,
he wanted to it just say it in a
different, yeah. If you wanted to rig it,
would you go after? How would you do
go after the judges or the fighter?
You got your explanation. Two explanation
for the game of Thrones thing. Okay.
Multiple tweets have come that
said that they can't swim,
but they can go and water. They
just sink to the bottom. Oh,
so they sacrificed them. Yeah,
but who's carrying those chains?
They're not strong enough to carry those
strings. Those chains were gigantic.
[inaudible] steel is,
can they get hundreds of them dragging
him? They just sink. But wait a minute.
They drag the dragon. How did their
strong, I have to drag the dragon out.
Why are they strong enough
to take the chains in?
A lot of doesn't make any sense.
There's still less holes now or whoever
to put them down there is still done.
Make sense? He just sacrifice them. Let
them stay at the bottom of the water.
They can't get out. That doesn't
make sense. So they're just walking.
Just walk out how you're going to just
walk out hard. It'd be to chain him up.
Even if you had cranes and all
this shit. The chain. Nothing up.
You'd have to have James Cameron down
there with that little submarine trying to
scope it out for awhile.
Done that shit up like the titanic.
Keith Peterson. Another
excellent refereeing. That
would be way harder. Titanic.
A dead body. No, it wouldn't
be hard than the titanic.
Titanic's like miles deep into the water.
Yeah. 13,000 feet down. Yeah, some.
It's crazy. How good its deal and as
shit to hook on. You could just look,
go hook it up. This, Ooh.
My concern is usually, does
it usually look like that? No,
he's going Jersey shore for this fight is,
he's a ruthless guy though.
Super Powerful fucking knockout
artists. Very dangerous. Yeah.
We knocked out Ellenberger.
I was like, wow,
he's just real reckless and angry.
Allen Joe,
Ben handled them know Joe Band did a
really good job. He had one last smart.
I think that's his loss. I think
that's as lost. But you know,
that's a good fight for him.
Joe Ban fought a technical fight and beat
him and for a guy like Mike Perry was
super dangerous up and come and do. That's
a good fight for him. Learn something,
you know, got leg kick there. As
long as they just learn, you know,
as long as fighters don't get discouraged,
fights like that are always good for them
because then you just realize there's
a higher level and the only way
to reach that higher levels.
You gotta you gotta see it
woo fuck room or is this live?
I was alive. Yeah. Yeah.
Kids, fucking ferocious man. Look at
that knee to the head. Look at this.
Fucking fighting him off. So good
tie right there. Hey, good, good.
Moitai good clinching, but most
importantly, like just relentless attack.
Look at a boom, that elbow on the clicks.
Boom. There's any, that's it. That's it.
Ruthless.
He's a ruthless motherfucker.
That guy is relentless and it's just
like all attack. It's all attack,
all full bore all out.
Just trying to smash you all the way.
The guy that's going to beat him is a
guy like Joe Ban who's going to fight a
very smart technical stand up fight.
Like Joe Band did a lot of footwork, a
lot of movement, but he also made him pay.
He made sure that like when it
comes charging out, I'm like,
you're not gonna get away with that.
Like boom.
We would catch them with some
stuff and you realize like, oh,
this guy can hurt me.
It was enough for him to keep Perry off.
I'm a look at this shit. Elbow and
tight. That's nice. That's nice.
I'll get this dough.
I limit limp Ville population one,
Bam hammer fists to the back of the year.
Did this guy have any kind
of camp them? No, he did not.
I don't see a lot of Thai clinches.
Well remember Anderson and rich
Franklin knows enough for like 10 years.
Do you think it's because,
because obviously it's a clinch that has
a thousand levels and we need a lot of
work.
Do you think it's because most fighters
don't specifically work on developing
that clenching,
controlling people from like clench
and their training camps or it's just
something that's low percentage in MMA?
Not,
it's not that it's low percentage.
It's there's less of a chance of getting
in an MMA because you're essentially
allowing to got to get
double under hooks on here.
I mean if you think about
what you're doing when you're
clenching someone's head,
Anderson was so good at it,
man.
He had such a tight squeeze
and it's like anything else.
Like you know how like some people
just have a sick Gabe cable grip.
Some people just have just a six
squeeze. They didn't have a, yeah,
our fight or spending time developing
that for short and Thailand. They,
they stayed in Thailand. They
specialize in it. They're working on it.
They spend time on it. Yeah. You
don't see it that much in MMA.
You think it's good, take it to its low
percentage. You're committing to this,
right. You're committing to this
guys are too good. You know,
you give a guy a double under hook
and he's tripping you and he's on top.
But people don't want that and it's also
guys are good at keeping their hands on
the hips.
That's what rich Franklin fucked up.
But there is a reality
though that if the guy has,
like if you have your hand on a guy's
hips and the other guy is like got you in
a Thai clinch,
he can't elbow you from that clinch while
you're grabbing on his hips and you're
not really going to be in a good
position to stop it if he's fast.
It's a very good position to be in.
You know,
if a guy is worried about your knees and
he does commit one hand or maybe even
two to the hips, like you catch
them with a couple of hard ones.
A lot of guys will just switch to
elbow like right from here. I am.
And it's a ruthless ruthless thing.
Elbows are so nasty. It's so,
it's really kind of amazing that we cover
up the knuckles because you break your
knuckles a lot. You never break your
fucking smash bricks with your elbow.
No problem. Nobody ever breaks or elbow
fighting unless you get kicked, you know.
But like hitting somebody,
you might get like little chips,
like Anderson had a bunch of chips in
his elbow that he actually had to get
removed, like bone chips and shit.
Stuff that snapped off on the job on.
I'm sure a serious problem with
that, with this album. Didn't Gerald?
I think Gerald's treatment had a bunch
of floating around shit and his elbow to
a lot of guys get that. I think he was
the third choice for this too, I think.
Really? Yeah. There was
one guy they had, um,
and he couldn't do it and I
guess I don't care who is second.
Will you watch how fucking
ferocious Perry is?
You realize why Tiago didn't want to take
this with no camp or far with a fucked
up camp?
What was talked about his camp.
Didn't he have a full scan to get out
of Florida for the hurricane? You know,
if that was like a week before the
here yeah. Pulled from the fight.
That's what they both came from.
Farm that that's I think what uh,
what the reason he gave was,
let me make sure that's right.
He's talking to some shit
about Tiago right now.
Everybody
Center.
Everybody wants to see me beat up
Robbie Lawler look at them. Wow.
This week
everybody wants to see me be a Robbie
Lawler. Ooh. What a crazy thing to say.
What a great fight that would be though.
Good Lord.
Hello.
This is a fucking interesting one.
If he really does do that,
if Tiago doesn't fight him
and then he wants happen,
cause he didn't get hurt in this fight
at all, he just swarmed them. And K Odom,
he could probably fight
again in a few months. Okay.
Wow.
I wonder what they're going to do.
Are they gonna read match or make the
remake remake rather the Tiago fight or
whether they really do give this kid
Robert Ponds and Aveo cause a good fight
that guys, that's actually who I thought
they were going to wind underneath.
They put them up an Nelson.
Yeah.
Okay.
I don't hear any of this nonsense. Yeah.
Yay. We go into the game. How can we,
what do you give a fuck?
You just knocked a dude unconscious
it enjoyable guy though. Yeah.
Ferocious fighter.
Yeah.
Just like his style is
just a marauding ferocious,
full attack. Reckless.
A lot of lot of, uh,
confidence in his ability to take a shot.
A lot of confidence and ability
to knock people dead. Like boom,
landed that and like that's it.
And then these great fight would
be him and Alan Jobe on again.
What the history. Um, yeah, it could be,
doesn't show up on and have a
big fight coming up. Uh, does it,
why do I think Alan has a big fight
coming up? Maybe I'm making that up.
I don't think I am now.
I think something was just announced.
I Dunno it saying that uh,
uh,
Jago lost his dog and
was living with family.
I with his family at the gym because of
the hurricanes and then he'd be like,
oh maybe you didn't before camp
Mack, right. Yeah. Fuck all that.
Being at the gym with your family and
he's got a kid, a really young kid. Yeah,
I get it. I think clinching
insane. Insane. He's a beast man.
And that's how Alan fights too.
He's got a serious crunch
to the fucker right there.
That's the picture on my phone.
I took my girlfriend off and put
Francis in Ghana cause look at his hat.
I love it. He's like, Edi mean
up in that bitch. Here we go.
Did they find anyone for him by the
way, are know Francis after dusk? I
don't know. They don't know what's
going to happen with junior. Uh,
what the substance was. They said it was
a very small trace amount of a diuretic.
Um,
so it wasn't like a steroid,
but a lot of times guys use diuretics to
mask steroids because it flushes it out
of your system quicker.
So like I say,
if a guy's doing something
he wants to test negative.
Apparently you can flush some stuff out
with diuretics because he just drains
all the water out of your body and
you keep pouring more water in.
It flushes things out quicker. I think. I
don't, I don't understand how that works.
Diuretics are illegal.
Yes. That's what, uh,
cris Cyborg got popped for a diuretic.
Um,
but then they gave her a
use exemption cause she has,
who has a legitimate reason for using it,
like a medical condition.
When are they know what he took over.
They never know.
They know what he took or was
it the process of they have to,
it has to play out.
Like what did they think happen?
What's the evidence? Like they're
very, very thorough about it.
As one of the things I really appreciated
about that Jeff Novitsky is that he,
one of the things he said about John
Jones, he said before you judge him,
we have to let this process play out.
And he's right, like it can play out.
Not yet. I mean they,
they got the B sample,
the B sample is positive as well.
Um,
but it was a lot of
weird shit was going on.
Like a lot of his chiropractor was
tweeting that John passed the blood test
free.
John and like this is so irresponsible
because like anybody who looked into it
even for a moment would realize that
they don't even test that stuff in the
blood. They only task for that
stuff in the urine. So there was no,
like when they said his
blood test was clear of it,
it's because they didn't task for
it. It's a, it's a urine test.
So like it was so disingenuous.
So then they waited,
they got the B sample, they tested that.
Yup. Same exact stuff. So it's in there.
So the question is now,
not whether or not it was in his body,
but how did he get in his body?
There's a big issue with a bunch of sports
guys. What, what does it, baseball guys,
they're getting popped with that stuff.
Brendan Schaub brought that up as well,
that apparently that stuffed Taranto Ball,
Toronto and a ball,
whatever the fuck it is,
tee ball is in a ton of supplements.
You can get in a lot of that GNC over
the counter muscle builder, bullshit,
all those testosterone boosters
and your mind could be,
but you're not supposed to take that shit.
You shouldn't take that shows you
have to come back off a suspension.
Like shouldn't you be sending everything?
And that's, that's, it's crazy.
But they're tainted
supplements are a real issue.
But obviously the thing is don't take any
fucking supplements and unless they're
absolutely approved and
certified and you know,
and you can get supplements
that are approved and
certified and then there could
be a random bad batch that's,
that's totally possible.
That happened to somebody.
Um,
I supplements where a guy never really
took a steroid but got popped because
something was going to supplant that
happened at Tim means to means took some
shit from a GNC.
Just some normal shit that supposed to
be some stuff you could buy off the shelf
like and uh, he tested positive
and he told everybody what he took.
They went to different
stores independently. Pull
that stuff off the shelf,
tested it. Yep. There it is
steroids, but he still got his boy.
Is it a six month suspension?
They do a year. Yeah.
He's not supposed to take that stuff. Like
even though it's not illegal, you just,
you have to approve everything.
And then on top of that they have a list.
They have a Usada list on the website
that you can go to and find out what's
tainted and what's not. Holy Shit Dude.
It is the craziest thing you've ever seen.
It's hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of supplements.
It's like there's so much shit that
makes you piss hot. It's crazy.
What's the most common? What's the most
popular? I think there's a most popular,
they start with like muscle
farm type stuff. Yeah.
They're starting with a and they work
in the way through P and, and sec. Yeah.
Dude,
I'm talking hundreds of things.
Like Novitsky pulled the
website up and we were laughing.
We were laughing at how many things
are work cause it's so absurd.
Is there anyone who doesn't take anything,
any supplements?
Do you know of any fires or
they talk the most minimal.
There's some guys that just take fruit.
Fruits and vegetables. Yup. That like, uh,
the ones from mom's
Sanford and son now are,
those are tainted Mon Sanford
and son and not total Elijah.
She saw fruit and vegetables. Those are
tainted, those are genetically modified.
They didn't have a shelf life of 20 years.
He posted a Joe Hogan from mayor sign
and somebody who put up the word. Yeah.
Well he might not have
somebody else did I guess.
And they were just talking about
him, jog and, but I think that,
um, there's a lot of tainted
supplements for sure.
But I think there's a lot of guys
using steroids too. So I was like,
which one is it?
Is Did Jon Jones take it
tainted supplement or it was
Jon Jones using steroids.
Those are the only two options at this
point cause that's Tufts in his body.
They'll all,
the other option is somebody dosed him.
Then I thought I'm going to
have somebody couldn't find out.
Well they have to do some sort of an
investigation. He has to come clean.
I talk about everything that
he's taken. Um, they have to,
if he took something that is not on
their list of approved substances,
any didn't claim that one. You
know when they, if that's the case,
he needs a goddamn babysitter.
If that's really what happened.
If it really was a tainted supplement,
just some normal bullshit from a
supermarket, a health food section,
who the fuck knows if it's really just
some nonsense. He needs a babysitter.
He needs someone that's around him
that he trusts and respects some mentor
figure that does not allow him to take
anything stupid and tells him, Hey man,
you're the baddest motherfucker of all
time and you're about to get put on the
shelf for four years over some nonsense.
Matt Serra raised a very
interesting point about, again,
it was just a speculation,
but is it possible that this was happening
because all those fights happened
before you saw sada? Yeah,
except for Osp. Well,
there's always going to be that
speculation. If someone pisses hot,
you always got to think,
well,
if they piss hot in Usada and back when
it wasn't very sophisticated and the
drug searching wasn't that sophisticated,
maybe they were doing it the whole time.
You got to, you got to wonder. You know?
That's why I like a guy like Tony Ferguson
is so fucking spectacular. You know,
you look at a guy like Tony Ferguson and
he's just got mad focus and work ethic.
He's just for Roche and he's
just ferocious in his, in his,
in his focus and his intent.
Like that guy doesn't need steroids.
He just needs food and life, you know,
and he's just going to keep going.
He just needs a place to
work out and he'll build it
too. That's the crazy thing.
He's up there in big bear building gyms.
Builds his own fucking rolling room.
He's got video of it and photos of it
and shit. They mapped it out a room.
He nailed all the boards down and
shit. And he built a bag stand. Yeah,
like a workout little why does he do
that? He just liked the act of doing it.
He's the kind of guy that if shit hit
the fan and we, it was an apocalypse,
uh, like he's the guy that you're
going to want to hang out with.
He's going to build your house.
He's on your shelter. Yeah.
And all you gotta do is just make sure
everything's cleaned when it gets,
I'm not that guy call up
like a Beta and I begged.
Yeah,
well that's what community is all about.
It's supposed to have one of those guys,
one guy like you.
So we'll just have one guy Ligeti I mean
that's, that's what a real community is.
The idea that everybody has to be
the guy that could build a bandstand,
but he can, he does man. He cleans
your friends the cabin. He's on
fire dude. He's just always on fire.
He'll go for a run through these hills
and these mountains in the streets and
he'll have a crew with them running. And
I'm in the car cause I have a torn ACL,
some of my car following them and he'll
beat them by so much and then come back
for him and then go and then
come back for him and go,
these are all professional athletes now.
His, his endurance is insane. He's at,
he's into doing extra credit and if
we're going to do 10 rounds of sprints,
he'll do 12. And he's always going to go
extra. What's going on with your knee?
Did you pour ACL?
Tore MCO.
Um, is it partially torn? Is that
deal is, yeah, it's not Tom to um,
Doctor Rati Mcgee.
He's talking about surgery and my doctor,
uh,
we're talking about,
let's try to rehab it and see what happens
first and then you could always get
surgery later. Um, he said,
has it, you know, with me,
I told you that all I did was just stretch
out and I just stood up and my knee
just fell apart.
It came out and I had to pop it back in
and then I got an Mri the next day and
it came back.
Partial tear in the ACL torn MCL.
You really don't need surgery for the MCL.
Those apparently they just heal by
themselves. You just got to stay off
the ACL. I'm on, I'm on the fence.
I could have surgery right now or
I could try to rehab it, but um,
what's,
what I'm the,
I don't know what Clz anterior cruciate
ligament is a ligament that stabilizes
the knee,
keeps it from popping forward.
I've had both my ACL reconstructed
from the same, from fighting.
One of them from Jujitsu,
one of them from taekwondo popped out.
Three weeks later I was doing a
seminar at 10th Planet Ocean side.
And right there in the middle of
seminar. Boom. It came out again. Yeah,
it's going to pop out in front of her.
I'm just like, if it pops out that much,
man, I would go to a different doctor.
I go to Rodney Mcgee, man, just go,
go to him in Vegas. I talked to him
and we see, he seems totally legit,
but when he's talking about
is the surgery, you know,
new kind of surgery that they're doing,
the new surgery only the
healing is only three months.
They don't use a cadaver anymore.
Now they reattach and you're a perfect
candidate for it because your shit's not
totally torn apart.
They reattach and they resell it up and
one dude did it in five months later he
competed in the Olympics.
The the,
the recovery time is so much different
because what they're doing now is
repairing your ligament.
Whereas before what they were doing is
putting in an artificial ligament and
then that ligament would
act as a scaffolding. So
not artificial, but a donor.
Like I have a donor on my right, one from
a cadaver, cadaver Patella or hamstring.
I had patella on my
left and cadaver on her.
She left feeling both of them are
awesome. Left Zoster, Baltimore.
Apparently people are moving away a little
bit from cadavers cause sometimes you
can get an infection like Benji radic.
He had his ACL,
a cadaver ACL and he got it got infected.
You got
infected from the surgery. He got staff
from the surgery, which is super, yeah,
it's common from the cadaver.
It's at the actual tendon.
Well you know Murcia I know,
I know the doc,
the doctor that I'm going to cause
the one who did his, yeah, but it's,
there's no way to tell whether it was
from the actual surgery itself from
cutting you open because a lot of people
get it from like any sort of simple
operation.
They get mercy stopped doing,
he stopped doing so you don't do consumers
and he's just does patellas well now
what he's Dr. McGee was saying is
the most latest cutting edge shit.
You don't even have to do that.
Now what they're doing is they're taking
this torn stuff and he had pictures of
it and images of the actual surgery.
They stitch it together and rope it down
and like literally stitch it together
and they have this technique that they
do and then you're up and moving like
you're up and moving. And if in three
months it's 100% instead of six months,
what's the technique?
When are they just kind of cocoon
it with a bunch of rows of stitches.
Crazy looking like apparatus,
the way they were doing it,
the way they had it stitched up
like some crazy fishing not but uh,
apparently it worked
amazing cause they the,
he had some videos of this guy a few
months postsurgery doing box jumps and I
was like this is crazy. Do inside box
jumps, like hopping on top of things,
hopping on top of another thing,
jumping over things left and right.
I was like that is incredible for
someone to go from ACL surgery,
do it like that was a rat. That's a
recipe for blowing your knee apart.
Three cause I remember after I
got mine for like six months,
I was terrified to do anything like,
and I,
when I first came back to Jujitsu I was
terrified. I was like, Huh, Huh, Huh.
Like every time I roll it's like,
please don't fall apart.
Please don't fall apart because
if you call them for six months,
so hard to do and how long until you're
doing it, you're like, all right,
it's not going to fall apart. A
couple months, like eight months in,
I realized I was like, this is
pretty good. I'm feeling pretty good.
I was through any kicks forever.
I didn't kick the bag forever
and when I did Jujitsu,
like if anybody even went for my leg,
I would tell him, I please don't,
don't Yank on this one. This one's
still ginger. And it was like,
I wouldn't like try to explode with it
and push off with it. I was real gentle,
gentle on it. This fights
about to go down. Ah.
What do you think Eddie? Bravo
initial thoughts. I don't know.
Does Luke Rockhold get the same guy
after getting catered by Bisbing?
That's a hard, hard one to call. Been a
long time outside the octagon. Jim Norton,
what do you think? You're the host of UFC
uncensored. I'm taking David Branch. Ooh,
New Yorker goes with the New Yorker,
David Branch moving towards him,
dropping some shots. Luke Rockhold
is got a powerful left kick. Yeah,
strong left kick. And he landed it
a few times to the body already.
It's a legit kick and he
catches you with it way outside.
And Luke Rockhold super hard to take down.
He trains all the time with
Daniel Cormier and Cain Velasquez.
He's got all these monster
wrestlers over there.
How be you've never met off and you
think branch wants to take him down.
He might,
he's kind of very good ground game.
Sends a Roscoe Spinning
Sidekick Kale finish,
is that right? No, he got wheel kicked
in the head by Vitor Belfort and,
and then he got um,
uh,
Chris Weidman tried to will kick them
and he took why into the ground and beat
the fuck out of them. And that was
the beginning of the end, right? Yeah.
It was crazy cause up until that,
it was like a really competitive fight.
Branches, Sarc doing a good
job of circling to his left
to avoid that left kick.
He's not well, but he landed it right.
Their branch is doing a real good job. Oh,
he's, he's putting Rockhold
and danger and Rockhold
he teed off on him. Oh my God. Rock
holds in trouble. This is a real fight.
And he's,
Oh my God,
he's take Rockhold down and that's
how you know rock is in big trouble.
I brought, she was super hard to
take down the state standing ab,
but he lets him know he can take
them down. God Damn, this is legit.
And he just looked over at his
friend and waved and said, I'm okay,
or as coach his corner,
but it doesn't look okay.
He got hit with bombs,
man. You never, okay.
When you get hit with those kind of bombs,
you might not have gone out,
but you're not okay. She's fucking him.
I may so much different than boxing.
These two fights highlight it like you do.
You guys barely know who Mike Perry
is, right? Yeah. But meanwhile,
he's so invested in that fight.
Chaos. Right? And this fight,
this is the fucking chaos
in so many different ways.
One 18 to one 10. I'm not going to, I
guess get a room or the fucking weekend.
Adelai Berge it's a very nice lady.
I can't say anything terrible,
but that's where it is.
She's always very pleasant.
She always waves and says hello.
I mean just cause I don't think I
agree with her. And boxing. Yeah.
Not Mad at the lady.
Do judges get removed for poor officiating
to good questions that ever happened?
Well,
back in the old days with the Nevada
state athletic commission wasn't being run
very well. Um, Bob Bennett, the guy
who runs it now as an animal, he's,
he's on the ball.
He's really good and he's really smart
and he's just a real easy guy to talk to
too. And you know, he wants
us commission though, Nate.
Yeah, he's, yeah, he
handles all that stuff.
So most likely he'll probably
be looking into that. That's,
do they ever get booted though?
If it's not corruption,
if they literally just think this
guy sucks and making decisions,
do they ever get kicked out?
Like you've questioned many times.
It's a good question. I don't
know enough about boxing. About,
I know when there's a bad decision
and I know names that I keep hearing,
but it's not like I know a MMA judges.
That was the,
that's that's disgraceful
score. Disgraceful. I agree.
And has she had an another? Yeah, there.
Just that she's had some
terrible decisions in terms
of what I think about the
call. Ooh, look out for the knees on.
He's trying to trip. Branched down.
Luke Rockhold super strong,
super strong.
Top game branch might be
fading and been here. Nope.
Branch still looking at wing.
Some shots.
One of the things that branch thought
was a big factor in this fight with his
boxing but he's got to avoid those kicks.
Especially the left one man,
the left one's the big one for Rockhold
and he'll do it off the switch. Ooh,
that's a nice right leg kick.
He'll do it off the switch
and he's got a nasty question.
Mark kick is question mark kick is what
he used to crack Bisbing with cause he
hits you with the body shots like
over and over and over again.
And then he gets your region.
So he throws one like this to the body
and then at the last minute he whips it
around over the top. He's nasty
with that. Really good with that.
And it's like one of his best techniques.
Okay.
That in his left power kick, that left
power kick to the body. It's just so good.
He stopped cops to Phillip. Who would
that left body kick as well? Oh,
we went jumping round. Kicking. Nice
straight left. He said, no, no, no.
He certainly looked like he recovered.
Yeah, he recovered for sure. Oh,
we just clipped David Branch
with a right hook. Look.
Rockhold does not want to
go out like that. Bisping
fight. See, here's the clinch.
Well, you're talking about, yeah,
so it's just way harder to pull off.
This is too much scrambling in MMA
and looking for take downs and stuff.
Look at how Luke Rockhold getting
the back. Get in the back. Oh Shit.
David Branch almost goes down.
Oh, Luke Rockhold on top.
Very dangerous on top. Super strong
and branches tired as fuck man.
Rockhold looks like he's surgeon here.
Branch is doing a good job.
That protecting them. One thing Brock
holds, got to watch out for is his legs.
What brand is on the Henzel Gracie school?
What's his motive?
And putting them up against
the cage when he's smashing,
smashed against the wall. They can't move.
He wants to just hold them somewhere.
Ooh,
not makeup.
Okay,
dude. What do that shit?
Um, yeah, just smash him.
Rockhold came on strong
towards the end of that round,
there's nothing more claustrophobic and
washing that when someone's mushed up
against the cage like
that. Uh, I could be,
but Johnson fight that it's probably
the most claustrophobic I've ever been
watching fight over it.
That was one of the worst ones over.
There's an art to smashing a
guy against that fence for sure.
Keeping them there and land in shots and
wearing them out and just smashing them.
It takes you back to
when you're 10 years old,
like that's how I got beat
up when I was a kid. Like,
you're just helpless in a corner. Dude.
That happened to me when I was 14.
That's when I started wrestling.
This guy took me down in the locker room
and he was like gonna Punch me in the
head, but he decided not to because it
was so easy for him to take me down.
He just grabbed me in a head lock or I
didn't even know if we were fighting.
Like I didn't know what was going on.
Like we were looking at each other and
he was talking some shit and I wasn't
exactly sure like what we're going to
do and then all of a sudden we were
grabbing each other and he just got me
in a headlock and threw me on the ground
and held me there and could
have easily punched my face.
And to this day I owe him a debt
of gratitude. Changed Your Life?
He did change my life because he
made me realize like, oh my God.
And then I had a friend,
my friend and Arduino,
he was a wrestler in high school and I
was already doing a martial arts den and
it just had no idea how easy it
was for someone to take me down.
And we went outside. We went outside
on the grass and it was like,
I could take you down easy. I was, no you
can't. He's like wash, boom. I was like,
fuck that. Try again. Boom. I was like,
oh my God, I gotta start wrestling.
So those two events
led me to wrestling class,
wrestle in high school and I was terrible.
I was probably one of the worst
wrestlers in high school history.
I got one one take down.
I would never take anybody down.
I was always afraid that I was
going to catch a knee and my teeth.
So I would just sprawl on dudes. It
took down, they tried to take me down.
That was my game plan. But regular
people, when I'd get in a fight,
I would take them down and I always felt
like I was cheating, but I didn't care.
Cause you use wrestling. Yeah, go.
You know what? I don't give a fuck.
If someone fucks with me,
I'm a double leg them and then I'd get
like twister cycle from a punch their
stomach. I did that to
us, a soccer player.
He was talking Shit in school and um, I
took him down. It took several guys down.
I think that it would be cheating.
I thought it was,
I didn't think it was real fighting
back then. So when I saw her voice,
when I saw, holy smokes,
he too, I'm like, Oh shit.
You could take dudes down and
fight. That's, that's legit.
He's hurting that light.
By the way.
Rockhold was really hurting that lag
bolt guys are hurting their legs.
Rockhold yes,
it's
been landed a bunch of hard leg kicks
on branch too. This is a serious fight.
That's what I mean. He's been, he's
been hurting branches like Oh yeah,
but rock holds her too man.
This is a, this is a real fight.
Very good fight.
Is it a funny now like a fight
where two guys take each other down.
It's like totally standard.
Like you know,
kids today would ever think
that would be cheating.
Like that's how you fight motherfucker.
If someone takes someone
down like Oh shit,
grounded pound kids know the moves so I
can draw. Oh you guys, I see fight videos.
Just street five videos where someone
takes him down and they tap like that's
like the understood move. Now
it's hilarious. I but it, look,
if people can tap in street fights, the
world would be a better place. Yeah.
Because if somebody leaves you alone
after you tap and they let it alone.
Like if you guys agree to fight and
then someone taps and then the guy who
respects the tap. That's good that
that'll done opens. Yeah. I hope it does.
I hope it happens more often I guess
of the Times it will push your fight to
begin with though. Yeah. You know.
Sure. You're not signing the contracts.
Some Guy Fuck your chair.
Exactly. Exactly. Boom.
Then what's some of the craziest shit
girls fighting? Cause it's so primal,
especially when they don't know how to
fight and that grabbing hair and just
screaming come off
laws wailing at each other.
See the thing about Rockhold is he's so
used to this shit cause he's in the gym
with DC and Cain doing this.
So like there's very few guys,
they're going to have a kind of clinch
game that Rockhold is going to have and
the kind of grappling like grinding
skills that Rockhold is going to have
because he's been doing it with these
fucking monsters. Yeah. I mean, Ryan,
his past, he's said, oh,
there's a lot of time left to full
Mount Cha not good for branch.
Super Bad for branch. Let's see if he
gives up his back and trying to get out.
That's, that's super dangerous.
Don't panic. Let's see if he panics.
He's got to figure out a way to
defend himself. Oh look at this.
He's given up his back. He's given
us, do you have it off of his back?
It's going to handcuff him. Oh, he got
that back. Oh, bad place to base flat.
And this is terrible planning at time.
Branches in a world of Shit.
Doing Rockhold does this
to everybody, man. Yeah.
He gets on top of you when he just smashes
you. It's so impressive to veto. Right.
Look at his top mount. No,
he did it to, um, uh, uh,
the Odo Leo Machida. Oh to our wheel.
Kicked him in the head, remember? Oh,
that's right dude. Ranches in serious
trouble. He's going to flatten them out.
That's a serious mountain man.
That back mountain is out of control.
His mount and his back mount or sees his
top game. It's just fucking ferocious.
Oh, branch has done. He has done,
he's just, he was just covering up.
Dan's giving me a lot of chances here, but
he's taken a fucking bad beat. Tap, tap,
tap, tap, tap, tap strikes.
Yeah.
To, to strikes. Great fight. Fuck.
Yeah. That was a great fight,
dude. Brock holds top game. Might
be the best in the fucking division.
He might be better than
Romero. He might be cray. Yeah.
He's a black belt under who? I don't know.
I don't know who they are. Um, it's not,
um, oh, it's an achy Dave Camera Rio.
How long has he been at this forever?
[inaudible] still in Aka? No, I think,
but a lot of guys,
I trained with them still.
A lot of guys still go over there and she
just, yeah, we'll throw it to somebody.
That's a joy. Would you suck on that? No,
I wouldn't. Would you put in your mouth?
No, I wouldn't. Girls
would. Some girls would.
Some girls want to get pregnant with that.
Spit get you pregnant.
I used to depend on the fighter.
Boom. I got a text message from
Vinny Shoreman fucking Adelaide bird.
Again,
a lot of people are aware that alley
birds does know the best decisions.
It's true. Boom, boom, boom, boom. She's
trending. Jamie knows who's trending.
Would you ever know who's trending?
Never. Not. You'd ever know?
Would you ever had any idea ever
who's trending? What was that?
Would you ever have any idea who's
trending? No. Sas. Jamie. Oh,
it's just the newer still trending.
Can't you train it? Two different ways
to like locally like I've had guys go,
dude, you're trending, but I'm not. It's
like a fucking local, like in Jersey.
I'm trying to compare it to other
Jersey people. Nice. Which is,
how does that work? How do you get, how
do you train in Jersey? I don't know.
There's a way to do it location wise.
Like it gets your hopes up and utilize.
I'll no one fucking cares.
Luke Rockhold put the beat down.
But I'll tell you what,
man,
David Branch made it a scrap made a scrap
from the beginning till Luke Rockhold
wore on him with that pressure,
that clench and that wrestling too.
I'm telling you man,
all those years with Cain and DC,
I mean you don't get any better wrestling
than that. You don't get any better,
more savage,
big giant dudes than to think about it.
Olympic class wrestler and the arguably
arguably the greatest UFC heavyweight
ever.
Well who puts,
but who helps cane light that cause he's
obviously he's heavier than combination.
Not much. Not much. DC walks around
all the time at two 35 to 40.
You know,
he'll,
he even said he was feeling kind of
slim like this time after the fight.
You know, we did commentary last
weekend and he said, uh, he was, uh,
usually he'd be at like two 35 by
now, but uh, he was lighter than that.
I think you'd be like two 15 or
two 20 or something like that.
But he'll get up to two 35 so it canes
to 40 so when they're in the neighborhood
of each other,
like five pounds difference
with a worldclass grappling
like those two guys have,
they're just going to war constantly.
It's always a problem
now for big guys guys,
two 50 and above finding
training part. Sure. Tough
man. It's tough. We don't have very
many big guys we've got right now
in my class,
I think the biggest guy
pro 200 pounds crazy it.
What a fight man. Huh? And that crazy
Luke Rockhold. I'll tell you dude,
when that guy gets people down,
they are not getting up.
He has one of the best fucking top games.
You don't see a lot of tap house due to
strikes. A lot of people don't do it.
They don't believe in it.
A lot of people have said
that like that's a bitch move.
I don't think it is even a, even a
little bit. I think it's a smart move.
When you're getting hit,
you're getting fucked up and you know
you're not going to recover, you know,
and the fights over it.
There's no need to take extra shots if
you know that you're done, just tap.
But it seems as if they
see fighters say this.
Well a lot of people
like George Saint Pierre.
That's one of the things that Bj Penn
was taunting him about how he tapped it
strikes against Matt when Matt beat him,
Matt beat the shit out of
him and a clipped him with
a pig right hand early gun
on top of them, banged him out. And then
GSP tapped his tracks and Bj was like,
I would never tap the strikes.
But really maybe some of those
career fights he should have.
If you know you've got
nothing left, why not? Yeah.
Getting out of what.
Okay.
Brisbane.
I Dunno.
That's some bad trash bitch being
cause he's saying it's his fights.
I think he feels he should be
fighting for the belt. Nut. GSP. Yeah.
Oh Man. You're getting credit for taking
that and so I got my first round. Yeah,
he was in trouble, dude.
He was in trouble for sure.
That Thai clinch stopped the strikes. Yep.
This, this is what stops everything man.
His fucking smushed game.
I look at that step over mount may no
resistance and getting that amount.
He just overwhelmed branch branches
couldn't keep up that pace.
You know Luke Rockhold.
I mean he's a reason why he was the champ.
He's fucking world class November,
November Madison Square
Garden. Whoa. He's,
so he's telling GSP to back out.
Well,
there's people who are still thinking
that GSP is not going to make that fight.
Yeah. There's a lot of people think that
GSPS crazy. Now he's lost his marbles.
Why didn't they keep delaying
it? Well, because of the, uh,
the time lapse thing and the Ufo thing
that he saw, he kept talking about aliens.
Like he was obsessed with aliens to the
point where they wanted to leave it out
of a, one of the UFC countdown shows.
No Way. He talks a lot about us.
Yes. Yeah. He's trying to tell us
we're not listening to, there was some,
he talked about it on my
podcast, man talked about, uh,
he thinks that like sometimes he'll,
he'll like be missing time and
then we'll like be somewhere else.
It wasn't comfortable listening to,
didn't you pointed out to them that
that was kind of a trauma? Yeah,
well that's one of the main
signs of trauma. You know,
loss of memory is one of the big ones.
You know when you start talking about
missing time and aliens like, Whoa, okay,
why would you think it would be aliens
when you got hit 800 times? Like he's,
he was hitting more than 800
times in his UFC career. It
was like, no, no, no, no, no,
I'm fine with that. Aliens
are fucking with me, dude.
Damn, that's crazy. Maybe it's true.
Maybe it is. Imagine if we were like,
we're joking around about it. Meanwhile,
every night while GFP, GSP sleeping,
his body freezes wool.
The room fills up with blue light.
Little dudes like fucking
walk right to the walls will
and he's like, no, don't take me again.
And they take him to this patient
cartoons. They want to get that.
You want that perfect super athlete.
GSP DNA.
They take them there and then fucking,
they have a whole underarmour lab and
space and they do an anal probe and him
and then he turns around and
goes, I am not impressed. Why?
Why is it always your,
but man that was playing with
your but regular doctors don't,
but I think it's like that.
That's how they test the blood
to see what you're eating.
Plus they probably know it bothers us.
I bet you could learn a lot from shit.
What did they started giving poop samples
like that was more accurate than than
pis. I mean we have no problem with
piss samples. Try Shit samples.
It is shit and colic. Hey,
piano, piano like all right,
can't believe you're making me do this,
but I'll do it like w if ups
made you shit in a bucket. Yeah,
cellophane. The top. We found a new,
there's a new blood, a drug test,
but we need your shit. That's the only way
you really, no way you're going to, yes,
you're going to do this and we have
to have at least four pounds of it.
Can you imagine
getting a friends to ship for them?
Dude, I need your shit to do, do to
just hide in the fucking air duct.
You have like a bag of shit.
You're like tap the wall twice and
you dropped down like a fucking demon.
Take a shit in my bucket and climb
back up bro. What can he get caught?
It is shit. Listen, you been eating
good. Like eat a lot of fiber.
Like can you shit on command
and they don't be dogs and smelled.
There'll be like a steroid sniffing dogs.
It was just a fucking Bagel and
they started eating your shit.
Then that means you're guilty.
You don't get this puppy.
And when, uh, when he was little, like
as the shit would be coming out of his,
but he be turning around and trying
to eat it like dance. It was,
he's was like taking a shit. He's like,
oh he couldn't wait with that. No.
Like puppies are weird man. They
smell shit and they, they're so,
they're their babies. They think it's
food. Yeah. They don't understand that.
Just like bad move.
Literally like soft serve ice cream coming
out of his ass always turn around and
try to snatch us. It's like a
thousand times stronger than ours,
but they don't think it's bad.
Can you imagine what shit smells like?
Liked the smell shit bad. They
like it. It's like it just,
it just flips out of like it's
a defense mechanism. Well No,
they like rotting bodies. Two dogs.
Yeah. Dogs find like a dead beaver.
Some shifts they'll roll around in it.
They're like, like it on their skin.
It's weird.
A weird,
maybe we've been brainwashed into not
liking it because we're supposed to eat
bugs where I was supposed to eat insects.
Right.
It was a smart thing to
eat when they're being,
I mean we wouldn't need to go to
supermarket if we'd like bugs,
which is eat bugs.
We just trapped.
We slice and stuff are only
up to a certain point. Like
once you can make shit,
there's no need to eat them anymore.
But she knows supposed the Ilene. Yeah.
I was listening to a lecture about this.
Well they were talking about, um, okay.
No, it was Terence
Mckenna. That's who it was.
And he was talking about how we used
to be insectivores and so that reward
system is still in our consciousness.
That's why people get super excited when
they catch a bug. I'll give you like,
that's why people like those
butterfly kept catchers.
They'll like to collect butterflies
and shit and the capture.
I'm like there's a whole like group of
people you know you can't trophy like no
one like no, you know like people don't
like trophy hunters. Like it's gross.
You go over there, shoot Ryan,
I was to put them on your wall.
Collecting butterflies is totally fine.
Nobody gives a fuck about butterfly.
They kill them once they get them right.
Well they don't last long anyway.
So that's like actually
like I guess the mindset.
But there's people that like
collect them like serial killer.
I think they have these butterflies
pressed up on the glass and I've,
I've collected all these
beautiful killing all these bugs.
It's like they're like trophy
hunters. But for bug, that's one step.
Throwing a fat girl and your well anybody
out there fighting for bug rights?
Well I'll tell you when it could happen.
It is possible that it could
happen some day with um, with,
with there's a bunch of different people
in different parts of the world that he,
crickets and cricket protein is
like really rich. It's very good.
Cricket protein is very good for you.
Yeah. Cricket protein powder right there.
People um,
are starting to turn towards crickets
for animal protein for vitamin B,
12 for a lot of things.
And a lot of people that might have
like ethical issues with eating animal
protein don't have it with like,
maybe insectivore will be like a thing.
Like people don't want to mess
necessarily commit to being Vegan,
but they don't want animals to suffer.
But they're cool with
eating crickets like that.
That would actually be a good health move.
Like you could get a lot of really rich
protein, like look at all the fucking,
look at all the shit that's in, in,
in crickets. Like how many crickets,
how many crickets you get out of 10 a
hundred, what is it? 10 gallons of water.
They're going to be in there anyways.
So for a hundred gallons of water you
get 71 grams of crickets versus 19 grams
of chicken.
I don't really know what this means.
I don't even that it's just so weird and
they must be protein protein versus a
or or the amount of a weight
of body mass of the animal.
Cause I would imagine crickets
use very little water, right?
They're creepy little bus.
They used to create that much less
water use to create that much protein.
Whereas like cows drink water,
chickens do like they need actual water.
How long we forced him.
Asshole comes out and tries to
defend cricket rides. It'll happen.
It'll also happen with robots.
As soon as we start making human
looking robots that do shit for us,
somebody will start to say you
have to treat them a certain way.
It may or may not happen.
Right.
There's a real problem that if we figure
out that plants have consciousness and
they know that plants do have some
consciousness. Yeah, they had,
they know there's some communication
going on between plants.
It's just not what we
think of his consciousness,
first of all because it doesn't
entail moving, but there's,
there's some sort of information
that's being passed on. In fact,
plants have chemical reactions
to being preyed upon.
Like clants plants change their floor,
their flavor profile.
Like they'll make themselves disgusting
for animals to eat just based on whether
or not an animal is trying to eat them.
So if something eats them,
it changes the smell of all the animals
around them or all the plants rather
around them. And then they
change. Like for the Keisha Bush,
they've studied these things when they
go down wind like one will get eaten by a
giraffe and then the wind will catch
the other trees and the other trees will
become inedible to the giraffe.
It's filed. It's crazy.
There's some sort of community.
I have my stuff trimmed,
wants to know while I'm
like dead fucking that hurt.
I really did the one more with the
snapping in the face and goods plants.
It's a good question. Like
what is pain though? Right?
Cause our pain might have to do entirely
with movement in our central nervous
system, which plans definitely don't have.
So even though there are living thing,
they might have consciousness but
they might not be experiencing pain.
But they do know that they have some crazy
rep relationship with fungus and that
the fungus or extracting minerals from
the dirt and he's like mycelium under the
ground and they have some
sort of relationship with
the root system and there's
a whole community and this like exchanges
going on and like these ecosystems of
plants, like when you see a jungle, we
think about a bunch of individual plants,
but they're all working together.
They're all like sinked up in some way
that we're too stupid and self centered
to consider. Plans gave me the creeps
I like, they fucking creepy out fuck.
Out of a plant is bugs. There's so
much about them. I don't get in the
fungus. They really do freak me out.
Anybody thinks the understand plants?
Look at Venus fly traps. Okay. D
that's a plant that kills bugs.
Look at this fucking plant in, I want
to say Ecuador. Is that worth from?
There's this plant,
it looks like a flower and mice and rats
go around the edge of it cause it's,
it's smell sweet and
the smells like rotting,
rotting meat in there and they fall in
and this thing closes up on them and they
absorb it and eat it.
They eat rats or that goes right to
check that. Okay. Back that up so I
can see it to sell Venus fly traps.
You can remember that shit. Look at this
show. This mouse is like, man, that's,
Michelle knows good. Whoops. I mean
they're now I'm dead. So it gets get out.
Is it slippery on the sides or does it?
There's a plant. It's just super slippery.
Like the mouse. It's, it
has a delicious smell.
So what else comes there and just
falls right in the hole. A frog bitch,
boom.
Venus fly trap eats a fucking frog son.
And how does the Venus fly trap
actually eat it. Crushed to death.
Trying to eat it.
It's like just a react.
It just the reaction and then they
just die and then somehow it just like
fertilizer just feeds it.
But it's an accident like that fell in
that plant that could be just like a
glitch and the design and we're actually
falling in will end up ends up being
fertilizer anyways.
All sort of changes in plants or in,
in in animals is all like
natural selection. Right.
So there has to be some random mutations
and then some of them stick and then
the was one funny, another rat shit.
It's going to smell the place up guy.
Maybe mice were eating it and slowly but
surely figured out a way over millions
of years to shrink those fucking
mice in the fall and into, yeah.
So like they fall under and
they starve to death. They die,
they get absorbed by the plant. What
is there, is there, I don't know,
some sort of a judge justice breakdown
and just digest them while they're alive.
Something I want to, shit way
to go eventually dies in there,
but the frog, the the Venus fly trap.
I didn't even know they can eat a frog.
That's a fucked up way to go.
Yeah. Plant clamps down on you.
If you're walking through the jungle,
they need to try to breed gigantic
ones of those two and why can't they?
If they can manage them in your house,
that's something that
you had Parana
besides Bronto.
That was the craziest, I was thinking
about getting crocodiles at one point.
The illegal or know exactly.
I'm Venus fly trap.
That's gangster. Giant breeding
giant ones. Big Ones, big ones,
some what do you call those dudes?
Botanists. Geologists. Triology
a tree side.
That's actually a great idea.
Someone should do the giant ones and
that's your security system. Climate.
Do you need for a Venus flytrap don't
try to rob me. Alero perfect. Kyla,
you can't grow them
here but what you do or
as a, as an animal, what a Dick, you
must feel like when a plant catches you.
So fucking humiliating badge if you were
walking through the jungle was probably
the retards and caught by some plant
that they didn't know about yet because
there's like hundreds of thousands of
different species in the Amazon and this
place is in the Amazon that people
just don't go. This is no one there.
And if there are people that
like these uncontacted tribes,
they find these villages like, what the
fuck are you doing here? And they're like,
what are you like this people to this day
that are like these uncontacted tribes
in the middle of the Amazon?
I read somewhere that 90% of the bugs
in the Amazon don't have names because
they've just evolved so quick. They
just can't keep up with the evolution.
I don't know if that's true or not.
Oh No.
There's a bunch of bugs that don't
have names, but I'll tell you this.
When I went to coast,
I got tricked into going to Costa Rica
once I that thought we were going to
Costa Rica Party, Ken Kuhn,
I was thinking Ken Kuhn,
the whole time going to Costa
Rica is a bunch of people went.
I'm thinking Cancun, Cancun. I didn't
know we were going into the jungle.
We went into the jungle and when
at night to sleep in the jungle.
A mansion in the jungle.
Oh, that's mentioned. I can,
but still you're in the middle of
the jungle and at night. Holy Shit.
I just doused mice.
I bought all the off at the knee at the
data village and they had like a little
convenience so I cleaned them out cause
I'm scared of bugs and I didn't want to
really let anybody know that I
was a big pussy about bugs. I got,
I got tricked into gone.
I literally die.
I used off as gel in my hair and put
her all over my face because I knew when
that sun went down it
was going to get nuts.
Even in the mansion you
worried about getting,
we were all hanging out outside of
Soho and the mansion has open, um,
ceilings. It's open air. Oh Dude.
It was a complete nightmare.
But my point is at night,
every night we'd all,
we'd all sit in front of the pool and
all first you'd see all the frogs coming
out of nowhere.
And that first night it was so trippy.
The guys that live there go, you're going
to love these frogs. Don't be scared.
They're the ones that are
going to save your ass.
All these frogs are everywhere in.
All of a sudden the bugs just
start coming out and it's,
it really is like Braveheart.
It's a bunch of frogs and you see them.
You don't have to wait and see.
You just see them just going after bugs.
It's just a war.
And the guy,
the guy that lived in a house that
was watching the house, it goes,
you're going to love this.
It's just chaos.
Was that they're preventing you from
getting bitten by just eating the fucking
bus was preventing that. I was cool.
They didn't, they didn't come around me.
But I swear only once
did I ever see a bug.
The same species that were all different.
They're all mobs looked like
mosquitoes that look like centipedes.
It looked like stick one.
There were all different and
there was all open air too, right.
So they were flying in your room and shit,
dude,
I could talk about this one hour,
but they tricked me.
It was a night mare.
Cause the people that liked it,
they're the kind of people that have a
giant like spider moth lands on their
shoulders. They do. You know, like one
of those dudes, you know what I mean?
You know those dudes that
don't give a shit about,
but if you would like Costa Rica,
if you want to move there,
you're 100% one of those guys that
doesn't get around you and you slept here.
She'll be hosted,
but no one told me to bring a
fucking net and there was no more.
Bring your own net,
put a shit hole the first I walked in
there as soon as soon as we're driving in
this bus through the jungle, I'm
going, oh my God. How many days?
It was a nightmare.
Every night was a nut.
But I had to keep it inside because there
was girls and when I was single and I,
it was like a slasher movie
and so I didn't say anything.
I just knew and I'm like, damn, I thought
it was going to be like king can shit.
So we get, we get to the Manchin, we
get to the mansion I have and they go,
your room's air, your rooms there
and everyone's got their own rooms.
There's a couple of couples, they got a
room and as soon I'm already tripping.
Uncle Buck when the sun comes down.
Holy Shit,
I'm a big gigantic vagina
when it comes to bugs,
like mod scare the shit out of me.
I'm a big pussy and we're going into
the jungle. That's all I was thinking.
Oh my God. Oh my God. So as
soon as I walk into my room,
I noticed that it's all open there and I
look up and there's about 40 50 bees in
my room.
40 50 be nesting in your room.
They're just flying all
over the fucking place.
So I dropped my bags and I go downstairs
and the guy that's watching the match,
an old Vietnam vet, white guy who left
civil, all those guys live down there.
They leave their jobs,
they leave their family,
they try a new life than they hate it.
And now they can't go back.
Now they can't go back cause they do.
They left everything. Yeah. But anyways,
so I went downstairs and I talked
to this Vietnam vet. I'm like,
is there supposed to be a bunch of bs?
And I room like God,
just turn on the ceiling fan on low,
don't turn it too high. It will make just,
you just want it to be
uncomfortable for them.
And then a couple hours there'll be gone.
They don't like that little breeze.
And I'm like, okay, all,
and then I'm thinking,
what about at night when the bugs
just flood in? And he's said, oh,
you need a, you need a net to sleeping.
I'm like, Shit, what do you get those?
It was a, they're usually sold out,
you know? And they were sold out.
There was no net. So I slept every
night, every night. I said, first of all,
I was complaining about the bees. I talked
her, I was like, I had to let it out.
I held it in and I said, dude, you
guys have bees in your only go. Yeah,
we got bees too. I'm like, oh my God.
So I started complaining about
bees and then a girl goes, okay,
captain be watched. We get it. You don't
like bees? And then at that point like,
fuck, I got to shut the fuck
up. No more peep out of me.
No Sarcozi captain be watched. Conscious.
The appropriate response. Yeah. Yeah,
so I never said Shit.
I held it in every night was an ironman.
I slept in the sheet like completely
covered and you could just hear z z and
then we now that when I had to
take a leak, the bathroom again,
if you like that you don't,
you don't care about bugs.
So they want crazy shit like a bathroom.
When you opened the door as a bathroom,
there's no walls and there's no ceiling.
It's like an outside bathroom.
They liked that shit.
They like that shit. Oh,
it's cool that people that don't
mind bugs. If you're like the jungle,
if you like the jungle,
that means you don't mind bugs
here that it's like there's like,
I think 60% of the population that
don't mind bugs. 40% are terrified.
I'm terrified. That
guy, that pets hornets.
I watch videos and this
guy to go on youtube.
There's a guy who will appeal
gently stroke wasps and Hornets.
He's like really fucking creepy
fingernails, but he touches be there.
That's probably my greatest
fears every night nightmare. Oh,
did you get will never go to
a jungle again in my life.
Did you stumble a baby much off on me.
Had completely doused in pets the bees,
but he actually does it with
this one probably has. It
looks like a, I don't know.
That one probably has those
stingers probably in Japanese horn.
It they're away from the nest. But
uh, this one may not have a stinger,
but this guy is that
he does it on the nest.
I've seen guys petting them on the next,
yeah. This guy can live in Costa Rican.
No problem. That might not have a
stinger. You'd fucking love that man.
It looks like a stand to me PPO.
They put those things honey on
their finger and it just fuck it.
It comes up to Jack Him Man is just
trying to sting him though. Yeah,
he's just avoiding it.
It keeps trying to jack and
I wish I had those powers.
I wished there was a pill that
could make me feel like that.
Why would you want to do that? I wouldn't
take that. Some pharmaceutical get fit.
Get rid of the fear of bugs like you
gotta it gotta be on it every day.
It's a weird reactions.
What if the shit hit the fan?
North Korea blows up the United
States and it's not gonna happen.
North Korea would go to war with Russia.
We go to war with China at
this place is a disaster,
but you can live in Costa Rica is still,
it's safe. You just gotta deal with bugs.
Eddie.
I would go, you'd get dapped. I
would. You would adapt. You adapt.
You adapt. But I couldn't bugs
really. A, it's a really weird,
I don't know how anybody
can be comfortable around
them. I don't get used to it.
I have silver fish in my apartment.
They fucking disgusting. Fucking whore.
Creepy. But I was diagnosed. I douse
myself every morning, fresh coat.
Does that make you feel creepy?
I didn't give a shit. No.
I mean like did it make your
body feel worth it was worth it.
The bugs didn't want not had too much
on me do I put it all over my face,
all over my hair in my balls.
I didn't want to get bitten a dick.
There's a this stuff like, you know what
line of Cain is like a pain killer? Yeah.
It's like a numbing cream they
put on. I uh, had a bad sunburn,
wants like real bad.
I was in Mexico and I was sitting on
the beach and I was not paying attention
and I didn't realize how bad I got burned.
My back was on fire.
I mean it was like serious, serious
pain, especially if I'd start sweating.
And so I got some, some of this
light of Cain stuff and it says like,
only put like two pumps of
this shit put on your back.
Of course I put like 13 pumps.
I put it all over my back
because my back is an agony.
And then like an hour plus later
I started feeling like shit,
like nervous, like sketchy, like
shaky. And I was like, oh my God.
Got like this
is like almost like I'll like a cousin
of cocaine, you know, it's like,
it's doing something to me. It's not
like getting me high. Like I'm like,
no, no, I felt shaky and creepy. And you
want to have sex. I didn't want to eat,
I didn't want to do any of that.
Did it go into your skin right here?
Fucking central nervous system,
but it makes your Dick numb. That's
like the thing. It's a numbing cream.
Like Dick would wilt with the numbing
cream and I feel it. When I was a kid,
my problem when I first
started having sex young,
I was 13 my girlfriend was 13 she talked
me into it. I didn't want to have sex.
I was cool with dry humping, but I was
cool with that. I was really aggressive.
It took like 10 months to get the
dry humping. It took a long time.
But once I got the dry humping, I
would not, she would not. We were done.
We never got hit a big wall.
We plateaued, but my problem,
well we ended up having sex and the,
after the 10th time she started crying and
I asked her, what's going on? She goes,
this is no way.
They thought it was going to be nice
and I know what the fuck I did wrong.
So I told my brother was older and he
was really experienced with girls at that
point. And the first thing
he said is, well, how long
are you fucking her? I said,
I don't know. Minute, 90
seconds. I don't know,
cause dude, that's why she started crying.
Dude, you've got to hold that shit.
So I had a problem. I was premature
ejaculation. Like that was my big problem.
So, uh, my brother gave me this cream
called, it was called stay hard.
That's how the poor of shops,
shit,
it was called the s s s t
a just without the y hard.
And I used that to just to, to, you know,
so I could last a couple more minutes,
but didn't really work.
I remember guys would always say that
there was talk about that. So yeah,
the reason one of those
girls could do the,
they put the shit on the Duke so
they don't feel anything. Yeah.
That's why they could folks along
first time, five minutes for me.
Then my shit just went right through.
It almost came by, it was fucking gay.
I was getting blown.
Me and my friend were hanging out and uh,
I had my dick through a hulk
doll and my friend is blowing me.
I didn't know what come was,
so I felt that come coming.
So I ran to the toilet and stood over it
and nothing happened. It was a real dud.
Um,
this dude that I know that was in the
porn business told me that back in the
day, they used to literally inject some
sort of chemical into the vein and their
average yet they use to make their, what
is it average yet? They still do that,
but it can fuck your dick up so bad.
It can turn purple and black
cause the blood doesn't leave it.
It's called Havard Jabber jet, I
think. I think it's cabbage yet. Yeah.
I've talked to guys who have used it
and they said one guy said that his dick
almost would've died. I, no,
no, no. I think he needed
to have the, uh, the pledge,
right.
Drained.
But he had a real problem with it
and he said he wouldn't do it again.
It got so bad in the porn industry that
they got their own form of Usada testing
porn stars for Viagara. Oh
my God. Like it wasn't fair.
Porn stars Viagara the business
would call apps. Can you imagine,
go back to those 19 days when John Holmes
had a limp snake. He's trying to
like shove it in checks or on Bola.
You remember our Bulla, he looked, he was
the fucking the worst looking guy ever.
But John Holmes, isn't that the guy
with the giant tick? Johnny White? Yeah.
All medications ever invented isn't,
isn't Viagara the most effective?
That's the one that works. The bad.
The side effects of Lisa's heart is bad
for you. I mean it was a side effect.
Yeah. But now it's wonderful, but the side
effects of it, like pretty mild stuff.
Who knows? But how many people
are dropping dead of that?
Are People dropping dead by
Agra? What does it say? You know,
fibrosis from this coverage act
is one of the, Oh, Caverject.
What is that? What's penile fibrosis?
And that sounds like a dick saying.
It's like we would know what the
fuck that is. You have to explain.
It's like psoriasis of the
Dick Penis Shit to form.
Penis shaped that way. Hmm.
I wonder what it looks like.
Maybe a curves down. That's good. Damn.
There's some chaos tonight.
I guess we missed a bunch of chaos.
So we found out that Brennan
shop is a fucking genius. Genius.
He's a soothsayer. Is that the word?
Uh, he's uh, he sees the future.
It's a prognosticator he's dead
right? He's right. He couldn't,
couldn't give it to go up
kid unless he killed Canela.
I wonder what the general public
thinks about the decision,
whether or not they think it
was a good decision. Yeah.
We're insulated to hear the
interview, but uh, yeah,
he didn't speak English anyway.
No, I forget what he thinks.
What I to he of course he, I'm sure
he thinks he won. I would like to see,
I don't think he thinks of one, but what
if he says like, you know what? I didn't,
when he deserves it as a bad decision.
What if he says something like that?
That would be ballsy.
That's a ballsy move guys up.
That said that recently in the UFC, right?
Yeah. There was someone who has that.
He won a bad decision and he's like,
you know what? I didn't win. Yeah.
Who was that? I don't know man. I
see too many fucking fights. Eh?
Are you going to be there on
October 7th for Beautiful Vegas?
Yeah. It's going to be insane, man.
He's training like a fucking
machine. I'm sure he is. Holy Shit.
His jujitsu is sharper than ever,
man.
You know it's going to be a great fight.
It's very fun. Very interesting fight.
Big Step up for Kevin Lee. Yeah,
he's a, he's an animal. He's a beast.
He's explosive. He's fast. He's got
a really good, a rear naked choke.
He likes getting the back and putting
a anacondas in body triangles.
He likes that. He likes super well
rounded. Yup. Yup. And surging,
surging young guy, you know, only like
25 but you got to kill Tanita beat him.
You do.
You've got to
kill him. He's a savage. There's no way
he's, he's going to fight to the death.
Does he rent the same house every
time when he goes up to big bear,
does he do it in a different
house? Yeah, Tito's place.
I think it was still for sale for awhile
back and we just work out at his house.
It just turn the garage out,
turn it into a little Jiu Jitsu,
the room and we just fucking work.
She's still fighting Tito? Yeah,
he's got a couple more fights going on.
He said he's supposed to fight Chael
Sonnen again and he wants to fight uh,
chocolate Dell. I think they check.
You have any interest in that? Yeah,
he needs that cash. Tina used to
have the sweetest set up up there.
He had crazy big log houses,
like two of them and one of them
is fighters would stay in that.
He was training with one of them.
He would stay in and he had a whole
gym set up with a full size octagon,
the whole deal. Pretty fucking dope.
And it was for sale for a while.
I don't know if anybody bought it,
but Tito was one of the first UFC fighters
to realize that I just fucking hit up
to big bear, man. Get that work in up
there. It's worth it. How old is Tito?
I would say now he's probably 37 38.
If I had to guess,
why do you feel when you got by going
to home? Find out how old title.
I've been aware of it like 30,000.
You know when you do a camp up there,
you feel like you've done everything
right and you've done everything you can.
Some mentally 42 just being up
there. Yeah, right. Mentally. Yeah,
I'm doing, I'm up in big bear. That's
like there's nowhere else to go.
That's the spot, right? These at as
high as you can train in I California,
California. Cow. It's smart.
You don't want to go any
higher. Um, like I said, the,
the best guys now,
most of the time they tried to work at
sea level and sleep up high for endurance
glove gun does. He doesn't
work out in Big Ben. No,
I think he works out of whatever
the fuck he does. Doubt that shit.
Cause that guy when 100% all 12 rounds
and he wasn't tired at all at the end.
Well for sure it's definitely beneficial.
The question is,
is it the maximum amount of benefit?
It doesn't need any more to be more maxi.
Why? He could imagine, check
this out, check this show. Right.
We know what big bear does
by watching glove. Good.
They're doing it the new way might
be better, but who's proven that?
Let me see a file. Let me see a high
level of fight like that. Let me see.
12 rounds like that. Oh you went down,
you trained at sea level and then slept.
I mean I could see that working,
but we already know what the glove
can style works. We already know that.
We know that. You know it's a
good point and I fuck with it.
We know it works because if
one of them works better,
if one of them works better, I think it
works. I think that would be like shit.
We don't even know if that even
works at all. No, it does work.
They don't know how it works.
Who Does it? I don't know.
I know that they've done these studies
on a oxygen utilization and you know they
do. Did they do those studies do
what's called vo two Max tests.
It's very clear like you can just watch
glow going against Canelo and I saw his
ass. I wouldn't change shit. I want to
go, you know what? This might be better.
Let's try that. If he had 10% more
endurance and he stopped, you know,
and canal training,
endurance training because of that woman.
That's what you gotta do is
heritable cardio but glove.
Kim's cardio is clearly better because
canola was dropping back. Well,
he couldn't keep the pressure.
He wanted to rest a little bit.
Glove killing was clearly in better shape.
What is on [inaudible] mom's shirt?
What are all those little gold? It
doesn't matter. As long as it's gold, man,
that's all the matters. Those glasses,
I hope they're not even real glasses.
I liked those clear lenses. Come
on, man. Those are some dope.
That's what I'm saying.
I hope they're just dope clear lenses.
Michael Cardio is so fucking terrible.
Like I literally,
I can't do 10 minutes on a treadmill.
You can do 10 minutes on a treadmill.
You've got to start at four and then
work your way up to five and then
eventually six. So this is the apnea.
Fuck it. This shit. I walk up the steps.
I'm like, ugh. Like I shouldn't be
feeling this. It's fucking awful.
You got to do something about that.
I know.
I might get the surgery again and
then go with the man because I Mac,
he was telling me take you Jitsu, but
I'm like, I'm exhausted all the time.
I really want to take it. But I
like that weird. It sucks dude.
Fuck it often is rough.
That's a rough thing man. It's
yours is all fucked up too.
Cause it's like central nervous system
stuff, right? It's not your, it's,
it's the both. Both kinds. Just science.
My fucking blow us. Speaking of which,
let's wrap this pitch up. I've got
to hit at the comedy store tonight.
Can I live a couple of dates? October
10th October 10th at the Ice House.
We're doing me and Sam
Tripoli Tin Foil Hat. Kameni.
We're going to just make fun of comedy,
uh,
conspiracy theorists and then doing his
podcast. Is that what it is? No, no.
It's a comedy show. Comedy show.
Nothing but conspiracy dairy themes. Oh,
you know, he's got that podcast.
Tinfoil hat conspiracy. Exactly.
That's why we call it that. Just cool.
Just going to, what's the date again?
Tuesday,
October 10th October 22nd Ebi,
13 Gary, Tony, lightweights, we're
going to have reach you, boogie man,
doing a four man combat Jujitsu and then
November 12th is Combat Jujitsu worlds.
One with Tony and again,
he's fighting three weeks before that
without strikes and then combat Jujitsu
worlds. One, Gary, Tony gonna
fight with palm strikes.
We're going to do the same thing. A lot
of the Mac Danzig's doing it, DL brand,
Dow's doing it. Cole Miller's doing
it. Vagner Rocha is doing it a day.
Amazon is doing it. Nathan Orchard,
Dude, it's going to be fucking nuts.
Jujitsu palm strikes. That's
a crazy lineup. Those are,
that's your lineup. Yeah.
What date is that again?
That's on Sunday,
November 12th we're doing it
at the Florentine Gardens.
What's the will and what's the a website
where they get good at checkout all of
it at,
on an Instagram APP.
Combat Jay Jay worlds pop
up, pop up. I got my a tour.
Kneeling Room only starts
September 22nd in Seattle.
And then I just go all the way through
February of doing every major city.
Oh my God. You're an animal. Just
doing, just trying to get tired. No,
I would love to do another special
man. I gotta do something. I
know you can't.
You know,
I feel worthless enough when
I'm working muscles for a lot,
so I got to just keep busy. Beautiful.
So Jim norton.com for dates.
Alright fuckers. Let's say
goodnight everybody. Bye. Bye.