Johann hari.
I got it right.
You said it right.
You are literally the first person to
have the same.
I was saint you fed that.
I once waited for six hours with a
broken arm in an emergency room because
they were calling for Joanna Harry to
come forward to anyone who gets my name
better than that.
It's just assumed that was you when you
hear you heard Joanna.
I could all but I was lying that light,
right.
We pig or be like Fox.
I want to help me so they have to get my
normal mind.
I would have done what went down.
What went down with your arm.
I just,
I fell and I tried to do nothing.
No glamorous story too.
I fell down a staircase.
I wasn't even drunk.
I wasn't even fucked on anything.
I just fell down the stairs.
It's right.
It's Daniel wasn't even a victim of
domestic violence,
you know,
like no,
no.
Uh,
surrounding narrative that we made that
an interesting story,
sadly.
So give me your,
if you had like a one paragraph take on
depression,
sure.
What is your take on depression?
So this is why I wrote this book,
lost connections and covering the real
causes of depression and anxiety and the
real solutions.
So
I wanted to understand why does
depression and anxiety,
what is depression?
Anxiety seems to be rising so much.
It's very personal to me.
When I was a teenager,
I had gone to my doctor.
I had explained that I was in this deep
sense of pain.
And all my doctor did was telling me a
biological story just said,
basically your brain's broken.
And all he did was give me drugs,
right?
And drugs play a role in treating
people.
But I was still depressed all that time.
I was taking these drugs,
right?
Most of the time.
And after 13 years ago,
I thought,
right,
I need to understand what's really going
on here.
So I ended up going on this big,
long journey,
over 40,000 miles interviewing the
leading experts in the world,
and what causes depression and anxiety
and what solves them.
And what I discovered is the,
we've,
we've told ridiculously simplistic story
to people about what depression is and
how to solve it.
That until I was a teenager.
Um,
and I went to my doctor,
I thought depression was all in my head,
meaning,
you know,
you just been week,
he'd be in a Percy basically and then
the next day,
10 years,
I thought it was all in my head.
Meaning you know,
it's a chemical imbalance in your brain.
What I discovered is a,
the overwhelming evidence from the World
Health Organization,
leading medical body in the world and
loads of other places is there are real
biological factors that can make you
more sensitive to this stuff.
But the causes of depression,
anxiety are overwhelming in the way
we're living there with these nine
causes,
depression,
anxiety for which I could find
scientific evidence,
seven of which in the way we're living
and some of which are rising,
which explains this kind of epidemic and
that opens up a whole different way of
finding solutions.
Now when you are young and you were
experiencing depression,
how would you categorize it?
Like what,
how would you describe it if you had to
describe it to someone who didn't
understand depression?
Yeah.
Try try to keep this amount of fist away
from sharks.
I think I'll move a bit closer to me.
Yeah.
I think depression,
depression is despair spreading.
Everyone has moments of hopelessness in
their lives,
right?
Right.
It's that spreading further,
but I think one of the things I learned
is a deeper way of thinking about this,
which is everyone listening to this,
everyone watching this knows
they have natural physical needs,
right?
You need food.
You need water.
You need clean air.
You need
warmth.
If I took those things away from you,
you would be a real trouble real fast.
Right?
Right.
This is equally strong evidence that
human beings have natural psychological
needs,
right?
You've got to feel you belong.
You've got to fill.
Your life has meaning and purpose.
You've got to feel that people see you
and value you.
You've got to feel that you've got
autonomy.
You've got to feel that you've got a
future that makes sense,
and our culture is good at lots of
things.
I'm glad to be alive today,
but our culture has been getting less
and less good at meeting these deep,
underlying psychological needs for lots
of people.
And that is the key reason.
So only one,
but it's the key reason why we have this
rising depression,
anxiety epidemic.
That can sound a bit weird in the
abstracts.
I can give you some specific examples if
you want.
Okay,
sure.
So I'll give you one example.
I noticed that lots of the people I know
who are depressed and anxious that
depression and anxiety focuses around
their work,
right?
Start to think what's going on here.
So I started to look for evidence about
how people feel about their work.
Best Research on this was done by
Gallup,
the opinion poll company,
massive detailed study to a couple of
years.
They found the figures for how people
feel about working in the u s and other
comparable countries.
What they found is 13% of us,
one 3% basically like our work,
most of the time we get energy from it.
63% of us or what they called sleep
working.
So they like their work.
Don't hate their work,
they're just kind of enduring it.
And 24% of people fucking hate their
work,
right?
Fear and dread it.
So I was quite struck by that when I
looked at it.
That means 87% of people don't like the
thing they're doing most of the time.
That's incredible.
It's so striking.
And bear in mind,
this thing that we don't like is spread
over even more of our lives.
Right?
Average person answers their first email
at 7:48 AM and leaves work at 7:15 PM so
this is most of our waking lives.
We're doing something we don't like.
I started to think,
could there be some connection between
that and this epidemic of awful sort of
forms of despair,
anxiety,
depression,
addiction.
So I start to look for,
scientists had studied this.
I discovered an amazing Australian
social scientist called Professor
Michael Marmot,
who I got to know who discovered the key
to what causes depression at work,
right?
There's several aspects of this.
I can tell you the story,
how he discovered it.
If you want to think it's an amazing
story,
but the core of it is if you go to work
and you are controlled,
so you feel you have low or no control,
you are radically more likely to become
depressed.
You're even more likely to have a stress
related heart attack.
And I think the reason is clear then
going a bit further than professor
moment does.
Um,
human beings need to feel our lives have
meaning.
Right?
And if you're controlled all the time,
you don't feel like your life has
meaning.
You don't feel like you,
it disrupts your ability to create
meaning out of your work and it makes
you feel like shit.
Right.
That makes sense.
And one of the things,
so one thing that was really important
to me in everything I was learning in
the research for loss connections was
there was this,
it required this kind of shift in my
mind because what I was basically told
by my doctor is,
your pain is a malfunction,
right?
He said,
you know,
we know what causes depression.
It's just some people naturally have low
levels of Serotonin in their brains.
Um,
you know,
you're clearly one of them that that's
what's going on here.
And one thing that was really striking,
speaking to the leading experts in the
world is that story is just not true.
There are real biological factors.
There are real things that happen in
your brain,
obviously.
But actually a professor Andrew Skull at
Princeton University says it's deeply
misleading and unscientific to say
depression is just caused by low
Serotonin,
right?
This is just not true.
Um,
but,
but one thing that was so important to
me looking at these nine real causes of
depression and anxiety was realizing
actually our pain makes sense,
right?
If you're depressed,
if you're anxious,
you've been told basically that you're a
bit crazy.
There's something not working,
but actually you're not a machine with
broken parts,
right?
You're a human being with unmet needs
and that requires a very different set
of responses.
So you think about,
I start to think,
well,
let's think about that problem with
work,
right?
Most people feel they've got no control
at work or low control,
and it's making them feel terrible.
They're not wrong to feel that,
right?
They've got a need as human beings and
it's not being met.
How can we deal with this?
And I learned there's a really
interesting strategy to deal with this.
Now.
This is something some people will be
able to do as individuals,
but it's something we can actually
change as a society so far more people
could do it.
I went to Baltimore and I interviewed a
woman.
Could Meredith Kio young woman,
meredith used to go to bed every Sunday
night just fucking sick with anxiety.
Right?
She would,
she would,
she had an office job.
It wasn't the worst office job in the
world.
Right?
She wasn't being bullied,
she wasn't being harassed,
but she just,
she just felt like she just couldn't
bear the thought of the next 40 years of
her life.
We're going to be this right.
And one day with her husband,
Josh,
she is quite bold thing.
Josh was a working class guy from
Baltimore since he was a teenager.
He that he'd,
um,
worked in bike stores and you know,
working at a bike store,
your viewers will know it's insecure
work.
It's controlled.
You do it boss tells you that you can
get vacations and less the boss,
you know,
it's nice to,
yeah,
and Josh and his colleagues in the
store,
they didn't hate their boss.
He wasn't a particularly bad boss as far
as policies go.
They quite liked him as a person.
But one day they just asked,
what does that boss actually do?
Right?
We fixed all the bikes and he seems to
make all the money was what's going on
here.
They decided to do an experiment.
They,
they,
they sit up at a different bike store,
arrival,
bike store.
It's called Baltimore Bicycle Works and
it works on a different principle.
So most people listening to this will
work in corporations.
Right?
Top down,
you do what the boss says.
It's modeled like an army that is a very
recent human invention rights and comes
along in the late 19th century.
What they did was try different model.
They called democratic cooperatives.
So at Baltimore Bicycle Works,
they take all the big decisions together
about their work.
They vote,
uh,
they share out the good tasks in the
shitty tasks.
I know I can just get stuck with all the
They share the profits obviously.
So they control their environment
together.
They're like a little tribe that control
their environment instead of an army
with one guy at the top controlling it.
And one thing that was so fascinating
spending time with them,
she's totally in finding a professor
Michael Marmots research about what
causes depression at work is how many of
them talked about having been really
depressed and anxious when they were,
when they were working in this
controlled way and their depression and
anxiety had largely gone.
It's to have bad days of course.
But there that kind of nagging
depression and anxiety had gone away in
this different environment.
And as Josh said to me,
there's no reason why any business
should work in this top down controlled
way that makes people depressed.
It's not even more efficient.
And study at Cornell University found
that democratic businesses grow four
times faster than,
um,
than,
uh,
you know,
top down businesses.
And I think,
well,
this opens up is a different way of
thinking about depression.
So what we've done up to now is we've
said to depressed and anxious people,
the job of fixing this is basically on
you buddy,
right?
Maybe if you're lucky,
your family,
maybe if you're lucky,
your doctor,
but actually once you begin to realize
that the reasons why people are
depressed and anxious makes sense.
This is just one of many reasons why
people are depressed and anxious.
It also,
one of things is fueling the addiction
crisis,
which you can talk about if you want.
And once you realize it,
it makes sense.
You suddenly realize what you've got to
do is deal with the problem in the world
as well as the problem just in the
individual skull.
Do you see what I mean?
Yeah.
So you're focusing on work environments,
right?
Um,
and there's,
there's many reasons,
as you were saying,
for,
for people being depressed.
Have you,
when you talk about work environments,
have you researched people who are
independent,
people who work for themselves,
people who you know,
make things or make furniture or what
have you.
Yeah.
And that was one of the things as well
at Baltimore Bicycle access,
most people are so removed from the
product,
from their work,
right,
from the outcome of their work.
To give you an example of a guy I
interviewed a lot,
um,
guy called Joe,
he works in Philly and he worked when I
met him in a paint,
a paint store,
right?
And Joe's job was to turn up,
but whatever it was,
eight 30 in the morning,
stay there all day until 7:00 PM and
just take your order for pain.
And then when you ask for a specific
shade,
his job was to put it in a machine that
shook it,
right?
And then just give you the paint.
That's it.
That was his whole life week after week,
year after year.
And Joe was acutely depressed and Joe
was really,
felt really guilty about telling me how
depressed he was.
Right?
He kept saying,
look,
I know how lucky I am.
Um,
but he felt like it felt like shit.
And he said,
I remember him saying to me,
look,
I know people need pain.
Right?
It's not,
I know that have some function here in
the economy,
I think to put it quite like that,
but this is not giving me any sense of
meaning.
But one of the real mysteries to me
about Joe and for that had to learn
about one of the other causes of
depression and anxiety and solutions to
that was so joe,
a lot of people,
some of my relatives who do work like
that,
that basically the margin for them to
change their lives,
it's really narrow,
right?
Like one of my closest relatives,
it's a struggling single mom.
Um,
you know,
she's,
she works every hour.
She can,
she get something today collapses,
right?
The idea of saying to her,
your job now is to democratize your
workplace is ridiculous,
right?
She can't do that.
That's why most of lost connections is
about how we can change the culture to
free people up to make the changes they
need to make.
Although there are things can do that I
go through in the book,
but the,
the,
a lot of people,
um,
how to put it,
they hit,
we live in such an individualistic
culture that people think what you're
saying is you need to do it yourself.
But Joe was in an unusual position in
that Joe,
uh,
loved fishing,
right?
He'd fished I think 20 of the 50 states,
and he'd recently been to Florida and he
said,
you know,
when I was in Florida,
I am,
I realized I could just quit this job.
I could go and live as a fisherman in
Florida.
I'd make less money.
I'd be much happier.
Right.
And there was somehow I knew as I was
talking to joe and I filled it up with
them over the years that followed,
I knew he wasn't going to go to Florida.
Right.
And I remember,
no,
it's just the way he said it,
it was a wistful longing and not musical
idea,
not something based on a real
possibility.
That's a really good way of putting it.
But I remember the last time I saw him
and he walked off I and I felt like a
complete Dick for doing this,
but I shouted after cause public.
So it's Toni Jo go to Florida.
Right?
Right.
And one of these,
it really troubled me was why are so,
so a lot of people are trapped in the
way our culture works,
which is why we've got to change the
culture.
And I talk about specific concrete
things that have been tried in other
countries that have freed people up and
have reduced depressions.
I'm sure we'll get to that.
But if you think about an individual
like Joe,
what's going on there?
And one of the things I learned from
this amazing professor Tim Kasser in
Illinois,
Knox College in Illinois is I think one
of the things,
this is one of the hardest courses or
depression to learn about.
Cause I realized how much it played out
in my own life as well.
So just like we all know junk food has
taken over our diets and made us
physically sick,
right?
Something similar has happened with our
minds are kind of junk values have taken
over our minds.
When I started learning about this,
I remember I ate nothing but junk food
for like 10 years from my twenties
basically.
And I remember one day,
it makes it even the story,
even Saturday,
it was Christmas Eve in 2009 at
lunchtime I went to my local KFC and I
ordered,
set my order,
which I won't even repeat it to you
cause it was so disgusting.
And the guy behind the counter said,
oh yeah man,
we're so glad you're here.
I was like,
okay.
And he said,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
And he went back and he came out and the
whole staff fucking massive Christmas
card for me and they'd written it to our
best customer.
And my heart is like sang because I look
at this and I suddenly realized this
wasn't even the fried chicken shop I
went to the most.
Right.
So I was at an extreme end of the junk
food spectrum.
Right?
I'm not anymore.
I've relapsed a bit lately,
but,
um,
but so we all know how that works,
right?
Junk food appeals to the part of us
evolve to what nutrients,
but it tricks that it's not actually a
part of you that wants nutrients.
It actually makes you sick.
Right.
And what Professor Casio Fan,
this is the similar things happen in our
mind.
So,
um,
weirdly,
so for thousands of years,
philosophers have said,
if you think life is about,
you know,
money and status and showing off,
you're going to feel like shit.
Right?
But it's not an exact quote from
Confucius,
but as the gist of what he said.
Right.
But weirdly,
no one had scientifically investigated
this until,
uh,
until Professor Cassa 25 years ago.
So he knew that basically to put it
crudely,
there's two kinds of motives that human
beings have,
right?
You've got them.
I've got them.
Jamie's got them.
Everyone's got them.
Right.
Um,
the first that might just imagine,
imagine if you play the piano,
right?
I'm totally,
I'm musical.
But imagine if you played the piano.
If you play the piano in the morning,
cause you love it.
And it gives you joy.
That's called an intrinsic motive to
play the piano,
right?
You're not doing it to get anything out
there.
You're just doing it because you love
it.
Right.
The experience is the point.
Now I imagine he played the piano in a
dive bar,
you know,
to,
to pay the rent and you don't like it,
right?
Or you play the piano because your
parents really want you to be a piano
maestro.
Don't know there's a woman who's really
into pns,
so you learn the piano to impress her.
That would be an extrinsic reason to
play the piano,
right?
You're not doing it for the thing
itself.
You're not,
you're not.
You're doing it to get something out of
it.
Right.
And what Professor Cassa discovered
loads of really important things about
this,
but there's a few.
We're all a mixture of these things,
but we move throughout our lives.
And what we discovered is the more you
are driven by extrinsic values,
the more your life is guided by how you
look to the outside by you know,
what you're trying to get out of life
rather than enjoying it.
The more you will become depressed and
anxious by quite a large margin.
There's loads of studies that show this.
Um,
and also he found that we have become
much more obsessed with much more driven
by these values over the last 30 years,
but all sorts of reasons,
partly because we,
from the minute we're born,
we're immersed in a machine that tells
us life is about consumption,
right?
About externally consuming things more
18 month old children know what the
Mcdonald's m means,
the know their own last name,
right?
So this,
this machine constantly geared towards
getting us to think extra.
As I mentioned,
imagine an advert that said to,
you know Joe,
you look great today.
You,
you smell great,
you're doing fine,
right?
You don't need to buy anything today.
That would from the perspective of the
advertising industry be the worst,
worst advice ever.
I would make you want to buy anything.
So this movement towards these kinds of
junk values and any shows,
lots of reasons why these junk values
make us feel like share.
One is it just corrodes the quality of
your relationships,
right?
If your wife,
if you think your wife loves you,
not because you're you,
but because you're rich,
because you look good or for some other
reason,
then think about the insecurity that
enters into that relationship.
You know?
Oh,
right.
If you suddenly got fat or if you
suddenly lost all your money,
it's over.
It creates that.
That sand of insecurity enters all your
relationships.
The more you're extrinsically motivated,
the more insecure your relationships
will be in the worst you'll feel.
Or another example would be something
that really makes human beings feel good
or what are called flow states right
there.
Moments when you're doing something you
love the meats writing view.
I'm sure it's partly broadcasting,
partly working out as you can see it.
It's not working out for me.
Uh,
the,
the where you just get into the zone and
time seems to collapse and you're in
that moment,
right?
But what x thinking extrinsically,
what being dominated by these junk
Bonnie's does is it jolts you out of the
intrinsic vice.
Imagine you'd go back to the piano
example.
If you're playing the piano just because
you love it and then suddenly you think,
am I the best piano player in Los
Angeles today?
Right?
How are these people in this room
thinking about my piano playing?
How much am I gonna be paid for this
piano player?
You can see how that would jolt you out
of the flow state.
Right?
People,
the more we are driven by extrinsic
values,
the less we get into flow states and the
worst we feel.
And there's lots of other reasons as
well one took about,
but well that completely makes sense
that relying constantly on other
people's approval and recognition and
love in order for you to be satisfied
and happy isn't,
is not a good recipe for getting by in
this life smoothly.
Um,
when you were young and you were
experiencing depression as you called
it,
what was the root cause of it?
So in my case it was a,
I mean there are a few things going on
and this is difficult for me to talk
about,
but,
um,
one of the people I've got to know for
the loss connections is this amazing guy
called Dr. Vincent Felitti and San
Diego.
And if you don't mind,
I'll tell you his story first and I'll
tell you why.
What made me realize about myself and
actually why I was very resistant to
this.
So it's going very resistant,
resistant to this insight that he had
and really did not want to absorb it.
Um,
so he actually made this discovery and
sca cycle talking about a whole other
subject,
but trust me,
I,
it gets to depression.
It led to an incredible breakthrough in
depression.
So in the mid 1980s,
doctor Felitti is doing all this
research into obesity,
basically,
Kaiser permanente or not for profit
medical provider down in San Diego,
um,
just had a massive fucking problem with
obesity,
right?
There is just hugely growing problem
with obesity and,
uh,
they were trying everything and nothing
was worth like giving people nutritional
advice.
That stage,
it wasn't working right?
So they basically said to him,
they gave him quite a big budget and
they're like,
just figuring out what the hell is going
on here.
So he went away and he started,
he started to work within,
think it was about 350 extremely obese
people,
right?
People who are way more than 400 pounds.
And um,
he starts doing all sorts of different
research with them.
And at one day he just had this,
this kind of almost stupidly simple
thought.
He thought,
what if they just literally stopped
eating and we gave them the nutrients
they need?
Would they just lose loads of weight and
then come down to a healthy weight?
So they obviously we'd like massive
medical supervision.
They did this right?
People,
they just monitor them and they stop
eating and they give them loads of
vitamins and everything and it worked
right?
They did in fact lose loads of weight.
But then something happened that no one
expected.
There's a woman,
I'm going to call Susan to protect her
medical confidentiality.
She been over 400 pounds.
She got down to 138 pounds and one and
everyone's celebrating.
They think vincent is like a miracle
worker.
And then one day she freaks the fuck
out.
Starts Massively obsessively eating.
And very quickly she's back to not quite
where she was,
but close.
Right?
And Vincent sits with Susan and he's
like,
what happened?
And she's like,
I don't know.
And he said,
well,
tell me about the day you cracked.
Right.
Tell out something had happened to her
that hadn't happened to her in I think
ever or sitting in a very long time.
A man hit on her right when she'd been
huge,
you know,
huge overweight,
no matter down to a man hit on her.
And that was the trigger,
right?
And he's like,
okay.
So they talk a lot more and it's like,
when was it you started to put on weight
for her?
It was when she was 11.
Um,
and so he's like,
well,
what?
What happened when you were 11 that
didn't happen when you were 10 that
didn't happen when you were 12 or 50.
And she said,
oh,
well that's when my grandfather started
raping me and he,
this just really start with him.
So he starts talking to the group and
he's got about 55% of the extremely
overweight people in the group.
I have 50% people in the group has had
on their way after being sexually
abused.
Right.
Which was an extraordinary,
far more than the wider population is
like,
wait,
what's going on here?
This is really,
Susan said to him,
overweight is overlooked.
And that's what I wanted to be.
Right?
So this thing that had looked like a
pathology,
right?
And it is a pathology.
One sense being extremely overweight
will kill you.
Suddenly didn't look like a sign of
madness.
It was actually performing a function
that we couldn't see,
right?
It was,
it was,
uh,
it was protecting them from sexual
attention.
But you know,
this is a small group.
It's a small study.
So Vincent wanted to get a lot more
research on this.
This is where it led to the breakthrough
in depression.
So he set it up with funding from the
CDC,
the Center for Disease Control,
kind of gold plated a organization in
this,
uh,
in the u s for this kind of research.
Everyone who came to Kaiser Permanente
in the next,
uh,
I think it was a year,
for anything,
whether you broke your leg,
you had migraines,
you had schizophrenia,
anything got given,
a questionnaire and it asked about,
it had two parts.
Firstly,
it said,
did any of these 10 bad things happen to
you when you were a kid?
Right?
Could be sexual abuse,
neglect,
that kind of thing.
And then it says,
have you had any of these problems as an
adult obesity,
injecting drug use?
And at the last minute they added
depression,
right?
By luck.
So when they got the results back,
the CDC,
we're just like,
what the fuck is this?
For every category of childhood trauma
you went through,
you weren't radically more likely to
become depressed.
If you had six of those categories,
you were 3000,
100% more likely to have attempted
suicide as an adult.
If you were,
um,
if you'd had six of them,
you were 4,000,
600% more likely to become an adult
injecting drug user.
Right?
And there's a debate about why this is,
and I'm going beyond what Vincent says
now,
but boom,
what the science says,
and this comes up,
brings it back to my experience.
So I had,
when I was a kid,
I had expressed some very extreme acts
of violence from an adult in my family.
You know,
my mother had been very ill and when I
was a kid,
my dad was mostly in another country.
And I experience,
he's really,
really extreme,
um,
and frightening acts of violence.
And I
sound stupid.
But until I went to see Vinson,
if you'd asked me,
do you think that played a role in your
depression?
I would have said no.
Right?
And it makes me realize one of the
reasons why I clung to this very
simplistic chemical imbalance theory of
depression for so long,
because I did not want to give the
individual who behave so appallingly
towards me,
that sense of power over me.
I didn't want to,
I didn't want to think about that stuff.
I want it to cauterize it.
I wanted to cut it out of my life.
I would say,
well,
okay,
that's bad thing that happens to you,
but you know,
but the,
but the reason why I stayed with this
and the reason why I kept,
you know,
spent this time with Vincent in San
Diego and the reason why I kept going
with all these different causes of
depression and anxiety is because once
you understand what's happened,
you can find solutions who otherwise
didn't find,
there was a second stage of doctor
[inaudible] research.
That to me was so powerful.
It's one of the reasons why I make
myself talk about this now.
So if you'd indicate it on the form that
you'd experienced one of these forms of
childhood trauma,
the next time you went back to your
doctor,
you weren't called back,
but the next time you went to your
doctor,
your doctor was told to say something to
you like,
hi Joe.
I see on the form you indicated that you
were violently abused when you were
child.
I'm really sorry that happened to you.
That should never have happened.
Would you like to talk about it and
quite a lot of people said thank you,
but no,
I don't want to talk about that,
but a lot of people did want to about an
average conversations is lost the five
minutes and then the doctor said,
I can refer you to a therapist to talk
more about this if you want,
and they were monitored to see what
happened.
The results were kind of incredible.
There was an enormous fall in depression
and anxiety just from the five minute
meeting.
Right,
and from the obvious,
people refer to therapy,
so an even bigger fool and it seems to
be,
again,
this is going to be this bit,
it's going to be on what Vincent Said
said.
He said,
I asked him,
I said No.
I think partly what happens is it's
related to shame,
right?
If you are a kid and you experience some
kind of abuse,
you,
you can basically do one of two things,
right?
You can either say,
look,
I'm fucked here.
Right?
I've unlike a pinball being smacked
around a pinball machine because I can't
stop this happening and I just got
accepted and I'm really vulnerable.
Or you can say,
this must be my fault at some level,
right?
Um,
which is what I did.
And of course it's what you've been told
anyway by whoever is treating you badly
in almost every case.
And a weight thing is if you tell
yourself is your full Angelie,
you gain a sort of weird internal power,
right?
You're not the pymble being smacked
around the machine.
You're the person controlling the
pimples sheet.
You can change your behavior,
right?
You can't,
you can't change other,
the pencils paper.
So you kind of develop this kind of
shame.
And one of the things we know is,
and there's plenty of evidence from
this.
People like Professor Jim Pennebaker
have shown it.
Shame is a catastrophe for human
psychology,
right?
We know,
for example,
openly gay man died two years later than
closeted gay men in the age crisis,
even when they got medical care at the
same time,
right?
Shame destroys you.
It makes you sick.
And what Vincent found was this model of
releasing your shame,
which led to the significant,
I remember one of the letters he got was
from an old woman,
she was in the 80s who just said she had
been sexually abused when she was a kid.
And she said,
thank you for asking.
I thought I'd die and no one would ever
know.
And you can see how that release of
shame would have a transformative effect
on people.
Wow.
So for you,
you had this traumatic experience of
violence when you were young,
you were depressed,
you were trying to figure out what the
source of this was,
whether it was some sort of a chemical
imbalance in your brain.
Now,
when,
when they say chemical imbalances is in
the brain,
have,
are they capable of measuring the level
of Serotonin in your brain?
Yes.
So there's a huge debate about this.
She couldn't,
for example,
do autopsies.
Um,
there's a big debate about,
but that's when someone's dead.
Yeah.
But there's a big debate about,
so there seems to be,
most scientists agree low,
not all of them.
And there are some people who dissent
from this,
but most scientists agree low serotonin
correlates with depression,
right?
But it's not the same thing in the same
way stretch marks correlate with
obesity,
but they're not the cause of obesity
that the product of it.
So there are real brain changes that
happen,
which I write about in Los Connections
and important to say that,
um,
that I don't think they should be
described as chemical imbalances.
But one of these,
it was really shocking to me,
was a,
one of the British experts on this Dr.
David Healey said to me,
um,
you can't even say the Sarah,
the idea that depression causes
serotonin.
You can't even say that that theory is
discredited because it was never
credited.
There was never a time when half of the
scientists in the field believe that.
Right?
The reason that story got sold to me and
most people listening to this in the 90s
is because it worked really well for the
drug companies,
right?
Because what it makes it sound like if
you've just got a chemical imbalance,
the solution is just to give you
chemicals.
Now it's important to say chemical anti
depressants do play a role.
We can measure that.
And there's a slightly nuanced point to
make about this,
which is,
so depression is measured by something
called the Hamilton Square,
right?
I've always felt sorry for whoever
Hamilton was.
The only way we remember him is by how
fucking miserable we all.
But anyway,
so how to scale goes from one where you
are,
you know,
dancing around in ecstasy or on ecstasy
to 51 when you would be acutely
suicidal.
Right?
And to give you a sense of what movement
on the Hamilton scale looks like,
if you move six points on the Hamilton
scale,
sorry,
if your sleep patterns get better,
you'll gain six points on the Hamilton
scale.
And if your sleep patterns deteriorate,
so you have a baby is crying all the
time,
you're generally lose six points on the
Hamilton scale,
right?
So professor Irving Kirsch at Harvard
medical school did the best research on
this,
and what he found is on average chemical
anti depressants move people 1.8 points
on the Hamilton scale,
right?
About a third of what?
Improving your sleep patterns does.
It's important to say that's an average.
So some people do get more than that.
Some people get less,
and you can see 1.8 points is not
nothing,
right?
If you're acutely suicidal,
1.8 points can take the edge off.
There's real value in giving people that
relief,
but it's not solving the problem for
most people.
I thought I was weird for being on
antidepressants for so long and
remaining depressed.
Turns out I was totally typical.
Couldn't doctor Steven [inaudible] is
professor of psychology has done a lot
of work on this.
Between 65 and 80% of people taking
chemical entity depressants become
depressed again.
Right?
So you can see that's not 100% there is
some balance.
Well isn't that,
that's what a bill of fives for right is
a bill of fire is the idea that your
antidepressant is not enough.
So he take abilify on top of your
antidepressant,
which is supposed to help you even
further,
and it's one of the most prescribed
medications in the country and it's an
antipsychotic.
Yeah.
Well this is terrifying.
The doling out.
I mean,
one in five Americans will take a
psychiatric drug in their lifetime,
right?
It's a sign of a,
uh,
a cultural madness that we are doing
this right where the,
now this is not to say that I want to
stress again,
there is a real value in these drugs.
There is some value to them,
there's some
value to them,
but they're most certainly over
prescribed and there's most certainly
actual methods that you could use to
improve your life without any sort of
chemical intervention that are readily
available to everybody.
Like exercise and diet.
Yeah,
but those things aren't stressed when
you,
when you go to a doctor,
the first thing the doctor doesn't say
is,
listen,
what we need to do is get you to start
running and get you start eating really
healthy.
And then let's talk about Antifa.
You're totally right.
There's a $10 billion industry and that
doctor giving you drugs,
that's a crazy numbers you just said.
And,
and I think billion dollars.
He said,
this is why,
although there is a real value for those
drugs,
would the the the why this is the first
primary and for most people only option
that's offered and one things that
really helped me change think about this
differently and it fits exactly what
you're saying joe is I went to interview
this South African psychiatrist,
got Derrick summerfield and Derek
happened to be in Cambodia when chemical
antidepressants were first introduced.
Right.
That's where they were interested in
energy.
He was just there when they were first
introduced in Cambodia.
They thought that would have been one of
the last countries in the world.
They made their way to and the Cambodian
doctors didn't know what they were.
Right.
So they're like,
what is this?
And he explained and they said,
we don't need them.
We've already got antidepressants.
And he said,
what do you mean?
He thought they were going to talk about
some kind of like herbal remedy or
something.
Instead they told them a story.
There was a farmer in their community
who one day worked in the rice fields
who one day had stood on a land mine and
got his leg blown off.
So they gave him an artificial limb and
he went back to work in the rice fields.
But apparently it's super painful to
work in water when your legs been,
you know,
we've got an artificial limit.
You legs been blown off and I'm guessing
it's pretty traumatic cause he's in the
fields where he's been blown up.
He starts to cry all day,
doesn't want to get out of bed.
Classic depression,
right.
They said to Derek,
we gave him an antidepressant.
He said,
what was it?
They said?
They explained,
they went and sat with him.
They listened to him.
They realized that his pain made sense.
They realize that actually make Patrick
sense that he felt so bad.
They figured if they bought him a cow,
he could become a dairy farmer.
He wouldn't be in these fields where he
was being fucked up.
So they bought him a car.
Within a couple of weeks he stopped
crying.
They said to Derek CC,
Dr Kao was an antidepressant.
That's what you mean right now.
If you've been raised to think about
depression the way we have,
we've been propagandized to that sounds
like a bad joke,
right?
I went to my doctor for an
antidepressant.
It gave me a cow.
If you understand what all these experts
who I met had been interviewed
extensively,
I've been trying to tell us it's going
to know what the World Health
Organization has been trying to tell us.
Those Cambodian doctors knew intuitively
what they knew through the science,
which is our pain.
Makes Sense,
right?
You're not crazy to feel like shit.
You've got unmet needs and what you need
his help to get your needs met.
Now some of the things you're talking
about are really good examples.
Exercise,
Diet.
Some of them are these bigger
intervention.
So one of the heroes,
a lot of connections is this doctor I've
got to know called Sam Arrington,
who,
who is based in,
in east London actually,
where near where I lived for a long
time,
very poor part of east London.
And sadly he was never my doctor,
but Sam was really uncomfortable because
he's a general practitioners,
general doctor.
Loads of people were coming to him with
depression and anxiety.
Right.
And He'd been told him his medical
training,
even though he knew the science was much
more complicated than this to just say
to people,
you know,
you've just got a chemical imbalance in
your brain and just drug them.
Right.
And Sam thought,
right,
like me,
he's not opposed to the drugs.
He does give them out to some people,
but he just thought this is,
this is not right.
This isn't dealing with the reason they
feel so shit.
Right.
So he tried a different approach.
He noticed that one of the factors that
was making the depressed and anxious was
how profoundly lonely they were.
It's a study to ask the obvious in
Britain,
but figures,
it's sort of Britain by Cuban American
examples to study the acid Americans.
How many close friends do you have who
you could call on in a crisis?
When they started doing the study years
ago,
the most common answer was five.
Today,
the most common answer is none,
right?
It's not the average,
but more people say none than any other
options.
So you think about that of people in
America are more people in the United
States have nobody to turn to when
there's a crisis than any other option,
right?
So you think about what life must be
like when you're alone.
That is not the species.
We are the reason why you and I sit in
here,
Joe,
in La,
the reason why we're alive is because
our ancestors in Africa on the savannas
of Africa,
what unbelievably good at one thing,
right?
They weren't bigger than the animals
they took down,
but they were much better at cooperating
then the animals they took down.
We exist because our ancestors formed
into tribes.
Every instinct we have is to live in a
tribe right?
Bees need a hive.
Humans need a tribe.
We are the first humans ever to try to
disband our tribes.
Right.
No one's ever done that before in human
history and it's quite running.
Yeah.
Well,
what do you,
let me stop you there because we're
getting deep in the weeds here.
What do you say to someone who is happy
with what they do lives,
uh,
a fulfilled life exercises and is still
depressed.
Yes.
I thought a lot about this provoked me
to come back to the thing about east
London.
I know this is,
this is an issue with a lot of people.
I,
yeah,
I know people that worship at the altar
of science and modern medicine that
firmly believe that all depression is
because of some sort of chemical
imbalance in the brain and anything that
debates that are anything that disputes
that notion is,
is pisses them off.
You know?
I understand that.
And I would have been like that for me.
That,
yeah,
of course.
I was looking at a a years.
Do you get that?
Some people responding that way?
Sure,
of course.
Of course.
I think the,
so the World Health Organization is the
leading medical body in the world,
right?
They did a survey study of all the best
evidence and they explained very clearly
that the mental health,
um,
it's a social indicator,
right?
It has social causes,
it needs social solutions as well as
individual solutions,
the science.
So this is overwhelming.
You won't get many scientists who say,
uh,
in fact it struggled to find any
scientists who say depression is purely
a biological phenomenon.
Right?
Pretty much everyone agrees there's some
social and psychological component.
I think when we,
it's a weird disconnect between what the
scientists know and what the public is
told.
Right?
I don't know anyone who went to their
doctor who,
um,
apart from this wonderful doctor in east
London and we can talk about who went
with depression.
I,
he was told anything other than a
biological story.
Minute maybe asked,
you know,
some of them were asked about childhood,
what was your childhood like?
And referred to a therapist.
But no one was talking about these wider
social causes.
No one was started.
Like,
do you feel controlled at work?
Well,
like it's a fact that could be making
you make you depressed.
But in terms of the people who,
who,
um,
who are depressed but don't,
uh,
cause there was a real mystery to me,
right?
I knew people I thought,
but this guy has got everything and he
feels he's still depressed.
What's going on here?
I think there's two things to say about
that.
One is I started to,
uh,
for various reasons for research,
for something else,
I was reading some like feminist texts
from the early sixties.
Right?
And a really common thing that happened
in the early sixties is women would go
to their doctor and they'd say,
doctor,
there's something really wrong with my
nerves,
people to talk about in terms of nerves.
Then we don't do that anymore.
Uh,
something really wrong with my nerves
because I've got everything a woman
could possibly want.
I've got a husband who doesn't beat me.
I've got a car,
got a washing machine,
I've got two kids,
but I feel like shit.
Right?
And the doctor would go,
you're right,
and give a value.
Now if we could travel back in time and
speak to those women,
what we'd say is right,
you've got everything you could possibly
want by the standards of the culture.
But it's standards,
the culture just wrong,
right?
As a w as a woman,
as a human being,
you need more than just a washing
machine and a car,
right?
You need a fulfilling life.
You need to be a meaning and purpose.
And a very similar thing I think is
happening today if you,
so if we don't want to speak to people,
he said,
I've got everything I could want,
but I feel like share.
So tell me,
tell me about your life.
Very often they're working really hard
in prestigious jobs that they don't
like.
They don't enjoy hour by hour to buy
things that don't give them pleasure.
It comes back to this hijacking by junk
values that we're talking about.
The professor Tim Kasser discovered.
So what you've got is because we've been
told a totally misleading story about
what makes us satisfied and happy as
human beings.
I think it comes up again and again in
the interviews you do.
Cause we'd been taught in different ways
because we've been told him misleading
story about that we live our lives
according to the wrong script.
We feel like shit.
And rather than question the script,
we think there must be something wrong
with us biologically.
Now there are biological contributions.
It's important to say that,
but one of these,
it really blew my mind on this was um,
Ainsley this woman's amazing social
scientists could talk of Bretford in
Berkeley.
She did this research.
It's kind of simple research.
It just asked.
Um,
if you consciously decided you were
going to spend more hours a day trying
to make yourself happier,
would you actually become happier?
Right?
And they did this research.
She didn't do a loan obviously
with our colleagues in the United
States,
uh,
Japan,
Russia,
and Taiwan.
And what they found was in the u s if
you try to make yourself happier
consciously,
you do not become happier in the other
countries.
If you try to make yourself happier,
you do become happier.
And they were like,
what's going on?
So they did more research.
And what they discovered was in the u s
and suspend a lot more time here,
but in Britain as well,
if you try to make yourself happier,
you tried to do something generally for
yourself.
You buy something for yourself.
Your biggest Alpha [inaudible] tried to
get a promotion in the other countries.
Generally if you try to make yourself
happy or you do something for someone
else,
right?
You tried to help your friends,
your family,
your community.
We're what countries?
Just Japan,
Russia,
and China is most of the race stress
this,
that if you,
this is a part of their culture that if
you want to be happy,
you do something for someone else.
It's so implicit in the culture that
they live collectively,
that it's not even just like we wouldn't
even if you said,
do you think happiness is an
individualistic thing?
We'd be like,
what are you even talking about?
Isn't that sort of an extrinsic idea as
well?
The idea that you're going to be happy
by trying to make other people happy,
but this is a thing.
So intrinsic values are not about just
internal to yourself.
The things that you value,
so your intrinsic value could be
spending time with your kids,
right?
That was probably most people's
strongest intrinsic value.
If their parents,
it's being with their kids,
bonding with their kids,
love.
My point is if your goal is to get happy
and the way you've chosen to get happy
is I'm going to get happy by making
other people happy.
That's,
that seems very strange.
I don't think so and that's that.
If you think about where humans
shouldn't you just make other people
happy because you love them,
but that is a way of loving people and
being present with them is a way but not
as like a specific for with a specific
goal of making yourself happy.
That seems that's not why they do it.
It's not like when they were told make
yourself happy.
They had an implicit script in their
culture,
which is like,
all right,
if I want to make myself happy,
I'll spend time with other people or do
things with other people.
But if you think about it in terms of
human evolution,
it makes total sense,
right?
We think about our ancestors where they
evolved.
If you were a group,
if our ancestors had been individually,
so we're out to big up themselves as
individuals,
we wouldn't be having this conversation.
Right.
So it makes us,
we evolved as a species with instincts
that are,
there's no argument there.
The the motivation of trying to get
happy by helping other people.
It just seems there's some implicit in
the culture for most people in say China
that they wouldn't even articulate it
that way.
It's only if you force them to say,
look,
try to make yourself happier that they,
then the script becomes obvious.
It's implicit.
But this script that we have,
this idea that the way you make yourself
happier is as an individual,
you know,
just doing something for yourself and
how you start because there is not one
script in this country of how to make
yourself happy.
That I think that's of sort of
disingenuous as I did at the only way to
make yourself happy is to do that.
What,
that's not what people are trying to do.
What people were trying to do is be
successful and I don't think they
necessarily equate success with
happiness.
What would they do?
Equate success with as an alleviation of
debt and the alleviation of problems and
alleviate a lot of the issues that
people face.
Hartley and they think of that as if you
look at the problems that you have when
you're growing up,
you look at the price.
Especially if you grow up in a poor
family,
one of the main problems that you face
is you're worried about paying your
bills.
So you say some day I'm going to get to
a point where that is no longer an
issue.
I'm going to make it.
I'm going to be successful.
They,
they're not doing it thinking this is
going to make me happy.
I I've,
I've,
I very rarely see that and which is one
of the reasons why people,
even people's parents in this freaks me
the fuck out.
We'll tell them to not pursue their
dreams,
but instead to pursue something that's
more likely to happen.
Like don't pursue your dream of becoming
an actor or a singer or whatever it is.
Instead pursue your dream of being the
foreman at the company you work at
because that's attainable.
I think you're totally right and there's
a lot of evidence that you're right,
that the financial anxiety is a massive
driver,
depression and an anxiety.
Obviously there's a interesting study
that found people who have an income
from property are 10 times less likely
to develop an anxiety disorder that
people who don't,
and there was a really interesting
experiment in how we can respond to that
is when the President Obama said,
lay in his time,
he thinks would have to happen across
the country in the next 20 years for
various reasons.
So in Canada,
in the 70s,
the Canadian government chose a town at
random,
it seems to genuine,
had been random.
It's tangled dolphin.
It's,
um,
anyone who knows a canter.
It's about four hours I,
winnipeg,
and they said to big group of people in
this town,
we're going to give you guys for the
next,
for the foreseeable future,
we're going to give all of you a
guaranteed basic income.
We're going to give you the equivalent
of in today's money,
15,000 US dollars.
Right?
There's nothing you can do.
That means we'll take it away from you
and there's nothing you have to do in
return for it.
We're just citizens of our country.
We want you to have a good life,
right?
It was partly because they had a kind of
welfare system,
but it was a lot of people were falling
through the cracks and they wanted to do
a little experiment to see with this
work better.
And this was studied very carefully by
women.
I need to be called Doctor Evelyn for,
uh,
to see what happened in loads of
interesting things happened.
Um,
people spent more time with their kids.
Very few people quit work,
but a lot of people turns down shitty
jobs.
So actual overall work standards
improved because employees have to
attract people with,
with better standards.
Um,
but for me,
the most interesting thing is there was
a huge full in depression and anxiety,
right?
Depression and anxiety.
That was so severe.
People had to be hospitalized,
fell by 9%,
which is remarkable in just three years.
And then the program ended.
Dr for Jay said to me,
I thought was so much about that,
that I'd learned about the cow dot.
To Vj said,
um,
you know,
that's an antidepressant,
right?
We should expand our idea of an
antidepressant to be anything that
reduces depression,
if I should include pills,
but also so you're totally right.
I mean,
look,
I grew up,
my dad,
my dad's a bus driver,
my mom worked in a shelter,
my grandmother,
clean toilets,
financial anxiety is a massive driver
of,
um,
of the despair.
This,
I mean more than half of all Americans
have not because of the incredible
financial pressure they'd been put
under.
Got $500 set aside for,
for crisis comes along.
Right?
So you're talking about that's a huge
draw.
And again,
that's really important cause explain to
people,
if that's making you depressed and
anxious,
don't let a doctor tell you you've just
got a chemical imbalance in your brain.
Right?
That's,
we'll do doctors still say that all the
time.
My,
my nephew's best friend,
um,
just literally a couple of weeks ago
went to the doctor and was told,
yeah,
you've got a dopamine and balance.
The doctor said is migrated in the 20
years since I went in there from a
surgeon,
England in England.
But I mean,
I get contacted constantly by people who
were being told they've got chemical,
they're told they've got chemical
imbalances in their brains.
They just as likely to prescribe
antidepressants in English as they are
American.
I mean,
slightly lower,
but it's still exceptionally high
stills.
Yeah.
There's that narrative that an
antidepressant must be in some sort of a
pill form and that navy,
even the expression,
antidepressant and antidepressant,
it's a very confusing thing that we've
sort of adopted very quickly in this
country.
And it's a relatively recent,
you know,
over the last 60,
70 years.
And the people that have
antidepressants,
uh,
in their body that take them all the
time and swear by them,
boy,
if you try to tell them in,
in any way that there's a better option,
they get extremely defensive.
Um,
I have friend,
she's very smart and she's,
she's one of the,
um,
one of the people that will,
you know,
very aggressively debate this idea that
it's anything but a chemical,
depression,
chemical,
a inbounds,
you know,
but she doesn't take care of her body.
She's not,
she doesn't exercise all the time.
You know,
she's slightly overweight.
She doesn't eat the best foods,
you know,
it's,
it's a weird thing.
Well,
and she's living in a society and
culture that has all these forces that
are arising that things will feel
terrible.
Right.
And so a big thing to me is when I'm
talking to this,
because I've had some of that reaction
as well,
not too much,
but I've had some of that reaction as
well.
First thing for me,
I would say I want to expand the menu of
options.
I don't want to take anything off the
table.
Right.
It's not about,
oh,
you say that.
And I,
and I think you're probably being pretty
honest,
but you really do want to,
you want to eliminate mode.
But just by the standard of improvement,
you do probably want to take most people
off of antidepressants.
Don't you want me to run it?
They have a choice.
I would draw an analogy.
Obesity is massively risen in the
western world.
It hasn't risen because people suddenly
became greedy and lazy.
It's risen because our food system is
terrible.
The way feed supply system is terrible,
and we built cities that people can't
walk and bicycle around,
right?
And they're really stressed all the time
and they get home from work exhausted so
they don't have time to exercise a lot
of them in that context.
Some people will do what's the stomach
stapling,
liposuction,
that kind of thing.
Right now I'm not against that.
But
if we change the society in the way that
I would want to with obesity so that
people could walk and cycle and you know
they had access to healthy food,
far fewer people would need stomach
stapling or liposuction.
Right?
So I would drugs,
not a perfect analogy,
but I would say is if the social changes
that I want to happen happen.
If we followed the places that have
succeeded in reducing depression and
anxiety over time,
you would see fewer people feeling they
needed.
And chemical antidepressants,
you read it with a couple of things.
First of all,
I don't think it's access to healthy
food.
I think most people have access to
healthy food.
They choose not to eat it.
They choose to eat refined
carbohydrates,
high sugar foods,
fast food.
Those are the things that are getting
people fat.
And I don't,
I don't think that salad is so outside
of the reach of the normal person.
I just don't agree with that.
I just think that they make unhealthy
choices.
That's much more low end.
They get addicted,
but people make choices on carbohydrate.
I understand what you're saying and I
think there's some truth in it,
but I think people make choices in a
context,
right?
So,
for example,
um,
you know,
one of my relatives who is very
overweight,
you know,
she's constantly fucking stressed
because she's trying to hold together so
much and one of the few reliefs in
pleasure she has is to eat too much.
Right?
And to eat pretty shitty food.
I'm not critical of her for that.
I what I want is to help her change her
life and change the society in which we
live.
So she's not got that constant stress.
Do you know what I mean?
I mean,
I think at this,
in relation to addiction and you tweeted
one smart,
a Ted talk,
I gave everything you think you know
about addiction is wrong,
which approach?
I'm grateful.
Thank you.
[inaudible] which is based on my
previous,
partly taken from my previous book,
chasing the scream,
which is about addiction.
And I think about what you're saying in
relation to that context.
So we had a lot of addiction in my
family.
And,
um,
you know,
one thing that really changed my mind
about this,
and I think it really relates to what
you're saying about food is most people
think,
you know,
addiction.
It is a drug addiction.
I say heroin addiction,
right?
Which is very close to me.
Most with the heroin addiction.
If said,
what causes heroin addiction,
they'd say Dark Heroin Causes Heroin
Addiction,
right?
We've been told this story for a really
long time that,
um,
you know,
if you took,
if we kidnapped someone off the street,
we injected them all.
We injected them with heroin every day
for 20 days.
At the end of that,
they'd have this desperate physical
hunger for the chemical hooks in heroin.
Their body would desperately need it,
and that's,
that's why they would be addicted,
right?
First thing that alerts him.
In fact,
something not right about that is when
it was explained to me in Britain,
if you get hit by a truck and you know
your break your hip and you're taken to
a hospital,
you'll be given loads of a drug called
diamorphine.
Right?
For the pain diamorphine is heroin is
much better than street heroin because
it's medically pure,
right?
If anyone listening to this as a British
grandmother who had a hip replacement
operation,
your grandmother's taken a lot of
heroin,
right?
If what we've been told about the
chemical hooks is right,
what should be happening to all these
people in hospital?
Loads of them should be becoming
addicted.
It doesn't happen in Britain with with
people who are given Domo theme,
so it's like,
well,
wait,
what's going on?
I only began to understand it when I
went to Vancouver and needs to be this
incredible professor.
They're called Bruce Alexander did this
experiment.
It's changed how we think about
addiction I think is very relevant to
what you're saying about food.
So this theory,
the chemical hooks,
theory of addiction and chemical hooks
are real.
They're just a small part of it.
The Chemical Hooks,
theory of addiction comes from a series
of experiments that were done years ago.
They're really simple.
You take a rat,
you put it in a cage and you give it two
water bottles.
One is just water.
The other is water laced with either
heroin or cocaine.
If you do that,
the rat will almost always prefer the
drug water and almost always die quite
quickly.
Right within think is a week.
So there you go.
You might remember his famous
advertisement for from the 80s so there
you go.
Right?
That's our story.
But in the 70s professor Alexander came
along,
I said,
well hang on a minute,
you put the rat alone in an empty cage
or it's got nothing to do except use
these drugs.
What would happen if we did this
differently?
So he built a cage that he called rat
park,
which is basically like having verace,
right?
They can,
they've got loads of friends that can
fuck all the time.
They'd got a grain they like and colored
balls and they've got both the water
bottles,
the normal water and the drug water.
But the fascinating thing is in rat
park,
they don't like the drug water that
much.
None of them used it.
Cut.
Some of it,
they do use it,
but none of them used it compulsively
and none of them ever overdose.
So when they deprived of the things that
make life meaningful,
they turn obsessive Lee to the drug.
When they've got the things that make
life meaningful per rats,
they don't the opposite of addiction,
isn't it?
Sobriety?
The opposite of addiction is connection.
I think you can see similar principle
playing out with food,
right?
Of course there's some margin to the
individual.
I don't want to say that we're,
we're not entirely the [inaudible] for
reasonably far away from this woman,
these,
these people that were on this dire
morphine.
So why are you saying that they don't
get addicted to it because they go back
to their lives meaningful.
There's a human example that happened at
the same time as rat park.
Why are their lives particularly
meaningful in relationship to like the
lives we're talking about here?
So I think you can see in an example,
a good example,
it was happening at the same time as rat
park and experiment,
the Vietnam War,
right?
Huge numbers of American troops in
Vietnam.
About 40% used heroin.
Right?
Um,
and if you look at the reports from the
time they were shitting themselves,
cause they were like,
my God,
when the war ends,
we're going to have all these heroin
addicts on the streets of the United
States.
They're going to come home.
And because they believe the chemical
hooks theory,
it's a really good study in the Archives
of General Psychiatry by Professor Lee
Robbins that followed these guys hope,
my select group of them.
And what it found was at 95% of them
just stopped,
right?
It didn't go into some catastrophic
withdraw.
Some of them did experience some
physical discomfort,
but they didn't.
You know,
they didn't.
Now,
if you believe the old theory of
addiction that you're taken over by the
chemical hooks,
that makes no sense,
right?
But they've been exposed to all the same
chemical hooks as any homeless street,
street addicted person to be on the
streets.
Um,
but if you understand this different way
of thinking,
it makes perfect sense.
If you took you and me now and put us in
a hellish pestilential jungle where we
don't want to be,
we could die at any moment.
We'd be made to kill people.
You would definitely survive longer than
me.
But we were both find heroin a lot more
appealing than we do now.
Right.
And then when we come back to our lives,
when we have meaning and purpose,
we would find heroin a lot less
appealing.
The core of addiction is not wanting
to be present in your life because your
life is too painful place to be.
So when something,
an intervention happens that reduces the
amount of pain in your life,
you could be less addicted.
There's a very challenging,
like Marianne faithful,
you know the British rocks,
I was to stop you right there because
there is a giant issue though with
people taking pain pills after
operations that weren't on pain pills
before.
And then they get addicted to them.
So that's because a lack of meaning in
their life or is it because there is an
absolute real chemical hook?
Like,
I have a good friend who had his nose
broken and a,
they fixed his nose and he got on some,
I think it was oxycontin afterwards they
prescribed to them and then four months
later he's taking it every day,
all day.
So there's a few things about that.
Firstly,
chemical hooks are real,
but they're a small part of the picture.
We know how much they are.
So this experiments that measure this,
so we,
um,
lots of people want to take him.
In fact,
some people listening to this will be
taking part in this experiment.
Now when nicotine patches were invented
in the late eighties and they become
marketed in the early nineties,
there's this huge wave of optimism,
right?
Cause the chemical hook in cigarettes is
nicotine.
Nicotine patches give Ya the chemical
hook you're addicted to.
Um,
and so there was this huge,
wait,
what?
They're like,
great,
we're going to give people the camp
because it's,
the diction is caused by chemical hooks.
We're going to give them the chemical
hook.
They'll stop wanting these filthy smoke
smoking's going to end,
right?
And in fact,
what happened is 17% of people,
according to the US surgeon general's
report,
when they take nicotine,
use nicotine patches and they're
motivated,
stop smoking.
Right?
Really important to say 17% is not.
No one big number that has saved
hundreds of thousands of people's lives
at a conservative estimate,
but still leaves 83% where something
else is going on.
Right?
But isn't that because of the delivery
method?
The digital delivery method of
cigarettes is incredibly satisfying.
You take a hit,
you get it right into your system and
boom,
you get that nicotine,
their transdermal,
it's very slow.
It's not the same feeling.
Yeah,
there are there experiments that show
there is pleasure that comes from the
delivery method,
but it's also about self soothing.
It's about anxiety.
It's about boredom.
Um,
and this is very important to relate to
the opiate crisis.
So one in 130,
um,
opioid prescriptions resulted in
addiction,
right?
So it's a small number,
but at catastrophic and devastating
number.
And I reported from the places that have
been most affected like this by this
like keene in New Hampshire.
One in what,
one in 130 if the users become addicted.
That's it.
Yeah.
It's a relatively small proportion now
that cause so many people in the country
wrong.
Yeah.
I can send you the study.
That's the,
the best studies that got that.
And that's in the United States or in
the UK,
in the United States.
We've got,
that's one in 130 prescriptions.
But bear in mind that some people get
more than one prescription.
So,
you know,
but,
um,
the,
but one of the things that's really
important to understand about that is
the context in which this is happening,
right?
In Britain in the 18th.
And this totally relates to what I write
about in lost connections about
depression as well as in chasing the
scream about addiction in Britain in the
18th century,
there was this thing that happened
called the gin craze,
right?
So huge numbers of people are driven out
of the countryside into these disgusting
urban slums where,
you
know,
they're living in this office,
they've lost everything that made like
meaningful to them.
Right.
And what happened was an outbreak of
mass alcoholism,
huge outbreak.
It's called the gin craze.
There's famous paintings of like a woman
drinking a bottle of gin while her baby
falls out a window,
that kind of thing.
Right?
And it really happened,
and at the time what people said is,
look at this evil drug gin.
Look at what it's done to people.
If only we could get rid of these evil
people selling this evil drug gin,
this problem would go away.
Now when we look back at it,
we know that can't have been because of
Jim,
because we could both have jen in these
glasses.
Now anyone in Britain can go and buy gin
at any point,
pretty much.
And if they're an adult and we don't
have,
I mean there's still some alcoholism.
Of course there was some despair.
Yeah,
it's caused a lot changed.
It's not the availability of the drug.
What changes the amount of pain in the
society.
And that is the key factor that's
playing out here with opioids,
right?
It's not the only factor.
Chemical Hooks are real,
but you know,
I'm a Brazilian guy.
He was absolutely adamant that,
you know,
he,
he become medically addicted was an
accidental chemical.
Hooks are taken him over.
He'd been a college athlete.
Right.
And he was in a particular about 21 he
was in a terrible car accident and they
get a,
and they gave him loads of opioids and
it became a doctor.
But then I said,
well,
tell me about what's going well.
So it's going on today.
He couldn't be a college athlete
anymore.
It's a whole life had been built around
being an athlete and because of his
injuries,
he couldn't become an athlete anymore.
And I said,
well do you think it might have been
related also to the despair around that?
It doesn't take long for people.
I think part of the promise,
because we've got such stigma about
depression,
anxiety,
addiction,
people will latch onto the biological
explanation,
whether it's the chemical imbalance
theory,
the chemical hooks theory as their path
out of stigma.
Where's,
to me,
you shouldn't be stigmatized in any
fucking circumstance,
whether it's because you're in pain,
psychological pain,
physical pain.
Did you see the point I'm making?
So I think one of the reasons why we're
so committed to this,
and it's not even a good way out of
stigma.
I can explain to you happy ones are
interesting evidence about that,
but did you see the point?
I'm making job.
I do see the point that you're making
that people with lives that are
unsatisfying or unfulfilling or there's
some sort of a major issue in their,
like the athlete that's no longer going
to be able to be an athlete,
that that's going to make these drugs
more enticing.
I,
but I know too many people that have had
like real issues getting off of them,
like physical issues.
We're no one to painful for withdrawals,
of course.
And most people,
I mean you're talking about the same
people that have a hard time not eating
shitty food,
right?
They have people that have a hard time
getting disciplined enough to go to the
gym.
These are the same kind of people we're
talking about.
They're going to have a massive problem.
If you give them pills and those pills
create a chemical hook,
even if it's a chemical hook that you or
I or a discipline person would be able
to get.
Like Dr. Carl Hart famously called it,
he said,
it's like getting over the flu.
He goes,
that's what heroin is like.
Everyone wants to pretend that you're
going to die.
He goes,
no,
you feel like shit for a little while
and then you're fine.
He goes,
it's not the thing that everybody makes
it out to be withdrawals or not the
thing that everybody makes it out to be,
but,
but if you have the average person and
you give them pills and those pills can
keep them
from getting the flu,
they're going to keep taking those
pills.
And if they stop taking those pills,
they get the flu.
People are comfort,
jumpy junkies,
and I think it's does too simplistic.
I think there's some truth in what
you're saying,
but I think the key thing that happens,
so I think doctor to is t who's a friend
of mine is totally right,
but the,
the,
the physical withdrawal is,
you know,
a flu is not a nice thing,
but it's not the most onerous thing in
the world.
But the thing that's really devastating
is the resumption of the pain that you
were in east,
that psychological pain that you were
nice.
The timing with the drug,
right?
Right.
Do you want to understand why people are
taking so many painkillers?
We've got to understand why they're in
so much pain.
And that comes back to the nine causes
of depression and anxiety that arrived
in las connections and then the kind of
seven solutions to this problem that I
offer.
So again,
that's about if are,
so let's say Joe,
right?
Joe In the paint store who I was talking
about,
who's,
you know,
he who has this job he can't bear,
has very little a meaning in his life,
feels his life is just slipping through
his fingers.
He took oxy for quite a long time.
He actually contacted me because of my,
my book.
Um,
and because,
and,
and my ted talk,
and he thought he was telling me a story
about addiction.
Right?
But the truth is when he took oxygen,
he was numbed.
It made him as numb as the work itself.
And then when he stopped,
he was acutely depressed and felt like
shit.
So I think the challenges,
if you are coming off of this drug into
a society of profoundly lonely and
isolated people who are financially
insecure,
who've been told that life is about
money and status,
who,
you know,
who think life is about screaming at
each other three screens,
a lot of those people are gonna feel
like shit.
And it's not because they're
individually week,
right?
It's become that and maybe individual
witnesses.
Of course,
we all have flaws.
Every human being has flaws.
But I think it's much more because the
fact that it's risen so much tells you
that it's a response to social changes.
Right?
Just like the fact that obesity has
risen so much tells us now there are
course individual agency.
I don't want to infantilize anyone that
are things individuals can do obviously.
And I talk about them a lot in lots
connections.
But I think the fact that it's a social
transformation,
um,
does tell you something,
there's a,
a good illustration of this kind of
weird thing that was discovered about
depression in the 70s that was so
inconvenient that psychiatrist tried to
brush it under the carpet.
So in the 70s,
the American Psychiatric Association for
the first time,
what it to standardize how depression is
diagnosed across the u s because up to
then doctors were just using their own
judgment about what it even was.
Right?
So they drew up a list of 10 symptoms,
kind of obvious things like feeling
worthless cry and a lot,
you know,
you could guess where they were.
And they send this out to doctors all
over the US and uh,
they use it but a cup of,
within a couple of months.
Dot.
To start to come back and go,
look,
we've got a real,
we've got a problem here.
Because if we just use this checklist,
we should be diagnosing every grieving
person is mentally ill because these are
the symptoms of grief,
right?
Everyone,
when you lose someone,
Cope wants to cry a lot,
fit,
you know,
has persistent feelings of sadness,
that kind of thing.
So like what do we do?
So the psychiatrist regrouped and were
like,
okay,
we'll create something.
It was called the grief exception.
Basically sad.
Use this checklist to diagnose
depression unless the person has lost
someone they love in the last year,
in which case none of this counts.
So they start using that.
But over the next few years that
followed this,
this really awkward debate,
cause they're like,
wait a minute,
we're being told to tell our patients
that depression is just a brain disease.
That you can just identify from a
checklist.
Unless there's one situation in life
where it's perfectly legitimate to react
this way.
But at that begs the question,
why is that?
Why not?
If you made homeless,
why not?
If you'd stuck in a shitty job,
you hey,
why not?
If you're really lonely,
the minute you admit all that,
you have to admit context and that was
so inconvenient.
They just got rid of the grief exception
that doesn't exist.
A fascinating fact and that seems to be
a huge issue.
That seems to be one of the primary
reasons why people today.
I mean if you,
if you stop and ask the average person
today who's not feeling well,
I guarantee you they're going to be able
to come up with at least one or two of
those things on the list that are,
that are factors who totally right and
is there.
It's a job or financial stress,
relationship,
stress,
loneliness,
friendship issues or death in the family
or losing someone they love,
but the fact that losing someone their
love like,
Oh,
we'll count that.
That's the one thing that's seems very
preposterous.
And the woman who did the most research,
and this is one of the best people I've
got to know for loss connections when we
could talk to Joanne [inaudible],
he's an amazing person.
She lost her baby in childbirth.
Babies called Cheyenne and she became an
expert on this and she said,
you know,
she talks about the craziness of this.
It just shows we don't understand pain
in this society.
Great.
She said,
she put it to me.
We don't,
grief isn't a pathology,
right?
We don't need cheap.
She's done this research that shows,
I think the figure is 32% of grieving
parents are diagnosed and drugs in the
first 48 hours after their child dies
and she's,
this is a sickness,
right?
That that grief is not a pathology.
We grieve because we've loved someone,
right?
It's not a malfunction.
It's not sign of madness.
It's a sign that you loved the person
and the way I'm going to be on what she
says now,
but you know,
I think one of the things,
the fact that the depression and grief
had the same symptoms is really
significant because I think depression
is grief for your own life,
not going how it should,
right?
It's grief for your own needs not being
met.
Now when someone we love dies or we can
do is hold the survivors and love them,
right?
But with,
um,
but with,
with your own needs not being met,
I mean,
a really interesting sample or there's
something you've kept brilliantly on the
show,
joe about psychedelics.
I'm the researcher on Psychedelics,
which taught me a lot about how we might
think about this differently.
So as you know,
uh,
you know better than anyone the,
until the mid sixties loads of research
was done giving Lsd to people with
depression,
alcoholism,
both problems.
They weren't done to the standards.
We want to do scientific experiments
now,
but they found really promising results
and then Nixon shuts the whole thing
down.
Right.
In the last six years,
there's been a huge reawakening this,
I went and interviewed blas connections,
the teams that have worked on this in
um,
uh,
here in la at Ucla,
Nyu at Johns Hopkins,
in Baltimore,
in London,
at Ucl,
uh,
in Sao Paolo and in Norway.
And loads of fascinating things and in
fact about this.
But there's one that I think really
relates to our conversation powerfully.
Um,
w well,
loads of things,
but we'll talk about one.
Um,
so there was a sub finding a,
one of the studies that I became
obsessed with,
they did this research at Johns Hopkins
in Baltimore,
some of the leading scientists in the
world where they gave psilocybin the
active component in magic mushrooms to
um,
chronic longterm smokers who tried
everything to stop smoking and had not
succeeded.
Right.
I've thought about my mother a lot
because my mother is a chain smoker.
This is a photograph of me and her when
I'm six months old,
she's breastfeeding me smoking and
resting the ashtray on my stomach.
Oh my God.
Uh,
and,
and so they take people like my mother,
right.
I'd already,
when I showed her that picture,
she said you were fucking difficult
baby.
I needed that cigarette.
It's a how they try to blame you when I
was a fucking baby.
She,
she's a good person,
but the,
the,
so they take these people quite a
longtime smokers and they gave them
three doses of psilocybin over,
think it was six months.
It was six months.
So two month intervals of thing.
And what they found was extraordinary.
80% of them stop smoking.
Right?
And it still remained not smoking more
than two years later.
Incredible.
Think about,
we were comparing it to 17% but nicotine
patches and they were like,
what's going on?
So they did all this research in this.
And what we've gotta be careful with
psychedelics is to not talk about it the
way we were misleadingly told about
antidepressants,
chemical anti depressants in the 90s,
which is,
oh,
it flips the chemical switch in your
brain.
Clearly a chemical process happens in
the brain,
but,
but what they found,
I think the most important thing and the
lesson for people who don't want to use
psychedelics as well is a sub finding.
So if you take,
if you take psilocybin,
most people will have a kind of
spiritual experience,
right?
Um,
some people will have a super intense
spiritual experience that people have in
Melbourne and a minority will have no
spiritual experience.
It turns out the positive effects,
like reduction in depression and
addiction correlate exactly with the
intensity of the spiritual experience.
So if you have no spiritual experience,
you don't have,
but here's isn't is dose dependent?
No,
this cut across those.
So they gave him three varying doses,
doses,
I can't remember,
but it's in the,
it's pretty significant though.
That's a very important factor.
Yeah.
So across the three,
so you were given it three times and you
always given three different doses,
so obviously you would have more.
Most people have much more intense
experience with the most,
with the strongest dose,
but the,
the key thing I think about that,
that finding is that
one of the experts put it to me.
It's not that it's a chemical process,
it's a learning experience.
What it does is it gives you an
experience of what it can feel like to
be deeply connected,
to feel deeply connected to the people
around you,
to the natural world.
Incredible,
strong,
natural antidepressant that we can talk
about if you want.
Have you psychedelic experience?
When was a teenager?
I bought some and I think they were a
drug dealer in Canada.
Tam Market.
I'm holding off because I've got to go
to the Amazon rainforest later this year
and I want to use Iowasca for the first
time in the Amazon.
Never had,
cause you know I'm getting that from the
way you're describing it.
It's interesting.
I interviewed huge numbers of people who
had,
tell me what you're,
what you're getting.
That's interesting.
Well this the what it is is a dissolving
of the ego.
That's a general factor that almost
everybody reports.
Um,
it also releases you from deeply
ingrained patterns of behavior and
thinking and,
and highlights them.
So as much as it is a spiritual
experience,
it's also a dissolving of the self.
And the,
the,
the way we define ourselves is
oftentimes very limiting.
You have this,
this is the way I describe it and this
is the way I described very powerful
psychedelic experiences.
It's like,
do you remember the old windows thing?
Control,
alt,
delete.
That's how you'd reboot.
It's like control,
alt,
delete for your brain and your brain
reboots with a fresh new desktop.
There's nothing on it except one folder.
And that one to folder is titled My old
bullshit.
And you have two choices.
You can either start fresh and try to re
examine the world with fresh eyes or
what's more convenient as you slowly
slipped into the my old bullshit folder
and start opening it up and repeating
patterns in lighting that cigarette up
when you really shouldn't.
Having that drink when you probably
shouldn't do that either.
And those things are common because it's
comforting.
It's comforting for people to repeat
patterns that they're familiar with.
I think it's a few things in that you're
totally right and the scientific
evidence is overwhelming.
In fact,
at Ucl,
University College,
London,
Professor David Nutt did all this
research that shows it.
One of the things that happens in your
brain when you take psychedelics is the
part of the brain that relates to ego
just doesn't function right and then be
interviewing.
One of the most moving into I did was a
guy called mark who was in one of the
studies in Baltimore who,
um,
was a very shy,
reserved shutdown guy when he was 10 his
dad had died and no one had talked to
him about his dad's death.
His mother was just totally devastated
and no one had talked to him about it
and he'd always been very shut down.
And he takes the psilocybin and he had
this really intense experience where he,
he thinks he's in space and he believed
he met his father and his father
apologized for leaving him.
And then he reached into mark and he
pulled out these walls and he said,
I want to thank these walls.
They've protected my son.
They've done a good job,
but you can let them go now.
And after that mark really changed how
he lived there.
She went,
she said he was able to sustain that
insight.
He went and learned a lot of meditation.
Um,
I think,
I think you're,
you're,
you're absolutely right.
It's about dissolving the ego and what
an experience of Eagles egolessness can
do is almost point a direction on a
compass.
Right.
But there's another aspect that emerged
in that,
which I think is one of the slight
differences between us.
I like the,
I,
I think there's a lot in what you're
saying.
So in the,
in London,
they,
this research with chronically
depressed people.
And Robin Carhart Harris,
he led that study.
He said to me,
you know,
there's one woman chronically depressed,
she takes the Psilocybin,
she gets everything you're saying,
the dissolution of ego,
the need for all the things you're
talking about.
And then she goes back to her job in a
shitty seaside town where you just can't
live compatible with those insights.
Right.
She just couldn't.
And so her depression came back.
So to me,
what the size of it,
where individuals can change the lives.
Obviously they should.
Right.
And we would totally agree on that.
And a lot of people do have more margin
to change their lives and they think,
and we're in total agreement on that.
And I think you would probably agree
that there are some people who are,
you know,
through no fault of their own,
like a lot of my relatives fucking
stock,
right?
And then the very people will have no
margin of change.
But a lot of people have such a small
margin to change,
but that margin will not carry them out
of depression or anxiety or addiction.
And that's why we need the widest is
what the World Health Organization says.
You need social solutions as well as
individual solutions.
When to change the way the society works
in all sorts of ways that reduce the
things that are causing this pain in the
first place.
Do you see what I mean?
Changing the way society works though is
a grand in,
in tangled,
gigantic undertaking.
Whereas changing your own life is not so
actually doing your own life is
difficult.
It can be very difficult for a lot of
people,
but it's far easier than changing
society.
I understand what you're saying.
Who you're telling me has the
psychedelic experience experiences this
dissolving of ego,
this beautiful spiritual awakening,
but then goes back to a job that's like
opening up the folder of mild bullshit.
It's the same thing.
She's going back to the same patterns.
Well I would say she's being forced into
that folder cause she's what she gonna
do,
but lean,
what she's going to do is what a lot of
people do.
I mean a lot of people change their
lives.
I mean it's not impossible to do.
I don't know if this woman had kids.
I didn't ask it.
Well,
imagine being,
even can't imagine people being stuck
big.
We makes it very difficult.
It makes it very difficult.
But she's not in jail.
She's not a president.
At some point you're making.
But I think actually,
and this might sound strange in some
ways,
I think changing the society is easier
than isolated individuals changing
their,
so I'll give you an exam.
How is that possible?
Well,
I'll give you some,
but I'm gay,
right?
Um,
if I think about the incredible
transformation I've seen in my life.
So I tell the story in Los Connections
about my friend Andrew Sullivan,
right?
1994,
Andrew was diagnosed with HIV.
His first thought was,
I deserve this,
right?
He'd been raised in such a homophobic
world.
He thought,
you know what?
I deserve to have this,
this illness.
It's going to kill me.
He was watching his friends die all
around him.
He thought it was about to die.
This is before protease inhibitors and
it goes to province town,
little town in Cape Cod to do what he
thought would be the last thing he would
ever do.
Right?
And he wrote a book about crazy Utopian
idea that he thought,
this is never going to happen.
I'm never going to live to see this.
But maybe generations from now,
this is what happened.
It was the first book ever arguing for
gay marriage.
Right?
And if I get depressed about this,
try to imagine going in time and saying
to Andrew,
okay,
noted.
I've,
okay,
I've got some good news.
25 years from now,
you're going to be alive.
But that's not the good news.
The Supreme Court of the United States
is going to quote this book in their
ruling,
making it mandatory for all states in
the United States to introduce gay
marriage.
And the next day you'll be invited to
the White House,
which will be lit up in the colors of
the rainbow flag to celebrate with the
president.
And by the way,
that president is going to be black,
right?
That would have sounded like ridiculous
science fiction.
Now imagine saying to gay people 50
years ago,
you're not going to change the society.
That's way too hard.
When you can do is focus on changing
yourself.
Actually,
gay people would be really fucking
miserable if that's what they'd done,
right?
If that's how it was,
my life will be immeasurably worse if
gay people are just said,
you know what?
It's so hard to change society.
Let's change ourselves.
We would've remained trapped in Shitty,
awful institutions and systems that kept
us down.
I actually think,
if I think about most of the people I
know who are depressed,
to be honest,
their margin for individual changes
limited,
but banding together,
their margin for change is huge,
right?
It's thinking about which was about the
universal basic income for example.
Right?
Massively.
We're getting,
we're going to another subject here,
so she'd gone.
Then it's you.
You keep going on one to the next,
shut up with one.
It's far easier to explain to one
person,
one life why it's wrong to be homophobic
than it is to change all the rednecks
and all the ignorant people who don't
read and all the people that have deeply
ingrained archaic religious ideas about
homosexuality.
It's far easier to educate and luminate
one person and it also can be done with
the aid of psychedelics,
especially MTMA therapy.
This one of the things that maps is
doing right now with Mtma therapy and
they're,
they're involved in a bunch of clinical
trials right now,
helping people to all sorts of traumatic
stress experiences,
soldiers,
people that experienced physical
violence,
all these people that are,
it's helping them alleviate a lot of the
problems that are life.
There's patterns that people are that
they have in their mind that they can
release.
Sure,
you could release and you can be
educated and you can understand.
You can change and grow as an
individual.
It's far easier to do that with one
person,
for one person to change their life.
Then it changed an entire culture.
I do agree that there have been great
strides in this country when it comes to
discrimination,
when it comes to racism,
when it comes to so many different
ideas.
But I think that's connected to the
exchange of ideas that we're
experiencing now because of the
Internet.
I think because of the fact that there's
so many different arguments back and
forth and there's so many different ways
to approach things that people are being
forced to change their opinions.
Even more religious people today or more
open to homosexuality than they have
been in the past.
I've really believed that is a factor of
all the information that's available and
the,
the amount of communication I amount of
gay people that people know from
television,
from news programs,
from all these different shows where
they get a different sense of,
you know,
do you see Ellen everyday?
Well,
gay people can't be Evil Ellen.
So Nice.
You know what I mean?
There's a lot of that.
I think you're totally right,
but I think that shows that the first
thing you said is,
is too simplistic.
So the thing is that the division
between the,
I think the last thing you point you
made is totally on the money,
but why didn't you were saying that the
division is the idea that is easier to
persuade individuals and persuade the
society.
You persuade the society by persuading
individuals who just persuade lots of
individuals and they banned.
Sure.
Well,
okay.
I think we're splitting hairs here
because I think if obviously if you
change every individual,
you change society,
but it's far easier to change one person
than it is to change 350 million.
But that's obviously true.
But you changed 350 million by changing
one person and one passport by banding
together.
But you also,
one of the ways that you changed those
one p that one person is by banding
together in a group,
right?
So gay people for example,
would be a good example,
but there are many,
many good examples.
But what you're saying about individual
psychology,
it's important to say you're,
you're right about that.
So there are,
there's a very broad scientific
agreement.
There are three kinds of cause of
depression and anxiety.
And most mental health if at all,
mental health problems,
they're,
the ratio varies.
So there's biological causes,
which we talked about.
Your genes,
for example,
can make chemo sensitive to these
things.
There's psychological causes,
which are the things you're talking
about,
which are very real and important.
And there's social causes so that,
you know,
a lot of the other things we've talked
about,
and I think at a way you don't need to
play them off against each other.
They're all real,
right.
And you want to deal with all of them.
Um,
so it's not,
I don't think it's a,
I want to get to argue with you.
It's like you're saying we should deal
with the psychological factor.
And I'm saying we should deal with the
social factor.
You're totally right.
We should deal with that.
I think we should deal with Bob.
Yeah,
exactly.
I think where we certainly,
do,
you know what I mean?
Yes.
Yeah,
yeah.
But I think that the idea that,
so like think of what you're saying in
terms of people,
uh,
living unfulfilled lives,
living in job or working in jobs that
they don't enjoy,
where they're being controlled by a
boss,
it's far easier for one person to choose
to change the path of their life than to
try to restructure society where that
doesn't exist anymore.
I agree.
Ceos like this is what this is,
is intent.
There's a Ma,
I mean obviously that was a huge factor
in the 2016 election.
It was one of the things that was talked
about is a wealth inequality.
Well,
there's no greater version of wealth
inequality than the difference between
the CEO of a massive company and its
lowest worker.
I mean,
it literally is like a king and a
peasant.
It's a very strange sort of a structure
that very recently has it become.
Yes,
yes.
But it's so common.
I mean,
it is,
it's ingrained.
I mean,
how many corporations are there that
operate like that top down?
I mean it's,
it's gigantic.
And to change that I think would be far
more difficult than to change an
individual's path and to tell this one
person,
hey man,
what do you really want to do?
Do you really like making pottery?
Well,
they,
you should try to make pottery for a
living because this working for
chemicals,
you're not going to ever feel fulfilled.
You're always gonna have that same
anxiety on Sunday night before you go to
bed.
You're always going to feel like shit
while you're at work.
You're always going to be numb.
You're going to be probably listening to
the podcasts like this while you're
working just to try to pass the time.
I think you're right
and totally,
if,
if you can do it,
if you've got that margin per change,
100% my advice to you is that why
wouldn't you
be able to do it eventually?
You might not be able to do it right
now,
but if you plan for it,
why wouldn't you be able to do it?
I think about one of my closest
relatives,
right?
She's,
she's
very depressed.
She's got two young kids.
She's working really hard.
She's in a Shitty town.
Um,
she has very controlled work.
I'm trying to think.
I've desperately tried to think of the
margins of change that I can help her
facilitate in her life.
Right.
And I've really struggled.
I mean it's an environment where most
people are depressed.
Most people are obese.
This is England.
Yeah.
But I mean it could've just as easily
manageable spent a lot of time in the u
s but I think it's more people with this
problem in the u s um,
you know,
now I think we've essentially cut off
case.
That's a very nice,
anyone who has any margin of change I go
through in Los Connections,
the seven ways you can change your life,
that the science at shows will reduce
her depression and anxiety.
Very likely,
right?
If you've got that margin.
Do I think the only disagreement trends
is,
I think you're more,
um,
you,
you think more can be done by individual
will alone than I do probably.
And I would say,
but that's not disempowering in the
sense that I would say the most powerful
individually empowering thing you can do
is band together with other people like
you and fight for something better.
Right.
Work together towards improving yourself
with the people in your community and
making some sort of a bond.
Totally.
And one of the most moving things I
learned about from the book was this
incredible protest movement in Berlin.
I can tell you about if you want that
transformed.
It really is one of the places where so
much of,
of what I,
what I learned from the scientists
really fell into place with me and it
was,
were very isolated.
People came together and just said,
you know what?
We're not going to take this anymore and
fought for something better.
I can explain that it's a longer story,
but if you want me to tell about the
world,
but the,
so I think you're right.
So you were saying,
you know,
what do you like to do when you said
pottery is an example of,
that is a good example.
But I will say it may be that what you
like to do and actually cause we're a
social species,
this is what most would like to do is
get together with the people around you
and fight for something better.
And I think you're totally right about
how this played out in the dynamics
around the election.
I remember.
So it really haunted me.
I was um,
with some people who were doing some get
out the vote work in Cleveland and
Cleveland.
I mean it's like Detroit without the
poetry of the rooms,
right?
I mean it's shocking.
And we were on this street in an area
called Slavic city.
Um,
that a why it's not slavic and we're
going,
what do you say that,
I mean there's great parts of Cleveland
each on in this area and the area.
Yeah,
sorry to be climbing the area that I
was,
okay,
sorry.
I should have,
it was this area of west Cleveland
called Slavic city.
Not the hot kick your ass.
Clearly not the whole Cleveland is like,
that's right.
Is that dude who had a t shirt at one of
my shows that I put on my instagram.
People in her death.
They're fucking serious about Cleveland.
They have the heavyweight champion of
the world,
steep vimeo chick who lives in
Cleveland.
So we're,
this street is one of those
respectfully,
not representative of all of Cleveland.
Right?
Well,
I mean you can find a place like that in
la.
I'll take you to skid row right now.
Oh sure,
sure.
We could just go to beverly hills.
You're your choice.
You know what I'm saying?
It's not an Einstein,
but the,
just just about the street that there
was this,
we're going down the street and a third
of the house has been demolished.
A third were abandoned or third store
have people living in them.
Some of them like literally behind
barbed wire.
Right?
Sounds like a children's math problem.
Sorry,
not 15 people live in this place.
I knew heroin.
If they've walked the streets,
how long does it take care I oxycontin
15 people live in that place.
They're on antidepressants.
Who's happier?
So we,
we knocked on one door and there was a
woman who,
from looking at how I would have guessed
was 60,
right.
She was actually the same age as me.
I was 37 at the time.
And she was very articulate.
She was,
she knew that she knew a lot.
She was really fucking angry.
She was raging.
And um,
she made this verbal slip that's really
stayed with me.
I thought about it while you're speaking
earlier,
she talked about the area used to be
like for parents and grandparents,
right?
And she meant to say,
when I was young,
what she actually said is when I was
alive,
I was like,
fuck.
That's how she feels,
right?
She feels like she has died.
And it made me think about this,
this other researchers think about that.
She was saying,
this,
I think relates to the individual versus
collective debate that we've kind of
been touching on.
So native American groups in Canada,
they call them first nations groups have
really high suicide rates.
Right?
Um,
and this professor,
I got to interview person,
Michael Chandler did this really big
research on this because what we
realized is 196 first nations groups in
Canada,
some of them have really high suicide
and some have none.
Right?
And he's like,
why is that?
So He'd spent 10 years researching this,
discovered loads of things.
But one of the things he discovered was
some of these groups have basically been
able to fight to regain control of their
community.
Right?
They rebuilt their language,
they've rebuilt their scope,
control of the schools and you know,
whatever.
And some have just been so cut down that
they haven't been able to do that.
Suicide rate correlates really tightly
with the amount of control they were
able to regain over the community in the
amount of meaning that you find in your
life.
I think it's about meaning,
it's about having a story about who you
are.
It's about having social connections
around you so you're not alone.
You're part of something bigger than any
side.
Exactly.
So I think when you,
when we were talking,
I thought about that when,
when you were saying,
you know,
what,
what do you like to do?
What should you do if someone's
listening to this and they're lonely and
isolated,
you know,
because we're such a fractured society
and because we find it so difficult to
be present with each other,
right?
The,
the,
the constant distraction and refracting
everything through screens,
which makes us be like,
shit,
I can talk about some of that if you
want.
Um,
the,
the actually that,
that initial step is quite hard because
we're so broken up,
right?
So it's not just the initial step,
it's you've gone too far in one
direction.
Like say,
look at it this way,
if we all started this neutral point,
right?
And W,
uh,
someone like Jamie does what he wants to
do and,
and finds a good path and starts going
in that direction and keeps improving as
life and then eventually is a happy
human being as an adult.
Or you have someone who goes the wrong
way.
They get addicted to food and cigarettes
and drugs and antidepressants and they
get into bad relationships and then they
have children that they have to take
care of them.
They have a job that they hate and then
they find themselves at 37 years old
looking like they're 65 trying to figure
out how to get back.
Well,
they've got to find a way to not just
move ahead,
but to get back to that neutral point,
this,
they have to go back in time over all
the shit they fucked up and they have a
far longer path.
So it's not an impossible path,
but it's a far longer path.
If you all,
if everyone's going in a direction and
that direction is 25 miles away,
but you go 37 miles backwards,
you have to go sell 37 miles forward and
then the additional 25 miles.
That's the problem with people.
They look at the,
the,
the daunting nature of that task and
it's very intimidating to them and they
don't feel like they can make it.
They don't feel like they can,
but there is satisfaction and hope and
happiness and moving towards a positive
direction.
And that's what people have to realize.
It's not about a goal.
It's about the journey being a positive
journey and the feeling that you get of
improving your life incrementally on a
daily basis.
And it's also the mindset that you carry
with you on that journey.
You can't look at yourself and go,
God,
why am I not successful yet?
Why am I not rich?
Why am I not this?
Why am I not that?
You have to say,
I am better than I was yesterday.
Tomorrow will be better than I am today
and I'm on the right path.
And there is a lot of deep satisfaction
and happiness and being on the right
path.
Now,
if you're a person who wants to be an
author,
but instead you're an accountant every
day you spend not feeding that idea that
you can be an author is going to chew
away at you,
it's going to chip away at you and it's
going to move you away from that neutral
point.
Many,
many miles.
I totally agree.
I totally agree with you and I think
that the,
that thing about when people realize
they have agency,
that's one of the most,
especially,
and it goes back to what was saying
about work,
if you will,
spending nine hours a day being
controlled,
one of the things you do to get through
that,
is it a process of internal deadening?
Right.
I remember talking to just a,
the guy in the paint store,
he would say,
you know how it would just get home,
go home,
and initially it was alcohol and then
later oxy,
he would just want to numb himself.
Right,
right.
Because there's an internal deadline you
have to do to get through that.
Which is why I think one of the key
aspects that I talk about those
connections is this transformation of
work.
If the thing that most people are doing
most of the time is making 87% of us
would,
we don't like it at the best bat.
You've got to go to the heart of that.
Right.
And,
and you know we're talking about margins
or change.
People who set up that bike store in
Baltimore,
they were working class people.
You know who,
who I'd not had fancy educations.
They set up a democratic cooperative,
right?
They,
they,
they transformed their lives.
So they were a good example of people
who appear to have a relatively limited
margin.
They were low wage workers in a,
in a,
in a low wage industry who,
you know,
have made this transition.
So I'm certainly not saying that people
can't make these transitions even in
difficult circumstances.
They absolutely can.
I just think,
um,
yeah,
I think I'll think about the,
the,
the farmer in the field in Cambodia,
right?
Whose legs blown off and he's in this
field and it's agony.
He needed to change his life,
but he also needed someone to buy him a
cow.
Right?
He couldn't have bought that couch on
his own and that situation,
yeah,
he would be an illustration or,
um,
or the rats in rat park.
Right.
If you're in that isolated cage,
I mean it's not a great example because
you know,
the rat can't leave the cage.
Whereas you could argue,
but you see the point I'm making.
I do.
You could attribute it just to
individual.
I know this is not what you're doing,
but I think some people,
um,
attribute this just to,
uh,
is definitely what you're saying.
But just to individual weakness or
individual failing,
what I think that the identity is
psychology is a significant component of
that alongside other components.
I don't think of it that way at all.
I think I think of it as poor choices.
I don't think of it as individual film.
I've made many,
many poor choices in my life.
Here's one of the big ones.
You could tell people because there's a
lot of people that are listening to this
at various stages of their life.
If you're young and you have an open
future,
you don't have massive obligations and
debt and all the,
all the different things that become a
real hindrance.
As you get older,
move towards a direction that is
attractive to you.
Do not move towards a direction that is
safe.
Don't do it.
Because if you do do that,
if you just take that safe job and then
there's a lot of people that will know,
a lot of people can do that.
That is a bullshit stupid way to think
and that will fuck you that that way to
think we'll fuck you.
You can do what you do,
what you choose to do.
You can get better at things.
If what you choose to do,
you can move forward and try to figure
out a way to carve a path through that
life and it's not going to be easy,
but nothing worth doing is easy.
But this idea that it'll give you want
to just do construction if that's
appealing to you,
you would like to just be a laborer and
there's,
there's look,
there's a need for that in society,
but it doesn't bother you.
It's,
but find out what bothers you and find
out what you enjoy.
If you're a labor and you really want to
be a songwriter,
well you better fucking chase that
songwriting shit.
You better do it because if you don't do
it,
you don't want to be a 60 year old man
sitting around just depressed and
crying.
Then maybe you call
your friend up who does do that for a
living and he's having a great time and
he just released his new album and you
both started out together in high school
and now here you are at different stages
of your life and you,
you haven't pursued your interest,
you haven't pursued your passion,
you haven't pursued what you really want
to do.
I,
but to endorse every word you just said,
I would just add a layer alongside it,
which is,
and we should change our society so
fewer people get trapped and more people
at the moment,
a lot of people feel we want to be
giving people trampolines up.
Right?
Yeah.
I think universal basic income is
probably a way that that's going to
start happening.
Yeah.
I think that can happen.
That can help a lot of people where your
basic needs,
your food is taken care of.
And I think President Obama talks about
this towards the end of his term,
partly because he said,
look,
um,
actually I don't attribute this to him.
I can't move.
He said it made this point in this way,
but it was interviewed wired magazine
and he said he thinks this will have to
happen in the next 20 years.
Partly because of the extraordinary
disruption that's coming to the economy
through robotization automation.
Exactly.
So Elon Musk said that recently as well.
Yeah,
well I think Elan Musk is saying it for
slightly different motive and that he
knows the pitch books are going to come
from people like him and Mark
Zuckerberg.
The anger is going to be directed at
Silicon Valley if there isn't a
universal basic income.
I'm sure they have genuine concern for
people as well.
But I think the,
so you think that's really why he's,
he's saying that,
oh my God,
maybe I'm just more cynical because they
just make so much money.
Well,
I can't remember who said that.
Someone said,
you know,
the path the economies are,
and there's going to be seven tech
billionaires and everyone else employed
to give them massages.
Right?
And I think there's something going on
here,
which is I think they know at some level
if they don't start providing some,
if the society doesn't start providing
some baseline of security,
I forget the figure.
I think 3 million people in the United
States make a living through driving
that's not going to exist in 10 years
from now probably right.
Self driving cars are likely to just,
that's going to be gone,
right?
That that's an extraordinary disruption
to the economy.
Those are mostly men.
They're mostly men with low educational
achievement attainments for various
reasons.
A lot which are not their fault.
Um,
and,
and you know,
that's devastating,
right?
So I think you're right,
the universal basic income is one of the
important strategies that can,
that can kind of deal with that.
But I think this comes back to,
I think you,
you've got your going back to think that
there is a kind of recurring theme in
this conversation,
which is,
you know,
for both my books for chasing the scream
and pulse connections can addiction and
it depression,
anxiety.
Both of them required me to go all over
the world and just look at really
different places that do things really
differently.
And there was some things that just
Rickard for both,
right?
Give example with addiction,
the places that have most reduced
addiction have not been the places that
have said this is an attributing this to
you very clearly are not saying this,
but people whose the places that have
said this is a problem for the
individual and the individual needs to
fucking sort themselves out,
have a massive and growing addiction
crisis from gets worse and worse.
The places that I went to where they
said,
actually this is a collective problem.
We need a collective solution.
We're very different.
So Portugal for example,
in the year two,
how one of the worst drug problems in
the world,
right?
1% of the population was addicted to
heroin.
It was incredible.
Every year the problem got worse as they
tried the American way more and more
rested,
more people in prison,
more people.
And one day the prime minister and the
leader of the opposition got together
and they were like,
look,
we can't go on like this,
right?
We can't have ever more people in our
contributing data to heroin.
Where are we going to do?
So it was quite bold thing.
They set up a panel led by an amazing
man.
I got to know doctor [inaudible].
Um,
and they said to this panel,
you guys go away,
figure out what would actually solve
this and we've agreed in advance.
We'll do whatever you recommend.
Right?
So they go,
it'd be like if trump and chuck Schumer
and Nancy Polosi agreed,
they would,
everyone would abide by finding on this.
So they go away.
They look at all the evidence including
rat park loads of the things we've
talked about.
They came back and said,
decriminalize all drugs from cannabis to
crack everything.
But,
and this is the crucial next step.
Take all the money we currently spend on
fucking people's lives up on arresting
them,
shaming them,
stigmatizing them,
imprisoning them,
and spend it instead on turning their
lives around.
And interestingly,
it wasn't really what we think of.
It wasn't,
there was a little bit of residential
rehab.
Most of it was a big program of job
creation.
They set up micro loans so people with
addiction problems could set up and run
small businesses about things they cared
about.
They set up a big program,
subsidized work.
So,
um,
you know,
say you've used to be a mechanic,
they go to a garage,
they say if you employ this guy for a
year,
we'll pay half his wages.
Right.
The results in Portugal have been
incredible.
Couldn't the best scientific study
published in the British journal of
criminology injecting drug use fell by
more than 50% overdose deaths,
massively fell HIV massively fail.
One thing that was so striking there was
going around and speaking to people.
I mean one of the most moving into that,
if the chasing the scream is with them,
a guy called wildfit guerra who was the
top drug cop in Portugal,
and he led the opposition to the
decriminalization when it first
happened,
right?
[inaudible] he said,
this is fucking madness.
We're going to have a massive explosion
in drug use.
It's going to be a nightmare.
And he said to me,
everything I said would happen,
didn't happen,
and everything the other side said would
happen,
did.
And it talks about how he felt really
ashamed that it spent 20 years before
the decriminalization fucking people's
lives up.
And I think that goes to the debate that
we're talking about because that was now
that's individuals changing,
right?
That's very clearly individual changing,
making better choices,
but they're making those better choices
in a context,
a context where the society,
instead of beating them down,
it's trying to lift them up.
But you see what I mean?
It's a very good,
yeah,
good point.
It's a very important point.
And what Portugal is done should be
studied by our country,
which is now falling right back into the
old Nancy Reagan.
Just say no bullshit days with Jeff
sessions at the helm of catastrophe.
He's a terrifying person in that regard
cause he's so ignorant as to what's
going on.
He's so ignorant.
He's still calling marijuana gateway
drug.
Yeah,
he's a fool.
I mean,
he really is.
And that the,
the pattern is terrifying because
they're trying to call Kratom and opiate
right now.
There,
there's,
there's all sorts of a resistance to
what we know of as safe alternatives to
pharmaceutical medications like cbd.
That's another one they're demonizing.
They want to categorize that with heroin
and cocaine.
It's fucking terrifying.
It's,
it's,
it's a very,
very weird time because there's so much
evidence and so much science and so much
history when it comes to things like
Portugal where it's been successful to
decriminalize everything and spend the
money on treatment programs,
but they're ignoring that.
They're ignoring that because it's
convenient.
You're so right.
But my concern is it's not.
I've Jeff sessions is,
you could imagine what I think about
Jeff Sessions is disgusting and insane
what he saying.
But my worry is it's not a,
well,
I've worried about jeff sessions
primarily,
but my other worry is it's not just jeff
sessions.
I actually think even our side,
you know,
when it comes to the opioid crisis,
I think had been talking about this and
quite quite the wrong way.
So it made me realize actually how deep
this Nancy Reagan's script is in the
culture that even liberals,
my side of politics,
it basically been saying their story
about the pharmaceutical,
the opioid crisis is basically evil drug
dealers came along,
they gave people these drugs,
they got accidentally hurt.
In this case,
the evil drug dealers or the big Pharma,
they've got them accidentally hooked.
Um,
and that's why we have this crisis right
now.
There's,
as you can tell from our conversation
and antidepressants,
there's a lot to criticize big farmer
about.
I'm very critical of them.
But that story is just ridiculously
simple.
If that were true,
antidepressant prescriptions had been
given across the United States,
right?
If that were true,
it would not make sense.
Now the opioid prescriptions are also
concentrated.
The opiate addictions are also
concentrated in the places where suicide
is highest,
where depression is highest,
where of course it's some everywhere,
but there's a reason for that,
right?
Angus Dayton,
the economist who studied this described
the opioid deaths,
despair,
deaths,
right?
If you go to the places where you turn,
right,
we're in the country and when I go to
places that have been most affected by
the opioid crisis,
what's going on,
he said he'd been deprived of the things
that make life meaningful,
so they want to be an Easter ties to all
the time.
There's a devastating line.
Marianne faithful.
He was,
Mick Jagger is best known for being Mick
Jagger's girlfriend,
but kind of pisses me off cause thinks
she's even better than Mick Jagger,
but she was,
I know it was controversial.
Better than Mick Jagger.
There's controversial,
I best fucking conversations.
Shut it down,
Jamie.
So Marianne Faithfull had a heroin
addiction in the 60s when she was
homeless and she has this very
challenging line in her.
In her memoir,
she says something like,
heroin saved my life because if it
wasn't the heroin,
I would have killed myself.
Right.
And don't misunderstand what I'm saying.
Heroin is not a good solution to despair
if we want,
if clearly for all sorts of very obvious
reasons,
if we want to understand why there's
been this huge increase in opiod use,
we have to understand these things that
I'm writing about.
His connections to the World Health
Organization is explaining this deep
kind of dispatch.
And my worry is that,
cause you're back to the worry about how
our side is getting it wrong.
So we've got jeff sessions getting it
wrong in the most obvious,
insane way,
right.
You know,
it's just we need to crack down on the
Mexicans and that will store it.
We,
the United States has spent $1 trillion
on the war on drugs.
It's done it for a hundred years.
It's imprisoned more people than any
other country in human history.
And at the end of all that,
you guys can't even keep drugs out of
your prisons where you pay people to
what we're on the fucking perimeter the
whole time.
So good luck keeping them out of a
country with two,
3000 mile borders.
That is so ridiculous and so absurd that
it's not just that.
It's why would you think that you could
tell a grown adult what they can and
can't do with their body?
Of course,
boss,
that really simple.
I think I'm,
I'm pretty sure all of your listeners
agree with this on GSA or pretty much
all of them agree that on jeff sessions,
what I think more of them will be
tempted by.
We'll be the more liberal argument.
I says as the liberals are not attacking
liberals,
but the,
the more liberal argument,
which is this simplistic,
even Bernie Sanders who I love and would
have voted for,
uh,
well I think he,
he's got this wrong,
which is the,
uh,
although I think Bernie Sanders has
politics would deal with some of the
deeper problems as well.
Clearly,
but there's this story that it's about
the drug companies.
We've got to look at the one place that
solved an opioid crisis.
If we talked about Portugal,
the one other place.
So Switzerland,
I'm a Swiss citizen,
come my dad's from there as well as
British,
obviously tristle until a massive heroin
problem in the 90s right?
Huge.
Almost as you know,
not quite as bad as what's happening at
opioids say,
but it was massive and uh,
Switzerland got this amazing kickass
female President Call Ruth Dreifuss to
explain to people that when you hear the
word legalization,
what you picture is anarchy and chaos,
right?
What we have now is anarchy and chaos.
When you prohibit drugs,
what you get is unknown criminals
selling unknown chemicals to unknown
drug users all in the dark filled with
violence,
disease and chaos.
What she proposed to do is legalized
heroin,
right?
It's important to understand that.
Well,
that doesn't mean it doesn't mean
there's like a heroin Ireland,
the cvs in,
in Switzerland,
right?
So different things that can be
legalized differently.
I don't know the rules in La,
but I'm pretty sure you could legally if
you wanted to own a dog,
a monkey and a lion.
But I'm pretty sure the rules are
different,
right?
Yeah.
I don't think you're going on a monkey.
You're aligned.
But you could,
you know,
if you really wanted to one,
and you were reaching and you could get
them in Texas,
in Texas for something that you could do
whatever the fuck you want,
except you can't have pot in Texas.
Hilarious.
So it's pretty sure in Texas it's
licensed.
So you could,
you know,
they're all legal,
but they're legal in different ways.
Right.
And it's similar way.
What Ruth Dreifuss,
the Swiss president was praising his
heroin should be legal,
but not in the way that alcohol is
legal.
So the way it works is if you've got
heroin problem in Switzerland,
you're assigned to a clinic.
I went to the one in Geneva where the
former president now lives across the
street,
which tells you something and you go,
you,
you got to go early in the morning for
reasons I'll explain.
You're giving your heroin there.
You can't take it out with you.
You've got to use it there.
And then you leave and you go to your
job cause they give you,
they do two things and it's the exact
opposite of what's been proposed in the
u s what's being priced in the USA is
stop prescribing and don't give support.
Right.
Well they didn't think Switzerland is
exact opposite in Switzerland.
They'll give you the drug you were
addicted to and then they give you loads
of support to figure out why you're in
such pain in the first place.
That helped me get housing.
They get your subsidized work.
Um,
they give you loads of therapy that you,
are you aware of a booger?
Yeah,
of course.
Yeah.
But that's probably one of the very best
ways for people to quit drugs,
especially some horrible drug.
And it's a ruthlessly introspective drug
that many,
many people have found great success and
kicking heroin,
cigarettes,
alcoholism,
uh,
getting over past abuse.
I mean,
it is,
it's a long experience.
It can last more than 24 hours.
Totally illegal in the United States.
But a lot of people go to Mexico and do
it.
And I've had very good friends that have
had problems with pills that went over
there and kicked him because of the Boga
does a,
you should,
I'll give you a purchases and intro to
doctor Gabriel.
Marta it,
Brenda don't really know who he is.
He would be a great guest for you as you
live in England and he lives in
Vancouver but he comes to La fellows in,
you should definitely talk to you,
recommend people look it's wet.
But the,
in terms of just to stay with the last
point about Switzerland,
because there was something really,
I think it relates to a bike or in a
way.
So one of things that really surprised
me and that spending time in that
clinic,
I remember there's chief psychiatrist,
they doctor Rita Mangus.
So they will give you as they will give
you any dose you want except one that
will kill you and there is never any
pressure to cut back,
which really surprised me.
So you could go to this clinic and
they'll dose you up with heroin.
They give you the heroin,
you have to use it there.
You can't take it out with you because I
don't want them sell it.
People selling it on.
And also it's kind of bad ass.
You're monitored by a,
by a,
by a nurse.
But,
but the results are pretty incredible.
Right,
right.
So,
um,
the,
well,
the headline,
most important factors,
there have been zero heroin overdose
deaths on legal heroin in Switzerland in
the 12 years that program has existed.
Has the ratio of people using to not
using,
how's it gone down?
Really significant fall in heroin use
because of best researchers by Professor
Ambrose Oakton Hargan who's shown there
been no deaths in the legal program and
an enormous fallen deaths in the illegal
program and enormous spalding use
overall,
the various reasons I can talk about.
But the thing that blew my mind was so
they give them every day as they want
for as long as they want.
And I was like,
oh,
but what we're told is that comes back
to chemical hooks.
What we're told is they'll just want
more and more for ethical.
Right,
right.
But actually what happens is almost
everyone chooses to cut back over time
and stop.
Right?
When I went in there,
I think there were like two people
who've been on the program at the stock,
and I said to doctor Manga,
who runs it?
I don't understand this.
How is this happening?
And she looked at me like I was an
idiot,
and she said,
well,
people's lives get better and it's their
lives get better.
They don't want to be anesthetized so
much,
which seems almost stupidly obvious,
right?
Goes right back to what you were saying
about antidepressants and people's
lives,
like the choice that you make and the
paths that you take and the people you
surround with and the happiness that you
feel from your community.
That's ultimately what leads to a
fulfilling life.
And if you have all that,
why would you fuck it up with heroin?
Right?
I think you're totally right that the
whole premise of lost connections is
becomes what song we were saying at the
start,
human beings have needs,
right?
And if your needs are being met,
you don't want to be an extra time.
I think what you said is very important,
that there's psychological needs that
are just as valuable and important as
physical needs.
Like we know we have needs for
nutrients,
we know have needs for water,
we have needs psychological for all
sorts of different,
our communities
are incredibly important.
Love is incredibly important.
Family's incredibly important.
You know,
I know some people that are older men
that uh,
have been bachelors their whole lives
and their child lists and now they're,
you know,
they just,
they don't have a deep connection with
anybody and they get to this very weird,
strange place where they're like,
is this it?
Now I'm 70 years old and I've never
really had children and I don't know
what to do and this is,
this is my life now.
And it's,
they,
they've,
all their friends have had families now
and their families,
a lot of times the kids are grown up and
it becomes very,
very strange.
No,
I thought about that a lot.
Intubate this guy and professor John
Kasey Opo at the University of Chicago
who is the leading expert in the world
on loneliness.
And he said this thing to me.
So it's a bit like what the woman in
Geneva suddenly way to live your life
studying.
They,
uh,
they had this really interesting,
it's a very simple point,
but it just said,
if you think about the circumstances
where we evolved,
right?
If you got separated from the tribe,
if you were alone,
you were depressed and anxious for
really fucking good reason.
You were about to be eaten.
You were in terrible danger.
If you got injured,
no one would help.
You would die,
right?
So all the,
he showed that,
as you know,
when we're,
when we're stressed,
we release a hormone called Cortisol.
He showed this wrench to experiment.
They wrote about in the book being
acutely lonely is a stressful as being
punched in the face by a stranger when
it comes to cortisol release,
right?
That's how deeply we are resistant to
loneliness,
right?
It's a signal telling you to get back to
the tribe.
That's why we bought,
it's a really important signal.
If humans hadn't had that signal,
we wouldn't be here.
Right?
Um,
and I think you're right.
So when you look at these,
these men,
if you have an isolated,
there was this woman,
so I covered this incredible protest
movement happened in Berlin on a big
anonymous housing project when no one
knew each other and they came together
to protest.
It was a woman who was about to kill
herself because she was about to be
evicted.
And the whole housing project came
together to say she should be allowed to
stay in our home and they should have a
rent freeze.
And it's an amazing story.
I'll tell it in the book,
but there's something,
one of the women said to me that I never
forgot it was called narrow man.
She grown up in Turkey and she come to
Germany,
I think when she was 17 she said,
when I grew up in Turkey,
well I called my home was my village and
everyone in it.
And then I came to live in the Western
world and I learned that what you're
meant to call home is just your four
walls and if you're lucky,
your family.
And then this protest began and we all
got to know each other.
And this whole place became my home and
I think everywhere here is home now.
And,
and,
and she realized that,
that we are homeless in some sense in
the western world.
The US humans have a need for a sense of
belonging.
And our sense of home is too small to
meet our sense of belonging.
There's a wonderful,
a Bosnian writer called Alexander Heyman
who said,
um,
home is where people notice when you're
not there.
Right?
And a lot of like these guys you're
talking about is all the guys who
notices if they're not,
they're probably no one probably are in
a sense homeless,
right?
They'll spiritually homeless.
And um,
I said,
that's it.
I'm not a religious person.
I don't mean that.
Yeah.
He'd go through saying,
you know what I mean?
And so I think it's about,
and this comes back to think about how
different that is,
what everything we're talking about,
they can have different,
our conversation has been to what my
doctor told me when I was a teenager.
And I go in and I say I'm in real pain
and I feel like pain is leaking out at
me.
And I can't control it.
And he says,
you've just got a malfunction in your
brain.
Right?
What are the worst things about that?
There are many things wrong with that.
Firstly,
what he said to me is not true.
Um,
uh,
I'm sure he believed it.
I think he was misinformed that I think
he was deliberately lying to me,
but what he said was not true.
But also to me,
the biggest problem with just telling
this exclusively biological story about
depression and anxiety.
There's some real biological factors of
course,
is it cuts us off from having this
conversation,
right?
All those people you were talking about
who I was so insistent as I was to that
depression is just the result of a
chemical imbalance.
If you think that it disconnects you
from the source of your pain,
it tells you your just biologically
broken and presumably always going to be
biologically broken when the
conversation we're having,
which is a different conversation.
It's a difficult conversation,
is a nuanced conversation.
It's not simplistic.
It's not one problem,
one lever to solve it.
It's a much deeper and more,
uh,
textured way of thinking.
That is the conversation we have to
have.
That's what the best scientists in the
world are telling us.
The World Health Organization and my
worry is,
um,
we're just being pushed in it.
Like you said,
that,
that broken metaphor about driving 37
miles in the wrong direction.
Right?
We're just driving in the wrong
direction.
We're driving away from the source of
our pain rather than towards it where it
can be understood and solved.
Of course,
it's always going to be some pain in
human life,
but the fact that we have this one in
five people taking a psychiatric drug,
you know,
I think the figure is one in 10 13 year
old boys is taking a stimulant drug to
make them focus.
I think the figure is 30% of old people
in,
in retirement homes have been given
antipsychotic drugs to shut them the
fuck up because they're rebelling
against the way they're being treated.
In between one in four middle aged women
in the United States is taking a
chemical anti depressant at any given
time.
One in four,
one in four.
You're talking about that a society
that,
I mean the figures about how many
children is much lower,
but it's so much more extreme.
The F number at number toddlers who have
been given antipsychotics in the United
States is just off the scale.
Right.
Um,
I think doctor Sammie to Mimi has
written about this,
there's some extraordinary figure,
I'm not getting figure slightly wrong,
but it's something like a majority of
children in foster care in the United
States are being given stimulant drugs
basically to shut them up.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a disturbing one.
The ritalin and rarely various
stimulants that they give to children.
Um,
what's that about?
What's the cause of that?
Well,
I think it's related to research as much
less than the other things we've talked
about.
But from it,
it came up a lot in the conversations
that I had.
There are many things going on here.
One of them is,
um,
a lot of the,
so a lot of the,
not all of them,
a lot of the causes of depression and
anxiety that I wrote about,
I couldn't help but notice reading all
the research into being the scientists
also can lead to,
um,
decrease in focus and attention.
So for example,
if you are dead end at work and you,
you feel controlled all the time,
you have to deaden yourself to get
through it.
It's harder attention's a muscle,
right?
It's harder to bring your brain back to
focus.
Like Joe wanted to just go and collapse
and watch,
you know,
watch whatever shit was on the bachelor
or whatever.
I would watch the bachelor actually,
whatever shit would have been on the
[inaudible] on the TV.
Um,
so one is full state of depression in
the bathroom.
He was prepared to take oxy but not to
go to that level of self harm.
Right?
But the,
but the,
or think about loneliness,
right?
There's really pressed casio potion.
This,
if you are lonely,
that triggers what's called hyper
vigilance,
right?
Again,
for very good reason.
If you're on your own in the savannas of
Africa,
right?
You want to be hypervigilant,
of course.
So you find it,
one of the things it was most
challenging to me is this evidence that
the people with the lowest levels of
attention problems and depression and
anxiety in the United States or the
amish,
right.
And I am a atheist,
gay liberal.
So the idea of going,
it's like learning something from the
Amish was initially challenging to me.
And I've got a mare,
I felt really humbled by going and
spending time with,
I went to this village called
[inaudible],
which is just outside of Fort Wayne,
Indiana.
And you know,
there's still a lot I disagree with
about the Amish.
Don't get me wrong,
not least cause I just rewatched
witness,
but,
uh,
the,
but,
but you know,
they,
I could see that they've got,
so it's very interesting about the army.
She's,
you know,
when you turn 16,
if you're an amish,
you've got to leave and go and live in
what they call the English world,
our world.
Right.
And then you decide whether it's come
back about 80% decide to come back.
20% don't.
It's one of the reasons why the amish is
never counted as a cult because no cult
would do that right now.
Call.
It's going to tell you to leave for two
years and then decide whether to come
back to the fact that the exact
opposite.
So they have lived in our world,
they know our world really well.
And even having this very challenging
conversation with,
um,
what's his name?
Lauren beachy.
His name is an amish guy there who said
there cyber,
because back to the weight conversation
we had,
he said,
um,
but there's loads of things I miss.
He talked about missing that seventies
show.
He said,
I used to love driving in trucks because
they obviously don't drive that ultra
steer off the grid.
And he said,
but you know,
if I kept those things,
I wouldn't spend time with my family.
I wouldn't spend time with my children.
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't know who my neighbors were.
And we said the spreadsheet,
angelic thing,
he said,
you know,
weight watchers.
And I said,
yeah.
And he said,
well,
the idea of weight watchers is you can
only lose weight together as a group,
right?
It helps or not only,
but it helps you to lose weight together
as a group that you would find it harder
on your own.
This is like that.
And I said,
what are you saying about the amish is
like weight watchers for the problems of
Western civilization?
And he's like,
yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
And to me that was so challenging.
The idea that you've got to give,
because we comes back to what is there a
junk news in our culture,
we told the solution is always to get
more.
And the idea that the solution is to
have less and be present more is really
challenging.
Right?
I don't even think it's about having
less,
it's about what they're doing is look,
eat,
think about what the amish are doing.
First of all,
massive sense of community,
right?
They're very connected.
They're not using cell phones and not
using email.
So the community is also based on one to
one interaction,
real social cues,
real social interaction,
which is critical.
It's a big part of being a human being
and it's one of the more apps and things
in modern society to physical labor.
They're involved in a lot of physical
labor because they don't use
electricity,
they don't use power tools.
There's so many things that they don't
do,
so because of their culture,
they're making their own homes.
All right,
so they have a vested interest in
helping each other,
working together as a community and they
have a deep sense of satisfaction of
constructing each other's homes.
You construct my home with me,
I help you build your home.
They take care of their animals,
they take care of their crops,
they take theirs.
There's a real connection with where
they get their food from.
A real connection with where they live,
their community,
the sense of just the whole,
the sense of belonging to something
that's bigger than you.
It's a,
there's so many factors involved in
their happiness that you can kind of see
where it,
yeah,
there's a lot of wacky shit with the,
the cult aspects of,
of being an amish person.
But what you get out of it,
it's almost like if you had a self help
group that subscribed to all the
positive benefits of being amish and
they just called it like regrounding or
something like that.
And you just go out there and you become
a part of nature and make mean that's,
that seems like a co op.
And it seems like some sort of a farm
based CO-OP,
right?
Yeah.
Bill each other's houses stay together.
You don't have to wear sexy clothes.
Let's just all wear the same shit.
It's no big deal.
I love how you put that in it.
You're right.
So the inequality,
the richest Dharmesh is as wealthy as
the forest,
but it's essentially as well,
cause it's not like they're not holding
them back.
I think that's one of the things that I
think about this in relation to
attention is,
so there's this theory that amish kids
don't seem to develop Adhd,
right?
And there's been,
it's been surprisingly understudied
[inaudible] doctors.
I mean that's the problem for kids are
bouncing off the wall and he's adorable.
I don't think it's that.
I,
I wondered if it was that and I would
say about it if it was like they don't
have electronics and then obviously I'm
kidding.
I don't think there's an element going
on there.
But actually the main thing is when I
spoke to them they said,
yeah,
we've got some kids who don't want to
concentrate and sit in school,
but so we just let them run around and
go fishing and hunting and state.
Right.
And so many brands,
right?
So there's always going to be,
there may be factors making it harder
for us to concentrate in the
environment.
I think there are,
but there's always going to be a natural
variation in people who want to sit and
focus on one thing compared to people
who want to,
you know,
run around medically.
And that's actually,
you can see how as a species it benefits
us to have both,
right?
But what we do is we try to bash every
child into one particular mode of being,
of course,
actually is designed to prepare them for
Shitty deadening work.
The reason our schools are shitty and
deadening does a,
a guy called Alfie cone,
he says every school has an official
curriculum and a hidden curriculum.
The official curriculum is like history,
geography,
whatever.
And the hidden curriculum is,
this is what we're training you to put
up with in your life,
right?
And if you've got a society where 87% of
people don't like their work and you're
more twice as likely,
almost twice as likely to hate your job
as love,
your job,
part of the job of the school system
will be to deaden children.
So they learn,
you've got to fucking sit there and shut
up and do what you're told,
right?
So that's not a malfunction of the
system.
That's an unconscious functions of the
system,
right?
So we,
we,
we've got this system where we're
bashing these kids to prepare them for
this economic system that's making us
feel miserable.
To me,
the solution is to change the way we
work so we don't have to fucking dead
and our children,
right?
So actually our children can be a bit,
but the arm issue,
who,
you know,
do as you say,
it's not like they're doing
high end cognitive labor is,
will be the fancy way of putting it,
right?
But the,
the,
their kids to them having a kid who goes
fishing and running around,
it's normal.
It's as valuable actually as you may
even be more valuable than the kid who
sits there reading.
Right?
Because actually,
so,
um,
I think there's a real thing about this,
what that tells us,
it comes back to one of the themes
that's come up all through our
conversation,
Joe,
these things that we're told our
pathologies make sense in their
contexts,
right?
Depression,
we're told it's a pathology.
Actually,
anxiety with tides project actually is
largely,
not entirely,
but largely a response to things going
wrong.
We're told addiction is a pathology.
It's a response to things happening.
We're told that obesity is a pathology.
In some cases it's a response to things
going wrong.
We told the kids not wanting to be able
to focus as a pathology in adults not
being able to focus.
I think we need to understand that these
things have meaning.
They make sense,
right?
It doesn't mean they're good most,
it's clearly not good to be a basis,
clearly not good to be addicted
obviously,
but if you understand that they make
sense.
That opens up a totally different way of
responding to them once that actually
fucking work.
Right.
The places that I think about the drug
war,
right for chasing the scream by book
about addiction and the drug war.
I went out with a group of women in
Arizona in that prison run by that
fucking psychopath Joe Arpaio,
who I also interviewed who trump
pardoned.
How the fuck did he pardon that guy?
Don't get me started on that.
About this deeply.
I,
it's funny,
I can tell you about Joe Arpaio cause a
in a funny sort of way.
I felt very sorry for him.
But anyway,
I went out on this group of,
with this group of women who are made to
go out on a chain gang wearing tee
shirts saying I was a drug addict where
members of the public mock them and
jared them.
Right.
And
I remember going back to the prison with
them is called tent city.
And the women were terrified is
something called the hole,
which is where you were sent if you
fucked up.
Right.
And I said to the gods,
we take me to see the whole,
and I've been in a lot reporting from
prisons and God's always
don't want to show you the bad things in
this one cause it's a fucking pantomime
of cruelty.
They want you to see it.
Right?
So they took me to the hole.
It was in fact a whole,
it's a concrete cell,
bare concrete cell with nothing in it,
no TV,
nothing.
Um,
and I saw this woman in there who was
like,
she saw my face through that was just so
desperate to be a human being who wasn't
one of these guards.
She'd been there for a month.
And I remember the audio is actually on
the chasing the scream website.
I'm chasing the scream.com and I
remember looking in the cell and
thinking,
this is the closest you could get to a
literal human reenactment of the cages
that guaranteed addiction in rats.
And this is what we're doing,
thinking it will stop this woman from
being addicted all the places which had
approaches based on punishment and shame
towards these things.
It's sometimes people say,
Oh,
punishing people with addiction problems
doesn't work.
That's way too soft on it.
It makes the problem worse,
right?
Those women go in fucking broken,
devastated,
then they're even more broken and
devastated.
They go out even more fucking addicted.
Right?
So reason why Portugal has massively for
portrait in Switzerland have massively
falling addiction problems and the
United States have massively increasing
one's right.
So to me,
again,
the evidence is approaches towards these
problem that are based on compassion
connection,
uh,
love,
understanding,
seeing that it makes sense work.
They're not magic bullets.
There's still gonna be problems in
anything we do.
And approach is based on shame and
stigma and rage and just condemning
people.
Um,
they just make the problem worse.
Yeah.
There's no doubt about that.
And there's also no doubt about what you
were speaking about when you started
that rant about schools.
Yeah.
About schools where children trying to
fit them into these,
these very convenient categories and
trying to get them to get comfortable
with doing things that they don't want
to do that.
That's great.
If we're,
we've resigned ourselves to turning
children into work robots.
I love that way of putting it.
He just said,
that's brilliant.
Yeah.
It shouldn't really ramping it.
Oh look,
I went through that myself.
I thought it was a fool when I was in
high school.
I was like,
there's gotta be something wrong with
me.
I can't concentrate.
I can't do it.
I'm never going to be good at anything.
I was like,
I'm just going to resign myself to be an
outcast.
I'm going to resign myself to be a loser
because I just couldn't sit still in
class.
I couldn't pay attention.
I didn't want to do the homework.
I was bored out of my fucking mind and I
didn't even realize there was anything
that I could do that I would be
intellectually curious about.
I mean,
I just,
I didn't think that that was a part of
my life.
I didn't think I was a curious person
and it was just merely because I was
being forced to do a bunch of shit that
I didn't want to do and it tainted my
idea of learning and when I got out of
school and then when I started reading
books just for my own amusement and an
interest,
then I realize,
oh,
I'm a very curious person.
I just,
I just didn't want to do what they
wanted me to do.
I didn't want to study what
they wanted me to study and I didn't
want to be stuck in some room with some
person who was under motivated and
really didn't have any understanding of
how to deal with children.
It was the rare person,
one out of five when I was six teachers
that would come along that would give
you like some spark of happiness and
love and you'd go like,
Oh,
this class is pretty cool.
That's a good teacher.
Like Oh,
she's nice,
you know,
he's fun.
And it was rare.
It was very rare.
Most of the time it was a dull grind and
I would wake up with nightmares after
I'd graduated that I'd fucked up and
didn't get the right amount of credits
and I had to go back to school.
I would have crazy nightmares that it
would have to repeat the 12th grade and
go back to school because I just,
it was soul sucking.
And to me it represented the future
because the future was going to be more
soul sucking because you're going to be
working 40 hours a week plus overtime
doing something that you hated and this
is what you had to do if you wanted to
get by in this slide.
And that is what was presented to me.
And that's what's presented to a lot of
people.
And if you take that and keep going with
it,
you eventually become that guy who was
in that job.
And then you say,
well,
maybe I'll get some happiness if I get a
nice car.
And so you take out a lease on a nice
car and then now you have this debt they
have to pay.
So now you have to keep working and you
keep working.
So you can keep this car.
Well,
I'm going to get a condo and then you
get a Condo,
you got more dead.
Then while I'm getting married,
we're getting married.
Well,
we've got to take out a loan for the
marriage because it's really expensive
to get married and all.
She wants a big wedding.
And then you get a big wedding and a big
ring and all this,
and now you're fucking deep deep in the
hall and now you have children.
Oh Shit.
And then you know,
you're like,
wow,
I really don't want to be selling
insurance anymore.
I wish I coulda,
I wish I could have been an artist.
I wish I could have done this.
I wish I could have pursued my
interests.
Well,
it's kind of too late.
You're 150 miles away from the neutral
point,
so you've got to go 150 miles back
before you could start at zero.
I think he put us so well,
and I'm just thinking about that the,
this is the heart of my bit.
Lots of connections is saying we don't
have to have a human culture that
deadens people,
right?
Yeah.
We don't have to have a culture where
people are controlled,
dead end and isolated.
That's not how most humans have ever
lived.
The Amish live much,
far more human beings have lived in the
way the amish live that have ever lived
in the way we live.
Now.
I don't want to go fully back to the
amish obviously,
but,
but there are lessons we can learn from
all these things that we're talking
about,
about reconnection to meaning and
purpose.
And part of what you're saying is we,
we live in a landscape that has been
constructed not to serve people,
but to serve corporations,
right?
This very unusual recent human
innovation actually is.
I said,
you know,
imagine if every corporation was
converted into democratic cooperatives.
Imagine everyone listening to this
tomorrow knew they were going into work
in a place where if there is a boss,
he's elected by them,
he's accountable to them.
Where you decide the priorities for your
workplace,
with your colleagues,
by voting maybe once every three months,
once a year,
whatever.
But the boss is accountable to you.
That's a very different way of living
and thinking about the things we do most
of the time.
And that would again require a vote for
a school system that prepares people to
be citizens taking part in a workplace,
not are you put brilliantly like robot
workers,
you know,
just passively receiving orders that
requires a big systemic change.
Now lots of people are making that
transition.
You know,
like the people I talked about in a
Baltimore bicycle works.
You've made that transition on their
own.
But these are,
these are big social changes.
We can make that the,
and again,
one of these that's so important is
about saying to people like,
it sounds to me like no one said to you,
Joe,
the fact that he fucking hate this
school is a sign that you are more
likely to be successful,
not less,
right.
The things that will make you a success
in your life are the things that this
school is trying to be out of you right
now.
I'm just presuming,
not literally be out of you,
but mentally be you.
Right.
And in a sense that that's what we need
to say to a lot of people about a lot of
these forms of discomfort.
It's not a sign of craziness.
It makes perfect sense.
You feel this way and you're right to
feel this way.
I wonder if that's what's causing all
these children to be on adderall and on,
you know,
all that.
The various stimulants they put kids on,
you know,
uh,
Prozac and all the different things that
they do.
A,
it's literally because they're trapped
in this thing and they can't do it and
they can't do it.
They can't do it.
And it's just they can't concentrate.
And so they give them something.
Yeah.
And they give them this pill and that
pill turns him into a worker robot.
And it's related to a lot of the things
we've talked about as well.
Increasing competition,
for example.
So parents are in such an unequal
society.
If you,
if you have a society like Norway,
where if a kid doesn't do well,
they're going to have a good life.
And if you could,
does really well,
they're going to have a good life.
Right.
You know,
there's less anxiety about,
oh my kids falling behind.
Yeah.
If your kid falls behind,
they can have a really fucking terrible
like,
yeah,
right here too.
But the counter that is rich kids don't
do well at all.
Miserable as hell.
Yeah.
I mean that's a real problem.
A real problem with kids that don't have
to do well.
But I think this,
this,
you've got society that drugs,
kids at the bottom to shut up these kids
in foster care who are traumatized,
not being looked after there being drug
to just basically make them dose aisle.
You've got kids at the top who are drug
to make them compete.
You know,
I mean I've got a friend who's a Wall
Street banker who,
um,
per his kid on,
on,
uh,
corrupt adderall originally one of the
stimulant drugs when he was a young
teenager cause he said,
but every other fucking kid in the class
is on it.
So if he doesn't go on it,
he's falling behind.
Um,
so you have the,
I mean,
what a,
what a sick culture is giving the
children a cocaine like drug.
Yeah.
To make them compete in,
in an unnatural way.
And the fucked up part is it works.
Yeah.
Well essentially,
so the research,
and this is interesting,
I think since the things worth pointing
out,
I'm worried about this in my book,
but um,
the actually there's evidence that um,
kids develop tolerance to it over time,
right.
So actually initially it works really,
really well and then gradually have to
get higher and higher doses until
eventually they,
uh,
there's a maximum limit it all day.
And then,
but then you have this real problem
where actually if you then take the kid
off it,
they will experience really severe
withdrawal.
Right.
And we'll often,
what that's misinterpreted is,
oh my God,
look at what happens to my kid when I
take him off.
And he goes,
it's like,
no,
that's not the baseline of your kid.
That's your kid in withdrawal from pain.
Like remarkable.
I mean I had a,
I spoke about this before,
so I think I can say I had a very close
relative who had a cocaine addiction.
And I remember at the height of her
cocaine addiction,
she had,
uh,
my neck,
one of my,
a young relative of mine that's friend's
prices ambiguously.
Who,
um,
she was drugging with Ritalin.
The doctor given it cause he didn't want
to focus cause he was traumatized
because his mother was a cocaine addict.
Right.
And I remember she used to go drive into
school in the morning.
She would snort a line of coke before
she went.
And then in the car he'd have to swallow
his cocaine,
like pill.
And I thought what a crazy culture that
her cocaine use is illegal and would end
up with,
had been criminally punished and his
cocaine lights substances required by
the police.
You know,
we required not required by the police
are required by the school and mandated
by the doctor.
What a crazy,
see what a culture that is fucked up
about how it thinks about altering
itself chemically about children,
about connection and that and the,
that my relative was very deprived.
The capacity to understand what was
happening to this is the coolest thing
we've done.
If you just give people these,
these ridiculously simplistic stories
about addiction,
it's just the chemical hook or this
ridiculously simplistic story about
depression.
It's just a chemical imbalance.
It's like we say,
you cut them off from understanding the
thing that's right in front of them.
And sometimes I think with,
with both my books were chasing the
scream and lost connections at times I
thought,
do I even need to say this?
It's so fucking Banal,
right?
If you're lonely,
if you're insecure,
you're going to be,
but actually he does need to be.
So when you say,
when you say it's people,
it's a very unusual position to be in a
position where you were saying something
that is both unbelievably obvious and
really quite radical.
Right.
That's a weird,
I can't think of managing it's common
sense but it's not common.
That's what got hungry by the time
they're really is what it is.
It's,
it's not a common understanding.
Now I want to get in to this,
um,
with you.
What about the criticisms of your work
and how have you,
have you taken that in?
If you debated anyone about your work?
Cause I read quite a few things online,
uh,
that were very critical and I didn't
agree with them.
I didn't agree with what they were
saying but I wanted to get your take on
it.
Sure.
So there were a few things,
few points that have been made.
Um,
there were a few pieces that were
written as soon as the book came out by
psychiatrist who admitted that to be
fair to the,
hadn't read the book and they were
responding to an extract from the book.
And obviously in the next structure you
can't make every point you want to make.
Right?
So is 100,000 what was the extract?
What was the,
so what I thought I was saying is even
though the piece I think break clearly
didn't say this is what they thought I
was saying is chemical anti depressants
are bad for everyone and people should
stop taking them.
If I had said that,
it would be totally right to criticize
me.
That's not my position.
My position.
Easy way to criticize you just cherry
pick and my position is,
you know what we said before,
chemical anti depressants give you a 1.8
points on the Hamilton scale,
right?
That's not nothing.
It's not much on average,
but it's not nothing.
Some people,
like for example,
one of my relatives,
the one that we talked about who is
trapped,
she takes chemical antidepressants.
I think she's right to take them right?
She's got very limited margin change.
She's not experiencing extreme side
effects as lots of people do.
I think she's right to caring for her at
1.8 points in a Hamilton scale is worth
having.
But it's not solving a problem,
right?
It's not solving the problem for the
vast majority of people.
And so I think there's been some
criticisms that are,
he's telling people to stop.
That's a dangerous and terrible thing to
do.
Uh,
so that's the most response to that is
read the book.
Cause I don't say that.
If I to say explicitly,
you should carry on taking them.
If for you,
the benefits outweigh the side effects.
Another criticism which I have more
sympathy for in,
I understand where it's coming from.
It's not,
is it's more like an ideological
misunderstanding.
Like we were saying,
we live in such an individualistic
culture.
The,
if someone comes along and it's,
we basically think there's two ways of
thinking about this,
right?
Either you,
your depression and your anxiety,
your addiction to due to a biological
problem,
in which case you deserve love and
support.
Or if you dismantle the biological
story,
what a lot of people hear is,
Oh my God,
you're saying it's my fault that I'm a
fuck up,
that I've got to solve this on my own.
And lots of people turning around and
going,
well,
I can't fucking go and democratize my
workplace.
I can't fucking go and you know,
take a load of Iowaska and learn what
they're just saying.
What are you talking about?
And I think because I'm talking in this,
this,
this third category,
which is biology is real,
is real,
but most of the drivers of this,
our social,
that in the way we live,
because for so long we've been trained
to not think in social terms.
I think a lot of people just literally
don't get what I'm saying,
right?
But when I was a kid,
Margaret Thatcher said the premise at
the time said,
there's no such thing as society.
There's only individuals and their
families.
Now,
I never liked Margaret Thatcher,
but this debate has made me realize how
much I internalize that.
Right?
I was depressed that 13 years I'd
fucking studied social sciences.
Right?
It never even occurred to me.
There was a societal component to how
bad I felt.
Right?
So I was kind of like a thatcherite to
my own pain and distress.
Do you see what I mean?
And I think we've,
so we've so individualized and
internally we start internalize this
individualism.
The,
I think people are understanding.
Again,
they were riffing on the extracts.
These are not people who've read the
book in the main,
but I think it was kind of
understandable for them to be like,
fuck you,
I can't do that.
You know,
I can see why they're saying that I'm
not.
So I wouldn't push back on them so hard
because think,
well,
there are narrow margins and this is why
we need to check.
And people get that.
If you talk about car accidents,
right?
We individual drivers should drive
safely.
Um,
but we don't just leave car safety up to
that.
We have airbags and seat belts and speed
limits.
Driving tests were dry arrest people
under Duis,
right?
If we just took away all those things
and just said to individual drivers,
hey,
drivers and pedestrians,
pedestrians take care of drivers,
take care,
we would have far more people dying in
car accidents than we do now.
Right?
So we accept that there's individual,
an individual role,
but there's a social role,
right?
The whole society deals with the problem
of car accidents and what I'm saying is
the whole society should deal with the
problem with depression and anxiety.
We need social changes like
democratizing workplaces is one we've
talked about a lot that reduced the
reasons why people are so depressed and
anxious in the first place,
but I think in a society that is so
devalued,
the idea of the social,
it's just I may as well be speaking
fucking Swedish where they could
understand it.
What is it?
You see what I mean?
I think they're just neglecting to
consider the possibility that some of
the factors are because of your life and
and the the social aspects,
the physical aspects,
the exercise,
the Diet,
all those various things.
There's many,
many people that do certain neglecting
to take those even into consideration.
I also think people work way too much.
I don't think that's the way to live
your life.
I think we've got a really bad system
and I think the system has existed for
so long that we assume that this is the
only way to live,
that you have to do a 40 hour work week.
I think it's ridiculous.
I think we should work maybe four days a
week and it might be three.
We might,
we may be,
people would be more productive.
They kicked ass for three days a week
and then had a fun time for,
for,
you know,
maybe,
maybe it's like one on one off,
one on one off,
one on one off.
Maybe it's like that.
And just that's the way we live life.
Like have a fucking work day and have a
day where you don't work.
Have you choose to live to work more
because you know you're trying to pursue
something and you're a dedicated person.
You have a job.
That's one thing.
But I just think this soul sucking grind
of,
you know,
getting out of college 21 and grinding
until you're 65 and the new look forward
to your golden years.
You're dying motherfucker.
There's no golden years.
That's all horse shit you,
you know,
you watch it on golden pond too many
times,
you're not going to make it.
The only
bad example,
he hit his daughter,
maybe the golden girls movie is a really
shit feel much epilepsy please.
She's like,
I'll wash it for the first time.
I played recently by,
there was another thing going on.
There's another thing going on.
I had to make sure I that miss my
flight,
but there's nothing going on,
which is
what we've done is we've told people the
path out of stigma is to say that the
problem is just biological.
Right?
Right.
So we said people,
you should not be criticized for having
an imbalance.
We even more than that,
it's like having a pancreas disease.
We just need to give you a medication.
Exactly.
We've told people you should not be
judged for your depression,
anxiety,
addiction because it's a biological
problem.
I entirely agree.
Obviously people should not be judged
for their anxiety,
depression or addiction,
but actually it's a really interesting
experiment.
They show you that this is just a
complete Monday's first trigger me and
this is I to be an amazing
neuroscientists call Mark Lewis,
who I was talking about this and I said,
you know,
I'm worried cause you explaining a lot
of the things we've talked about to me
early in my research.
And I said,
you know,
I'm worried about this mark,
because won't this just reintroduced
stigma,
right?
If we're saying it's not just
biological.
And he said,
yeah.
Did anyone ever doubt but leprosy or
AIDS were biological problems?
Right?
Right.
Literally nobody ever doubted that.
Zero.
You might have noticed there was some
stigma against leprosy and aids.
Why do you think saying something is
biological removes the stigma around it?
I thought I say it again.
It's a simple point.
The wow,
I'd never thought of that.
But there's actually an experiment by
women I interviewed called a Professor
Sheila matter,
which looked at this question of stigma.
She,
so she wanted to pick her out,
which is more de stigmatizing,
telling people,
uh,
that,
that mental health problems are caused
by your biology or saying that caused by
your life.
It's what they do is it's a little bit
of a complex experiment.
I think it's worth explaining.
Say you're the guy who's taking part in
the experiment.
They bring you in and they say,
before the experiment begins,
we just want you to sit here and fill in
a questionnaire,
right?
This is you don't realize,
but this is actually the experiment.
It's you're sitting next to someone else
who you don't realize as an actor and
you get chatting and the actable sup.
They'll run it two ways.
Sometimes the actor will say,
I've got a mental health problem because
of my biology,
and sometimes he'll say,
I've got a mental health problem because
of bad things that have happened to me.
Right?
Then you told the experiments beginning
come through to this room and you're
told you joe have got to teach this
other person.
The person you don't realize as an actor
a pattern.
It's like a patent on a computer is
we're testing how well people learn
patterns and every once you've taught it
to him,
every time he gets it wrong,
I want you to push this button and this
button,
we'll give him a short sharp electric
shock,
right?
Won't kill him or anything.
It's not going to fuck him up,
but it,
it's uncomfortable.
Right?
And they wanted to see would there be a
difference in how many electric shocks
and how hard you hit hit the button,
depending on what you were told,
what they found was you were
significantly more like you zapped the
person more and harder if you thought
that the problem is just due to their
biology than if it was due to things
that happened to them in their lives.
And I think that's because I think this
is the stuff we're talking about is the
part that stigma because what it says,
if what we're saying is this just this
class of people who are biologically
different to us and they have this floor
that you and I don't have,
um,
you can see why that leads to stigma,
right?
But if what you're saying is actually
we're all uniquely,
we're all vulnerable to this stuff.
I'm actually the things that are making
some people depressed,
anxious,
and addicted and making loads of us just
less happy than we could be less
fulfilled than we could be.
What that does,
instead of making dividing us into two
tribes,
it says we're all on a continuum,
and actually the fight that will help
these people who are depressed and
anxious will also improve your life.
Right.
That's to me a much more powerful
message.
It's solving a problem,
being an inexplicably biological
malfunction.
It's a response to things that you can
see in your life.
Right.
Well,
it's interesting that we've always had
the term sadness,
right?
People have always experienced sadness,
but if you go back and go through
ancient literature,
you don't see a lot of stories about
people suffering from depression.
That's a relatively new distinction.
You did get people who talk about melon
Melancholia.
Yeah,
sure.
Do you think depression has always the,
the state's been acute and extreme
unhappiness.
Always been people living on happy
lives,
but the state being depressed
as being a clinical,
psychological sort of a diagnosis that's
relatively recent.
Well,
the idea that it's a pathology and it's
probably coming up to,
I was thinking,
but this way you were speaking earlier.
Um,
we do,
when we talk about food,
that's the thing of it is you can tell
him what was that British when I first
came to the,
the u s I never remember,
I remember the first time someone ever
offered me an indigestion pill,
which they don't exist.
Ingestion pill that you can buy them in,
like,
like pepto Bismol or something like
that.
Right.
And I meant that just saying,
but,
but wait,
indigestion is a sign from your body.
You're eating too fast.
You don't want to,
you don't want to get rid of that
signal.
You'll,
you'll,
you'll eat too much or hurt yourself.
Right.
That,
that's,
that's not a malfunction.
That's,
that's a function.
Right?
Right.
What about that?
You know,
that the,
it comes back to so many things we're
saying,
the things,
the feelings that we have of distress
are not malfunctions.
That telling us something is missing in
the environment,
in the psychology,
in our lives.
They're not fuck ups with as a signal
industry that they,
they,
they benefit from feeling that void.
Like if you've got an issue,
they've got a pill for it and as soon as
you create that sort of an an
environment,
they're going to constantly be
innovating and trying to come up with
new pills for new issues and even create
ailments,
makeup ailments and come up with
solutions for those ailments.
And a lot of those are actually,
we've,
we've shown this on the podcast many
times.
Those were done by advertising agencies.
They've actually created names of
diseases and issues just so they can
come up with solutions.
One of the things that was most shocking
in the research,
but the loss connections was realizing
how much of what I had been told was
invented,
not by scientists but by drug company
PRS.
So it,
I'll give you an example,
two examples that print,
I'm going to have to go in and set.
No worries.
Um,
what got you one other interview before
my flight.
So fuck that interview.
Sorry.
The uh,
the,
there's this so everyone knows,
if you think about taking selfies,
right?
You take 30,
30 selfies,
you throw away 29 and you only used the
one that can't do that.
Don't be a bitch.
Take a selfie and go with it.
It's like deniro in the deer hunter,
one bullet,
the three that you already have.
You know,
you use the one where you look good,
right?
Turns out in the whole process when,
um,
antidepressants were first being
marketed to us,
they basically did that with scientific
studies.
What they did is they,
they,
they would commission a hundred studies.
Uh,
90 of them would say mixed results or
poor results.
Those all got put in the trashcan.
And the only,
the ones where,
I mean,
there's one study I cite in the book,
I think it was,
they tested the drug on 247 people and
they only published the results for 27
of them,
who you will not find it hard to guess
where the 27 for whom it,
right.
So the early
results were hugely exaggerated.
You'll remember that when
antidepressants were first marketed,
people are told,
you know,
it'll make you better than well,
right?
No one says that.
Now you'll notice that stuff's all gone
away,
right?
It doesn't happen anymore.
Um,
so there's this huge,
actually Eliot Spitzer did an amazing
job when he was attorney general in New
York state.
I've taken the pharmaceutical companies
to,
to court because it's particularly
affected me when I read it because it
was the drug that I was given as a
teenager.
It's,
um,
called paroxetine or Paxil in the u s
that the,
the company that manufacturers,
it literally had a leaked memo from them
in which they say this doesn't work for
teenagers,
but that I think the phrase they used
was this would be unacceptable for the
commercial profile of paroxetine.
So they just said that it did and that's
the fucking drug I was given.
Right.
It's shocking to see the drug that you
were given the,
this company involved.
So it didn't work for people like you.
Right,
right.
Um,
and,
and you know,
when it had very powerful side effects
on me,
I gained a huge amount of way.
It has all sorts of side effects.
Um,
the,
did it help you at all?
I thought a strong initial boost and I
would say it probably did give me 1.8
points on the Hamilton scale.
Like what we're talking about probably
gave me a very mild boost,
but it didn't solve my problem.
And the problem is the story I was told
about it,
that this is the solution because the
problem is the chemical imbalance
disconnected me from a much wider
program of reconnection in my life that
did in fact solve my depression when I
embarked on it.
Right.
The,
the so,
so I think the,
the drug companies,
it's scandalous what they did.
It's not that the drugs have no value,
they do,
but when you read through what they
actually did and the way the stories
were constructed,
um,
and the,
the,
the
bullshit we were told,
you know,
I mean I remember it just being a
clinical psychologist talk to Lucy
Johnson and he's a brilliant person and
her just saying,
you know,
everything you were told is bullshit.
And me just sitting there and going
through this is what my daughter told
me.
This is what my doctor told me.
This isn't my daughter.
She's the fact that shit bullshit
cautions,
no legal repercussions against those
people for doing that.
It's just stunning.
I mean there was something about what
you think about like insider trading,
how devastating the penalties are for
that.
This is far worse.
One of the scandals is the um,
the FDA,
how much of it is funded by the drug
companies itself?
Right.
40% of the budget.
I mean,
imagine if you had a ballgame where one
side was fun,
where one of the teams paid the referees
wages.
Right?
Right.
I think you'd find that gate that,
that that team would win a lot more
often.
All right,
so what we think is,
oh,
there's this dispassionate judge,
the,
and one of those scans.
Even the way the rules are constructed.
So to get a drug,
and I think there would have been
slightly tightened recently,
but the t one entity presence were first
introduced to get a drug to market.
You only had to demonstrate to studies
anywhere that shows any efficacy.
Right?
So that means you could commission 3000
studies and if two of them,
it's not that the FDA would take the
balance of the research,
if you could show to that it works.
That's what they represent those studies
to the FDA.
They didn't have to show them everything
they've done.
Exactly.
It's gotten a bit better now.
There's now more publication required,
which is one of the reasons why so few
new chemical antidepressants are coming
onto the market because the rules have
been slightly tightened.
And as a result where all the new ones,
they're not coming on,
you know,
the,
I mean there are some,
but they're far more limited.
How has he shown also that rigorous
exercise is actually more effective in
treating depression than
antidepressants?
I think I was going a bit too far,
but there's evidence that while there's
very strong,
if it's taught to Isabelle banker who
you should,
you would love,
I should introduce you to her.
She's a primatologist Chilean
primatologist,
basically the best person in the world
as far as can said.
She's a hardcore chalea and she's
currently in some jungle somewhere
better than Mick Jagger's ex wife.
Uh,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
I like Marianne Faithfull,
but Isabel as something else.
Right.
So it's about ultimately is my last
point,
but Isabelle,
so she's demonstrated,
she showing loads of things.
One of the real interesting things is,
um,
nature,
so she's shown that exercise is a
massive,
really powerful anti depressant.
But interestingly,
exercise in nature is even more
effective.
And she's shown her theories.
And I really liked this.
She,
she did a lot of work with Bonobos,
both in zoos and in the wild.
And she's got really good stories about
how Benobos basically bond by lesbian
group sex.
And she,
she,
she's had a pioneer how they managed to
create vibrators when they're in the
zoo.
It's an amazing story,
but the,
uh,
like literally she would like get the
buckets and they would find a way to
turn it into a vibrator.
She was more of them,
right?
And then have massive lesbian origins
with their vibrators,
British Zeus,
and he's like polite British parents
would be like,
what's happening?
And they'd be like,
come over here.
But the is the most theories.
So animals go crazy and zoos a lot of
the time,
right?
Carrots rip out their feathers,
horses start obsessively swaying.
Elephants will grind their tasks down to
nothing.
Um,
uh,
and,
and she basically argues is [inaudible]
Bob,
this is simplifying your argument.
She has as many things going on here.
But um,
the,
the humans are being animals deprived of
their habitat feel like shit.
And we are increasingly deprived of our
habitat.
The habitat we evolved in,
right?
There's lots of evidence that people who
live in areas with no green space,
I'm much more likely to become depressed
than people who don't.
And people who move from one area
without greenspace torn area,
we greenspace become much less
depressed,
rise loads of research on this.
There was actually an amazing study.
Michigan State Prison looks out by just
by accident,
no one designed it this way.
One part of it looks out over just bare
concrete and one part of it looks out
over like lovely green space and the
people who when the,
there was just random where you ended
up,
but the people who looked out over the
concrete,
we're 23% more likely to develop mental
health problems,
right?
So this thing about as Isabel says,
we are animals that were designed to
move through nature.
If you are not an animal moving through
nature,
you are not a healthy human being.
You are not in your habitat,
you need to be in that habitat at least
some of the time.
Right.
And um,
yeah,
I,
she's got by has the best stories I've
asked that you should do.
You should,
you would love her anyway.
She,
I'm sure she has both lesbian group sex
stories and stories about how you can
kill your depression with nature
exposures though y'all aren't.
Thank you very much in one more time.
The name of your book.
So the book is called lost connections,
uncovering the real causes of depression
and the unexpected solutions.
If you go to the book's website,
www.thelostconnections.com you can find
out what loads of people from Hillary
Clinton to Tucker Carlson to Ellis Elton
John had said about the book.
You can take a quiz to see how much you
know about depression and anxiety.
And the book has a facebook page,
it's facebook.com/the lost connections.
And the other book we talked about is
chasing the scream just about addiction.
Or you can find out more about that at
www dot chasing the scream.
Scream as an ally.
Like Jen,
Jamie Lee,
curtis,
and halloween.com.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
I really do their job really so much.
That was fantastic.
Cheers.
All right.
I really enjoyed that.
[inaudible] we're going to the proper
little bit.
Didn't way.