The Joe Rogan experience,
we're also paying for the sins of a lot
of other people,
like for centuries let's,
you know,
white American men dominated everything
in this country and like,
you know,
there's also a reality of a lot of
people were treated like garbage for a
long time and a lot of promises were
broken and there's a reality to that.
That's not excuse making,
it's not,
it's a real thing.
And then they say,
well,
you know why people have benefited from
that system leading to.
So what's happening is in an effort to
balance the playing field a little bit,
a lot of us today are being treated
unfairly because the balancing act is
making things go so far and like I do
understand that.
That's why I had a conversation after a
tosh has a 10.
Who did they get?
Oh,
Tracy's gay jokes.
And I had to get from folks who don't
know,
Tracy Morgan did a joke about if someone
was gay who had stabbed them.
Yeah.
And everybody went crazy and I had a
couple of gay comics on Rick Chrome,
Jim David,
and we talked about this on this comedy
special I did.
And uh,
the as Comedians,
I asked them how do they feel about the
imbalance in the language,
like the fact that you get in trouble
for that now and Jim Davidson,
I'm okay with it.
And uh,
I'm like,
well,
how are you okay with it as a comic?
And he goes,
because it's not a level playing field,
meaning what he thought was like in
life,
gay people had not treated as well,
so he didn't give a shit if,
if that guy got into a little bit more
trouble.
And I kind of,
I heard what he said.
They're like,
even though I don't want to get in
trouble for it,
in that sense,
he was right.
It's like,
you know,
we still have a big segment of our
country that can't get married and
they're treated like second class
citizens.
But yet we go around and tell other
countries how to live their lives were
so full of shit.
It makes me nuts.
Well,
I think there's a real legitimate
argument in the idea that until it
balances out,
until everyone completely relaxes on
discrimination towards gays,
like,
like there's no discrimination on
bachelors anymore,
you know,
like if a man has a 50 year old man,
he says,
I'm just not getting married again,
there's no discrimination or social,
not a social pariah,
but if he decides to marry a man than it
is like,
well what?
Well,
what is that and why is that not
eradicated from our culture that?
Well,
once that is eradicated from our
culture,
then I think people are going to be much
more likely to accept gay jokes much
more like.
Because I keep hearing that gay jokes or
homophobic and I'm like,
guess what?
No,
they're not.
It's not homophobic at all.
It's a gay joke.
Just like ha jokes about straight sex
aren't header of Bobek.
Alright.
There are jokes about sex and there's,
there's jokes about everything and it's
really about context.
It's not about the subject matter and
you can't eliminate certain subject
matters.
You just can't because the human
language is very nuanced.
There's a lot of shit going on and every
single interaction that you have,
we're humor could potentially be crafted
from.
It can be taken in a whole wide variety
of different ways and I like all of
those ways.
I like people saying fucked up shit.
They don't really mean.
Sure.
I think there's something funny and
Tracy Morgan saying if a photo most
good.
I mean it's ridiculous.
It's ludicrous,
right?
It's not real.
Of course he wouldn't do that.
Of course it would be.
You know,
it's,
it's ridiculous.
The idea that it's like,
I do a joke.
I'm like,
guess what?
Johnny cash didn't really shoot a man in
Reno just to watch him die either.
Maybe.
I don't think he did.
He might have more likely that he did
it.
Then Tracy Morgan would establish son,
stupid johnny.
Johnny.
Johnny cash probably should have said I
took some pills and fell asleep on the
tour bus.
They might be more accurate.
Longest boxing match ever.
Let's find out.
March ever typing
was the longest boxing match in history.
Oh my God.
A boxing match landed.
Lasted seven hours already.
If I can do the man fuck is that.
Is that real?
Oh my God.
Listen to this.
The longest boxing match ever took place
in New Orleans on April sixth of 18,
93.
The matches between Andy Bowen and Jack
Burke,
both of whom claimed the lightweight
title.
After the reigning champ,
Jack Mccall full all of fee all fluffy
Jack Mccall.
If he retired,
the winner of this take all purse was
set at $2,500 and in order to decide who
is really the new champion,
that match was set to fought to a
finish.
They fought to a finish like that all
through the contest.
Fighters went at each other aggressively
pounding each other with their gloves,
inflicting and sustaining tremendous
punishment that read like someone wrote
it with their pants off.
That Red Light is vigorously oiled,
up and shaved and are yet three minute
rounds wore off.
Oh my God.
They went to a hundred and 11 rounds.
Both fighters,
dazed and weary gave up and did not come
out of their corner.
Pull zoos or you can't fight one hundred
and twelfth round.
We'll move.
It'd be one guy telling them,
just get up rocky here and you'll win
Guinness.
Guinness says it's 276 rounds in 18,
25 English people might.
We heard it much longer than that.
We are.
Endurance is superior with proper boxing
training.
That sounded more South African,
so maybe they're right man.
I don't know.
Whoever fought over 100 rounds is the
craziest fucking human being that's ever
lived.
That fight was only four and a half
hours.
Oh,
that's weird.
One of the 32nd rounds.
It doesn't even make sense.
I can't even do the math.
I'm not going to try 2,500 bucks.
That's crazy.
For the welter with a welterweight
championship of the world,
what are lightweight rather these days?
It's a good question.
It's a very good question.
I've been at building a million bucks.
Yeah.
Is that weird?
Like when you hear about like economies
imploding and then all of a sudden like
a loaf of bread is worth a million
dollars.
How the fuck,
what does that even mean?
Yeah.
I don't even understand that people have
billions of dollars.
How does that number even a real number
and can I have you?
I'll pull out a billion dollars in cash.
Let me see.
Yeah.
At a certain point in time,
you have to admit the hack the game.
Okay.
You hacked the game somehow.
Dude,
how'd you get $10,000,000,000?
Don't understand.
When you know you're a guy like Bill
Gates,
you have submarine inside your giant
bear.
You know like,
Hey,
what happened here?
What did exactly that you do?
Where are you getting all that money is
this.
This isn't fair.
You have escape pause in your house to
jettison you to the middle of the
fucking ocean.
Whenever it fucking dangerous shows up.
Yeah.
You have a constant team of security
detail run you.
That's like having a bank.
You know around you all the time.
Bill Gates is worth what?
A hundred billion or something crazy
like that.
It would have fit with that whole jv.
Him dropping $40,000.
He shouldn't pick it up kind of thing.
Yeah,
that's what they say.
It's like if he drops $40,000,
it's worth more of his time to keep
moving forward than it is to turn around
and pick it up.
He just was.
What happened was he just didn't turn
around to pick up the bonus.
I just got almost for,
for bludgeoning another man for 15
minutes.
He,
if he dropped that,
he wouldn't pick it up.
Oh Shit.
Itunes or recording to server,
get the fuck outta here.
Server.