Hello Freak bitches.
How much material do you think?
I would say if you're going to become a
big name standup comedian,
you're going to have to put out a bunch
of specials.
Right?
So if you put out how many specials can
you do on your life before you have to
start talking about other shit?
Probably,
you know,
or five,
four or five specials.
Just cause a lot of stuff that I
remember it like it was so edit time,
like I can laugh at it now,
but back then it was paying.
So I didn't get all drugs like my sister
did.
I didn't do,
my brother didn't got on drugs to deal
with bullshit that we was going through.
I just,
they,
you know,
sober thought he mava goes crazy.
So to get rid of the pain,
I just kept putting it in the back of my
head.
I didn't want to remember it.
So when I became a comic,
all of this shit start rushing through
my brain and I have to ask my sister,
bitch,
is this real?
I just asked my sister the other day,
my granddaddy ran a bootleg house.
So in this bootleg house,
I had a retarded uncle named uncle cecil
that was crippled,
but my granddad would buy him pussy on
Friday.
But me and my sister would have to go in
there with a prostitute and hold his
legs back until he gets his dicky before
we could go outside and play.
So I called her up and I said,
is this shit real?
You get a hold his legs back cause he's
a cripple.
You know how when they need so he
couldn't,
we couldn't get it in until we move this
fucking legs back.
Wow.
I remember one time I was like,
hurry up probably eight.
I was like,
oh go see.
So stop fucking smile because they were
retarded.
He's
awful.
He's so fucking off.
And I asked my brother,
I was like,
do y'all
limited shit?
I'm going crazy and all.
I'm like,
come on brother.
Last weekend I said,
my Mama used to have this theory.
She's saying when when it rains and the
signage shine,
the devil was beating his wife.
You ever heard of that?
Yes.
And as you say,
if it will rain and the lightning and
the song was shot,
he caught the beast.
Cheeky.
He's all season.
You should be the beach.
Cause she don't believe in God
damn.
Talking about you crazy.
Somebody I used to think they stole me
Joe.
And it's fucking crazy.
I am being distracted by how much I have
to urinate.
Oh,
the other day I was thinking about,
I'm glad gas just started man.
I know,
but I was not prepared.
I had a water.
I drank a whole one of these.
Good.
And then I had Andre.
Yeah.
Stay healthy.
Uh,
and I had a bunch of coffee this morning
too,
but uh,
I was thinking yesterday,
this is related.
How much would you weigh if you never
went to the bathroom?
You'd be dead.
How quickly?
It wouldn't take long.
I mean,
what if we had evolved to just not ever
have to,
I like a baby after just a month would
be bigger than the biggest human ever.
I need to do the math.
Well,
it depends on what you need to consume.
Like,
if your body was so efficient that you
no longer to urinate,
like we kind of assumed that your body
would need to urinate.
But why?
If your body needs water to stay alive,
like what,
why are we assuming that it has to
protest to get water waste?
That it doesn't have one anymore?
Well why could,
could we just turn that into more hair
instead?
But why does it have to get rid of
waste?
Like isn't it possible that we can
become so efficient that we no longer
need to get rid of waste and we can just
sort of exist by breathing completely.
Just like self.
Yeah.
We,
I mean to get to a certain size and once
we get to a certain size,
we just,
you know,
whatever you evaporate off by walking
around like that you have to take back
in.
Right.
I guess,
you know?
Yeah.
Cause they have,
you know,
robots that that just dissipate heat.
They don't have her make a waste
product.
Your laptop doesn't create as much waste
as a human,
but it's also not nearly as like
complex.
Right.
Uh,
but in some ways it's more complex.
They've been able to make machines that
can poop.
You put food in and then it's got
bacteria and different pumps and
reservoirs inside and it creates
something that resembles completely and
smells just like a human dump.
Whoa.
The first one I saw was done as a piece
of art as art work.
Like an artist created this machine that
could poop just like a human.
And uh,
now they do it ad they call it a Robo
Gut.
It's actually a medical thing because
when people have gi problems of poop,
transplant is commonly used to
reintroduce the healthy bacteria and
taking poop from someone else and giving
it to the sick person,
shoving it up.
There is kind of like,
you know,
there's a lot of possibilities for
rejection,
infection,
stuff like that,
I guess.
But the Robo Gut can make just perfectly
clean poop just with the kind that you
want.
Whoa.
Yeah.
You get some artificial poop put up
inside of you to fix any imbalances that
you have in your gut flora.
That's fast.
And that crazy can have like a poop farm
of robot intestine,
right?
That are just,
and what do you feed them?
Yeah.
Digital digitally do burger runs for the
Robo guts and then they totally are.
It's got to be totally organic.
It's got to probably,
it's probably just like a paste or a
liquid.
You'd be like baby food.
It wouldn't have to taste good.
The robot's not going to complain.
Yeah.
Fuck that robot.
Just eat it,
bitch.
Well,
you remember when Jay z went to Cuban
and got in trouble and everything,
the media was like,
oh look it does he know that that um,
fucking che hated black people and
you're like,
what are you talking about?
Like what is going on?
It was the weirdest and Che Guevara
Dialing 1964 or something with a Che
Guevara.
And he also went over to,
and Golan fought like the revolution in
Africa.
So it's like,
I don't know if that's really true,
but it's just so crazy.
He was the perfect guy though.
It'd be on a tee shirt.
He just looked like such a great
revolutionary.
I know people that wore a Che Guevara
tee shirt that didn't know Jack Shit
about,
remember there was that wave of Che
Guevara support that happened like,
like a decade ago or so.
I can know one body was really what they
were talking about.
You could look cool.
They have one,
a Che Guevara tee shirt on people that
Che Guevara Tattoos and it's like,
why?
What?
What about Che fucking Viva La
[inaudible]?
You know,
like the guy and he would have hated it.
I mean like the fact that he's become
this commercial figure would have been
like,
he wouldn't fucking hated that.
You know,
it's just funny that he's become this
icon of like capitalism.
What's a perfect example of these like
surface inquiries?
Like people just go to look at it like,
oh,
that guy was bad ass.
No,
no,
like looking into it at all.
No.
Trying to understand who he was or
knowing like deeply about who he was.
Yeah.
This is like a baby when you fucking
check.