Okay,
yeah.
Put Your Rogan's podcast.
Birthday all bitches millionaires
smoking bag.
Bring Dope scratching,
scratching.
I love that dude's voice.
That dude's got some serious.
Sold his voice.
I can listen to the beginning of that
song 100 times in a row.
I don't care how gay it sounds to
follow.
Blaming me.
I love that fucking song.
I know it's stupid song.
I don't care.
You know what I mean?
There's some songs where you're
embarrassed that you love him.
I love that fucking song.
I don't give a shit.
If you like sublime,
you would like that.
That's like a sublime to 11.
That would wrap.
Got that vibe.
Especially when I saw him.
I'm like,
wow,
what a weird looking dude.
He's tattooed all the way up to his
neck.
Real skinny little happy,
friendly guy.
Don't get me wrong.
I would like to be a billionaire as
well,
but not feeling the flashlight is
sponsoring this my birthday podcast and
all of the podcasts.
If you haven't fucked one,
you don't know what you're missing.
Joey,
have you fucked one flesh?
It's been so long.
It just turned into a straight
commercial.
Let me get this fucking who I still talk
about it.
Make it shorter.
Make it short and sweet.
It's like I'm a representative for the
flashlight.
I liked that line.
Did you rehearse?
It was the first time you got to drop a
link in it before,
but it didn't reverse at the joint.
Yeah,
we got to actually make a commercial for
it.
Not only are you sick and tired of
waking them up by yourself and out the
fucking window waiting for Cinderella
coming cock sucker from the flashlight
is here.
Pick it up and fuck one of these things
in the ass and the amount you could fuck
around with how you want your.
Close Your eyes and you're that open up
the flashlight.
Show what's inside.
It's a clean white little monkey.
Shaving the assholes clean.
No hemorrhoids.
That's how they do it.
Over that,
the flashlight.
You stick a finger or two fingers.
You can practice whatever you want to
do.
Here we have happy customers.
Read bed.
Tell me about the fleshlight.
Smells great.
Tremendous.
After you wash it off,
before you fucking know.
After you.
Fuck it.
I love it.
Another word from westlake coming weird
and everybody out again.
It smells great after you fuck it.
Oh Jesus.
Load smell terrible.
When you leave them in your stomach,
you know you get like a little puddle in
the summer and you leave a load in your
belly button and it smells like dead
fish.
What the fuck?
Or if you ever like jerk off and you're
so lazy,
you don't even bother cleaning off your
balls and your balls smell like fish.
That's happened like two or three times,
but my balls and smelled like fish
though.
I'll tell you what I do is dry and
crusty.
How much moisture you're generating down
there.
This is what I said.
It's like a jungle son.
I got the treadmill next.
I hold the top of the total there and
the cop comes in,
swells up like a fucking balloon.
You know what I'm saying?
The toilet and opened up the gentleman
there.
You know what I'm saying?
So it pays to be uncircumcised.
Cocks up.
You hold the tip when you're ready to
come and the cop comes up.
But it swells up like a balloon and you
just hold and draw that teach science
bitches.
How funny is that?
It's a common practice to cut your Dick
when you're born.
That's the most common thing,
right?
Why are you even talking about.
I mean he would if pussies came all
trimmed back.
We've pushed these,
came out,
trim back and expose them.
Because of that,
they weren't as sensitive and you know,
the.
We just got used to the way they looked
in their trim back and expose.
We got mad at girls.
Had Lips like it.
What do you have Pussy Lips for?
Those are gross.
I can't even see the pussy.
It's all covered in his fucking pussy
lip.
It's just a matter of perception.
You just get used to it.
There's nothing that's smart about
cutting a kid's Dick.
Did you get your cut?
Fuck yeah.
I didn't want to ask me.
What would you want it not cut right
now?
I think that's supposed to be the way
it's supposed to clean your desk on my
team,
like a motherfucker raised were probably
brainwashed,
but we were raised to believe that you
got like 700 isn't circumcised.
It has a dirty deck.
We're raised to believe.
Well,
I know it's not true.
It's not true.
Fifty program that's not more mushrooms.
The highest self cleaning,
just like a woman's.
We just got to wash it more right
outside and I don't shake it because the
cops are coming to some gonna smell,
but that's everybody in this room now
say ours is built so it just has like a
gutter.
It just drips right off into your inner
legs.
Oh,
it's not a smart move.
You can't argue chopping the forest can
offer.
That's just crazy.
You do lose sensitivity though.
Yeah.
You lose a lot of sensitivity.
It's supposed to feel much.
It's supposed to feel better.
I don't need help.
Kick your belly,
take it,
and I don't need any more knowing that
sucks.
It's not less sensitivity.
It just would feel better.
How do you treat them like that?
More sensitive.
It doesn't necessarily mean you come
quicker,
it just means it feels better.
Have you ever used a condom on a check
so that you can last longer?
No.
You've never done that.
What about you Brian?
I use a condom on my flashlight so you
can last longer as a disclaimer.
See right away we are high as fuck.
Alright.
So some of the stuff seems silly.
That's what's going on.
I just spoke with joy for five days.
I watch the Anderson Silva fight sober
like a priest bitches.
You understand me?
I held out to today because I want to
look good for this thing and I'm going
to buddy guy tonight and bb
motherfucking king.
So I gotta save that Shit.
I'm getting fucked up tonight.
You understanding that Anderson Silva
was insane.
What I fired my was dad.
There's no way.
There's anything in the world that gives
you that much entertainment,
that much drama that there's nothing
like that.
There's no movie that can fuck with that
fight forever.
It's impossible to make a movie that's
going to be as entertaining that draws
you in like that.
So much emotion.
So much anger.
So much,
so much explosion,
so much fucking struggle.
So much.
It looks like all hope is lost.
Slaps on the triangle.
The fucking crowd goes crazy.
She also had the guy pretends not to tap
and it hangs in there.
You're like,
what the fuck is gonna happen here?
And they break it out.
Be like,
wow.
He fucking pulled it off.
He pulled it off,
man.
He.
He kept in there for five rounds and
getting the fuck beat out of them
getting taken down,
getting punished,
getting beat up.
Very little success on the fee.
Hits them a little bit,
but then it gets taken down every time
for fucking rounds.
Chael Sonnen did that shit and he
knocked him down and he knocked them
down and people are giving them 10,
eight rounds.
He got some 10,
That's rare.
It's rare you're going to take it round.
I used to argue with people at King of
the cage all the time where they were
really back in like 2000,
2001 there were seriously thinking about
making a 32nd ground rule because the
groundwork is boring and it's all about
putting asses in seats and I'm like,
what are you talking about?
The groundwork as bar?
Are you kidding me?
He goes,
what's someone getting put on a triangle
isn't as exciting to someone getting
knocked out.
I go,
it all depends on the situation that not
in a prelim,
no one gives a fuck.
That's what it gets knocked out in a
championship fight.
It's different and I mean it's all about
the situation.
That was Anderson Silva losing the
fucking,
losing every round,
getting Jack.
He's,
he's invincible.
He's fucking everybody up.
He was going to crush son and son and
does everything to everything right.
Takes him down,
stays away from submissions,
beat some standing,
knocked him down.
Um,
did everything right.
Everything was perfect.
And Anderson Silva out of his ass throws
up a fucking triangle and it sticks Joe
Rogan because Joe Rogan goes where?
As soon as the fifth round started,
he goes,
it's chill southern.
How's he going to start to celebrate?
No.
I said,
is it too early for celebrate?
I'm like,
this is through the kiss,
but then you catch the drama over three
minutes left.
You can never,
as long as he's acting thing can happen
with that guy.
He to knock you out in one second.
He can get up.
He can get up out of nowhere.
You charge forward.
You get fucking flying kneed in the
head.
I liked Carlos Newton.
Remember that fight?
Carlos Newton was dominating him on the
ground.
He got back up to his feet.
They restarted him because he couldn't
do anything on his feet and pride and he
fucking left through the air and slammed
Carlos Newton in the head with the
flying knee and put them away.
He's a beast,
man.
He's a bad mother.
Anderson Silva is a
skin.
Didn't even break.
He got hit 20,000
fucking times.
The skin didn't even break.
That's that credible.
That's that Brazilian lizard kid he's
got.
You know what I'm saying?
I wanted that,
but my grandmother went their different
directions.
He thought guys is tough as hell talking
about tough guys because I've always
liked them.
I've heard pro and con,
but I've always liked him because he
came up to me and talked to me.
It was very nice.
And that's the farm,
you know,
and I called the farmer Matt Hughes.
I love him to death,
but after last week I just want to say
something.
He did the remake of Chinese connection
because he'd beat the whole fucking
Gracie family.
It needs to do is wait for the Russian
to come over.
You know what I'm saying?
He's got a handle on the lamppost.
And so the uncle of fucking,
the other wise voice one was the worst
one.
I mean,
he's the voiced one crusher.
Ricardo.
So in other words,
Eddie,
you're off the hook.
How sweet was that movie?
Hit Him with.
He hit him with the,
that um,
they call it the headlock.
I guess I tried that last night.
Did you see man,
it's just,
man,
that's instructional.
No,
he put a thing on the,
uh,
under the mixed martial arts.com.
Josh.
Josh Barnett is,
you know,
he's,
he loves all that catch wrestling stuff.
He's a huge casserole catch wrestling
fan,
so anytime there's like a move like
this,
it's like that's a Dave Schultz
headlock.
Dave Schultz and his brother Mark
Schultz.
He's bad ass restaurants used to fuck
people up.
They used to get them with like
Camorra's and Shit and do a lot of
illegal things.
Like they hit a Komora.
There's a beautiful video.
Have you ever seen the video of Schultes
hitting that Kamora and flipping the guy
over?
No,
it's pretty bad ass,
but it's totally illegal and wrestling
and he's basically yanking the guy's
shoulder out of socket,
throwing them over his head,
but a date they would just do like
submissions in a real wrestling match.
Like there were famous for that shit.
They would put guys to sleep with this
headlock and then roll them over on the
back and the referee didn't even know
the guy was unconscious and then they
figured out what they were doing.
They stopped them from doing it.
Wow.
Yeah.
These two brothers that were so crazy.
Have you ever kill anybody?
Like go to your car or anything?
No they didn't.
But the crazy thing is there's a,
um,
I forget the guy's name,
my answer hunter,
who was the guy that killed them?
There was some guy who was this
eccentric millionaire who used to pay
wrestlers to come and work out with
them.
That's what we wanted to do.
It was just crazy guy and he lost his
fucking mind and shot a shot him.
Wow.
Yeah.
So yeah,
the whole thing is pretty crazy,
but yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
I don't remember the exact guy's name.
I don't remember the story and I don't
feel like googling it right now.
If you want to google it,
look up Dave Schultz murderer.
But I mean that was a great card from
the beginning.
I didn't see the prelims,
but I mean,
Mark Scholz in the UFC way back in the
day.
Remember he fought a Gary Goodrich?
Yup.
Wasn't it his brother that died and his
brothers and his brother got shot?
Sat.
There were,
there were monsters.
Monster wrestlers.
Oh,
you cleaned the Olympics?
Amateur Wrestler?
Yeah.
Does it say he won the gold in 1984?
Does it say
who murdered him?
Uh,
with some crazy dude.
You used to want to just wrestle dudes.
He like hired these guys to come and
wrestle him.
I don't know if it was some gang stuff
or what.
I mean,
you know,
look,
there's guys who,
you know,
maybe they will know.
It's not like John e Dot d dot
[inaudible] from the part that was the
guy who killed him was this billionaire
characters.
He slipped a bunch of paint.
I'm not saying that the rest was gay,
but I'm saying if some guy who was a gay
guy just wants to wrestle,
just meet up.
I'll tell you how many rich gay dudes
are there.
A fly people in to teach them some
Jujitsu privates.
I think for a lot of gay dudes,
it's the same game as for a lot of
dudes,
they're looking to turn somebody that
hasn't been a good somebody's wife to
suck their Dick.
They're looking to get some dude who's
not gay to let them fuck them.
You know?
It's beautiful.
It feels beautiful.
Turned somebody want,
they want to get some guys like,
I don't think I could ever be gay too.
Is that the ultimate Mrs Rogan.
So gay friends,
they love straight guys.
They have a thing for straight guys.
They want to turn straight guys and you
know there was a guy that was working in
one of the shows I used to work on who's
working behind the scenes and he was a
gay dude who would tell me how many
straight guys who would get drunk and
let them suck their Dick.
Wow.
He said,
he goes,
you'd be fucking surprised,
honey.
You'd be fucking surprised.
Excel.
Many of these straight guys that I met
at a gay bar,
they're acting straight and that's what
it is that I met at a gay bar that we're
acting straight because I haven't come
out of the closet yet.
There's probably a lot of guys that are
straight,
you know that hang out in that.
Fuck.
These guys think it's that
or do you think there are some straight
guys who are just so silly that might
suck a dick once now?
I don't think so.
I think if you want to suck a Dick,
you,
you're,
you're gay dudes who don't have any
friends.
That's like your bisexual joke.
There's no such thing as bisexual estate
talk here.
I think there's dudes that are just
really fucking dumb and you can talk
them into blowing you.
I really do believe that.
You could talk a guy at the second.
You'd think there's some dumb dudes out
there.
Dude,
there's some real real dummies out
there.
There's some people out there that will
basically do anything you want them to.
You just have to talk enough to them.
Eventually they'll suck your Dick.
That sister.
That's a good reality show to get the
guy to pick is going to suck your Dick
and then tell him to fuck himself at the
end of the night.
Like,
let the guy do the whole thing.
You'd have to get close.
You don't have to like be kissing.
No.
Let them see how strong his game is.
So you have your jimmies that deep.
You know what I'm saying?
Come get me.
Take me out.
Why me and diabetes get them out to.
It's basically a blue balls gang show
for those of the host comes out and
says,
so what do you think?
Suck your Dick.
Not that night,
Johnny.
I'm going for the couch and the trip to
the Bahamas.
Fucking I'm taking second place.
I'm like,
tail salad.
I took the silver.
You know what I'm saying?
Fuck that shit.
A little more.
Get hit by a few cds.
Then at the end of that,
I could pull you aside.
What do you think it even happened?
I just had the night off.
What the fuck the game would be that the
gay guy doesn't realize that if he can
talk a straight guy into it,
he gets like a boss who asshole.
They tripped.
They give him a plaque,
you know?
Give him the fucking world.
A whole wolf run trip of Santa Monica.
The whole thing.
Oh my God.
And he don't know like you gotta say,
Bro,
I got a straight friends.
I think he's gay.
I want you to take them out and just
fucking,
oh my God.
His head or he'll greases hair or shave
his balls.
The whole thing,
he's going there with the intention of
fucking a virgin.
We all get hot when we fucked over the
first time.
You fucked the virgin.
How happy were you on the way home?
I don't think I've ever fucked over.
Even if it was a horrible experience.
I never got a virgin come on time.
I got a virgin was when I got divert.
Denies and that was it.
That's it.
You got to be virgin.
I have many in high school.
The ugliest dude in the room and I got
like 10 grand.
I got a girl one time.
I stuck my Dick in a divergent it.
Then I went to eat.
I didn't know and I came up with like a
little red fucking thing on my mind.
It was disgusting.
Could you imagine if you had to deal
with the kind of shit that you had to
deal with,
the drama that you have to deal with
when you were like 14 and 15?
Could you imagine you have to go back
and do that today.
You fit right in.
You didn't have to change your clothes
already do it.
You just slide right into it.
I dated Peter Pan.
Parents hated spics needed fucking specs
and they get mad at you.
Oh,
they would say right in front of me,
but the chicken was so hot.
I didn't give a fuck all you want the
way out the door.
I would just knock on the door and
they'd open the door and just walk away
from me.
Oh my.
Then she'll come up and then she'd go,
fuck you mom or whatever.
Shut up mom.
But one night I'm at her porch in the
shit,
like 10 minutes and all of a sudden I
turned around.
The father was right.
There was like red in the face.
I just took my hand out of those pair of
jeans and I just fucking went.
I never called her again.
Nothing.
I seen him like years later,
her brother hated me.
He was a fireman,
but they couldn't do dick to me.
You know what I'm saying?
Oh my God.
You ever get caught bone in your
girlfriends when you're a teenager and
your parents come home or her parents
come home and you have to jump in the
closet naked.
It didn't have to jump in the closet
naked,
but I got busted.
I did.
I jumped in the closet naked.
It was her house.
Her Dad showed up.
Our Dad shot.
I jumped the cloth.
I'm naked.
I was so fucking terrified on the condom
was just on and shit and she stayed.
She stayed for hours.
I passed fucking out the closet.
If you were snoring in the closet,
that's how they caught you.
The cost and there you are naked with a
condom on.
Condom was stuck in my leg.
Motherfucker is in the closet and he can
just go to sleep,
feel so comfortable in the closet with a
condom on and he got busted.
Fucking my daughter and he's just
sleeping for this young man.
This is.
How is it?
That would be.
That might be the worst way to meet
your.
Your girlfriend's dad if he wakes you up
because you're snoring because you're
naked in the closet with a condom on.
I have a friend,
I have a friend who just got arrested
because he found his 15 year old
daughter and her boyfriend having sex in
the garage and he beat the fuck out of
the go.
You told me about that.
Yeah.
You told him that I know a guy.
He's a friend.
Hey man,
it's kids are kids are going to do it.
Kids are gonna do man.
Would you be so you think you could have
sympathy on a guy like that.
His daughter's getting banged.
The real thing,
the real problem with men and women is
that a lot of kids grow up in an
environment with their mother and their
father don't get along and they,
they're,
they're volatile and there's a lot of
fighting and yelling and so that's their
model of what a relationship should be
light.
And if you grow up in a happy household
and everybody's cool and everybody,
you know,
everybody's like friendly with each
other and that's what you associate with
human behavior with.
Then that's the type of person you want
with your daughter.
That's the type of girl you want with
your son.
You don't want no crazy shit,
but the problem is that most people
aren't like that.
Most people a fucking wreck,
so the real problem with some kid coming
over and wanting to finger banged your
daughter,
isn't that your daughter shouldn't enjoy
a good finger banging.
I said,
this kid might be a fucking creep.
That's what you have to worry about.
What people have to worry about is how
other people are raising their kids.
You have to worry.
There's a lot of people out there that
are completely ignoring their kids.
That guy,
before he beat that get up,
you should have stopped him and said,
what kind of a house full of abuse
fucked up.
You don't want some kid growing up in a
house full of abuse finger and your
daughters.
That's normal.
That's a normal reaction,
right?
All of a sudden you walk in on your
daughter have done.
It's not normal and hold them up.
If you look at your daughter wanted to
do it,
if she wanted to do it and he wanted to
do it is absolutely not right that you'd
be,
oh no,
there's no way.
No Way.
You have to say,
Hey,
listen,
this is irresponsible.
You guys could get pregnant.
You have to be wearing protection.
You shouldn't be doing this so young,
you know,
but look,
you can't do it like this and you can't
do it so stupid where you get caught in
the garage.
Is this consensual?
Is Everybody happy?
That's what the conversation you have to
have.
If the girl was crying and say,
look,
you know,
this is a,
this is an embarrassing thing.
You fucked up.
Learn from this,
this absolutely correct.
You can't beat the kid up because that's
you,
man.
It's a kid too.
You got to remember that's a big manner,
so why to beat him up?
His brain's not big.
He's just fucking.
It's what you want to do all the time.
It's what everybody wants to do.
Hey,
let me tell you something guys.
When it comes to daughters or wives,
it's all fucking different.
We're not in that room,
so wipe the slate right now when it
comes to the daughters and wives.
It's a whole different animal,
gentlemen.
So relaxed with that shit.
You know what I'm saying isn't wise?
It's a duplicate shotgun,
but you should look if the guy's hurting
her.
If he's hurting your daughter,
that's one thing,
but if your daughter's liking it,
your daughter shouldn't be able to like
sex.
No,
no.
That's ridiculous.
I know what you're saying is right.
When the animal instincts take over and
talk to real animal instincts,
those should be about disrespect.
Okay.
Check this out.
Disrespect about disrespect.
If you were the 15 year old kid and you
got caught banging his daughter and he
walked in,
would you be terrified?
Of course,
because of movies,
because the movies,
because guys have no.
No.
Because of natural instincts of born.
Thinking that the whole time from when
you're a kid.
Don't think it's a thinking thing,
bro.
I think that's an animal thing.
I think that's what I'm saying.
What I'm saying.
You're born thinking that takes over
sometimes.
That's why men have such a huge problem
with men like grown men having sex with
like 14,
13,
12 year olds because those are like
little kids,
you know,
and when grown men want to fuck little
girls like that.
That's.
That is one of the most disturbing
things in one of the things that that's
the least acceptable.
Least,
you know the least likely to be
forgiven.
You might be ruining my fucking
daughter's life right here.
That's what that is like.
You fuck everything?
Not Forever.
You're probably going to get a pregnant.
I'm gonna kill you.
All the work I've done and now you're
fucking it up and you don't even love
her.
You'll probably tricked her situations.
You've been with us for two years.
The father walks in,
he likes you.
Do you ever have sex?
I mean,
after six months you figured that
they're having sex but in the garage a
total different guys.
And that's why we're with daughters and
wise men and I wouldn't beat the fuck
out of the cake because I'd be a
hypocrite.
I and hate behind the high school.
I remember one time I even dug into snow
and Dick and I wasn't a fuck this
chicken,
there's snow.
I'd got a little hot behind the fire
department in the fucking stopped the
night before I was fingering her little
monthly and the next day I like 12 feet
of snow.
That wasn't going to stop mad flavor.
When you're full of testosterone,
you're 14.
I called it.
The thing about kids,
they accelerate,
they kick it to the next level,
finger in one day,
the next day,
the daytime with a shovel shovel,
the little patch.
We were partying the night before and I
thought I was actually going to fuck
her.
I was even happier because I was going
to have my whole sexual igloo.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm going to have a sex Eglu Alaska
motherfucker.
I swear to God.
You know what testosterone takes all,
but that's not the situation at hand.
It's been having a parent that I would
beat up a kid.
I think I said,
get the fuck out my house.
Yeah.
Would you would definitely be very,
very quick on the draw.
If he was disrespectful,
he started being an addict to you.
You might be a little hyper aggressive.
You Bank your natural instincts is going
to be.
It's hard to ignore your natural
instincts.
Going to be to beat the fuck out of him.
When I was a kid,
I did a lot of young girls and that was
the only parent.
They were German,
German people,
you know.
They were the only ones that were ever
rude to me.
The only ones,
the only panel,
whatever that route to me.
Really?
Yeah,
like the only.
Think about this.
How would you react?
Your daughter's dating some dude.
You met him a couple times.
He's totally disrespectful.
He has no respect for you.
You don't like this motherfucking dude.
You don't want them to be together and
you hate this motherfucking kid.
He's a Dick.
He's a Douche.
She thinks he's.
He's arrogant and then two weeks later
you catch him banging.
You walk in the garage and he's banging
your daughter right now.
You just have a stern talk with them.
You have to realize that you got to put
them to sleep.
Well.
You've got to stop this know if your
daughter marks.
I've never got hurt.
Never threatened.
Harm against a kid.
Used to choking people out,
but he wakes up.
She's dressed in God if she's putting.
Yeah,
but she's not getting raped.
She's liking it.
Exactly.
Where you did you not have sex when
you're a 15 year old boy?
I was 13.
13.
All right,
so in your head though.
Okay.
I was a fucking elicit.
I didn't want to do it though.
I didn't want.
I got talked into it.
If you want the girl to be happy,
you should want her to like boys wanting
to be around nice boys and have fun with
your body.
You know,
responsibly.
That's what you should be doing.
Shouldn't be beating the fuck out of
some kid that's banging your daughter.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I could easily talk to.
I'm gonna.
Look,
this is the last time you allowed here.
I don't care.
You know what you guys do out of my
house,
but you can't be here if you hate them
that bad.
You have to do something.
You don't just fucking start choking the
guy out and now you're in jail.
I think jo jo Jo's got a really good
good,
get the fucker out and three seconds to
read his daughter for a little bit.
By the time he wakes up,
he'll be dressed.
You drag them out of the wake up in the
fucking all backwards.
That's what I think Joe's going to do.
Best case scenario is you find some kid
who likes your daughter and you like
them and he's like a cool guy and you
become friends with them.
That's the best case scenario.
You know some dude who's,
who's dating your daughter,
who you actually like when he comes
over,
you know,
like he's your friend.
Now he's dating your daughter,
but you're like,
you could fuck her and stuff like that.
She's going to want you to fuck her.
She's,
uh,
she's going to want you to imagine dude
hooks it up.
Dude.
Hooks it up,
tries to convince the daughter,
pays for the hotel,
pays for the hotels,
the guy.
I'm telling you,
that's the easiest.
Which
way to turn your daughter into a lesbian
ever.
Could you imagine they would just go
straight laszlo.
That's their deal.
That's probably how lesbians are
created.
When it's not natural,
that's probably how you create them.
You get the father to get you to try to
fuck his friends.
That's probably formula.
That's the best way to have a woman.
Completely distrust men for the rest of
her life.
Just get.
Get your daughter to fuck your friends.
Get your daughter.
Fuck your friend.
Right?
She's just going to try to rebel.
How's she going to rebel?
It's going to go.
Let's go.
That's the only move.
If you've got to check my father in law,
that's pretty fucking cool.
I had a great father in law.
He's the one that bailed me out of jail
the first time.
We were like shaky when I got in
trouble.
Then all of a sudden he was definitely.
There was a weird relationship because
he had boys,
but he was kind of upset how his boys
had turned that they turned into
pussies,
right?
Will.
He wanted them to be very educated.
They didn't want to do that,
so he was kind of upset with them.
In a way.
He doesn't understand,
you know,
that I think you told me this,
so yeah,
yeah.
He was very upset with them and they
were successful.
This roofing company,
you know,
to read different states,
but he just wasn't into that stuff.
So we're always going to be weird when
someone's fucking your baby,
you know,
all my relationships in high school when
I was dating a girl and you know,
as soon as the parents knew or bone and
it was always creepy,
he'd be around them like you're stealing
food from them,
you know,
it's like just filled.
I had my parents walk in and my dad
walked in and my step mom walk into was
having sex when I was like 17 and the
step mom got pissed.
But the data is like,
man,
it's pretty cool.
Yeah.
My mom
used to like fucking try to set ground
rules and shit.
Like she couldn't,
she couldn't come over my house and be
in my bedroom with the door closed.
All right mom,
just get the fuck outta here.
All right.
This other girl,
this other girl I dated,
her parents let me spend the night when
I was 16 sleep in bed.
She would wake up the next morning time
to wake up school bus or whatever time
to wake up to go to school and I just
remember looking up and seeing her dad
and I never thought it was crazy and my
parents knew I would stay tonight,
but now I look back at it.
I'm like,
that's fucking weird.
The only time it happened to me,
I was 21.
She was 17,
was my girlfriend for about three years.
She.
She was 17 million.
Yeah,
I know what you mean.
18 right now,
but we didn't have sex at 17 when she
was 17.
When she turned 18,
that's when the SEC started.
It was just like a month later.
You're not under Clinton definitions so
that when you're just pen pals before
you know.
I didn't even think about that.
I didn't even think about 21 slash 17.
That didn't even enter my mind at all at
our parents were totally cool with it.
She,
their parents let me spend the night.
They were totally cool in the,
unless you're an Iowa where you're now
allowed to be 16 to be a stripper,
but the only law is you have to come
home before 11:00
PM.
How?
That's incredible.
What state?
Uh,
Iowa and I think also Rhode Island.
Is that what I said last time?
You think you got the two to 10,
15 shift.
It's the,
you gotta push that law through someone
fucking 16 year old to see the process
of that reality show on the birth of
that.
Fuck.
That's got to be some people from the
ghetto boys.
He pushed it to the seller.
Hey,
I never found out.
Remember that Shit.
No one covered.
Whereas eyeballs falling out.
Was that real?
Or if that was a real shot himself.
I heard it was real,
but I don't know if that was fake.
Real dude.
That guy was off the deep end.
Crazy.
There'd never been a guy like Bushwick
bill.
That was crazy pitcher,
man.
It's a midget star rapper who with one
guy who shot himself who was fucked up
and all of drugs and still
is a giant star.
Wow.
What kind of pushing you to that guy?
He must've gotten dad.
Bill is probably the.
I'm the Michael Jordan of black bitches.
You know what I mean?
He knows the most painless.
The only other guy is von Troyer.
That guy.
I'm sure midgets around the world have
posters of Vernon troyer and fucking the
street midgets for sure.
Bushwick.
Bill is the number one dude in their
soul.
That's that Bruce Lee.
Hey Dude,
I'm fine.
Fine.
Cold War.
Wait,
wait.
By the Geto boys.
This is the best geto boys.
So hold on.
No,
no,
no.
Fuck award.
Find that.
Please find fuck a war.
But this is shows you bushwick.
Bill could fucking flow too though.
You know,
he had a weird way of talking,
you know,
but his boys were good.
It was fucking talented.
I don't know what he was mad,
but he was talented.
He rose midgetry totally transcended all
that.
He got hoes.
Everybody respected him as a rapper.
He was a fucking rock star mission.
This is a great song.
Hmm.
What is this?
No Shit.
Okay.
Let me play.
Fortunately for him,
he doesn't have to be all that fucking
mad.
They'll never draft a midget like he was
all pissed off.
Like then we're going to pick him like
he was going to be like,
you really felt that angry.
I liked that.
My favorite song.
It feels good to be a gangster.
That scarface,
that whole song was Bushwick.
Bill,
scarface,
scarface.
It's a different guy singing yet.
But that was my get a voice on.
Yeah.
It's a different ghetto boy though.
His best song is a fuck a war.
That's his best one,
man.
That's the best one.
That's all.
Bushwick.
All flow.
That's a good fucking song.
And it's fucking right.
And then there's that little wee man.
Day.
Jackass.
Skater dude.
The comedian that a little kiss.
What does the Dude's name?
Ms Dot Daly's friends.
What was it about the spot right now
though?
You what I'm saying?
Do you know his name?
Brad.
He's imagined with Coleman considered
images.
You funny.
It's people just want to hear these nice
kid.
He's a nice kid.
He's really.
Gary Coleman wasn't considered a midget.
Oh yeah,
no,
but his head was small.
He was different.
He was like a little person,
Gary Coleman.
He wasn't like a real midget dwarf
summer mentioned,
so you know,
it'd be awesome if they remade with
story of Gary Coleman,
but they used webster to play Gary
Coleman,
that guy,
that photo of him in bed dying and his
wife taking a picture.
She's right next to him taking a photo.
That is one of the creepiest photos I've
ever seen in my life.
Which photo can I say?
There's a woman.
I think I saved it.
I saved it here.
Hopefully I did,
but it's Gary Coleman and he's in his.
On his deathbed.
You see if you can find a brian.
All right.
Here.
I'm going to look for it on Google.
Joey,
what's the story though?
You teach today?
Tonight.
What's the curriculum this week?
What's that?
What the fuck are we doing?
We're doing the ham sandwich.
Okay.
Awesome.
Half guard and we're also doing.
I'm old school from quarter guard and a
writer and north South chokers.
She took a picture of herself.
It's all watermarked.
All over it.
You can find if you just google Gary
Coleman death photo,
it's him all fucked up,
lying in bed and she's taking a picture
just like totally coldly just into the.
Is this the.
That's what I'm getting from her.
She just wants to get a photo of herself
next to this freak next to this family.
That's his wife.
Famous thing.
It is his wife and his wife.
She's fucking selling photos of her next
to the dead body or dying body.
He looks like a baby baby.
Damn.
He got a big white girl.
God Damn.
So that was his wife for sure.
Yes.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
He.
Well,
he divorced her,
but she still had a some power to sam I
guess.
I don't know.
Poor fog.
I don't know what he did in a past life,
if you believe in that.
He did some shit.
Well,
I already was like an asshole too.
I already was probably so hard to not be
when you're three feet tall and
everybody's fucking with you everywhere
you go,
you know
going dynamite.
And he's like,
that's not,
that's not my thing.
Oh,
that's right.
I'm sorry.
What you talking about Willis must have.
Oh,
you're not the guy from good times.
Good Times.
I so thought that was you.
I seen her to the audition with the.
Yeah,
the,
the only thing.
Good.
No more know.
She's older.
She had 60,
70 or something.
She shouldn't be on the show.
I was reading something about,
you remember that band live and other
live.
There was a,
an article that I was reading about how
they broke up and about how the singer
wanted all the money.
He wanted them to sign off all the
rights to the songs and everything to
him.
I don't know who was right or who was
wrong,
but I was looking at that and I was
like,
how fucking hard is it to make it in the
music business?
Is that the hardest thing in all of show
business?
I think it is,
right?
You think that's the hardest thing?
It's the hardest thing because,
uh,
yeah,
I guess maybe,
I mean acting is kind of hard to,
you know,
sometimes it just depends on how good
you are.
It's a good product.
If you have persistence and you keep
pushing if you have this,
but some people will never get the good
product.
You know,
Comedians,
songwriter.
Look at Mike Posner.
He started off doing like itunes or
garage band,
shit in the giving a cdna and now he's
got one of the number one cds out right
now in that no idea who that is.
He's the one that's seeing Mike Posner.
Is it?
Is he good?
I like them.
Oh,
you want to hear?
Once you hear the song,
you'll see.
You know what?
I'm going to stab you with a pen.
I want to stop.
You have a pen.
Cock sucker you think is good music.
All right.
This is to laugh a fax with a Banjo.
It's very tough.
You know,
you see these bands that break up the
two fucking up.
So there was like,
yeah,
you know them.
Them getting along with each other.
It's impossible.
Whoa,
super loud.
What is this?
Mike Posner,
he's the one that he was going to
college up to like three months ago.
Now.
He is like the number one CD.
He was just found online pretty much.
This is the number one album.
It just came out yesterday.
The aliens are landing cocksucker
fucking garbage.
Fuck.
The world is coming through.
You don't want to judge this song
harshly because maybe I would like it
under other circumstances.
I've heard it before.
Is it the guy with the big hoop
earrings?
I don't think so.
Now here's the thing about songs by if
someone tells you this is the best song
ever,
never heard of it,
and then they play it.
If it doesn't grab you in like 15
seconds.
What this is,
this is like.
I've heard that we used to use it on the
desk squad a couple of years ago.
Yes.
Oh,
that's a couple of years old.
Is that?
Yeah.
This song,
this song has been redone,
like just support this new album that
came out because they buy some rapper
found them and they made him Redo all
the songs and so there's like old school
versions he used to do like on garage
band in his dorm room at this song and
now this song is like one of the number
one songs.
It's crazy,
like it's really interesting.
He liked his.
His story is really interesting and he
just has discovered on my space,
I think just office website and word of
mouth and he said throw free songs up on
torrents and on his website and cds and
it just became big.
It's crazy.
I can get into.
That's a good story.
I like that.
Sorry.
There's a band called M I l l and the
song's called chasing shadows.
Change.
Listen to this for for 20 seconds.
What's it called?
It chasing shadows by ill.
I got super crazy baked on the vaporizer
yesterday at a buddy of mine and he
goes,
check out this song.
It's just,
I don't know.
You're either going to love it or hate
it,
but it fucking blew me away.
It's like music you've never heard
before.
Like super coming out of the closet.
Radio.
It's band
chasing shadows.
Is this it?
Is it chasing shadows?
Already went really high,
son.
Hold on.
I feel like I should go put on my elf
costume.
Maybe I should dress up like a wizard to
the beach.
Chosen.
There's no vocals or nothing.
It's just all instrumental.
That's just a really.
Yeah.
It's just all a do dish,
freestyle and on electric electronic
shit and it's like playing all these
different gadgets and the like that it's
called a dubstep supposedly like huge
and clubs.
I love listening to music with no lyrics
for a writing.
It's just chaos.
This is like when Mars attacks.
Yes,
exactly.
It's just like the background of a bank
robbery scene.
Yes.
Rich Ob guy.
All right,
let's kill this.
I want you to do.
I can respect that.
It's like boom.
My fucking happened to classic video on
these fucking people.
Less time I was here.
I saw you talking.
Yeah.
I'm going to drop another one,
but this is my present to Joe Rowe
because I know he likes to do,
but you gotta plug in your computer.
Okay.
What do you want?
You got to just see the first minute of
his performance and I'm going to show
watch on my computer because around here
it's not the head.
You've got to see this.
You've got to fucking feel this.
What is it?
It's James Brown live in 1974.
During the big payback,
just the first minute 19 for xy.
Yeah.
I just.
The first minute he was dead for the
Muhammad Ali fight.
This was the.
The concert from Mohammed Ali when he
knocked out George Foreman or whatever
the fuck it was.
I want you to see the first minute of
this.
This is just for you,
Doug.
You're going to fucking die.
I'm gonna die.
You're gonna fucking die.
He's not 10 with fucking organs or given
away.
He's 50 gentleman who will make your
bladder's.
Wow.
This man will need
you will welcome the Godfather.
He comes out,
get up.
Oh my God.
He's a genius.
Holy Shit.
God Damn road bond.
For those who's not,
we're not saying that.
It's open chest to his neighbor.
This is a classic slice at a time.
This is a classic moment of captured,
captured moment of a crazy time and
there's no internet.
There's no TMZ,
no CNN.
He's got a fucking thing on his belt
that says f o s Godfather.
Look at that fucking hair styles.
That split catch.
That might jump out with miss a fucking
beat.
He's a master with that thing.
Brown must have.
He must have
them all.
That is the hardest working man.
That was impressive as fuck.
And you look at that.
How many people doing that today?
Huh?
Nobody can fuck with that.
That's your heart.
That's what it's all about.
Suck it.
R Kelly,
suck as bad to the bone motherfuckers.
But you gotta give him props.
Are you getting a lover?
I kill.
My favorite black Canadian was sophie.
Went up from James Brown power.
Nobody makes me laugh more than r Kelly.
I've watched.
I've watched every video he's ever made.
I have a whole series.
The trapped in the closet on DVD DVD.
So crazy.
It's like a window into madness.
You know Mike,
Bro.
This look,
this right here.
This is switch rockstar.
Shut up his mic.
There's this new song that people are
saying it's even worse than r Kelly,
like it's been so bad.
If it's a brand new song by soldier boy
called pretty boy.
Pretty boy.
Soldier.
It's fucking.
The video.
Looks like it cost 700 bucks and the
song and the lyrics are fucking
hysterical.
We were just super bad.
I don't know if it's as bad as our
county,
our Kelly private crashes and I don't
think that could be a worse on r Kelly
thinking about r Kelly is.
It's not just bad.
It's just so much drama going on and
choosing me as shit.
I ain't fucking clown clown.
Who's going to be cool is you be cover
guy,
like he'd do it.
You're covering it like they do on
Youtube.
There's all these people that got the
whole thing down.
There's kids that have you seen these
youtube videos?
I've seen it for other songs,
so that was the most amazing one.
It has no rhyme or reason,
you know,
to be able to memorize that song.
It's a feat that's like,
oh,
this is pretty boy swag.
Yeah,
it was terrible.
It's one of the worst songs ever,
but you know what?
There's so many dumb people out there
and they need stuff too.
They need stuff that appeals to them.
There's people that you play him a good
song that's complicated and deep.
You play a whole lot of love and they're
not going to get it.
They're not going to get the song,
but they'll listen to that and like my
favorite.
They need entertainment too.
I like that.
I though that soulja boy.
I love it.
You know what man?
He's just having fun.
I liked that.
He's having fun.
I like watching us.
You streamed videos.
He makes use stream videos and any
parties all the time.
It's fucking like this kid is having a
blast,
man.
He's driving around laughing and joking
and talking about the chicks.
He's banging.
I mean he's.
He's wearing giant diamonds and shit.
I think he's having a good time.
I love it.
I liked watches.
USTREAM show.
I don't like it.
I like that other song he had to was the
first Song Superman.
Oh yeah,
that's a good song.
That was a cool song.
That's a good song.
People love that motherfucking song and
he's young.
He's young too.
It was like 20 years old or something
like that.
I mean,
how do you expect them to act?
This is perfect.
I like what he's doing.
I think he's doing a great job.
Just keeping it friendly.
Reagan Miller videos,
very entertaining.
Even though it's low budget,
it's very entertaining to watch them
dance around.
He's very smart.
He did that thing where he got that at
saint now number.
Oh,
I haven't seen now.
Number two.
But he did this thing where he got a
saint now number and with his st
outnumber he put it on a song so
everybody can call him.
My St Number is eight.
One eight,
two,
three,
seven,
four,
two,
five.
My favorite is listening to your
message.
Okay.
I don't really have anything to say but
keep it on.
What do you think about UFC 12?
Yeah,
it's strange.
It's strange,
but it's cool because I did it.
I've used it a couple times.
It's like a little conference call,
like I used it.
Um,
uh,
going from the airport to the hotel,
I just call it.
I set it up and then it goes live at
tweets that I'm going live and then
people wait in line to talk and you can
talk to me.
You have your own radio station,
like you're taking collars,
like what's up man?
And so anybody could listen to the call
listening.
Everyone's listening.
Yeah.
Anyone can listen to the calls and all
the people that are waiting to talk to
you because it's 100 people waiting.
They're all listening so it's like a
radio station.
It's like a 100 person radio station.
I,
you know,
I was like giving people advice and
talking to people about life and joking
about fights coming up and joking about
all kinds of different shit.
It's pretty bad ass.
Is it growing?
Is that like as well that,
that soulja boy do it this way.
I brought it up.
He,
he got two point 2 million friends on st
out two point
2 million people following Dan contact.
Anytime he wants,
he can send them all a voicemail.
That's what the same.
Nothing does.
It alerts you when you get a voicemail.
So I'll put up a voicemail.
I'll leave a message for everybody,
like,
you know,
headed to the fights.
Can't wait,
is going to be fucking crazy,
blah blah blah blah blah.
I'm looking forward to this fight and
look for that fight and then I send it,
see bitches later and then everybody
gets a notification and then they can go
listen to it.
You get contacts.
It's even more direct than twitter.
Pretty crazy shit man.
Because people might miss your shit in
twitter.
Like how many people do you follow?
Do you follow a lot of people?
Uh,
I dunno,
I follow like 600 people.
I think something silly like that.
Yeah.
Six hundred 76.
I just,
anytime someone says something even
remotely interesting,
I'll click follow and I probably
shouldn't have said that because now
people are gonna be asking me to follow
him.
But um,
when you do that,
you get this endless stream on your
homepage.
You don't,
you can't even keep up with it.
There's like so many new tweets.
It's,
it's constant.
You know,
you're always getting,
you might lose like cool shit that
people say,
but if someone sends me one of these,
like you get it.
A lot of people follow a lot of people,
right?
You guys don't follow a lot of people.
I do.
How many of you fall?
Uh,
I don't remember,
but I follow a lot,
like 748.
But I also delete.
I delete a lot of them.
I get annoyed with people super fast.
They tweet too much a tweet too much.
They do delete Kevin Smith.
Yeah,
I did.
I added him back on recently because he
doesn't do it as much.
Or you know,
there's this new thing where you can
choose if you want the at replies are
not on each profile.
Have you seen that?
No.
Twitter on twitter.
If you use twitter on the website now if
you go to their profile,
there's this little logo you can click
on and say show at replies or turn it on
or off.
So his problem was is he was replying to
all these fucking people and it was just
clogging up my twitter.
But now I have this little button I
pushed and I don't get any of it.
So.
Well I don't mind it when people spam,
let them talk to you.
Like a who?
Whose tweets to enjoy.
I Love Kevin Smith.
That's why I want one of the reasons why
I brought it up because he,
he,
uh,
she cut them us.
Yeah.
And I liked how he talks to people,
you know,
he said Anthony Kumina from opiod.
Anthony didn't like.
He's like,
he's always fucking replying to
everybody.
Like he tweets too much,
but I was like,
I don't care.
That doesn't bother me.
I can look over that.
People are so impatient,
you know,
can't look over,
six,
seven lines of texts and just scroll
down the annoys you that much.
Sometimes people end up,
because it's cogs,
his promise he would clog,
it would be the whole page and then you
have to go to the second page and then
it's like,
isn't that hard to do?
It's annoying.
I know.
Why.
Why?
Why do I want it?
I mean he's using it like he spam.
Like if that was your email,
you would be like,
why is this guy spamming and does it
every now and then for like a few
minutes.
Does he do it too much?
Slow down,
slow down.
I had no.
I'm just saying I agree,
but now it doesn't bother me because you
can turn it off.
So now I follow him,
so that was just my only thing.
Don't get another of his retweets.
None of it.
I want to see all the interaction
though.
Don't you want to see the interaction?
Yeah,
but I'll go to his page or something.
You know,
part of the fun for me though is
watching
people interact with people.
So like there's a voyeuristic thing to
at all.
I like watching like porn stars talk to
each other and celebrities talk to each
other.
I like,
I like watching all that shit.
I'll look into everything.
Marched in just regular normal Weirdos.
Talk about different things.
I watched people getting douchey with
each other.
It's fascinating.
It's like a little community man.
This fucking podcast,
last energy feel that shit
are doing two days in a row.
We already talked about at the top like,
oh,
he's doing a podcast that it wasn't him.
It was a two of his guys,
Dino and Gary.
They flew when I talked to him for a
little while.
I was kind of fun.
I'll see him today time like,
is this done?
Huh?
No,
what was good to us guy always,
uh,
always hooked us up always when we,
whenever we needed to promote gigs,
always had us on what was a nice guy.
Canceled the show.
Well,
there's the whole radio station switched
formats.
They went,
I don't know what they went with.
Some hits,
hits top hits,
shit,
you know,
that whole talk radio thing that didn't
work.
It didn't work out.
Demos around for like 15 years,
20 years.
Solid,
right?
It should've worked out.
It's the most entertaining thing to
listen to on the radio.
But people get tired of listening to the
radio and that satellite radio came
along and so much freedom.
So commercials kill.
You can't fuck with opie and Anthony,
do they have the best comics in the
fucking country?
They go on all the time and those guys
go off.
You're not gonna be able to keep up with
that some regular morning zoo radio
station that's wacky.
If you want to listen to something funny
in the morning and you have the option
of opie and anthony or you know some
morning fucking nonsense zoo,
that's all censored,
you're not going to listen to them.
Did I use podcasts and I don't even need
satellite radio because I just had all
podcasts are audible.
You know like you.
You can download opie and anthony
everyday on audible so.
Well Dude.
Yeah.
A lot of people get this off a
honorable.
They get this off of a bunch of
different things.
You can put it on your iphone and put it
on your Ipod,
put it in your car,
listen to it in the way to work.
That's what a lot of people are doing.
I mean,
that's the reason why this podcast is
successful.
It's not like everybody's got the time
to this.
I think most of the people are listening
This is some background shit while
they're working.
Totally.
So my background friends,
we're here for you baby.
All you people out there and regular
people land,
working shitty job.
Joe,
you said,
do you know anything about the UFC being
in three d?
I live in filming in Three d for what?
Do you know what they're going to do
with that?
Do you have any idea how to talk to the
boss?
I don't know.
I need to get on that.
That'd be cool.
Yeah.
I don't know what they're doing.
They've been filling it for a while
though.
Very nice.
A UFC card was fucking nasty.
Nice.
Great.
What'd you think about your boy Roy
Nelson?
What do you think you should do right
now?
So they lose weight,
Bro.
He got hit 50 fucking times.
I mean,
it's not like,
you know,
you got to take guys stood in there.
That guy takes it,
you know,
whatever it takes to do that.
He said he can take bombs.
No one's ever stood in there with junior
dos Santos for three rounds like that.
You think we get to the point where he
just snaps and says,
fucking,
I'm just going to watch my.
I'm going to get in
great shape.
I'm going to go down a two.
Oh five.
How you think that'll with those punches
to the head,
he might be able to move faster away
from him.
I don't know.
What do you think?
He would definitely be.
There's no way.
There's no way to a champion to be a
champion,
to have to be in the best shape of your
life.
He's obviously not in the best shape of
his life.
I know he likes to eat and all that
stuff,
but I'm thinking something's eventually
will make them snap.
He'll get shredded.
He'll be.
He'll be training like a fucking home.
So I think of Roy Nelson was really in
shape and in shape or bad motherfucker
two.
Oh five.
He would crush.
He's got some serious knockout power.
Let's just is awesome.
Jujitsu's awesome.
And he's,
you know,
he's not afraid to fight and he can.
He just needs to get in shape and enough
with the belly.
That's all.
Now what about my job is kind of cool
about when that fucking big belly
motherfucker knocks essentially.
I'm a huge fan of right now,
so I would just like to see him
shredded.
That's my boy.
Roy Rogers Nelson.
Is that Roy Rogers,
Roy Rogers,
years ago.
Is there any news on cro cop at all use
on cro cop.
Where'd that come from?
The chat room.
Don't listen to them.
Those people are looking for a UFC
questions.
Don't listen.
No thiago out chat.
People you use stream chat fucks you.
When you got a question for both of you
guys in the rematch,
how do you think it'll go down?
So the sun until shit.
Who knows,
man,
I want to start a guest.
You had to guess I would never.
You know what I'm interested in seeing
vtr now let me see.
I want to see what vr can do to
Anderson.
I think that's what I was thinking
about.
A rematch for awhile,
which I would still love to see,
you know,
cause it was such a close fight.
But the reality is an interesting one.
You know,
he,
he did tap him and won convincingly,
you know,
and the fight is an interesting
situation,
you know?
I think I'd like to see that next.
What about you?
I'd like to see a rematch.
Either one would be fine with me.
I'd be fine with the rematch.
I would love,
I would love to see a rematch and I
would love to see the or fight.
I would like to see him against a
different guy.
I mean I think we have Anderson for,
you know,
only a certain amount of fights more.
I want to make sure that the fight
actually does happen and if it,
if they set it up now it can actually
happen.
I think that's a big fight.
If Dana decided to go with Silva son and
two,
how do you think that would go down?
I think so would fuck them up quicker.
I think so.
Maybe now he really worked at me like I
was telling jody and I the phone,
you predicted all this shit and the last
two big fights they will onboard,
you know,
fader and this guy went down at the last
minute.
You know,
this is the only sport that if you
really watch UFC for a new watch,
you see the evolution and the vows so
quickly.
It's not like baseball where they had
like Sam gloves and 2000 or something.
I mean,
it's evolved so much and these files
that a top level fighters,
they evolve,
evolve
also.
That's the only way to stay at the top
level,
you know,
as we evolve also.
So.
And Silva,
you know,
I don't think you guys,
everybody keeps saying he pulled this
out of his ass.
You know,
he,
he didn't pull it out,
pull it.
I was asked this guy pull triangles out
of your ass.
You pull punches.
I mean if you wing a wild punch,
the guy runs into it and you're like,
wow,
what are the odds are that landed that I
could see being kind of wild.
But it's still,
I don't think that's why.
Because you were intending to punch the
guy in the face if you intend to punch
the guy in the face and you do.
How has that lucky not lucky.
It's silly.
You know,
it's not like just because you got
caught and you know,
you can't say,
oh he got you with a lucky punch.
No,
he fucking punched you in there.
He wanted to punch you.
And that's what he did.
Like I was at Lucky,
lucky triangle.
Get over,
they start to use either one of the
guys,
the gracies,
their point was to to go Jujitsu,
it gets any other style to prove to the
world at Jujitsu,
could go up against any other style and
that night that really came to fruition
again,
but it was disproven in the fight
before.
See what was important was that Anderson
was able to do something when he got put
in a bad situation.
But look at Damien Maia,
when Damien.
Mine was trying to get ahold of
androgens and Jujitsu certainly wasn't
the answer because he needed to be able
to close the distance and get a takedown
until he gets that take down his
Jujitsu's it's worthless.
So that was,
that's what we saw in that fight.
But what we saw with a killer,
like Anderson,
a guy who's such a killer striker,
he's got to be dangerous off his back
and that's one of the beautiful things
about Anderson.
He is.
That's why I grabbed because I grabbed
the good and the bad child.
Southern is a bad motherfucker and I
applaud your dog.
You were there.
They're all nice and cute.
He left there,
looked like Eddie Munster,
just like everyone gets ugly and
everybody fight,
Bro.
That guy for time.
I was impressed.
He was right.
I would love to see that rematch.
I would not be.
I would not be sad either way.
I mean I would not be upset one way or
another,
either one.
I'm really looking forward to.
I just thought that while Anderson is
young or relatively young man,
I don't know how many more years he's
going to want to do this.
I want to see him fight all kinds of
people.
You know?
I want to see him fight Hector Lombard.
You know what I'm saying?
I want to see him fight some interesting
dudes who were finding another place.
Jon Jones,
Jon Jones up to five.
That's the one.
Fuck yeah.
Are you kidding me?
While we are writing from this and I,
I don't,
I don't have a problem with the child
center rematch if they decide to do
that.
I would love that too.
Either one.
Either one is good jail southern Jon
Jones.
She's like,
we get so far the live ramp,
but you know what?
Charlson is not fine at two.
Oh five.
He's always one 85.
I mean I guess he could go up but he
never has before.
Right.
I mean maybe it was earlier.
Fine.
Two,
two.
Oh five.
I don't remember them though.
He was fighting into wc one 85.
So Wec one 85 and UFC one 85.
I don't think he's ever Ms Dot Wade
because he missed weight.
Not that I can.
So there's no reason to.
I mean Anderson like had some fights at
two.
Oh,
five.
Like to go up there.
I guess jail could do it too though.
You probably walked around pretty heavy,
right?
Jon Jones is a scary motherfucker
though.
That's a scary though.
They just got them.
They're in a cage right now.
Let me know when they going to let them
out.
They might let them out on new years.
They might let them out for the
Thanksgiving thing.
They don't even know.
They just give him a title shot right
away.
As soon as possible.
I don't know why I fuck around because
he wants to develop.
He wants to be the greatest of all time.
He wants.
He doesn't want a title shot.
Is that what you're saying?
Oh,
he doesn't want a title shot.
You Know Greg Jackson is the guy who
guides him.
Right.
Gary?
Greg Jackson said to me that what he
wants to do is make sure that he's
tested before he fights for the title.
He wants him to really be tested and
really to get worn on.
I'm like,
Greg Jackson's a smart man and he got
smart.
He got tested.
He ran through brandon that he did.
He did Vladimir.
Those are.
Those are some tests,
right?
Buddy hasn't been put in an adverse
situation.
That's what he's good because he's
bright,
but he wants to set them up with someone
who may test them.
Who Will they taught them guys at two.
Oh,
five.
That could probably work in right now
that I don't know if anybody could work
him.
I think he might be able to beat Shogun.
Yup.
I think he might be able to win the
title.
You know?
I mean,
I,
I think he's incredibly talented.
I could see shogun catching him and who
knows.
Shoguns really good office back to
Shogun can dive on some leg locks and
shit.
He doesn't fuck around.
Shoguns a bad motherfucker everywhere.
But John is special athlete.
He's got something.
The way he does it.
It's just so confident and he's got an
aura about him,
you know,
to use the Hixon gracie term.
There's some shit that Jon Jones was
doing.
He's,
he's got a very rare ability to look
impressive against everybody and he's
super duper ultra cool.
So Nice.
I mean,
it's just like the coolest dude.
Coolest,
friendliest.
He's down to Earth.
He's intelligent.
The opposite of a Douche.
Yeah,
the opposite.
And he doesn't have a burden.
Douchebags have a burden there.
Always hating themselves.
They're hating themselves to the way
they treat other people.
They hate themselves the way they live
their life.
They hate themselves.
Well,
the negative energy,
they've created all the negative energy
from your childhood,
all that Shit.
So they just,
everywhere they go,
that wears you out,
man.
You know,
it might motivate you to a certain
extent,
but when it comes to the long race,
when you don't have time for ego and
bullshit and it's all about,
you know,
who can really,
who can raise the greatness faster.
The guys who have the best personalities
get there better.
They get there cleaner cut like fate or
faith or has some doubters.
But I don't know about any haters.
You know,
who hates fader,
how can you hate that guy?
He looks like a fucking dishwasher
repairman and knock senseless,
you know,
and he doesn't talk shit.
Talk Shit ever.
And he doesn't even get upset when he
loses,
when he loses.
He's gracious,
he's a gentleman,
he doesn't lose for 10 years.
He loses and he says,
uh,
you know,
those who do not fall down do not stand
or something like that.
Some.
So he said it more eloquently,
eloquently,
something from the Internet.
It's like he needed that last for
character.
Yeah.
Who knows how he's going to come out in
the next fight with something approved.
You know,
just like Bj,
anytime bj loses,
he always comes back on fire.
You know,
they're not fucking doing fader and over
him,
they're not doing that fight doing fader
and bigfoot or the overeem and bigfoot
rather
over.
So they given state or
I don't know,
man,
they know.
They don't know if they're going to do a
rematch or not,
but I want to see that over and fight or
flight.
That's what I want to say.
That's the fight I want to say I want to
see for doing fight a overeem began for
the title for sure because we're doing
beedamon pride,
but I want to see overinflate or that's
the fucking fight.
That's a good fucking fights on the real
quick shout out to Matt Horwitz.
She's fighting out.
He's fighting Talus latest this Saturday
and Irvine,
I think it's called war on the mainland
or something like that.
But uh,
the,
the main fight is Tim Silvia verses Paul
Born Tello.
Matt Horwitz took the fight against
silence late to Sun on short notice,
but he's always in shape.
His jujitsu's awesome.
It's going to be a great fight.
I want to give a shout out to a kid,
Patrick from twitter.
It's his birthday today.
Good tweeted me and asked me,
he said,
this kid had the same birthday as Rogan.
If we give them a shout out,
happy birthday,
Patrick.
I think hulk Hogan's birthday's today to
that fucking will.
Hey,
it's a time for a word from our sponsor.
No flashlight.
We're back.
Bitches.
Look at this or something that gave me
that we talked about yesterday.
Now why would they give you this for?
For folks that are only listening is a
limp rubber.
It's not real pink limp rubber Dick
that's made out of the same material at
the flashlights made out of.
It's funny because they sell it like
something to put on your coffee table as
a gag.
It's just to make you feel uncomfortable
that you just hold the deck in front of
him,
man.
It's like Bachelorette parties.
Stroking it yesterday.
Well,
we're talking.
Just sit there like a porn star.
Eating off,
having a conversation.
He's fucking face to wrestle you fucking
around.
Fucking around,
man.
We're going to start with a solid
product.
No,
it's blue advertisers.
Blue.
Joey.
Does she ever talk?
No.
You missed shit.
I just watched kick ass.
Wasn't that great?
Did you like it was 20 minutes too long,
but the girl stole the fucking.
I love that because it's too low bullet
the other night.
What?
The law?
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's good to.
Steve Mcqueen is always an animal.
It's crazy looking at San Francisco and
uh,
you know,
in the 19,
60,
19,
68,
there's nobody on the road.
You know,
you just driving.
It's easier on the highway.
You just drive and I'm going to
straighten.
Just driving.
No.
Realize how much the population has
increased until you watch like a movie
from the sixties.
He still like New York Street in New
York in the 19 fifties movie,
the Hustler.
There's not too many cars and,
but it's just driving around.
No problems.
Now we just take it for granted that
anywhere you go,
it's gonna be a city,
there's going to be too many people,
too many cars.
You're not gonna be able to get
anywhere.
But at one point in time that wasn't the
case when they first made cities.
Like why would everybody lived together
in this one thing?
Well,
because when there's not that many
people and you can drive around,
it's really pretty fucking cool.
New York City with no traffic.
That would be the shit.
The drop boring.
I hate to be boring,
wouldn't it?
Why would it be boring?
That wouldn't be that many people will.
You can use.
There would still be plenty of people.
You're still gonna have some traffic.
You're just not going to have the kind
of traffic that you have now or it takes
you half an hour to get across town.
At least you know it can take you hours
to get around New York when it's around
rush hour.
It can take you forever to get out of
the city,
you know,
to get to long island to get the fuck.
It's a nightmare.
There's too many fucking people.
I sway people as an ongoing subject in
this podcast.
There's no answers.
That's the unfortunate problem.
Answers.
He just happened to move out of la or a
big cities and Columbus,
Ohio.
It was always one mile,
one minute or better.
Here it's like 15 minutes per mile is
the average or something retarded,
but people,
let's be honest,
it's more fun here,
right?
Well,
the weather's better.
The weather's better for what we do.
It's better here by other people.
Wines.
You run into more interesting people out
here that you don't hang out with.
Retards that like any city,
there's cool people.
Like you've met some of my friends from
Columbus if you know we all hung out
there.
All Nice guys.
Yeah,
they're done.
Earth people.
So where do you think is,
but don't you think like there's certain
parts of the country where people are
more interesting per capita?
Well,
just because you have more people like
top Texas is awesome is one of my
favorite places ever been because it's
huge.
It's like a big city.
People say that it's because there's
more people,
but I also think that when you get a lot
of people together,
like in New York and in any big city
like that,
just the sheer competition,
there's so many people in there.
Everybody's moving fast.
Everybody's got to keep up with
everybody else.
Like no one is like no one's faster
thinker or faster talker than like East
Coast people like New Jersey,
New York where they're angry.
The angry hustle competition,
sort of a right jolly.
Don't you think New Yorkers?
No one's more aggressive than New
Yorkers
as aggressive people,
but they're really aggressively.
Or you've got to fucking go in New York.
Yeah.
You got to go for the stop sign.
How they do healing?
No,
you go get the fuck somebody fucking
gold.
Fucking moron.
I got to get to the weed store.
That shit don't make know.
Uh,
there's just a lot of things I see that
you look at and you're like,
this shit wouldn't fucking fly.
No,
it's just wouldn't fly.
The other day,
some guy in front of my just pulled in
front of my house and got in the car and
three people behind them.
Beeper.
I went upstairs and got my police badge
and said,
move the fucking car bitch.
And they fucking moved,
you know.
But it's like,
Eh,
I don't like that part of it.
Like,
you gotta go,
go bro.
What's all this knowledge?
And you have really good.
Yeah,
whether in really good conditions and
things are easy,
it tends to make you a bit soft and
that's what I think.
I think there's a lot of people that
grow up out here,
you know,
like a lot of Chad's,
you know the type of guy I'm talking
about,
like there's a softness.
They don't have to deal with like harsh
winters.
They don't have to deal with the
craziness that the northeast has to deal
with.
You know what I mean?
I think people think faster and the east
coast
in general.
Oh,
you got to
fucking thank you.
See,
look at it.
Look at that thing.
I watched the interview with William
Chapman.
He interviewed Bernard Goetz.
Yeah.
Did you see that?
No.
Is that interesting?
Very interesting.
I heard Bernie gets used to be on opie
and anthony all the time.
He's crazy.
He just shot for motherfuckers for just
insinuating.
But he proved them right.
He said they like,
I,
you know,
was going to mug them.
Well look at 20 years later,
three out of the four in prison.
Well,
it couldn't be because he shot him and
fuck their hand up and then they want
that motherfucker what was crawling and
he went over and pulled the fucking
trigger.
He had the bullets.
You see the fucking interviews he gave
afterwards?
No.
He told The New York Times that mothers
should have had abortions.
Listen,
you don't talk like that before you go
to the sentencing.
That's the shit you say from behind
bars.
He was a stern guy,
but I think about that guy.
When I think about New York,
he said,
I ain't even giving them the opportunity
and he's out of jail.
Out of jail.
How long has it been out of jail?
A long time.
I got thrown out of jail.
What happened?
I had to throw it out.
I did he go to jail.
What happened was he made bold
statements afterwards.
His attorneys were like,
shut the fuck up guy.
So they prosecuted him for something
else.
I forget the story now.
If you look it up.
They prosecuted him for something else,
but he was a hero.
I just don't want to encourage people to
be vigilantes,
but the problem is man,
but I look at that.
What do you do though?
Do you know anthony from opie and
Anthony.
He's got to carry.
He carries a pistol.
They don't talk about it on the radio.
I guess the station doesn't like
bringing it up,
but he,
he's kind of.
He's got a fucking gun on him.
You have to kind of carry pit permit.
You have to,
you have Texas,
you can carry it with you.
It's way better when you need it,
need it.
And I'm a firm believer.
I guy carried a gun for years and
fucking bad guns and hot guns and I'll
tell you what,
and this is what I tell people all the
time.
You carry a gun,
you carry a knife,
you attract that energy.
The next time you get into a beef,
some of these in have a knife.
I never carried a knife again.
Nobody ever attacked me.
Like I got to tackle in life in Aspen,
Colorado really?
And I picked up a fucking pipe,
but that if I wouldn't have slipped away
I did.
That guy would have caught me,
picked up a pipe and hit him across the
fucking leg with it.
But he had a,
he had like a little fucking.
Where were you attack that?
We were hanging behind like a strip club
at three and I was at a gas station and
the guy was fixing my car like a,
like a big garage place.
And the guy thought I had said something
to them.
I'm like,
I didn't send them to you.
My car's right.
He was like,
no,
you cut me off before I haven't been
here for two hours.
He was just looking for somebody to
stamp.
He was just a little crazy.
She pulled the knife out,
he went like this and I moved back and
when I moved back there was a pipe on
the fucking like,
you know,
those pipes for wiring.
They were doing the place and I slipped
and I picked up the fucking pipe.
But I always remembered that when I
carried a gun,
everywhere I go,
people had fucking guns.
I got a gram of coke.
The motherfucker had a gun.
What are the odds?
Stopped casual.
There was a coke dealer with a gun.
Wait a minute.
Once I stopped,
you know,
like one time I heard a bullet go off
one night when I had a gun real 20 feet
behind me.
The guy shot another guy in a club,
you know,
and this was,
I was a kid.
I remember hearing that fucking thing
and I stopped with guns.
How old were you?
Twenty four maybe,
but I never ever cared after I got
caught for the machine gun with the
kidnapping.
I never bought the last time.
When was the last time you went out?
Didn't happen.
Somebody's machine gun.
Fuck Ya.
No fucking around one.
What you got pitched the things over
here like with the ammo.
That's the ultimate shit.
You can tell somebody.
You know what I mean?
Little things.
The little instant respect.
Tell me you were arrested for kidnapping
and yet a machine gun.
Damn,
that's deep.
I don't want to fuck with that dude.
That's the way to get out of a wedding
with a gun.
I have a lot of things.
Trust me,
I got something to tell you.
Carry your weapon that it'd be prepared
to carry that weapon.
I tell that to people all the time.
People like,
Bro,
I'm thinking about getting a gun bitch.
Before you take that gun out,
you better think twice.
Is it possible?
Here's the question,
is it possible for human beings to ever
evolve past this?
Is it possible for people to ever evolve
past violence and bullshit and lies and
and hate?
Is it possible or do we need it?
We need it.
We needed to because it fuels.
It makes you appreciate,
love more,
makes you struggle more.
It makes the competition greater.
Thinking about what's going on.
Think about that.
Half a world away.
Everybody's got a machine gun shooting
at each other.
Right now you're going to be walking in
Israel and fucking a bus going home and
somebody comes up and says,
fuck the Jews and they fucking pull the
switches,
but on a,
on a smaller scale,
if people can be.
Is it just a certain amount?
Is it a certain number?
Is it like after a certain number,
you can't be friends with everybody.
I mean,
how the fuck the wars get started?
I mean it doesn't get started with a
group as small as us,
right?
It's not for people.
So if four people can get along what,
what are the numbers?
What are the numbers where everybody can
have a good,
healthy every 20 people 20 years,
one bad motherfucker,
but if you can get rid of them,
what's a manageable size?
Like if you wanted to start a tribe of
all your own people,
what's a manageable size where everybody
can be cool with each other.
Nobody's going to have any problems with
each other where we're all going to be
friendly.
Everyone's going to whine.
One in the cat,
the cat,
the of flashlight.
It's impossible.
Listen man.
And and and,
and a drama.
Sometimes you need it.
I think so to change this an expression,
I can't remember.
I've said this before and it sounds
crazy,
but I think it's all a mathematical
equation.
I think everything you do in his life,
all the people you come in contact with,
all your actions,
all your motions,
it's all part of a giant equation and
everybody's equation that's piling
up together.
Everybody's numbers.
Everybody.
What you're doing is affecting me when
I'm doing is affecting him.
We're all doing it together and it's
we're working towards some fucking crazy
goal that we just can't say.
I believe that me to Vinton Zeus wasn't
the god of war.
What was the mythology?
Zeus or thor was a goddess.
Thunder.
A war was one of those guys said he was
so bad.
Motherfucker.
The grand poupon.
One of those guys sent this sudden down
to see what was going on at this
motherfucker came back and everything
talked about war,
all the damage this guy had done.
His son when he went and he asked,
is something what the fuck is going on?
You know,
what are you doing?
What?
He's chopping these heads off.
He says,
without war,
there's no change.
Is that what it is?
Something to do?
Yeah,
but the question is can we evolve past
us?
The problem is you look at the numbers,
you look at sustainability,
like the,
just the sheer numbers of human beings,
and then you look at the amount of space
that we have and you've got to think if
we're at like six or $7 billion now,
what's gonna Happen when it's $20
million?
What's going to happen when it's $80?
Million?
There's a shitload of land now.
So there's,
there's tons and tons of land.
If you go to Ohio,
there's just millions and millions of
acres of land.
So think everybody's just moved to Ohio.
I know,
I'm just saying that there's a lot of
states out there like,
you know,
South Dakota is that there's fucking
land everywhere
growing their food.
Uh,
Mexico.
Where are they getting their meat?
Mexico,
Japan.
Yeah.
Um,
I don't know,
man.
That's what I worry about.
That's the kind of shit that fills my
head up every day.
Stopped taking it about getting drunk.
I got to get you some Marie low man your
weed and get some take away your
birthday.
We got to start some shoppers shop.
You have to kill her.
I got to drop to drinking,
just hanging around with a bunch of men
will go into the tank together for us.
I'm not.
I'm not looking for birthday shots.
Thank you though.
Appreciate it.
How about birthday?
High fives.
All you with everybody.
The olive garden.
Olive Garden later go to the off
gardens.
My favorite.
When you're there,
your family though.
You didn't say it right?
Say it the right way.
When you hear your family,
there was that show that used to be on
Sirius.
The wiseguys showed you remember that
show?
I'd never heard it.
Oh,
it was.
It was that for two hours.
It's not even available anymore.
You don't have anymore.
Part of it made me a the
nostalgic part.
It made me remember all these idiots
that I knew back in New York.
Very,
very specific part of the country now.
Very specific.
So it's going to be interested in UFC is
in Boston.
There you go.
That's what Fox.
What do you think so far?
Just Bj and fucking Frankie Edgar to.
It's going to be interesting,
man.
Gonna.
That's gonna.
Be Interesting as fuck because you know
pj is going to come out angry.
I think Bj is to try to take Frankie
Edgar down.
I think you're right.
I'm trying to strangle them.
I think you're totally right.
All he didn't have fight with standing
bang with them and try to stuff to take
down.
You know,
I think Bj a learned less than that
fight.
He's gonna come back stronger than ever.
But Frankie Edgar's coming back stronger
than ever to man and Frankie Edgar is
better and every fight,
every time that dude fights,
you see a new,
improved version of him,
you know,
after he beat Sean Sherk.
And then after he uh,
beat Matt Veech and strangled Matt
Veech,
I was like,
this guy is fucking getting better,
man.
He's getting better.
And then when he beat Bj did,
he's going to be even better now coming
into this fight.
He's going to kick it up another notch
and he's not getting tired thinking
about that dude.
He does not get tired.
He can go five,
five minute rounds,
full clip.
And He's good.
He's good.
It's crazy.
He doesn't get tired.
He was just as fast in the fucking fit
for hours.
He wasn't.
The third is the.
Just wasn't a second.
I think it gets tired at night.
I think he go night night.
I think you get some warm milk and maybe
someone reads them a story and I can get
tired and then he goes,
no,
totally ready.
Go to it.
Last.
James,
Tony,
randy coture is a fucking fascinating
fight,
man.
I loved it.
I love,
first of all the fact that James,
Tony is the first guy who's like a real
professional boxer at a,
at a high level stepping into mma and
yeah,
he's 41 but he still got skills.
Do James.
Tony is still a bad motherfucker.
Randy couture is like 48,
47 I believe.
Yeah.
So,
but you know,
the thing is like he's doing the right
things.
He's training with a Antonio Monkey.
He's training with Mola Wall is trending
with King Mo training with wrestlers.
You know,
they're teaching them how to try to
stand up.
Who knows?
All he has to do though,
realistically all he has to do his
stuff.
One tank down,
stuff from one tank down and get close
enough to get a hand free.
Just get close enough.
I have a position where he's got a
little,
a little bit of distance he created and
fucking all he has to do is one with
those four ounce gloves.
I'm not saying he can do it,
but I'm saying if he can do it,
chances are he's gonna fuck randy up.
If he can land it.
My sources telling me he's not training
at all.
Really?
This is bad for the promotion of the
Bravo.
Oh no,
he's training a lot.
Yeah.
Well Eddie did I just fuck it up?
I think he might have fucked it up.
Part of the promotion has he been
trained in today's today is opposite day
by the way,
as the opposite thing.
Oh,
that is opposite time.
Well,
who knows,
man,
maybe they're.
They're putting out rumors,
studies,
training so that people will respect it.
But I know he lost weight.
He looked pretty God damn thing when I
was interviewing him.
He didn't look fat at all to him at home
with a fucking train of fucking shit.
Whatever you posted on fuck about trey.
Fuck that.
I'm gonna.
Go Run for 10.
This is what he said to me.
It was no punch.
Punch.
Three inches,
three inches on.
Knock his ass out.
That's all
it is,
right?
Do let me tell you something.
He,
if he,
if he clipped you,
look,
this just like that.
Just gave himself like three or four
inches.
It would fucking really hurt.
It really hurt.
He could.
Jack.
He was given it up to Bristol.
A bad motherfucker.
He got it wrong though.
I told it.
Dana.
Dana goes,
Bruce Lee at a one inch punch.
Why can't they figure out the Bruce Lee
killings and like all the murders and
stuff.
That whole family murders,
but you think there would be by now dna
or something.
They can.
They can solve so many heresy.
Bryan spears,
we need to get mythbusters on.
Did they just give up on that whole
thing?
They've ever even looked into it.
I don't think there was a conspiracy
that I've even looked into it.
Was there a conspiracy?
Was Bruce Lee yesterday?
What was it?
What was the conspiracy was found dead
asleep and like some has Mr [inaudible]
apartment.
So they think someone killed him.
They think someone did.
And his son,
why would they kill us?
Fuck you and your son killed his son
later in like put a bullet into the gun.
That was supposed to be a blank gun.
Right?
How do you get it?
How do you get a real gun on a set that
doesn't even come close to you don't
look into Brandon Lee back in the day.
Yeah.
So what were the details that it was in
competence?
No.
Why would there be a right.
You have props for movies and stuff like
that.
You don't use real guns.
They're just not even a real gun on
warner brothers except in the security
guys.
His pockets,
you know,
but,
but you don't mix fucking fake guns with
real guns.
That's impossible,
you know?
Well,
it's not that.
It's not a real gun.
It's a real gun.
It's just shooting a blank.
Right?
But they can't.
Those guns can't shoot real.
People have died by taking those guns
and putting them up to their head with
no bullet in it and it's blown their
brains out.
You know that,
right?
Right.
But that's not what happened.
You know,
he would happen with.
What I read was that it was,
there was something in the barrel on
that as he fired the blank,
something,
whatever it was in the barrel,
we should probably look it up when we
were talking out of our ass,
but he did get shot and killed on sap.
I always felt that the father got ice
because when he left Rudd Rudd and those
motherfuckers to come to the United
States to shoot into the dragon,
that was his ent.
There was a seat that was big heroin
money.
I'm telling you this from the heart.
If you know anything about that,
you check out that company.
The people may fist of fury and Chinese
connection.
They invested.
You know what it costs to make the
Chinese connection.
How much?
80,000
really know how much.
You know how many times they made that
over.
Do the fucking man.
How much he thinks that movies my head,
look at it.
There was no explosions.
There's no three g,
there's no three d go Sag.
How much you think the Chinese
connection is made?
$10 a day for all those Japanese guys.
So you're saying that the company that
made festival,
the people who put up the producers on
that,
if you know anything about Raymond Chow,
it's all heroin.
It's direct.
They were money laundering.
Money Laundering guys,
you know you've got to make up to,
to,
to have Mercedes.
I got to make money and make this
Mercedes.
I got to make it the cover this.
How am I doing this?
He made three movies.
They will all box office.
Fucking worldwide smashes.
One was bigger than the other and I come
to you and I go,
Hey,
I'm happy now.
If anybody knows anything about anything
mafia concept and even the Italian,
those morons could never figure that
out.
It's fucking Chinese.
You know?
Look at Japan.
When you fuck up in the in Japan,
don't they cut your fucking finger or
don't you have to color up?
If I told you to cut your finger off,
what were the chances you understand me?
These people don't fuck around.
They're not white.
They're not sure if these people don't.
So they were making tons of money to
leave them.
He decided to go to warner brothers to
make enter the dragon,
and so they killed.
They gave him a little taste,
but not the taste.
They were waiting on.
Not The big taste they were waiting on.
They made Raymond Chow,
a little partner and then they gave him
a piece of death with Charles Bronson,
but that wasn't enough.
So you really think that's what
happened.
Any other ideas?
Oh,
I mean,
I don't know if it's officially.
It was a brain aneurysm.
It's a brain aneurysm.
While when someone shooting in the head,
your brain bleeds,
right?
It's mysterious.
Nobody knows nothing.
I mean,
he was 33 years old.
He was in perfect health.
You know,
it could have been poisoned.
the.
You could say that we could have paid
for this,
the Chinese could have paid for this all
across the line to the,
you know,
that's a corrupt country.
Like any other place like that,
they could have paid dr to say whatever
the fuck they would've said they buried
them.
And that's it.
Why hasn't Linda,
Lisa,
let's dig up the motherfucking body and
see what's really crackalackin lacking
because they probably gave her.
She knows they killed his son to boot
brush.
So your husband and your fucking son
dies.
This is a coincidence.
Was there any threats on his life?
Reading how it actually happened?
I guess they were using blanks but they
were rushed at a time.
So they took real bullets and took out
the,
the powder out of the bullets that I
guess would also make a blank.
Uh,
so.
But what happened is somebody on unknown
fired those blanks and they reinserted
like bullets on top of it,
like more blanks.
And so eight exploded in a piece of a
bullet flew out of it or something like
that.
Because not only are we going to shoot,
you were going to shoot you on fucking
camera.
I didn't.
I don't think it was crazy videos on
youtube.
Yeah,
right,
exactly.
There's just so many.
It's just weird going to watch it by so
many doubts with both of them.
That's that.
It's not,
you know,
it's just the brandon sounds like it
could be just a coincidence that all of
a sudden he was dead and buried and gun.
That's it.
And then the movie came out two weeks
later because he died before the break.
Perfect timing died.
He died July 16th or something like
that.
And the movie came out eight days later
they were filming the movie and they
were done filming and then they released
it eight days later after he died.
None of the movie was done.
Two weeks before they it.
He died.
He never,
he wait one more movie.
It was legend wasn't there?
I was 10 minutes.
I thought you were talking about Brandon
Lee though.
Bruce.
I'm sorry.
So you know the cell body catalysis as
this is American studio,
they would never kill somebody.
You know what I'm saying?
You don't.
I think there's some crazy producers out
there that we kill people.
They understand.
They understand the depth equals money.
Now,
is there a documentary out there about
brandon?
I think there is.
I think was it legend or survivor
producer?
His wife and Cancun and he's back.
He's back in America.
Mexican government's trying to figure
out how to prosecute him.
You're going to from Mexico can kill his
wife.
Bob will tell you something.
I'll know if you seen it.
I mean,
I've been on that side of the fence.
I just watched that Michael Jackson
documentary again a couple of weeks ago.
I'm looking at his death,
but know about the thing we want to see
that night.
I'm watching him watching him.
Does he look like a fucking dude?
That's fucked up to you.
As much as they said he was fucked up to
do all those dance.
Move.
Watch the movie.
You're an intelligent guy.
You get back to me or he wasn't just
doing coke or whatever.
He was doing oxygen or whatever the fuck
they said he was doing that one part
where he freaks out.
Remember he fucking freaked out.
There's one part where they.
They show most of the movies.
Just all good.
I don't even get into drugs or anything
like that.
It's all good,
but they showed a piece where he's
freaking out with the director and he
doesn't feel.
It feels like it feels like just.
I don't know what it is.
We got to get the right mixture,
but that guy was a freak.
I was going.
They were going to take this little
Afro.
We're going to take.
Never,
never land so much money on
motherfuckers made since he's been dead
a lot.
Right?
Punch,
punch.
They're all jumping up and down.
The Red Dragon was the documentary by
Red Dragon,
the Bruce Lee documentary.
It's Lee,
Brandon Lee.
Both Brandon Lee,
sorry,
grabbing Red Dragon,
red dragon.
Cool.
Little bit conspiracy guy,
but it just,
just to his death definitely sounds like
if he had some very few really pissed
off some Chinese mob guys,
I don't think they would let that slide
because the guy became a movie star,
you know,
if he's making some other people.
Yeah,
I could see them killing them.
I don't know the details either where
they shot those movies.
They shut those.
Like those movies cost nothing.
They shot those in the jungles of
Thailand.
Fist of fury.
The first one they shot that there was
no set.
They shot that in the jungle with pilot
on a dark street.
There was no,
there was no crap services.
There was no.
There was one tons and a fucking type
with Chinese music on.
You know what I'm saying?
It's crazy.
When you think about how recent movies
really are when a recent invention,
I mean movies were,
you know,
I believe in the 19 hundreds they were
silent,
right?
When did they start making sound movies?
Sure.
A 40 years.
And by the way,
that was Bruce Lee and Brandon Lee.
Sorry,
what was that?
Red Dragon.
Oh,
that was the documentary on Brandon,
Bruce Lee.
Okay.
But I think it was like 1940.
I would say 19.
Was that when you start thinking about
how recent invention movies are,
the crazy thing about the whole movie
experiences,
it really does program you.
We have some certain things that we want
to see in life and when you show them to
us like we have a natural inclination to
fall successful people.
It's natural,
you know,
fall.
Someone who's better than you learn how
to be better than you are,
you know,
learn,
learn from people that have already
learned.
But when you see a movie,
it's like the guy has all these
attributes of the hero in real life,
but it's fake and he's 60 feet tall and
every time he talks fucking music plays
and your whole system gets so confused
because you really.
The girls,
especially girls,
there's a lot of people that believe
that life really should be like a movie
that was really shocked that life
doesn't turn out like a moving.
How crazy.
It wasn't that when Bruce Lee,
all he ever wanted was a shot in
Hollywood and he got ripped off.
He got rejected,
he got sent back to China,
he blows up in China and now warner
brothers wants him back.
Now they want to know,
and then he finally gets a shot.
He gets the fuck.
He gets to call the shots of the movie
and it doesn't show up to the set.
He has cold feet.
He's fucking nervous as hell.
They're shooting around him.
He won't show up.
He's freaking out.
He's having a nervous breakdown.
How close is that?
Then he finally shows up and just
crushes you.
Watch that movie.
Now I'm sure there's some corniness from
enter the dragon and that's an old
movie,
but there's so like a good 75 percent of
it just stands.
The test of time.
The scenes,
the wet shot,
like when he's out with are out during
the day and he's those when he fights
Bob Wall and Bolo Young,
God dammit.
Those are the best fucking scenes.
It was so intense like Muhammad Ali had
come along before that that represented
martial arts at all in a mainstream way.
There was no,
there's been no one that grabbed the
public's attention.
He was the first and when he did pick
bosses,
first of all,
but he wasn't even the start first.
He was like built third or fourth and
then he just started directing and
fucking putting together the fight
scenes and then they bumped them up and
made them.
They go,
this motherfucker's just taken over.
This dude just start.
They just throw them on the film,
you know,
last minute.
And he took over and then from that
point on,
he just took a lot,
which is one of my all time,
top five and when I get down and dirty,
what am I,
old time movies as a child,
these connection which was released,
whatever the big boss here,
fist of fury in that movie,
his fucking anger comes through.
I mean,
he's so good in that movie.
Everything he does,
he hang with.
This guy took clint eastwood.
It took them a step further.
He would kill the guys and then hang
them on the streets so people could see
him.
That's nobody's done that shit.
Nobody's ever thought Charles Bronson.
He hung up twice.
You know,
why'd you kill my teacher?
Why?
Think of that last fight scene where he
goes to the school and he says,
this does not concern you.
I'm allowing you to leave.
He throws them out and then three that
stick around,
he jumps over a coffee table.
What's the movie?
Guys jumps over the coffee table into a
flying psychic.
This ain't no joke.
He beats the fat guy with the sword.
He puts them down to the store,
goes through his back.
Then he goes to the yard and he fucks up
two guys.
He fucks up the Russian.
Then it goes into the studio with the
new chancellor.
Shit fucks the master up.
Then it goes back to the day to the
school.
He tells the cops not to fuck around
with his school and the cops are scared
of him.
He's talking to him and he's like,
if I go to jail,
don't fuck with them.
Then he opens the door to open and
there's a bunch of people outside ready
to shoot him and he runs to the camera.
He throws a flying psychic and you hear
the fucking bullets go off in a year.
That's what killed me as a kid,
not seeing my mother died that tormented
me when Bruce Lee got shot at the end of
the fist of fury because I didn't know
where he come back or not,
but think about that fucking movie he's
acting.
Coach was.
I quit Chinese connection.
Steve motherfucking mcqueen.
Long Distance.
Do you understand me?
He was calling Steve McQueen saying,
Doug,
this is what I do doing this scene.
What do you think?
Do you understand me?
Dog and him and Steve Mcqueen were
running together and they both wanted
what each other had.
Steve Mcqueen didn't want to be no star.
He didn't like people.
He didn't want people talking to him.
Steve McQueen beat the fuck out.
Ali Mcgraw and went to work the next
day.
Nobody gave a fuck.
He was a mean guy.
Steve McQueen.
He wanted to be a fighter and Bruce Lee
wanted to be a fucking actor,
an international star.
They both had what each other wanted,
bro.
Steve Mcqueen,
just one of the pis on people.
Fuck people from one time and said,
dog,
let's take a ride.
This producer died.
I'm going to go piss on his grave.
Like I told him when he fired me from
that movie.
Steve McQueen wasn't a nice guy.
Wow.
When you die of cancer,
he went to Mexico and couldn't get
healed.
Breast Cancer,
breast cancer,
enter the dragon was so fucking strong
like Bruce Lee was so amazing.
They put out a pregnant,
put out the craziest thing about the
whole Bruce Lee thing.
The craziest thing is that they put a
movie out after he died,
game of death,
and the only,
the last 10 minutes is him.
They decided to make a movie with 75
percent.
Another dude.
It was another dude,
and if you watch that movie at the,
they put,
they take pictures or scenes from return
of the Dragon.
Stick an extent.
Although they mix it all up.
The photo in the first five minutes of
the movie,
they put a photo of Bruce Lee on a
moving body on the double.
Really?
They put a photo.
It's the worst photoshop ever.
The beginning of that movie.
Then they shut the whole rest of the
movie with like anytime you get a good
look at Bruce Lee.
It's another movie.
It's another fucking movie man,
and then they cut back and then when you
see the profile,
it's a stunt double with glasses.
Fucking glasses though.
They had a stunt double for Kareem Abdul
Jabbar too because they had to have an
excuse for him at the end of the movie
when he actually does come in.
So if you watch the movie,
you see the big tall black guy is that
even crew,
but you know he's going to fight them at
the end,
but people talk about the seven wonders
of the world or Grand Canyon.
Know what the eighth wonder of the world
is that they seek old.
That movie.
Eighteen Times.
We've had this conversation with how
you're doing.
We're here today,
Eddie Bravo.
Joe Rogan.
You'd like to speak to you about a
pitch.
Oh,
we're all is.
We'd like to do game a death three.
You know what I'm saying?
Isn't Bruce Lee debt?
We don't need Bruce Lee.
You understand?
To break the pictures down to show
pictures and shit.
So how much are we going to make a
that's not gonna.
Make any money.
What boxes are fucking how much the
game.
That's why I like to see it.
They don't even have what those movies
made.
You can't.
No.
You can look up any movie on white pity
and see what they made.
Whatever the fuck it is.
I still got it.
You know,
white people.
What about the whole forget about game
of death and using a fake Bruce Lee for
most of the movie,
the worst editing ever for the editing
shit.
But how about the like bruce lie.
And then there was like a bruce at Lou
that all these total rip offs of Bruce
Lee.
They just went with it.
It was like kiss kiss.
Now they got,
they got a for Lee's makeup.
Peter Chris's makeup,
but they call him Tommy Thayer and Eric
Singer.
But they got a saint Peter's makeup.
It's incredible.
Asians were so hot back then.
That's like a certain dose escalation.
But the kiss,
no one's ever pulled it off like kiss.
Did Kagan dudes wear the same makeup?
The guys who they're replacing first.
I didn't do that now.
At first when they first last ace,
they got vinny events and he came out as
an Egyptian.
He was.
And then when they lost Peter,
Eric Carr came in as the Fox.
So when they decided to do the reunion,
they get ace and Peter Back.
Once they start leaving again in the
exact same order,
a slept first and then peter the exact
same thing.
They go,
fuck it.
Let's not start any new characters as
keep the old characters with.
Just have different dudes plan.
So Jesus was always like,
Jean was always like,
no drugs,
no alcohol,
no,
nothing.
Was Paul Stanley a partier?
No,
not both of them.
So both of them didn't party,
but the other dudes really party like a
motherfucker.
So Peter,
Chris,
right?
Massive.
Yes.
Peter.
Chris,
I think was an alcoholic at ace had a
coke problem.
She,
Samson,
you can't play guitar like down unless
you do a little coke.
Exactly.
Gene Simmons,
family jewels.
The new season last night.
Wow.
They got a new skulk for his hair.
You have to see it.
Yeah.
They got a new scarf.
He's got like two inches.
Tyler.
He's always had the gene.
Simmons will never be hosting a show
about hurricanes.
You're.
The crazy thing too,
is,
um,
going to be wearing a
motorcycle helmet.
They know.
Kiss knows the biggest kiss fan on the
planet.
So are you.
Kiss knows that.
You know what?
Most of the people now that are getting
into kiss,
they won't even know that.
That's not a severely.
And they'll go there.
The cap,
the fucking spaceman.
That's more important than their actual
fucking names like that.
It is.
As long as they can reproduce the songs,
you just can't have the songs at Ace
because ace had a very distinctive
voice.
Yeah,
I liked his voice,
man.
I liked these freely and Peter had a
great voice too,
but both of them can sing.
Eric singer is a really good singer and
he's really good at imitating Peter
Criss.
He really is.
Sound like that song [inaudible] man.
Fuck yeah.
Dynasty.
Nineteen 79 son.
Site to track too.
Right after I was made for loving.
Powerful.
That's another ace.
Didn't even write that song.
The producer wrote that one or so.
That was a cover.
Two thousand pounds.
An actual old cover.
I'd love.
I was made for loving you.
Give me some.
I was made for loving.
You find that shit.
Shit.
Typical remix that was made for loving
you in tough fucking house song.
It sounds awesome.
Three big tech.
Oh my God.
What a great idea.
That's a jam.
That was a disco song.
That's gone disco,
but it was good.
That was good.
Disco Heavens
on fire.
Everybody.
That's loud.
I was like,
we don't want to go live.
Sound like shit.
Can't be alive,
son.
Yeah,
go with the other video.
You go youtube there.
Let's go.
Fuck it.
Fuck yeah.
How many guys who were following him on
that?
You guys were blowing him off.
He didn't want to go there.
Want to start going there?
I think,
but without going further.
I think that's the reason why Paul and
Jamie for such a great team,
I think it's because of.
Because of what?
That could do.
Some guns and roses.
If you guys.
No one knows what the fuck we're talking
about.
Guns and roses accused him of what?
Love.
God.
Damn.
You're hot.
We can't even.
We can't even go there.
I don't want to go there.
All right.
Sorry.
I'm a big kiss fan.
What?
Okay.
No need to disparage them.
Yes.
Paul Stanley is one of my gods for sure.
And by the way,
he's freely as clean and sober now.
Really?
It Paul Stanley was gay.
I'd love him even more.
Who Cares?
Yeah.
I hope you got some good.
I Love Rob Halford.
I love rob from Queens.
Fucking Freddie Mercury was awesome.
Awesome.
I love to click and I don't like no.
Ricky Martin.
I don't like him to down.
Nah.
What about other gay singers?
Nelson is Elton John's a bad
motherfucker.
Motherfucker.
Come on.
John's a bad motherfucker.
One tiny dancer.
Come on,
come on.
Come on.
Come on man.
You a great gym.
I don't care if he's George.
Michael.
Freedom by George Michael.
Oh Shit.
Shit.
Hearts to that saw this poor different
parts.
It's not just the person cause it's
verse fucking secondary.
Bruce pre course and course for
different parts and they're all awesome.
And the video with all those hot models,
all the hot models are singing and
dancing along and as long as he doesn't
look at me in the eye when he thinks
that I'll go to a concert,
I want to be like,
you're right in the eyes.
He's sagging and a spell on that would
be different.
I would say a legacy.
If it's like Joey Diaz,
his joke,
George Michael could put a spell on me.
He pulled a diamond encrusted Dick
starts hiplet.
Seriously though,
Dude.
If you went to go see George,
Michael was playing and after parties
playing Dana White's fucking party,
whatever.
And he starts singing them.
Looking directly in the eye with you of
like started texting.
Okay.
Facebook I might try to do with Joey
Diaz would do them.
Blue Ball.
I get arrested again lately.
That's got to be the only thing that
turns them on at this point.
That's a secret shit.
Who wants to start?
We make the video and make it a straight
gay.
Just be real.
This next album.
I just want to come.
This is perfect.
Thank you for real.
This shit.
He's good at this.
I'm just surprised my Gaydar did not
work as a child because he bought this
like cd for my birthday.
His gaydar was not.
Not on.
Maybe as Keto was dead on it.
He thought that you were gay and trying
to test you out.
Kelly.
Joe.
Michael.
Yeah.
We haven't even got to the right after
this
music.
There's no argument.
This is not.
This is the ship.
That yellow heavy music.
Like a real grind court death metal.
This.
I understand that there.
Keep it playing in the background with
all the guys.
Fuck it.
Just give us a little background.
I'll be honest.
This is a good fucking jam.
Yeah.
I like some fruity shit man.
I do.
I a lot of fruity shit.
Like that billionaire song I like.
Um,
I liked that Katy Perry Song,
California girls that some fruity shit
cow.
But the fact that I would like it pop
music like some don't like a lot.
Pop music's good because it gets.
Once it gets into your head,
it's good.
Quickly.
That eminem song with Brianna,
I listening to her saying her parts
parts alerts too much.
Fucking these goddamn sense.
I love it when you lie.
Who the fuck loves it when you lie?
Everyone hates that shit.
I don't get the lyrics.
I just love her voice.
I just want to liberalize this.
Awesome.
Riata is definitely one of my peers.
Something terrible thing to say.
There's something extra sexy about her
and there's something extra attractive
but her that she got her ass kicked by
that too.
I don't know why there's something about
her that she's been through some shit.
Now I can understand this pain.
This is the legit.
Okay.
This girl's crying.
She is crying.
I man,
she loved.
Beat the fuck out of her and the whole
world knows about it.
She's,
she's allowed to be in pain.
She's allowed to be twisted.
She's allowed to cry.
And you know,
it's like when Tupac went to jail,
he came out better than ever.
Painful songs,
better than anybody.
I didn't even know she got beat up.
How sad is knows that when I first heard
before,
it was huge.
I don't even like rnb.
When I heard that song,
I knew it was going to be fucking
whatever the fuck that is.
That is a great song.
And then it blew the fuck up because
basically you pull the vocals out of
umbrella.
That could be something.
That could be anything.
It's alternative music with an RNB chick
over it
with a hip hop drum beat.
It's fucking perfect.
Music man doesn't even make any sense.
Fucking believe.
It doesn't make any sense.
How much impact?
Just a bunch of frequencies.
People talking and you know,
and the songs frequency.
Does it resonate with yours?
That's all.
It's real simple science.
So amazing though.
It's amazing that something like that is
real.
You know,
that people don't respect it.
I mean,
when you get really baked and you start
thinking about music,
people don't smell pot.
They don't even know what music sounds
like.
You don't.
You really don't,
you actually don't.
You're missing like a,
like about 30 percent of it.
You're missing some,
some extra layers that you wouldn't even
see her here.
Try listening to a seal when your baked
seal.
That song by a road was a big seal fan
back in the day.
Listen to that shit with some headphones
on when your baked.
There's like symbols out here.
You know what I'm saying?
Like the sounds so well engineered and
crafted,
you know,
it all flows together.
That dude was a bad motherfucker.
He was a bad motherfucker done with some
other shit that I didn't like.
Embedded to people that are like seal.
I like to seal.
Second album was for first two albums
were good man.
Crazy.
He was on the first album.
Oh he was brave.
And that second album,
man,
that's like six,
seven really good songs on that.
The quality is shit.
I'll tell you what I listened to
yesterday the first time.
Unbelievable shot day.
Yeah.
Oh classic.
Oh the first two albums are the ones she
did for the movie.
When the guy bought the million dollars
the guy gave,
that'd be more of a million dollars when
she's rolling around the money.
What's that song gave you love?
I don't remember.
That was a bad motherfucker.
I love chicks.
Oh,
we should sing.
That's my favorite and my favorite shit
to listen to.
My favorite all time.
Sarah Mclaughlin.
She just crushes everybody,
man.
She does.
But forget about sheryl crow has a
different element or fumbling towards
ecstasy by Sarah Mclaughlin.
Get that motherfucker the whole fucking
owl crimes of passion by Pat Pat.
Better time.
Passion.
Husband was fucking killing that guitar.
Crimes of passion.
That's a great jam.
Sheryl Crow and kid rock.
That fucking song.
That song we did together.
What does that woke up?
What is it?
What is the name of that song?
It's her voice in that.
In that song.
Her voice in that song is so good.
What about the fucking check for missing
persons?
Man,
remember Terry Bozzio played that.
That kid rock and show that way.
I just want to hear her.
Okay.
Keep going.
Live son.
Live here.
The first one's favorite singer in the
towns.
I like her way last because that
interview introduction rather broke
very much Mr Kidd rock.
Who said that?
It looked like Pamela Anderson.
Oh,
that's what it is.
People can watch.
That was a smart thing.
You did a little slow.
His part is cool because I like some
country music and I think this is kind
of interesting.
A man.
When that bitch starts singing,
it makes me want to curl up in a fetal
position and take a nap.
I want to go back to the womb.
It just makes me like be a little more
of that.
It sounds like a country rock star for
years.
He does a lot of songs like that last
album was holding all country.
He's a bad motherfucker that Eddie John
his shit,
man.
I liked his country music,
but here's.
Here's what gets you to come on Sheryl,
because this an original song or a
cover.
I think it's an original song,
but I don't know.
I could be wrong.
It could be some shift from the fort.
Is Kid rock road getting real powerful
kid rock.
I love her voice.
No,
we're watching.
Chick's got a soft spot for show girls
rather pissed off people out there right
now.
Let's take it back to.
We need a balance.
You need to put the slayer.
Two
bars.
It's a.
it's not a good version of it.
Anyway,
man.
Studio Angel of death on really quick.
Fucking voice is so awesome.
But if you guys should keep going.
No,
we're get to done for 20.
Get outta here.
Best time to end for 20.
We're sorry we subject you to that
music,
but we smoked marijuana.
That sounded really awesome to us.
And uh,
we thought it would have been a fun
thing to do.
I still love Sheryl Crow's music.
Saw about the fuck are you a carcass?
And I like nods to sun and much respect
to the fleshlight fleshlight.com.
Or go to Joe's website and click on
fleshlight for two.
If you get 50 percent much respect to
Eddie Bravo,
Jujitsu,
master of music producer,
you can catch him.
Eddie Bravo on twister at Bravo.
Much respect to mad on twitter,
but twitter on twitter,
that's a twisted sister.
That's his nickname is the twister.
Eddie Bravo on twitter.
And you find my mind space.
You still rocking mindspace I go there
once every 10 days.
I got friends,
you know,
so many profiles have been deleted.
So my top friends are like,
dude,
I don't even know.
And they're like,
they're like,
damn,
you're,
you're uh,
you got me on your top friends gave up
certain trends.
You just feel compelled to follow in the
abandoning my space even though it
helped me quite a bit.
Soon as Jodie Fox left our pal Jordy who
worked over there as soon as God would
often like,
all right,
I'm done.
Well,
I send people people that want to listen
to my music.
My music videos are up there.
They're not on facebook.
So if you want to check out my music,
my space.com/the
twister.
Why don't you have a section of your
website?
That's what it's about to.
Well,
not to do it.
It's not.
The new website will drop in about a
week or two.
I got the new website going up.
Meanwhile it's still gonna be 10th
Planet,
j.
j Dot Com.
So it's all good.
You will see Joey Diaz with me this
Saturday night at the Canyon Club,
will rock it in the Canyon Club and
we've never been there.
It's an old school rock and roll barn
out in the middle of fucking a gore.
It's the Shit Ted nugent's there next
week.
I'm very disappointed.
I'm going to miss uncle Ted of love to
watch that.
But uh,
it's gonna be me and Joey and we're
going to be there this Saturday night.
So come on down and uh,
thank you for all the birthday wishes
and thanks for tuning into the podcast
every week and thanks for tuning in to
this one are extra special happy
birthday day podcasts.
They enjoyed it and we made you listen
to Sheryl Crow,
but uh,
I really like it.
Alright.
Later bitches.
So you guys,
next week,
I love you.
Red Band.