Five,
four,
three,
two,
one Yamaha.
And realize my good friend Doug Dorin.
Hello Douglas.
Hello Joe Rogan,
who to see or so away,
man,
dude.
And uh,
Brian Richards,
your friend,
a wildlife biologist and um,
well we're going to talk about a bunch
of things,
but one of the things that I wanted to
talk about is this scary disease that
uh,
well when Ted nugent was on the podcast,
he downplayed the consequences and
effects of something called cwd or
chronic wasting disease,
which has made it onto your farm and you
live in Wisconsin and you have this
beautiful place that we visited when we
did the immediate or television show.
And this is a new thing that this
chronic wasting disease was just,
just,
it decimates the deer's health and kills
them.
And the suspicion is that some of us at
least comes from these high fence
operations where people grow dear,
um,
and treat them like,
instead of like a wild animal,
they treat them like a domesticated
animal and have them all feeding off of
the same pile of food and they share
this disease.
Is this all correct and accurate?
Brian
boy,
you just started out about an hour's
worth of congress.
Um,
so yeah,
just a little bit.
I'm a,
I'm a wildlife biologist with the
national wildlife health center,
US geological survey up in Madison,
Wisconsin.
And so,
uh,
one of the things that I spend a lot of
time on is chronic wasting disease.
I wouldn't say that makes me necessarily
an expert,
but I've gotten to know a lot of people
that I would call experts over the
years.
So I've gained a little bit of
knowledge.
So I don't,
I mean your,
your statement there,
we could start a number of different
places
this disease.
Um,
essentially,
well,
describe what it does do these animals
and why it's such a major concern.
It hasn't jumped to humans yet that
we're aware that we're aware of,
but it is a possibility,
a very real possibility.
We can't rule it out at this point in
time.
Science is unable to rule it out.
So,
okay,
that's a great place to start.
Why would we care about this thing
called chronic wasting disease?
And I would argue in,
in some other scientists have argued
there's two major reasons.
Number one is the impacts of this
disease on members of the deer family
themselves.
And the other is that we cannot rule out
the possibility that cwd could become a
human health issue at some point down
the road.
Guys,
you kind of nailed those two with regard
to deer or members of the deer family,
whitetail deer,
mule deer,
elk,
Moose,
and most recently it was picked up in,
in reindeer,
in Norway of all places.
Um,
we,
we could articulate some reasons,
some rationale why this disease might be
thought of as being important.
First we look at is would be geographic
spread.
So,
you know,
cwd 20 years ago was thought to be this
really novel thing in a very restricted
geographic range in south eastern
Wyoming,
adjacent North Eastern Colorado,
and maybe a little spill over and in
Nebraska,
a wildlife biologist,
wildlife disease specialist looked at
this disease.
It was interesting.
Uh,
we didn't know much about it at that
point in time,
but it seemed to be very isolated there.
What does it do to the dear Kilz dare,
right.
But how does it kill him?
Alright,
so this is a member of a family of
diseases called transmissible spongiform
encephalopathy.
These are tss.
So big long words.
Transmissible means it can go from
animal aid.
Animal be spongiform means looks like a
sponge and encephalopathy means disease
of the brain.
So you put it together.
And so this disease results in holes in
the brain resulting in progressive
neurological degeneration followed by
death.
Okay.
It's a,
it's a death sentence and there's no,
or for it,
it's not like you can capture the deer
and give them some sort of metal
cation.
No cure for these diseases.
The sweeter diseases.
You know,
there's a,
there's a members of the TSC group of
diseases in humans.
Most familiar is,
is one called crites veiled Jacobes
disease.
So it's very similar to mad cow disease
in the same family.
Second one,
the champions.
Well,
I'd say [inaudible] you could say price,
honestly.
I'll just read it.
It's an interesting,
you know,
there's,
uh,
goes back and forth on whether it's pre
honor,
prion stand poisoner to receive the
Nobel laureate for his work on these
diseases,
coined the term to prion.
And in his first publication describing
these diseases,
he did a phonetic spelling and it's
prion.
So other researchers,
it's especially,
you know,
um,
some from across the pond,
say it's gotta be prion.
And the main reason that,
you know,
some of them I've talked to about that
is that an ERC stand poizner when he
hears it called Prion.
Oh,
so we'll say Priyanka.
Yeah.
So I'll say prion from now on this
disease,
which people know as mad cow disease,
um,
obviously,
uh,
is transmissible to humans.
And um,
that's one of the reasons why people are
very scared that this could potentially
jump from deer into humans.
And correct me if I'm wrong,
but it also is making its way into the
actual plants that these animals eat.
You're correct on both accounts show
with BSE,
mad cow disease.
That was an interesting disease where it
resulted from,
in essence,
turning cows into cannibals.
We were,
which all cyclists in New Guinea,
right with KCC,
Coatesville with,
with crew,
which is a human,
uh,
disease.
A tsc likely started when one individual
developed Roitfeld Jacobes disease.
That individual died.
And as,
as a practice was the practice in the,
for a tribe in Papa New Guinea,
uh,
they practice ritualized cannibalism to
honor the dead and to help release the
spirits from you now deceased family
members.
So they would feed upon,
uh,
upon the corpse and port and you know,
the bodies of their deceased.
So when one individual died of probably
some variant of Coatesville Jakob's
disease,
then the causative agent,
the prion protein,
which is concentrated in the central
nervous system and lymphatic systems of,
you know,
of disease patients,
this was fed back to other members of
the family and the extended family.
And so when they got sick and died
veteran again,
so we saw that with brew,
um,
in,
uh,
in the 19 abused in 1960 around there,
um,
it was realized that this cannibalistic
behavior was likely the result,
you know,
or the right view,
the cause of disease transmission,
cannibalism was outlawed.
And at that point in time,
you broke completely the d disease
transmission cycle.
So no more new cases of Kourou,
but they had lingering cases with an
extended incubation period up to 40
years later before Kourou finally burned
out of that population.
So now with,
with BSC or mad cow disease,
we were doing exactly in essence the
same thing,
not exactly the same thing,
but in essence.
So in an effort to maximize production
and reduce the amount of waste when they
butchered cattle,
we would take all the awful Oh ffa l you
have the high,
the bones,
the parts that are inedible and we would
had rendered them cook them at high
temperature and typically,
you know,
high pressure as well.
And it turns into a slurry high protein
slurry.
You skim the fat off the top of that and
then dehydrate the rest of it.
And you have,
you know,
kind of a meat and bone meal,
a high protein supplement,
realizing that cattle grow faster and
produce better when they're,
when on a hyper higher protein diet,
it seemed reasonable to use waste
material from cows to feed back to cows.
So at some point,
turning,
turning thousand,
the candles.
So at some point in time a cow developed
a TSC,
a prion disease,
whether it came from scrapey,
the tsc of sheep or arose on its own is
unknown.
But that cow died.
It was rendered into meat and bone meal
and this high protein feed was then fed
out to hundreds to thousands.
And correct me if I'm wrong,
for these crayons,
they could survive up to more than a
thousand degree temperature.
Yeah.
Surviving is kind of a,
a strange term,
Joe in,
they're not alive to start with.
It's a protein a,
they can persist,
they cannot be inactivated.
So yeah,
it to,
he's to Cook Pretty Harley.
These premiums are not necessarily the
living thing like a disease or a virus
or a bacteria.
Well,
they're a disease causing agent,
but they are incredibly unique.
They're so,
they're an edl logic agent,
like a virus or bacteria or a parasite
could be causing disease.
But all these other things have genetic
material.
They're alive,
which allows them to change rapidly to
evolve over time.
So the,
the whole concept that you have a
protein,
a protein that all mammals produce in a
normal form can be converted after
production into a disease associated
form that has these radically different
characteristics.
One that you mentioned was,
you know,
resistance to heat,
heat treatment,
a normal prion protein.
And we have billions of them circulating
in our bodies right now.
Um,
have a specific purposes,
cellular purpose,
we don't know exactly what it is,
but it's likely involved in some sort of
intracellular communication.
It's a string of around 250 amino acids,
so relatively short protein.
It does whatever it's does,
and then the body recycles,
breaks that chain of amino acids down
into its component parts and recycles
it.
It turns out that normal.
So we would preamp protein likely has a
half life of maybe four to six hours.
Okay,
so you're producing them relatively
constantly.
Then there's the disease associated form
in all diseases associated prions start
as the normal cellular Priya.
So they're converted from one,
three dimensional form to a different
form.
Okay.
And this different form has these
radically different characteristics.
One is heat resistance and other is UV
light resistance.
Um,
I mentioned that the normal cellular
prion protein has a half life of maybe
four to six hours.
The disease associated ones can persist
in the environment for years and
potentially up to decades.
Okay.
And when you say persistent,
the environment,
you mean in like on the ground on
leaves,
on like how would they be,
yeah,
all of those things.
Just through,
so if a deer,
Moose sheds infectious agent,
this prion protein,
and so yeah,
from the time of deer is infected,
it's probably around two years before it
develops.
Clinical signs of disease goes down,
he'll lose as it's fear,
a human's dramatic weight loss.
Um,
all of those things,
that incubation period,
you know,
it's probably shedding infectious agent
for the vast majority of that time
period.
So it looks healthy,
but it's able of transmitting disease.
We'd call that Ala typhoid Mary Syndrome
Syndrome.
The two deer that we,
uh,
that were positive on our farm,
two bucks,
two and a half year old bucks were we
had them tested.
As you know,
we're,
for the last several years we've been
getting,
uh,
initially we got our,
only bucks tested and then the last
three or four years we've gotten all the
deer tested.
They were a two and a half year old
bucks,
perfectly look,
perfectly healthy.
And these are the first ones that you've
tested that tested positive and we
tested
in excess of 35 deer over the last,
well more than happy,
more than like 50 during the incubation
period.
Would they still test positive at some
point?
They will at some point.
So that could be spreading infectious
agents without testing positive.
Yes.
So it's say it's probably between three
and six months out when we can test an
animal test positive,
but it's likely shedding infectious
agent at least at lower quantities prior
to that point in time.
And so then he said it's shedding
infectious agent.
It's capable of transmitting disease and
cave long before it looks clinically
ill.
That's,
that's one of the real challenges with
this disease.
From a management standpoint,
they look perfectly healthy,
they act perfectly healthy,
but they're starting to have that
progressive neurological degeneration
that we can only see very near the end
of disease.
So,
correct me if I'm wrong,
but this seems like we could potentially
be facing a ticking time bomb of many,
many,
many deer that are wandering around out
there right now that look totally
normal,
that are spreading this stuff all over
the place and they're,
they're acting normally look perfectly
healthy.
And then obviously with this multi year
incubation period,
this kid just cascade and I think we've
seen evidence of that now.
Um,
started at,
you know,
he talked about being isolated disease.
It was picked up in Wisconsin at the end
of 2001 as of today,
cwd has been,
now penn picked up in 25 states in
captive and or free ranging populations
in whitetail deer,
mule deer,
elk or Moose,
two Canadian provinces,
uh,
in addition to two is picked up in South
Korea.
And that was real interesting.
It was in captive elk and those elk
still had Canadian ear tags in them.
So we pretty much know how cwd those
Elkton swim across the Pacific pond.
Most recently it was picked up two years
ago in free ranging reindeer in Norway.
And subsequent to that,
it was picked up in a small handful,
like three or four moose and a red deer
in Norway in a single moose in Finland.
It's a real concern over in Norway,
um,
with reindeer.
Okay.
So reindeer are very gregarious,
you know,
whitetail,
deer,
Caribou,
reindeer.
So not unusual to see him in herds of
hundreds of animals.
So very,
very different than what we see with
whitetail deer,
mule deer,
elk,
or Moose.
We don't see those huge hurts.
Met with elk.
You can in the wintertime.
But anyway,
it's thought that this gregarious
behavior might really facilitate
transmission in reindeer.
Right?
So when it was picked up in reindeer,
nor we said,
you know,
we maybe should do something.
It's an interesting story.
And um,
you know,
Norway has got experience with scrapey
in sheep and so they have a long
history.
What is scrappy?
Scrappy is the same as well.
It's the same family diseases and sheep.
It's actually the first one that was
described scrapey we've known about
since the early 17 hundreds a disease,
a domestic sheep,
and it's called scrapey because of the
behavior of these animals,
once they enter the clinical phase of
disease display and they,
they seem like they itch bat.
And so they'll go up to fence posts and
other objects and they will literally
rub their hide off of their body.
So that's the name scraping.
And it's the same progressive
neurological disorder followed by death.
I think about it.
So as this disease creates vacuums in
the brain,
it's killing off neurons.
And so without those neurons firing,
you fall into that progressive
degeneration.
And yet at some point your body can no
longer survive.
And that's what's really spooky about
how this thing kills.
So anyway,
go back to Norway when they detected
cwt.
Trying to keep this a little bit closer
to you.
You're very soft spoken.
Oh no worries.
I'll talk.
I can hear myself.
Plenty of the problem.
Is that recording?
I'm sorry.
Okay,
no worries.
So when they picked up cwd and reindeer
in Norway and the researchers over there
had witnessed what we are lack of
success on this side of the pond over
the course of the last 20 years,
they took it very,
very seriously.
Um,
so they took kind of some harsh
medicine.
Uh,
they announced their plans that they
were going to eliminate a herd unit.
They were going to kill every rain deer
in an entire herd unit in Norway.
The idea is to eliminate the host
population.
It's called stamping out,
and it works in a pen.
This is the first time had been done
realistically in a free ranging
population.
Oh,
ideas.
We don't have effective tools for
management as disease.
They were very fearful of what would
happen if this spread throughout that
reindeer population and throughout other
reindeer herds.
And like Alaska,
they have multiple herds.
Like last year I hunted Caribou with,
with Steve up in the,
uh,
40 mile river area,
but there were,
and so they're very,
uh,
we'll localize.
This is probably not,
but at least they have a range that they
move through.
So,
and then in Norway they have two or
three different herds,
many more than that.
So I don't know exactly how many heard
you could isolate of the herd.
So the idea is before this gets to be
any worse before it gets any farther,
let's take it out.
So they had a hunting season,
they allowed a hunter's to take as many
as they could,
which was a little over a thousand range
here.
And then they came in with government
agents.
But it's sharp concern that the hunters
could eat something with cwd and then
catch it.
Well that's always a concern.
But what we can talk about human health,
let me finish this one up though,
with Norway.
And it took,
literally took the bull by the horns.
They decided to do what was very
unpopular,
what we have not been able to do in
North America,
they,
and so after the hunting season,
government agent sharpshooters took an
additional 1400 reindeer as they killed
every reindeer in this herd unit and
they're going to keep it foul,
allow no reindeer in there for a minimum
of five years.
So it says every bit of promise of being
the first large scale success with
dealing with this disease in a free
ranging heard pretty different than what
we've been able to accomplish over here
five years.
Is that,
uh,
with it being in the soil and dirt from
what I was reading,
wouldn't everything else is that,
um,
so at some point there becomes a,
the,
the [inaudible] um,
diminishing population or they die out
or whatever the proper word.
I mean they're not living so they don't
die.
But if I become viable anymore,
yeah,
five years is probably a pretty good,
it's a guesstimate.
Okay.
As well with regard to how long these
prions remain viable in the,
in the environment and in the substrate.
So it's a,
it's a good first guess.
And what,
what they'll do then is slowly allowed
reindeer to repopulate.
And as they do,
they'll be harvested periodically and
every one of those will be tested.
So,
I mean it will be a long term experiment
into,
you know,
successful management and also learned
quite a bit about whether how far along
the environment was contaminated.
So those thing,
they caught this disease very early.
So after killing off,
you know,
2,400 reindeer,
I think they had around 20 positives.
So very low prevalence,
suggesting the disease was very,
very new in this system.
If you're going to be successful with a
disease where animals are shedding
infectious agent out into the
environment,
it persist for years to decades.
Do it early.
If you're gunna get on it,
get detected early,
get on it fast,
get on at heart.
Why the decision to let human beings
consumed them?
Well at this point in time that we
really don't have any evidence that,
that humans can get cwd could that
potentially though be an incubation
period issue?
Just like it is with deer may be
extended with humans.
Cause you were talking about how do you,
it was the correct pronunciation.
I was pronouncing it wrong.
No,
no,
no.
W or Jakub [inaudible] disease.
So that has a long incubation period in
human beings.
Correct?
Likely.
Yeah.
And mad cow.
Same thing.
Extended incubation period.
Kourou could,
you know,
some of the cases,
it looks like we're up maybe even to 40,
maybe even 50 year incubation.
Prts individually,
I'm talking about crew for me because
every time I talked to this guy,
I mean I've learned a lot from him about
all kinds of things and diseases.
But,
uh,
yesterday we were talking about Kourou
and I'm,
one of the things that was interesting
to me about it is that these tribes,
the women and children contracted it.
Yeah,
that's true.
Isn't that interesting?
And the reason why was the man ate the
meat and the women
and children,
it,
the internal organs,
the internal organs as well as
concentrated as coolaroo took off.
It was one of the features as the
researchers in the,
you know,
in the 50s and in 1950s we're looking at
the population.
Um,
very few adult males had Kourou and it
was more focused in the females and the
children.
And so it came back to that ritualistic,
you'll cannibalism and he hit it right
on the head.
Um,
the women and children got to internal
organs,
including the brain that have the
highest concentration of the,
of the prion protein,
the man,
if they consumed anything,
consumed the finer cuts of meat,
which have a lower concentration but not
now.
So I don't know,
that's just one of those social things
that just kind of stuck with me.
You know,
it is kind of,
it's pretty,
pretty interesting story.
Well,
a bunch of people reached out and some,
some were very angry after Ted nugent
was on the podcast.
And,
uh,
I don't know how cwd got brought up.
I don't,
I don't know what the context was.
I don't remember.
But I remember him saying that winter
kills more animals than cwd does.
And uh,
many people were very angry that this
was a gross simplification of what could
be a ticking time bomb.
I guess I would,
yeah,
I'd have to agree with that.
Um,
his other disease out there called
epizootic hemorrhagic disease,
he ahd and periodically you'll have
significant outbreaks of this disease.
And in,
in northern latitudes where the disease
is not been present has often you can
see dramatic mortality.
80 90% of our herd can be killed in a
single event,
but a very distinction between these
diseases.
You know,
Ehd is spread by midges little black,
no seams,
okay.
Sabbagh,
he actually transmits,
transmits the disease,
the virus from Adelaide animal be here
from the environment to animal a either
one.
So while you have these pretty dramatic
die offs,
as soon as the weather changes after the
first frost,
the first hard frost kills off the
midges and within about two weeks,
the disease cycle is broken completely.
So it has significant impacts on a
localized level periodically.
But the disease cycle,
there's a definite end to the disease
cycle and then it's no longer present.
Well then for that period of time and
for a period of time anywhere the virus
may persist in the environment,
but once the transmission cycle is
broken,
the mortality he snob and isn't there,
uh,
genetically engineered food plots that
they're putting together now or
different types of seed that a inhibits
midge growth and inhibits the HD?
I'm not aware of that,
but I wouldn't doubt it.
And I think there's also some stuff
they're doing that bolsters animal's
immune
system.
They're,
they're supplementing some of the,
the,
the food with a,
I don't know what they're using,
but it bolsters the animal's immune
system.
It makes them less susceptible to it.
And populations that had been histo just
are exposed to Ehd over time.
Definitely develop a herd immunity to
it.
And as the HD transferable to humans,
no,
we don't,
not that we've ever seen.
There's no evidence that it is,
this is a disease that deer and it,
you know,
it's,
it also can get into livestock.
So even if people get bitten by these
midges,
there's still no concern that we could
potentially get adhd.
No.
So contrast that this disease ehd with a
very definite end to the transmission
cycle.
First Frost kills off the midges with
cwd.
There's no known ecological factor,
which signals the end of the
transmission cycle.
So that's why we see prevalence or the
proportion of animals that are positive
in individual locations in individual
hurts.
It just keeps going up,
up,
up in captive.
Um,
facilities,
uh,
the,
the hall farm in Wisconsin where cewd
was first detected in 2002,
the,
the place was depopulated in 2006
prevalence was nearly 80%.
So four out of five deer in that cap of
servant facility had it.
Wow.
More recently we had a farm,
a deer farm in Iowa where in know
disease had gone undetected for some
period of time.
And when the herd was depopulated again
about 80% prevalence,
but this was a big hurts.
There were over 200 positives in this
single high fenced enclosure.
And so winners not going to change that.
It grows.
So no stop.
There's no known feature which stops the
transmission cycle.
And so when you say that something like
ehd kills a lot of deer,
yes,
it does.
With the disease transmission cycle
stops with cwd.
We don't know anything that's not
opposite.
It's
Ehd is more like the flu or you had it
on your,
your farm esd?
Never.
No,
no.
Let me rephrase that.
I not that I'm aware of.
Um,
and,
uh,
so when I learned about Ehd and you
know,
comparative,
uh,
diseases,
you chronic wasting diseases,
like none other,
it,
uh,
as it develops within the herd,
as it develops within the animal,
it just continues to grow.
So it'll start out as a very small
problem.
Um,
there's some maps of how it developed or
how it spread in the,
in the southwest Wisconsin and we're on
the front edge of it now.
Um,
and it's all correct me if I'm wrong,
Brian,
but it's like,
it's almost like the way it develops
within the deer taking that period of
time before it becomes a clinical and
the deer dies.
It's almost as if that's reflective
of how it moves from the landscape and
moves very slowly.
But once it's there,
it's there.
Now I have read about hunters eating
meat from some sort of disease,
deer and getting sick and dying.
What would that be?
Misreporting would have been possibly,
I mean,
I shouldn't,
I shouldn't say that.
I mean,
I don't know the,
there there've been instances where,
um,
people that hunted deer later died of a
prion disease likely developed
Crutchfield,
the outcomes disease.
Okay.
And so was it the deer that gave it to
them?
Well,
there's no epidemiological evidence that
this occurs at this point in time.
And we've hinted about some of the,
the human health issues.
So there's a few things we can look at
in areas where cwd is known to exist.
Do we see higher mortality rates from
Christ spelled Jacobes disease?
The,
does he have a prion disease,
have humans than we do elsewhere?
The answer is no.
Okay.
So from an epidemiological standpoint,
there's no evidence that cwd has crossed
over that species barrier into humans.
Now we can take a look at a number of,
of science experiments that have been
conducted and at least in,
in some of these studies,
in experimental models,
we have evidence that the cwd prion
protein can cause human normal prions to
convert to a disease associated form.
Okay.
But now these are models.
They're not,
it's not quite the same as pumping cwd
into the brain of a,
of a human patient and seeing what's
what developed.
Okay.
So the science suggests that there is a
small nonzero chance that cwd could
become a human health issue.
There's also some of the more recent
science that's been conducted suggest
that this barrier,
we call it the species barrier and it,
and it really is a very robust barrier.
One would think that keeps CD wg cwd
from crossing into human hosts.
That barrier may not be as tough as we
think it is and that barrier may be
changing over time.
Is that because one of the things we've
talked about before is that they've
discovered different strains of cwd.
Yeah,
it sure is.
Don't choose.
So yes ma'am.
It gets worse.
It's fascinating.
It's fascinating stuff.
You got to get to that point.
It's fascinating.
It's definitely fascinating,
but it's scaring the shit out of me
already.
So yeah,
the idea is strange.
It's really interesting with scraping,
I mentioned that disease a sheep,
we recognize some 30 different strains
and it's still all that same identical
strand of amino acids.
And it's shaped that tertiary form must
be slightly different and it manifests
slightly differently and sheep.
So,
um,
now with cwd there's at least two are
recognized strains that have been
published in peer reviewed literature.
There's probably more strains out there.
In fact,
it's,
it's kind of interesting.
There was a,
there was a paper done a couple years
ago which looked at the actual,
the architecture of this disease
associated prion protein.
And there's a,
there's a portion of it that's referred
to as a loop structure and it's just
kind of,
you know,
if you take a rubber band and or a piece
of yarn or something and ball it up into
a three dimensional shape,
there's a little loop hanging off the
side of this disease associated prion
protein and in deer and cwd,
that loop is very,
very rigid.
Okay.
It's very inflexible,
shall we say in humans.
It is more of a flexible loop as opposed
to the rigid loop.
And it's thought that this difference in
that architecture is part is partially,
you know,
controls that species barrier.
Okay.
So I was telling Doug that paper
yesterday,
it's pretty cool.
It's pretty neat stuff actually.
It was right zone.
So now it turns out mice,
experimental laboratory mice,
they're prion protein has the same
structure as the human pre Honda's.
Okay,
so you cannot give cwd to a normal
laboratory mouse.
They just don't get it.
And it's likely this different,
some of this difference in their prion
structure,
this one cannot convert that one to a
different form.
So some researchers in Alberta,
um,
identified a strain of cwd which came
from wild deer.
So it's not something they engineered in
the laboratory.
They have a strain from wild deer that
does give mice cwd fuck.
So most of the strains out there,
mice can't get,
but they discovered one that mice do
get.
So researchers from a few years ago,
and lately I've seen it in the,
in the popular media that hey,
this difference in this loop structure
is going to keep people from getting
cwd.
Well,
the,
all the,
all the assumptions that people can't
get cwd are based that on this idea that
cwt is cwd and it will always be exactly
the same thing.
But our experience with scrapey strongly
suggests that even though there's no,
um,
there's no dna in these things,
that they do change over time.
They morph over time into slightly
different,
uh,
disease characteristics and etiologic
agents.
Now,
in the hunting community,
is there skepticism about this as Ted
nugent's ideas?
Are these unique or is this a common
thought that,
or is it a convenient thought for them
because they don't want it to be real?
It's,
it's a challenge,
um,
of education.
Yeah.
Mostly
just in whatever period of time that we
talked here and it's,
you know,
it's really complicated in it it,
and to get to the,
you almost want to stick your head in
the sand and just forget about it,
you know,
besides of the sort of things that,
your friend that we were talking about
before that like I was doing on the farm
of,
you know,
managing deer in a particular way for a
particular kind of deer,
um,
which might be contrary to the,
to the spread of the disease.
So He's,
nobody wants to hear that I can't do
what I want it
do management.
We're talking about management wise and
we were talking about my friend John
Dudley's,
a farm in Iowa is that he only shoots
the big mature males and he lets all the
other deal grow to a very large size.
So he has a really healthy population of
big deer on his farm.
Now what are you doing in your place?
I understand you're just on a mass call.
Well,
I feel like I'm on the front edge of,
well,
I don't feel like I am on the front end
of the spread of this disease.
And there's some in Wisconsin and
Wisconsin,
southwest Wisconsin.
So 15 years ago when,
uh,
or 16 years ago when cwd was discovered,
there were a lot of changes in,
in,
uh,
hunting structure and there was an
effort by the Department of natural
resources to eradicate the disease,
uh,
in,
in the,
the core area south of the Wisconsin
River,
about 70 miles from us.
Um,
in 15 years the disease has moved 70
miles north.
Um,
that effort that the dnr started was,
um,
became political.
Um,
and,
you know,
and quite honestly that many years ago,
um,
I would have likely been a little
skeptic.
Well,
I know I would have been skeptical.
You want me to do what?
They wanted to kill all the deer in a
particular area.
You know,
that many years ago had they come to my
farm and said,
we're going to kill all the deer here
and all the near the neighboring dear,
I would have had some real hard
questions.
I have no idea how I would react to it.
I continued to do like buck management
and you know,
you were there when we were still doing
that.
Um,
and uh,
and there's,
we can talk about,
you know,
how,
how bucks contribute to the spread of
the disease and,
and that sort of thing.
Uniquely versus doe.
Um,
we see different prevalence or curves
depending on the demographic faction of
deer,
adult males,
the ones with the big hours.
Um,
but gears on the law over there tend to
have higher prevalence sometimes,
maybe two,
three,
four times as high as other segments of
the population.
So highest prevalence and adult males
followed by adult females and then by
juvenile animals.
So,
um,
so it's likely behavioral reasons why we
see that in adult males.
So adult male deer,
uh,
during the Rut or
breeding season,
they greatly expand their home range.
They contact multiple,
a female or a family,
groups of females earlier in the fall,
especially with the white tail deer,
adult males tend to gather in these
bachelor groups.
So there's a lot of social contact.
I'm grooming,
things like that.
So because of their behavior,
they contact more animals at different
times of the year.
And this number of contacts,
it's believed it's likely responsible
for them,
uh,
becoming infected at a higher rate than
other members out in the herd.
So now if you are an adult male,
then you're in the,
in this group,
you also have a higher likelihood of
being able to transmit disease to other
animals because you're out there during
breeding season,
isn't it?
Is there any evidence that w that any of
these deer have transferred this to
livestock or that it's God into
agriculture,
the food sources to corn and what have
you that could,
could be consumed by people even that
are veggies.
[inaudible] okay,
interesting questions.
So with regard to transmission into
cattle,
it's basically the same situation as
with humans.
No evidence that it has,
but in an experimental sense we can push
it over that species bear here.
Okay.
Now,
interesting you bring up plants because
we have shown a research that we've done
at the National Wildlife Health Center
has shown that if you grow some plant
types in a slurry,
I concentrate a prion protein that those
odds can be uptaken through the roots
and deposited into stems and leaves.
Hmm.
Okay.
And so that's one possible mechanism.
A second is that Cypriots himselves a
disease associated pre hands tend to
form very tight chemical bonds with
various surfaces.
Like showed him a paper on the way out
here yesterday where they bind to just
about anything.
They bind the plants as well.
So that deer that's out there with cwd
positives,
shedding infectious agent out into the
environment,
through its urine,
through its saliva,
through its feces.
So if a deer urinates as dear cwd
urinates on plants,
the prions have a tendency to bind to
those plants form a chemical bond.
It's not just drying on,
it forms a chemical bond to the plants
and literally become part of the planet.
It's,
yeah.
Okay.
So a deer could eat those plants and
that could be one of the possible
transmission mechanisms.
So that's a second one.
The third one has a,
we speculated about and some folks
who've looked at in,
in it has potential impacts for,
um,
agricultural commodities.
So when cdot video was,
you know,
20,
30 years ago was really,
really rare,
you probably couldn't happen.
But now it's in 25 states,
vast geographic areas we have,
I'm just south of where he lives
in adult males,
nearly 50% prevalence.
So when you kill that big buck,
take a coin out of your pocket,
flip it in the air,
and that's odds at that deer.
I cwd.
And when he says just south,
just 15 miles.
Okay,
so now let's go out west.
Yes.
Or,
yeah.
So let's go out to overall in the county
at this point,
let's go up into the big agricultural
areas in Saskatchewan or out west.
Okay.
So you got a mule deer herd out there.
We cwd and let's say maybe 20% overall
with that herd is cwd positives.
You've been out in some of those big
wheat fields and hayfields how many mule
deer standing up there before sunset?
Shitload.
Yeah.
Okay.
So take that amount times 20% or that
amount,
whatever prep sent,
have cwd figuring out how many times
it's a deer defecate or urinate on a
daily basis.
And that's a bunch.
And now think about the possibility that
when you harvest those agricultural food
stuffs and roll it up into big bales,
that you might have fecal material
rolled up into those big bales,
not just Mike,
Right?
I mean,
most likely,
um,
we'd need a graduate student that we
could have,
you know,
pick apart large bales of hay to really
prove that.
Um,
but I mean,
if someone was,
certainly now we're now we're putting
those on semi trailers and moving them
across borders and are those,
could,
is there a possibility that these
agricultural commodities then deer could
come up to them and be infected by
contact?
I think we don't know
wharton to say that,
um,
Brian's a scientist,
these other folks studying that are
scientists and they don't,
you know,
it's evidence and it suggests and they
get attacked for that,
um,
by people who don't want it to be true.
Well,
and,
and you know,
that's how science is attacked anyway,
right?
Because it's hard to speak in absolutes
is a real hard thing to do.
You know,
so it's,
you'll hear him say,
the evidence suggests the information is
this.
I just think that's a real important
distinction to draw here.
When you're,
you're having those kinds of
discussions,
you know,
there are,
people want absolute proof.
Proof is hard in a biological world
because there's so many factors out
there.
We can't control for them all.
But there are certain tactics that had
been used quite successfully.
It goes all the way back to smoking.
You now when,
uh,
um,
you know,
what the tobacco companies were
attacking science and the whole idea is
to sow the seeds of doubt.
There's a,
we've seen actually merchants of doubt.
We've seen that.
We see the same thing going on with cwd.
So you mentioned it earlier.
Hey,
um,
you know,
cwd it's not so bad.
What about winter kill?
What about Ehd?
So instead of focusing on that saying,
don't look here,
look at this one.
This is worse.
Why
aren't you doing something about this
one?
So it's a simple diversion.
Another tactic which is,
and I mean there's some,
there's a body of scientific
approach this because these are an
unrelated issues like Ehd does kill
animals.
Winter Til most certainly kills animals,
but we're not talking about the same,
right?
We're trying to divert the conversation,
Another thing is,
it's very easy to do is,
you know,
it's Cherry picking the literature
that's out that's out there.
We saw a real great example of this
about a year ago where,
um,
there's a lot of letters to the editor
being sent into newspapers in areas
where cewd is.
And I think it's,
it's an,
uh,
an attempt to change the conversation.
So they were very careful to use
citations from peer reviewed literature.
And one of the ones they used was they
found that in researchers in Wisconsin
found that cwd was not having a
significant effect on mortality rates
when they studied the disease.
So this is a true statement taken
directly from peer reviewed science.
What they didn't identify was that when
they studied that disease was between
2003 and 2007 10 12.
Yeah,
11 years ago.
Then the next sentence in the paper was
our study can use as a baseline for
comparison at a later point in time
should disease change over time.
So you mentioned that exponential growth
curve and how early on back in 2003 to
2007 this area disease prevalence was
probably lower than 5%.
Now it shot up in that curve and it's
probably in that,
you know,
25 30,
30 plus percentage range.
So you're cherry picking literature to
make your arguments that even scientists
say this is not having a big effect when
they studied it,
they're just not saying when they
studied it.
Mm.
So as a non scientist,
when I'm looking at here is everyone's
always terrified or the next pandemic
disease,
and this is one of the reasons why I
felt was so important to discuss this
because you know,
people would say they look at it
casually good,
don't eat animals,
don't eat deer.
This is,
this is not that.
This is something that has a potential
to reach large scale agriculture.
This is,
I mean if you,
one of the things about your farm,
and we talked about this when we're
there,
it's like these animals are farm animals
almost because they're,
they're absolutely free range.
They're absolutely wild.
When you talk about the deer on your
place,
you don't,
you don't have them controlled in any
way,
but they're feeding off of your corn.
Yeah.
They're eating all this stuff that
people eat their eating.
I mean that's what they eat.
They,
that's one of the reasons why the deer
populations are so enormous in farm
lands is because it's a massive who
super perfect environment.
Yeah.
And it's also one of the reasons why the
so delicious,
so well fed and
you know,
there's so uh,
nutritionally balanced diets,
but the,
the real,
what what's horrifies me is this
potential for a pandemic disease also
comes with an incubation period and that
we are looking potentially at like if
you just objectively look with no
hysteria and no hyperbole,
you look at the history of diseases,
diseases,
mutate and,
and many of them come from animals.
This is why swine flu and avian flu and
all these different things have actually
come from either farm animals or wild
animals that have somehow or another
manager transmit diseases that have
morphed to mutated and become dangerous
and deadly to human beings.
This to me seems like a ticking time
bomb.
He has a potential one switch one way or
the other like you've observed or
they've observed rather with mice and
this could potentially infect human
beings and spread across the entire
country.
Like wow,
fire.
Well,
we're seeing that spread right now in
deere,
you know,
Salian dear,
we're seeing Yale clear geographic
spread.
We're seeing clear increases in
prevalence and in areas where the
disease has been present the longest
we're seeing population level impacts.
There's a locations in Wyoming where
we've demonstrated where we've proven
that cwd is driving population decline
and dear.
So that's uh,
that encapsulates why we should be
concerned about deer.
And is this an mule deer?
That's a mule deer and in wait,
yeah.
And the mule deer have a,
an extended range in terms of like their
migration.
That's one of the things that we've
realized,
I believe over the last decade,
right?
Is that mule deer travel far mall far
longer and far longer distances on
average
on it.
And we ever saw before I even whitetail
scan.
So there's an interesting,
uh,
research tidbit.
The state of Minnesota,
um,
you know,
they've got,
uh,
appears to be a fairly recent cwt
outbreak in the southeastern part of the
state.
So they're researchers are really trying
to get ahead of this and figure out what
could move this around.
So they went in and captured deer in an
adjacent area,
but radio telemetry collars on these to
see,
well just how far do they go?
Um,
this was in a,
in an article just about a week ago,
pop popular media article,
so it's not published yet,
but they had a doe,
single doe coward that went 80 miles,
pretty long distance now,
80 miles circular or 80 miles,
40 miles as the crow flies from
[inaudible] Christ.
So in that 80 miles could potentially be
spreading cwd if it was an infected
sure.
Throughout crops throughout.
I mean,
and this is,
and then there's that exponential
growth.
So it's,
yes,
it's there.
Sure.
It takes a long time for it to become a
large problem.
And we're seeing that and we're seeing
that in richland county.
Um,
it crossed the river,
the testing has begun,
surveillance testing has been going on.
It crossed the river and it just keeps
moving and it be in,
again,
all these different plants,
all these different berries.
People could be eating these berries,
eating these plants,
fruits,
vegetables,
all these different things.
And they could be potentially consuming
these pre
well they're being,
I think it's very clear that there's
exposure.
Um,
and I talk with Doug quite a bit about
the difference between exposure and
disease transmission.
Okay.
Um,
so it is certain that lots of humans are
exposed to disease associated prion
protein from cwd,
unlikely from plant materials as well.
Whether that will result in transmission
of disease across that species barrier
is an open question.
We absolutely cannot say it will.
We absolutely cannot say it will not.
It's an open question.
And one thing we can though I identify
very clearly is that the rate of
exposure is increasing exponentially.
As disease has a larger geographic
footprint and prevalence goes up.
More and more hunters are just by simple
math being exposed to that positive
material.
So we're rolling the dice.
And when you do biological experiments,
I mean,
there's a certain likelihood that you'll
see outcome a or outcome be.
So if you keep rolling the dice enough
times,
you might see an alternative outcome.
We cannot rule that out.
So when we talked about this,
when you were on with,
uh,
with,
with Rinella and I at the farm
immediately podcast number 70 of
you,
Brian,
you put it as the chances are very small
at this point that it can,
and this is what the CDC and the World
Health Organization says,
well,
the chances are very small,
minuscule even,
but they're not zero.
And,
uh,
I'm assuming that we continue to,
that continues to be the,
you know,
the concern.
And I know you're talking a lot of joe
about,
and I get it because after all humans,
um,
but I've actually begun to focus more on
the effect on the,
on the resource,
on the,
on the deer.
I mean,
I tested positive animals.
Uh,
we,
we properly disposed of the meat,
um,
which is a whole nother,
you know,
line of discussion.
Um,
I'm still eating venison,
but I'm not eating.
Are you testing the animals to eat?
Every one of them.
We test every deer killed on the farm
now.
Uh,
how long when you raise a cow,
how long before you kill it?
Like,
how long do you do grass fed beef?
And this is actually kind of
interesting.
You were talking about the deer
whitetail deer on our place,
eating corn and beans and gmo corn,
gmo beans,
Alfalfa,
whatever they want to eat.
I control it.
What my grass fed beef eat.
I mean,
you're
right.
You're not taking my couch now the one
says hello by the way,
telling us
way.
Um,
but it's very controlled.
So even though my dear [inaudible]
affected your cow well and that they're,
they're not organic,
my cattle are right.
Um,
because it is controlled.
How ironic.
Oh yeah.
I mean you have farm animals in
captivity that organic purely eating
grass as nature intended and you got
deer eating Monsanto corn.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Um,
and you know,
and,
and before anybody out there,
it gets the idea that my cattle are
confined in a little barnyard or
everything.
That's a big law,
big,
large area,
big pasture.
There are,
you know,
free ranging within that pasture,
pasture raised.
Um,
so short answer,
uh,
with grass fed beef,
I just sent for him,
unfortunately,
none of it was ready.
I was going to bring you some,
uh,
they just went in on Monday.
Uh
Oh would like to see him go through the
security checkpoint caring,
you know,
bags of beef with him.
But
26 so they were two years old and two
years old and two months or three
months.
Now,
what the incubation period that you were
discussing earlier,
you talking about a two year incubation
period with deer before they potentially
show any effects.
So these animals would fall into that
line between birth and slaughter,
that that would be inside that
incubation window for deer.
Um,
it could be potentially larger for cow.
Is that correct?
PSC,
I think the incubation period is between
three and five years.
And so that's why one of the
precautionary measures for BSC in the
United States is we don't allow those
older aged cattle into the human food
chain.
What does BSC stand for?
Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy,
Aka mad cow disease.
So,
so that's one of the precautionary
measures has not aligned cause to get
old co for mad cow disease.
Well,
and from my standpoint,
they're prime at 26,
27 months.
And so when they are in an incubation
period,
they're still capable of distributing
the disease though.
Correct?
Well,
that's what cwd and with scrapey and
sheep as well with BSC and clarify,
if cwt went into a cow in a,
in a natural world,
we don't know exactly what it would look
like.
We know what it looks like when we
injected into the brain of account,
but we don't know what it would really
look like.
But BSE is quite different in that.
Um,
similarly with,
with the human prion diseases,
um,
uh,
an individual with Kourou could not give
Kourou to another human being.
They had to consume it.
So that with a verse,
that artificial process involved,
same thing with BSC cow.
A cow
would be s he can't give BSE to another
because they're not shedding that
infectious agent out into the
environment.
So when they stopped it,
when they stop feeding the cows,
that's called transmission cycle.
Cwd is a different animal.
So uwd and just our deputy Yazzie Times
10 on steroids,
while they're contagious,
kind of freaking me out a little bit
freaky because these animals are
shedding.
Okay.
Uh,
that infectious agent cows with BSE or
not shedding infectious agent cwd
positive deer and scrape the positive
sheep are these two diseases are unique
in the world of TSC.
TSC is a prion.
Diseases are unique amongst themselves,
but scrapey and cwd are in a different
world of their own.
So,
okay.
What,
if anything can be done?
Well,
I tried to break this stuff down to like
the most basic level.
So a guy like me can understand it.
MMM.
By time pay for science.
That's sort of one of the things slow
the,
this slow the spread of the disease.
There's a lot of work being done.
Um,
uh,
all kinds of studies being done,
um,
different organizations and,
and,
and the government.
Uh,
unfortunately in Wisconsin,
not as much as we should be doing where,
you know,
we're a hotbed of it.
I think that in Wisconsin,
quite honestly,
that we've become an example of how not
to handle the disease.
And a lot of the other states have begun
to,
uh,
you know,
take that idea that if you don't have
it,
you don't want it.
So let's do what we can to stop it from
coming here.
That's why you're seeing things like,
let's not transfer carcasses that,
you know,
there's bands on being able to transfer,
uh,
carcasses in Wisconsin and in some cases
you can't take it to another county.
You can take the finished meat so you
have to bone your meeting in the area
and then you can take it home.
Um,
which you know,
is a bit of a problem for,
you know,
for some folks,
um,
uh,
we're beginning to stop the movement of,
of captive deer from one farm to the
other.
But that's just recent and there have
been hearings on that lately,
so,
yeah.
So people resist that,
right?
Sure.
If your,
if your economic vita buy him a vitality
depends on selling and moving live deer,
you're going to be a post to
restrictions on your economic activity.
That is one of the primary infection
sources.
It's one of the infectious sources.
Yeah.
So they will always correct you when you
say something like Doug Skating had
mobile,
like break it down.
So that's a world at 11.
So we'd think of,
there's appreciate,
there's two mechanisms,
primary mechanisms if we lump them for
how cwd moves.
One is dear to deer,
to deer,
to deer at slow diffusive process.
Neo moving out on the landscape that's
really hard to deal with.
The other one is this anthropogenic or
human assisted movement where humans are
moving infectious material and that
might be how it got from Colorado and
Wisconsin in the first place.
So highly unlikely that a mule deer,
whitetail deer got up,
woke up one morning in Colorado and
decided to go 900 miles,
cross the Mississippi River and settle
in,
you know,
western Dane County.
And back in the day,
my dad and a bunch of his buddies used
to go out to Colorado and they,
uh,
are Wyoming's actually where they went
and they hunted,
uh,
elk and mule deer and it ran the whole
damn thing back.
I mean,
just what you did,
right?
You put it on the back of the truck and
off you went.
And then a process,
I can remember doing it in the garage in
Cazenovia as a kid,
you know,
working there with knives.
This is a great thing.
Well what do you do with the bones and
the,
you know,
the non meat stuff when you're done?
Well,
back in the day we used to and it still
happens,
we take it out and put it in a weed
called bone pile.
Coyote pile or something like that.
Dumped on the back 40 yeah.
Well where,
where
that's still could have infectivity if
it was a positive animal.
So it's a hospital out to Wisconsin is
who knows.
But anyway,
these are so he's,
he's absolutely correct.
The 25 states that don't have cwd don't
want to get it.
They want to do everything they can.
So these,
what is it?
Eastern states or southeastern states
and some of the far western states
haven't picked it up.
Oh yeah.
If you go to our website,
you'll see a map there that shows the
current known distribution of where the
disease is.
So the other states really don't want it
and they don't want it bad.
So it makes sense,
you know,
to look at these anthropogenic factors,
human assisted identify the possible
mechanisms,
how humans could bring cwd to him,
to you and stop them either with
regulatory frameworks or with education
teaching hunters that it's a risk to
move carcasses around is likely and much
more effective than just putting a rule
in place that says you can't.
And there are unscrupulous people who
purchase dear from these high fence
operations and release them in the wild
because they want big racks and animals
that it like people don't know there are
these high fence operations,
I shouldn't call them high fence
operations cause some of them are wild
animals that are contained in a fence.
These are farms,
there are farms that grow deer and they
grow dear with special protein feed.
So they have enormous racks.
So you have these really perverse specie
perverse examples of a deer and people
look at that and it like to,
to someone who enjoys wild animals,
you see those and you're like,
it's like a stripper with triple f test.
It's like what the fuck did you just do
like these?
They don't look real.
They don't like,
they have like 80 points.
Yeah.
Instead of like an eight point buck,
which is,
you know,
very typical or a 10 point buck.
You're like,
wow,
look at that monster.
That's a natural animal that lives in
the wild.
They have these things that they don't
even look like deer.
They look
like some,
some cartoon.
Like that stripper with the triple f
tits.
There are dudes or go,
I'm digging that.
Yeah.
But it's
vs to all who are in the know,
like you go over a guy's house and he
has one of those over his wall.
You're like,
did you just walk right out to that
thing and put a pistol in its head?
Like the deer hunter,
you know,
like what,
what is that?
That's not even an a wild animal.
That's some weird science project.
Well,
and genetics play a role in will correct
me when I start to veer off the science
thing here.
But um,
but uh,
genetics play a role in,
uh,
in,
in bigger deer.
Yes.
And,
and your,
your friend,
uh,
John Dudley had say the number of,
he's doing it.
The number one way to get big antlered
deer as it's not let them grow.
Let them get old.
Let them get old and give them plenty of
food.
Yup.
Yeah.
But genetics have a role in it.
Two,
three,
three factors in production of antlers.
It's genetics,
age and nutrition.
I really the the key three there,
but now know a lot of places will
identify these as genetically superior.
Well that's kind of a misnomer when you
get back to the definition of fitness,
genetic fitness,
there's only one measure of genetic
fitness and that's how well represented
you are in the next generation.
Okay,
so let's take an example where we took
one of the cl 80 point whatever and
let's release it out into the wild.
And during breeding season it comes
across a prime,
three and a half or four and a half year
old.
Eight pointer.
Yeah.
This physical specimen that you've
witnessed him,
they're unbelievable.
So now if you put those up against each
other in a mortal battle,
I know who I'm putting mine my money on
the wild animal.
Absolutely.
Yeah,
for sure.
Every time.
And it's just so,
so these animals,
while they're bread,
uh,
very much like livestock for very
specific characteristics,
big antlers,
these don't necessarily translate into
something that would be more fit out in
the wall.
Well,
let's also point out that the reason why
you're bringing this up,
as these animals actually do fight to
the death and it happens all the time.
They kill each other in,
in combat.
That's the reason why they have those
antlers in the first pace.
They don't have them to protect
themselves against wolves like Caribou.
Do.
They literally have them to fight with,
you know,
female Caribou have antlers as well,
and they have these antlers so that they
could try to fend off animals that are
trying to eat them.
There's a big difference between that
and elk and deer.
They have them for combat.
That's why once the breeding season's
over,
they shed them.
Um,
and then they start all over again.
Yeah.
There's an interesting example.
If you look to history,
um,
it's an animal called the Irish elk.
That's things where they're,
they're extinct now.
Okay.
They were,
they were twice,
three times the size of our normal elk
in their antlers were measured in feet
instead of inches.
Okay.
And so during their evolutionary time
period when they were on the face of the
arts,
that was when he,
all animals were larger predators were
larger.
These things got Gargantuan.
Okay.
Then they disappeared from the landscape
and at least,
you know,
they offered author Stephen Jay Gould.
Yeah,
there you go.
I'm Stephen Jay Gould has offered up
that likely what occurred was a change
in the habitat that climate changed over
time and that forest grew up.
If you're in the plains and you have
antlers that are seven,
eight feet wide,
you can walk around.
But now when trees start to grow up,
how can you survive when the world
around you changed?
And you'd have to literally walk with
your head turned sideways and Irish
Schalchlin extinct.
So there's a very real example of how,
you know,
a,
a phenotypic characteristic.
These mega antlers.
Really in the longterm.
We're not in the best interest of the
species.
Jamie,
pull up a photograph of these farm deer
antlers just right.
Just type in google,
ridiculous farm deer antlers and you get
a sense of what we're talking about for
the people that are watching this on
youtube because until you see it you
don't really,
you don't understand how gross it's
gotten.
Yeah.
I think one was called Goliath that I
remember.
Well there's um,
the,
there,
there good go.
Perfect example.
That is a perfect example.
What in the fuck is that?
Because that's not a deer like that.
That thing is,
that's crazy what they've done to that
deer.
It's a product of selection.
Give breeding there specific
characteristics that some people will
pay a lot of money for.
Yeah.
And there's a certain high fence
operations that you can go online and
they they,
you know,
this is what like look,
go back to that photo you just had with
that guy standing there drawing.
Oh it's a drawing.
Yeah.
Duh.
You went to so quick.
I thought it was real.
Look at that thing.
I mean that is just insane.
Look at the one behind it though.
Very normal looking deer.
Yeah.
It's probably a one year old.
These,
uh,
this is,
there's these places that have these
animals and some people will take these
animals and then they import them to
purchase them,
import them,
and then release them into the air
quotes wild.
And then they'll hunt them.
And then they'll pretend that that's a
wild animal they shot.
And this is a,
this is a source of cw.
They are potentially,
well,
okay.
So deer has to have cwt in order to be a
risk.
Right.
So it's been shown,
I mean,
in the lower 48,
we're just,
I think we're at a hundred captive deer
and elk facilities that have been shown
to be cwd positive,
uh,
say
we can definitively identify that the
captive service industry has been a part
of moving cwd across the landscape.
Uh,
we know that,
you know,
cwt positive.
Do your,
have been moved by the industry even
across,
you know,
international and state lines.
Okay.
The ones in Korea are a great example.
Right.
And even we had a recent one where cewd
positive farm in Wisconsin that can do
trace backs where this animal came from.
It turned out it came from Pennsylvania,
a game farm in Pennsylvania,
and then a doing testing in that source
heard they found additional positives
there so definitively.
So now while that's me,
I'll say that very clearly.
The cwe or the captive industry is a
portion of the equation.
They're not the whole equation.
No,
they're not the whole equation.
So where did,
where did originate?
He said there were the first testing of
the positive testing of the stuff was,
it was first described in 1967 in a
research facility in the state of
Colorado.
Okay.
That's not to say that was the first
instance of cwd.
It was the first time it was described.
Mr. Chan dear farms.
Well I think dear farms have been around
for a long time.
There is,
if you Google,
you know,
tame dear,
you'll find some from the you with the
late 18 hundreds when photographs became
possible of a deer following people
around.
So we've domesticated animals for a
long,
long time.
But as an industry probably really came
into vogue in the,
you know,
maybe the sixties and seventies and more
recently now it's grown,
you know,
that industry has grown exponentially.
I used to work for Texas parks and law,
but before I worked for USG GS and,
uh,
one of the things I did was I
administered the deer breeding program
for the state.
So when I started this,
I didn't start the program,
but when I came into that,
that role there were administered a well
deer breeders in the state of Texas.
Oh.
Like many states need a permit from a
state agency to conduct those
activities.
Okay.
And so I was administrating that
program.
I think there are around 120 a licensed
to breeding facilities,
whitetail deer breeding facilities in
the state.
At that point in time,
you know,
10 years later when I left parks and
wildlife in Texas,
they're around six or 700 so it just
grew exponentially.
And now I believe they're there around a
thousand captive deer facilities in the
state of Texas,
cheeses,
Pennsylvania.
There's around a thousand of them.
Ohio's got several hundred,
Wisconsin's got a couple hundred.
So,
so I'd say they're part of the equation,
but I don't want to,
you know,
I don't want to place all the blame for
cwd moving it around because there's
other possibilities for how this disease
moves around.
Uh,
doug hit on a one of them.
and that's the,
the idea of carcass movement.
It hasn't been proven that this occurs,
but it,
when
you look at it from a,
from a scientific standpoint,
it's very easy to identify.
So if,
if,
you know,
I butcher my own deer,
so if I kill a deer,
it happens to have cwd a butcher my own
dear,
I've got to do something with this
stuff.
Okay.
Um,
you know,
the meat component in a deer is probably
around 30,
35%,
something like that.
So I've got a lot of other stuff.
Landfills,
it turns out,
are very loathe to accept this material.
You know,
it's almost taboo.
Know who it might have cwd so we don't
want it at our landfill because the
effluent might be pumped out onto a
farmer's field and they could come back.
And you know,
they see it as a liability.
So I,
I've,
I've gotten my deer bones and,
and awful the rest of the material and I
drive to the dump,
which is 25 miles away.
I said,
no,
we're not taking that.
Well now what am I going to do with this
stuff?
So I could double bag it,
you know,
a little bit at a time and put it out in
the trash,
you know,
or maybe on the way home,
I'm driving past a state owned or state
park or a state natural area or a
wildlife management area,
and I see a trail go down there and I
drive down that trail and there's a pile
of deer bones and their heads here.
Whoops man.
Did I knocked that over?
Sorry about that Joe.
So it's easy to see how inadvertently
just hold your thought when you're not
on a microphone.
Just,
uh,
that's,
and it is one of the w one of the
concerns is how are we,
uh,
how,
what kind of hygiene do we have with the
carcasses?
So this is something that we're talking
about a lot more in Wisconsin now and
it,
and it's become an issue in one of the,
interestingly,
I'm the county deer advisory committee
for Richland County and we,
um,
it's a citizen group and we have some
say in,
um,
uh,
seasoned structure and then how many
antler this permits.
There are,
there's a lot of things we don't have
any say in which is fine.
I'd rather leave it to the biologists,
but because there are a hunter's
involved,
I'm happy to be one of them.
Um,
one of the things that happen in our
inner spring hearings is that we had
folks come in and say,
you know,
we're concerned about,
uh,
chronic wasting disease and we don't
want to spread it on the landscape,
but when we put the bones out on the
curb,
they aren't taking it on the,
uh,
Wisconsin Dnr cewd website.
There's a list of haulers who will take
it.
So there are some that will take it.
There are some who don't,
but my grandmas were they taking it?
Well,
they're taking it to clay lined,
um,
land landfills and
how it's being handled.
There's,
you know,
there's some question but it can be
isolated.
So the effluent isn't being taken out
and pumped out the fields.
It's something that you,
we can do something,
right?
Absolutely.
There's PR,
there's clear science.
So,
yeah.
And we noted how prions bind to various
surfaces.
They bind to clay particles very,
very tightly and say one of researchers
at Uwm,
Madison's name's Joel Patterson.
Yeah.
Tom was looking at this issue,
you know,
10 years ago to try and figure out is
can it be safe?
We'd done,
it turns out if you put about an eight
inch clay liner underneath Yale,
one portion of your landfill,
you can put all the deer and all the
prions there that you want to and allow
the preop,
this will then migrate down,
you know,
over time through the soil.
When they come in contact with a play
clay particles,
they bind and they don't go anywhere.
So it can be completely safely done.
So there's,
there's a way to dispose of these
materials very,
very safely.
But the,
the,
the thought of it,
the risk associated with it,
the liability,
some,
uh,
some landfill owners are just like,
Eh,
we'd rather not,
interestingly,
because we were challenged about this,
what are we supposed to do?
And you can incinerate it,
right?
Because they'll,
well,
it ends up being a budget issue in
Wisconsin.
Everything's a budget issue.
And the DNR is having,
you know,
issues with that.
And is something that I'd like to talk
about a little bit.
But,
um,
uh,
they were,
when,
when this all first happened,
uh,
in 17 years ago,
they were incinerating urine.
It became a,
you know,
a problem.
Um,
but there are,
uh,
landfills that are taking it and they're
our haulers who will take it.
They have dumpsters that they use
specifically for it.
They're aligned with,
uh,
you know,
heavy mil plastic that it's,
they're very specific to deer bones.
Um,
but some haulers aren't doing it.
So I contacted the head of a solid waste
for the state of Wisconsin and asked,
well,
how is this,
I go on your website and I see some take
it and some don't.
And her response was,
we have no legislative authority to
require them to take this.
So some are doing it voluntarily.
And actually one solid waste haulers
said to me,
um,
Geez,
we're putting a hell of a lot worse
stuff in the,
in the landfills then,
you know,
some deer bones.
Um,
but it's,
you know,
it's,
it's simple hygiene.
So one of the efforts that we're working
on in,
in southwest Wisconsin right now,
um,
is to,
and it's a funding issue,
um,
is to put place dumpsters in areas
where,
um,
you know,
like I'm volunteering to have one on my
farm.
It's a question of who's going to pay
for it.
And if it comes down to it,
I'm going to pay for the damn dumpster
on or about 500 bucks for a 20 yard
dumpster.
But,
um,
so that then,
you know,
people can come by,
throw their,
put their bones in that dumpster,
and then there'll be properly disposed
of because we have a,
a hauler near us who's said,
we're willing to bring them there.
Um,
uh,
you know,
to bring the dumpster there and then
dispose of the bones properly.
Like they do with,
uh,
at our,
and one of the lockers that one of the
butcher shops that,
you know,
processes deer,
they have the setup,
which is actually when I saw this when I
was like,
well wait,
why aren't we doing that in,
you know,
countywide and in various so that people
aren't chucking them in the ditch.
I mean,
otherwise you're holding onto the damn
bones until you find out whether the
things,
if you're,
if you're being completely careful about
the hygiene,
which we,
I've been trying to do and I'm telling
you,
you got a pile of bones in the old milk
house down there until you find out
whether it's positive or not.
And I'm literally keeping it the deer
bones separate so that when I find out
that deer a was non-positive well,
okay,
I can put those out or something like
that.
Um,
so that's one of the things,
there's a difference between what we
can,
we can,
there's natural spreading of the disease
and then there's human,
like putting them on trucks and move
them around or taking the bones around
and doing its carcass thing.
Is it really a low hanging fruit and the
idea that we can't fix this one,
I mean that's,
that's ridiculous.
And it's,
it's,
it's easy.
It seems easy to me.
I mean,
it's just a matter of will and money and
then,
and education obviously,
um,
that we're,
we're providing opportunity for this.
I've been working with the dnr a little
bit on this.
We're in some discussions about,
um,
two things.
One is a self service kiosk,
so to make getting,
uh,
getting your deer test that easier where
he wants to essentially cut the head off
the deer and leave it in a kiosk,
um,
with some information about where it
was.
And it's,
you know,
they're fairly simple.
They've been doing this for a couple of
years on an experimental basis.
Um,
but again,
it becomes a,
uh,
a budget issue.
So we're hoping that we're going to be
able to do is start something called
adopt a kiosk,
essentially that hunters and people who
are at sportsman's groups.
So,
um,
uh,
gather those heads and then take them
into the testing facility and therefore,
you know,
keep the budget money targeted at doing
the actual testing right next to that,
that a self service kiosk really should
be a dumpster that um,
you can throw your deer bones into
whether you know,
whether it's positive or not,
otherwise you are holding it.
The other thing that the dnr suggests
that we do is if you killed the deer on
your farm,
leave the bones on your farm.
Makes sense to me that way if it is
positive diseases already there and said
you're not taking his grand a chance at
moving it,
that's not an optimal solution to leave
that stuff on,
on the ground surface.
And an optimal solution is dig a hole.
But it's pretty hard to take sometimes
in December in Wisconsin.
Well,
if,
if I,
if the dumpsters thing doesn't end up
working out with me,
there will be a whole,
I mean last year we just kept the bone
separate and the,
and the ones that we,
uh,
I actually took the,
the,
the from the one deer was they went into
the dumpster at the locker.
Um,
this all seems to me,
sorry to interrupt,
but this all seems to be like bandaids
on massive gunshot wounds.
It is.
But go back to what I was saying before.
Let's buy time,
right?
Cause this
shit's spreading,
man.
Yeah.
Let's buy time and pay for science.
Not Ah,
there's nothing we can do about it or
the other one that it's always been
here,
which I think the guitar player talked
about.
Is there any consideration whatsoever
that there could potentially be a cure?
Absolutely.
See,
we hit on a couple of things.
I think it's important to talk just very
briefly about some paid generic disease
management practices.
Number one.
And I said,
beetle,
wildlife disease,
human disease,
livestock,
disease prevention,
number one,
if you don't have it,
don't get it.
Do everything you can.
That's why we get vaccinated.
Okay.
For various diseases if you do get to
see is do everything you can to keep
from moving it artificially.
So that's why we don't want to move the
carcasses around.
That's why you know we don't want to
move captive deer or not.
That's why we went when we had an ebola
outbreak in 2015 in Liberia and Ivory
Coast,
we stopped commercial airline flights.
We didn't want people inadvertently
moving it up.
So prevent,
don't move it around.
Conduct surveillance around areas where
it is to see what's going on in states
are doing that very well.
Largely.
The next one is a tough one.
Do something about disease manage
disease to try and knock down prevalence
incidence and get rid of the disease.
So that's challenging.
But two other things.
Number one is support research because
if we don't have a cure today,
we won't have one tomorrow either.
How is resorts funded right now?
Either by states or by the federal
government and there's not a ton of
money.
The last one is being transparent with
your stakeholders.
Being open and communicative with them.
So it's with many diseases.
We have good therapeutics,
okay,
we can treat some diseases cwd and other
prion diseases.
We have no therapeutics,
we have no treatments right now,
but people are certainly working towards
him.
That's so likely it's going to be very
challenging to create a therapeutic,
something that treats a prion disease
because treatment would then mean you
would have to get past the blood brain
barrier.
And once you start this cascading
interaction of normal prion to disease
associated preamps in the central
nervous system,
it's going to be really,
really challenging to stop that.
I mean,
it's a,
it's a roller coaster gone awry by the
time it gets up into the brain.
So then you're looking at preventative
measures,
the idea of vaccines as number one.
And number two is looking at animals
that through their genetic profile are
resistant to disease.
And there's some advances on each front.
So we can talk about vaccines for a
moment.
Um,
so people,
individual scientist's research outfits
have been trying to develop vaccines for
tss,
for prion diseases for a long time.
Okay.
None have been successful.
There's no,
there's no human prion disease vaccines.
There's nothing for BSC.
There's nothing for,
but there's research ongoing and there
have been some advances.
There is a Canadian research group that
had a vaccine candidate for cwd.
They thought it looked very promising.
So I went to a field,
a production stage,
and I actually tried deploying this
vaccine in a captive facility in
Wyoming.
Can I research facility?
It turned out that this vaccine was not
ready for prime time.
And actually after,
after a,
I'm giving this vaccine to some elk,
giving a placebo facebow to other elk
and then leaving him in a conceit obd
contaminated facility.
Actually the vaccinated animals got cwd
faster and at a higher rate than the non
vaccinated animals.
So it turned out to be almost an anti
vaccine.
Okay.
So it didn't work.
So
being an earth,
there was some sort of active cwd in the
vaccine.
Is that what it is?
No,
it just,
for whatever reason,
it that exceed supposed it predisposed
the animals.
So it,
it was a massive failure.
But even from failure,
you learn,
okay,
so they're working now in base,
you know,
they learned a lot in that experiment.
There's another research group centered
out of the university in New York who
published a paper,
I think in 2015 was her most recent
work.
And they've got a vaccine candidate that
provides some degree of protection,
quote unquote,
protection from disease.
Now all but one of the animals that they
gave this vaccine to and then challenged
with cwt got cwd.
Okay,
so that's not good news.
But the average incubation time was
extended.
That's something like 300 days.
Okay.
So they're on the right track.
They have a mechanism that is somehow
interfering with the conversion from
normal host prion protein to the disease
associated form.
So very valuable.
Now will they get there?
We don't know so,
but think about it.
Even if we do create a vaccine that
works,
that prevents cwd and prevent as opposed
to slowing,
there's a very big distinction.
So if you have a vaccine that makes the
average course of disease three years
instead of two years or four years
instead of two years,
they still have cwd are there.
Okay.
Dear farms that have 100% negative cwd
deer and them like none of them test
positive,
right?
The vast majority of dairy farms have
never had cwd the vast majority.
Absolutely.
There is a potential that you could
isolate these populations of completely
cwd free deer,
and if there's some sort of a mass die
off,
you could reintroduce these deer into
the wild.
Well,
okay,
so you're,
again,
you're,
you're looking at a giant,
you're looking at the difference there
between a herd that is cwd free,
which means it likely hasn't been
exposed to cwd versus animals are cwd
resistant through genetics.
Right?
So today we have,
we have not seen any deer that are
genetically completely resistant.
There are different genotypes of the
prion protein gene out there that do
impact the length of disease and also
seem to have some impact on how often
the frequency that these animals get
disease.
But even the genetically resistant deer
do get cwd.
Okay.
They get admitted,
they get it at a lower rate,
they likely transmit it,
they're likely shedding infectious
agent.
So instead of that,
that kind of garden variety,
two year incubation period,
it might be closer to a five year
incubation period.
So now for on the one hand you're gone
great.
Most deer die before they're five years
old anyway,
so this would be a good thing.
But on the downside,
you're talking about a population of
animals that have cwd with all these
other side effects.
They're shedding infectious agent out
into the environment,
this,
that and the other and you know,
cause a,
a potential risk to human and other,
other health impacts on the landscape.
So I'm not so certain that this is uh,
a success story,
just like a,
a vaccine that results in a longer
course of disease where there are deer
can get cwd but they die from something
else.
A population of,
of resistant animals that have as a high
prevalence of cwd.
I guess I don't see that it's a
desirable end point because of the other
consequences and potential repercussions
must be more desirable for killed him
instantly.
A shorter incubation period would be
preferable.
Yeah.
Because then you have the,
I mean it's almost like engineering deer
to survive longer,
gives them more potential to spread it
absolutely sit down.
Um,
recently sent out there,
there's claims that,
and there's research going on in some of
the,
at farms to dear farms that they've
identified genetic markers,
ones that are not published in the
literature yet that are affording a
higher degree of protection from
disease.
But until it's published in the peer
reviewed literature and really tested
it,
it's,
it's a speaking point until that point
in time.
So we don't know if they'll get there.
We've got to put a fence around
Wisconsin dog giant one 30 feet high.
Well,
it's,
you know,
there's 30 feet.
The Northern Illinois,
no northeast style.
All the places that have it.
25 but so what happened?
Half Alaska doesn't,
does Alaska have it?
Not that we know.
No.
Hawaii,
no.
No.
Okay.
So lower 48,
25 it's more than 50% then more than 50%
of the states have it.
Wow.
25 out of 48.
Yep.
So this is something that it just can't
be dismissed.
This is not,
this is not something that's a hoax.
This is not.
So the reason people were upset,
it would,
uh,
Ted said on the podcast,
there's very good reason.
Well,
look,
if I want to,
yeah,
I play guitar and a fine.
Want to learn some kickass Detroit
Guitar riffs.
I'm going to listen to Ted nugent.
If I want to learn about cwd,
I'm gonna listen to [inaudible] in
Richardson.
Guys like him.
Well,
the thing is,
ted does know a lot about hunting and he
knows a lot of wildlife.
You know,
it's a lot about conservation,
but it appears that he's,
uh,
very misinformed or under informed.
Let me try and put this in perspective.
Okay.
So you have a disease which is
contagious,
so always fatal upon close clinical,
always invitation,
a hundred percent fatal deer don't
survive if humans don't survive prion
diseases.
When it enters the central nervous
system,
it's a death sentence.
Okay?
So it's contagious.
It's fatal.
Neurodegenerative disorder,
it's gotta be a horrible way to die.
Okay?
So that's a pretty significant set of
clinical signs or symptoms in an
individual animal.
Right?
Okay.
Now let's look at the geographic spread.
Rampid geographic spread.
So it has an ever expanding geographic
footprint in areas where it's,
it's been known the longest.
We now have prevalence in a cohort of
animals,
adult male,
so around 50% and in adult females
around 30%.
Can you name any other disease of
humans,
fish,
domestic livestock,
dogs,
wildlife,
anything else that has that set of
characteristics and that degree of
penetrants into the population and you
go,
that's no big deal.
Um,
I'm not aware of one.
There was a one.
Now this is obviously very,
very significant,
which is one of the reasons why I wanted
to have you guys off.
I wanted to ask Jamie to pull up some
photos of,
of clinical cwd deer or elk.
I think you had something and then you
kind of took him down photos of the ones
that are sick.
That,
so again,
24 month plus or minus a incubation
period in the last six to eight weeks or
clinical.
Um,
I,
you know,
I gotta tell you,
man,
I killed this dear,
uh,
anti tested positive.
Yeah.
Tested positive in the office.
That one's not cewd.
That's not the one before that one.
What is that Scott?
Some of that was called,
that's a cutaneous fibromas.
Uh,
there are tumors that grow on the
surface of the skin.
Pretty grotesque looking.
Those are that,
um,
it's a virus.
It's,
well,
if you get those awards and those
fibromas on your eyes and they block
your vision,
it would be,
but otherwise it's about,
it's a stressor on animals and you can
actually eat down there.
Fine.
But I don't think
chronic wasting disease that Jamie's got
up there,
the larger image,
scroll down what it is that,
um,
that's likely cwd.
Yes,
absolutely.
Pick the one that's on the row
underneath
the second one from the left.
That one that the buck there.
That's,
yeah,
that's,
that's a photograph.
No,
you had on there.
So that was taken by a game warden.
Um,
Michael A.
Hopper is his name was in the state of
Kansas and he's,
you know,
this diseases has a pretty decent
footprint in Kansas as a game warden.
He had gets calls about deer acting
funny and so he's taken a number of good
pictures.
If you can zoom in on that photo,
I don't know if you can look at what's
coming out of that.
Deer is mouth.
See that stream of saliva that's all
filled with infectious material.
So that's one of the clinical signs is
it's hypersalivation well,
deer,
that's a wild deer.
So it's almost like this disease's
trying to spread itself.
It's been pretty efficient.
Yeah,
yeah.
But,
but by doing that,
by forcing these animals to have all the
saliva excretion,
this is a very effective means of
transmitting this disease throughout
the,
the set of characteristics of this whole
disease where the protracted incubation
period shedding infectious agents
through bodily fluids for the majority
of that incubation period,
the,
uh,
the infectious agent persistently
environment for years out to decades.
I mean,
if you wanted to stack the deck for
disease,
you couldn't come up with a better set
of characteristics.
Plus they look perfectly healthy.
So we have no idea.
You know,
that they're there that are diseased
until later on in,
in,
in the disease progression.
Now is there a prevalence in or is there
a higher prevalence in deer versus moose
versus a elk or anything else?
We tend to see higher prevalence in the
deer species,
whitetail deer mule deer in isolated
areas.
Then we do in either elk moose,
there's only been,
you know,
worldwide,
there may be only been 10 positive moose
okay.
To date.
And it's likely in a,
and it doesn't seem that they're less
susceptible,
it's just that they're likely haven't
been exposed because they're not in the
same systems.
And there are moose tend to be a
solitary,
definitely Wisconsin,
you know,
periodically a single a yearling,
we'll,
we'll wander down from a northeastern
part of Minnesota,
but very,
very rare.
What about wolves?
Have Wolves contracted it yet?
Wolves are interesting story.
So,
um,
to date,
there's no evidence that any Canaan,
any member of the dog family has ever
developed any TSC.
They never got bse as far as we know.
Uh,
no evidence at any Canaan has gotten
cwd.
Now that could be a real observation.
It could also be that we haven't done
enough science on it.
Okay.
But there's certainly exposure as
opposed to cats.
Um,
in the BSE situation,
both great cats and domestic cats got a
TLC.
We,
it was referred to as feline spongiform
encephalopathy and it was from consuming
BSE contaminated meat.
Okay.
Very similar to how he wasn't mountain
lions.
Yeah.
Great cats,
which most certainly consumed.
Yeah.
Regular basis.
Now in,
in with cwt in North America,
we,
again,
we have no evidence at any mountain lion
or any great cat or small cat,
um,
has contracted cwd and facts.
It's very interesting.
In a research study in Wyoming that I
was a part of,
um,
it turned out that the highest source of
mortality for cwt positive deer was
mountain line predation.
And so somebody is going,
ah,
Aha.
CWT doesn't always kill deer.
Well,
but it predisposes them.
So think about that.
Progressive neurological degeneration
and think about how mountain lions hunt.
They're ambush hunters.
So if you're a deer and you're not quite
right,
you know,
I mean this disease is developing in
your brain,
you're progressing progressive dementia.
It's not at the point where we are
humanized,
which really are very,
very poor.
We can't see disease yet,
but disease is progressing and an ambush
Predator can leverage that and take
advantage of that.
And that weakness in the prey.
We see the same thing in Colorado.
Um,
studies have identified that cwt
positive,
do your tend to get hit by cars more
often than cwt.
Negative negativity.
It,
it's very logical.
So now let's extend that to two wolves
and asked the question,
could wolves be a management tool for
cwd?
Okay.
Wolves are present in northern
Wisconsin.
You know a lot of them over there,
a lot of other locations and at some
point wolves and cwd we'll meet.
So there's been mathematical models
developed,
which are,
there's a lot of assumptions built in
those models,
but it leaves it as an open question.
Could a large coursing Predator who's
vision and senses are much more acute
than ours.
Could they take advantage of this
disease in earlier stages?
And so when disease meets
geographically,
Wolf's could wolves slow or maybe stop
the progression of disease because
they're taking the weak and the sick and
the old still wouldn't stop the
excretion and it still wouldn't stop all
of the bodily fluids and they could they
could they slow the spread or stop the
spread?
Maybe could they reverse disease?
You could likely take all the predators.
You could find wolves and mountain lions
and dump them into Iowa county just
south of where Doug lives and they
likely would not be able to eliminate
disease.
But at that [inaudible] has disease
spreads geographically at the interface.
Could predators
be an effective tool to slow or stop
disease from spreading?
It's an interesting question.
Especially when states are contemplating
more aggressive control measures opening
up hunting and trapping seasons to
reduce population densities.
So woes.
So we don't have good tools and I'll
leave it an open question.
Do we want to take that potential tool
and take it out of the tool?
What about,
what about,
uh,
okay.
So,
uh,
Wolvercote well,
coyote by us,
you know,
they're eating deer die in our woods and
from,
we found a dead one,
uh,
last time Steve was there and I was very
suspicious of it being a cw,
cause it was a two and a half year old
buck.
It was laying there and it turns out it
was probably hit by a car,
but it was fairly well consumed by
coyotes by then.
Um,
and I cut the head off of it and sent it
in and it came back.
Non-Positive um,
what happens when that coyote,
which is going to travel while they're
traveling huge distances,
but,
so he's eaten a cwd positive deer on the
durian farm and he's running over to
bunker hill seven or eight miles away
because they do that and he takes us to
dump over there.
Yeah,
we've done that.
Science has been done and so it turns
out if you take cwt,
cwt positive material,
you put it in the front end of a coyote,
it comes out the backend of a coyote and
it's still capable.
It's still infectious.
They still infectivity and it is capable
of transmitting disease.
You said mice don't get it.
A rats eat coyote poop,
correct?
Yeah.
So they,
they,
they don't get it.
Not that we're aware of.
Um,
there's a potentially spread it and
their urine because they would be
carrying it.
So that,
that kind of,
and I have to ask you,
you say he could eat cwd positive
material,
you could poop it out x number of hours
later and he might be a mile or two
away.
Okay.
So that's a fairly local geographic
phenomenon that could be spreading
infectious material.
Now you have to ask your self,
you know,
more questions when they defecate on the
landscape.
Is it dear likely to encounter and
consume that material?
Well,
maybe not now,
but it might be fertilizer two years
down the road for plants if the deer
could eat.
So,
but I think that's just quite
restricted.
It's a localized geographic phenomenon.
Okay.
And that's something that we can do a
hell of a lot about.
It's hard to,
same thing with,
with crows,
you can put cwd in the front end of a
crow or probably other scavengers and
cwd comes out the back end about four
hours later she could ask her Christoph
the question,
how far does it crow fly in for hours?
And it is a deer likely to consume crow
poop.
So these had been shown to be possible
in a laboratory environment,
but how much they really apply out in
the field is of Co of question.
So we go back,
we know that deer,
the deer,
the
deer,
the deer,
we see that slow diffusive process on
the landscape.
That's the biggie that's going on just
south of him and now his past him.
Then we have that answer.
Pathetic movement,
Yo humans moving long distances and the
potential for agricultural commodities
to be involved.
I mean there's likely other things like
crows and coyotes,
I a proof of concept in a laboratory,
but whether they're really happening in
the field as an isn't entirely open
question.
And if they are,
how big are they as compared to these
other features?
So why not do the,
you know,
and,
and some of the detractors will also
say,
well,
you can't stop dear from doing dear
activities.
Right?
And branches licking each other,
uh,
those,
those normal dear activities.
But if we're concentrating them in an
area,
let's say a mineral lick,
um,
where every deer in the area comes
through there and then looks at in there
or a feeder or a feeder,
um,
and you know,
a bait pile.
Um,
uh,
and,
and we've seen bait.
I mean,
I've seen bait piles where there's a
pile of corn.
It was a pile of apples.
Well,
they're all eating off the same pie.
You've got all these deer coming into
that.
That's something that we can do
something about.
There are all these natural movements
that we can't do anything about,
but if we can slow the spread by
stopping these unnatural gatherings of,
during these unnatural,
you know,
spreading of the disease,
why wouldn't we do that?
Yeah.
There's a few things.
You know,
you keep honing in on,
you know,
there's these anthropogenic factors and
then what can we do where disease is
truly his ear?
The things you're talking about,
the baiting and feeding artificial
congregations of animals.
Okay.
Um,
in where TB is in,
in Michigan,
you can't bait and feed.
And in Wisconsin,
some of the other states where cewd is,
you can't bait and feed deer.
The idea is you're artificially
congregating them.
So remember that single deer,
we saw him up there on the screen is
shedding Mayo,
copious amounts of saliva.
So if that deer goes up to a pile of
corn on the ground,
he's sharing spreading infectious agent
into that corn.
It can persist on that corn for a long,
long time.
Decades,
healthy,
naive,
susceptible animal comes up at each set
corner,
licks that mineral lick and it's likely
that that animal is ingesting viable
infectious agent can transmit disease.
Um,
the,
the analogy there is,
is his daycare.
Okay,
if you want to get your kid's sick,
your three year old kids sick,
what's the best place to do it?
Send them to send them to daycare.
Daycare is the analogy.
There is that pile of corn on the
ground.
So if every child that ever goes to
daycare is perfectly healthy,
they're not little disease factories,
but we know that's not the case.
So they're in a great place in schools
are a great place to spread disease and
then those kids come home and share it
with you and then you can share it with
others.
Right?
Same thing there.
So these artificial congregations,
if all the deer healthy,
we'll then,
they can't be a place to transmit
disease,
but we know that's not the case.
So it's an iguana.
Those risk factors we can control.
But now you hit doug,
you know,
we get back to this area where disease
is established.
Is there anything we can do?
And there's certainly things we can try,
right?
And we haven't,
we haven't exhausted the toolkit yet.
Um,
Mike Samuel at uws and I now retired.
he,
he looked at this from a mathematical
perspective and he's trying to leverage
the idea that adult males have higher
prevalence,
right?
So there they are sync spur disease,
they're gathering disease and then
they're shedders of diseases.
Well.
So what if in our harvest regime,
in hunting season,
we focused on adult males.
Okay,
we hammer the bucks because they're the
ones most likely to have disease.
So we would lower prevalence and that
we're reducing the proportion of the
population with the highest prevalence
of disease.
The idea is if you knock that segment
down enough that you would interrupt
disease transmission cycles and you
could actually lower herd prevalence
over time.
Now you still have the persistence in
the environment,
but on from a modeling basis,
it works.
All right,
so now think about the deer hunter out
there listening to me today,
listening to this show today.
Oh,
now they want us to go out and kill all
the bucks.
So it's not going to be a very desirable
from a hunter's perspective tool.
So all the tools we have,
you considered these like medicine for
bird disease.
They're very bitter.
It is a bitter pill.
I,
you know,
you were there when we were still doing
the wearing the Sombrero.
If you,
uh,
you know,
shot a smaller buck or whatever and uh,
yeah,
we had a management idea that we wanted
to grow some bigger bucks,
but at the same time we were pretty
lenient about it.
Um,
we,
we're not doing that anymore.
The deer I shot last year were deer that
seven,
eight years ago.
I wouldn't even take another look at
that first bucket shot.
The first buck I had an ethical shot.
Yeah.
Or the I'm giving you more tags or give
housing.
Know
there's resistance resistance in the
hunting community to that.
Um,
that's unfortunate.
It is unfortunate.
Um,
I'm not one of those,
those people,
we are in my part of the county deer
advisory committee and we're giving more
doterra eggs or antlerless tags because
the other part of it,
sure.
We have a,
uh,
a population in the box that because
their sinks as he said,
and they're spreading the disease,
um,
and,
and they're traveling more,
you know,
a doe and her family tend to kind of
stay in one area a little bit more where
the bucks have a bigger range.
Um,
but the other thing is then is
population.
So one of the things that,
for a couple of different reasons,
I mean,
you saw the number of deer that we have
in our place in richland county.
We have in excess of 75 deer per square
mile of habitat.
And I know there's places in the country
that are higher than that,
but,
um,
you know,
it's,
it's sort of a,
it's a,
it's a big population and I'm,
I have issue with it for a few different
reasons.
One of them's disease.
The other one is that when I have too
many deer,
my little oak trees are getting because
they love those little oak trees and
they're getting chewed off and I'm
trying to do multiple things.
I'm not just trying to raise deer on our
farm,
um,
and our woodlands.
So,
uh,
you know,
that,
that's one of the issues.
So there's this demographic issue that,
that,
uh,
Mike Samuel,
it had been working on,
but then there's the population issue as
well.
Um,
we're given four.
When I,
when I was a kid,
when you bought up buck license,
you and four other dudes would get
together and then fill out this form and
send it in and like August to get a,
what was called a party tag.
And you could shoot one doe between four
people because we had,
um,
they were trying to manage the herd to,
to have mortier.
Cause again,
when I was a kid seeing deer,
it was a big deal.
It's exact opposite now.
So now you buy,
you get a buck tag and you get for a
antlerless tags with every tag that you
buy in our county.
What changed from when you were a kid
where the population exploded?
Well,
uh,
management was a big part of it.
Um,
and the management exploded is,
I mean,
I'm going to be 60 years old.
She was an exotic and look.
Great.
Well,
thank you very much as the,
you
and Brian,
you look pretty good too.
Um,
pretty good.
Jamie on the other hand over that,
I know he's still a young buck,
no kid,
but,
uh,
I don't know.
Of course,
uh,
that's a pretty long period of time.
And when you,
uh,
when you're controlling because you
don't have many deer and your managing
to increase the deer herd and you have a
mentality out there that will,
I'm not going to shoot a dope because,
you know,
those are the,
um,
and they're having to fonts.
And this year,
at least in my area,
we're seeing a lot of those having three
fonts.
That's,
you can see how that growth of,
of the,
the herd.
Yeah.
If you want to hurt to grow,
stop shooting dose,
if you want to take a her down,
you know,
shoot does,
I'm gonna get back in Grad School in
Illinois,
they gave away these little pins that
hunters collected.
And when you brought a dough into the
registration station,
you got a pin that said,
I shot a doe.
So the herd won't grow.
You know,
people collected these little momentos
during that time frame.
Like I said,
I grew up,
uh,
Yale,
a couple counties to the north and west
of where Doug was in,
in the,
in the 1960s.
I mean,
there weren't a lot of deer around there
and watched,
you know,
as I grew up.
Yeah.
We,
we didn't shoot many dose.
The regulations in the state didn't
allow you to shoot dose by 1980 on
opening day.
I remember I counted 160 dear on opening
day,
15 years before that,
probably saw three,
something like that.
So exponential growth in the deer
population over that point in time.
The deer management program worked
really well.
Oh yeah.
We know how to go out there.
And that along with all of that that,
that we've already talked about the
agriculture and the agriculture expanded
well agriculture but the uh,
but you know,
it was always there so it had the
potential for all of the explosion.
So,
so there's a interesting,
you know,
I talk with folks in,
in the state of Michigan and they've got
a shoe,
you know,
pro relatively recent likely issue is
cwd and yeah,
there's user groups out there that are
trying to advise the state on how to
manage cwd.
One of the groups is,
is talking about,
um,
it's called antler point restrictions.
Okay.
The idea is a,
you know,
a yearling buck,
18 months old has fairly small antlers
and then as they get older,
they typically get successively larger
antlers.
So a group is out there right now as an
active proponent of implementing antler
point restrictions and promoting
antlerless harvest at the same time.
Okay.
As a disease management tool.
So as we noted,
you know,
lowering the population that already how
cwd is beneficial in it.
If we have,
if we have a herd of 500 animals with
10% prevalence,
that's 50 positives versus a herd of 20
animals with 5% which would be one.
And that's a dramatic difference.
The prevalence is the same,
but we have fewer positives out there.
Right?
So lowering populations overall does
make sense with regard to disease.
Okay.
But now the other part of antler point
restrictions is allowing males to get
older.
And they argue that that will keep
hunters engaged.
And if hunters are engaged,
they'll shoot more dose and keep the
population down and that'll be a good
thing.
But you know,
we've already discussed how adult males
have tend to have the highest prevalence
of cwd.
Okay,
that's fair.
Now you're talking about promoting,
pushing more males into these older age
groups in an area where cwd has already
known to exist.
And so from a,
from a biological perspective,
from a numerical modeling perspective of
disease,
I failed to see how this can work.
Um,
so will keep in hunter's engaged.
That's a sociological question that I
can't really address.
But from a purely biological disease
driven process,
promoting more older aged ma animals,
older hd or in a population with cwd,
I cannot figure out how that could be
beneficial.
That seems the opposite.
I'm hoping that through this podcast,
this information becomes more digestible
because I think that in order to get
what you just laid out over two hours,
in order for someone to get that by
reading,
it's like they're not going to do it.
Most hunters are just not going to do
it.
And so I,
I have a feeling that like what Ted
nugent had said that this is a,
the,
his perspective is possibly way more
prevalent than should be.
And because this information is not that
digestible,
I think that there's,
you know,
the,
I know you talked about it on meter
episode 70 70 and then now today,
this is going to reach a lot more people
and it's in a very digestible form where
they get to sit down and listen to it.
And hopefully we can get the word out on
this in a way that it's not getting out
now.
So people understand the consequences of
this.
This is a real issue.
And it's,
this is not simply like,
hey,
we don't want to do this because this
could negatively impact our hunting
opportunities.
We might not have any hunting
opportunities in 10 years or 20 years
like this.
This literally could devastate the
entire population of deer.
This is not,
it's not a simple thing.
This is an incredibly complex thing with
a terrible disease that is 100% fatal
and is absolutely spreading.
No question.
Some of the,
you know,
the take home points,
I always thinking and I get regularly
asked by hunters,
will,
what can I do?
Okay,
well what a hunter's do.
They sit at deer camp and they shoot the
crap around,
you know,
whatever libations or whatever.
So,
and they're going to talk about things
like cwd and good.
So let those conver conversations be
driven by fact and science as opposed to
rumor and Innuendo.
Right?
Okay.
That's what we're doing here to that.
And that's why I think this public
information is,
is so important.
There's other things it can do.
We talked to doug hit on a bunch of
them,
you know,
hunting as part of a,
promoting a healthy deer herd.
Can't haunting keep populations low.
Test your deer and manage those
carcasses.
Don't leave them out on the landscape.
There's another category though of
things it can be done.
You know,
in deer camp,
what's the easiest thing to do is blame
the dnr for everything.
The Department of natural resources.
Okay.
It's,
it's a,
it's almost a sport to kick around at
night and see who can insult the dnr the
worst.
Right?
So it was regard to disease though.
Is that really an effective use of your
time?
It might be fun,
but it's likely not affected because
think of the state management agencies
that deal with deer.
It might be the Agriculture Department
or the natural department.
They're very,
very restricted in what they can do
there within a legislator.
Operate within a legislative framework.
Okay.
So if you really want to impact change
in how a government agency goes about
its business,
should you talk to the local biologist
or should you talk to the elected leader
who establishes the legislative
framework that that agency works
underneath?
It's important to put pressure on,
uh,
on our elected representatives and,
and we've seen change in that in well,
Wisconsin being a great example.
Um,
are,
uh,
management used to be science based
wildlife biologists making decisions
about deer management.
It's politically based.
Now politicians are,
are deciding what the,
you'll,
you'll often hear that in uh,
I will county Wisconsin where this,
this first effort started.
Um,
well see it didn't work up.
Their dnr is,
you know,
they had this idea and it didn't work to
stop the disease.
It didn't get a chance to work because
social and political pressures and
political stars forced the dnr to vacate
their plants and their aggressive
measures.
And even more recently,
and there's a,
but it was a court case,
uh,
the state of Missouri,
the Missouri Department of Conservation
tried to implement some restrictions on
the captive serving industry to stop
importation of live deer seeing them as
a risk factor.
Um,
the deer breeders sued the state,
uh,
went through the court system and,
it was decided by the Supreme Court in
the state of Missouri,
uh,
about three weeks ago that in fact,
all dear are,
you know,
reps or represent wild deer and that the
Department of conservation was well
within their constitutional and
legislative authority to implement
measures designed to protect the
integrity and viability of that deer
herd for future generations.
So the Supreme Court said,
yes,
Department of Conservation,
you do have the right to restrict import
of animals into captive serve facilities
to protect the integrity of the herd.
And it's the,
the,
the legislative part of it is really
important and I can't put too fine a
point on it.
Um,
laws can be changed and there's pressure
to do that under lot of for you know,
a lot of different reasons.
I've been a part of changing some
legislation it had to do with forestry
and I know how it's done.
Um,
and you know,
one of my favorite quotes from Ella
Leopold is ethical behavior is doing the
right thing
even when no one's watching.
And the wrong thing is legal.
So just because it's legal doesn't mean
it's the right thing to do and it
doesn't mean it's the ethical thing to
do.
Is there any potential to changing the,
the limits tag limits or making them
more widespread if they understand the
issue with this and they understand that
one of the main tools of,
of handling this in a more manner and
slowing the populate or slowing the
spread of this disease,
who the population at deer is reducing
the population itself.
It mean even the,
the,
these hunters would resist this because
it would limit hunting opportunities.
This could potentially be a large tool
in the toolbox of conservation and
stopping the spread.
Short answer on that is yes.
As I said,
I'm on the county deer advisory
committee.
We have the opportunity to give out as
many tags as antlerless tags is.
We want,
what about Antler tags?
Cause that's the issue,
right?
One that's it.
One per person is legislatively control.
But even with this disease,
which that might be the number one tool
to,
to slow down the spread.
Yeah.
We used to have a um,
a policy in uh,
Wisconsin called earn and buck.
And it was not particularly,
uh,
popular with a lot of hunters.
Cause you know,
I want to shoot my book and I don't want
to have,
shoot earn a buck.
He had to shoot a doe a last year to
earn a buck tag.
Um,
and it wasn't particularly popular.
That's really a mild way to put it.
Hmm.
Well it was a post [inaudible] opposed
by a very noisy group of hunters.
Just like,
and again,
with my experience with working with the
legislature,
a small group of people making a hell of
a lot of noise with a certain amount of
money can change things.
It wasn't popular.
It was popular with me as well.
Again,
you hunted on my farm,
um,
we shoot way more antler of a steer that
we shoot bucks.
Um,
when when earn a buck was in place,
we'd have a stack of buck takes because
we were shooting so many dose.
That was because it was politically or
socially,
uh,
became a political issue.
Um,
it was rescinded.
And so now what we found in Richland
county is we can give,
we could drop antlerless tags from a
helicopter to shoot as many as you want
and we're still gonna kill.
But the same number of those about the
same number of dose,
every,
there was a little bit and there's been
a little bit of an uptick.
But when we had earned a buck,
we killed a shitload of them,
you know,
three times as many.
And,
um,
it becomes a,
and I understand,
especially like casual hunters,
like,
you know,
gun hunters are a good example.
Bowhunters or you know,
different example because they're not as
casual,
but they're more interested in,
in,
you know,
killing the big,
big buck a generally,
um,
uh,
gone hunters.
Yeah.
You go out there for two or three days.
I mean,
you were there and we froze our asses
off.
I mean,
it's like,
well,
how long am I going to stay out here?
We have a really short season.
We initially had much longer season
when,
when the cwd management first started,
we had a much longer season.
I loved it.
Um,
I,
I got to hunt with folks that,
you know,
that,
that maybe had their own place to hunt
where I invited folks from the community
to come in and hunt.
Uh,
you know,
friends from different places came down
and hunted.
But again,
a small noisy group.
Um,
and I dunno,
smallest,
I don't know what the numbers are in
that,
but,
um,
made that go away.
So now we're back down to the 90 season.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
Like who,
who gave into that?
The politicians,
politicians understand
and they're doing it from an ignorance,
from point of ignorance,
political pressure,
political pressure.
I've got to hope that something like
this podcast gets to them.
I sure hope so.
Man.
I'm not sure why we came out.
This is a terrifying couple.
Couple of Erica.
So the Wisconsin experience was really
important and the data shows that the
first couple of years,
so they say aggressive management with
earn a buck was actually forcing the
population down,
but it was very unpopular.
And so,
um,
political pressure was applied and that
tool was taken out of the toolbox thrown
on the ground.
Immediately.
When you stop doing,
uh,
earn a buck and you stopped having
longer seasons,
the population trends reversed and
started going back up.
So it was easy to label,
Hey,
the dnr failed their effort to eliminate
disease by,
by having aggressive seasons failed.
Like Doug said,
we don't know that because we stopped.
We pulled the plug on the tool,
Alberta,
when the wind cwd started really
blossoming in Saskatchewan,
Alberta was like,
we don't want it.
And they found their first handful of
cases right on the border between
Alberta and Saskatchewan.
They took,
they raise the odds a little bit.
They started harvesting deer from an
aerial platform called a helicopter.
Okay.
That helicopter with government agents,
sharp shooting deer to try and basically
eliminate deer in a buffer zone between
Saskatchewan and Alberta,
knock the disease,
deer out and create a buffer zone where
disease wasn't well,
that was not very popular either.
Like a Fart in church and uh,
land owners and outfitters went to the
ministry and said,
we can't possibly have this.
And that program I had every chance of
being successful and the rug was pulled
out from underneath them.
Okay.
So now here we have time.
Sure.
We are,
uh,
you know,
years later and the western states,
Montana,
Colorado,
Wyoming,
where disease has been a long time.
Their wildlife health professionals,
I have put together a set of uniform
management recommendations for the
western states came and they're
promoting the things that we've been
talking about,
reducing those artificial congregations
of animals,
implementing a harvest structure to
focus males.
Okay.
The male focused the most,
the social group with the highest
prevalence and also kind of what I guess
I would refer to as hotspot shooting.
When you see a new spark of disease out
there on the landscape,
get on it.
Don't allow it to become established.
Your only chance to be successful to
eliminate disease is very,
very soon before it gets established.
And Starch,
you know,
spreading.
So now we're seeing in Wyoming and
Colorado and Montana,
they're actively talking,
they're talking to the media,
they're talking to their commissions and
they're talking about implementing these
regulatory structures at least on an
experimental basis,
recognizing that doing nothing
is no longer an option.
And that's one of the things that was
learned from the Wisconsin experiment,
for lack of a better word.
Um,
that are our failure.
I mean,
you know,
the analogy that I often use is,
we had this,
we had this car and it was,
you know,
pretty decent car.
That's pretty decent model of how we
were going to control the disease.
But you know,
they kind of let the oil go out of the
car and they ran it into,
rented in the ditch and banged it around
and then brought it up and say,
damn,
this Ford doesn't run worth a shit.
And if you can't actively tried to
defeat something and then say it doesn't
work,
you really have to let it,
you know,
this is of course,
and in Whiskey,
what I hope that what's happening and
what I can see is in,
you know,
in the 15 years that I've learned about
cwd is that not only is there a lot been
learned about the disease,
but there's been a lot learned about how
to manage it both on a scientific level
but on a social level as well.
And I can tell you,
man,
if you don't have it,
you don't want it.
Um,
you know,
15 years ago I felt,
and there's so much more known now than
there was 15 years ago.
Um,
you know,
I feel like we,
it's not too late in Wisconsin.
I mean,
we can keep slowing it down and we can
protect the rest of the state.
But,
um,
we get a lot of work to do and it takes
a well,
it,
but it really doesn't take the medicine
was very bitter,
I think technical information to,
because I don't think people are really
aware of the extent of this disease or
the danger of it or all the
ramifications of it.
I agree.
I'm surprised in my area intelligent
people that I know that are casual
hunters.
Yeah.
So it's getting to be deer hunting time
and I'll talk to them what I'm like,
ah,
they don't really,
well,
you know,
they don't know.
They don't know.
Yeah.
That,
yeah.
And that really is one of the things.
So,
you know,
I appreciate so much the opportunity to
come out here and talk about it.
And,
and Brian and Mike Samuel,
um,
are going to come to a regional center
in September,
which is the capital or a county seat,
I'm sorry,
of Richland County.
And we're going to do,
uh,
another,
presentation on chronic wasting disease
and we're advertising it.
Y,
you know,
widely and more of that information has
to get an education,
a big part of Joel.
You're exactly right.
Yeah.
Just don't think there's enough
digestible education.
And I think this sort of form is one of
the most digestible,
oh,
you have to do is you put it on your car
and drive around,
you listen to it,
you put it in your headphones and you're
at the gym,
you'll get this information,
you'll get an a and M in a way that
you're probably not going to sit down
and go through these studies.
And I appreciate it as well.
I mean to,
I'm pretty,
uh,
not very savvy on social media and
things like that.
I wasn't even sure what a podcast was
when Steven Rinella,
you asked me to come on and do meat
eater.
And so we did that.
And um,
I,
I understand now it's been downloaded
like 650,000 times.
Okay.
Which for a scientist,
you know,
I've been an author on a lot of peer
reviewed papers and I can guarantee you
they haven't been read.
You take a couple zeros off of there and
that's probably the readership on those
snakes.
So from an impact,
being able to get a message out to
people,
this type forum really,
really is helpful.
And getting it down,
like you say,
down to a level that hunters can
understand and digestible I think is
very,
very important.
Um,
cause I w o he talked about how
misinformation,
active misinformation to try and,
you know,
it's not so bad or look over here,
don't look at this,
look over there.
You know,
these diversionary tactics are very,
very successful.
They were very successful with tobacco.
They were successful with other
scientific endeavors,
you know,
today and also the simplistic
perspective that hey look how many deer
get killed by winter.
You know,
it's way more than cwd stop,
stop crying wolf.
Yeah.
So diversionary tactic,
I'd like to bring up about that.
Um,
I've killed some big deer and uh,
I get it.
Guys want it.
People want it.
Hunters want to do that.
Don't want to kill.
That's what they look forward to it.
They look forward to hunting season.
It's only one time a year.
Yup.
And you get to do that as we're not just
hunters,
we're conservationists.
What we do is going to affect the future
and we have an obligation to do what's
best for the resource and what's best
for the future.
Um,
and I'll tell you this,
last year I shot a two and a half year
old buck opening day.
And,
uh,
this is a nice little eight pointer and
I celebrated that deer.
I enjoyed that year.
I remember that moment just as much as
the 200 inch block that I killed.
It's,
it's different.
But it concerns me that at times we get
so wrapped up and I was one of a man,
I feel like a recovered alcoholic
sometimes about the whole aler thing,
you know,
like,
hi,
I'm doug and I used to be a and step
process.
Well,
and there,
you know,
there is a part of that.
Yeah.
But remember what the joy of hunting is
and the,
the,
the reason for it and how important it
is to make sure that that continues into
the future.
Um,
there've been some folks who really,
you know,
sounded huge alarms about this and you
know,
you talked about it a little bit.
Yeah.
20 years from now,
it could,
you know,
it could be,
well it might take a generation or two,
but it really could become that.
Um,
I want to be able to eat the meat and I
want to know that in future generations,
you know,
a hundred years from now and that farm
is still there and it's still in the
during name,
it's been in my family for 115 years.
I want to know that a hundred years from
now that my descendants and their
friends and their family are going to be
able to come there and still enjoy that
and in order for that to happen,
just like when I'm managing my oak trees
so that a hundred years from now there's
going to be those big Oak Tree Sarah
again a hundred years from now,
we have to do what we need to do now in
order for this
opportunity,
be there for the future.
Our hunting heritage is huge.
Not to mention that the financially,
that the economics of of deer hunting in
a place like Wisconsin,
there's over 650,000 people that hunt
deer.
They pump in excess of $1 billion every
year into the economy of the state of
Wisconsin surrounded by hunting.
If we put that on a national basis,
there's millions of hunters and more
billions of dollars spent.
So it's not a small thing when you think
about,
you know,
the economics of hunting.
But the heritage of hunting is very,
very important.
I mean,
I,
I've been hunting my whole life.
Yeah.
Now I hunt.
Uh,
primarily one county was to him and you
know,
cwd has coming.
I'd say I'm sitting in my tree stands
three years ago and Cwt is in the next
county.
Over two years ago,
the first cwt positive deer in Crawford
County,
Wisconsin was detected,
um,
less than two miles to the southwest of
the tree that I'm sitting in.
Last year,
cwd had been detected in another,
in a secondary in Crawford County.
This time,
one mile to the northeast of where my
tree stand is.
I find myself looking at deer
differently.
I'm looking for those subtle queues,
a disease,
and it,
they say it's changing the experience I
get.
I get calls pretty regularly from,
from hunters who are like,
you know,
really it's a coin flip out there.
I'm not so sure I want to hunt there
anymore or no,
because I'm on the deer advisory
committee.
A group of hunters came in who bought
land south of us,
you know,
uh,
20 miles south of us in a significant
portion and they're doing,
uh,
they were,
they bought it to manage it for,
for bigger box,
um,
and population and all of that.
They came into the county deer advisory
committee and talk to us about what
they're doing.
They shot 43 deer on that property last
year.
All of the box tested,
all the antler bucks tested positive for
Cwd,
um,
about 25%
of the dose and some of the Fonz.
So a doe fawn who as cw who has cwd and
she's going to be clinical and die in
two years,
she's never going to have funds of her
own.
That's the population issue.
But what I,
you know,
I hope those guys are listening.
Um,
what I plotted about them is what
they've done is really worked with
bringing in other people and I'm going
to do the same on our place.
Um,
bringing in more people to hunt,
um,
to,
to take more deer and to do what they
can manage it because they saw it.
Well the,
and what,
they're not seeing big old bucks anymore
cause they're dead.
They're dying,
they're finding them,
but they're finding them dead.
We've seen that in and a Wyoming in,
I mean what we look at,
the longterm impacts had disease.
And I talked a little bit about
population impacts driving population
down.
The other you're saying we would
identify is changes in that demographic
structure.
So you know,
when you were hunting for the big
antlered deer,
you're looking for animals that are four
or five years old and mature over mature
animals in an area where cwt as
established at high prevalence levels,
those animals are not going to exist or
what would be extremely,
extremely rare.
They're rare.
Now,
here's an example of a,
a real large ranch out in Wyoming and
there's about a hundred thousand acres
and eight managed historically,
exclusively for these over mature mule
deer.
You know the ones with the antlers,
you know like that monstrous muled
there.
Even in the good times,
they probably killed maybe three of them
a year,
something like that.
On that vast acreage because you know
there's a lot of sources of mortality.
They're not anymore because you,
you know those deer living that long.
I think about it at math question,
math quiz for,
for,
for during here.
So in this population with super high
prevalence,
so let's say at 18 at 18 months of age,
yearling deer,
let's say they have 20% prevalence,
and we have that,
we demonstrated that at two and a half,
it's probably 30% prevalence at three
and a half and four and a half and above
it's,
it's close to 40 45 50% prevalence.
So this is a two year disease,
right?
So half your prevalence dies every year.
So if you have 20% prevalence,
half of those deer are going to be dead
the next year,
half the year after that.
Okay.
So over time you would expect these
cohorts to diminish.
So the math question is in that
population,
how many five year old bucks are there?
Because disease penetrance grows over
time.
The answer's not meant.
It's not a,
I'm supposed to.
It's a sound.
The alarm.
Yeah,
yeah.
No.
And that,
you know,
that really is the case and it's,
it's,
uh,
I,
you know,
again,
that's why I wanted to bring along,
because he's
going to provide the science and I'm
going to try to break it down to,
you know,
Doug's level and,
and hopefully that,
you know,
folks can understand it and I know I get
emotional about it,
but,
you know,
part of it is,
yeah,
well my dad would be 94 years old today
and he's the guy that I started deer
hunting with.
You know,
he died a couple of years ago and I,
he grew up with that farm,
you know,
it was my great grandfather's farm in
that area,
in the driftless area.
And you've heard me talked about the
driftless area before and how important
that area is to me.
And this is a big part of that area.
It is an emotional thing for me,
which is why I then look at the science
and what can we do about this?
And I think about,
you know,
I think about Elva Leopold,
what leopold do right now.
I mean,
what would he be thinking about this?
You know,
what am I old man?
I'd be thinking about this,
you know,
I know what my dad would be saying.
He always sat my,
my antler thing was bullshit.
Every time he'd see a bucket on the
trail,
chemical shooter,
you just,
he just like,
he was just an old school buck hunter,
man.
He did an antler on it.
You shot it.
So all those things are in my head as I
think about this.
And,
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's the emotion's important and I get
the emotion part from all of these,
these,
these folks.
Um,
and I understand that some of them want
to kill big bucks.
And,
and you know,
maybe because I have killed a couple of
big ones,
that's it's not as important.
Maybe.
Maybe it has something to do with being
60 years old and maybe you understand
the consequences.
This is a real serious issue.
Forget about the ego of killing a big
buck or you know,
this desire to achieve something that's
more difficult than shooting a young
one.
There's more at stake here.
Yeah.
So you brought up an interesting,
what would leah do and he,
I mean
this disciple,
you know,
father of modern wildlife ecology
started the first program of Wildlife
College at University of Wisconsin in
the 1940s populations of deer in the
northern part of Wisconsin.
We're growing by leaps and bounds and
they were dramatically changing the
landscape.
PM denuding the landscape,
you know,
eating eastern white cedar and deer in
northern latitudes tend to yard together
in the wintertime.
And so leopold knew that this was
deleterious to the longterm viability of
that ecosystem.
He took people out,
landowners out in hunters out into these
deer yards in the spring to show them
how there was nothing to eat within
reach.
Of a deer on a hind feet and there were
bodies of dead deer that it stopped
through the wintertime in order to
demonstrate to them the consequences of
mismanagement if deere hurts.
So he,
he was a real proponent of showing
people the results of doing things the
wrong way and education.
So I think,
yeah,
it comes back,
it's what we're trying to do.
Not saying that,
yeah,
we're leopold in or anything like that,
but education,
getting information out,
getting accurate information out as
maybe one of the biggest things we can
do.
I think you guys did down here today.
So thank you.
Thank you for being here,
Brian.
Thank you doug for organizing that
together.
I'm really happy we got a chance to talk
and scare the shit out of me.
Thanks for the opportunity.
My pleasure.
Thank you guys.
Thank you.