Three.
Two.
One.
Okay.
Hello Jeffrey.
Hello Joe.
How you doing man?
I'm a young and handsome.
You are young and the amps.
Yes.
We all are.
If we're not dead.
I don't know what that means.
It's all good.
I'm all jet lagged.
Yeah,
it's cracking.
And how are you?
I'm a big bowl of wonderful.
You're a big bowl.
A big ball of fucking huge bowl of
wonder.
Aggressive with that statement.
I am.
I am the head.
Don't doubt me with dendrifund.
Don't doubt you.
Yeah,
it's good to see you,
man.
Good to see you too.
What's the latest,
what is the latest,
uh,
about to start another season of the
Goldbergs,
another season of curb after working
with the fabulous Brian Cowen.
I love working with Bryan County.
He makes me laugh all the time.
It's here later.
He's going to guess a two o'clock.
Oh,
so then I'll see him or three.
Yeah,
maybe not.
But Anyhow,
point being is I dig Brian callen very
much.
And he likes you too.
Yeah.
That's cool.
That's cool man.
What's the latest,
uh,
with the,
the standup career?
Uh,
see you around the store a lot at the
store.
On occasion.
I don't do the store that much anymore
because I've stopped doing showcase
spots for the most part.
I just do,
I have a regular show every Friday night
at the Improv in the lab and I do,
you know,
an hour,
hour and 10 minutes.
And then occasionally I do flappers,
which is a horrible name yet in Burbank,
but they'll look club but a great room.
A great room.
Yeah.
And I do there on occasion on Sunday
nights.
So I do an hour,
uh,
going out of the House for 15,
20 minutes.
Not Worth my time.
Does it,
um,
do you,
when you do like an hour set,
do you plan your sets out or do you have
like some material that you'd like to be
working on in?
Is that why you like the freedom of
having an hour or so you could just kind
of fuck around?
I have no preparation whatsoever,
except I may think,
oh,
I'll talk about that tonight,
but I have no preparation.
It may bring up a story I've told
before,
but I have no idea.
Literally when I step on stage,
I have no idea what I'm going to talk
about,
what does help me,
what I've done for quite a while now as
I come up to a different song every time
I come up and then I just talk about
that song,
the story of the making of that song,
who sang that song,
what that song means to me and that will
usually lead me to something.
That's all I need.
Yeah.
The reason why I asked is you have a
very unusual style,
like I've seen you a bunch of times at
the store,
very loose,
very loose.
It's a great thing because you have the
confidence to do that.
Like a lot of people have to be like
super rigid and their preparation
without a doubt.
Yeah.
Same thing.
Set up punchline in the correct order
every night.
I'm only confident in the fact that I'm
funny.
I am not competent.
And any other fact in terms of going on
stage that's going to support it is the
most important.
And so I go up with the knowledge that
no matter goes down.
I am funny and we'll be funny.
Boom.
That's it.
Goodnight.
And Are you doing the road at all?
Hardly ever.
When I do the road it's,
I did London in December,
that a couple of weeks of shows a week,
a couple of weeks at a theater there.
What they did.
Oh,
theater.
It's a small cool theater.
That's like 500 seats or something.
I don't even know.
I don't even pay attention.
How's that?
I've done that.
I've done uh,
leister square.
Have done a couple of different of
squares.
Good.
Yeah,
I just,
I got to London,
I go to New York on occasion and
perform.
I use,
I played everywhere.
I played everywhere from Indianapolis to
Seattle to Miami,
like an all points in between,
you know,
um,
Tucson,
uh,
you know,
Phoenix,
I mean,
like all over.
I've done it.
I'm,
I'm 56 years old.
I've got two TV shows,
I develop a bunch of other stuff.
I'm passionate about my stand up,
I get enough,
I don't know if they earn a living by
going on the road,
which I have had to in the past.
So I stay home and do my standup when I
can,
which is every Friday for sure.
Because the thing is it's a very nice
and I've worked towards that and that's
a beautiful thing to work towards
because the thing that does get you is
that travel.
Oh you know it was the thing that no one
understands is the only joy that you can
possibly get when you travel is the
moment when you're on stage.
And if that's troublesome or not fun,
it's a drag.
It's depressing.
But those moments on stage,
if they're great,
it's all worth it.
Yeah,
no,
it's the thing that also when you go on
the road,
if you have to do morning radio,
that's your health.
It screws up your time.
You know what time you go to bed.
Cause I,
I like to set,
I don't worry as much on a consistent
basis what time I wake up cause that'll
automatic b automatic.
I tried consistently to go to bed at the
same time every night.
It's a different approach that a
psychiatrist told me and it has worked
wonders for me.
A psychiatrist told you yeah,
that it's bad because everyone always
focuses on waking up the same time every
day.
He said focus on going to bed at the
same time every night and that'll be
more productive for you.
And I do that with a sort of a half hour
bump to fall asleep to maybe read for a
minute,
whatever.
But I'm in bed usually by 10 I've never
gone to a psychiatrist,
but a one,
one of the shows that it was on,
I was like the only person on the set
that didn't go to a psychiatrist.
And I'm like,
maybe I'm fucked up.
No,
by the way,
if you're functioning in the world,
that's great.
Congratulations.
I have sometimes trouble functioning in
the world.
How's,
and,
and a well,
it's like I find going on stage,
I'm fearless and I don't even like
leaving my house.
I prefer to stay home.
I love napping.
Oh,
do I love napping?
If I could smoke some endeca and take a
nap every day.
I do transcendental meditation.
I do all the chill things at home and I
leave to work.
I don't like going to parties.
I like a good dinner party because that
means I can have an actual conversation
with someone.
But I was just at a party the other
night,
a goodbye party for a friend of mine.
It was a Jeff Ross House and I had the
worst time.
I lasted 20 minutes.
The only people I could talk to where
Comedians I there were looking to be a
Jeff Ross,
his party,
but comedian,
some people with man buns in the hot
tub.
It was very unsettling and wrong.
I wanted nothing to do with it.
I said my goodbyes to my friend and uh,
uh,
she's moving to Japan.
So I um,
I uh,
said my goodbyes,
but I was out of respect to her that I
went,
but out of respect to myself,
I didn't stay long man buns in a hot tub
because we never see combination in a
hot tub.
You Go,
I don't belong here.
You don't belong there.
Yeah,
I can't be done.
No,
it's bad.
When did that start happening?
When did the man bun stones to me like
in a big way a couple of years ago and
was like Samurais and then there was a
big dropoff for a long time and then a
big drop off.
That's exactly it.
I don't get it.
Maybe why grow your hair long if you're
going to wear a man bun?
I think either lawyer,
you have the idea,
but it's ridiculous.
I was at a gas station in studio city
and I was seconds away from talking to
this dude.
He had a man bond that looked like a
bird's nest with Kaitlyn with a
waterfall on the outside and I just
went,
why?
I just want to pass him.
I go on being totally friendly.
I want to make this a conversation.
Why explain?
I don't get it.
I feel like what it is is it's like
they're,
they're letting you know that this is me
when I'm out,
but when I'm at home and I'm feeling
sexy,
I just undo that and let it down.
I don't know what it is.
I just relax and I unwrapped the big
ball,
the wrong.
It's a big bouldering and no,
you're not sexy,
Douchey,
douchey.
Just what's your hair's ever been mine.
I had like a Jew fro type festival
happening when I was younger.
Like longer curly,
but not like shoulder length.
No,
it's ridiculous.
It's weird that hair grows that long.
Only on your head.
That's what's weird.
Rocker arm and you're grown like Robert
Plant's had cool hair.
Like,
go for it.
Don't man bun it.
Yeah,
go for it.
I'm all for long hair.
Rockers of different rules.
I saw a guy last night,
a bay in a band,
a bass player,
a big man bun.
Big baller wrong.
You know what?
I'm uncomfortable with a cel haircut in
a rock band.
Oh,
what are you doing with that fucking
button down conservative haircut?
I dig the play in a band.
I think playing against type is a big
bullet.
Delightful.
Nah,
not Angela.
We differ on this one.
Yes we did.
I think a group of men,
like I thought David Bowie's band,
tin machine.
I didn't really dig their music,
but I love the look of all of them
wearing the suits with the close cropped
hair.
Well Bowie's so odd and so undeniably
creative that he was allowed to get away
with anything and he's allowed to do
anything he wants.
But,
but truthfully,
if you have any sort of a confidence you
can except the man bun.
There it is right here.
There it is.
History of Bowie's.
Yeah,
but that there should have cut his hair
short.
The one with the long hair maybe,
but he's Kinda John Travolta and he cut
it short.
Here is the pressure from the other
three guys got to be too much at tired
of buying shampoo and all that bullshit.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The upkeep is ridiculous.
Outrageous.
Do to condition their hair.
And they have to leave it in for 10
minutes.
Oh,
that's a big bowl of,
come on man.
Come on Bro.
Yeah,
but for something,
there's some reason why it is okay in a
band,
but it's not okay for comic like a comic
with long like led Zepplin here because
you know what happens when a comic does
that.
Their whole act becomes about it and
it's like,
dude,
that's just boring.
You remember Jackson Purdue?
I do remember Jackson.
Pretty crazy long hair.
Like a band guy.
A lot of material about his hair.
He did.
I know I just,
you know,
I used to,
when I was younger I went for the
obvious,
I did a lot of material about having a
big head.
Ah,
now it's of no interest to me.
You couldn't also do like the Robert
Plant shirt thing either.
I have,
I have a Robert Plant shirt but not him
or like let it open now.
I think it's called nurses do it better
or nurses and some of nursing on its
powder blue.
Uh,
he wore it on one of the zipline tours
in the early seventies,
and I saw it for sale on Amazon and I
bought one.
It doesn't give off the same pie.
Yeah.
It's different with different people,
right?
Yeah.
But I always,
one of my non sequiturs to tell people
all the time is,
you love the nursing industry.
I just said to people,
hey,
you know what you love?
You love the nursing industry.
I've said that to nurses.
They say people just chuckle.
They don't know how to make,
what are,
they don't know.
You know?
Nonsequitors laughter,
nervous laughter is a certain things or
certain looks that came and went and
people tried to bring back.
Like,
do you remember a few years back they
were trying to bring back bell bottoms?
No.
Yes.
That's how much of a failure it was.
Bill Mary was actually photographed a
couple of days ago at a golf course with
some fabulous bell bottoms.
You see?
That's delightful because it's so wrong
that it's beautiful and perfect.
Bill Murray picture look at them.
Oh,
see that.
It's a big ball.
He's so fun that dude,
and he's wonderful.
He is just,
he is so fun.
Look at him.
Rang up South Carolina.
I think it's because of his kids.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
I think it was a family thing.
Oh,
he's a,
a beautiful shot Bourdain's show.
And uh,
bordain interviewed him in his small
town where he lives and it's like,
wow,
look at this guy.
Just kinda hanging out,
being normal.
No girlfriend,
no wife,
just,
just being himself.
Now he doesn't have a girlfriend or he
was talking to him.
It.
Oh,
he was talking about,
yeah.
I don't think he was talking about on
that show was talking about in an
interview and he just doesn't want to do
it anymore.
Please leave me alone.
Leave me alone.
Stop.
Delightful.
That's why I liked staying home.
It's nice.
As a matter of fact,
at the end of my shows,
I always thank the audience for actually
leaving their homes to come see me
because I know what an effort that is,
and I'm so appreciative of it.
So you're just a homebody type
character.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
it's like my life was extraordinary,
so I want to live an ordinary,
ordinary life as I can.
That makes sense.
You know,
just calm.
It doesn't have to be ordinary down
chilling man.
Yeah.
You need that,
right?
Yeah,
I chaos.
I'm not big shows.
Like tonight I'm going to an opening of
a movie.
My friend wrote it and you know.
Yeah.
Prepare yourself for it.
Here we go.
I'll be cool with it.
Like if I know I'm doing it and why I'm
doing it,
I do it.
You know we saw party whose party?
Jeff Ross,
but you know,
I'd go to a dinner party if he had one.
Again,
I'm,
I'm done though with the Jeff Ross
parties.
Jeff at all was a lot of parts.
I know I love Jeff Ross,
but I am not going to anymore of his
parties.
Tell him I'll go by myself.
There was house,
I did have them put two hands on his
shoulders.
Tell him you love him,
but the way I will,
I'm going to talk to him about the man
bun in the pool or like who?
Who are you friends with it as a man?
He's a producer,
bro.
He's helping me with a project.
He didn't look like a producer.
Just snap the shoulders go,
I love you.
I can't come to your fucking pool
parties anymore,
Bro.
Yeah.
Well it wasn't even a pool party.
That was a thing.
Somebody went,
I'm going to bring my suit
and getting the pool and he got in the
pool with these two other people.
I didn't even really notice that man.
But that's unfortunate.
If it's not a pool party and you decide
to get in the pool,
that's always awkward as fuck.
I just didn't belong.
Yeah.
You gotta be like a really comfortable
person to take off your clothes when
everybody else has theirs.
Only.
I'm pro naked.
Good for you.
I mean for me,
I'm all comfortable.
Well,
you're fit.
The fact that I'm prone to the kid,
you're angry at me.
No.
By the way,
I saw your little festival here.
You're really,
your passions are comedy and fitness.
That's one thing.
Let's,
yeah,
it's one thing hard.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm just an American Werewolf in London.
That's the thing.
In the middle of the day,
I recognize that.
I love that movie,
but that's when he was in,
uh,
Trafalgar Square.
Yes.
I remember that moment of scary.
I'm not happy unless I'm a exercising.
I've tried both ways.
Not Happy unless I'm napping.
So we both have our ways about us.
Yeah.
Well everybody's bodies by the way.
But I do exercise.
I eat well.
I eat gluten free,
I eat dairy free and I eat sugar free.
That's awesome.
That's a good combination.
Yeah.
And I aspire to be more of a vegetarian,
but I'm not obsessed with it.
Do you read books on nutrition?
I have read many books on nutrition.
Yes.
Some that Brian Cowen even recommended
to me once.
Uh,
I couldn't think of the name I probably
have and where they want to know.
Ryan counts a big recommender books.
Kindle.
Hold on,
I'll tell you what he recommended and
they were good.
I like,
you know,
every one of those kind of books,
even if they're not well written or
whatever.
I learned something from,
I picked him.
I read uh,
a ton.
That's what I do when I'm at home.
I read a lot.
I listened to albums and I read music
and a,
a platelet Tasi albums.
Do you have like a record player?
I have a record player and I have a
thousand albums.
Okay.
Wow.
I'm one of those good thousand albums,
right?
About a thousand.
Holy Shit.
Yeah,
I enjoy it.
Do you have like a room that you go to
and you know,
I'm going to,
I'm moving into a new house which will
be able to,
a specific room that I will go into
districtly play guitar and listened to
analog watches.
Yeah.
If you,
uh,
do you know Henry Rollins at all?
I do know Henry rounds.
Great friends.
I mean,
but I do know him.
He's an acquaintance of mine.
He's a fascinating guy.
Good man.
Very good dude.
Very inspirational guy to inspires me.
I dig him.
I did an interview with them at Largo.
Dig Him big time.
He's got these crazy quarter million
dollar speakers in his house.
You know like there's this speaker room.
Yeah,
you look at this,
this is the room is all these albums and
those,
those gigantic things.
That dude on the right I think as Robert
Hilburn who was the critic for the La
Times.
That's how much I do music.
I think that's Robert Hilburn.
I'm pretty sure.
So Henry gets it.
Henry who obviously became famous,
very Johnny Cash.
He wrote the Great Johnny Cash Book that
came out of here.
It's cause,
cause I saw you dig Johnny Cash by the
pictures on the wall.
I love Johnny Cash.
I had a dog named Johnny Cash just died
recently.
Unfortunately.
My granddaughter's name is Johnny Kin.
That those still speakers are fucking
crazy.
Look at these speakers he's got,
yeah,
I just got new speakers and they were
like 8,000 for a pair and I thought I
was nuts.
Look at the size of that.
That's ridiculous.
That's like who underground.
It says like 2001 a space odyssey
looking speakers.
I want to go over his house,
but I don't want to ask.
I don't want to be like henry,
come on Bro.
Let me call your house.
I don't want to be that weird guy.
I'm looking for the day of voids cause I
know I downloaded them.
I didn't want to own them.
But how many people do you think owns
those speakers?
I mean,
I thought yesterday,
but that person,
if you have to be wealthy
or that's where you want to put your
money,
click on the yellow one that you just,
what's that?
Oh,
that's the same speaker except in
yellow.
Those are a big ballroom because they
look like plumbing supplies.
Do.
They don't look good.
I don't think they look,
oh,
I think they look good.
I think they look futuristic again.
So here we go.
Why we get fat.
I was that by on,
I can't remember the guy's name,
why we get fat and the four hour body.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
Tonight.
It's embarrassed and I learned stuff
from both,
but I'm,
so I learned stuff about nutrition and
stuff and I'm in my,
at my most,
I was three 20 and I'm currently in the
two forties that's nine.
I'm making the transition now to
hopefully low to 30 somewhere in that
two twenties and then building up muscle
and I'll never be fit like you.
And I'm not,
I'm,
that's,
I'm not saying that to insult myself in
terms of like,
you know,
but you,
this is a passion of yours.
It's not a passion of mine.
I just want to live life at a higher
level and a better level.
So I feel good.
I want to feel great and I already do.
So if I can improve on this,
delightful,
the big things,
cutting carbohydrates,
most people eat far too much for me.
That's where the gluten and the sugar
came from and the dairy.
I,
and I feel good when my body not having
those things.
I react positively my,
so anything else is okay for me.
Can I exercise to do,
I do.
[inaudible] I bodies is fucking hard.
Really hard.
Yeah.
Was Great.
Polonius teacher is great.
I do,
I swim,
I work with a trainer.
I play tennis,
playing tennis.
Uh,
tomorrow morning,
today's Wednesday.
Yeah.
Tomorrow morning I'll be playing with my
tennis teacher.
I play golf,
which is not that physical.
However,
like I went,
it was at the store buying stuff the
other day,
you know,
at the golf story.
And he wasn't,
the guy was very nice guy helping me,
wanted to sell me something that I have
to bend over to get the ball.
I go,
I think that bending over and as matter
of fact,
stretching my hamstrings,
really,
I don't know the benefit I'd get from
golf if I didn't at leats bend,
he's telling you not to bend well that
they have these things so people don't
have to bend.
Well,
that's for people that are like really
bad back.
No,
no,
no.
It's for lazy people.
That's why I think a lot of people,
so for me it's a matter of pride to
bend.
If you have a bad back,
you probably can't swing either.
You can't swing a lot of you back.
Um,
but I do a lot of different things.
I love sports.
I used to play when I was younger,
I played baseball and football.
Do you ever play golf or tennis rather
with Callan cause he's a tenant's freak.
No,
I should actually,
by the way,
I just started again and played tennis
since I was a kid.
I'm actually going to talk to him about
that.
Hopefully we can play some.
The thing about tennis though is it's a
lot of like going left and right and
left and right and putting weird strains
and pressures on rainier.
It's,
but it's great for a bone mass.
Oh,
okay.
It's good for it.
Bone mass.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
It pushes you pushing you pushing.
I dig it
and by the way,
I'm not going to play competitive with
them.
I'm going to hit with him.
Right.
Because he could probably beat me.
Also weighs about 70 pounds less than
me.
Yes.
So he can move better.
Brian's been playing,
he's very spry.
He's his.
He takes his physical fitness very
seriously.
He doesn't tell you about it.
Oh yeah.
Listen,
I know.
Yeah.
He gets very serious about half thing.
Everything.
It gets very serious.
You know what I'm saying?
Like he's never going to get,
he's never going to like commit to being
like a professional tennis player.
Right.
It'll get pretty serious about kind of
getting into tennis.
Who needs the stress?
Yeah.
When no,
I'm saying it's like a good balance.
I guess he's,
I get obsessed about things.
He gets obsessed about kind of getting
into things,
but then it doesn't go like those
started out doing through.
Exactly.
You are a follow through fucking
motherfucking follow through.
All purchases do as a walk around here
and go or look at you.
You're a fucking specimen.
You booked her.
You're a specimen.
Just trying to stay sane.
Jess.
Right.
Do you,
are you married?
You have a girlfriend,
you're married.
Yup.
Yeah.
Your wife must appreciate that.
What the,
the,
the physical illness.
You're a good man but,
but being looking over and going,
my husband's not a fat piece of shit.
He's a fit mother fucker and I'm going
to fuck his brains out tonight.
Does she ever say that?
No,
not around me.
At least she should.
Maybe I should start bugging the house.
You Sharon.
When she says when I'm not there.
When you're not there,
I bet you that's what she says to her
friend.
He married.
Um,
I can't answer.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Okay.
I don't want to pressure you.
Don't pressure me.
That's like a,
I can't,
I can't talk about that right now.
Yeah.
That's probably good.
Transitions.
Healthy.
Yeah,
I like it.
Yeah.
Things are in flux there.
Fluxing I'm going to flux festival.
It's not bad.
Yeah,
it's,
no,
it's bad.
There's no winning.
Oh yeah.
There was no one in hand before.
I love my wife,
but I don't want to go home and I love
being alone,
but being alone blows.
So there's no winning.
There's no winning.
I'm a sad young man,
but I'm really happy cause I'm
functioning at a high level on eye
level.
I'm rising and rising up.
You know what I mean?
I'm,
I'm facing adversity had,
had,
had on,
but uh,
yeah,
my wife is a lovely woman.
Lovely woman.
Go down.
That's one of the things that are going
on the road.
You appreciate people when you come
back.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
When you're with them.
I appreciate you buddy.
Yeah.
If you're there with them every day
staring at each other.
I mean,
no,
I don't care who it is.
Could be your best friend on the planet.
Too much time with somebody except for
rare exception.
Right?
Wow.
Is that bad?
Yeah.
It can be terrible.
We terrible.
Almost everybody.
People will,
you know,
you need to be around variety in terms
of like different files.
Most of them.
By the way,
I don't stay home because I'm not like
I'm staying home because I want to avoid
experiences.
I like experiences and I'll go have an
experience,
but when I,
when I deem that experience,
like Jeff's party not good for me,
I leave.
Yeah.
But if I'm,
if I'm having an experience that's new
and I'm digging it,
I'll stay.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
Well,
you know what?
You liked?
56 years old,
man.
I know.
You're a man.
I'm a man.
I am a man.
Yeah,
man.
I'm,
I'm Jeff Garlin and actualize command.
I'm an actual,
actually,
I'm aspiring to grow all the time.
That's when,
that's my thing to be a wise man.
I aspire.
My goal is to be a wise man and I'll
never breach it.
Not that I'm be stupid,
but I'm saying it's always evolving.
I have a friend
and many,
many years ago it was at her house and
she had the sign that said enlightenment
is possible in this lifetime.
When I saw that and I went,
Whoa,
wow,
that's,
that's a deep by bobby levels and
putting you at a higher place than you
are.
I agree with but true enlightenment.
I,
I'm just Kinda,
I'm not cynical.
I'm,
I'm have more of a critical eye.
There you go.
Right.
That's possible.
I'm not saying I've never seen it,
I've not seen it,
but it's like I'm not going to deem it
impossible.
Cause then who am I and saw me saying
there's no god.
That's like me saying,
I'll tell you who killed Kennedy.
I don't know.
Right.
And it's also what exactly is
enlightenment and by whose standard by
definition was.
So maybe if you have a very low standard
for enlightenment and your reach,
whatever that level is,
you go,
I did it in my lifetime.
Look at me.
If you are,
if you're smoking,
Endeca,
listen to great music and having
fantastic sex after a great meal,
and then someone says,
no,
you're just supposed to meditate and
just sit in a room and,
and,
you know,
be mindful.
Okay.
How about fuck you?
How about a big ball of fuck you.
Yeah.
By the way,
can we make that happen for me that I
smoked some Minika listen to some music,
have some great sex after a great meal.
Totally.
It seems that this,
it can be done.
Should,
Garlin it should be done.
Yeah.
That's what a Tony says to me.
You're Jeff Garlin.
Tony Hawk.
Hinchcliffe yeah,
yeah,
he's right.
Yeah.
Well,
I,
I tend to be,
I'm confident in my comedic skills,
but he should be.
Yeah.
Funny Guy.
But outside of that,
I am not lacking in confidence,
but leaving my house is,
like I said,
uh,
quite the effort.
What I'm saying is like,
by whose definition is enlightenment?
Because like say if you wanted to go to
a concert or you wanted to go to a great
movie,
what an enlightened person.
Enjoy a great movie.
I would think my version of an
enlightened person would in fact enjoy a
great movie.
I,
I've been enlightened to the concert.
I saw James Brown when he first got out
of prison and I've found that that that
performance he gave was the most
enlightened performance I'd ever seen.
Was this when he was in the car chase,
was that that prison?
Yeah,
it was the,
what was the last prison he shot at cops
because I believe so.
Yeah.
That one was someone else used his
bathroom,
right?
Isn't that what happened?
Someone took a shit.
Don't know.
I know that he got in trouble with the
cops,
but maybe it was that,
I don't know.
There's a big difference,
but to someone using this toileting is
that he had gotten out of prison and
just the idea that James Brown was in
prison.
I think w maybe I remembering this
incorrectly,
but I think someone used his toilet and
then he got mad at that person and shot
at something like either shot the wall
or something.
I don't remember that story,
but I assume you're looking it up right
now,
so we'll find out.
I feel like he was in a high speed
chase.
They shot his tires out.
They shit.
I don't remember it this way.
Show something in a car though.
Maybe.
I'm pretty sure they shot his tires out
and he was driving around on my rims.
He had to have been doing a lot of
blowers and making that agitated.
You know what I mean?
No.
Normal Human Doug.
And we're talking about James Brown.
Is that agitated?
I mean,
who gets that?
And he was Finna fucking phenomenal.
When does he or she was young to state
chase that went up to 85 miles an hour,
involve 14 cars.
He said he didn't stop because he feared
for his life though.
I don't try to see why it started and I
don't see that.
I feel like that that's what started it.
He was,
he fired off a gun because someone used
his toilet,
by the way,
a two stage chase.
I'm guessing he lived near the border.
I probably lived in what I was wacky
states.
We live it.
We live in Georgia.
Oh,
okay.
Well maybe it's like Georgia,
Florida.
Yeah.
It could be close to each other.
Georgia,
Florida line.
It's not a band.
It is,
right.
It doesn't know.
Wheeler Walker make fun of them.
It says you've failed a,
a Beta pullover.
That's all it is.
But I'm pretty sure that's why they were
pulling them over.
I think they were going after him.
Um,
I might be wrong about that.
Maybe.
Maybe I'm confusing him with.
Okay.
Chuck Berry was the one who was filming
people go into the bathroom.
Right.
I think he liked to go in the piece like
the PM ladies,
I'm pretty sure.
Interesting.
I'm pretty sure,
interesting,
genuine.
When I enjoy James Brown's music,
I'm not thinking about his car,
thinking about his other side,
you know,
let's say that your story.
Oh,
really?
It was right.
Oh,
here it goes.
Okay.
He carrying a deadly weapon in a public
gathering and attempt to fleet perise
driving under the influence of drugs.
Okay.
He reportedly stormed into the insurance
company next to his office waiting a
shotgun and complaining.
That's trainers.
We using his bathroom as time reported
for six miles.
There you go.
Are you kidding me?
Years later this episode would frame the
2014 j brown bio pic.
Okay.
88 on up.
I'm guessing that I saw him after this
cause it was right after
that.
It would be,
uh,
it would be late eighties,
early nineties.
Jesus Christ.
He did six years.
Yeah.
He was in there for a while.
Six fucking years.
Yeah.
How about just sober him up?
He was on PCP pay.
They gave him a year for each mile.
He drove on his Mac.
Rumors of a PCP habit already surfaced
by the time his erratic behavior came to
a head in September.
Wow.
PCPS,
a tricky one.
Sang in the prison choir.
I bet he did.
Shit.
Imagine you'd go to jail for like
stealing the car and you're fucking,
sally is James Brown.
Like,
hey buddy,
what do you want to do?
Something that's a hell of a story.
Yeah.
Help him write some songs,
you know,
get on up.
Yeah.
Did you ever see,
um,
when he opened up for,
the Mohammed Ali fight with George
Foreman documentary?
Holy Shit.
Was that incredible?
That was incredible.
Yeah.
Incredible.
He had so much power.
There was something about him,
man.
He would get on deck age.
It was just power.
Give you an idea.
How much power prince wished for that
power fuck yet.
Well,
prince had it,
but he had another way,
different way.
But prince looked up yet.
Oh No.
James Brown was ridiculous and I looked
up to it.
Yeah.
I don't have any musical talent.
It just tells you what a waste all of
this was because Elvis had that power
and he didn't use it.
He had it early on and then w w he could
never dance like James Brown though.
Or if he did,
he never showed it.
It would be different.
It's a different kind of power if he
just took and harness.
Here it is.
Look at this.
Look at his dress to get an ice chest,
the fucking pants,
and they show you is God damn.
Drop it down doing splits.
I know.
No,
he was not human.
And by the way,
he,
he's not even really flexible enough to
do a full split and yet he's still
dropping down on stage.
You know,
he was wearing a turtle neck that night
and I said to him,
cut that baby out.
Let's leave a little bit.
Let's put your initials on there.
I think that that was done in advance
what the girls was hanging around with
fucking shame around.
Oh yeah,
look at these giant ass band.
I don't envy those people.
Do you know when you see people with
bands,
Torin got all those people,
all those working pieces have to fall
into place.
Yeah,
they got all that though.
but God damn would a performance.
When I saw him and I saw him,
it blew my mind.
It literally blew my mind.
Well,
what's interesting too is that,
you know,
prince who died of painkillers,
he died from fentanyl.
He blew his hips out.
Dancing like that was,
that was the thing,
you know,
and that that apparently is a very
common thing.
My friend Maynard Maynard Keenan from
tool lead Santa tool,
he just recently had his hip replaced
and he was doing,
he's,
he's big into Jujitsu,
loves Jujitsu and he was having a really
hard time doing certain things.
So I went to a doctor to see what's
going on
with his hip and they're like,
dude,
your hip is gone.
Sign.
Like it's just two hours.
He functioning at a high level.
Yeah,
yeah,
he's fine.
That's the hip replacement is one of the
most unusual ones in terms of like its
ability to restore you back to a,
a fairly normal state other than a bride
being a comedian as delightful.
And we don't have to do any of that
shit.
No,
there's no up.
And by the way,
when you see someone moving around like
that on stage,
I will bet you every penny I have,
they're not funny.
Callen moves a lot on stage.
He's very funny.
I hate as a move,
like like 20 throws kicked upstairs in
the,
in the telly room and know the Improv
upstairs.
You know that Green Room thing?
Okay.
There's a monitor on stage with a thing
and I will turn to our own weather go
funny.
Not Funny because like I can watch and
tell how,
whether the comedy is coming to them or
whether they're pushing it and most of
the move around people are pushing it.
But Jim Carrey was a move around guy.
He was always really funny,
but move around in a different sort of
way.
Characters.
Well there's exceptions to all stuff
like that.
The all things,
but in this sort of way I'm done.
But when someone just stands there and
talks and then they're doing some sort
of movement,
it's not good.
Jim Carrey,
there was a purpose,
right Brian?
It's part of who we is.
That's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about people that just
oversell shit by physicalizing.
What should be just funny the way you
say it,
not even what you're saying.
The way you say it,
Thompson or calls it dance moves it.
His dance moves thompson girls.
Right.
I'm sick.
Girl is funny.
He's a genius.
He uh,
I used to call it English putting like
English on the two bar.
Yes.
Totally unnecessary.
As is better dance moves.
Damn moves.
And that's what I'm talking about.
So Jim Carrey and Brian Cowen do not
have danced with.
Right.
They just are funny.
And they also move.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's a reason for their moving moves.
Oh,
come on man.
And you're always so funny.
Years ago,
I remember anytime I saw someone miming
having sex,
you know,
pumping air,
I would just go.
Not Funny.
No,
it was just like,
it was a sign of like,
well what if there's a bit where you
have to mime pumping,
pumping air.
There's gotta be a bit pumping air.
You mean like it's gotta be some,
yeah,
some bits.
What?
But who doesn't know what that looks
like?
Why do you need to pump?
Maybe there's a reason it's something.
Unless like you're imitating someone
having a heart attack pumping,
right.
Or you know,
if there,
if the content is about your
physicality,
that's not dancing.
Dancing's when you,
when you put like English,
like when you,
when you're doing this to accentuate
what you're saying,
it's like screw that.
We don't need that.
Well you ever go to open mic nights?
I used to do them up until recently.
Really?
I would just show up and
say,
can I go up and do 10 you know,
and,
and what was really fun was when the
person who had them didn't know who I
was.
Oh that's great.
And then I watched as other people
explained and it was cool cause I didn't
have an attitude,
you know,
and I would do my sets and the audience
has an open,
Mike nights are really,
they're terrible.
Lot of times,
yeah,
they're there to see their friends or
they're tired or whatever or they've
been beaten down by totally unfunny
shit.
Totally unfunny shit over and over and
over again.
So yes,
up until about four or five years ago,
I used to go to open my,
what's fascinating about open Mike
nights is you're watching people try to
figure out how to be funny.
Like you're watching people like,
and you go to the store like tonight and
you'll,
you'll go there.
It's going to be a packed house.
It's all Chris Delea and fucking Andrew
Santina.
No and Allie Wong,
it's all killers.
You know,
and you,
you're seeing high level comedy over and
over again.
And so you get you into that vibe and
you're like,
oh this is a great place to be.
But if you go to an open mic night,
you're seeing this like primordial ooze.
You're seeing single celled organisms,
things that you really shouldn't be
seeing sometimes.
You know,
because every now and then you see a
little,
I explained to people,
get as much state when you start,
get as much stage time as you can
without people seeing you.
That's good too.
That's very good advice.
But you need to go on stage over and
over and over again.
But don't go on stage at any popular
places.
Go onstage at the suckiest cause you
only learn from when you suck.
That's a big part of it for sure.
That's why I really admired,
uh,
Charlie Murphy.
Cause Charlie Murphy was essentially a
famous open miker and well when he
started mean when he started,
he'd never done standup comedy ever.
And then he was just a really funny
actor who is the brother of one of the
greatest comics of all time who got on
the Chappelle show and then started
doing stand up.
And you know,
Charlie would just just fucking do it.
Just go and do it.
And you know,
he had some rough sets too when he was
famous,
like really famous.
Are you think when I did,
did those things that I didn't eat it
plenty of times open mike nights
everybody.
But,
but what I had was I was in control of
myself and it didn't fall apart.
Right.
If you're an amateur would fall apart.
Yeah,
it does.
It doesn't mean I did well,
but of course I remember,
I remember one time dice came into the
store,
this is probably four or five years ago,
maybe five years ago.
And uh,
he came up to me,
goes,
oh,
go up after you,
you know,
it was very respectful,
very nice.
And I said,
no,
I really want to follow you.
I want to see what that's like.
I've never followed you.
Please go up there and go for broke.
Go for fucking broke.
How long are you doing?
He goes,
oh,
maybe a half hour.
I go,
great.
Go up there for a half hour.
I've got nowhere to be.
I'm going to watch and the I want you to
just to fucking hold nothing back.
And then I went up after him.
You know how I did fine,
didn't do good,
didn't do fine
because I knew how to handle myself,
my professionalism,
the craft of what I know one out,
but there's no following that with what
I do,
which is totally different.
And having the audience go,
oh,
this takes it to a whole new place.
No.
Did you ever listen to the day the
laughter died?
Rick Rubin's with them.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Fucking phenomenal.
Great album.
Just eating shit,
right.
Chill hours.
He showed up at danger fields for people
who don't know.
It's literally,
I will never forget,
I was just starting out.
I think he did this look this up when
that was,
I want to say it was like 1989 1990 no,
it was after that.
It was fairly early.
It was fairly early because I was very
young in my career.
It might've been then cause I was still
living in Boston.
No,
no,
it might've been then because 89 yeah,
because I was thinking about me living
here now,
but it was the,
it had came out the first time I lived
here.
Well I was living in Boston and I was
just starting out and there was a great
comedian named Mike Donovan who to this
day,
he's one of the funniest guys I've ever
seen in my life.
And uh,
Mike Donovan was laughing to the point
where he couldn't breathe at dice doing
this set while he was doing fucking
stadiums.
I mean dice was doing enormous Nassau
Coliseum.
What's in the bowl,
bitch?
Oh,
20,000 people.
He was the biggest comedian of all time
and he just decides to show up at danger
fields in New York city randomly.
And I'll come Monday and a Tuesday
night.
It doesn't tell anybody he's going to be
there.
I mean there's 1320 people in the crowd.
He records two different sets and he has
no material.
I mean fucking none.
He's making things up as he goes along
and people are getting angry at him and
they're walking out and he did a bit
about Richard Nixon about how he eats
ass and when he eats ass he does it like
Richard Nixon.
He was like,
Oh,
I love this fucking house.
He was doing this Richard Nixon
impression of eating ass and for
whatever reason Mike Dunn,
Vin thought it was the funniest thing
he'd ever seen in his life.
He was wheezing,
like couldn't breathe,
talking about dice doing this impression
and I was like,
wow,
this is like comedy for Comedians.
But for the people that were in the
audience,
like a guy got up,
he goes,
you're about as funny as our glass of
milk.
The Guy said that to him and then left.
That's one of the best things when the
album,
these people from like Kansas getting
your about.
It's funny,
as our class on milk and walking off and
dice shitting on them,
but the two to have them mindset to be
at the,
not just the top of his game but
literally the top of standup ever.
No one before him had ever sold out
Madison Square Garden multiple nights in
a row the way he did.
I mean guys have done it since then.
You know,
Dane and Louis and this been a bunch of
guys who've Aziz,
but no one did it like he did then.
He was the first ever to do that and to
do that and then to record these fucking
awful sets and then put it,
uh,
we'll go on a fucking pool.
I guaranteed that was Rick Ruben's
ideas.
Do you think so?
Without a doubt.
But you know,
dice,
and I know Rick Rubin.
I bet it was both of their ideas.
Well maybe he didn't fight Rick Rubin up
to ask Rick Ruben next time I see him.
Yeah,
asked,
never asked him that.
But that sounds to me like Rick Rubin
going,
let's do this.
Interesting.
Yeah.
But it was such a crazy bold move.
I remember thinking at the time,
because I was terrible in 1989 when it
came out and I was just like confused.
Like how does one do that?
Like one is so confident they release
something that suck.
Cause I had as,
I was a,
when I was 19,
it was me and my girlfriend,
Mark De mi and Marta were sitting in my
car and I had a cassette player and
we're listening to dice.
It was just called dice and w crying,
laughing,
crying,
laughing.
It was before I'd ever done standup.
And I remember thinking,
Wow,
this guy is fucking something.
Like what,
what?
Like the,
the,
the amount of power that he had like on
stage.
And these are the roars from the crowd
and we're sitting in my car laughing our
asses off to this seat.
This cassette wasn't even cd.
Um,
that couple years later he decided I'm
just going to put out something that's
sucks.
The day the comedy died.
Did they?
Laughter died.
Yeah.
And he's got like one of them fucking
paper Boi hats on the cover.
Oh,
it's a,
it's a little old man boy.
And there's the little picture of him on
there.
Is that what it is?
I can,
yeah.
Small picture I think or maybe it's a
big picture of him.
There it is right there.
I remember was the big picture.
We should get a Oh yeah.
So,
so,
but is small in comparison to the actual
CD?
Yeah.
See if we can get Jamie.
Um,
let's get a framed copy of that and put
it on the wall somewhere.
Is it released as an album?
I Dunno.
Guarantee Image.
I guarantee there's vinyl guaranteed.
Let's get,
find it.
See if we could buy it.
And Vinyl,
look on Ebay right now for the day they
did it again.
Get it three years later.
I've seen him do that at the store.
I've seen them go up late night at the
store.
I'm like,
look,
good.
You look at you over there and just
start talking shit to people like mean.
What does he wear?
Weightlifting gloves whenever.
He wasn't like touching people's hands.
Is that what it is?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And Big Jay oakerson whereas
weightlifting gloves in Oman.
He does.
Yeah.
That's great.
I was trying to get the two of them
together in a podcast,
but scheduling wise,
it never really worked out.
Shaking the photo on the final,
Oh,
for 400 bucks on Amazon.
by that shit.
No,
no.
We're going to frame hundred bucks.
I'll go to dice.
He might have it.
Yeah.
Guarantees.
Got It.
Hey,
yeah.
You're pay for lunch.
I'll give you the,
the,
the album.
Have you ever seen his instagram?
You a go to dices instagram?
No,
it's hilarious.
It's just so random.
It's like an older rich,
famous guy who does whatever the fuck he
wants.
Opposed to had coffee or lunch with them
a million times.
I had never had.
It's one of those things never happen.
Yeah.
He,
um,
instagram is him like Wa with a Gold's
gym tee shirt on with crazy sunglasses
and he'll do like these little sketches,
but there's so random and weird like him
talking to a girl,
like maybe we should do something later
in the girl's like,
okay,
like click on this,
play this.
This is like his,
this is his whole thing.
I was thinking about it.
We should do that.
Can you cook dinner for her?
Here's the question.
What are you,
what's your name?
Nicole.
All right.
I'll call.
I'll call you.
I've got to go and take care.
Oh,
it's the end of it.
Afterwards he goes,
he's got another one,
a followup when he gets mad at himself
for not doing anything about it.
Like go to the next video.
Yeah.
That's cited.
There's another there.
Play this way.
What a beautiful night.
Huh?
Beautiful.
It's,
it's just this little beautiful night.
Eleanor Carrigan.
Yeah,
they're so random.
The videos or I guess the text in that
video was like,
I should've done something was wrong
with me.
Yeah,
it's,
but this is him.
Why did I leave?
I'm so dumb.
But they're so random.
It's like,
what is he doing?
He's just been dice.
He used to do that at the store.
He used to have comics do these little
sketches is,
okay,
you're going to run through the door
there and you're going to knock him over
and you're going to go,
what the fuck?
Okay,
go.
And the guy would do it and you run into
the door and knock the other guy over
and go,
what the fuck up?
Perfect.
Do it again.
And he would just,
he would just film,
this was like vhs tape,
you know,
I go old school one and then he would
edit it together himself,
but he did nothing with it.
And this was like dice was giant,
just fucking top of the world giant.
And this is what he's doing to amuse
himself.
The comics would just do it.
Oh Jesus Christ.
You're just so happy.
Dice is talking to you.
He's the reason why I started doing the
road.
I would just do the store all the time.
It was constant.
The store.
One time were in the bag goes,
it's funny,
you know you should do the row.
I go,
yeah.
He goes,
hey,
he goes,
you don't want to rely on these fucking
assholes for money.
He goes,
you could fucking do whatever you want.
Go through road.
I was like yeah,
why don't I do the road cause I was just
doing tv shows and then you know,
do you do on TV shows?
You kind of trapped in this,
this is how you make your living.
You got to kind of always be acting and
always be going on auditions.
I was like yeah I was cause I wasn't
making,
you don't make real money at the store.
You make like 15 bucks a set or whatever
you make.
You know I,
I've spent one year I'd ever collected a
check and then they'd ever had them
again at the store.
Yeah.
I probably,
I'm guessing that the number of sets I
did probably about $2,500 $5,000
probably donated.
Donate it back to the club.
Yeah.
Tony hit it back to the clubs and not
donated to any charity by on behalf of
the store.
Yeah.
No,
not a charity.
You're donating to the charity of the
store.
I don't care.
Yeah,
that's good.
Good.
Good donation.
Yeah,
that's a,
a place is a fascinating place really.
I was gone for seven years and you know,
I've been back for four now and it's,
uh,
it is,
I love the original room.
Oh,
it's incredible.
It's the room that's got it going.
The main wildlife,
all three.
I don't,
they're all different.
The belly rooms.
Okay.
And the main room,
Eric,
by the way,
the main room performing in the main
room does not bother me.
I hate it.
The green room really hate it.
Why?
No cane piano in the middle of the room
and the best piano.
Oh yeah.
The point being is most of those people,
I don't want to see,
oh,
hey around back there.
Yeah.
They just steer it.
I know.
There's just such a negative vibe.
I think that there's a lot of comedians
at play there that are a big bowl of
dead weight.
Wow.
Yeah.
But there's a lot on the names,
but Baba,
if there's a lot that are joyful and
great,
and I dig and I like watching and my
favorite thing to do is laugh at my
fellow Comedians,
but on the flip side,
some people just,
man,
they're there.
Their presence just depresses me.
Interesting.
Yeah.
I don't feel that.
Okay.
Maybe do an impression of
just mimed my,
no,
no.
But some really,
I think,
yeah,
because you know the thing,
when I started in comedy,
which is 82 working through comedians,
really,
we're a group that stuck together.
You don't think that's the case now?
No.
I think that bridge,
I think for the past,
I think it started changing in late
nineties two thousands to where it was
every man for himself and a lot of
people,
it wasn't like,
you're part of this fraternity.
It was like,
fuck you,
I'm going to do this.
You know?
My thing with competition is I go do
your thing.
If the audience digs you more,
great.
If I'm auditioning and you're
auditioning,
go beat me in the room.
I don't give a crap,
but there's such a competitiveness.
And I know that's part of why Eddie
doesn't do spots because Eddie Murphy,
Eddie Murphy,
because when I work with them,
I would say,
why don't you go?
He,
he'd say,
the,
the looks that I get and the vibe that I
get from comics,
it's not pleasant.
And I go,
I know exactly what he was talking
about.
That's so weird.
I have the exact opposite feeling about
comedy now and about a particular,
like the store and like the comradery of
that place.
I don't,
I don't get it,
by the way.
I dig a lot of people there,
but the people who I dig know I dig them
right.
And I,
and the other one,
so I don't dig,
don't know anything.
It's not like I spent hours,
but there's lots of guys and gals that
are great,
but so plenty of them that like please
step away.
I was just having a conversation about
this with a friend of mine recently who
was living for a while and the place
that he hated.
And he was saying that if you're in a
place where everyone's negative,
you really kind of forget that people
can be positive without a doubt.
Yeah.
So why should I leave the comedy store
and at least half of the Times I play,
they're leaving.
They're driving home feeling like not
positive.
That's so weird.
Whereas by the way,
I sometimes now arrange it.
The only set that I do at the comedy
store now is I sometimes will close the
seven o'clock original room show.
Uh,
cause there's no one after me.
So if I'm five minutes long,
no one's giving you crap.
Right.
And they've already seen the whole show.
There's no it just,
and I can do that zip and do it and get
the hell out.
I'll do a benefit in the,
in the main room or like I did,
uh,
Tony Show,
right.
Killed Tony killed.
Yeah.
We're gonna bring into the fold Jeff
Garlin bring wedding to the fitting you
into the fold of the nice people.
By the way,
I know the Nice,
we have nice conversations with him,
but the other people are always,
they're hovering hangovers.
I don't like I'll go,
I don't like a hover over is a stopover.
And Ted is brutal when you're having a
good conversation and if you're not into
a group,
if your group is not about making
people,
like,
I don't care whether your political,
social,
w w how you do your comedy.
But if your ultimate goal isn't to bring
joy into peoples lives,
what's the purpose?
If it's not about the laughs and joy.
And so I find,
here's the thing,
I don't dig lot of ego running around
the store when I'm there.
And most of the people I don't like have
the biggest egos.
Do you think that the most common you
because you're a very accomplished guy,
so maybe that's why you're getting that
weird vibe.
Okay.
I've been told that before,
but if I thought that that would be
weird.
So I don't maybe,
well that's cause you know,
there's a great line,
I'm not an,
I'm not an alcoholic,
but I do know this line from the
program,
which is what you think of me is none of
my business,
which I love.
That's a great perspective.
Great perspective.
So what they think of me is none of my
business,
I just know what they're putting out
there.
That's all.
Yeah.
I think sometimes people will look at
you and go,
well here's a guy who has been on
some of the all time greatest television
shows ever.
You know,
your,
your guy that's got a massive,
like your,
your,
your resume,
your accomplishments as a comic and
performers.
It's very enviable.
So maybe perhaps a city like this myself
as a generous guy,
I'm every level.
I like being generous and I like helping
comics,
you know,
sticking my hand out,
doing what I can to help.
So I don't feel that I put anything that
they should be fearful of out.
No,
but I think it's their own issue.
I mean I remember when I was yes,
but I was starting out.
I would get real uncomfortable when I
was around really famous people,
I'd be like,
wow,
this feels weird to be around this guy
in real life.
I mean I get that.
That can be you.
You've always been very,
very friendly.
That's what I want to do.
I like to be a warm,
thoughtful person who most of the time
prefers to stay at home.
If I'm going to go out,
if I'm going to go to the farmer's
market,
if I'm going to go to the comedy store,
I'm prepared to talk to people,
take pictures of people,
be warmed to people,
engage with people.
Cause if I don't want that,
I stay home.
Right?
And so if I'm in a negative,
bad mood,
um,
I really will go do my set and get out.
But that doesn't happen very often.
But I'll stay home.
Yeah.
That's why you need that downtime,
right?
Cause you gotta be able to recharge.
Gotta be able to recharge.
And I never,
I used to not allow myself that I used
to be worked so hard.
I was reading this article yesterday
about Tom Cruise,
about Tom Cruise's life being very
strange.
Jesus Christ,
Jeff Garland has going on with your
phone.
What was that?
My brother Ringer.
What does that,
it's a theme to a man and a woman,
but a Duh,
Duh,
Duh.
Do,
do,
do no.
When a man and a woman is,
I thought it's a French movie.
She's,
but hold on a second here.
How am I supposed to know that?
But actually I actually sing that with,
you know jeff who plays piano in the
Jeff,
not Jeff,
Richard,
Chuck Scott,
Scott.
He and I,
I'll start,
I'll look at them and I'll go,
I'm not singing tonight.
And the audience,
most of the time goes,
ah,
it's if I'm known for a second,
which I make fun of them done in the
middle of the show,
I'll just look at them and go,
you're Jones said Johnson,
Lyndon more sentimental alone.
Joan said,
and I sing.
And then when I'm done,
I tell the audience that I'm in a very
accomplished at French jibberish,
which is what it is.
Um,
but yeah,
it's a great song.
So do you have custom ringtones for
different people call you?
Oh,
I just have the one and Julian my
ringer's off,
which is off now last thing,
I was listening to his buddy guy.
Those is alive and well,
but he guys' newest album,
he's a,
I think about to turn 82 I'm going to go
to Chicago for clear out the new album
and just put that too.
And it's a bad ass album.
Of course it is.
Oh,
he rips it the whole hour.
He said magazines,
but that inspires me to still,
by the way,
everything about aging is about
relevancy.
How are you contributing?
Right.
Like George Carlin,
no one would care.
The George Cardinal was,
doesn't matter.
75 or whatever it was.
Doesn't matter.
He's relevant.
He's tripping Ireland.
That's what I aspire to.
Relevancy to contribute to mankind,
to my art,
to everything.
So I'll never be like,
you know,
if someone says who's that old dude and
I'm not doing anything based on what I'm
aspiring to do,
that's their issue.
Right,
right.
You know,
because I will be to my best ability.
Relevant.
That's an interesting perspective
because it's really true,
but it's something that people don't
think about.
You know?
It's like,
like rock stars in particular,
like no one looks at Mick Jagger and go,
why is that guy still doing it?
Because when you watch him do it,
you're like,
oh Jesus,
he's still doing it.
He's still doing it.
He's like,
yes.
Watching them live is ridiculous by the
way.
He really moves.
No kidding around like at the oldest 30
no,
he looks phenomenal.
He's ridiculous.
And he's 70 70 something still shooting
loads into hot models.
He had a baby recently.
That's my stage name by that is it?
That's my band.
How do you have that state name?
And that's my band's name.
I didn't license it though,
so I'll give it back to you.
I put my apologies.
Bruce springsteen's another one
springsteen's in his sixties I saw that
show.
I saw that show and I,
my jaw was on the floor.
I could not believe that's Broadway show
Broadway show.
It was one of the greatest things I've
ever seen before.
He turns to Morrow,
Jesus Christ.
And he works out,
I believe twice a day.
Every day.
Does he really?
He does yoga and he trains with weights
and see if he could find Mick Jagger
shirtless.
Uh,
as an other as cotton.
Yeah.
But I mean like recent,
right.
Well then I would go to tools,
go to tools to the right and,
and then go to uh,
yeah.
Time.
Yeah.
There we go.
I know.
Say right recent.
See if he can find a recent one.
There's a lot of pictures of him on his
clothes off Jesus Christ.
Put a fucking shirt on.
A hot model.
He's a interesting man.
That's why I say to you,
there's always exception there.
Far Right.
What do you got there?
That's a model.
Oh,
that's not Mick Jagger.
You son of a bitch.
That's him at 40 with the beard.
I know that for sure.
So that's the oldest one I seen.
Okay.
Well either way the guy,
he's what is movements or what's amazing
is voice as not.
I think it's still amazing and the way
he moves.
Yeah.
It's so fluid.
It's so beautiful.
He does a lot of yoga.
I'm pretty sure Google is workout.
Mick Jagger's workout cause um,
he's incredibly disciplined apparently.
And then look up,
uh,
Barnaby Jones reunion.
Oh,
just out of curiosity.
Common
look at him.
Look at that right there.
Takes up yoga at 73.
There you go.
I was already did.
Yeah.
Oh I should.
Oh,
it takes up aerial yoga.
I guess you're doing it on the ground.
It didn't work for him enough anymore.
Need to take it to a new level.
That's just ridiculous.
Yeah.
Incredible.
Mick Jagger at Diet and exercise
program.
Live long,
long stay young.
What if he only eats peppers?
I was just in Thailand.
And um,
when you go to the bathroom right by the
toilet,
they literally have one of those garden
hoses that you would wash a car with.
Play with big days.
Because with those peppers,
are you eating that Thai food?
Like this kind of splatter that you're
creating that like let's just,
let's be honest.
Toilet paper is not good enough.
You're going to need a hose down.
So funny if there was a guy waiting
outside the bathroom to explain that to
you.
You just walk out,
he says you,
you're probably a little confused but
toilet papers and I'd explain it or
nothing there.
There's something that I put up on my
instagram today about a sign that I saw
that said,
please don't pee on the floor.
And I'm like,
How many people have to pee on the floor
before you put a sign up that says
please don't pee on the floor.
And by the way,
if you're a person who pees on the
floor,
are you really going to go?
Oh,
I was going to,
but now I'm not at all.
I'm stopping the [inaudible].
Exactly.
It's like,
please don't rape.
By the way,
the truth is about Floor Ping.
It it p ends up on the floor.
Some does.
Yeah.
Some done for dudes.
Yeah,
for dudes.
And the other thing I read that,
that's very honest that I've read that I
agree with.
Some guy said because of Smartphones,
I pee sitting down much more than I
would like to admit.
Oh,
that's a fact.
We did an episode about that on a curb
your enthusiasm.
I sit down like,
well,
just take a shit and if it doesn't come
out,
I'll just p and I'll read my phone.
Yeah,
I'll just read.
Just read stuff you guess?
No,
I can look at people with their phones.
That's a whole thing.
Yeah.
The a problem with phones as a tool.
No,
I do not.
But as a avoiding being in the present,
I do.
Yeah.
They're addictive.
Very addictive.
And by the way,
I gotta be honest,
I don't remember the last show where
somebody didn't pull out their phone the
last show,
like when people are texting people or
someone is,
even if it's one person,
I can't even remember somebody not doing
that.
And that's the ultimate,
that's so disrespectful.
Well,
one of the things I did before my last,
uh,
Netflix special that I've filmed in
April was I went on tour for three
months where you had to use those cell
phone back.
Did those yonder bags?
Yeah.
There a giant fucking pain in the ass.
I,
by,
by the way,
I play a lot at largo and I would just
make an announcement and then if someone
does,
you could come out.
No,
I mean some people just feel like,
yeah,
but I got to just answer this text.
Yeah,
yeah.
But I just got to do this.
Hey.
But I,
I'm a big fan of it is.
Yeah.
But,
but my response is yeah,
yeah.
But I'll see a lighter.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's an issue.
Um,
but what I was going to say is that it's
a big pain in the ass,
those yonder bag.
But the show was like 10% better because
no one had their phone and you just sit
there and you would actually be
connected to the show.
But people are your,
but waterfall fuck plan leader would
have,
I got a deuce waterfall.
Go to Turks coming in.
What's that character's name?
I don't have one.
You don't have a name for the care,
Doug?
Oh,
no,
but I don't let stand how toby toby.
Okay.
Toby.
Toby,
toby.
Fuck him.
Fuck.
I got a call coming in.
I'm going to leave the show to answer
the phone.
Tell me what your,
your buyer to the Caribbean movie is
your favorite.
Oh,
all of them are fucking huge.
Johnny Depp found
one of the reasons,
it's why I did that because,
um,
cause Chapelle was telling me how much
he enjoys it and Hannibal,
Hannibal burress who tell me how much he
enjoys using those bags too.
But another reason was this woman
complained that,
um,
when she went to my new year show that
some girl behind her made two separate
phone calls and was saying happy new
year to people during the show,
during the show.
She was like,
this stupid fucking bitch was making
phone calls while the show was going on.
The way I've,
I've,
I've been behind in front of next to
that person.
That's a crazy thing to do.
To me,
you were at
form,
it's a live performance and you're
calling people and talking to them or
even answering the phone and talking on
the,
but I think if you have signs with a
stern language saying you'll be no,
I was like peeing on the floor,
Bro.
No,
but I gotta be honest with you,
I really respect my audience and I
really think that that would eliminate
the handful of people that would be
douchey most because I play at Largo a
lot and at Largo they make the
announcement and I have,
I have never seen anyone during my show.
That's an exceptional place.
Yeah.
But,
but you can create an exceptional vibe,
but yes.
In your audience with,
by respecting them.
I certainly agree.
I'm like,
it's like,
you know,
when I go someplace and they want to put
a stamp on my hands,
I just go,
no,
no.
There'll be no stamps on my hands.
And you're,
the doorman usually says,
okay,
really?
Yeah.
So when they do not look,
I don't really drink alcohol,
so,
but so,
but like if I go to the bar and order a
drink,
the guy who's going to look for my stamp
point being is fuck all that.
I got to have respect for it.
But if you go to like a mythical
festival,
it's like also when you go to the
bathroom and they have the sinks,
I don't mind the sinks where it senses
your hand even though it doesn't always
do it.
But man,
those times,
those ones where you push down and you
get 10 seconds,
that's so disrespectful.
It's wrong,
wrong,
really wrong to mankind,
you know,
bothers me.
What?
When you wave your hand and a thing and
it gives you a tiny little strip of
paper,
you know?
Yeah.
A little stingy ass piece of paper to
dry your hand wave and the second time
give me a real fucking piece of paper.
What's great?
Those powerful new blow ones?
No,
those are no good.
I'd dig them.
There was an article that I tweeted
about those things.
What are the problems?
There's like shit dust in the air for
people and all that bacteria by,
by,
by the way,
let me ask you,
the premise of the shit does.
So you're saying people take a dump,
wash their ass,
wait,
yes.
And then don't go to the sink to wash
their hands.
They just go straight for the dryer
thing cause it's fun and let's spread
this shit around.
The thing is with that,
when you hit that dryer dust from that
the wind kicks up ups.
This is science.
Scientists are,
there's too much for me to think about
it too much for me to pick up.
Listen man,
I did no research.
I just posted an article that I read
said that those things are hygienic and
then somebody goes,
hey if if joe posted and it must be true
because he did his research can be very
click baity right.
They could've just got you some
bullshit,
some bullshit.
Some guy named Bob who's a doctor.
I'm tone Ya.
They're shit there.
That's my character of Bob was an angry
doctor.
Third shouldn't here am I right toby?
Shit dust.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I was on the phone and I didn't have
time.
I'm tired.
Wash my hands,
hand dryers,
sucking fecal bacteria and blow it all
over your hands.
Study finds.
See Bro,
we go enjoy.
So I will not be using that anymore.
I wouldn't use the borough dryer and
when I touch the thing to have the tower
will come down.
I know that that's very clean.
Yes.
No,
no,
no.
That's not,
but at least it's not,
but there's no cool.
Let's just send it.
Just put it this way.
There's no winning,
no winning.
No,
but you gotta take a dump in public.
There's no wind.
Well,
there's also the issue of like becoming
some ocd person who's fucking completely
crazy.
Sports rl all over their body everywhere
they go,
because they're afraid of everything and
they touch and then they don't build up
immunity.
I had,
that's,
I have a giant issue with,
with that many people who in auditions
won't shake an actor's hand because
they've got,
that's not,
well,
da friends with Hawaii.
Yes.
I know that.
How he doesn't touch,
he doesn't even bang knuckles anymore.
He was banging knuckles for a while.
He wouldn't.
He even do knuckles anymore.
He's gotten worse.
That's his business.
He's a good man.
He's a very good man.
He really liked that guy a lot,
but I want to hug him.
I want to go,
come get him on the fuck.
Give me a hug and give me a kiss.
Right on the lips.
Imagine you said
he's such a nice man.
He's a good man.
He's a very good guy.
But I want him to get over that because
I think it's insane not going to happen.
Why not?
You think people haven't worked with
them on it?
It doesn't make any sense to want to
change Joe.
Ooh,
your own psychiatrists don't want to
change.
You're not going to change.
That's true.
And that's what the addiction with
anything.
If you don't want to do it,
nobody try the way when it comes to
addiction or behavior,
like how he's,
logic does not enter the right.
You can present your logical cases to
all those different types of people.
It doesn't matter.
They got to wanna.
Yeah,
well he um,
he goes so far as that he puts down a
trail of paper towels in his hotel room
so he never has to stay on the carpet.
So yeah,
I did not know this.
I don't want to know this.
I
don't want to think about how we in
hotels,
sorry,
I want him to be happy in hotels.
Well I'm sure he's happy once he steps
on that paper towel.
You know what special I loved as a kid.
Well,
how are we from Maui?
Oh yeah.
It was hilarious.
He told me,
I told him this the other night.
He goes,
that was shit.
And I go,
no,
no.
I laughed really hard at that special.
Well,
it's because he's very funny that he's
self critical.
Every funny person I've ever known
thinks they're the best response is just
thank you.
Yeah,
that's a good response.
Thanks.
I'm glad you enjoyed it too.
I feel that way.
Look,
when people come up to me and they go,
you're my favorite character on curb
your enthusiasm.
What I could really do is look them in
the angle.
Really,
really the guy who does all the
exposition.
Larry,
David's not your favorite.
I think you're wrong by the way.
Every blue moon,
when somebody says that to me,
I can tell that they mean it,
but all of them wouldn't know the
difference.
Cause I thank say thank you to all of
them.
No one needs to hear that shit.
People do say stupid shit that they
don't really mean just cause they want
you to respond to them.
Yeah.
I want to tell you,
you're the best famous,
weird.
I learned that when I was at 100% true
and I had this moment where it became
clear to me,
I found myself waiting at valet parking
with Tony Danza and it wasn't like we
were even looking at each other or we
had an awkward moment together.
I really wanted to say hello and not
because I'm a big Tony,
Tony fans a fan or any reason.
It was just the fame factor wanting me
to talk to Tony Danza course.
Not even like,
Hey Tony,
I'm Jeff Garlin Wright.
Just Hey Tony Danza oh you know,
hey.
Right.
And so I thought,
oh this is fucked up.
Shut up.
I didn't say anything.
He seems very approachable.
He seems like a very nice fella.
But,
but that is not,
yeah,
when I was a young man,
um,
I always wished that I was as nice as
Tony Danza.
Cause when I see Tony Danza on taxi and
all those shows him like he always
seemed so friendly.
Like why can't I be nice and friendly?
Wouldn't be weird.
As you got into show business,
you found out he was a prick.
But the truth is I've never seen,
I've never heard a bad thing ever said
about him.
There was a fist fight with him at the
comedy store one night.
Oh really?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Long,
long time ago.
I want to say like it was before my time
and I started there in 94 so someone
said something stupid to him somewhere
back in the day.
And Tony Dan's was a professional boxer.
Yeah,
go really good boxer.
He actually took a pro fight in between
tapings of taxi,
driver of taxi rather when he was a
first season in between first and second
season,
he was offered a few months.
He's like,
fuck,
I'll have a fight.
And then he was like,
what am I doing?
Fucking actor now?
Yeah,
he is,
but he's,
somebody got mouthy with them.
Well,
by the way,
when you see someone like that get into
a fight,
you know,
whoever approached him really,
there've been times where I felt like it
was just not worth it.
Yeah.
Because you lose that person,
you lose,
I don't care if someone calls you a Nazi
kike any bad word,
uh,
just along,
that's the other reaction,
right?
Like there's some people that would come
up to you,
Jeff Garlin.
Hey boy.
That'd be like,
Oh,
you fucking think you're all funny cause
you're on curb your enthusiasm every
like maybe once every two,
three years.
But you're really continuing the
character.
Was it as is?
No,
but some guy.
Was that toby toby?
Yeah.
Jimbo math.
Jimbo was on math.
So sad.
No,
but,
but I just avoid,
you know,
I don't get into it.
You know what you think of me is none of
my business that includes fame.
Right?
So people come up and say things.
Thank you.
That's the right thing to say.
Yeah.
And then,
and then you want to say to them
sometimes,
and you know this one,
could you move along?
Because they just stay.
They just stay there and it's really
awkward.
There was a dude at the comedy store
scared the hell out of me because he
told me how much I meant to him and then
he didn't leave.
And then he was telling me personal
things about him that were not the,
I'm not going to repeat them because I
don't want to let them know that I'm
talking to him.
But he started telling me things like,
oh wow,
you're really a scary individual and I
want,
I never have said the words move along,
but I actually moved along into an area
he couldn't enter.
A number was behind the rope,
you know,
buy the cars or in the bar,
the something to get away.
And he still tried,
you know,
it was scary and people get crazy.
You know what bothers me?
Sometimes you'll be in the middle of a
serious conversation with someone,
a tea.
They're telling you something like
really intimate and someone to call
here,
hey man.
Hey,
what?
Buy,
buy,
buy
and you're like,
but Tony's just telling me he's
suicidal.
Yeah.
In the middle of a competition thing
about jumping in front of a bus and you
don't give a fuck.
No,
it's,
it's a big bowl or wrong it just because
really just be respectful and kind.
Anyone that comes up to me as respectful
and kind,
I'm kind to,
anyone comes up to me as an asshole.
I'm kind to being an asshole.
They just don't know cause they are
either you're an asshole,
you're not either or you're not.
But there's also taught,
you have a couple of drinks and you
don't know what to say.
What's the number one rule with someone
who's,
who's drunk too much,
but telling them that they're drunk.
That's good too.
You know what I'm saying?
Hey man,
you drunk.
Yeah.
Hey man,
I didn't really,
I don't really talk to drunk people
drunk.
Oh always.
It's the,
it's,
it's the only goat too.
There's no other goto in that situation
drive.
I,
yeah,
I can do it.
Yeah.
And so because whatever it does,
it really plows into your ego.
And so I just make the quickest
connection and get,
get out.
Yeah.
That's a good move.
Yeah,
it's true.
But I'm appreciative when people come up
to me,
I'm appreciative and I treat them the
way.
If someone I dug,
especially a comedian,
if I told them I dug them,
I treat the people the way.
And the more the warmer and the more
interesting the person is,
the more I give them of myself.
How does Larry David handle it?
He's not bad.
Yeah.
I'm a big fan of,
oh,
thank you.
You about that.
Yeah.
I've seen them go through,
because it was,
I saw him become famous,
you know,
he was on Fridays.
He created Seinfeld,
but that still wasn't the fame that he
has now.
So I saw him through curb your
enthusiasm become truly iconic.
So he's had trouble figuring out how to,
people want to take a picture of people,
you know?
Well,
how do I do it?
And it's always changing.
He's never an asshole.
It's truly one of the greatest comedy
shows of all time.
Well,
thank you.
I 100% and I have to say the new season
we're about to film in October,
the storyline may be my favorite and
it's really subtle and fun.
It's like one of those things like,
oh,
I,
it's like,
I think people watching it will feel
that they're living a fantasy and after
the first one airs,
I'm happy to come back and talk about
it.
You know what I mean?
Because that premise of where we're
going is delightful.
I love how hbo gives him sort of carte
blanche.
They're like,
you know,
take a couple of years off,
do whatever the fuck you want.
Like,
yeah,
take some pretty great.
Well,
for Larry,
it's not about the money.
Of course it's about can I do another
good show?
And that makes us different than most
shows in history.
Yeah.
And uh,
he,
um,
he only wants to do good work and enjoy
himself otherwise there's no reason.
And,
uh,
an HBO is smart that way.
Their genius there.
I mean look,
and you think about the show soprano's
fucking game of thrones and now they
know how to let a show be a show.
They,
from what I understand,
they give a lot of notes on their
pilots,
but once you become a series,
they kind of leave you alone.
That's amazing.
You know?
Whereas when you're doing a network show
or from other pay sources,
I've heard that the notes never stopped.
Well when I was on the radio is the
easiest thing to ruin with notes.
Drama can survive notes.
Comedy cannot because it's like the uh,
you know,
doing comedies,
like,
you know,
the,
the dominoes and if you take one of
those and just move it a little to the
left,
to the right,
you're screwing up the whole thing.
That's very good point.
When I was on news radio,
we weren't successful and that is when
you get the notes.
We were,
so my friend Lou Morton,
who was one of the writers,
he would wear a shirt every Monday after
the ratings would come in with a number
on it.
It would take a white t shirt and write
it.
And one day came into the number,
said 88 I go,
fuck dude.
Really?
He goes,
yeah,
we're 88th I'm like,
fuck.
I was like,
God damn it.
I'm going to say three years,
right?
Five,
five years.
So the point being is that was an
immensely successful show.
Barely,
barely made you stay on the air.
That's pretty great.
No,
no,
for sure.
It's definitely better than being
canceled.
But the point being is that we were
never a hit,
so we always got notes.
We're constantly getting notes like we
need a gay neighbor,
we need a black guy,
we need a,
we need
of this.
We needed that.
We needed a love interest.
We need a fucking watch that show,
by the way,
the gay neighbor and the Black Guy,
if that was the name of the show,
I'd be in.
That's what probably good name of
sitcoms gaining black guy was next door,
gay neighbor.
And it's the problems that,
there's a lot of sitcoms and I don't
want to name names,
but I watched them and I know they're
very,
very successful and I watched them and
I'm stunned.
I don't understand it.
It's like they're speaking a different
language.
I don't get it either.
I don't,
but I don't watch comedy,
man.
I'm Erica.
I think there's,
there's something going on with tired
people.
Here's something that I noticed.
This is something that's recent to that.
Audiences now respond to what they think
is supposed to be funny.
Like real comedy fans,
dug news radio,
like people who dug comedy.
I think Doug News radio people did
comedy dig curb.
Do we have other kinds of fans too?
Yes,
but I find that comedy fans really do
get comedy,
but everybody likes to say they like
comedy or they watch comedy and they may
not have any sense of humor.
So I find there was a show,
I'll give you an example,
and this one was like the specific,
and I don't care if I'm slamming it,
it was the something in the girl and the
apartment b or the bitch and something
be,
it was um,
lead actress.
Very talented.
But I watched the show and the rhythms
were,
this is what comedy is.
It wasn't funny.
It didn't have a natural vibe to it.
It had no reason for me to keep watching
it,
but it was done in a style that other
shows have done since where this is how
comedy is done,
this is the way we spend a line or do a
situation and I don't know why,
but it always involves a lot of that.
That putting the,
the the spin on the ball or what's the
dancing in English?
Yeah.
It has a lot to do with it because even
if you watch a lot of nickelodeon shows,
her Disney shows,
they tend to do that.
They put the spin on it.
It's never funny enough just to have,
here's the thing about comedy TV,
comedy.
I think for the most part you're
supposed to be enthralled with the
situation,
the situation.
So the situation Lucy got into a
situation.
Yes.
And you laughed at Lucy dealing with the
situation.
I really,
I bet in the entire time lucy ran on the
rent on the air that there might've been
12 great jokes that she said in the
situation.
You're laughing on how she deals with
the situation.
Very good point.
And you look at any great comedy and
that's where this,
it's Larry David dealing with a
situation.
Yes,
it's,
it's um,
so,
and by the way,
one thing Larry and I are very proud
about with curb your enthusiasm.
If one of us says something funny to the
other one,
cause we improvise,
we laugh.
So these shows,
you see people say these lines written
by writers and then the audience laughs
if it's on stage,
but yet the actors don't laugh at one
another.
So on a lot of levels it's just not
right.
And then there are shows now that I've
watched for maybe five minutes where Ma
I cannot believe how they're,
how terrible they are and yet they're
successful.
Hugely successful,
hugely successful.
Don't get it.
Yeah.
When you guys do a show,
you don't really have like a full script
in terms of,
no,
we have a very tight outline.
We have seven pages line.
Larry has written the story and in that
story maybe a half dozen things are
like,
he says this or she says that you have
to move the story for story purposes.
Not because it's a great joke.
Right.
And then I play it every time
differently unless I'm told by the
director or I'm one of the producers,
we have a meeting of like we need to get
this across.
This is not coming across and I'll make
an adjustment.
But in general,
I try and do it different.
Every single tech that is so crazy and
how many takes we do,
well if it's Larry and I just us,
he and I alone in the scene it we can,
we can have a scene done in less than an
hour,
but if there's a bunch of other people,
could be three hours.
Wow.
And the idea is just like this is what
needs to take place.
We know we have to figure out how to get
across the fact that the refrigerator's
broken and we're going to have to go buy
ice and who's going to buy the ice?
I don't want to drive to buy the ice.
Right.
And then y'all just talking.
It's more in depth than that.
The story is really that.
But yes,
how we approach it.
And sometimes that can change that.
That's one of the reasons why the show
is so good because it seems so organic
when you guys are talking.
It is,
well that's what I get out of it.
We don't rehearse.
That's amazing.
They are so,
um,
the Goldbergs we don't even do a lot of
rehearsing,
but I have to stick to the script.
If I want to improvise on the Goldbergs,
I have to let the producers know not to
get permission to let them know this
take,
I'm going to do something different and
I have to let my fellow actors know.
Ah,
that's interesting.
I don't,
I still do adjust to go from two
different styles.
I W I don't know that it's difficult,
but I find the curb your enthusiasm way,
way more enjoyable.
Oh,
I'm sure.
But I'm really proud the Goldbergs is
the number one show on tv that families
watch together.
So I'm very proud of that and I get why
people dig it.
It's not my style,
but when I watch it occasionally,
I don't watch it very often.
I get why people dig it.
I'm not confused by the show.
Right,
right.
You know what I mean?
Like these other shows we're talking
about,
I'll be confused as to why they're
successful,
why they're on there.
But other ones I watch,
like I watch monitor family.
I get why people dig it.
Right,
right,
right.
It makes total sense,
you know?
Um,
so it's,
it,
it's
much more enjoyable during the curb
thing.
It's edgier and all that.
But I still dig the Goldbergs and I also
dig the crew and I dig the people I work
with and I dig the writer.
So it's a very positive,
wonderful experience.
And I'm lucky I'm on one of the most
popular network comedies and among the
most popular alternative comedy.
How'd you get to be so lucky?
What,
by the way,
I'm grateful.
I keep on getting told in therapy.
Don't say lucky so much.
I says,
why is he telling you that?
Because grateful because I do have
something to do with it,
but not from an ego standpoint,
but like I've worked hard.
I've done this,
I've done that.
So I'm just incredibly grateful.
You're lucky too.
I think I'm lucky.
Grateful.
And by the way,
what have I told you?
I'm not kidding.
That dude has taught me so much.
That might be the only thing I disagree
with him on.
Yeah,
he doesn't know shit.
No.
Lucky is good.
Now,
Roger.
Dot.
Roger Dog Daltrey uh,
always said be lucky.
And it's the cause that means no matter
how great you are,
no matter how much you have to do with
this or that,
if you look at it,
that you're lucky being hung.
By the way,
being humble is a big bullet.
People,
the combination of being competent and
being humble,
you can't beat the being aware that you
know,
you could be born in Ethiopia.
You could have been,
well Lorne,
that funny in the middle of nowhere.
Yeah,
I,
you know,
could have been fun.
I'm not big on ego.
Ego.
Ego screws me.
And by the way,
I was ignorant enough at one time to
think I can eliminate my ego.
You can't.
You just got to recognize it when it
pops up,
recognize it and keep it under control
and we'll just say,
hey man,
don't need Ya.
Thank you.
You know,
some not going to ask to do something.
And as I'm thinking about it am my
saying yes to this out of an ego move.
You know,
I've definitely done that before.
Yeah.
I think that's,
well one of the main reasons why
exercise so much just to try to keep my
body in balance in,
in not in terms of like the way it
looks,
but so it doesn't get in the way.
And I think that a lot of your body's in
balance then that helps your mind.
Oh yeah.
And that helps your soul.
Oh,
for sure not.
It's not a vanity thing man.
That's,
it is too.
I definitely like looking good while,
but it's also,
but that,
I think that's more of a uh,
uh,
respecting yourself.
That's a,
that's a self respecting to me.
There's definitely that,
but I think,
um,
how new actually,
which is weird.
Why is it weird?
Because that's not something that
people,
most people generally love.
They hate going to the gym,
but they go,
you feel at your best when you're
exercising.
That is amazing.
That is awesome.
I wish I could have that for a week.
Just let me broward for a week.
Just,
uh,
I'd always rather nap then do anything.
I don't mind stand up.
I liked over napping,
sex over napping.
Uh,
sometimes eating not as much anymore.
It hasn't because it's not a big thing
for me to more so I'd say sex and,
and,
and stand up and spending time with my
boys that that takes precedence over at
my boys are 18 to 22.
I'm madly in love with them.
And so,
um,
that takes precedence.
I'd rather be with them than nab.
Yeah.
By the way,
when they were little,
when they were little taking a nap with
them,
I was in heaven.
Yeah.
Cause I knew they were good.
And they'd be laying,
laying against me.
Goodnight nurse.
Yeah.
That's uh,
the pleasure of having children.
I don't know,
like having these people that you love
more than you could ever have imagined.
Loving someone more than,
by the way,
that's the thing.
Like when someone's having a kid,
they're about to have a kid,
whether it's a woman or man,
I don't say to them,
oh you know,
because you can't explain it.
It's truly a thing that you can't
explain and you only sound like an idiot
when you try going,
well,
here's what it is.
No,
you can't tell me and to be unique to me
and it's so big,
much bigger than I ever could have
imagined.
It's a different thing than you can ever
imagine.
Like you become a different person too.
There's like a litter,
the,
there's a,
an actual switch that seems to go off
and the change of course,
let me just say something cause you know
people at,
I know people were for whatever reason,
that's,
which doesn't go off and they still stay
the most important person in their own
lives.
That's where it's weird and it throws me
and that's somebody I do not want to be
friends with.
No,
it's so people that are bad,
parents that don't like their kids.
It's a unfollow area.
Unfortunate thing.
It's a big bowl of wrong.
It's such a,
it's so sad.
Painful.
I think there's certain,
I mean I,
there has to be levels of sociopath's,
right?
There's levels of it.
I think there is,
I mean that's just me.
I don't know anything about that topic,
but must be UCC pull people with
sociopathic behavior and you just go,
oh,
okay,
well it's also the business that we're
in to the business solves them.
Well for sure they want the ice to do a
joke about it.
That the problem with actors is that
they have this big hole in their soul
that they need to fill up with other
people's attention.
And I would say not me,
I'm different.
That's how I am up here with a
microphone.
Right.
Well by the way,
comedians are completely different than
then for the most part.
Then actors.
But you also know that to be a great
actor,
you can be dumb as a rock.
Oh yeah.
It's the only Ari's,
it's the only art form.
Excuse me.
I had a little hiccup,
something,
something happened.
It's the only art form and I know plenty
of really intelligent actors,
but I know some that are so talented.
And if I could never have a conversation
with them,
I'd be thrilled.
Oh,
it'd be amazing because they're just so
dumb.
But when the time comes and they said
they can become that person,
they can,
they can fall into that role and there's
something,
something wrong with them,
what they could do it like Wayne
Fetterman has a bit about it,
you know about,
unless you for just mentioning Wayne,
Wayne Fetterman.
I love him so much.
A pilot with him way,
way back in the day room.
He's just,
he's so funny.
He's a rock man and known him since I'm
20 years old.
I met when I first started doing comedy.
Oh Wow.
We're from,
I'm from Chicago,
but I started comedy.
I had moved to Florida with my family,
south Florida,
and we're from the same little town in
Florida called Plantation Florida
outside of Fort Lauderdale.
We did a pilot together 20 years ago,
1998 I think it was.
I think that was his last one.
Might be right,
but I love him so much.
He had a bit that he was doing on stage
once about actors and I grabbed him off
stage.
Dude,
you put it,
you said it like the way you said it,
you said it the right cause it's like
also he's free,
right.
Because you know he's,
he doesn't have notoriety.
He's not worried about running into
these people that he talks shit about
onstage so you can be free.
And he was like,
he was like,
it's not normal to be able to cry on
cue.
It's like,
yes,
you can cry on cue.
Yay.
Cause you're fucking broken.
Is something wrong with you?
By the way,
that's another change in the world of
standup.
The number of people who sew and this
started from the comedy boom when people
were getting set comes,
actors saw this and they went,
oh,
if I do stand up,
I'll be discovered.
Yes.
And um,
so that's brought a lot of people that
aren't truly comedians to a comedy,
which I can spot them.
There was a dude,
he gets bought bottom.
Oh my God.
Yes.
There was a dude in the laugh factory
who was actually funny and he was
actually good.
And he said,
if I don't,
uh,
have a sitcom,
I'm quitting.
And by next year,
and he didn't and he quit.
Wow.
I don't remember his name.
Who could otherwise I'd tell you off
there,
I'll talk to you about it.
Fortunately,
no.
So,
but the point being is,
is that if you're really a comedian,
it is so part of your DNA.
It is so part of who you know.
But it was like,
it's not who I am.
No comedians.
It's part of who we are on a deep,
deep level.
The Passion and caring the comedians
truly have for comedy.
And that's why I look at other comedians
as my brothers and sisters.
So if you're dealing with ego,
if you're dealing with a,
you're an actor,
you're trying to get famous.
If you're dealing with the competition
that I got no part of you,
when you look at me and you go,
Jeff Garlin has no choice but to be a
comedian,
then you're thinking on the same
wavelength as me because I have no
choice.
I have to be a comedian.
Yeah.
Some people get very,
very resentful of those actors.
Like,
why don't I get resentful of him and I,
there's plenty of room and I remember
some famous actors trying stand up,
you know,
in anyone would try it.
And the eighties like,
I remember,
um,
well she's uh,
what's her name?
She was Sean Young.
Is that a no?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
She was coming into the Improv and I
remember she was doing standup was,
but hers was full of Shit.
So I was like,
I was the only one there who didn't help
her.
Everyone bent over backwards.
But she wasn't sincere and she did it
for five minutes,
but they like being around a famous
woman who is beautiful,
you know,
but the point being is that people
forgot about it.
Anyone can do whatever they want,
but do me a favor,
if you're going down that path,
don't screw me with your negative shit.
She's an interesting case.
Um,
I read a whole article about her and
fame and her struggles with it and you
know,
you got people forget she was in the
original blade runner.
She was a phenomenal actress and so
beautiful,
stunning,
but so good too.
I mean,
just so a probably was a very
intelligent woman and there were flaws
in her life and flaws and being an
actress.
And by the way,
being in the public eye is not,
especially now with social media,
is the opposite of a walk in the park.
And you,
I am not entitled to any privacy.
I am not entitled to any alone moments
when I'm walking in a park.
I'm not.
And that saves me to look at it that
way.
Yeah.
That I'm not entitled to it.
Because if I want to be alone,
I'm going to stay in my living room.
I'm going to sit in my back yard and
look up at the trees and the breeze,
man,
oh,
I can't see the breeze,
but I can feel the breeze.
But the point being is they're there.
The world of any privacy for you in the
public eye gone.
Yeah.
And you know when I'm at like a
restaurant or the airport and the TMZ,
people coming with their microphone,
I don't say a word.
Why help them sell that crap and then
they turn off the mic and they know this
at this point now and I'm very friendly.
How are you guys doing?
What's going on?
And I know some of them,
but I don't have the right to walk
through the airport without them in my
face.
That's part of the thing.
The demand of a get out of those is you
say something stupid and people get mad
at you like,
and any board,
they only thing you get out of that is
saying something stupid and people get
mad at you.
There's no winning,
there's no time.
What you're going to say something to
Tmz and people are going to watch it and
go,
that was so damaged cycle possible.
It's certainly possible.
You can blow that out of time on long
shot.
That is such a long shot.
Specifically tmz.
Yeah,
but bordain got a shitload of death
threats when uh,
he was at the airport and they said if
you were going to cook dinner for a
trump and Kim Jong own,
what would you serve?
And he said,
hemlock,
you know,
just a joke.
He's a funny guy.
He said something funny and uh,
no,
but see that's the thing.
There's no winning.
Yeah,
there's no winning because by the way,
he could say that at a dinner party.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
And if someone's offended than their
tool,
right.
You know,
he could say that by the way,
you could say that in a room full of 11
republicans.
Yes.
And they will laugh.
Yeah,
but you're opening yourself when you'd
say that's right.
So I don't say anything.
You know,
you can ask me comments about things
that go on in the world and I know I'll
have an answer that will not get me in
trouble.
That's the case
today with comedy,
right?
It's like you're opening yourself up to
the world.
You're not just opening yourself up on
people.
Over.
When I went onstage was ever in fear of
going down a path where I would say
something that was wildly inappropriate,
not,
well,
not inappropriate for the standpoint of
taking a risk,
but just because my sense of humor
doesn't go the way to use certain words.
Like I don't use that word.
Not because I'm scared of anything.
Um,
but uh,
so people who do that and do that,
it's like,
like Michael Richards.
Michael Richard.
Yeah,
the pool.
By the way,
example,
by the way,
you know when he walked off stage,
and I think it might've been Tom Papa
who was standing in the corner,
he went up to him and went a weird crowd
having no idea that his life was over as
he knew it.
Because by the way,
I remember being furious because certain
people that came down to them on the
news like the next day or two where
people who I had heard say worst things
in their standup and they were talking
shit,
they were talking stuff.
It's like when someone's swimming in a
river of Shit,
you don't throw shit on them.
I agree.
Let them swim in there.
Shit,
have a good time.
You chose to get in the shit,
you know,
but I'm not going to throw shit.
And that's loaded with shit how I felt
with Roseanne,
you know,
and this Roseanne Buddy went down,
you need to say anything else except she
really needs some sort of help.
And support.
Not like,
oh,
she's a Nazi or she's a horrible person.
No,
no,
no.
She needs help.
Yeah,
she,
and that's the whole thing.
Why do I need to do art when Harvey
Weinstein or any of these fuckers come
out?
I don't have a twitter account because I
also know just like Tmz,
how long until I say something that
pisses somebody off.
Right.
But there are people,
and I'm not saying their names,
I don't want to get into a thing who
will come out and go,
gentlemen,
that's not the way to behave.
Or you know what I mean?
Like,
but I really do.
I need to say rape is bad.
Do I need to say hauling a successful,
accomplished black woman?
Something bad is bad.
No,
you don't need my comment.
All these people on twitter to think
their comments necessary.
Oh,
I need to add into this.
I need to be part of this dialogue.
No.
Well,
it's virtue signaling.
You know,
it's letting everybody know the suicide
and I'm on the right side.
It's a bunch of crap.
But it was a want people to assume that
I making the right choice.
I want people to assume because they're
not going to hear what my choice.
So there's a guy who was a journalist
who is angry and he was saying that the
lack of a blow back from other comedians
about Louis C K that they weren't
screening and how horrible this is
speaks volumes.
And I was like,
[inaudible] don't know what you're
talking about.
That's what speaks volumes about this
dude.
He doesn't know what he's talking about,
by the way.
Shit,
anyone disrespect a woman to mend my
knowledge.
Never.
Should anyone be sexually forward in
a room and a woman in an inappropriate
way?
No.
Do I need to say that she ever yell out
and say this is wrong.
No,
this is,
I'm telling you this is then,
no,
it's wrong.
I know.
Five days of it coming out of him
admitting that he did it right though.
The whole thing was crazy.
Like you know,
this guy was accusing all these other
communities of being pieces of shit
because they are not wrong.
They're not.
You don't need my opinion designation of
something.
If someone's swimming in a river of
shit,
I do not need to throw shit in that
river.
It's like,
what are your requirements as a person
when something happens,
if there's a mass shooting,
do I need to stand up and say that that
was a bad thing,
right?
No,
no.
It's obvious.
That was a bad thing.
I don't,
why do I need to comment on everything
that happened?
I need to come in and if that's the
case,
is there an action I can do to help
write it or was it just commenting?
Which does nothing.
Nothing.
Oh,
really?
You're letting us know.
That's what I'm saying.
These certain individuals,
and I'm thinking of two in particular
who I know and like both of them.
Can you do three of them?
Are there three of them?
Actually one,
I don't know as well.
No,
but I'll tell you afterwards.
I'm always in these situations.
Say the obvious like,
yeah,
who wouldn't believe that?
And I get furious.
Especially,
one of them's a great old friend of mine
and it's just a comment every time and
it's like,
yeah,
I have a friend that does the same
thing.
Uh,
who's a an accomplished stand up and
it's always,
how do I word this without giving this
guy away?
It's always about anything that has
anything to do with women.
And like he's always standing up for
women.
But meanwhile I knew I was kind of lives
in hell.
I know he lives in hell.
Like his marriage,
his shit,
he like literally hides like he's,
he's in hell,
he's in hell.
His wife's a monster.
It's amazing.
It's amazing though,
by the way.
Isn't that amazing though?
It is.
It's just like,
they almost like,
he's like holding like when the divorce
comes like down the line,
which is definitely an come,
like at least [inaudible] guy.
I will have a reverent conversations
with my friends,
drinking coffee,
hanging out.
Sometimes I'll even talk too loud in the
coffee shop.
Hey,
it's tongue and cheek,
but fun.
But,
but I will,
I'm not,
by the way,
here's another one.
You know the worst possible things you
could ever hear.
Comedians at the funeral,
comedian dies.
What comedians are saying to one
another.
It is stuff that would be unforgiven
unforgiven but it's just the way we deal
with grief in those situations.
It's also the inappropriate thing at
that time is very funny to someone like
you or I.
Very,
very fun.
I was sitting right next to Dave Foley
and we went to the emmy's and Phil
Hartman had just been murdered and he
was nominated for an emmy and he lost to
this guy from frasier.
And uh,
Dave looks over at me.
He goes,
what the fuck's the guy I have to do to
win?
That's a great,
and we were like crying,
sad.
We're drinking
and we're just so bummed out.
It is death.
Right?
And then Dave says that,
and then he says,
it was like a total straight face.
What the fuck's going to have to do to
win?
That's really funny because in the
moment it was just that.
But we say the most inappropriate things
in tragic moments to make each other
laugh,
to make Jews left.
But I'm not going to say them on my
twitter.
No,
I'm not going to say them to other
people.
By the way,
anytime I've ever tried something sort
of inside with someone not on the
inside.
In terms of comedy,
it has been a disaster.
Disaster every time.
How about you?
I'm talking to even privately like like
with at a party or something or what
about with your kids,
parents,
your kids,
friends,
parents.
The way the,
the biggest fights with my wife,
I look back over the years are when we
either went to the principal,
we went to have the meeting,
we went to the open house.
Something I said I never left there
unscathed.
The only one that you couldn't get that
mad at me for was I convinced our tour
of a school that the building was
haunted.
That was the only time where she went.
That was kind of funny.
But you freaked everybody out,
including the school officials.
So yeah,
inappropriate.
You're inappropriate,
Jeff Garlin you're my big bowl of
inappropriate half but,
but,
but it's sort of how we get through
life.
We meaning comedians and and,
and the thing is we're wired alike.
We are,
we share,
I'm not going to say DNA,
but we share something where a brother
and sister had worked together.
So I remember coming off stage,
this is like a classic one coming off
stage of caroline's doing a benefit and
they're not coming after waiting to go
onstage.
Cohen's Onstage,
Colin Quinn and he's fucking eating it
and I'm thinking,
this crowd sucks.
Fuck them,
but I'm going to go do my best.
It's a benefit.
Some guy comes up to me and he says,
I can't wait to go up.
I go,
thanks.
He goes,
this guy again,
I go,
just know you're talking about my
brother.
My brother is standing up there doing
that.
You're not complimenting me if you're
fucking with my brother.
That's what I told them.
Because it's the truth,
right?
We are together.
We experienced something.
But that's what I'm saying.
There's a uniqueness and a specialist
and not everybody is part of that.
Everybody is an actor trying not,
I mean a lot of people were actors.
A lot people are any cause their ego,
their singing voice,
maybe it wasn't good enough.
Like I'm just saying,
it's like,
and by the way,
the people that I have problems with
almost never are true comedians yet to
where it's the brother,
you know?
And like we're really,
when we're together,
you know,
it's almost never,
it's always ego people.
And it's always people that are doing it
for the wrong reasons.
And by the way,
it's not me sitting in judgment.
It's me getting what they give me.
And by the way,
I don't have conflicts with them.
I let them,
you know,
that's something I learned a long time
ago.
That's ego to put my shit on them.
Right,
right.
But I drive home feeling sad so I avoid
doing,
I've learned to not have conflicts.
Took,
took a while.
I would disagree with something.
I'd be like,
fuck you,
but that fuck you doesn't get anywhere.
It's like the same thing as like when
something happens and you complained
about it on twitter,
but I am not chasing Jane.
Let's talk about change.
Did you read about that girl from
Sweden,
from Sweden,
maybe.
Who got on the airplane with the guy who
was both sent to Afghanistan.
I did read that this morning.
I have never been more,
I think I was being deported and would
sit down.
She knew when he gets back he's going to
die.
He's going to be murdered.
This guy,
that was her attitude.
What is the stuff,
cause I only read the headline of it,
the whole story.
So she's on the plane specifically
bought a ticket knowing that he's being
deported.
So she did it on purpose.
She's an activist.
She's an activist,
but I don't know what she's done in the
past.
All I know is she refused to sit down
and at a certain point there was a
soccer team on the flight,
stood up with her.
There were other people who said we back
you.
But there were also a lot of pieces of
shit.
Shut down.
You're making us late.
So one's going to die and look at her
putting herself on the line.
And then she was,
as she and the guy who was being
deported,
we're finally escorted off the plane
because she did her research and her
research told her that the captain can
have them both taken off the plane and
take off.
Anyway,
so the,
the story was that he was being deported
because of ice.
Is that what it was?
See,
I did,
I only read the one either in the gym.
So,
but he,
they were deporting him and then he was
going to get sent back to Afghanistan
where he was going to be killed.
Yes.
We live in a weird time when we come to
start our story,
I was reading about some woman who was
devastated because her,
um,
her daughter in law was being deported
and choose a trump supporter and her
daughter in law was being,
she's been in the United States,
uh,
her whole life and,
being deported and you know,
just couldn't,
couldn't believe it,
couldn't,
you know,
came over here as an infant,
that kind of thing that when you're an
illegal alien that no one gives a fuck.
Have you been here for 30 years?
You only been alive for 32 they don't
get it.
You get sent back and that's,
that's a disgrace.
It really is a disgrace.
No,
it's a horrible,
it's a horrible thing.
And you like,
well,
why don't you fucking to this young
girl,
young girl,
but believing so strongly that she
bought a ticket,
got on the plane and then wouldn't sit
down.
But what happens now though?
What if the guy's still gets sent back?
Kill,
but she's still,
she should do.
She had something.
She did something and maybe he won't.
You don't know.
But that's more than just her putting on
her twitter account.
This is not right being deported.
This is someone actually doing
something,
doing something that doesn't injure
somebody else and it can inconvenience
as people,
but nothing more than that.
What if you had a layover though?
He had a big gig.
What have I had?
A layover?
Yeah,
it was a huge drama.
I'm on her side.
I know that from the gift.
Yes.
Sold out crowd.
No,
I don't care.
I'm filming a Netflix special.
No.
Are you going to film a special?
I am next.
Next spring.
So when you do that or I'm done with the
Goldbergs and curb,
I'm going to do a Netflix special.
So a year from now,
essentially somewhere in the range in
the summer,
less than a year from now.
So when you do that,
will you change your approach where you
have an outline like you do on curb and
like roughly,
um,
know what you're going to talk about?
I W I have stories and things I've been
telling on stage that have been coming
out of me,
so I will tell all those,
but I will,
I'm doing,
uh,
three different locations here in La and
three different shows.
So you're going to film it here.
I'm filming in here,
three shows.
I'm not doing a big theater.
I mean I,
I played big theaters,
but that doesn't help me for a special,
that's just the typical,
come out to the big applause.
Do My schtick.
Goodnight everybody.
Right,
right.
No,
I'm going to actually,
uh,
Tom,
um,
Papa's going to actually direct this was
his idea.
Um,
it's going to follow me around during
the day and then how my day comes into
my show that night.
Beautiful.
Yeah.
So,
but I'll have some prepared,
but between three shows I should get
enough and you know,
hopefully it'll be an interesting thing.
That's what I aspire to do.
Make something worthwhile and
interesting as opposed to billing my
ego.
I don't care.
Can we do this again?
Sometime my friend,
I am honored.
It's,
it's too long and coming and I am,
I'm thrilled to have been here.
People ask me,
I'm like,
you know,
I don't really know Joe.
I go put the first chance I get,
which was the other night when I saw
where it was like,
oh,
hey,
can I do the thing I really want to?
And you're like,
yeah,
sure.
You know,
it was,
it was so simple.
But people have said to me all the time,
go on the show.
And I'm like,
yeah,
I will.
You know,
but being busy like yourself,
it's not like that opportune or I have a
list called Joe,
you know?
Right.
Yeah.
So we did it.
We did,
it works.
And I will again,
anytime you want to do it.
Yes,
it works.
It was an honor.
This was great.
I had a ball.
I enjoyed it.
Yeah.
Thank you,
man.
Jeff Garlin Lazy Gentlemen.
Thanks,
brother.
Thank you.