Oh Shit. Here we go. Recording.
Oh, you know what? What?
Okay, go ahead. Go ahead. We're done.
So many goddamn enemies on
boiler fucking Gracie. I,
we don't know. Fuck that. Yes,
we're broadcasting right now.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the flashlight.
If you go to Joe, who was that? Oh,
so you, Brian, you goddamn rookie son.
Uh,
if you go to Joe rogan.net and click on
the link for the flashlight and enter in
the code name Brogan,
you get 15% off of the
number one sex toy for men.
Ah Ha. And with that said, oh,
the black guy,
you're a gentle,
just sound today. Are there people that
are on the fence about the fleshlight?
But that 15% I was like, you know, when
I heard the 15% I just jumped on it.
Like maybe, maybe there's a few
frugal master bars out there.
Ignore 15% fucking off.
That never makes a difference.
Even when I was broke ass motherfucker,
15% off, never meant really? It. Never,
not 15 didn't mean I ain't gonna make me
get up out of my fucking chair and call
somebody in order some shoes.
Well they made me 30 Penn,
I'm a member of,
I'm a member of all the coupon websites
and if I had a flashlight web 15% off.
Fuck yeah, I'm like free shipping,
you know. That to me is like,
oh I got extra free something.
Whoa, okay. I think everybody thinks
differently when it comes to money.
I think you're a lot like me and that you
would rather not think about it at all.
I don't want to think about thinking
about it as much as you have to. I'm like,
well how much is it? Would you
consider yourself? To be honest,
it's totally cool. Would you
consider yourself a really
big tipper? Yes. Oh really?
Yeah, like 20% the coupons. I don't know
that many of the guys in the coupons,
but usually guys that are in the
coupons usually generally don't tip
well. I, I consider it more of
like that's human and you know,
like I'm helping somebody out compared to
like, fuck if I can get $20 off Amazon,
I'm going to do that. Fucking Amazon
in the ass. Yeah. Or you know,
Amazon's actually hooking you
up and giving you a way to make,
what is the reason for coupons? I mean,
is it just to see what happens when,
when they offer people less
money for things? Well,
I don't know what the
grocery stores have changed.
They used to be relying on coupons.
Now if you don't,
if you go to a grocery store
without one of those cards,
you're pretty much paying a good 15 20%
more than you would if you didn't have a
card on here. What's the benefit
in that for them? Because for, uh,
for those people that aren't loyal,
they just come in and just spend money and
I think a charge him arms advertising.
When you put up a billboard and
it said call now 15%. It's just,
it doesn't mean shit to them.
It's just a reason to have an ad like
that will have like a storyline for an ad.
So let's just say 15% off, we'll blow
that up. It doesn't really matter.
It's a reason to get the logo out.
That's makes sense.
So sort of like an advertising move.
Yeah,
but I've always thought it was probably
to see like maybe our shit's too
expensive.
Maybe we could actually make more money
if we sold more of them at a lesser
price.
Probably also averages out.
Like if you have a product that's
$20 but you could also charge
$30 for it,
then the average is at the people that
use the coupons would probably make it
more like 25 economics major right now.
Pull it is fucking hair out.
Usually know what you're talking
about. I know. By the way,
did we say this is Eddie Bravo Ramos.
We opened the show with coupon.
Your,
it's a new day are he's not even here.
I've never been one to, whenever I
go to Ralph's or something like that.
And they always said, Ralph's our
local supermarket. Do you want to? Uh,
do you want to have a Ralph's Card
fucking card? I don't want another car.
I have a free shake on a roll backs card
or something. I'll just throw that away.
You guys.
So not good with coupons.
They're keeping all that stuff in
a little bag. Different mindset.
Eddie and I have this,
it's a modified stoner mindset.
We get a lot of shit done.
But you and I are both the same way in
that if we don't have to think about
something,
I'm not going to think about it.
And if it's not going to make a
difference in my life, I'm not,
not gonna physically, physically
feel the difference. Come on now.
I need to do that. I guess in certain
for the goods, man, it helps you.
You need to like save money.
Yeah.
I need to make sure if you just didn't
smoke fucking cigarettes, cancer boy,
just throw those fucking things away.
You'd have a lot of extra money.
That's a terrible fucking
drug, man. You know I,
that was the number one
thing when everybody,
anyone ever talks anything about
politicians caring. I just say,
why the fuck don't they
ever talk about cigarettes?
What was the last time you heard Obama
talk about everyone should quit smoking?
Getting on TV, talking about the
400,000 people. Sure. But it doesn't,
you try to quit or hasn't he tried
to quit? Everyone has. You know what?
I'll be honest.
Every now and then I have a cigarette.
I don't have a problem with cigarettes.
You know, every now and then,
you know what it does when you get high
and you throw cigarette on top of that,
after five minutes you
get like a big head buzz.
That's pretty fucking cool. You've
been having those menthol cigarettes.
I can tell I really liked cigars
and cigars are essentially,
it's just pure nicotine that
you're smoking. You know, it's,
this is probably the same buzz that you
get off of a cigarette and one way or
another I don't recommend it,
but I have full control of my body.
I've been drinking since I was 14 probably
younger than that and I never drink
alone. I never, I'm not
an alcoholic. I don't,
I only drink in social situations. And
if I don't drink for four or five months,
you know, I'm not an alcoholic.
You rage hard in social situations.
I wrote a blog about you.
I'm a temporary drunk.
Yeah, well you, what you have is um, you,
you have the ability to control your
impulses and even though your impulses
might be crazy, you know, you
have ability to put them in check.
Whereas a lot of people when they start
drinking and blackout and become another
person, those people, they can't
just not do it again the next day.
The next day comes around.
They have a couple of drinks in them.
They can't step aside. You
can stop at two drinks. How
about the pizza story and Phoenix are,
no. Yeah man, we were, we were out. Okay.
We were ham or 2005,
2005 I did the Improv and Phoenix and
Tempe rather, we had a great old time,
went out, got our party on God, drink on.
We were hammered and we're at a pizza
place and it's two o'clock in the fucking
morning and Eddie Bravo was on the
Atkins Diet. So he's blackout drunk,
blackout drunk.
And he still won't eat as crusts.
God rest his soul. Gracie, Tony
[inaudible] Harris way last year.
I always fucking committed to that shit.
I also remember your cheat
day retake ridiculous.
It's hard to have a Sundae with
pizza inside of it. Chocolate sauce.
Anything you can think of,
you're just dudes are famous for.
The cheat days is a dude who trains with
Bj Penn. I Apologize, I forgot his name.
He's a wrestler and he would put pictures
of his shit online cause it was so
ridiculous.
He would go to Mcdonald's and get a
quarter pounder and then he would go to
Krispy Kreme and it would cut a donut
in half and he put the cheeseburger in
between the donut. Oh Man. He was
just fucking off some foods cheap.
When you're on the Atkins Diet
and you're restricting carbs,
you think about bread like every day.
Sometimes you dream about Brad and you're
thinking about that Sunday and you're
thinking, you're thinking about food
so much Wednesday. I'm like, damn,
all that matters to me. It's
just a couple more days. Hold on.
And I did it for almost three years where
I was looking forward to that Sunday.
Oh Man. And when I would wake up
and stuff my face and I'm like,
it's 11 o'clock in the morning,
I'm stuffed and it's my cheat day.
I've been waiting for this all week.
I want to get hungry again.
That's our spoken a lot of pot getting
the cushiest of Kush. You ever grow up?
I'm sure I did. I mean you had to
have some of the Shit I saw you.
He was just ridiculous.
I even know my fattest day never ate
and then I would extend it to Saturday
night.
I call,
I'm going to start early and then for
like after a year I Saturday night and all
day Sunday?
Yes.
You waited till midnight and
then I did that for about a year.
I would start Saturday night and
midnight and just go off. Right.
And take it all the way through Sunday.
Dennis started Saturday afternoon
around six UFC, you know,
were eating before the UFC.
Okay. Then it just became,
let's just do Saturday and Sunday
and less. I think about it no more.
Let's just wake up Saturday,
fuck it,
and then when I added Friday
night that I was like,
I love sitting off opposite cheat day.
I was like,
I'm not going to get crazy with it now.
I'm not going to suffer. And I'm like,
well, it's not even making
a difference now. Yeah,
you were doing that for a long time.
I miss those days. That was fun.
You are so insane with it. I was
disciplined. Very disciplined. Yeah.
You would just eat lettuce.
I remember you were eating bunny food.
You were just eating and time.
People thought I lost so much weight.
People thought,
I remember at Abu Dhabi 2005 like people
on the Internet were saying that, man,
is he a heroin?
I because Enzo said something had Enzo
said something like on the Internet where
they thought I was on like drunk.
Will you growing your out then
you'll no, no. You haven't
done that yet? Nope. Nope.
It was hiking the way it is now and I
was really skinny and it was from the
Atkins Diet and people at Abu Dhabi
thought I was on heroin. That was,
that's a true story. When people were on
underground talking Shit, oh he's, look,
he's on heroin. It looks like shit.
Crazy thing is how much you train you.
You train a lot, but you would eat
so bad that you would gain weight.
You would just go off of Burritos
and you would just go off.
So now I'm like on a diet like
part of the day, part of the day,
like w how much of the day?
A good 65 70% well,
as long as you just maintain,
you know,
it's when you let yourself go and then
you've got to get fucking skinny again.
That's what happens with dudes and it was,
it happened with girls.
It happens with everybody. That's the
hardest thing is getting back in shape.
You know, it's not staying and shapes
they can shape is not that bad.
You get some momentum and keep it going.
The one thing to taught me a lot though
is my girlfriend cooks for me all the
time now. She moved in, so we were,
I rarely go out before man in the
middle of Hollywood. I had choices.
That was all night that we want Carl's Jr.
You Want Jack in the box?
You know you can get Wendy's all night.
You can,
there's so much taco bells right there.
You have so many choices in it.
All I gotta do is get in my car.
And what?
What got me fat was the
place I lived at before you,
it was terrible parking.
You got to,
sometimes you have to punt four blocks
down the street just to get a parking.
So if I had a good parking
when I got home after Jujitsu,
I wouldn't been want to lose that parking.
It wasn't worth it that Carl's Jr
was not worth losing my parking.
But then once I got my old official
parking man, you can leave at anytime.
Just right there at three in the morning,
ready to go to your place.
Used to be brutal for parking.
Yeah, I miss that shit.
How do people live like that? That
sucks. That's where live like that.
And I'm thinking like what if he had to
poop really bad and you couldn't find a
parking spot and you
always like champ pants.
It's like when we were
talking about with the,
all the area around the Improv that
everywhere you go on those side streets,
it's all residential only parking and
like you're literally not even allowed to
park there. They just did just saying
sorry. Even though this is the street,
there's no room for regular people.
You have to live here to park your fucking
car here because we fucked up and we
put too many people in one spot.
You can park. That's ridiculous man.
That's the worst thing in the world
above when you do sets and Hollywood.
I used to park my car in the Improv.
I you still let the valet parking but
they let some fucking chick, she was,
she was drunk man and she
fucked up my car. She just,
she was pulling it out
of a spot and you know,
it was a really tight little area and
she just turned her wheel and hit the gas
and just jacked my fucking car and she
didn't have no insurance and I'm like,
why am I letting these
people parked my car?
And you're obviously not looking after
my shit. So I stopped doing that.
You know that that reminded me of back
in 2002 when you tore your knee and you
couldn't drive your Nsx and I had
a driver, you were so mad at me,
it not a driver. He was really mad
at me. It wasn't really mad at you.
He kept like putting it
neutral on the highway
and then dropping it down and it was just
sex. It had a lot of horsepower, man.
I wasn't just, I was driving
caravans and shit up to that point.
And Larry 1972 Ford curry and it was
so funny because I've never been seen
someone so like breaking down
the effect of car has on girls,
his needs tor,
he's sitting in his car,
I'm trying to help him and he's fucking,
he's got pain here and he's like fuck,
he's grinding my clutch fucking
like locked up and it's,
I'm taking him to like emergencies,
not surgery.
We had to go to get an MRI.
The doctor gave me an MRI
immediately. We screaming on the top of
your lungs cause I fucked my knee up.
I was just,
this was the reading of tears.
I've had a bunch of different
knee injuries, but uh,
the most painful one is ironically
the one that healed the quickest.
That's the meniscus one.
Once they did the meniscus surgery,
it was like six weeks later
I was on the mat again.
But when I had my ACL torn both times,
it's not that painful.
Not nearly as painful.
The meniscus is what's really painful.
The ACL just kind of snaps and it's
fucked and it hurts a little bit and then
you can't move your legs wobbling.
Like what the fuck?
And then you go to a doctor and they go,
you don't have a ligament anymore.
You have to get an artificial ligament
put in place and it takes six months
before you totally heal up.
But the pain is nothing.
It's like it's not that big a deal.
The pain of the meniscus tear.
I had what's called a bucket handle
tear and it's called the bucket handle.
Cause you know how a bucket handle can
like flip up and it can like stop like in
the center and the center position.
Well, that's what it's like.
It's like the handle of a bucket,
like literally peels up
and gets locked in place.
So this sliver of meniscus is law and
it's tearing and it's just excruciating
fucking like soft tissue pain.
It's really good.
I had, I don't know what this is called,
where that top bone in the bottom bone,
like I, I twisted my leg weird
and it hit each other like, oh,
the thing in the middle,
I guess the knee socket or snapped
out a place in the top and hit,
they hit bottom bone and then snapped
right back. It's still fucked up,
but it's still,
yeah,
it's still feels like it's going
to happen again all the time.
Like I'm so paranoid
because when that happened,
I was filming a home video and when I,
in the video you can just hear
me scream like bloody Mary, Mary,
and then a bloody Mary bloody murder.
And it,
I'm thinking of a different thing and then
post it. Yeah, you have that shit. It's,
it's one of those videos my dad
has on some VHS tapes somewhere.
I'm gonna have to get
scour your dad's closets.
We need to have a video for this story.
So I never finished the video too.
So, um, you, did you break a ligament?
I think he said he said that, I mean
this was a long time ago, but he said it.
He told me what happened and then I had
to wear like this cast thing for a long
time. Uh, maybe like six months or
something like that. Ever since then.
Six months, Huh? Yeah, it was a while.
Wow. Yeah. The body is
so God damn fragile.
I was in,
um,
we were in Pittsburgh and we were watching
dudes on motorcycles with no helmets.
They don't have a helmet law there. Just
watching them drive around like, God,
you silly fuck.
Like your body's so fragile.
You don't even know you.
If you knew what could happen to
your head if you hit the ground,
would you be willing to roll those dice,
which you really be willing to just get
on a bike with a bunch of people and
trust them not to slam into you.
Trust them.
Not to smash your fucking
head off the concrete. Really.
You didn't just trust him.
The problem with motorcycles is that the
reason you get it is because you want
chicks to see you on the motorcycle.
The helmet, they can't see you.
So that's why there's hardly guys
they like had found a loophole.
They just a little cap on the fucking
top. They want their face exposed. Man.
It always goes into that with you.
It always goes to his
dudes were in that Nsx.
We're driving around,
I'm a fucking pain.
Eddies driving and dropping it down
to fourth gear on the highway and she
doesn't know what the fuck
he's doing. Right. While he's
looking around, he's like,
damn, check show looking at me
man. Cause I'm looking at me.
They never look at me in my fucking
Bronco are looking at me like that bitch
right there. She's looking at me, man.
She's looking at me right now. Explore,
explore.
I'm sorry
dude. When we would drive, we would drive
your Barracuda, the big fish, a catfish,
catfish, sick fish. Old
Men wanted a soccer dad.
They were like pulling up going
whole, everybody that was, you know.
Have you ever been in his car driving
around? Everybody says Holy Shit,
like 15 year old dudes that are rappers
and shit look over and trip out.
You know it's, it's too ridiculous. It's
too, it sounds like a tyrannosaurus rex.
Someone like machine when you rather,
how does it sound?
I forget slot a lot.
I used to have that.
My friend just did a photo shoot with
that kit from the original knight rider
car from the 80s though. A
photo shoot with a kit. Yeah.
And now it's like thinking wow,
some guy owns kit and he rents
it out like some that, yeah,
I think it's an Asian businessman and
he rents it out and I'm thinking, wow,
they actually let kit mixed with porn.
That's weird to me.
I guess I can have control.
Yeah. Isn't that weird though?
I think after 25 years it's like
public domain or so I wonder if it is,
some things are right on some movies,
public domain and like books are public
domain. Yeah. A certain amount of time.
Yeah. How many, how many years
is it comfort with theater?
I think you could do anything
you want with those lines.
You can start your own TV station.
I'm just putting nothing because
it cost,
it costs more to just get the,
keep the license going then if they're
worth really so no one owns them.
Literally you can't nobody.
Yeah, nobody owns it.
Nobody owns in the public domain.
How many movies you think, dude,
I'm not an expert in this panel.
There's nobody in the public.
Once I plug public domain,
you've got to get the shit
registered every 25 years or so.
And if there's no one there to register
and most of those guys are in China and
they're dead from the triads
and nobody's allowed to
the mine from my old taekwondo days,
my friend Larry Jones,
Larry Jones was a phene for Chinese Kung
Fu movies and he would always go and
he would like come to the
gym the next day. Oh Man,
I saw this bad ass Shaolin
is Shaolin seven months.
He would like every week it will be some
new fucking Kung Fu movie that he just
saw and loved and he would get together
with a bunch of his friends from the gym
and they would all go
watch he's come from,
would they get excited and while she's
there was like real fighters and they're
going to watch these shitty Kung
Fu movies and I try to watch them.
I never got it. I tried, man. I sat
down and then I tried to watch them.
That's the problem.
Anybody who got Bruce Lee first
is not into comfort with theater.
I don't think so. How could you
tried? You know what I mean? I think,
I dunno what it is really.
That's just my guess.
But after on Bruce Lee or like fuck
these guys are, everyone's trying to,
I mean there was Bruce lies about
that. He's more than one, right?
How many downsides were there? How famous
was he? Was he famous like in China?
Was he going to them popping bottles?
You know what I mean?
For a couple of years we've probably
got laid. He was like Dan Cortez.
That's how dumb these
people think the people are,
that they could just put a fake Bruce
Lee up and a good percentage of them
automatically get to know the difference.
Is it because they,
he was almost playing a character,
would you think like maybe like he was
almost like a James Bond put out game of
death. They only had 10 minutes
of that movie with Bruce Lee tree.
The whole movie is not Bruce Lee.
It's a game of death.
The beginning is,
but the beginning of game of death
is the end of return of the Dragon.
They start with the Chuck Norris fight,
so it looks like a Bruce Lee movie,
but that's another movie.
So they replayed that scene again,
the exams in the beginning, that's how
the movie started. Game of debt starts.
The only thing that's Bruce Lee is the
end where he goes up and fights, fights.
Kareem Abdul Jabbar, that's
all him, but everything,
the whole movie is an
imposter. I need to see. Wow.
I need to see that again to every
year and there's a beginning.
There's a scene where the big
Muesli sitting in his dressing room,
because this is how they started,
they start the movie with the fight with
Chuck Norris and return of the Dragon.
And then the movie is about a famous
soup martial arts superstar loosely based
on Bruce Lee. So once all the credits are
over and the fights over, they go cut.
And then Bruce,
I think Bruce Lee walks offset.
Like all of a sudden
that was just a movie,
that fight scene and it's about a
famous actor and the Chinese tried,
they're trying to control them or
whatever. So from that point on,
it's a fake Bruce Lee. The whole time
he's sitting in his dressing room,
he's talking to this guy, this
mafia guy, and they put a picture,
a still picture like right where his
head's at. There's a still picture.
So it's a Bruce,
a picture of Bruce Lee.
You could see the guy's shoulders
are moving. It's a moving picture.
That's how bad it was.
And everyone wants to see this.
I don't want to believe I was seven years
old when that shit came out and get to
know the difference. I didn't know
the difference. They fooled me.
They pulled the kids maybe back then.
That special effect actually
for the adults too and the
whole movie he's got big
shades on and they never get any closer.
It's always from the side
and he's got big shit.
I wonder how much that one would be cost.
How much does that cost to make?
And they probably made a fuck
load of money with it too. Right?
Cause people probably saw your movie.
They didn't have fucking Yelp back then.
They didn't have fan Dora.
You know what I mean?
You can't look find out how bad a movie
was by just going online. Like now.
Well now you find out real quick.
If a movie's a piece of shit,
it's like it could be out a couple hours
and people were already freaking out
about it. Yeah, it may even
before, because people get
screeners, they get, they get,
they get previews before
people go to previews.
You can't sneak a shitty
movie through anymore.
The bank and that the amp committed
took weeks before everybody figured out.
That movie sucked. Yeah, I came
up with that. Yeah, the kids,
I thought it was great because the
end is a class. It's still Bruce Lee.
They ended strong. He fights down in a
Kareem Abdul Jabbar, some taekwondo guy.
All that Shit's beautiful. Yeah,
that was pretty bad ass and that's,
that's really the only seen people like,
remember when they watched as a kid,
you remember, remember game of death.
He's finding Kareem Abdul Jabbar.
That's really all you remember. You don't
remember all the bullshit fake shit,
but when me and my friends are talking
about the best Bruce Lee move move ever
to Wa, the the Best Bruce Lee movie ever
was actually done by the fake Bruce Lee.
If guy was holding him,
a guy who was holding him like this,
he came from [inaudible] and held them
and the fake Bruce Lee did a backflip,
kicked him and landed back on its feet.
It was a fake Bruce Lee.
The vape was there from
game of Dad. He, the guy
did a backflip, kicked him,
and then landed on his feet.
I wonder if that one dude is
that he still goes around.
You remember that scene came of, he looks
like Bruce Lee. It's not loosely ads.
Meek. We need a documentary on
the fake Bruce Lee. All of us.
Well we need a documentary
on the guy who did that flip.
But that was cuts in it. So it wasn't
like one thing, you know, it was,
there was some cuts and so it wasn't
just some wild kamikaze type shit,
but that wasn't the top three
of best Bruce Lee moves ever.
And it wasn't even him.
When I met Chuck Norris,
who was one of the few times in my
life where I was genuinely freaked out,
like, like I'm shaking his hand,
I'm going to meet him and him to,
and he knows who I am. He's talking
to me and I'm like, Holy Shit,
this is Chuck Norris.
Like this is really Chuck Norris.
And the third thing I thought about
was that movie with him and Bruce Lee.
And I'm like, this motherfucker
fought Bruce Lee in a movie.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean that is a crazy scene too.
He's like the bad ass karate guy and
then loosely and him go at it. Holy Shit.
That was a good scene. It be hard
to top Bruce Lee. Just the base.
I used to like Chuck Norris because Chuck
Norris was down with Bruce Lee because
by association, even though Chuck
Norris wasn't as dynamic as Bruce Lee,
he was still in a Bruce Lee movie,
you know,
and there was some cool shit
about him because he was American.
He wore cowboy boots and fucking cowboy
hat and he jacked guys up sort of like a
karate but American style, you
know. I thought he was a high,
low most McQuaid him. David Carradine.
Come on son. You Remember Billy Jack?
Yes. Cowboy with a roundhouse
kick is known for his roundhouse.
You remember he would tell the guy,
I'm going to put this foot upside your
head and there's not a thing you can do
about it. I remember
thinking at the time, wow,
that is fucking a white guy talking shit.
Nobody wasn't really white.
He was an American Indian.
Nobody under 30 remember until the job
Billy Jack, like there was
always these hippie bitches.
They were like around him bothering
him all the time. You know,
he would like take care of the hippies
and he was like half Indian or something,
wasn't he?
I don't fucking know.
That'd be cool if Chuck
Norris flew around in Airwolf.
You don't like that was his
modes of transportation.
If you flew around with a giant helicopter
from the eighties you remember those
when,
how did we ever talk about this?
It seems like we did where helicopters
were really popular in the 80s and it was
like blue thunder Airwolf and there was
all these sitcoms about helicopters,
drama shows, drama shows. Yeah.
What the fuck was that helicopter?
It's like, you know, it's like sort
of, we were talking about Knight Rider,
I'll fucking, you know a
show about a car. Right.
But at least that car talk
back then was just like, no,
that's just a bad ass helicopter.
Remember was Roy Stridor Scheider
yes. In blue thunder, blue thunder.
Stupid movie about a giant helicopter
went crazy. What the fuck, man?
It's amazing when you go
back just a couple of decades
and look at the shit that
people are willing to tolerate.
People were so stupid. Yeah, I know.
If you want evolution, man, you need look
no further than human television. Look,
look, look at TV shows for like the
50s. Go try to watch like Andy Rooney.
I was watching a clip online. It was from
the Andy Griffith show and it was um,
it was a Jack Nicholson. Jack
Nicholson was playing a bad guy and um,
Ron Howard was in it and
when he was a little boy,
when he was opie who he was before he
was opening preop pre AOP. Wow. What was,
who was he? He was opening on happy days
before. What was he on the other show?
The Andy Griffith show. He was the
little Brat Kid. There's a little boy,
he's a little boy and Jack
Nicholson is there and it's like,
it was fucking phones
on and it's so stupid.
It's just so obviously dumb, you know?
It's like if you had it on today,
you would just start throwing
shit at the TV. Go, what the fuck?
Kind of acting is what the fuck kind of
shows us who wrote this stupid thing.
But back then that shit flew.
That was, that was entertainment.
I can't watch fucking anything in black
and white except for twilight zone.
I can still watch that cause it
didn't happen. They never had,
they sometimes had happy endings,
but you never knew if it was going to be
a bad ending. Sad ending, happy ending.
I love that.
But one show,
one 99.9 of everything back
then. To me, my opinion suck.
You're right. I Love Lucy. Every
now and then you watch that.
There was some clever
writing and I love Lucy.
I mean that thing stood the test of time.
It's still showing it now.
It's still on now. You're
right. Most things suck.
But there's a few that fucking that
really stand out still like the hustler.
You ever watched the hustler with Jackie
Gleason and Paul Newman? The movie? Yeah.
With who the fuck played Burt,
the guy from
Shit I forget,
but a very famous actor as well and
it's fucking incredible. Piper, Laurie,
you know the, that woman, she
played a a check in the movie.
It's a fucking great story.
It's like it's a good well acted movie
and it's from like 1963 like there's a
few who's afraid of Virginia Woolf?
That's Elizabeth Taylor.
Back when she was hot as fuck.
Elizabeth tail was hot as fuck back then.
And who's afraid of Virginia Woolf is
a bad ass fucking movie that completely
holds the test of time. If you watch
the movie today, be like, Whoa,
that was a good guy that I'm moving.
And it was like from 1960
or something like that.
There's a few movies from back
then when they really nailed it.
They really got it right.
Do you remember that movie? I
Africa, the name of it? It had,
I think Joe Piscopo during his big,
when he was kind of famous in the early
eighties and it used to have like this
little documentary in the middle of Johnny
dangerously. Is that the name of it?
Yeah. And John, John and
dangerously was, um, what the
fuck is his name? Joe Piscapo.
Yeah, Joe Piscopo. And what was the
other guy? The good, the guy was Batman.
The first Batman. Michael Key. Michael
Key. Everybody remember the cartoon?
I as a kid,
I remember thinking how cool this was
that your penis in you and it was like
this animated cartoon of this penis
and two balls walking around and stuff.
I don't remember that.
Check out this penis sometime.
It's pretty George.
See Scott was the other guy who was in
the hustler, so fucking great movie.
And that's 1961 man.
It's not even 63 61 they were a,
it's back then.
Damn. They were stupid. Really Mad.
I mean it's, it's a good movie,
but even though it's a good movie,
you could still tell me how goofy
people were back then. Richard Nixon,
you watch him talk of your bullshit.
Radar doesn't go off when you're watching
Richard Nixon. Just any kind of speech.
It like, it's like George W.
Bush. Yeah, that's what I was
going to say. If you, yeah,
if you can't say that because of Bush,
the real problem with,
with dump Alta or right lying politicians
is there's a lot of fucking dumb
people out there, man. Yeah. And George W.
Bush is the master for sure. He's
the master of the dump, the dummies.
But Richard Nixon was pretty
bad too. Everyone else's,
not that bad. Bill Clinton,
Smooth Obama, smooth as hell. Even Ronald
Reagan was smooth this out. You know,
Richard Carter, he sounds like
he's a smart guy. Richard Carter,
James Richard Carter,
you know that fucking guy,
opie Richard Nixon. He's just, he sounded
like a smart guy, but he was always,
he sounded paranoid and insincere in
everything he said. Richard Nixon,
Richard Nixon, he was a, he was a piece
of shit. He was a terrible person. He was,
he was one of those guys that got away
with shit back in a time where you could
get away with anything. You know, the
days before they killed Kennedy, you know,
till you know, till Nixon's era and you
know, you'd go deep. The Reagan did.
P three p were getting away with all
kinds of crazy shit that you can never get
away with now.
You know,
and they got away with a lot of the
dirty fucking politics back then to what
Nixon did was totally standard stuff.
What he got impeached for it water
game was something they all did, man.
We've been doing that to the Russians
forever. You know, I have a buddy,
I guess we shouldn't say his,
who used
to work for the u s embassy in
Russia and he would find all these,
uh,
it was like standard.
They would find all these audio detection
devices all over the place or audio
recording devices and the Russians
were listening in to them.
They found these Russians,
uh,
things that they made were so complicated
that they operated on the swaying of
the building,
that that's what powered them.
The swaying of the building back and
forth actually charged them up and power
them. So they had no external
source of power. These are like,
this was so complicated. He's like, when
when they found that stuff, he's like,
we didn't even know this shit existed.
So that's been standard.
People have been spying on
people and listening into people.
That's just what they do. Every fucking
politician, every president did it.
You don't think Kennedy did it?
You know,
everybody likes to look at Kennedy
like he's says rosy, you know,
beautiful figure from our liberal
back, you know, or liberal pass.
But Kennedy's family was all
fucking moonshine runners.
They made all their money selling
illegal booze and there was all sorts of
people that were just like the tea party.
People are today trying to get rid of.
Obama gone crazy about the
democratically elected president,
Democrat president rather. They were
doing the same thing for Kennedy.
They were wanted for trees and they'd
make posters with Kennedy's face on it.
Nobody likes to think about that
shit because it happened so long ago.
What about the fact that he was,
out of all the presidents
that have ever existed,
he's the one who had the worst reputation
as far as womanizing. Oh yeah, dude.
If they found out what he was doing today,
he was probably just straight Clinton
and bitches. You know more than Clinton.
You think he was? I don't, I
don't, I shouldn't say Clinton.
And because when Clinton Clinton move
is Clinton moves, you get a girl alone,
you just whip your cock out,
you know,
and then they scream and fucking run
away from you and freak out and you go to
jail.
That's a Clinton move.
He's the only president that
probably rocked it that way. Yeah,
it probably is it probably
Obama and in that shit,
you know it's actually shit up. Obama
was probably not what they should do.
A president should be smart if they're
going to fuck around with these,
these interns offered them
and their family a thought.
The underground cities
when shit goes down,
they ain't going to say she was a firm
believer in the underground cities
they're building out. It's not like
that much of a secret. Oh yeah.
I mean I've seen, I've seen underground
bunkers and bases and shit like that.
But you're a friend, you're a believer
in that shit. Like you want to go there.
If the shit goes down. I'm trying to,
I'm trying to teach Jujitsu to CIA.
Give me a couple of VIP passes the moment,
the moment,
the first,
uh,
the first atomic bomb blows
or the first asteroid hits.
I want to be under that thing.
I want to be at the epicenter
wherever that bomb goes off.
I want to be at the part where
all they find a view as a shadow.
That's what I want to be.
I want to be right there.
Fuck that down with some Mad Max shit.
I don't want to be sick not
having hospitals to go to
the song. Yeah, I agree with you
though. You know what a mom drops
and we're feeling the fallout here,
but still alive. What do you do?
Like blow your head up.
No, no. Look, I'm going to,
I'm going to follow my human
instincts and keep on keeping on.
But if I had to choose between living a
life of fucking cancer and radiation and
zombies or getting hit in the head where
media I'll take getting hit in the head
by a media.
What's your take on the Zombie situation?
It's funny how many fucking
shows and movies and things.
People that believe they're real.
There's video shows where they're talking
about preparing against zombies. Yeah,
I mean, the book, the reason
why is because we know
about so many parasitic, uh,
animals in,
in the,
in the animal kingdom that changed the
host and turn the host into something
that it's not. We know of. There's a
aquatic worms we've talked about before.
Take a drink. If you're playing the
podcasts, we've talked about it before.
Will wreak programs, a grasshopper's
brain, this aquatic warm,
it infest the grasshopper
reprograms its brain,
and then convinces the
grasshopper to drown,
to convince is it to jump into water
and drown so that it can be born and it
busts out of this things body cavity
and it makes it commit suicide.
So we know that there's
all sorts of parasites that
changed the host and get the
host to do their bidding. And we also
know about rabies. We know that, you know,
dogs get rabies. That's a wrap
son. They're dead. That's it.
You've got to kill that dog.
They don't even cure him.
You can't cure a dog from rabies,
so you've got to kill that fucking thing.
And if you get rabies, you
could die too. So rabies,
we'll turn a dog into a vicious
fucking animal, like your own pet.
I had a dog that had distemper
once and it tried to bite me mad.
A Doberman Pinscher dove and picture
snapping at me. I was like 12 years old.
I was stuck in my living room with this
dog that was sick and I realized like
halfway through, like looking at his dog
science, there's something wrong here.
I'm like, this thing is really
going to get me. This is my dog.
My Dog's going to kill me. I really,
really thought it was going to kill me.
We had to get the dog put down. It
was scary shit. People that are dead,
they're buried and then they were all
out of the dirt. Those people retarded.
That's not going to happen. But what
could happen is, you know, look,
there's all these people that are getting
their heads chopped off in the frozen.
You know about all that cryogenics
I've heard about it. Well,
there's people that are getting
their whole bodies frozen as well.
Like Walt Disney did.
Apparently they freeze your whole body
and so the one day they can bring you
back, regenerate your body
tissue. I believe that.
Well that might be one zombies happened
because maybe your soul's long gone and
all of a sudden you just got this,
this tissue with no consciousness that
needs food all the time and eats anything
in front of it.
And we'll just grab a person and just
start eating you if you don't feed what?
I don't want to be cremated.
That's the exact reason I wanna.
I wanna come back Zombie
and want to do that.
You're going to kill people. It
could be a cool zombies, zombies,
all the hangout flesh bro.
Do you not learn,
listen to the movie or
what about pay attention?
What about the soul comes back?
I gotta go back while does it going to
be alive and a couple of seconds I've got
to go back.
Maybe.
Maybe there would be the first generation
of people that came back with a memory
of the afterlife when Kennedy died
in south London. And that. Yeah.
I remember when he was playing video games
and having to kill the Mormons. Yeah,
but Kenny died like a hundred
times mean that's ridiculous.
But within the episode he came back
to the lap. That's never happened. Oh,
oh really? Yeah. Hmm. Yeah.
Every week you just came back and no
one said a word about it. Robot chicken.
They had an episode or Walt Disney comes
back to life and he became like this
monster that just ate Puerto Rican babies.
It was pretty funny.
The real possibility is the possibility
that was expressed in that 28 days later
that someone comes out with some fucking
genetically altered super virus that
attacks the human body and literally
turns you into some fucking freaky,
crazy monster animal thing. Like
those 28 days, hard to kiss.
Those fucking movies were awesome, man.
Especially twen 28 weeks later was okay.
It was high. It was pretty
good. It's pretty good,
but it was following one of the greatest
harm movies of all time. You know?
There was no way he can
fucking really top that,
that that thought is very
terrifying to people.
The thought that one day you wake up
and the whole world's fucked and there's
people out there in long
your sleep and they're,
they're coming in and they have axes
and shit and they want to eat. You know,
I mean, that's, it's a terrible fucking
thought. That dot that, you know,
people eating human flesh,
you know,
there's been documented very recently
that they think that it was a,
it was done like ritualistically for
thousands and thousands of years.
And then people have been eating people
like whether they killed them in battle
or that small children,
they found a small children with tool
marks on their bodies that they're
positive and inside their brains in the
brain cavity that they're positive with
someone's scooping and scraping out their
brains and cutting off their meeting,
eating it. So people have been, yeah,
people have been preying on other
people for forever. That's look man,
when people are starving to death,
you know if you're living like thousands
and thousands of years before written
language and people are starving to
death and you're a bunch of fucking skin
wearing savages and you look over the
hill and there's a bunch of other skin
wearing savage,
do you look back at your babies are
screaming in agony because there's no food
in their body and you say,
I'm just going to go kill these
motherfuckers and eat them,
and people did that shit.
I bet they did that shit all the time.
They probably ate their own babies too.
They did eat there. I'm sure they did.
Animals do it all the time if animals do
it for sure somewhere a human before it
became the human being of
circuit 2011 for sure. Someone,
someone did everything that an animal's
done. Animals always eat babies.
I had hamsters man, and they got a wet
tale. I think it was what it's called.
It's a disease.
I was a little kid and all of a sudden
our sweet mama hamster started eating her
fucking babies, man, and
eating them brains first.
Like just attacking the brain. My
mom was like, get out of the room.
I don't want you to seeing
this. Get out of here. Oh.
And I had a car can see and his fucking
hamsters just holding onto our babies
and just brain in. Are you kidding?
Oh Dude. It was fucking deep,
man. You know, that was a
real thing, dude. It was
deep. It was so hard to watch.
I was like,
I couldn't believe what I was seeing.
This mama hamster that I always loved.
You know, we had the momma and the,
you know,
and the baby boy and they got together
and they made babies in the baby.
Somehow or another got this fucking
disease and the mother just killed him in
front of us. Killed them in
eight dumb bro. It was, fuck.
I never looked at that pitch the same
way again. She was no longer my friend.
You are, you're, you're rocking it to
a different set of rules, you know?
I can't really,
I can't just pick you up at pet.
You now I want to bash your
brains on the sidewalk.
You fucking creep your baby and creep.
You know what the fuck man
did you ever have those balls where you
put the hamster in it and we're like go
around the circle and stuff like that.
I rolled around and everything.
I was so mad at my sister once and I
didn't know she had her hamster in a ball
and so I'm like,
I'll take this.
And I kicked it really hard thinking
I was just going to break the ball.
The hamster just flew right out
of it though. And uh, it was okay,
but it was the most scariest thing ever.
It was so grift yeah,
but it was so gross.
It's,
you know when you're a kid and he sees
something disgusting and you're just like,
I'm
not going to look at it.
[inaudible] hamsters.
How Durable Hampshire's this motherfucker
is filming a video and he falls down
screaming like a little
bitch cause cause he's,
he twisted your knee in a
funny way and his hamster,
you kick it across the room in a bar
doesn't even need to go to the doctor.
Yeah. Hamsters. So speaking of people
and their affection for animals,
I was in Pittsburgh this last weekend
for the UFC and it was the same time as a
furry convention.
I don't know if you're aware of this
because I certainly as fuck wasn't,
I had heard of the term furry.
I'd heard it like very,
very abstract. I never sat down and had
a conversation with anyone about it.
It was just something that I've maybe
heard on the news or maybe saw, you know,
an article on the internet or something
that I never paid attention. I was like,
oh there's some people that have a thing
about wearing animal clothes and maybe
they have sex with animals that I had
no idea of the depth of this hobby.
Or I go, well I don't know what
the fuck you would call it.
You know the w this fascination,
this,
this thing that these people have
and this is what the fairy does.
What a furry is, is they want to look
like a cartoon animal like bugs bunny.
I think the terms,
the ampule anthropomorphic anthropomorphic
and what that means is you know human
characteristics and an animal's body and
so they, they liked like Wiley Coyote.
Like cause he stands up straight and
looks like a person you know like that's
the shit they're into.
So they dress in these costumes that
make them look like animated cartoon.
People that are animals,
you know like dog costumes
and Fox costumes, costumes,
but they look like mascots or
things from like an amusement park.
Mascots is the perfect
way to describe them.
They looked like mascots and I guess a
lot of them are wearing mascot outfits
and that's where they get
these things from and they,
all they do the whole weekend is get
together and play like they're animals,
they don't talk, they have
their own language of like
grunts and certain things.
That means certain noises like they've
created like a sub language and a fake
language. And when they were staying at
the Westin hotel in Pittsburgh, they sold
out every fucking room in the hotel.
Okay,
so there's like 600 rooms in
Pittsburgh or the western,
they're all furries and they requested
a giant litter box in the front lobby
that they requested that the west
and put in a fucking litter box.
So this is what these people do.
They go and get litter boxes and they
bring them up in the room and they take
shits in their litter boxes.
They don't use the toilet and they don't
wash the light tubes. If you don't,
if you don't wash, you stink
like an animal. And that's
what we're trying to do.
They're trying to smell that candle. It's
not all of them. I mean some of them,
most of these varying,
no, no, no. There's women.
And to varying degrees of depth to how
far you go into this thing, I don't know.
You can't see. They're wearing this
fucking crazy outfit whole time.
We know what their bodies look like,
man, they don't talk. So you don't know.
You just know she's
wearing a girl's outfit.
So you assume it's a girl and they have
sex with their outfits on and they,
they have, uh, the opening in
their crotch. They're like undo it.
A velcro or zipper or
whatever the fuck they do.
Whip the shit out and just banging each
other right there with their outfits on.
They fuck all the time.
They fuck crazy, huh?
My girlfriend's actually,
before I even heard about this,
my girlfriend's been actually recently
trying to get me to go to our furry party
and she's like,
you know,
we won't have to have sex with anybody
else and no one will know who you are and
we can just fuck.
It's like an orgy by a bunch of furries
and wants you to bang her in front of a
bunch of other freaks that aren't
showering and they're shitting and litter
boxes and they're wearing, and she's
just for the experience. And I,
part of me almost would do it cause no
one would know who you are, you know,
and stuff like that and
you'll see all these other,
but I think just seeing a bunch of people
fucking in costumes like that would be
worth it. And I know it's like so
bad. Some of them were diapers too.
That's the other guy at the counter.
The hotel was saying that it's
a real horror short, excuse me.
Real horror show for the maids.
The port maid's go in there after
these freaks of left. Oh God.
There's litter boxes and
bowls of milk everywhere.
The big the order bowls of milk from the
hotel and they have him bring it up and
like in a giant bowl and they drink
it out of a bowl. Like a dog. Yeah,
I'd be a bunny. Yeah, you wouldn't be cat.
And he looks into my back yard,
Jesus rabbit running around and he was
like, oh my God, look, it's a bunny.
Got a bunny runs and chases it. And
you, you're like, oh, he's so sweet.
Oh Bonnie's Bro. It's so funny. People
would think that. That's a joke. No,
that's, that's for real man. Do you
think you could kill a bunny to eat it?
Of course you could. Fuck
no darling. Maybe. Nah, man,
I don't even like those people say
rabbit stew jokes and all that shit.
I don't think that's funny.
Really.
You really have that much of
an affection for rabbits. Mad.
That's a little loving
creature, man. I mean,
we have a relationship going on and man,
I love that fucking thing,
man. I love rabbits. They look so
cute. They're so fucking beautiful.
And they don't, they don't meow. They
don't bark. That'll make any noise.
And they love massages, man.
They load us. Don't love massage.
She's
like, you know what? Cats, but cats
love massages and they're more, they,
they ask for it. The more flamboyant
and the way they ask for. But you pip,
I pet a cat fur. I have two cats. I
pet them for 30 seconds to a minute.
They're gone. They don't want to
massage no more. Not The bunny. I is,
he's willing to go all night.
I could pet them here
going, there's no way you, you
know my cat spass yeah, that guy.
You could pet that cat for a hundred
days in a row. Oh really? Oh No. My cat.
My cat. You better. I pet him for
30 seconds on how they're raised.
If they're raised with
people all the time.
Like my cat's been with
me since she was a kitten.
So from the time she was a little,
it's all like,
you know what jumped me on me own
pets and everyday it's affection.
So she associates people with
affection. But if you, you know,
you're around a cat and you just go to
work all day and you barely pay attention
to the fucking cat, then the cats like,
yeah, you can pat me down with you.
I got other shit to do. Yeah. So
it's all how the cat grows up.
Bunnies are so cute that even their poop
is cute, but the problem is that high,
that doesn't stay. You know,
that was on fear factor.
We were trying to get
people to eat bunny poop.
That was one of the things injected
by the network. That's bullshit.
Maybe they don't say
drink your own piss too.
There was another one that the network
rejected rabbit shit don't stink.
My auntie in it, I would
totally eat it. Nonfat milk.
My ex girlfriend had a bunny and the
one thing I did notice the negative part
was,
is that there was bunny shit everywhere.
Like little rabbit turds everywhere to
come up with your hand there like raisins.
Yeah.
Yeah. Wow. How weird. I
love that motherfucker.
I have a whole room dedicated to him.
You have a room in your house dedicated
to all around. He's got a whole room.
He doesn't even know he's captured.
I leave,
I leave the gate open
because the gate goes around.
Hold them cause we can't let him
chew the base board. So it's a room,
but there's a gate all the way around
in the room and we leave the gate open.
He doesn't want to leave. He hates
leaving that motherfucker. I got up,
I got a castle form. I
got a Ufo form. If a car,
Thomas Forum.
Yeah,
you uh, you would make a great dad.
Dude. You don't even know the, the, the,
the love that you have for this bunny
is pretty fun. It's interesting to see.
But the love that you would have for a
kid would really freak you the fuck out.
Be like,
fuck that bunny.
The animals take a quick backseat deer.
Every woman that says that she has,
I had, you know, I almost had, I
thought I had it there for a few months.
You know that kid.
He's 15 now and um,
mmm.
Not any want to talk about it.
Whoa.
Just opened up the door
and close it on people.
Did you meet him at a bar or like,
yeah.
That's okay. No, I actually, look,
what happened is I had an ex
girlfriend of mine when I was 26.
She, uh, she got pregnant.
I thought it was by her.
I thought her new boyfriend
got her pregnant, but it was,
there was a kind of gray area when she
got pregnant. Like, Ooh, I think the,
you know, maybe it could be mine. She had
a baby. Your sister calls me up and says,
Hey,
Maretta had the baby.
MMM.
You should come down and check it out. It
could be yours. I'm like mine. She goes,
it looks kind of Mexican because she
knows what Thoreau family thought.
It looked Mexican. So I came
down and I'm like, Oh my God,
I'm, I have a son. I totally
didn't want it. We had broken
up with, they're like, oh,
it was around nine,
10 months ago or maybe longer and I didn't
want to have anything to do with her.
I mean we were done.
I had a new girlfriend,
I was moving on and now this kid
could be mine. I went to the hospital,
looked at the kid and all babies
looked the same to me. I'm like,
you guys think it looks Mexican? I don't
think like, yes, look, look at his face.
I'm like, he looks like me. So I
go, let's take a DNA test then.
But you had to wait three months before
he could pull the amount of blood that
you need to take the test.
So I had to wait three months.
So I broke up with the girl that I was
with and as I said, this is my son.
I want to be around for the
first three months, you know,
so I'm going to treat him like my son.
So for three months he, he was my son.
And by the third month when it was,
we were almost ready to take the test.
I don't, I want him to him to be mine
so bad. I'm like, man, I got a son,
he's three months. Let's do this. Like I
was ready to do it, let's go. And then he,
it turned out obviously that he wasn't
mine and I stuck around for a while and
then me and me and me and
that the girlfriend broke
up a couple of times and we
would separate them and come back and see
him cause I was in love with them. But,
um, it was like a six month stretch when
I came back and he was around two after
we'd break up, he's running to,
and when I got to the house,
he looked at me and he didn't recognize
me. She wasn't sure. And his mom was like,
look,
he's the one who took you to the zoo.
And we're looking to zoo pictures and
he's like looking at the zoo pictures and
then look at me. And he's like,
he's maybe like a year and a half.
And that look right there. I'm
like, man, I gotta I got a boat now.
Got Now's the time to do that.
He didn't even know who I am anymore.
I love this little kid. You
don't know who I am. I'm gone.
So that was the guy in the
picture? No, he was in jail. Yeah.
That guy was in jail. So
anyways, long story short,
of course I think about him every
now and then. Like, you know,
I was in love with that kid. How would
it definitely, he's 15 now. He's 15 now.
He's in Jujitsu.
I found them on Facebook and I went
through all the names that it could be.
I went through a bunch of guys and sent
them messages. I was like, you know what,
I'm gonna, I'm gonna, I'm
gonna look for this guy. Wow.
So I found him. Holy Shit. So,
uh, um, I thought, you know, we went back
and forth a little bit on Facebook and,
and did you tell him the story?
No,
we never talked about it. Whoa.
So he doesn't know. Now his mom,
his mom was remarried.
They got a little happy family going.
I don't want to cause any
problems or anything like that.
I just wanted to touch
base. And, um, I, you know,
he doesn't, he lives like five or six
hours away up north and, and, and I, I,
um, I got ahold of the nearest Jujitsu
school around where he lives in. I said,
man, you'd be interested
in taking Jujitsu. It's a
paragon. It's a Jeff Glover.
You know, Jeff Glover, some
paragon paragon affiliate,
got ahold of the guy. I said,
um, you know, I told
everyone he's my nephew.
I didn't really want to get into details.
It as really matter. He's not my nephew,
but you know, I thought he was my son
for a while. I thought, you know what,
I'm going to get them into Jujitsu. He's
all into it, man. He's obsessed. Oh Wow.
That's awesome. Yeah. He's all facet that
he loves it, so, wow. What a crazy story.
Did you ever think what would happen
if we decided to just stick around with
that little dude? Yeah, man, I
do. I do. Because at that point,
within those first three months,
that was my boy accurate. I'm like,
like, you know, he was my son. I
thought this, he could be my son.
I thought he could be
deep down. I was thinking, I mean
everyone says he looks like me.
I don't think he looks like me. That's
it. Everyone's saying he looks Mexican.
So funny. You know, I didn't
even know Eddie was Mexican.
I thought he was fucking with
me for like the first two years.
Cause at the comedy store you're
like, I'm half Mexican. I'm like, no,
you're not Mexican or you said
something like that to me.
He used to say he was having,
yeah.
You said something else Japanese and
how fast or something like that. Yeah.
You said half Japanese.
Half Mexican.
Yeah.
I used to say that when I was a teenager
just because I was an idiot and I want
her to see who would believe it. And I'm
like, wow, the Ed people believe anything.
Did you use to do that with a lot of
things he used to like tell people crazy
stories and see how far you can go
with it. Man, it's still happens,
I think the whole, the
whole, the whole, uh,
why do you get into doing that man?
Do you have a hard time not doing?
If you look at,
if you look at the [inaudible] and then
you look in and then you look at that,
what we did on the Joe Show,
like with a 10 foot 10 foot screws,
let me tell people, I don't know.
Let me tell you what we did.
We were in Denver and I
was doing standup and uh,
Eddie and Tate and Brian and Dunkin,
we were all hanging out and we're
walking and we went through this little
shopping area that, what does it, those
six street malls and what it's called,
whatever the mall is,
whatever street it is. Anyway,
we're going to this downtown Shami here
and we see a wig store 2005 2005 was it?
And just as a goof we decided to go in
this wig store and then first of all we
were high as fuck and somewhere in this
wig store we came up with the idea of
having a fake band and that you guys
were all going to wear these wigs. So we,
everyone bought wigs.
Tate had this crazy afro wig and you
had this crazy wig and everyone decided
that we were going to play a band called
10 foot screws and we even announced
the band like as having
an after party in town.
So people thought that it was like
a real band and Eddie goes on stage,
I get off stage,
the show's over and he goes on stage
with his fucking wig on and sunglasses we
have video of it's still right.
Yeah. Well there was a whole show.
Which episode is it? Seven yeah.
How do people find that one?
Just type in Joe show seven, but you know,
all the episodes were on your website,
but since you moved to servers now
everything is kind of weird. It was,
there were probably
getting too much bandwidth.
The premise of it was Joe
wanted to put together a reality show
based on him going to all these clubs
across the nation and his
posse and me, Tate, Brian,
Dunkin, Ari, even Larry back then we
were all as a producer when he got,
we were all in this,
that's what Joe show was.
It was an actual origin of the word
powerful. When you hear me say powerful,
it's all because there's one dude,
our friend Lara. So the show,
what was that called? The Joe
show. You had it on your website.
We did about 11 or 12 episodes
or something and episode
seven we were in Denver.
We were trying to come up with a pet
premise and then it was, it was all about,
we just, we just formed a
band. So Joe's on stage and we,
the way we sold it was Dunkin would
get on stage and we'd say, uh, uh,
who's going to the 10 foot screws
showed an I, that's what we call it,
10 foot screws.
And that was Brian's idea.
And so we wanted to, so Dunkin was
getting everybody in the audience use it.
The fact that we got 10
foot screws backstage and
they're playing a big show at
the boy with the holiday, the holiday
home next to me, I'll know sixth,
three to know point logos. So people were
like, oh shit, there's a concert tonight.
I didn't know about this 10 foot screws.
Are they big?
So then it was already there too.
Who else are you wasn't very,
wasn't there for Dunkin was
selling it like he would,
he was like the host
and he was selling it.
We got 10 foot screws tomorrow we're
going to give away some tickets.
So I've got a stack of half
off drinks on Tuesday night.
I got a two stacks of them and Dunkin
introduced me. I was the lead singer,
I was the total douchebag lead singer.
I was like just basically playing the
singer of oasis, but backstage. So we,
I got up on stage and said, who wants
these tickets to the show tomorrow?
Backstage they were going nuts.
So like Paul Stanley,
I divided the crowd to one side
and I said just I Paul static.
Okay. This side, let me hear the noise.
Like a one to let me hear the noise. Ah.
And then I stopped him and I go this side,
it was just a total Paul Stanley in
1985 rip off. Most bands find that,
find that, find that in, queue it up.
Just that part of it. Because when I,
when I threw those tickets
into the audience too,
were flying headfirst over tables that
we're scrambling only to find that number
Tuesday night,
half off drinks and use of
crazy man wearing a wig for
a band that doesn't exist.
Yes. So when the concert let out, people
had to walk by backstage. It was a weird,
the club was set up.
Weird word ever walking out
next to backstage and we
had the door open and dudes
are walking by gone, where's
that bad? So we were,
we grabbed one dude and we pulled,
we were,
we pulled in maybe three dudes
and we pulled him close the door.
Now they're backstage with 10 foot
screws and me and Tate are just huge bags
were total douche bag. Do you remember
those fucking questions you guys,
now that I'm thinking about it, it was
a great guy got down on his knees. Yes.
He wanted to. He was astounded.
Do whatever to hang out
with the band. He didn't,
he thought we were a real band
so we got them to do crazy shit.
He just wanted to hang
out with the bath. So we got, we're
going to have to get on your knees. Okay.
You're going to have to pray for
us. Pray with us like, you know,
band sometimes permitted up before
they go out. Thank you Jesus.
And he would replete, thank you Jesus.
And you said for this dig a hole.
And then he jumped up and
ran away and then Tate was,
he's like six foot four.
He was so intimidating to the guided one.
I like fire back, right. Just
takes sitting there looking
like a monster, you know,
he was scared and then we got girls that
he probably thought that you were about
to try to get him to suck your Dick.
And I keep really probably thought though,
I mean you think about it, you're
some fucking Wacko living in Colorado.
You know some dude who's willing to go
to some green room for some band that he
doesn't even know, never heard of
before, some van, it doesn't even exist.
He's on his knees praying back and forth.
You in his head when you said that
for this dictum about the saga,
he probably thought, oh, I fucked up.
I done fucked up. I'll do it, but damn,
I didn't. I'm not going to like it.
And that was a great episode two.
And then the other good episode
was when we were on Boston,
remember in Boston and
Ari salt or Aryan Dunkin,
they both sold to the audience to open
up and they said backstage where we're
auditioning for the Joe Rogan life
stories that they're going to film.
And we're looking for guys to play Joe
Rogan. We want authentic guys from Boston.
So the guys in the audience are thinking,
Oh shit,
they're auditioning to play for
play. Joe Rogan. I think I could do.
You could do it, honey, you can do it.
So people lined up and we had a
fake audition. Like I'm this bad.
I probably shouldn't talk
about this. Cause I think
what you did was illegal was,
yeah, I'm pretty sure
we did. I'm sorry. Yeah,
we probably just didn't really happen.
We denied that. Yeah. Yeah. This,
this is all in another dimension. We deny
this. We deny this parallel university.
Bravo does not seek to get suited this
moment in time. This is all fiction.
Dunkin was the director never happened.
It never happened.
This didn't take place.
He can't timber saying it.
Probably.
You just farted. No, I did not
know. I smell it too. No, I did not.
And we need some air conditioning happens.
Did you fart? He wouldn't do that.
What'd you, Eddie, listen,
this is not helping the podcasts at
all. Not one moment. Jewish. Sure.
Seventies unfound double unfindable
when we have it somewhere. Right.
Did you Google it somewhere?
Yeah. It's not even on
googling, right. The, the, the,
the location it was on. It was on your
website. Do you have the raw video still?
I'm sure I do.
On batteries.
You might not have the chance
that you'd lost that forever.
Uh, Brian, how sad.
I really doubt it. Well,
really, I have, I have,
I've had a hard drive die on me
reasonably. We need to find that man,
because that was a, that was a
classic for sure. Somebody saved it.
It's got to be someone out there that say,
I'm 100% sure I have it,
but it's just finding it. Those are those
things. Don't make me laugh anymore.
Those tricking people, things
like jackass type things. No,
I shouldn't say jackass,
like pumped type things.
They don't make me laugh anymore.
They used to make me laugh, you know?
Oh, this guy's getting fucked over.
And like the Jamie Kennedy experiment,
I thought that show was hilarious.
Guy's gone nuts. Used to make me laugh.
But now I don't want to watch that stuff.
I don't want to watch people get lied to.
I remember what what it is.
I became a pussy. It became
super sensitive. I don't
like watching that. I'm like,
you know, you're taking
advantage of somebody for
entertainment. That's not even
I like,
I like my poo Barry flashlight joke that
gets me every time somebody does that.
That was not very fleshlight.
Yeah. I told you this.
I have a fleshlight at my house and
then this guy gave me this thing called
liquid ass.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. You could bury.
You make people smell. You're fucked.
I don't make it. I'm just like,
hey, you should try it. Got It.
That new pair Coobury fleshlight smells
like blueberries. That's not that funny.
It is funny when you see him
doing it though. I've seen
it. I've seen it on video.
You think in real life it's funnier just
cause you get to watch the real sick.
It makes me giggle.
Smell making some,
seeing somebody's face when they're
smelling poop. Just make me laugh.
That kind of shit.
You used to take photos.
It doesn't make me laugh as much anymore.
The premise has got to be good.
If there's a good promise,
you can't just,
it's gotta be deep and good and
it's the best one recently is it?
But you know Jason Tebow, his girlfriend
Danielle, uh, she never did it,
so she opened it up and she smelled it.
She was like,
oh that smells like a homeless person's
underwear or something like that.
And then I'm like,
put your finger in it.
And I had just poured a new fresh
thing of liquid ass inside of it.
So she puts her finger and gets all
over her hand and her whole and was like
poop.
You're 12 years old. This is 36 years
old. Can you believe that? A 36 year old,
12 year old, let me see your Id. No.
Aligna it's motherfuckers
going to be dressing up like
Winnie the Pooh next week,
banging his girlfriend in
a room full of strangers.
She's going to be just up
like a little Fox. Would you,
would you admit though that that's
going to be interesting to see? Oh yeah.
Listen, I would go no doubt about
it. Especially if, you know,
I knew for sure that the crotch and
the ass of mite thing was zipped up.
Nobody could get at me.
Right. You know? I would go,
I would just think they'd be crazy though,
man.
I think they just do take shit
to each other and they just like,
it can get like really uncomfortable.
I think some of them are
probably pretty normal,
but I think whenever you get
an opportunity to completely
pretend to be somebody
else, you get to dress up in
some outfit. You don't even talk.
Everyone agrees to not talk. You get
to see like how wacky some minds are.
Some people's brains are fucking
fried, you know, and you,
you kind of put yourself at the mercy of
being around those people without being
able to filter them socially.
You know,
if we're all sitting around
talking after five, 10 minutes,
we all kind of figured out how
we're each others vibes coming from.
Even like do something that surprises us.
You know,
you find out someone's a little
weirder than you thought,
but for the most part you get a kind
of vibe and some people get a vibe
immediately. Okay, I don't
want to talk to that guy. Well,
when that guy's dressed up like Wiley,
coyote, you don't ever get that vibe.
Yeah,
you're going to have that one Wiley,
coyote guy walking around
creeping everybody out. Maybe
that's what excites them.
Fuck yeah, I bet a lot of them. Look,
I think that would be like a
great thing for a serial killer.
A great thing for serial killer would
be go and hang around with a bunch of
other people that are dressing up
like this fucking Weirdo outfit.
You know this Weirdo animal thing and
you could wear one of those weird animal
things and just infiltrate them and then
hang out with them and a way that other
people are never willing to hang
out with two bunnies. Serial killer.
I don't like. I would assume that most
serial killers like you are around them.
You'd be tripped out by them.
Like most of them.
Like you would get a weird vibe
from them. Most of them, right?
Wouldn't you assume?
I mean you think that serial killers
would be able to just like sneak on by Ya
or do you think you would get
like a weird vibe from him?
I think I would definitely be able
to get a weird vibe from somebody,
but then of course I have no idea. You
have no idea. Right. It's all speculation.
A lot of friends,
the more friends you have and the
more people you come in contact with,
you can spot those in a second.
Like people that look at ideas all
the time and spot them. Fake ones,
good ones all day. Yeah.
This one's different. It's
different. It's not the same.
Yeah,
you're right.
If you have a bunch of different friends
and you run a bunch of people and if
you're honest,
that to me I think is the big one.
If you're a real honest person and
you're honest and the way you communicate
with people,
you can see you pick up deceptive behavior
very quickly because it just seems
off. You have your guard down,
you're relaxed, you're open,
and then you see something
that's like just not quite real.
I just something about what you're
saying. It seems like bullshit. You know?
I think psychedelics also helps that
sense too because you actually see the
person's inner soul at certain points of
doing psychedelics where you could see
their energy and ever since he see
that or that feel, that feeling,
I think he kind of have that
feeling in the back of your,
do you ever go to the movies when
you're high? Yeah, of course.
You know how when you can tell that
they're acting bad. Dude, I want,
I saw the hulk, the Eric Bana Hawk
and Eric Ban is a great actor.
Don't get me wrong,
he's in the movie chopper.
He's a bad motherfucker in that movie.
But in the Hawk there was some scenes
where you didn't really have much to do
and it didn't seem like he was
the most focused, you know,
there's a few scenes where
him and this chick or talking,
and I'm listening to the two of them
talking about like if this is so not real,
like I remember in the
movie theater going,
this is like some of the worst acting
ever. This is so fake it seems like,
so you're not committed
to what you're saying.
You're not thinking
about what you're saying,
but it's because the weed that we just
lets you tune into it, you know? But it's,
it's that way with the conversation
too. You ever, you know,
you've been high before when you,
you feel like someone's lying to you
and to you it feels like even more so,
it's even more shocking and weird if
you're, if you're vulnerable and you're,
you know,
a little high,
maybe he had to touch a paranoia and
then you realize it's someone's lying.
He like, they just feels
fucking gross. Yes,
yes, yes it is. Thinking about
bunnies or anything about that.
I don't know how to break this to
you though. But these are fake bro.
Dude, dude, I got it from amazon.com
okay. Guaranteed. It's legit.
Get it from Peru. Conspiracy theory.
Crystal Skull. That's big foot.
Oh no big fuss on a battle on a man.
You know there's an animal
channel show right now.
It's sort of finding big foot or
something like that on the animal planet
or animal channel.
I've seen the commercials because on one
video was in Spokane this past weekend,
and, and as we're landing on the Spokane
airport, you know, you're, you're,
you're looking at all like the forest
and the pine trees and, and you know,
I started thinking about
Saas, squash them. Like,
I'm going to ask the guys at my
seminar what they think, you know.
So in the beginning of summer, I go by
show of hands, who believes in Sasquatch?
Nobody to school. The Edy's
running. This is how he starts off.
I wanted to, I want them
to know this. Nobody raised
their hand. So I'm like, Shit,
none of you guys believe in Sasquatches
holy shits. I'm thinking right there.
Okay. If these people live here in
Spokane, small city in the woods,
if they don't believe it, then a couple
of guys start going, well, you know,
you never know because of this one,
because of I go, wait a minute.
So you're saying you kind of believe
it? And I go, okay, by show of hands,
who thinks that maybe they exist?
They all raised their hands. Whoa.
They all I go,
really?
They just didn't want to raise their
hands initially because they didn't want,
you know, they would probably ridiculed
in school. Well, here's some new,
there's some
weird facts.
First of all,
there's 250 different native
American names for Sasquatch,
250 different names for this big hairy
man that lives in the woods and the pro
primary, uh, the, the big
predominant, you know,
a group of sightings is
in the Pacific northwest.
You think if they had the internet back
then one back then I won't be one name.
Right. That's 250 people talked about
it and they all made it their own name.
Well, no, they had a bunch of
different languages to squash the best.
That's the Indian name. I Sasquatch.
Like Henry. Yeah. Well, the, the,
the reason why it's interesting is because
so many different names exist for it
because of there's no other, um,
mythical creatures in the, uh, the, uh,
native American, um, like, uh,
I don't think they have like a mythology
that has like maybe different Indians
do and some of them do and some don't.
But for the most part,
I don't think it's like,
you know,
the Greeks had all these fake gods
and all these different, you know,
the griffins and all these different
things that they had created.
There was obviously a
lot of fiction going on.
I don't think there's that much fiction
in the native American folklore.
So when there's all these different names
for this one animal, it makes you go,
hmm, maybe there was a thing
like that at one point in time.
And then there's so many fucking sightings
of these things and that makes you go,
hmm, maybe, well, what
the fuck would it be?
How could there be an ape
that no one's ever heard of?
Then you find out that it's not an ape.
It's no one's ever heard of it.
There actually was an eight foot tall,
erect giant ape called Gi do epiphysis
that actually lived in Asia and lived in
Asia as recently as 100,000 years ago.
And they think that this thing may have
calmed down the Bering Strait along with
American or along with
native Americans rather.
When people first came to America,
America 10,000 years ago,
half of North America was
under a mile high sheet of ice.
So there was a connection actually
between us and Russia and Asia and animals
would come across that connection,
the Bering strait.
And that's how people supposedly got here.
And they think that it's very
possible that at one point in time,
this now extinct animal that they
know exists, made that trip as well.
This animal, they say it's definitely
existed. It wasn't 100% exists.
It's called tall person or no, it's called
gigantic [inaudible]. They have, um,
they,
they found this thing because they found
an extraordinarily large tooth and a
one of these Chinese
market somewhere. And, uh,
it was a tooth that they
knew as a primate tooth,
but it was so large they couldn't
believe that, you know, it was a humans.
And so they've tried to figure out what
it was early man, what the fuck it was.
And then they found some
other bones and then, uh,
eventually discovered that there was an
actual animal called gigantic epiphysis.
Hmm. So what about the argument that
you don't find bones are, you know,
500 errors either man, you don't
find dead bears who wants the bone?
If there's a small population of them,
if there's a small population of them
and one of them died, things that die,
there's a video,
a time lapse video of Africa,
which is obviously much more
predatory than the Pacific northwest.
But in this time lapse video of Africa,
an elephant dies and these hyenas
start tearing this elephant apart.
And even some,
uh,
some lions actually scavenged a little
bit if the thing's gone and three days in
72 hours is gone. There's
nothing, nothing exists.
And it's a fucking elephant cause
hitting in the bone, everything,
they're all just chewing everything up.
They all just take things away.
The hyenas cause smash bones,
hyenas,
they have like some of the most
powerful bites in the animal kingdom.
And the reason why is cause
they're scavengers. They
smashed bones and you know,
bite off chunks of meat from the bones.
I mean, those are just ruthless cont.
They're just there. They're the fucking
total cons of the animal kingdom.
They're just mean, vicious fucking
horrible animals that screech and laugh.
And the females are larger than the males.
The reason being is because
the males are so evil.
They eat their babies all the time. So
to keep the males from eating the babies,
the females have to be larger than the
males. And the females have a fake Dick.
They have a giant full penis and they
mount the males and dominate them with
this fake deck.
It's a giant like arm hanging
from between their legs.
It's the creepiest shit you've ever seen.
This giant female who's bigger than the
male humps the mail and dominates him.
It's a matriarchal society.
I want to fake Dick you,
you kinda real one though.
Brian went to,
if you look up gigantic mythic as
though they have skulls in this thing.
I didn't even know about that.
I thought it was just like a cave man.
Well you know they don't
have a full skull, you know,
but they have enough that they piece
together what it would look like.
You know they have bones and various
parts of jaws and second video that didn't
exist anymore.
They probably don't exist anymore.
They probably did exist like maybe even
just a few hundred years ago and they'd
probably died off or there might
be a few of them out there.
It's really possible.
The thing if you went to Spokane,
you know that as you fly
over that Pacific northwest,
it really occurs to you how
fucking dense that shit is.
There is so much forest up there. It's
hard for you to wrap your head around.
It's hard for you to wrap your head
around over an hour of flying through the
air and it's still forest and
that's what it is up there.
I mean in some dense dense shit.
So if you think that they've absolutely
done a a survey and an account of
everything that lives in that forest,
you're crazy. There's no way they have,
they just killed the fucking a Jaguar
or a panther rather in Connecticut.
They thought that there was no panthers
on the east coast for a long time. They,
I think the last one I believed that
killed a New Hampshire and like the 18
hundreds, you know the, when they, uh,
the settlers first came to the east coast,
they eradicated most
of the mountain lions,
but they just killed one in Connecticut,
140 pounder and they saw it.
There was a spotting of one in a New
York 20 miles away from that could have
been the same panther
because they've known,
they're known to travel like a
hundred miles in a day sometimes.
So it could have been the same
panther that went 20 miles away.
But you don't know where this thing
came from. It could have been a pet,
he could have been a pet,
but it also could have been something
that was living in the fucking woods.
It's really possible. They did use to
exist and there are so hard to find men.
You know, I saw one where when I
lived in Colorado, but you know, it's,
it's fairly rare to see one,
you know,
I've talked to people who lived in
Colorado for years. He never saw one,
but there's plenty of people that have,
but they've got a documented population
of thousands of mountain lions up there.
You know, it's not like they're
scarce, they're just kind of crafty.
They're crafty animals and that's way
more populated than the Pacific northwest.
You know, if you're living in a place
like, like you know, Spokane or,
or any of those areas where they
have those Sasquatch sightings,
it's always like northern California.
It's always like the rain forest man.
There's some fucking sounds that these
guys have recorded and it could be hoaxes,
but people who have studied these sounds
like primatologist have studied these
sounds. They said their
primate in nature, you know,
they don't know what the fuck it is,
but these guys are camping out in the
woods and they hear these screams and he
screeches and the night,
who knows?
The thing that has me curious is that
there's an actual animal and there's
pictures of this thing. Look
at this. This is, this is a,
it depends because I mean look at it.
It's God damn big foot man. I mean,
the real animal is a big foot.
It's an animal that absolutely existed
that that hooks us based off of probably.
It could be. They could be, it could be.
It could very well be a hoax for sure.
Or it could be, there's a big fucking
ape out there, but the thing is,
if it did exist, brow, here's the
thing. If that fucking thing existed,
it would be in a cage right next to the
gorilla at the zoo and nobody would give
a fuck. It's because it's a mystery
that's so intoxicating to people.
We have this weird thing where
we want things that are secret.
We want things that we don't know yet.
Oh, I don't know. Is it real? Is it real?
And we want to uncover
these fucking secrets,
his deep desire to do that more
than to accumulate knowledge.
Like people have a much stronger desire
to find secrets like ghosts or something
retarded like that. Like who the fuck
cares? It goes, have never killed anybody,
you know, you know, you don't get
anything from goes see, you know,
you can't record them on film.
Everybody that sees them,
they all sound like they're full of shit.
You know, you really believe in ghosts,
man. You're going to dedicate
your time to go say theirs.
But I was going to say is when there's
all this shit out there that is real and
it's fascinating, some incredible
shit, the discovery, you know,
they believe that there may be small
black holes traveling through our galaxy
and that can pass right through the sun.
That can go through the sun
and we wouldn't even notice it.
We would still be a little blip,
little blip out there,
and they would just pass
right through the son.
They know that there's a fucking RV sides,
uh,
asteroids that just whizzed by our planet.
Just the other day,
just yesterday I think it was like
really close between us and the moon went
fucking flying by in the same orbit,
the same place as satellites are.
That's how close it was. It's
RV sized. I mean, you know,
that's pretty small as far
as as far as asteroids go.
But if it hit it hit a city
or something like that. Yeah,
but that would have gone through
our r whatever atmosphere,
atmosphere burnt out maybe.
It depends on what it's made out of.
They don't all burnout. The really scary
ones. The ones that are made out of iron,
you know, there's some, there's
some that are made, I mean comments.
When you see the trail of a comment
that's cause it's mostly ice, you know,
that's water.
That's w there's so much fucking water
and comments at that trail is actually
the, the water vapor like coming
off this giant fucking hunk of ice.
Those are not nearly as terrifying as
the ones that are all iron. You know,
the ones that are all water and all
sorts of other other shit, you know,
as they're getting close. A lot of
it's going to go away. But you know,
even when it blows up in the atmosphere,
even when it erodes in the atmosphere,
sometimes it still produces insane damage,
man.
Like there's an area of the Soviet
Union that was hit by a meteor in,
I think it was the turn of the century
and it's called Tom Guskey, you know,
that's the,
uh,
the area and there's photos of just
flat and miles and miles of trees.
I mean,
it just as fucked,
like they got hit by a nuclear bomb
man and there was no actual asteroid.
By the time it got to earth,
it had been eaten up by the atmosphere.
Those fucking things are terrifying,
man.
I want to know if it goes kills that goes,
then you die and you're on
the same level as the go is,
can you think kill that goes,
then he goes into another ghost level.
You mean if a ghost kills a person,
you become a ghost. Can you check that?
Go Sas for killing you? Yeah. And then
you kill the ghostmen ghost world.
You can't kill Gusto. Yeah, but
so there was no dine in a movie.
That's the thing about ghosts. That's
so scary. You can like get rid of them.
If you have a good priest,
a good priest who loves his mother,
but if you don't have that the fuck man,
you can't even can't kill him.
You have to be able to kill a ghost and
the ghost level cause then that has to
be a third ghost thing.
You can't kill him, Bro.
That goes level would be really
crowded. Then it goes, who's that?
They have to trick you on a dime.
You have to like get scared and
fall down flights, stairs and shit.
You have to get scared back up
into an open elevator shaft.
That's how ghosts kill you. They can't
really do shit. They're just bluffers.
You know what's funny? This goes hunters
is a real TV show. It's about one one.
This is like a bunch of his more than
one too. There's a ton of ghost shows.
There's a ton of go shows and
they're all exactly the same.
It's all three stupid white people and
occasionally there's a black guy with
glasses and they're in a basement and they
have night vision on and then they go,
did you hear that?
Sh and they cut the commercial and
then they play music and be like,
why are you playing music? Cut that
fucking music out. And then they edit.
There's nothing to see here.
That's the thing about it goes.
There's nothing to see here
to fucking look all day.
No one's the most you have
is like some weird image,
you know whispery image and again, it's
only interesting because it's unknown.
It's only interesting because people
think there might be ghost might be real
into secret thing.
It might be real crazy.
It all depends on
what you define as a ghost.
You know, something that isn't in this
plane or whatever. But you know when you,
you talk science,
the smartest motherfuckers that have
ever lived with a Nazi scientists,
they are invented missiles that
were so far ahead of everyone else.
Tech in science and technology. Those
was good. You know what I'm saying?
Like when they went down, Russians
raced in a, took half their scientists.
The Americans took the other scientists.
Yeah.
A lot of people don't even know that.
Our space program is based
entirely on Nazi sign.
Never the smartest motherfucker,
Wernher von Braun, and they were
down this,
I mean,
to ancient aliens. I don't
know. According to age,
that is maybe the worst
reference you could ever say.
It's like according to Wikipedia,
you are a fucking skull and bones.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm very excited about
it. No, I am me nice. He's a nice guy.
I liked the guy because it's, it's,
it's a show. It's an entertainment.
Show me talks about Atlantis maybe being
a spaceship that flew off in this guy.
Of course.
Maybe it's a rabbit in an eight,
a giant magical carrot and that created
the end of the Atlantic and empire. Yes,
I did. It was fascinating.
It was fascinating.
The actual facts of what the Nazis were
into and a lot of what they are into is
like ancient Hindu scriptures, like the
vimanas. They studied all these, you know,
vimanas were like these flying things
in ancient Hindu scriptures that from
thousands and thousand years ago,
these flying ships that people have
always tried to interpret like,
what the fuck did they mean by
this? You know, and the, the,
the Nazi scientists were
fascinated by all that stuff.
They were very much into the cult
and very much into a, you know,
the idea of ancient knowledge.
And you could throw that aside and say
they were silly if it wasn't for the
incredible technological capabilities
that they had back then. BMW,
that was, those were, they made engines
for Nazis. Man. I mean Volkswagen,
that's the car for the people, you
know, there was, there was so much,
they made incredible rockets there.
Rocketry was so far ahead of anything
and the rest of the world they were,
they were the innovators when it
comes to the, the field of, of
rocketry and space travel,
pop Warner, von Braun. Yeah.
Warner von Braun and Hermann Oberth
are both quoted as saying all that
technology came from help from beans,
from another solar system.
It never channeling, never
channeling information. Yeah.
To build UFL is they built four different
models of UFS and they're saying they
were getting the information antigravity
information by the virtual society,
which Hitler was a part of and they were
running the Nazis, the rural society.
And it was all based on channeling from
another solar system that there were
this, this chick, I forget
her name, Maria. Oh,
stitch was the head out of medium and
she was channeling ancient Sumerian tax.
And then they bring in a, uh,
a dude who can transcribe it.
She had no idea what she was writing.
It was an ancient Sumerian text and
there's instructions on how to build Ufo.
They built four of them.
It's on record of Honeboo one
Honolulu to Honolulu three.
They built you elbows and they're saying
they build space ships, they build Ufo.
Well, you have photos are unidentified.
Yeah, well yeah, they belt antigravity.
So a lot of the,
the sightings in the forties and fifties,
and probably even to today are all based,
or not all,
but I'm sure a lot of
them were German Ufo.
When they say that they build something
that's antigravity that can't really be
proven because we can't do
antigravity today. Right.
So because we can't do antigravity,
we don't have a working model that they
actually had that we could fly around in.
A lot of that is speculation,
but we do know that they were coming up
with some weird shaped aircraft. I mean,
some photos of them with these
saucer looking a Nazi ships,
like actual undisputable photos.
They didn't fly. Who knows?
Who knows if the flu or not?
I don't know.
Do you know that they didn't find it
did fly me back then that for models?
Well they had planes,
man. I mean, they could,
they could make one of those fucking
things flying the jet engine, you know,
I don't know if it would, uh,
obviously it would be any good. I mean,
it might suck.
Maybe that's why they stopped using it.
There's a funny picture online of a
Adolf Hitler with, uh, with an alien.
I think he's just in the center
then. Adolf Hitler. Dude,
don't even say shit like that
on my podcast pitch. This don't,
you didn't pay attention to what's
happened to fucking Tracy Morgan.
Just talking about Charlie Chaplin.
There's a, there's all these weird photos.
Are these fucking these things
at the Nazis built? Man,
I wouldn't know how many of these photos
are hoaxes and how many of them are
legit, but it's a pretty
fascinating man. It's,
to me the most fascinating part is
that they were using mediums to channel
aliens from another rep and how
do we know that? That's true.
Is that an ancient aliens then? It
was probably the u s government. Yes.
What are you doing? What am I looking for?
The, what's the size of royal society?
Spell that. R. I. L so sorry.
Yeah, it makes me wonder if
maybe they were just really
dumb. Yeah. He's like, yeah,
we're talking to aliens and,
but they were really talking
to our government and we're
like, oh yeah. Well, yeah.
Well, you know, you can poo
poo all you want.
The idea of secret societies,
but the bottom line is almost every single
fucking president has been a part of
one of those fucking things in high
school or in college. Rabbit's gone.
Bullshit is so disturbing that these
people get together in college and decided
to run shit based on, you know, this,
this bond that they make
when they're in college.
But it completely makes sense if you pay
attention to how people operate, man.
Especially if you could,
I mean,
the best way to keep something secret
really keeps something secret is to have a
bunch of people who belong
to some exclusive group
and they won't rat anything
out. You know, it's like, like, like a,
a group of buddies who will talk
about man law. Like, you know,
you don't say shit about
nothing, nothing to, you know,
what happens in Vegas stays in Vegas. I
mean that's, this is that on a huge level,
you know, skull and bones is
basically what happens in Vegas,
stays in Vegas on the biggest level
possible, raping the world, causing wars,
doing all this crazy shit and doing it
under this premise of we're all a part of
this group that agrees to be
running the world in secret.
What happens in Iraq stays in Iraq
and they put in, they're asking,
they're asking each other to join
this thing and so to join it,
they make them do some really
embarrassing shit. Like, you know,
you hear different stories from Soc Cox
to let guys piss in their mouth or to
all sorts of weird shit and
they get it all on film.
And this is how you become a
member in this, this group.
Everyone has to do these things,
dress up like a diaper,
let dude shit in your hair like that.
Just the most fucked up thing possible.
And they film it so that they always
have you. Yeah, but who the fuck knows?
That sounds like,
that sounds like some shit that you're
saying in your mom's basement and there's
like wood paneling on the wall and
you're doing bong rips like dude.
And then they totally make you eat shit.
Really? Yeah, man. So my cousin said,
my cousin said that was real.
Eddie likes super eight.
It was all right. Yeah. That's how
I felt too. People got mad at me.
We talked about last week I gave
some spoilers away. I would see it.
I'd see it again. I mean if I
didn't know any better, if I,
if I didn't know that the plot, I
would go see it. It's a fun ride.
The fat kid is a great actor of
all those kids are pretty amazing.
They were good. Elliot to his Gig,
they're probably going to be spectacular.
Fuckups later in their life bank on them.
They're probably going to be amazing.
They're probably going to be Macaulay
Culkin, ask it. Just kind of,
they're all going to be on Dr drew show.
Have you watched the new episodes?
Joey Diaz swears it's the best of
celebrity rehabs I noticed. I don't know.
I looked at my DVR the other day. There
was a couple of them, so I was like,
oh Jesus, here we go again.
Lindsay Lohan, his dad's on it,
and Amy Fisher. Is He really? Amy Fisher,
the WHO got famous by shooting someone.
She's on it. She's a celebrity.
She shot married Joe Butter Fuko in the
fucking face and that made her celebrity.
That's hilarious. What kind of a
weird world we live in and man,
where every fucking show is real
housewives and teen moms and mob wives and
auto. Fuck are we doing man, you want to
see real shit. That's not even real shit.
We want to size UFC and all reality shows.
That's like real shit.
We don't want to see fighting
movies but out a fighting movie.
Most of those reality
shows are bullshit. You know that
as much. But we think it's real.
Most people think it's real.
You know what I think it is?
I think our lives are becoming more and
more complex and people are more and
more stressful and they have more and
more real problems and they want to be
distracted with a problem that they could
focus on that they have absolutely no
stake in.
So they could watch people with their
drama and getting mad at each other and
crazy and screaming and this girl was
fucking his wife and he's going fucking
crazy and they're going bankrupt.
But meanwhile,
you personally have zero stake in it,
so you can sit there and watch it and
get totally caught up in it and you know
and you don't. Your life
doesn't fall apart. It's like
Cathartic. Yeah, makes sense.
Totally makes sense, right? Yup. That's
what I think is going now. This is,
if you want real proof that
there's an apocalypse coming down,
it's what the fuck is on TV. That's the
real proof. The real proof is mob wives.
The real proof is real housewives of New
Jersey. You Watch these morons living,
they're retarded life.
They're non introspective,
no common sense.
Not Thinking Ego testicle under
the microscope and can't handle it.
The spotlight's on them.
They don't know what the fuck to do.
They're acting crazy and here their
nonsense talking. That's, that's the,
that's the sign. That's a sign. It's all
going down. That's the sign. Eddie Bravo.
You know what?
We should do Joey's shit.
We should try to get tickets to that
comic continents coming out. Fuck yeah.
I would love to go down there and
start some shit. We should speak.
Speak at comic con about podcasts,
like we're experts, we should speak.
Somebody asked me to speak
at the zeitgeists movement.
This is like guys thing.
Uh, September 11th, 2011. There's the
you want to grow, they want to go that,
I don't know, it's an la, there's a series
of them. It's like guys, the media event,
they asked me to speak in it, which I'm
down. But the problem is meant with,
with all of these things, whenever you
claim that you fucking got the answers.
All right.
Whether it's just like guys throw,
whether it's Scientology or whether it's,
I don't want to equate zeitgeisty
Scientology, but it's too late already.
Did they? They don't have the
answers, man. And everybody's
saying, you know, like,
like if you, if you look at a, there's a,
there's a website called
zeitgeists debunked and you know,
there's a lot of shit that they got wrong,
man. Just straight wrong. Of course.
When it comes to, even when it comes to
the way they were backing up the, um, the,
uh, the, the, uh, the, the
history of, um, of, of religion.
They got all these, these things wrong
with Mithra and all that and it's,
it's been corrected on all
these different websites,
all the things that they
got incorrect about,
but they're so confident in these points
of view that they can put these points
of view out. No, no, no, no, not
at all. No. I was like, can I see,
it's pretty interesting. There's
a lot of this, like I said,
I've been nine one one, right.
It's a lot of, it's nine one,
one in the area and also I have
a problem with it where there's,
there's things when they talk about
the towers and how the towers fell.
I just farther this time, this time was,
was me. That was me. If you smell as far,
don't run away, Brian. Don't be
scared. Anyway, the, uh, you're a,
you're using this as an excuse to
get up. Did you fart? No, I did.
I actually just had to go to the bathroom
and they said it wasn't even bad,
but I'm just, um, in so many
didn't own up for the last one.
I felt like I should only have it a
smart man. Okay, man. Maybe it was Brian.
Maybe it was thing my cat's in
here somewhere. And by the way,
she took a nasty shit and that
litter box in the bathroom,
it might be that walk out here.
What percentage is explosive and which
percentage of solid loaves? Well,
I've been eating a lot of lettuce lately
and I've also been drinking this new
thing. Uh, this, this, um, this
vegetable drink. It's amazing,
man. I got this Vitamix,
you know Kevin James loss 80 fucking
pounds, right? Kevin look great dude.
His face skinny, he looks so healthy.
It looks like vibrant. It's crazy.
And he got on Chubby at all while he's
still got a gut. He still, he look dude,
he was 300 fucking pounds.
He's got extra skin, you know,
but he's in way better shape then.
Awesome. Almost since I met him,
I met him in 91,
maybe somewhere around then.
And this is about as healthy as I've
ever seen him as far as like his diet and
what's what he's doing. And he got this
Vitamix thing and he swears by it, man.
He's like, he's like, he
told me about this book, some
woman wrote this book on on,
you know, how are you supposed to eat
vegetables? And that, the problem is,
you know,
your,
your body spent so much time digesting
food and breaking food down that it
causes a lot, uses up a lot of
energy. So she has this, um,
she tells you to take this blender and
you blend all your vegetables together.
So I blend like Kale and I blend cucumbers
and I blend like a pear and in some,
some, some, um, some
ginger and some celery,
a bunch of shit together into this
drink that looks like the hulks loads.
That's what it looks like,
just as green crazy drink.
And I drink this shit and first of all,
my shit,
full clothes out of me like a
river. No, nicely, just nicely.
Just slides out like,
like if you were logging on a river
and it was a nice strong current to the
river and you unloaded
a whole truckload of,
of logs into this river to take them
down hill. And then he just went, ah,
just traveled down hill. That's what
it's like when I take a shit. My,
my logs just traveled down hill.
Ah Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So it comes out nice.
You don't ever have explosive. No, no, no.
That's probably Mexican
for the 5% much time.
You know what that is 100% that what
that is, it's a food allergy. A,
you should get tested with food allergies,
cell test,
everything and give you a percentage up
and down that how allergic you are at
that rate of explosive shit. It's food
hours. You'll be surprised your body.
Cause it's after I eat. Yeah. Yeah.
It's probably most likely bread.
I bet you have a food allergy to bread
and it might not be like you can't eat
bread, but definitely be
talking to the microphone more.
So I think a lot of people
have a analogy to gluten. Jeff,
Jeff's wife has me. That's
exactly what it probably is. Yeah,
it's a real common one.
Apparently it's not that good for your
body to be eaten bread. Apparently bread,
even though it fills you up, you know,
bread, you know as great for poor people.
You know,
you take your wheat and you make your
bread and it fills your belly and it gives
you carbohydrates. Apparently you
body doesn't like breaking it down,
especially processed white
flour. Apparently that's
just just glue. You know?
It's just like funky glue like you're
supposed to eat. Like Ezekiel bread,
like Ezekiel bread is really good for you.
I love that shit.
I have zeal bread with peanut
butter in it. I don't even feel like
I'm doing anything bad. You know?
I don't feel like if I have a peanut
butter and Jelly Sandwich on whole wheat
bread, I'm like, how much sugar is in
this man? This is all sugar, you know?
But if I have like some a Zico bread
with some natural peanut butter,
I don't feel bad at all. It's
terrific for all the time. Great.
Can we have a moment of silence for
Fogo de Chao? I love that place. Oh,
what fun is silence. Why don't you
fucking go, there's one in Los Angeles.
I was going to say, I went there
two days ago. Did you guys,
we need to do another
desk squad trip there.
This is what we're going to do folks.
We're going to take a
trip to the salt and sea.
Eddie and I talked about
it as soon as he showed up.
I got a book here on the salt and sea
and I got to documentary sitting on my
desk because being the retard that I am,
whenever a subject comes up on the podcast
or that I get up said hip too, um, I,
I get fascinated by it and the salt and
sees the thing that I've been so I'm so
fascinated by it lately.
And apparently Eddie says that Sonny
Bono was the guy that was trying to save
the salt and sea trying to bring it back
and apparently it can be brought back.
Yeah, it could be according
to the documentary they,
which documentaries
this is it any of those?
This one plagues and pleasures of the
salt and seeing plagues and pleasures of
the salts. And isn't that a John
Waters documentary? I'm not sure,
but it's amazing. It is. Gotta see that
them pleasures on the salt and sea. Yeah,
I just received it because somebody
sent me hip to a, a video online.
They linked it to me on
Twitter and I tweet retweeted
it. Yeah, it quite open it.
It was a while back, maybe a
couple of weeks ago. And uh,
I watched this video online
about this ocean inside,
I mean almost like an ocean that's huge.
Manmade Lake inside of California's
coast. And I was like, what the fuck?
This is nuts,
man.
And then it talks about how
toxic it became because of
the runoff from all these
different farms and that
it got saltier and saltier.
The point where like a lot of the
animals of the fish just fucking died.
And these people still live there
and in the city got flooded, flooded.
That's what fucked everything. Okay.
And when you see it, man, you're like,
what the fuck?
It looks like like some crazy,
it looks like some Mad Max shit
like we were talking about.
It looks like Armageddon.
Yeah,
so we're going to do a desk
squad photo shoot from out there.
That's what we do live there. Yeah.
There's 400 people that live there.
That's incredible. It's cheapest. Fuck.
You can buy a house for
our property for like man,
it's, it's a, it was a three
it was probably $3,000 a month.
You can buy a lot time. Does it take to
drive out there? It takes about two hours.
We should build a death squad
studio at the salt and sea.
Just do once a month salt and see shows.
If I buy a house for 300 or 3000 bucks,
you could probably buy 300 might be 300
but I think it's 3000 some of the people
that they showed that live there,
it's seriously,
they're like crazy homeless
people like meth heads.
Well that's okay as long as we
don't leave any equipment behind.
But what if we like have
a place and we set it up,
we get some couches in there and shit,
get an internet connection,
bring our laptops so we don't
really have to have equipment there.
Bring our laptops and our mixer set
that shit up and do like a weekly or a
monthly show from the salt
and sea. It's scary. Salty.
I mean there was a thriving
many French Riviera right in
California, two hours away. Jack the,
I think it's the biggest manmade
lake in the country. Yeah.
And it's the biggest body
of water in California.
It was thriving in the 50s all the,
they were building all these condos and
houses. People were moving out there.
It was amazing. They're like fuck palm
springs, you ain't got no Goddamn Lake.
They were going and salt and sea
and then they had a big flood.
Like the levees broke and all this
shit cause was all manmade, flooded,
everything out.
People freaked out.
And there's still people today that are
living there that were there waiting for
it to come back. They were back. They
all, they remember the good old days. Wow.
And it's dark. It's like, uh, it's like,
um, it's really is a ghost town.
It reminds me of like California.
Remember Brad right
head and uh,
and David Duchovny.
Remember the whole, yeah. Cal
California ghost towns like this.
I'll do you've juke driven from California
to Vegas before you've done that,
right?
Did you go with me?
We drove and you and me and Dimitri and
we stopped off in one of those little
ghost towns where they
had like a fake gun fight.
Do you remember that Shit that was
happening? It wasn't, you know, it was,
it was me,
Dimitri.
Then we were headed to Vegas to see the
k one that we went to one with a couple
of times. We did a case that we
did a couple of k one trips. Yeah.
Well back then there was no UFC in
Vegas is so old school were going,
there was no UFC in Vegas. So Eddie
and I would want to go see fights.
We'd have to go see k one Vegas.
Scott Coker used to promote k one and
Vegas and it's got hardly no one there.
It's tiny little ballroom.
The Bellagio. A ballroom.
It was as big as are tough enough
is, yeah, just like that. Exactly.
We'll tell people don't know
what tough enough. It's tough.
And I was a local amateur show in Vegas
and we would go down there and there'd
be, you know, a few hundred people and
you'd get to see fucking Peter Arts,
Peter Arts, fos, Stefan Leco, you know
like high level top of the food chain.
K One guys. We're going at it, man.
It was some great fucking fights.
The K K one in Vegas was awesome.
They should bring that back.
I tried to talk to Dana about
that. I tried to take, dude, man,
maybe you should fucking get
involved in k one k one in.
I'm telling you to think about what's
the most exciting aspect of the UFC.
It's striking, right? You get the
best strikers in the world. Look,
I love watching Abu Dhabi.
I love watching Marcello Garcia
and and Pavel Popovich go after it.
I love watching Chaco Ray and Hodgett
Gracie go after it in in Abu Dhabi because
they're the elite of the elite grapplers.
I also like watching elite of
the elite strikers, you know,
in just straight up striking.
There's a lot of guys,
you don't get to see their full striking
skills in the UFC because they're
always worried about getting taken down.
They're always worried about getting
submitted. They're always worrying about,
you know,
dealing with certain things.
So it's hard for them to relax
and just get into the striking.
But if you watch like that k one max,
you ever watched that Shit Dude?
I'll be honest with you man. I try
to watch it. It's hard to watch it.
Is it really? Yeah. I'm not
that into it, man. I tried to,
maybe it's because you don't
have a striking background man.
Maybe that's what it is to
me. It's exciting. It's fuck.
That's all I watch when I watch a fights,
when I have the garage and I'll have
the set up in the garage. When I work
out all, I watched the k one Max I saw.
It's hard for me. [inaudible] fights.
I watched up crazy motherfucker.
Those fights are wild dude.
All that fucking just
straight stand up man.
When their leg kicking the shit out of
each other and flying knees and Tude you
can, you can't wash that. That
doesn't just an extension. I want to,
I want to like it, but it's boring as
hell. Wow. That's so weird. I want it.
It's gotta be, because that's not your
background because it's like, look,
I like watching pool.
I watched professional pool.
I've got hours of pool on my laptop.
I got like maybe 10 15 hours of pool
matches on my laptop at any given time.
So if I'm ever in an airport by myself,
Ooh,
I'll watch Mika eminent play F and Reyes
and I'll sit there and watch a pool
match that I already know that the,
the result. Got It. You got to be God
that wants it happily. If I'm gonna
watch striking, it's gotta. It's gotta.
There's gotta be a threat of the fight
going to the ground. I mean, really,
if I'm going to watch striking, it's
going to be check Congo and Pat Barry.
That's what I'm going to watch.
You know what I mean? Right.
There's a threat of going down there
on the floor. They didn't stop it.
I mean that fight could have been
stopped two different times easily.
Was that not the craziest end of
a fight you have ever seen? Ever?
This is the greatest comeback
in the history of combat sport.
I was watching it with a friend who
doesn't train. He'd done it. He didn't,
he was just telling me right before the
match. He goes, I hate it when people,
when a fighter hurts another fighter and
he goes down and then he jumps in his
guard and then strives to knock them out.
Why doesn't he just let them
get up and stand up? I go,
well a lot of times when a guy has hurt,
he throws hay makers and,
and if you catch one of those haymakers
while you think you have him hurt so
many fights can just turn it at the
blink of an eye. You want to get them,
you know your natural instinct is,
I got them hurt.
Let me put them in a spot where there's
no way he's gonna knock me out. Exactly.
So people just, that's a natural
instinct. I got you hurt.
Let me ground and pound you now and I
know for sure that there's even strikers
do that all the time, man. Yes,
exactly. They get on the wrong side.
They'll climate guys guard and we were
just talking about that and it happened.
Yeah.
Pat Barry would have just took him
down and pounded them on the ground.
That wouldn't have happened. Did you
ever see a Diego corrals and a Castillo?
No. You never saw that fight? It
was the boxing equivalent to that.
Jose Luis Castillo and Diego corrals,
dio corrals was fucked up.
He was getting dropped and battered
look at the fight was almost stop, Bang.
He connects and corrals goes out.
It was just like that.
I mean almost except there was
knocked down and they counted.
The excitement level of this was higher
because there was no counting, you know,
it was like the fight was
almost over at any second.
And literally Dan Merch Leon,
I got on top of them was going to
touch them and stopped the fight.
Like he had his hands over
them to stop the fight.
But then check Congo went for a single
and he changed his mind like a brilliant
decision and a lot of people said,
oh you should have stopped that fight
the fuck they should have stopped that
fight. Luke, who won? He won by knockout.
There's no way he should have stopped
his fight. He still wanted to fight.
He still could to fight.
He still could win and he did win.
So there's no way they should
have stopped that fight early on.
It was the absolute perfect stoppage.
You look,
you just know you had to
stop the once Pat Barry
was out cause Pat Barry was unconscious.
That's why I hate early stoppages.
Let them take an extra shot.
They,
they understand the danger they're in
there cause they're crazy freaks. I do.
I agree with you.
You don't like he seen a guy getting
blasted when he's already hurt because I
know what it does to them. I know the
physiological effect. Did you see, hey,
pull this up man.
Pull this up.
Roy Jones Jr can't say spectacular Po.
You're going to listen to this man.
This is traveling all over the Internet.
This is a really uncomfortable thing.
I saw it on my headphones. Yeah, you'll
see it. You're hearing in your headphones.
You don't have to see it because it's
just Roy Jones doing commentary and he
can't say the word spectacular.
You know,
he just got knocked the fuck
out by a Russian guy. Yeah.
Russian guy battered him and the 12th
round just like I thought it knocking you
out. You know it's all listen to play it,
play it. And this is, this
is going to freak you out. I
listened to Roy Jones. It's,
she's starting to slip. Listen
to this, we're going to it
this
region and it's country short Straw.
We sit and he's different slick tech
because he has typical here.
Wow, that's great. Wow.
Has he been at the beginning? If you see
it on video it's even more noticeable.
Like he really was. Yeah. And you know,
what's, what's dark about it all man,
is that Roy Jones was the guy who never
wanted to get hit or Jones was the guy
who never wanted to fight really
dangerous fighters because he was always
worried about brain damage cause he
was buddies with Gerald Mcclellan.
Gerald Mcclellan was one of the best
fucking middle weights and light
heavyweights ever.
John McClellan was a fucking animal,
but in his prime he got in a fight with
Nigel Benn and he cut a lot of weight
for that fight.
And during the fight the fight was ugly
and he blasted Nigel Benn in the first
round.
But Nigel Benn had Matt Hart and Nigel
Benn Hung in there and was there and the
second and third and they,
they fought like dogs, dude.
And they headbutted
and they clashed heads.
And at one time Nigel Benn and him
clashed heads after Nigel Benn was jacking
them with some punches. Like they were
just, they were just going after it, man.
And he,
Gerald Mcclellan took a knee,
he went down and took a knee and then
quit and then sat down was corn and there
was like, Whoa, what the fuck is
going on? And then he just collapsed.
Like he was obviously done like he was,
his brain was starting to bleed and he
had realized that something was terribly
wrong. So we tried to like, you know,
stop. You started to try to sit down.
Like there's so much that a
guy like him who's a, just a,
a furious killer watch like the Gerald
McClellan, Gillian Jackson fight,
Julian Jackson rather if you want
to see some, some crazy barbaric,
top of the food chain, KL, KL,
action boxers going at it because Julian
Jackson was like one of the hardest
punchers ever and Gerald Mcclellan
fucked him up and it's a crazy fight.
It's a fun boxing fight to watch.
But so Roy Jones jr saw that man
and never wanted to be that guy.
He was always scared that he
would be lecture on McClellan man.
He was always scared that he would have
some serious brain damage and he would
get really badly hurt.
So he never took any damage.
He fought so smart in his reflexes
were so good up until he fought Antonio
Tarver. He never really got fucked
up and then he beat John Ruiz.
He went all the way up to heavyweight
and who knows what he did to get to
heavyweight cause he was like 200 pounds
and shredded and that's not normal.
Usually when you do that you're doing
some sort of testosterone or something.
You're taking something and when
a lot of people don't realize,
especially like fighters,
they don't know who to turn to.
They get their advice from,
you know,
from either shitty doctors or they get
their advice from bodybuilders that are
their friends or something like that.
What what people don't understand about
hormones is if you join your body,
you make your body like a
hyper testosterone levels
where they're far above
normal. What happens is
afterwards your shit crashes.
So when you get off this testosterone,
if you take some crazy amount of, of,
of testosterone in your system,
your ball shut down.
So you need double the time that
you were on that shit to recover.
So say if you went on a
cycle and you were Roy Jones,
this is hypothetically speaking and
decided to gain 20 pounds of muscle.
If you are on a cycle of
steroids for three months,
you need six months just to get your shit
down to a normal level again. You're,
you're shit, it's fucked up man.
Your balls aren't working anymore.
You're doing something that your
body's not supposed to have you,
but he's not supposed to
have these levels in it.
And so when your body has those levels,
it's shuts off natural production and
it takes a while for that shit to kick
back in. And if you watch the
difference between Roy Jones,
his body from the Antonio Tarver
fight to the genre Weise fight,
the genre is fight.
He fought at heavyweight and the
next fight is at light heavyweight.
And he was like smooth.
It looked like you had no muscle tone.
It just didn't look good man.
And he did.
He looks slow and Antonio Tarver knocked
him the fuck out and there was a first
time you ever got knocked out. And, and
from that point on it was all downhill.
And then he fought Glenn Johnson
and Glen Johnson fucked him up.
Glen Johnson knocked him unconscious,
dead, stiff legged, you know, just eat,
you know that arms up in the air
when they're just out cold like that.
Glen Johnson did that to him.
And then ever since then, man,
it's been a slow slide. You know,
he fought scared against Hopkins.
He didn't,
it didn't go after Hopkins.
He just was happy to win a decision or
happy to rather to lose a decision and
did not get knocked out. He never
tried to win that fight. You know,
Hopkins was just too good for him and
you know, and then he fought that guy,
Danny Green and Australia.
He got knocked out in the first round
and then he fought this Russian dude and
got knocked the fuck out in the
last round and it was ugly dude.
He froze up like halfway,
like like was crumbling and the referee,
the guy looks at the referee and the
referee wouldn't stop it, so he goes,
all right,
pop bang while he's crumbling while like
Roy Jones essentially slowly crumbling.
This dude tees off with two full power
shots and he face plants of completely
unconscious and so then he goes on HBO
a couple of weeks later and he can't say
spectacular. We are, we are
watching the slow slide.
We are watching everything that that guy
was terrified of when he was a 20 year
old phenom when he was on top
of the world. Lighten people up.
What about that rap song that he did?
Can we do put it?
You've got to talk into the microphone.
We can't that you know that. Yeah.
That's all. Must've forgot. Yeah, we need
to see. We need to hear that. Yeah. No,
I don't think we can man.
But now that we're on a serious,
we're on Sirius satellite radio. We're
not allowed to play music anymore at all.
He gets sued. You see this shit? Yeah.
The Nebraska power plant is about
to get fucking flooding here.
Here's a question. Why?
Why do we get the pictures?
Obviously they've have flooding problem
show Eddie that photo because
it's just a trip to see the photo.
It's a nuclear power plant, Bro. Wow.
Why isn't there a wall at least the
size of maybe 10 times the height of the
current wall around the whole entire
place if it's near water or the ability to
get flooded?
Well, there's a lot of floods going
on, man, that nobody ever anticipated.
You know what we're finding out right
now with Japan and what we're finding out
with this as well is there's,
there's not,
they didn't do a whole lot of what ifs
when they built these fucking things,
right. You know, they, first of all,
they don't have any options to shut
them down if they don't have any power.
When they lost the backup generators
in Japan and every got everything got
flooded out by the tsunami,
they had essentially they had eight hours
before the thing started melting down.
They're fucked. There's no way to
stop it. They made these crazy things.
He's fusion or fission reactors
whenever they are fusion or fission.
Which one is it? Nuclear fusion.
I think it's fusion, fusion,
whatever the fuck it is. This incredible
amount of energy in this one, you know,
one isolated area and they can't stop it.
They don't know how to stop it. Those,
the what's going on in Japan right now,
man,
the Michio Kaku just wrote
a really fascinating and
terrifying article about it,
about how the three
complete meltdowns in the,
in those plants in Japan and you know,
there's people online that are in
denial about this. For some reason,
like someone in my mess, my
message board was, you know,
a thread about this
was like, oh, you know,
you're giving out misinformation about
your parents. Not that bad. Like the fuck.
It's not man.
There's video online on Youtube of people
that live miles and miles away that
have taken Geiger counters and they
walk around with a Geiger counter on and
then they take the guy your counter
and they put the Geiger counter on the
ground. And that's when it's fucking
terrifying because in the air,
when you walk it around it looks like,
yeah, it's a little radiate radioactive,
but not too bad.
But then when you put the fucking thing
on the ground is a couple of videos like
this.
You see the,
the fucking levels are off the charts
like way into the levels where people
aren't supposed to be anywhere near
Harris. Yeah. And it's on the ground, man.
It's on the fucking ground because
that's where apparently the, the,
all the radioactivity collects,
it collects on the ground.
So this guy takes this re this Geiger
counter and puts it on the ground.
So I'm freaking out,
man.
So I bought some Geiger counters on
Amazon and try to buy some Geiger counters
it. Yeah. Especially after we had the
conversation about Rocketdyne Rocketdyne,
which is only, you know, fucking 10
miles from here. Something like that.
It had a total meltdown supposedly in
the 50s that's probably where the zombies
would start. Right? In Japan. Yeah. Dude,
I think we should do what Japan is just
to help those fucking people that are
anywhere near that place.
Help them get out and then use that as
a place to store the world's garbage.
That place idea. Your idea. I've been
saying that on stage for weeks. Page.
Yeah,
and I said,
I'm the one that said that like dare you
like to pump podcasts ago. I said that.
I was like, we should use
nuclear places to put our trash.
You don't remember that dude. I send that
to you. Think you said that before me.
Yeah. Yeah, I did, but no,
it's not. Not before me.
Before I saw it on stage and brought
100% I dumped that bitch. No,
cause when I said you're like,
that's actually a really good idea.
He might be right now that I think about
it. Either way. It's a perfect idea.
It's a perfect idea. Yeah. I think
it's an awesome, whoever's idea it was.
Maybe it was yours. I smoke too much
weed. If it was your idea, right.
And then Joe Zombies Zombie
was a movie right there.
A spot where we could just dump garbage,
garbage right into the whole of it.
Fly over in a helicopter and just drop
it right into the, what would happen?
Well hopefully this a, what is that
thing called? That's making a black hole,
hopefully turns into a
really bad black hole.
And then we can just put the
garbage on the black hole,
the large hadron collider so we could
litter litter in other galaxies.
It's terrible.
I D [inaudible] crying,
you know,
they have hyper Novas in space.
They find these hyper knows that
are there basically these uh,
these like really super powerful knows
that I have these jets of energy spraying
out in either direction.
What if that was garbage?
What if we got like really close?
We saw like cans and shit and rubbers and
it turns out that all that shit spring
out was the garbage of another dementia.
They had figured out how to launch all
of their garbage with a rocket ship into
black holes. The planets all
clean, super clean like that.
Walk around with a portable like
connection to that black hole. I saw.
Another thing that I see and I'm going
to report on this cause this is number
nine for me.
This is the ninth time I've seen this.
A fucking guy in a Prius throwing a
cigarette out the window. God Damn,
that drives me crazy.
This motherfucker pulled into a organic
foods parking lot of an organic food
store, gets out of his Prius and throws
his fucking cigarette on the ground.
I'm like, you cunt. You
dumb, dumb, dumb cunt.
You stupid.
Fuck what?
What kind of a person goes so far to
think they're helping the environment by
buying a Prius. He had a ponytail
on so he's like, I'm living natural.
I'm going to go get some natural organic
food and I'm just going to throw my
cigarette right there,
king of the hill episode.
Did it really do and I can get the hell.
He started working at a whole
foods and it's similar to that.
Didn't throw cigarettes out
the window at whole foods.
They had Prius's and never, ever just
constantly contradicting themselves.
Well, it's people, man. I've
seen nine times now, nine times.
I've seen a guy in a Prius throw
a cigarette out the window.
Nine over the course of my entire life.
This is the ninth guy.
I've been documenting them.
The last one was in San Francisco,
the last one in San Francisco. I
saw two in a weekend. I was there.
I was there Thursday through
Sunday working at Cobbs
and I saw two guys in their
fucking Prius's throw cigarettes
out the window. That's incredible.
It's incredible. Videotape
it. Put It on, you know,
do you never know to have your fucking
camera? How like there's a kind of Prius,
let's follow him and smoking.
I know he's got this. Fuck,
he's going to throw it
out the fucking window.
Gizmodo also has a article about LSD
being used to treat what they call suicide
headaches,
which are people that have really bad
headaches to the point where they almost
to kill themselves,
like
migraines times a billion. Right? So
these two psychiatrists have been, uh,
giving Lsd to these patients.
And I think they said like
almost all the patients, uh,
all six patients reported decrease in
the number of cluster attacks and fives
have this effect lasted four
months after they had taken LSD.
Well,
if they had the right dosage of Lsd,
if you could administer it in a laboratory
and you knew exactly what you were
getting. There was an article
really recently that said that Mtma,
which is ecstasy and Lsd, let's
beautiful, far, far closer to being, uh,
available for prescription than anybody
would really imagine really far closer.
I tell you, man, that is one of the
most beautiful drugs in the road.
Credible Molly,
pure ecstasy or whatever it is.
I can't get enough of it.
But what's weird,
it's recently I bought some
ecstasy and I didn't feel the same.
I've normal XSD feeling. And you came
in and talking like Roy Jones allegedly.
And uh, uh, and so I was telling him this
other guy I know, I'm like, Hey, yeah.
So I got the stuff, it looked like Molly,
but the guy said was ecstasy and uh,
and it did this, this was my effects on
it. He goes, oh yeah, that's bath salts.
People are actually selling that as
ecstasy a lot in la right now. It's like,
I've seen US basketball.
Hey, did that mess fast?
So in the house you're retarded. Yeah,
I was doing whatever people get it.
And what's funny is that it felt, it
felt like ecstasy. Like it started like,
okay, here it goes. I'm feeling
good, feeling good, and I
guess I'm tired. Goodnight.
It was, it almost got to the
point, God like euphoric,
euphoric body kind of feeling good. Kind
of, kind of like the ecstasy feeling,
but then it just fizzles off.
Every ecstasy
have that, that that
next day, Blah feeling.
Well I was using on it labs
dotcoms roll on and roll off.
So I had no feeling the next
day I felt fine. This is real.
This stuff really works.
The on stuff
I gave that shit the, the,
the nootropic formula. Eddie,
do you know we're making a brain pill.
Oh wait,
I got to talk about this to
make it a brain pill. We're
making a neutral. No, no,
no. Me and Chris Markus criminal. Chris
mark is doing all the work. We're gonna,
I'm gonna help promote it. But uh,
he started a laboratory when he left.
Fleshlight started a laboratory for a,
he's been on the podcast a bunch
of times and twice. And uh,
he decided to come up with
his own business and one
of them was that there's a
bunch of different nootropics,
a bunch of different like supplements
that can aid in brain function.
And what he did is kind nightmares,
combine all the best ones
and put them together. Dude,
they give you the craziest fucking,
well that's when I had the Arnold
Schwarzenegger. What else? What's on here?
My girlfriend,
I had been letting her have some of it
nightmares really cause he's just intense
nightmares and I didn't have
nightmares but I had intense dreams.
You said after you said that
I started actually realizing,
oh it's because of that.
No they're not. They're not.
Um, well maybe like that,
but this is going to be much stronger.
And this stuff is like super called brain
factors and I like can't go below but
everything,
everything for the brain in one formula.
I don't know what his levels were and
what stuff he had as opposed to what stuff
Chris has had. I would like to look at
the two of them, but whatever it is,
this shit that Chris has put together,
he's thoroughly researched this and
come up with this incredible formula.
It really fucking works. First of
all, it really freaky thing is, man,
you don't get tired on this shit.
That's the weird thing.
Like if I travel all the
way across the country,
you would figure by the time I get there,
five hours later I'm exhausted. Right?
But when I take these fucking pills,
man, we did a show on Friday. We've,
we threw it, flew a red eye. All
right, landed Friday morning.
I didn't sleep at all. I slept a little
bit on the plane. I ate something,
got in the shower, went to the UFC, Wayans
went from the Wayans and got some food,
ate food. W W W worked over my
material, went over some of my material,
gotten with Joey, we smoked
a joint, went onstage,
then did our show afterwards wanting
to hang out with Ralphie May.
Afterwards we went to a
strip club afterwards,
came back to the hotel and I'm still
awake. I'm like, how the fuck am I awake?
And then I realized I took six of those
fucking pills. I took three earlier.
Three. Yeah. Cause I was exhausted.
I took three in the morning and then
three like an hour before the show. Wow.
Woo Dog.
Just figured some shit out man.
That's the crazy thing
is when you have dreams,
the dreams are super vivid and
you can remember them, man.
It's because your mind's eye
that whatever receptors awake,
it's something's awake.
That's usually not a wait cause that's
like when we were talking about nicotine
where it keeps your nicotine receptors
in your head awake when you're on United,
do a patch while you're sleeping,
whatever's in that shit.
It has something that it's reacting to.
Well,
what I was impressed with is that I had
some good ideas and I didn't want to get
up and write them down and I
actually remembered them. Oh really?
That's never happens. That never
happened. It feels sharper. Definitely.
I was going over that video.
You know there's a video.
Have you seen it online of a,
the Miss USA pageant contestants.
They asking them about evolution.
Yeah. Have you seen it? Yeah, I saw it.
Pull that shit up cause it's fucking
fascinating. Pull it up and we'll just,
we'll play a little bit of it. Cause
it's, it's the most ridiculous shit ever.
And they get these girls and
all of them from the deep south,
all of them don't believe in evolution.
They're all like,
well I don't believe in evolution. You
know, and I'm thinking while I'm there,
I'm of course you don't believe
in evolution. You 20 years old,
nobody's ever caveman fucked you. Nobody
ever gorilla. Fuck do you? You don't,
you don't know what darkness really is.
You don't know that there
are shades to man. There's a,
there's a whole progression.
There's a fucking spectrum
of human behavior from really
civilized and beautiful
and nice to barbaric and animalistic and
that shits because we came from fucking
animals hooker. You, you just haven't
even, I haven't experienced that yet.
And your, your little cute life
with your sash on your fucking,
I remembered it all vividly when I
woke up in the morning. What is the,
we don't really have to see it.
Yeah,
it's really a low fruit as low
hanging fruit. It's, it's just really,
really poor dumb girls that are 20
years old and they're asking him about
evolution and they're saying things
that they want people to hear. Well,
I think Jesus put me here for a purpose
because they think that all the people
from their church and
all the people back home,
that's what they would want to hear.
You know, when you're 20 years old,
you're indoctrinated into the world
of religion. What are the odds of,
you actually have a real opinion of it.
You actually sat down and
sorted the shit out.
Most of the time they're just spitting
out shit that other people had been
saying to them their whole
life. You know, 20 years old.
The fuck did you know
when you were 20 you know,
could you imagine if somebody had you
on video talking about what you thought
about the world when you were 20 I was
an atheist at 20 do you got to talk in
the mic, Bro? I was an atheist at 20
yeah, I have a video made top 20 just
smoking weed with a bunch of my friends.
That's all I all I cared about
smoking weed and music. Yeah.
Well you probably just, you
were stuck in Ohio too, man.
You know what the fuck you were
in Columbus. What am I doing?
You're all over the place now that you're,
your shit's blowing the fuck up.
You're planning a 10th of planets.
Are you ever at home?
Are you going out to a
different city every week?
Are you doing classes at Buddy's buddy?
What you're talking about when you,
what do you were talking, you were
saying 10 planets. Planets. Yeah, just,
just schools. But you, you have them all
over the place. How many do you have now?
Around 30.
Wow.
And so you're traveling pretty much
every weekend and do a seminar.
And one of them,
I'm trying to do two a month.
And for me they cation and staying in la,
staying home and I like,
I like being at my house. I love hanging
out with my bunny and my girlfriend.
Just relax and go check out a movie.
Just doing nothing,
doing nothing at home when you have a
day when you don't have to fucking be
anywhere.
So beautiful.
So I try to try to stay home two
weekends out of the month, you know,
that's why I quit the UFC as well.
I was trying to make it to my schools
and do the FC. I'd be gone every weekend.
Just can't do it. Well that's
good that the school, uh,
your schools have become quite successful
now and you, and it's so funny.
I see your shirt,
your logo at all these places.
I would be just sitting there
and I'm like, Oh my God,
that guy has a 10th planet shirt on
and it makes me almost want to be like,
hey dude, what's up? You're
not like, I feel like, oh,
they all know Eddie's take Jujitsu. I
got an already to do it for a year. Well,
one my knee to time. You need
Zell fucked up. All right.
It will pop out of place in Jujitsu. Oh,
probably. I'm not going to risk that.
That was the last time it popped out of
place for popped out once and then once
it was close popping out
where it felt like it did.
How long after you actually injury
was that popped out? Uh, three years.
Four years? Yeah. It was
pretty far afterwards. Yeah,
it was skiing too and it was like,
oh my God.
Did it just pop out to fucking hurt or,
yeah,
you've got to develop a higher
tolerance to pain, son. I, you know,
I just don't have time.
Thank you.
Get from Jujitsu,
man,
you got a high tolerance to pain
because you're always in pain.
You always getting smashed. You always,
when you're next getting choked yours,
your face is getting smushed. You
know, like when you get tattooed,
like some people get tattooed
and they fucking scream in agony.
I fell asleep getting tattooed once,
literally nodded out.
Just you get used to putting it out.
You used to putting pain and then the
any martial art and you're hitting things
and Moy Thai guys, man, they don't
think they get accustomed to paying you.
You leg kicks always hurt, man.
They're going to hurt forever.
But you just get accustomed to that.
You just deal with it.
You know your legs certainly toughen
up. Especially your, you know,
your thighs toughen up and
your shins really toughen up.
They actually develop like little micro
fractures over the surface of your Shin
from clashing and other shins and kicking
fucking banana trees and shit like
that.
Like those,
those crazy tag ions that are
constantly kicking like banana trees,
they develop like shins that like
weapons man. You know, they've, they've,
there's like a sports science on it where
they showed um, uh, Melcher um, God,
I forget the last, his
name, his name, his phone,
but it is a phase a Moy Thai guy.
But uh,
he's a former world champion and they
had him kicked baseball bats and he was
breaking baseball bats
with his shins. Dude. Dude,
it was so crazy to watch
it just swing in that leg,
kick into a baseball bat and snap
in the handle off. Fuck that dude.
He did two different kinds of,
did an ash one and ash bat and a maple
bat because the ash bad apparently is a
little easier. So then he
moved to the maple one next. Oh
yeah.
That is grabbing my shins.
There's such a difference in striking the
difference in your striking in Jujitsu.
I mean, you can get hurt and both
of them, for sure. Miguel Torres,
former WCPC bantamweight
champion posted a picture,
worst Bjj injury ever at my gym and
it's a dude's toe. His toe got broken.
Have you seen it? You have to
see it. You need to look at it.
Do Toe got broken and snapped off and
the bone was sticking straight out. Dude,
it was ha ha, hard core. And I was
like, yeah, that can happen, man.
Dudes can get fucked up.
But it's striking you much more
likely to get Roy Jones and striking.
That shit is a,
that's shit's happening on a regular
dudes are constantly getting brained.
You know,
there's constantly getting knocked out.
There was a post on the
underground the other day,
some guy was talking about getting
knocked out and training, you know,
and how much it pissed you off.
Some,
some new guy came in and didn't
really know what he's doing,
swaying full blast and he didn't get
out of the way and he got knocked
unconscious, you know? And
it's fucking not good man.
When you watch something like Pat Barry
and check Congo does that shit, uh,
does that Shit Register with you?
Do you see that and go, whoa,
like what's what's going on inside Pat
Barry's had right now and check congos
both of them got rained
on, you know? Yeah. I mean,
it was for a fan. It was amazing, but
I would never want to do that show.
I love watching it though,
but I'm not down for getting hit.
It'd be awesome if they could fix it.
You know? It's like, you know, if,
uh, if you tear a knee ligament, they
can fucking get another ligament,
stick it in there and screw it in place
and they can fix you up. Nice. You know,
if you like hurt your brain, they
go do it. Don't worry about it.
We're going to put you in his chamber.
It rejuvenating all your brain
cells and it's, you know,
you're going to be 100% a couple of weeks.
What if it was Chris Markus stuff
actually does that? I don't think so.
What's it's going to be a lot more
complicated than some herbs, I think.
I would think that if there's gonna be
something that regenerates brain tissue
that's injured, it's going to be
something like some nanotechnology,
something that re rehabilitates or fixes
tissue sponsor Roy Jones and see what
happens.
Oh,
we can Shakespearian
off the top of his head.
The crazy thing is he's not even
willing to retire. He owes taxes.
Apparently he was a three
point $5 million in taxes
according to my online sources
that I quickly googled.
How does someone with millions and
don't pay? Man, they don't fucking pay.
They just don't have enough
business manager and accountant.
They just get stupid man. They get
stupid, they get stupid. They just,
they just spend all that money and they,
you know,
they have some wacky motherfucker
that's handling their money.
Just like a kind of guy who would
have a wacky motherfucker handling his
hormones.
There's a guy that would have a wacky
motherfucker handling his money and that
guy tells you like Wesley Snipes
is dude told him, you know, hey,
you don't have to pay taxes man.
That shit is unconstitutional. Look,
I'll show you the closet is man,
they ain't even going to come after you
because they don't want anybody to know
about this. And they're like, oh yeah, no,
they're going to come after you and you're
going to have to go to jail for a few
years. You know, you're a movie star and
all of a sudden you're in jail. You're in.
He's still in jail. He's in jail
right now. He's in jail right now.
He's going to be in jail for three
years. They want to let people know, hey,
we will lock you in a fucking cage.
Stupid.
You need to pay us and you need to let
everybody know that you're paying and let
everybody know that they need to pay.
We all need money to make this fucking
thing work. No cops don't work for free,
you know it's not free to fix the
highways. We need fucking money.
Even if you don't agree with it,
even if it's too much and I agree it is.
It's definitely too much.
You've got to pay that shit anyways.
Side to put you in a
fucking cage. Right? Brian,
did you have some tax problems? I
still do. What's your tax problems now?
The states coming after me.
What did you do a use
TurboTax and blindly was like,
oh I have receipts for all this shit.
Thinking that I would just use my credit
card statements and then I didn't know
like credit card statements
only go back now like a year.
Like if you want to go back in time and
look at a statement or something like
that, they don't let you go any farther
than a year. You can't even find them now.
No. No. Whoa. I didn't know that so
cause I was doing my taxes thinking like,
oh yeah,
you know I got proof of purchase that
you know all my students that like the
bank getting together with the
fucking absolutely tax people.
Do you think that they conspired to like
let's just find a lot of people out of
money, man, we can get a lot
more money that way. Yeah.
All these assholes claiming
the deductibles and shit.
Yeah, it's stressful stuff,
man.
I've had a business lounge are now three
years and it relieves so much stress.
I don't think about shit.
If the government came after me,
I got all that shit under control now.
I just don't do it.
Even though I should be writing all this
shit off that I do and stuff like that.
Now I'm just like, you know what?
Fuck it. I'll just do like I do.
And why don't you go
to like H and r block?
Because it's like $1,000 or something like
that. I don't want to do it. I should.
Is it 1000 bucks? It's a couple
hundred bucks, man and r block.
I was doing that before I
got my business manager.
My girl right now just paid something like
$700 at h and r block to do her taxes.
Really. Maybe just robbed her
members. Like, Ooh, this bitch,
I'm gonna get her to give me a lot of
money. Yeah. I mean, to me, I'd rather,
you know, I hate taxes so much,
so I'd rather just go to TurboTax,
take 10 minutes and do it and
get it sent away, you know?
And then having to pay extra and try
to find money and do all that crap,
which I should do. Yeah, I got to go.
It's also got their fucking complicated.
It's too stressful to think about.
That shit is so fucking complicated,
isn't it? You're one of my movie
drops. I'll go get me an accountant.
When you move the drums, what are
you gonna do in the movie porn? Hmm.
First person does not worth any
money in porn anymore. Dude,
you gotta come up with another strategy
and that strategy would have been the
shit and 1993 you could
have been like Peter North.
Peter North drives a Ferrari and he
did gay porn. Yeah. How about that?
How about that? He's the only one
that got away with doing gay porn.
He did gay porn and they're like,
all right, don't do it again.
And then he came back and did
regular porn from then on out.
He did a little gay porn. I didn't believe
it. Like people told me, it was like,
no way. Not Peter man,
no way, dude. You know,
cause if you're going to have a porn
idle, that's the one that have, you know,
dude shoots these giant monster loads.
But then he'd go and
find some videos online.
It was a dude sucking his
cock and like, hey, hey, hey.
And this dude's bone in them in
the ass. Be like, hey, hey, hey.
And he tried to say there was like a body
double sun to ain't no CGI that good.
Talk about the hungry as butter ward. Can
we talk about that already? Yeah, we did.
I think we talked about it on stage
and time that you came on earth. Oh,
we didn't really, we talked about it
on the podcast. Yeah. Second time.
That is a crazy story.
Good story.
Is it good for the quick version of it?
Is that a friend of ours?
We won't say it. I wouldn't
do that. I think we do. A
friend of ours, no we didn't.
We never did. How dare you?
Friend of ours, uh, was uh,
running a small mixed martial
arts corporation and he found, um,
they did a,
an internet search on one
of their fighters and they
found out that he had won
the Hungary is but award and then they uh,
googled and there was no Google back then.
This is like the nineties.
And they found some online pictures of
him with two dudes treating him like
Chinese finger.
How many dicks in your ass do you have
to get to get that and that in a year to
get that award?
Like I think it's wrong weekend.
I'm thinking it's just what they
called a video to sell it. How much?
I don't think there was really like an
award show. No, I think he won like eight.
It was AVN, Hungary, his
butt or something. Like it
was the name of a video.
The hungry is butter wards
or something like that.
It wasn't an actual award that he
won? No. I mean it might look, look,
we could give out an award
for the hungriest butter. No.
Worst side. Brian wins it.
You know they are. You're
in the business. Hey,
do you know who the Helio
Gracie of gay porn is?
Like who is the master of get
like who just crushes everybody?
Who's the Kelly Slater of her guy?
Gay Porn for gay porn?
I don't know anything about it.
That must be,
it must be a Jenna Jamison of gay
porn, right? Master one more gay male,
male gay porn star.
We shouldn't even be googling this.
There's probably puts you on the list.
Yeah.
Male porn.
Is there a guide that just stands head
and shoulders above everyone else?
I don't know. I don't know.
Maybe a Twitter would know.
I bet if we asked Twitter,
dear Twitter,
what is the number one gay
male porn star in the world?
Is there a Michael Jordan? I read off the
first answer. Not. You don't think so? No.
I think there's so many. I
Dunno. I just don't think porn.
Some Lance Armstrong type motherfucker
that figures things out that other people
can't just rises to the top and becomes
famous at a genre where no one else is
getting famous gay gang. A gang bangs.
Like is there a dude who went to 50 oh,
the DP or triple p and the butthole.
Do they do that?
Can you were asking me? Okay. This guy
says, I only watch Steph Brent again,
or this is a woman rather ampers
and she says it's Brent Corrigan.
That might be her ex boyfriend.
Let's see. Oh yeah. My
passion. I like this fucking clown. I'm
going to, I'm going to get him on the,
on the Joe Rogan podcast. Okay. Let's see.
He's a male modern gay pornograph as
best known for his stage name. Hmm.
Yup. There he is. A little
fellow's already highlighted.
[inaudible] known for his
roles in schoolboy crush. Uh,
and Velvet Mafia.
He has won six Gay v n they have the,
gave Ian's et cetera.
Higgins Avn awards including best
bottom award two consecutive years.
The butthole, or are they just talking
about the shape of the butt? Um,
best bottom is you being on the
bottom, taken in the ass. Yeah.
It doesn't mean they wouldn't say
bottom instead of bought hall. You know,
Jesus Christ, they're, they're
pretty open about how they feel.
And I say I love his bottom.
No, they'd say is asshole.
What's the record for Gay Gang Bangs?
So is it,
what the fuck? Right. This guy's been a
lot of God damn movies. All right, let's,
let's find out what the number, uh, w what
would we, what would we say? Gay, Gay,
gay record. See,
Greece holds the record for
the biggest gay gang. Bang.
Grease the movie. No,
probably probably a dude.
This was 780 men.
Regular checks going nuts on ass suck.
Wow.
780 men but not one dude, right? Yeah.
There's one dude,
I believe they've got a crush women
because the women are doing like 50,
maybe a hundred is the rec side,
but guys don't stop the craziness that
are causing more durable that buttholes I
think that the problem is finding these
guys that get in line and film it.
Gay guys finding that would be hard
cause it's 10% of the population.
It'd be hard.
But if the numbers weren't a problem,
they're willing to ship people in.
I think guy gay porn would crush
regular pointing. Gangbang wow.
Listen to this though, man.
Listen to this shit. The most, uh,
Jackie Latori orgasms ever recorded in
one hour for a man is 1616 in one hour,
orgasms recording in one
hour for a man to die,
for the furthest a woman has ever been
recorded to ejaculate was nine feet 29
inches. Well, why would it be nine feet
29 and she scored 12 inches is a foot.
That's stupid.
That doesn't make any sense.
I came 16 times in an hour. Why
was it same? Nine feet, 29 inches.
Oh, it says three meters. Okay. Is that
three minutes is just nine feet, right,
isn't it? No, no. It's three feet
per meter, right? Roughly. Right.
So three meters is nine feet.
So why is it nine feet 29 inches?
That doesn't make any sense
of 12 inches is afoot anyway.
Whatever the fuck this says,
the greatest distance ever attained
for a jet of semen that has ever been
recorded is 18 feet.
Nine inches. That's huge.
Wow.
Why would it be Lexington Steel?
Horst? Schulze, that's the guy's name
that shot a load that went 18 feet in the,
in the, in the air. That's a
credible up, up in the air or across,
uh, what are the ways by distance?
It's gotta be a distance. No Way.
It could be straight up at 18 feet.
That's incorrect.
You as must have an arc to it. A Nice
Arc, like a McDonald's sign type thing.
Going on for 18 feet. Did they video
it? I don't know. They must say this.
I mean these are all world records. This
is the top 10 sex world records. It's on,
believe it or not,
the average speed of a man's loads.
What would you say your average speed,
your loads would be like 35 miles an hour.
What do you think Brian?
80 to 28 miles an hour.
28 miles an hour, so it's pretty close.
It's pretty close. If the car drove by,
you could tell the difference between
cargo in 28 miles an hour and 35 miles an
hour.
That's pretty fucking close.
Having swallowed the most amount
of semen ever officially recorded.
Michelle Monaghan had 1.7 pints of
semen pumped out of her stomach in Los
Angeles in July of 1991 it was that
pumped out by her ass. That'd be awesome,
dude. 1.7 pints, but maybe if she
had like a glass of coconut water.
C Two o very delicious right before
and it mixed in with the loads.
Maybe my increased the size
of the quantity of fluid
in her when she threw up.
Maybe she was throwing up loads and a
sprite. You don't know. Right, right.
What are they going to test it and make
sure it's a hundred percent loads? No,
they're just looked at it and a slice of
pizza. He wouldn't know the difference.
Yeah.
She just came into a big one of those
big glass baking measurement cups.
She just threw up in it.
There was 1.7 the fuck is this podcast
com female gang bang record is owned by a
woman named Houston who had intercourse.
It's 620 men.
I think that's been been by then.
This is some old guys. Yeah,
that's the old one. A lot. I don't
think it really is 600 men though.
I think what they do is they do is the
same guys and they keep rotating them.
Consider the idea that guy,
they like the common and they come back.
That's not the real records like who
made those records at Saint People? Me,
girl fucks two dudes and they
switch off a couple of times.
She can say she fucked 15 guys.
This doesn't even have gay.
It has a male gang bang male gangbang
world record goes to porn star.
John Doe who worked himself over 55
women and one day he had five to six
ejaculations. Hmm.
Pretty good. Well, yeah,
the checks.
Meanwhile that got committed suicide.
I got blew his fucking brains out.
I have so far Jack culation and see the
other day and then within an hour. Yeah,
but all of them were like
little teardrops. It's funny.
Most of them came from your eyes.
I lose the egg becomes really
thick and clumpy hatched.
Yet he counts it. When he
cries, I'm coming. Oh, kill me.
He was,
this was this masturbation
fucking real shot.
Now you weren't on that.
Now I just have a hot girlfriend
that makes me have boners all day.
Are you bragging bro? No, I'm just
saying that like literally I can have,
I can have sex nonstop all day. First
time in my life. What's that smell?
That's incredible. That's great. Do you
believe him? That's hard to believe.
I don't know anybody like that.
That's right. Again, it's
possible. It's all possible, dude.
If you were like some Super Alpha
Quinten Jackson looking mother Fucker,
I might buy it. I might believe it.
But maybe all your testosterone,
it's just stored up in your balls and
your buddy doesn't use any of it for
muscle development or you know,
behavior or any of that shit.
It's all just in your balls.
Ready to shoot.
I say two minutes to take like a
minute after I come. If I look at this,
boners comes right back to your fucking
pictures of your girlfriend away.
You're really making me sad. Seriously.
I never goes away. I just have like my,
for the, for the first time in my life,
my boner never goes down. I just can,
you know why you're saying this?
Cause you know his,
his ex girlfriend listens to the
podcast is just too much lie.
I swear to God it's not why Taylor was
Joey Diaz right now and do that to Taylor
vixen all diet guide.
No, no, it's a different thing, right
Brian? Just difference. Love this time.
You never find doon doon doon too
fucking doing man tech guy.
Ah,
so hot room. Impressive man. I really am.
I just thought it was weird because I
never thought it was possible in my life.
Like I've always wondered how like
guys in porn do it and stuff like that.
Viagara when you drink. Some might
be because I've already said that.
I think she's like
get it in there and maybe she got
tired of you. Like remember you,
you say you would fall asleep because
you were too tired to go down on her and
then fall asleep because you
were too tired to do anything.
You do her and then you would fall asleep.
You talked about on the podcast, so
yes you did. My current girlfriend,
she said she was horny and you were
too tired to have sex with her.
She would go down now. That was
one time. That was one time.
One time. One time. Maybe that time
she's like, I'm tired of this shit.
I want to get fucked and so she started
crumpling up by Agra and I'm going to
cook for you tonight,
honey.
She made you a nice Viagara meatloaf in
like 2001 I got third row tickets to the
cure. I was so jazzed that was,
remember born again, that stripper.
Sure there's a long time
we were going in a true,
but that was a born again Christian.
So he would call her born again
that that was her nickname.
Born again. That's
hilarious. So anyways, uh,
she was only stripping
just to pay for school,
but she was like hardcore Christian
cause you're thinking of this.
But we were going to the
cure. So I'm like, I need
some ecstasy for this concert.
So I meet up with my buddy in the
afternoon to get some Mexican and I always
have bought vitamin bottles with me and
I put them into my vitamin bottles and I
go, when I eat, I'm going to take them
out of the vitamin bottle and you know,
eat and take my vitamins.
It's one o'clock. I go to El
Pollo Loco, we're sitting,
we're going to leave around seven.
I eat my chicken sitting there watching
TV and I just got really horny.
I just looked at him like, well,
fucking beast. Fuck this chick.
So I threw in the bed, I'm fucking
the shit out of her. And I'm like,
God damn. It feels like I'm
on ecstasy. And they go,
oh my God. I jumped off the bed
with open up my vitamin bottle.
Second Fuck,
are you fucking [inaudible] I forgot
to blow them out of my vitamins.
I didn't know I was on ecstasy until
right in the middle of sex. That's,
it was incredible sex. I'm like,
it's like I'm on email and it's just,
that's funny.
I flew eyes.
He supposed to kill your boner.
Didn't you say that you would
take Viagra and eat together
called after a while.
After a while it kills your bone,
but not in the beginning and the
beginning. You get really, really horny.
But if you want to go because when you're
on, yeah, well people are different. No,
no. People are different.
Like for me, if, if you know,
back in the days when every
now and then I pop a pill,
I would get a boner really quick. How many
times would have done he in your life?
How many times, man, back when
I was younger I probably did eat
maybe
40 times. Whoa. Oh Mike. Is that
a lot? That expensive? Lots of it.
It explains a lot. What do you
mean is it was, and I was like,
when I was younger,
this motherfucker's taking shit.
He doesn't even know what it is.
He's taking bath salts.
You gotta get your shit
from reputable sources.
You need to find some friendly person
that works at a club somewhere,
but excess is bad. Okay. I don't,
it kills your brain and for sure
does or ecstasy is not bad like MDM.
And the problem is, is that you
don't know what you're taking. Yeah.
Bass Hall boy shit. Exactly. That
stuff's supposed to be really tough.
If you've seen it, this,
this crocodile shit,
they shit that they're taking the Soviet
Union to shooting it up and it's making
your skin runaway.
There's all these photos of people
with their bones hanging off.
Literally your bones exposed when
were were wherever they shot it up.
Like their flesh has deteriorated to a
point where their bones are exposed. Yeah.
It's crazy to look at it, man. That's
gross. What a weird world we live in, man.
People will take some
drug that will make your,
your skin literally rot off your body.
People take some shit that they think
is ecstasy and it turns out to be some
weird fucking amphetamine that
somebody made in the lab. You know,
who knows what the fuck is going
to do to you and it's not the end.
They're gonna keep coming up with
more and more of these things.
Thinking about stuff off the dummies.
Yeah. These bath salts. That's you bro.
You took that shit. Does it, does that
scare you when you think of that? Ah,
that you could have taken
something really nutty? Yeah.
When you buy stuff like that, if you
biolink ACCC, doesn't that scare you?
Like you never know.
Like you might get it from some,
some dude that is scaring you.
Heard about this cocaine that's
making people's fucking flesh rot.
If you heard about this shit,
this is some cocaine is bad cocaine.
That's in California.
It's in New York and it's treated
with some livestock dewormer.
That's what they cut it with.
And you know,
let me look it up right now
because it's fucking crazy.
And people you probably hear,
yeah,
okay.
Yeah, yeah. It's um, cocaine,
bad cocaine in Los Angeles,
in New York City tainted with a,
some sort of a,
I'm hearing this a livestock
dewormer yeah, it's really fucked up.
What happens when you do it? They, they're
getting, they're getting really bad. Um,
uh, noses, ears and cheeks develop
ugly purple swatches of dead skin.
This is like d, it's, it's called
Lavana soul. That's the stuff.
And the dealers are
cutting it with this shit.
And they say like 90% of the cocaine
in New York and California is,
is contaminated with, is this, this shit?
90% of the cocaine and cow,
excuse me,
70% of the u s department of Justice
is reporting this. Okay. By the way,
this is just the u s
department of Justice.
They might just be saying this
to cut out the cocaine business.
They're saying up to 70% of the cocaine
in the u s is contaminated with this
love van,
Mother's soul,
which is cheap and widely available and
commonly used for deworming livestock.
Whoa. What the fuck man?
What are they doing?
You would think that debt would be
something that someone who hates cocaine
users would do.
You would think that that would be
someone who actually wants to stop people
from using cocaine.
Would you know?
They would like mix it in there so
that people would stop coming back.
You know what I'm saying?
Like why would you do that if you're
trying to sell more cocaine then almost
seems like something like the
government would do ma'am.
Like the whole story's probably fake
and they're just putting it out there to
scare you. Like people are on Pirate Bay,
like, oh there's a buyers in this file.
I Dunno, maybe, but it's on La la weekly.
It seems like they would do their
due diligence, don't you think? Yeah,
I like Waco. Don't you think? Yeah, you
fell asleep on me. You mother fucker. No,
I'm just thinking about your girlfriend
said, Elliot, what do you think getting,
do you think that they would do this?
Who the fuck would do this?
Do you think this is the government?
Who knows?
Do you see the UFO videos over London? Do
you believe in those? Did you see that?
I saw w what does that look like to,
I just,
there's so many videos like that dude
looks like Cgi to me. It's too convenient,
the whole,
the way it's set up as two convenient.
There's a bunch of people standing there
looking up and everybody's looking up
at night. They're catching these things
and they fly in and out of the clouds.
I've seen it, but you know what
really makes me think that it's,
it's a two convenient. The
guy film looks up, films,
some of the Ufos and then looks
down all these people watching,
which is the fucking last thing that
you would do if you actually thought you
saw a real Ufo is flying through the air.
You would keep the fucking camera on them.
You wouldn't want to turn it point down
it all these people watching. Maybe.
Maybe you don't know what the hell it is
and like look, everyone's tripping out.
You know he showed that before you showed
everybody looking up at the sky and
then he catches this actors.
Yeah, I think it's fake.
People get a kick out of doing shit
like that. They think it's cute.
So much fake shit on the Internet now.
That's one of the fun
things about the Internet.
Trying to figure out what's
fake and what's not. Brian's
the master at that Shit.
He calls fakes. He calls fix better
than anybody but sometimes he's off.
Sometimes it's just sound sync
problems and it looks fake.
Look at this cocaine shit like
we was doing these people.
It's making their skin right off.
Its like making that year turn
like blue on black hair skin.
Your skin's fucking farm
cocaine. Yup. Oh my God. Yeah.
There's some people have suffered
permanent scarring on their body from this
shit. You know what got
the good shit. No fall off.
This message brought to you by
prescription pills. What is that shit?
What's it called? It's
called love van muscle. Yeah.
L. E. V. A. M. I. S. O. L. E. Van Assault.
It's bad for your kids.
And on that note,
I think this fucking podcast started off
real strong and then someone other than
we,
we lost the last team
we got into gay porn.
It was my fault.
We got into gay porn and Brian started
reminiscing about his girlfriend
looking at pictures. Oh.
Um, tomorrow, somebody,
I'm not sure, somebody will be
on the podcast. The guy from, um,
ancient aliens is coming on the podcast
and he's coming on at the end of July.
It will be July 27.
And um,
his name is Giorgio and it's
just a tough one to pronounce.
T. S. O. U. K. A. L. O. S.
I think the is silent. Yeah.
Soup. Gallows, sucralose,
sucralose,
Giorgio sucralose.
And he's the guy from ancient
aliens with the crazy hair who's a,
a self professed wacky,
alien, loving bastard.
Cause that's what I called them
and said yes. Guilty as charged.
He's cool as fuck.
I like him and I'm,
I'm excited to have mom because we're
going to talk about some weird shit.
You should probably be on that one,
man. I would love to ask a question.
You should probably be in on that one.
That would be a fun conversation. Yeah.
We might have to bring you in on that one.
I have to bring Eddie,
Eddie Bravo and with the the
alien dude. Be honored. Yeah,
because no one loves the aliens more
than you and him. You and him together.
It would be a fucking, we fucked
people. I tsunami of aliens.
Don't you have like aliens all
over your logos and your shirt?
Just don't necessarily believe
in them. I do my logos. Well,
my whole logo is an alien. If I'm down.
I love a love Ufo DVDs and
I do short 200 of them,
but that's why I don't believe in them.
I seen so much stuff.
I think the way I look at it,
and this is not,
not that I don't in them because it's not
that I don't believe in them. I don't
not believe, I don't believe you are.
Foes don't exist. I don't believe
that my, in my mind is open about it,
but I'm not convinced either way.
But the way I look at it,
it's like everyone's got a goddamn camera
with a f on their phone. Everyone does.
Now you would think that if there,
if I meet a thousand people, okay,
out of every thousand people that I meet,
at least 10 of them are fucking morons.
Like extreme morons,
right?
If you meet a thousand when you
say 10 or just complete idiots,
pathological liars completely fucked
up, right? It a good solid 10 right?
So I would think that if there's that
many people that are idiots and fucked up,
and then you look at the number of Ufo
stories, like what are the numbers?
The numbers like are similar to what
you would expect from a population of
retards.
I got a small population and dominant.
You look at the smartest people on
the opposite end of the spectrum.
Wernher von Braun and Hermann Oberth.
There were rocket scientists.
They not only believe in aliens,
they're saying our technology
came from messages from pea beans,
from other solar system. That's
what they're saying. Yeah.
I would have to talk to them. I
believe that. I believe that quote go,
go Wernher von Braun.
Well,
uh,
beans from Ufo beans from other worlds.
His exact quote is beans from other
worlds helped us. I've seen that.
I've seen that written, but who knows what
that really is what he said. You know,
it's so hard when the dude's dead
and he died in 1977. You know,
who the fuck knows what he
actually said? You know? Well,
you know that he's quoted as saying
it, so maybe that's, yeah, maybe,
but yeah, two different
guys. No, I think, look,
it is entirely possible if it's proven
that the quote was actually legit,
like yes, here's the video of
him actually saying then what,
what happens at that point? That's,
that's pretty convincing evidence. Maybe.
Or He may be, he's a troll. Maybe
Wernher von Braun was a big Nazi troll.
I mean,
the thing about Wernher von Braun is
he was the head of Nazi of NASA rather.
But he was a confirmed Nazi and
the Simon Wiesenthal Center said,
if that guy was alive today,
they would prosecute him for crimes
against humanity. So who the fuck knows?
He could have been trolling, but I don't,
I don't believe that it's impossible.
It's definitely possible. So I'm looking
forward to having this Giorgio dude on.
It should be a fascinating conversation.
I want to find out how his brain works,
man. You know, because he said, he says a
lot of crazy stuff. I want to know. Yeah.
He seems like I almost like it could be
a character, may be a little bit, maybe.
Maybe it's fun, you know, maybe some of
it's sexy. I mean, he runs x. He, yeah,
it's sexy. It's sexy to believe
in bigfoot. Right. You know,
it's sexy to believe in aliens.
It's sexy to believe in all that shit.
It's interesting. Who the fuck
knows? But that's coming up.
I don't know who's going to
be on tomorrow, but we'll
get somebody. Uh, and then,
um, maybe Thursday's going to be
my friend, young urban, you know,
young dude who wrote all the
books on, um, on mushrooms and,
and religion. The problem is he's got
the flu and I don't want the fucking flu.
Yeah. Let's give him a couple
of weeks. Yeah. I might,
I might have the guy that he's the guy
that turned you to Terence Mckenna. Yeah,
he turned me on to a lot of things.
Uh, he's uh, he's a fascinating cat.
He's a real, real odd duck. And uh,
he's written two books now on
psychedelics and religion one,
and he was with us when we first did.
Damn t he was with us when we,
you had that crazy bad trip. The
first one was horrible. Yeah.
It was pretty bad.
Screaming and gallon screaming.
Well Eddie fucked up and he ate food
right before he went on his trip,
which you're never supposed to do.
You're not supposed to have anything
in your stomach when you go on the trip
because your body, you
know, kind of freaks out.
So he in the middle of this trip gets up
and I have to help him get to sink and
he threw up in the sink. You,
you hurled in this sense,
just throw up all over the floor. No,
no, no, no. You made it to the sink.
You manage the sink. You don't even
remember the story that could, right.
It's probably [inaudible].
I just don't remember exactly.
It was ed per Gail the whole
time too. I was like, wow,
just hanging out with ed brick gal,
because when whoever wrote this whole
story on your message board didn't put
Eddie Bravo.
That was John.
John Changed the names of everything
and I thought it was ed per gallon.
It was a Johnny rotten,
I think it was Johnny rotten.
Maybe I was either Yana Johnny rotten
changed the names of everything sink and
your little bar, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. That's what he threw up. Yeah.
You heard, I looked up at you and
I remember because I was screaming,
I was screaming and I looked up
at you and I'm like, all right,
don't worry about me. And then like
that was like me letting you know,
just let me fucking throw up,
scream, I'm going to be fine. Well,
the thing about bad trips is the real,
real bad trips happen when you're
trying to control the experience.
Like the whole idea is to just let go
and let this journey happened and you got
to,
you got to trust in the psychedelic,
but you are fighting it tooth
and claw and it was all going on.
That first time was a disaster.
Shazamm this Friday night,
July 1st we will all be in Las Vegas,
Brian included. So if you want a hug,
Brian,
come on down.
We met this dude who had a fucking
death squad tattoo your little logo.
This guy had an sat too. Just four
people now with it. That's crazy.
And there's a few that have
the higher primary tattoos too.
And there's a bunch of time. I hate
10 plan planet tattoos are there now.
We causing people to get ink
on their scandalous skin. No,
we're not tattoos off of that
and making it prettier. Uh,
this Friday night we will all be at
Mandalay bay. It's going to be Joey Diaz.
Ari should fear me and Doug
Benson is going to stop by.
He's going to do a guest
set and um, um, Brian,
if we get them drunk and off from my,
push him in front of the microphone,
I'm going to push you on at the end,
the very end.
You're going to come out and talk
to the crowd, do some Q and a,
some Q and a when you're on acid.
Um,
so that's this Friday night and then next
weekend we are in Irvine at the Irvine
Improv and that should be fun. It's fuck,
that is, yeah, Irvine is great. That is a,
the Irvine weekend is the seventh,
eighth or the eighth.
Ninth and 10th of July.
So that's it. Bitches. Uh, thanks
for tuning in everybody and uh,
we will see you all tomorrow. Thank you.
And thanks to the flush. Yeah, yeah.
Oh sure.
If you go to Joe rogan.net,
click on the link for the fleshlight
answering the code name, Rogan.
You get 15% off the number one sex
toy for man. Go ahead, fell out,
shoot some loads in it.
Knowing that you have
saved a couple dollars. I got
a seminar in El Paso, Texas,
July 23rd I think that shits
right close to the border. Right,
and next week is the 10th Planet Cruise.
I don't know if it's too late, but we're,
we're going on a cruise man.
What is this at the ocean next Saturday.
Next Monday to Friday. Holy Shit. Where
do you start? Where does it start?
I think Ella. I don't know too much
about it because who's organized it?
Donna and Amy from legends.
They put it all together.
So you got 70 guys going.
70 guys,
what are the chances to do are
going to bud fuck each other? Yeah.
Well there's a lot of people
are bringing their wives.
Actually a lot of people are bringing
their wives. Yes. Still 50 guys.
So that's next Monday you could, I'm
not sure again if it's too late or not,
but if you've got a 10th planet,
j j.com on the forum.
There's information up there and
also 10th planet cruise.com I do.
That sounds fucking awesome.
That's going to be fun, man.
You scared that anybody might freak out,
that someone tapped some money and
then they just throw him overboard.
Can you imagine being on that cruise
with like your wife? Like, Hey,
happy anniversary. Oh, what the fuck
is going on in 70 trained killers?
I'm going to teach a seminar. Danny's
going to teach seminars on the boat,
on the boat. God went to seminars
on the boat. That's a crazy thing.
We didn't invent this. The
Gracies Gracie is do agree. Yup.
And have a Gracie creek. Wow. We need to
do a desk. Squad crews. How cool that it.
Yeah. I don't want to go on a boat and be
stuck. Yeah. Be Scared and what have you.
There's some Weirdos on the boat. They
know what your cabin is and knocking on.
We've got to get the VIP suite
a VIP suite. All right folks.
Thank you Mister Bravo.
Follow me on Twitter. Eddie
Bravo on Twitter. Um, e d d,
I. E. Bravo. Just how it's spelled. You
know how it works. Uh, Brian is red band,
and you can also subscribe to the red,
the death squad series of podcasts
that Brian hosts on iTunes.
It's called death squad, and
it's Sam Tripoli's podcast,
Thompson Girls podcasts,
Ari Shaffir fears podcasts,
and a bunch of other different
ones every now and then,
the throne in new ones
into the mix. But, uh,
they're very entertaining and fun and
especially if you're into liquid ass
people sticking fingers and other
people's flashlights. Thank you everybody.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah.
Hello?