Yeah, my oldest one's super. Here
we go. Five, four, three, two,
one. Ben And ladies, gentlemen, Dude,
I've talked about you on this podcast.
It at least a dozen times. You are the
number one guy that I'm most disappointed,
never fought in the UFC. Yeah. I
always get, whenever you talk about me,
I get like 15 texts. Like, hey Joe,
Joe talking about you now and you know,
they'll send me clips or whatever. So
obviously appreciate that. Um, but yeah,
I never,
I never really got to fight those top
guys and it was for reasons beyond my
control. Yeah. And you're done
now. Yeah, I saw, I said, I said,
I don't want to say I'm done period.
I said I'm done excluding the fact that
I get to fight and prove I'm number one.
That would be the excluding facts.
So if you could get in the UFC,
you'd be willing to do it again. I mean,
I don't care where it is. Right. I,
I really genuinely don't.
And obviously that would be the,
the thing that makes sense.
But there is legislation like the
alley act and the things going through.
So I don't know that maybe, you know, I'm
still 33 so I'm not old. And you know,
polluted GSP took four years off
from one flight to the next fight.
So I'm not saying I'm an age overnight.
Well your style to you avoided
so much damage. I didn't get,
I didn't get hit once this
until of 2017 so yeah,
I think you hit once in three fights.
So yeah,
I should tell people you
were fighting in one FC,
which is a big Asian organization. It's
like the Asian version of the UFC. Yeah.
So one FC started in 2012 I think.
Um,
obviously my contract with Belcher
came up in 2013 and then there was that
negotiation process and stuff obviously
went south. And what happened there?
You were the champ of belt or,
and then all sudden you left and
you are still undefeated, right?
I'm undefeated 18.
You know what the fuck happened?
That pellet tour let the champion will
go. That wasn't what happened. So no,
there's so much misinformation
out there. And you know, I,
I'm popular but I'm not that popular.
And so lots of times in my story gets
missed toll because I get spoken over by
other people. Right. And they don't hear
what I say. So here, here's what happened.
Um, obviously, so prior
to me and Bella tour,
Hector and Eddie were the ones
that left, right? There were,
Hector was the lumber yard and Eddie
Alvarez, Alvarez, both of them,
both the middleweight champion
than the lightweight champion.
They both got taken care of pretty well.
But if you,
if you remembered Eddie's situation,
I don't know if you remember this,
he got an offer from the UFC still
under the matching period of Beltre.
Beltre says we matched it.
Right.
And in terms of what was in the
contract, it was matched. Right?
But because Belterra
has no paper view venue,
well if you have c says we'll pay you on
pay per view belts as well. We will too.
But that's not real life.
That's still patients.
They've done two paper view shows
ever and they've never met any type of
threshold. So you know, they
say imagine, but it doesn't say,
I don't know if you remember,
but they went to court over it and the
UFC one Eddie has got the right to,
I'm sorry he didn't,
when he,
he somehow did it like a one more fight
in Bellator and then went to the UFC.
I don't know exactly what the finality
of that case was. But anyways,
when that happened, his, his
contract became public knowledge.
Right.
And so a lot of UFC fighters
were pissed because he,
they gave him a whole bunch of money.
And so when I was 12 and older, I will,
I have my last fight in belt
organs down under crush cough,
July 30th May 31st of 2013
beat him up pretty good.
And then I had a 12 month matching period.
And so what was expressed to me by the
UFC brass was that you need to get rid of
your matching clause and
we will make you an offer,
but we will not make you an offer until
that happens. Get rid of your matching.
Yes. How do you do that? Well, here,
here's how I went about doing it.
I exist 12 months. Right.
That's a freaking, I'm not
going to sell for 12 months.
So I'd call Bjorn or did it and say,
Hey Bjorn, I'm not gonna resign.
Please let one guy who was running belt
or correct. Yeah. And now he, you know,
he got fired. But um, and Bjorn
had a terrible reputation,
but I never,
I had a decent relationship with them.
I never like butted heads too bad. So
every tear this had Bjorn, let me go.
I'm not coming back. And then so
everyone says it will bell toward,
didn't want to reassign me. Well
that's, that's not true at all.
Every day is Bjorn. Let me go. If you
aren't, let me go, because you know,
I love challenges.
What I love more than anything in
the world is a challenge myself.
If you look at my wrestling career,
that's what it's all about.
Taking the next best thing
every single time. And so, yeah.
So finally in and all this time, you
know, Dana and the UFC is saying,
we want Ben to ask him,
we won't been ask her.
And I'm ranked number seven in the world
or you know, somewhere around there,
12 and [inaudible].
And so I remember I was going to the
Asian food store cause I was gonna make
some Tom cost soup and Bjorn calls me,
said,
you're released full, full, you're
released, you can go. And I have to say,
I appreciate that. So Friday morning,
it was Thursday night, Friday morning,
it's in November, sometime
in May, mid November, um,
morning they fax over the release,
my management faxes it to UFC headquarters
and all of a sudden that afternoon
there's a,
you know,
like a little scrum where
everyone's asking Tina
questions and the dentist says,
we're not interested in Ben
[inaudible]. And I said, wait,
what just happened there?
Right.
Because for the last three months
they were saying, we were interested,
where's your,
where's your where's did now I finally
produced this full release from Bella
tour that I got and now they're
not interested. And so I said, wow,
I just got caught in the middle
of this. And uh, was there
a reason given? Well, so,
okay, so the Monday, so then
I say f that I buy my potato,
I bought a plane ticket to Vegas for
Monday, so that was Friday. That happens.
I say, fuck that. I'm going to Vegas.
I'm not taking this shit, you know. So,
uh, Monday I buy my plane ticket to Vegas,
I fly out to Vegas to UFC headquarters.
Uh,
I met with Lorenzo.
Dana was on the little speakerphone
dealy and they offered me a,
a zoo for contract,
but it would be confidential and I would
have to fight one fight for the world
series of fighting, which is like,
well that's bizarre. What? Yeah.
And they said,
didn't fight for the world series a
funding the exact relationship with the
world series the world. I don't like a
feed organization at that time. Something,
yeah, I mean I, yeah,
Marlin Mris. Just engage you both
those guys came from champs over there.
Yeah.
I think the relationship was,
is very hazy between the old world series
of fighting in the UFC because there
was also, people don't
want the other way. Right.
Andre Arlovski gets dropped from the FC
goes to world series. I, Anthony Johnson,
boom. All these people. Yeah. So
they say one fight, one fight,
world series of fighting. We will pay
Zoopla, we'll pay you, what'd you do?
One fight. Okay. I say let
that's F it up, but okay. I said,
I don't think anyone's going to go for it.
I'll do it.
So I leave and about six hours
later I got a phone call.
Is that deal is no longer available. We
are not going to make you an offer. Yeah.
So, wow. And you have no
idea why? Well, I, I, so I,
here's my guess. I've never got to
sit face to face. And you didn't say,
what was your problem with me? I
think there's four things. My mind.
Number one, he didn't really
like me. Um, stemming from the,
I called them out on the steroid thing,
you know, where he said it's impossible.
And this is where our disagreement,
it's impossible to test all UFC athletes.
I said,
well that's not true.
You cited does it all over the world
for all kinds of athletes. Right.
You can do it. It's just expensive.
But let's just call it what it is.
You're a private business.
You don't have to do drug testing.
And it's obviously they do it now.
Do it now. Yeah. Do it through Usada.
So you were totally right. Yeah. So I,
I was correct and now, but that was,
you know when Dana is wrong in an
argument and he's got this huge army that
follows him and he said,
I'd rather hit,
I think his quote was bad cause
I'd rather watch flies fucked.
And Ben ask him fight. You know, I think
he said something like ambien takes,
Ben asked her, he goes asleep.
Yeah. There, there's a few of them.
So the personal attack started, right.
So that, that's number one. Number two,
my fighting style is
not highly attractive,
but I also think that's a little bit of
fake news because if you look at George
St peers to consistently novelty,
McGregor trumped him.
But only a couple of times,
but if you will get consistent basis.
George Saint Pierre is the
number one draw of all time.
He heavily relied on take
downs and ground and pound.
I mean he didn't have a finish in
like five years or something. Let me
say what my take is always been on you
and that style is that it's important and
that it really, it really
works. Yeah, absolutely.
You're able to do really works,
and I've always said this and it was
proven son a Saturday night in the steep
Emile Chick Francis Econo fight. Wrestling
is the most important part of MMA.
Absolute ability to take
the fight to the ground.
Obviously Steve Bay has a
lot of other attributes.
He took tremendous punches in that fight.
I mean,
I know you didn't get a chance to
watch it, but I saw some highlights.
The Holy Shit.
I mean the first round was chaos.
I mean Francis and Gannon was a terrifying
guy and Steve Bay took the shots,
use great movement,
you striking of his own,
but most importantly after a
while God is wrestling going.
And then once he got in God
but to the ground and gone,
I didn't have any answers. He
didn't know what to do. What your,
what you've been able to do to guys
like Douglas Lema who just fought Rory
macdonald for the bell to our title.
Really good fight of course golf who is
another fantastic fight who uh, you know,
it was beaten a lot of really top guys.
Yeah.
You're able to use your wrestling
and completely nullify all,
they're striking an offense and
that's a huge part of fighting.
Fighting is not what's
exciting for people to watch.
Fighting is what actually works and what
you've been able to do time and time
again is take these guys who looked like
world beaters and completely nullify
their offense, taken to the
ground and beat the shit out
of him. Yeah, that's huge.
That's very,
very important.
Yeah, absolutely. And so, you know, not
so we can get back to the UFC thing,
but so yeah. I mean when I started
fighting, right, it was just like, hey,
let's go fight.
I didn't live in a coaching.
And so I didn't move to Duke's
until to Souk Rufus. Yes.
Until 2010 I think. So I
started, no, no, no. 2011 I'm
sorry. Cause I was in Arizona.
I was coaching for Arizona
State University. But when
I moved there, I know, hey,
the I, there's a lot of elite
strikers in this gym. I said, but I,
I'm never going to be elite striker. But
if no one can hit me, they can't beat me.
They're not gonna outlast me. They're
not going to help her. Apple, me,
they're not going to beat me
if they can't knock me out.
They're not going to beat me.
Plain and simple.
So my whole goal was how do I not get hit?
Not,
I don't need to be a great striker hitting
people. I just need to not get hit.
If you can't knock me out,
I'm going to eventually get you on the
ground and I'm going to beat your ass.
Right. And so that was kind of my
whole goal when I got an amaze,
how do I not get knocked
out? Right. And so you said,
obviously I've found a
really good way to do that.
And it added a lot of longevity in my
career where I wasn't taking damage a,
a lot of other people were taking.
And I think there's also a lot of other
things to being a really high level
wrestler that,
you know,
besides obviously you can control
where the fight happens, right?
But there's a lot of other things that
high level wrestling provides us, right.
That came from that world that other
disciplines don't get. You know,
a lot of competition. We compete
thousands of times. Right?
How to get our mind right.
Um,
these wrestlers are just strong and then
there's just a different strength that
he's actually,
I got to go work how term Burroughs
last week cause a many time world champ.
And it's like you forget how
strong wrestlers are. Like
you grab him, you're like,
good God, this guy is like, you
know, I don't feel that from him.
Maybe people like grab him and
I'm like, oh my, everywhere.
It's like there's no worries. Week.
Um, very, very disciplined. Right?
Cause a wrestlers,
like we've been in the system from youth
wrestling to high school wrestling to
college. I said, well,
we're under, you know,
coaches and have a very strict training
plan and understand how to put a
training regimen together where a lot of
other martial arts don't have that kind
of structured system.
So I think there's a lot of advantages
that we as a wrestlers have when we come
in mixed martial arts.
And if I could add to that,
the intention is pure,
it's pure for competition because
there's no financial reward.
It's not a bunch of people
that are getting into
wrestling because they want to
get rich. It's a bunch of
people that really want to
prove that they're the best.
And so you have so many top flight guys
that are incredibly mentally strong
feeding off of each other,
knowing that they're going to be
competing against each other and almost no
financial possibilities
except for coaching.
Well, yeah, there's, I mean
now, so 2018 to 20, uh,
2008 when I was wrestling and then
when I decide to make that jump MMA,
there is a lot better financial
structure for senior level athletes. No,
none of them are getting rich and there's
only about a dozen and I'm making like
a decent living. Right? Yeah. And so which
is crazy. There's thousands of wrestlers.
Exactly.
So your points mostly correct,
but there are a handful of top United
States athletes now who can do nothing but
wrestle. Where when I was in,
in 2008 when I was trained,
that wasn't even the case. I had to go
do camps. I was coaching at Missouri,
so I was doing other things
in addition to wrestling.
So like a top Olympic athlete. What
else would they do to make money? Well,
so like in 2008 I was doing
a lot of camps, right?
You'd travel around the country, do
camps, make money, coach a college team.
I was making money that way.
So the handful of things I didn't like
w w it wasn't just wake up and train
every single day.
But the athletes today that you were
saying now that's what they're doing.
That's it. Coaching and different
things. No, no, no, no, no.
Some of them don't have to.
Anything you're saying that just do it
from where are they getting the money?
Jordan Burroughs and James
Green for example. Um,
sponsorships are slightly
more lucrative than they were.
Then there's something called the regional
training center system. Um, which,
you know,
most major colleges have one that's a lot
more lucrative and that's fundraising,
right? They're not, they're not earning
money that the RTC people go say, hey,
rich guy,
would you like to fund this program?
That'll help us develop Olympic
level athletes. Sure. Okay. Right.
And then the United States,
uh,
you soc has slightly more funding given
to USA wrestling than in the past. Well,
it's the tragic story of John Dupont. I
mean, that's literally why that whole,
if people have seen that movie, what was
that movie called? Fox got Fox catcher.
Yeah. Awful crazy story of,
um, Dave and Mark Schultz.
And this millionaire or
billionaire crazy guy,
I believe in her and wound up
shooting Dave Schultz and uh,
was just Weirdo guy that
was running this camp.
And these guys kind of got stuck
training with this gap because I mean,
and that's 96 was when Schultes got shot.
Right.
And so that's 12 years prior to,
you know, my Olympic birth and,
and so then it's even worse.
I mean,
these guys are literally making
nothing and that then, you know,
then we'll go back to the argument of
amateurism and the Olympics is stupid,
which was abolished like 92 of the
Dream Team was kind of totally abolished
tourism. But yeah, those guys in
that era, that 84, 88, 92 nights,
they were making nothing.
And so when this guy,
John Dupont offers them money
and stipends and places to live,
they don't really have a better option.
And it's freaking sad
to be honest about it.
And then obviously USA wrestling
sanctioned him because he gave you as a
wrestling a lot of money. So yeah,
it was really bad thing. And,
and so we're doing a lot better in 2018
than we were 10 years ago. And Way,
way better than we were
doing 20 years ago. Yeah.
The Olympic thing where they try to
treat the Olympics like it's an amateur
sport event.
It's a business you're making absolutely
ins and billions of dollars off these
athletes who get paid zero
is to me it's disgusting.
I think it's just this relic of ancient
thinking and these guys are using it to
steal money from young athletes.
That's what I think.
I think the hard thing is theft.
Yeah. I usually don't know whom.
Who's more evil that you
soc or the IOC or the NCA.
Cause the NCA runs right
along the same lines.
And I think both are pretty evil and
both are archaic and both DDB changing.
And you know,
if you could abolish the NCA and the IOC,
that'd be fantastic for
athletes worldwide. Yeah.
Well especially when you look at the
football teams that are getting literally
billions and billions of dollars every
year and these athletes are ruining their
lives. I mean you have football
players that maybe play one,
two seasons if they're lucky,
if they get their back blown out,
their legs get blown out and then
they never have an NFL career.
And meanwhile the university
has made tons of money,
tons of money and they make nothing.
Yeah. And to make that even worse,
cause I actually had to,
I had a whole podcast about this argument
with someone and to make that end,
we're on the same side of this,
but to make it even worse,
if you're an NCAA athlete,
Joe,
you can't even make money off
your own image and likeness.
You can't have a youtube channel.
It's crazy.
It's so not only will
they not pay you anything,
which I think we can
debate and argue on that,
but the fact that they can't
make money off their own name,
own image and likeness it,
that's, it should be criminal
for that to happen. Jimmy,
you were telling me about this,
right?
Like a guy got in trouble for having a
youtube channel where it was punter for
like an a college football team
or a kicker. I remember his name,
I don't remember his name,
it on and there was a,
there was a wrestler from the University
of want to say University of Minnesota.
He made a rap album and he had to either
quit the wrestling team or or donate
all the money back or something
like that. It's like rap, rap,
rap and wrestling have,
they have nothing to do with each other.
The fact that he can't go make money
off freaking recording an album is like
mind blowing.
It's disgusting because you're
keeping a kid from being industrious.
You keeping a a young guy. I was trying
to find his way through the world.
You keeping them from
being successful and,
but though that kind of success like
figuring out a way to make some money off
of that other name, doing rap that could
lead to all sorts of paths in life.
Like he's, he's learning as a young guy
like, hey look, I could be industrious.
I could go do this. I can be
creative. I can go do that.
Like this is what we should be encouraging
people to do to take chances and make
money.
The idea that you're saying like somehow
or another this spoils his amateur
athletic standing. It's just stupidity.
I think it's fucking disgusting.
It drives me nuts. Agree a hundred
percent. It just drives me crazy.
So we're back to your
situation with the UFC.
So the UFC says we're not offer no offer,
no offer.
So tours release too. So I, I had
spent three months telling Pella Tor,
do you think you played, you feel like
the USC might've played a little way?
They played me harder sell. Okay. So
number the reasons Dan doesn't like me,
number one. Number two, my
style and not that great. Right?
Didn't you say something
like he's a bald steroid?
It was mostly after the fact,
after that went down that I really
torture him. But um, you know, but the,
the original one was, he's lying
about this, the Usada thing.
So that was the simpler the,
those people who say me and
Dana had beef prior to me
not getting it off.
Have you met him? Yeah, I
mean, yeah. Not Talk to him.
We've never had at length conversation.
So great guy.
Well the wrong impression of him.
I mean, I really love it that yeah,
you and I have had different experiences.
I always feel like I should be
there when people have experienced,
let me let you know the Dana. I know.
Yeah. So, um, so that would be too
three.
I think obviously stealing a key piece
away from Bella tour was important to
them. Um, and then number four,
I think they thought I really had the
ability to be their champion and if
someone can be a belt or champion and
make this transition directly to the FC
and then be the UFC champion. I, you know,
they remember this when they're going on
filters down spike now that bell toward,
use that to say, look, we're the
same. He was a champion here.
He's a champion there. So I think
those four things are, and I've, Hey,
I've never got to sit down face to face
day in and say, why was there no offer?
That one I've never got,
you know,
like when Anthony Pettis
was the champ and you know,
I'm helping coach him or tire was,
I,
I've haven't had more than five
words a day in passing. Right.
And so it would be really interesting to
me to sit down and say what was tell me
for real, cause I have my
assumptions on what the deal was,
but I don't really know.
And then if I have to add number five,
number five is I think he got the
idea that I would never be a yes man,
which I'm not going to
be. Never would be. Um,
where Dana really kind of likes the yes
man champion. I mean he, you see he's got,
he's got some heat with Tyron.
He's got some heat with steep
bay as we saw on Saturday night.
And he dated really struggles with the
personalities that won't cater to what he
wants to happen.
Well,
fighters very rarely are yes men.
Then that's by nature of who they
are a little bit. Yeah. You know,
especially the really good ones,
especially as things start going
well and start going their way.
They realize they're the fucking man.
I mean this is,
if you're the guy was
running the division,
you're the guy who's running the division
and then you're not going to take any
shit from anybody.
Yeah.
But that's [inaudible] you see as some
of these guys ascend right up the ranks,
they do. Like John Jones started
having trouble with Dana. Right.
But didn't have it
till he was Jones was having his problems
I think had very little to do with
Dana and more to do with his
actions outside of the cage.
I mean inside the octagon he was and the
way he was promoted, he was promoted.
Fantastic. But he's just
crazy. John's crazy.
You know John John needs a babysitter.
The baddest motherfucker at 205 ever.
He just needs an ear. Let him drive a car
anymore. When you got that much money,
it's beyond me like pace the,
pay your buddy 40 grand a year and
have him drive you permanently.
Like why he was driving his own
car. That one's beyond me. Well,
they didn't know until they bought him
a Bentley and then he wrapped around a
tree. But that's when, that's when
they should have known. And then,
but then there was the other one where
he hit and that was at the hit and run
was after that one up.
The hit and run was after that one.
And then there was the other
one we got pulled over speeding.
And it's good that he told the cop to
go fuck himself. Terrible decision.
Two ways. A fucking wild
dude. That's why he's so good.
But then one of the reasons why
he's, but then you put, you got to
put safeguards in place, right? Like, like
you're making how many million a year?
Multiple. At least for sure. You can't
pay someone 40 grand to drive you around.
You're preaching to the choir.
I mean,
I wish I could clone me and send
me all to all these camps on top.
John, listen to me. Everything's
gonna be fine. I've got a driver,
we've got a Cadillac and escalate
out here. Wherever you want to go.
We're going places. We're going to have
some fun. But no driving, no driving,
no none. We don't need driving. We've
got [inaudible] we've got fun. Let's go.
Oh my gosh. I mean, seriously. Yeah.
Well that's what you would have if
you know you had like, you know, it's,
I dunno what he's doing. I don't
know. I never been to Albuquerque.
I don't know how he's living,
but he can't babysit everybody.
You got the UFC has 500
fighters on its roster. I mean,
how many of those guys are prone
to wild behavior? I would say,
yeah. Yeah. Most of them. Right?
High risk males at playing a sport
where you have the potential to be heard
every single time you step out on the job.
Yeah.
But when you're making
millions of dollars,
you got to put safeguards against
yourself. Yeah. But I think also what
makes John so good is his self confidence
and he probably, he's like, ah,
I got it. Yeah, I fucked up
before, but I got it now.
So I'm really into sports psychology
and I want someone to write this book
because no one's ever written
it. But I think there's this, uh,
I call it the hypocritical elite athlete.
So there's two sides to every coin,
right? And if you're a really
elite athlete, you need
both sides of those corner.
And I'll give you a great example because
this is kind of what you're talking
about. There's these guys who are
ultra elite prepares the eat, right?
They sleep right, they train, right?
They do everything right, right?
But then if one little thing goes
wrong, it messes with them, right?
If they don't get the right food or their
weight cuts bad, they start panicking,
right? And then on the opposite side of
the coin, there's these cowboys, right?
And they're just like, I'm not going to
eat right. I'm not going to sleep right.
I'm not gonna do anything, right?
But when time the step of the cage,
I'm a fight my ass off and nothing's going
to bother me, right? And so you need,
you need both sides of those
coins to make, to make it whole.
And so you want someone ideally
who does everything right,
but at the same time when when something
goes wrong or their toe hurts or
whatever, they can just say,
well, it doesn't really matter.
I'm going to go compete anyways. Right.
You want to have both sides of those.
And that's where I think a lot of the
UFC fighters are more on the cowboy side
of it. Like, well, I'm not really
gonna do a lot of things right,
but I'm just going to go, I'm on fire.
I'm just, we'll fight like cowboy Debbie,
a fantastic example. This, yeah,
the namesake of my argument.
Yeah, that's a good
point. And it, it is, uh,
it's probably one of the more fascinating
things about any form of high stress,
high level competition is there's no real
guidelines of how to prepare your mind.
You know?
I mean,
everybody teaches you how to wrestle
every teaches you how to kickbox.
There's all these martial arts schools.
A teacher technique is very few real
like rock solid programs of a how to,
how to manage your mind. Absolutely. Like,
I think you should be
taught almost like in, in,
in a step by step basis. Like,
Hey, you get a flat tire,
do you kick your car and scream or do
you just go, this is what it is. And Hey,
I could have been born in
Ethiopia with no, right.
I could be living in a fucking coal mine
somewhere. No, I'm lucky. I'm fortunate.
This is thing.
This is a minor setback.
No.
And so like I actually started going to
graduate school for sports psychology.
I got nine of the 36 credits done and
then I actually got a scholarship to go
further and, and you know,
get paid for. Um, but I was
just, I was traveling so much,
that was 2007,
eight when I was trying to make the
Olympic team and I was gone all the time.
And then once I was out of school
for a year, I was just like,
there's no freaking way I'm going there.
I'm not going back to school.
I'm not going to sit in a class.
You're not going to freaking write papers.
I'll still study sports psych on my own,
right?
And so actually every Monday
I do something called the
mental Monday and one of
my Facebook pages and just people
message me questions and I talk about the
mental aspect because you're right,
there aren't enough people that
talk about it. And then, you know,
written wrestling is actually this
company that's being highly successful,
I'll call wrestling mindset.
And they have a training program for
athletes' minds because you're right,
there's nothing out there. Is there
a website for this? Yeah, right.
It's rest of mindset.com.
No kidding. That's great.
And they're starting to s that'll
apply to everything, but well,
they're starting to explain, expand in a
different disciplines. But you're right,
I think, I think there's these
general principles of sports psych,
which can kind of go into any
domain, right? And you're,
you're 100% correct that every single
individual is different. Right.
And one of the, like for me, uh, um, I'm
an overthinker, right? I'm obsessive.
I'll do something over and over and
over and over it again. Right? And so,
like when I was 14 I was at this big
national tournament and I was obsessing
about who I'd have to wrestle and all
this stuff. And it wore me out mentally.
I got my ass kicked right.
And my coach said, hey,
I was that person many,
many years ago.
And it helped me just to talk about
fishing. Right. Cause that maybe, cause I,
if I don't think, I don't want
to think about what I'm gonna do,
I'm not one of those guys because I
think about it too much. All obsessed.
And so ever since age 15 I've,
I've always taught myself a train myself
to not think about the competition
within like, you know, six hours, right?
So maybe the day before I can think about
are a couple of days before I got to
think about it. But like, even
when I'm in MMA locker room,
I'm not thinking about my fight, my
minds off of it. Because if I'm not,
if I don't understand what my strategy
is going to be by six hours before and I
haven't trained myself by six hours
before I fucked right. I'm already fucked.
Like, what am I going to do? Six hours.
It's a brilliant strategy in six
hours, you know, so like six hours.
I intentionally fly people to my fights
who are just my friends who have no
intention of telling me what to do MMA
wise and just want to pull shit backstage.
Right?
Because really smart keeps me really calm
cause otherwise I start obsessing and
that's going to lead to
something really negative.
So that's like one thing is where, you
know, but some people are the opposite,
like the f off too much. You kind of got
to bring them back to focus. Right, right.
You know, in other sports side
concept is is what we'll learn. Gee,
do you want go into the competition? Some
people, you've got to get them amped up.
Some people, most people you got to calm
them down quite a bit. Like let's relax,
let's execute because we need to
up. You're gonna execute. Right?
So I think there's a lot of these sports
psych concepts that can cross over many
different genres. But you're
right, no one trains you about it.
I think it's a huge part of
the sport and it's, it's,
it's overlooked because
the sport is not just,
and I think this is true with every sport,
the sport's not just the
movements that you make.
It's what's going on inside the machine.
Who, the manager of the body as the mind.
And if the manager is like poorly formed
and the structures all out of whack and
you, you have like, whenever a problem
comes up, you fall right into a pit.
All these things should be addressed
and you should develop this mindset,
develop the ability to manage your
mindset. And He, I think at a young age,
I think it's,
it's really critical.
Yeah. No, I totally agree. And you know,
I think, I think one interesting thing,
which I don't know if it's going to
happen to them or now we'll see. Right?
There's very few people who came from
a wrestling background that are head
coaches of MMA teams, right?
Who came from this very,
very structured environment of college
wrestling. It's like you go to,
I want you to remember my first training
camp went to American top team in
Florida. And I show up, it's
11 o'clock practice show,
but 11 o'clock uh oh where's,
where's everyone at? Right.
And then we started 1145 like 45 minutes
late. And then so the next day I'm like,
well,
am I assuming and charm and 1145 or should
I show up at 11 because we say 1145 I
can show up more. So I show up at 1130
and then they started 1120 you know,
like what the hell where's in college
wrestling? If you're a minute late,
you're going to get punished. And college
wrestling, right. It's a very structured,
organized system.
So I'm very curious to see the day
where there is an MMA team that is very
structured like a college
wrestling team would be,
I think it would be very effective
towards performance for athletes. And,
but then again,
you are going to have is a
different structure because
called dressers are poor,
right? Where are you going to a bunch of
MMA fighters who get rich and then say,
well, I don't want to do
what you're saying right now.
How are you going to make them? Right?
They're the one paying your paycheck.
So it does become an
interesting circumstance,
but I think if there was someone
who ran a highly structured,
mixed martial arts team as
structured as a college team,
I think they would have a
gigantic amount of success.
I think their guys would get a
lot better, a lot faster. Um,
and I think you'd see a really interesting
dynamic developed between the high
level athletes and the coaches.
Well,
I think they're still trying to,
trying to figure out what's
the best way to coach fighters.
And I think everybody's got their own
way of doing it. You know, for us,
the hobbies, ways different than the
way they do it at American top team.
Matt Hume was doing it different
than the way Duke does it.
Everybody's got their own way.
And the only way you could tell is
how well the athletes compete. Yeah.
That's the only way you really find
out who's correct and who's need,
who needs to make adjustment.
Yeah.
And it's really hard and in fighting,
because I mean even your highest level
camps, how many say Bella Torn Uca?
How many high level MMA
fights did they have per year?
Maybe 30 and I think that'd be a
lot for most of these teams. Right?
And so you only get 30 samples sizes,
right? Whereas the college wrestling team,
you're going to have between everybody
on the team, the all 40 guys,
you're going to have at least a thousand
matches every single year. Mint minimum.
Right. And then obviously
every event is scored by team.
Every deal made is scored by team,
every NCA championship scored by team.
So you get a very good indication of
what coaches are doing right and what
coaches are doing it wrong. And then
obviously with recruiting process,
the coaching or doing a right now get
the next crop of the best talent. Right.
And so you have a very good idea of
what's working, what is not working.
We're in MMA.
I think we struggle to see it because the
sample size isn't large enough to give
us a really,
really direct correlation.
Now you were able to instigate
your strategy in pretty
much every single one of
your MMA fights.
The only fight where you really struggled
as a j Heran turnoff fight. Yeah,
absolutely. That was a close fight. What
was different in that fight? Well, the,
so that was the,
my first fight at dukes. Um, obviously
Jane Iran is pretty damn good too.
I really don't want to take that
away from, I think he was right,
number 16 the world or
something at that point in time.
That was my first fight at dukes. I
think the biggest mistake I made, I mean,
and obviously at that time, I'm literally
two years into my fighting career,
right? So I stopped
wrestling completely. Um,
I didn't do one wrestling practice.
I moved to Duke's August for, well,
I moved to Wisconsin August 1st search
training, Duke's August 1st I fought, uh,
three months later at the end of October.
I literally did not do one wrestling
practice. So what were you doing? Uh,
I was just as striking
like six times a week.
I was doing Jujitsu a
handful of times a week,
and then I was doing conditioning instead
after that fight in my rest. Well,
and then actually I went to, my brother
was living in New York at the time,
who my brother is also an NCAA champ and
went to visit him for Thanksgiving and
he whooped my ass and I'm like, I freaking
suck at wrestling. Like, you know,
like I went cold Turkey and so it's like,
okay,
I don't need to wrestle every day to be
great at wrestling anymore, but I need,
I need to wrestle once a week,
twice a week with high level competition.
So at that point in time,
and for pretty much the rest of my career,
I would go to one of the local colleges
once a week or twice a week just to keep
my skills sharp.
And so I think that was the biggest
mistake I made in the rom phase.
I didn't wrestle at all prior to
it. Um, but Jay, Ron was good.
He was also a division one
college wrestlers. He knew
what he was doing also. Um,
but I think if I, if I had to pinpoint
one thing that that would be it
isn't it fascinating that a guy with as
much wrestling the experiences you have,
all you have to do is take some time
off and everything degrades? Well,
it's timing.
It's all timing. Right? So you, you
take three months off your time,
he's going to go to shit.
I mean, literally amazing.
Tell you I wasn't even one
practice and it's like,
but that was also what helped me get
the striking thing down is I was doing,
and this is what I think you
actually made this point.
A who the hell are you talking to about
wrestlers are willing to go to the
environment?
I was striking six to seven times a week.
How many strikers go and wrestle?
Six to seven.
None of them. Do they want to
leave? They refused to. Well,
there was Francis in Ghana. It's training
camp. When I talked to people outside,
uh, afterwards, it's crazy. Before
everyone was saying, oh my God,
he's in tremendous shape.
Everything's amazing.
And then afterwards there was like,
uh, he doesn't train on the ground.
What he crazy train on the ground. Like
all he wants to do is strike. Yeah.
Well you can't let them do that.
You can't split up. I can't let him,
he's going to fight and a
division one wrestler. Yeah.
Like how is he going to do this? How is
he going to, how is it going to stand up?
He's going to somehow or another
magically stuff. All the take downs.
You have to train that.
You have to train it.
Yeah. And well, and then,
but you got to train it.
But then even when people train it,
the striker the hell, those strikers,
they don't want to do it. Right, right.
Like I said, when I go to Duke's,
when I started at dukes and it went
down to four times a week where we are
striking,
right.
But in the beginning it was six or
seven times a week sessions a week.
I'm striking. Right. And so I'm immersed
in that culture. I have to learn.
You can't not learn me doing six to
seven times a week and but the strikers,
they want to do one restaurant practice
a week to wrestling practice a week.
Well if you're here and they're here,
how are you going to catch them
by doing one practice a week?
It's freaking impossible.
You need to, I mean if I,
if I got to like be in charge of
an MMA guys camp and I dunno, I,
I coach wrestling,
I love coaching the kids.
I don't know if I ever want to coach
Emma people I would consider for someone
like high level,
but you've got to immerse yourself.
You literally have to take three months
and freaking wrestle every single day
because Russell, you've got to bill,
you have to build those skills.
You're not going an alert.
You're not going to learn something
well doing at one time a week.
You are going to do it.
Period.
No, I, I completely agree
and I think that it,
it all depends on what the
athlete brings to the table.
Like some guys have like a little bit
of wrestling and then maybe they need to
work more on submissions. Maybe some
guys need to work more on their striking.
They get hit too much. I mean it's,
it's every single fighter is a,
there's a different recipe and you
have to figure out what that recipe is.
And it's hard because it's like you
only way you find out is how well they
perform in competition. And how many times
do you even get the chance to do that?
Three a year. Three a year. Yeah, maybe.
Yeah. And so, you know, that's, that's
that. And listen, so I'm not saying,
I'm not saying a striker has to do six
sessions a week for three years straight,
but I'm saying it take three months, take
six months, immerse yourself in that,
be obsessed, be obsessed,
learn those skills, figure
it out. And then after that,
it might be once a week, twice
a week, three times a week.
But then when, when, when,
when, when we start considering
the, the CTE factors,
which I'm not totally sold on, on
CTE yet, cause you don't get hit.
And you know, this guy, he's a poster
boy for wrestling, martial art.
If you really think of,
yeah, no, for sure. But, so I
watched, I watched concussion.
I was actually flying to my fight in
April of 2016 a wash. I said, shit,
that's scary. I did, I spark two
more times the rest of my career.
So my crew was 19 more months.
I spoke twice. I just didn't,
I didn't do it just because you
didn't want to get hit. Uh, yeah.
I felt as an an an an an uh,
an unnecessary risk.
Well, there was a recent
study that came out, oh,
just a few days ago that said that it's
repeated subconcussive hits and they're
causing CTE,
not concussions.
Yeah.
So the,
but the study that made me really question
the CTE phenomenon was they did that
study where they studied a whole bunch
of professional football players and it
was like a hundred per se. It
was like 99% have CT. Right.
But then they studied people who had
played football for any length of time.
Yeah.
Any length of time.
And it was like still like 80%
of the people and it's like,
well f I can't live my life in a bubble.
Right?
Like are like how can 80% of people
who have ever played football,
I mean how many American males,
what percentage of American males walking
around at 40 years old today put some
level of football?
It's like gotta be 80% so you're telling
me 70% of America is walking around
with CTE? Yeah. Or the American males.
Like that's crazy. But that's real.
Come on really is what's
happening. No, I buy, you've got,
you've got to think there's gotta be
some kind of low threshold because
otherwise 40 years down the road,
if everybody played football and
everyone who played football has CTE,
everyone's going to be
walking around like there.
A lot of people are walking around like
that. Come on, that's what's going on.
Or is it a diet? It might be the Diet
coke. A little bit, a little bit of that.
I think way more people have some
form of brain damage than I do.
Well, I think in the world of martial
arts, I know so many guys. Yeah,
well let's talk about not martial artists
are just regular people, ball players.
I think football players,
it's even worse because you're running,
you're running at each other clashing
heads. I mean you watch football,
I mean the damage those
guys take his crave.
It's once in a UFC you'll
see like a wild head kick,
k boom and football games. These guys
are literally running at each other.
I mean it's crazy.
One team's running this way,
the other teams running that way and
they slam into each other and these guys
are 200 5,300 pounds that that impact
that the jarring of your brain.
Plus they have helmets on,
which allows them to be more
confident clashing into each other.
I think a giant percentage of those guys.
But you think,
but so like I said,
so if that one study said it was something
around 80% of anyone who ever played
any level of football field length of
time for anything like that has CTE.
That means like, I mean, if we
take the American population,
at least hit 2% of American
men played football.
Yeah. They have CT. So we're talking
about like a gigantic population. Yeah.
I think there's levels of CTE
though. I mean, I think, you know,
you get to the point where you're like,
Joe Frazier,
he could barely talk before
he died. Um, rest in peace.
But then you also get two guys that are
just like a little forgetful and don't
know why, or impulsive and don't know
why. You know, there's a lot of that,
there's a lot of weird
stuff that comes to CTE.
I've studied it pretty extensively.
Okay.
And the more studies that I've read on
it to more of [inaudible] gotten really
derby. So do you think there's maybe just
a low threshold for what they call CTE?
Well, there's also genes that certain
people have. What was that gene? Rhonda.
Patrick talked about it. Uh,
I don't remember what it was.
Fantastic. She's amazing,
right? Yeah. And she
was talking about, uh,
some jeans make you more susceptible for
traumatic brain injury than other ones.
Like if you have it, you are many
times more likely develop CTE.
But then also,
and then so the other thing that I would
is out of curiosity to me when they did
a CT studies, especially
with they're doing, you know,
after death with these football players,
right? That were so now if they're dying,
their pipe played in the sixties
seventies eighties that time period, uh,
steroid use very,
very high and drug use is also very high
in that culture and so, and and alcohol.
I'm including drugs. So it's
like, did those things contribute,
contribute? Is it a, you know,
is it like a mitigating factor or is it
like going to create this crazy storm of
brain damage that you're, you're going to
freaking running into people like this.
Then you're doing steroids, then you're
a freaking drink and a pack of beer.
Then you're doing some cocaine like
that. That can't be good for you. Right?
Can that be good for you? Can't be, no,
it can't be. Yeah. Especially the pills.
A lot of them get caught or the pain
pills if you're caught up on pain pills,
that's a, that's a big one, man.
We just found out a Tom petty
died from fucking pain pills.
My wife and I were talking about sad.
That was that a man,
he couldn't have a sense of a,
because at my wife and I both love
Tom Petty music, but how he did, how,
how at 66 years old,
he was still like not so okay with
himself that he was jamming pills down his
throat, you know, that he
didn't have a sense of, I have
had great accomplishments.
I've had to create life. You know, I
have people around me that love me that,
you know, I mean, it's gotta be a sad,
lonely thing when you're overdosing
on pills. I would have to assume,
well, I mean, I don't want
to guess, but I would,
I would imagine he's in some
kind of pain if it was free,
is taking those opiates hip
fracture he was recovering from, ah,
I got hooked on them, man. My
friend from the amber from the UFC,
she hurt her ankle recently.
She blew out her a Achilles and she
said the doctor immediately tried to
prescribe oxycontin. She was like, got
the fuck out of here. Yeah. She's like,
I'm not taking that shit. No. And
you know, um, it happens, man.
Doctors just try to shove pills down
your throat. It's a real common thing.
And if you have any sort of serious
injury and they put you on that stuff,
one of the things they put Tom Penny on
was fentanyl and fentanyl is that shit
that's fucking killing. Everybody took
meth. Meth are very similar. No heroin.
It's a extreme deal. Heroin. Yeah. It's
an extremely potent opiate. Yeah. It's,
it's much more, much more potent
than heroin. I didn't many,
many hundreds of times more potent.
Yeah.
And so they give these people fentanyl
patches and then they're taken
oxycontin's too. And who knows what
else. I take it and I mean, I, I've,
I feel terrible for someone who
has bad pain, like, you know,
from a broken hip or something like that.
But Jesus Christ take the pain
rather than death. Seriously,
this shit you could take CBD,
you can take CBD.
It doesn't even have a psychoactive
effect and as radical pain reducing
properties to, yeah.
Yeah. And I, and I, I,
I don't do drugs,
but the fact that people are
so actively prescribing these,
these heavy,
really heavy hard drugs to patients,
people kill people and weed is still
illegal. And I don't smoke weed,
so I'm not even like for myself,
but just for other people.
Well, that's crazy. We need
to be a pain reliever. Really.
I've heard a lot of people say no. A lot
of people do say that. It's just maybe,
I don't know. I just, I'm one
of those people that you're in,
if you're in pain, just be in
pain. Just like, just, just, yes.
Just relax, you know? I mean,
I remember one time though,
I got my knee operated on,
I had an ACL reconstruction and they
gave me one of those buttons in the
hospital. You press it and you get more
fun. And uh, it was when, uh, they,
they had my leg on this motion machine.
Right. So like right after surgery,
they're trying to get your blood moving.
And so there's a couple of screws in
there and they'd taken my patella tendon
and cut it and put it inside and
drilled it all in place and everything.
And then I'm sitting at, it's, this
thing's just, it's this throbbing pain.
And they gave me this little
button. I'm like, clap, clap.
But I'm like, I'm in the hospital.
I'm not going to overdose. But uh,
I remember thinking,
wow,
this could be really fucking
dangerous if you had this in life.
Like it was like a little button on your
hip and you just press it and you get a
dose of morphine.
But it was a wonderful feeling.
I've only done it once
while I was in the hospital.
I got it for that brief moment. I was
like, wow, this is an amazing feeling.
It feel like,
like you're floating through a cloud of
love and just flying through the air.
Like, ah, I went from being
in exacerbating pain too.
So how, how do you feel then we,
so we got in this discussion,
we're talking about
CTE. So now like, okay,
I think MMA is a terrible career path
and people ask me all the time as a
professional MMA fighter,
two different,
two different organizations
or like a couple people.
It's probably the right career
path for majority of people.
Probably not a great career
path, but so, you know,
how do you feel about it when you think
that you, I mean you're obviously saying,
and I'm on the fence,
but you're saying I think a lot of
these people aren't getting CTE clearly.
How do you feel about, you
know, being involved with it?
Cause that's like in my future
I could probably coach them MMA,
but I struggle with it because it's like,
well,
should I really recommend this person?
Do you have a mayor? Should I not?
Because are they gonna end up fucked up
and not be able to take care of the kids
are aware. I don't think you should ever
recommend MMA to anybody. Okay, good.
I usually don't,
I don't think anybody should recommend it.
But I think some people,
it's their destiny. Yeah.
There's a few people out there
that they want to, oh look,
I don't think you should
recommend skydiving to anybody
either though career to
that.
I mean my friend Andy stumped is a
world record holder of squirrel flies.
That's, that's this death. Did you ever
read there was that book called uh,
something chasing superman or do you
remember talking about it was about people
like him and how it almost always ends
up very poorly because you need this
bigger rush and this bigger
rush and this bigger rush.
I was telling him big wave surfers
in the flying suit and all of this,
I was talking about the psychology behind
it and how like it ends up poorly very,
very,
very often because these people need
bigger rushes and more challenges and the
end up fucking themselves up.
It only makes sense.
Yeah. I would never encourage
anyone to do that. But for him,
I mean he's a retired navy seal and
this is just another level of psychotic
shit we can do to fill his time with.
But he's got a bunch of sponsors and
he actually makes a living doing that.
I would never recommend that to anybody.
I wouldn't recommend skiing. You know,
my kids liked skiing. I don't even like
skiing. I go skiing with them every time.
I skied like, no, I've never gotten
hurt. But I'm like, fuck that.
Every time I'm skiing though, I'm
like, don't get hurt. Don't get hurt.
Don't get hurt. Who wouldn't get hurt?
Don't get hurt. Don't get hurt. Oh,
I think it's Sonny
Bono. Oh Geez. Who else?
One of the Kennedy's in a tree.
Right then maybe that was a,
that could have been false flag.
No one could have been right until
we'll push them into the tree. Yeah.
Fuck it took a ski out
with a sniper rifle,
but I wouldn't go too close to the woods.
Yeah.
I think that there's a lot of very,
very dangerous career and I think
if you feel compelled to do that,
no one should be talking you into that.
But yeah,
I don't think anybody should stop you.
Like, I like the fact that boxing exists,
you know, would never want to tell. You
know the Civil Lowman Chanko don't fight.
Sure. I don't know. I would never
want to tell him don't fight.
I want to see him fight. Well,
what if they, what if, uh,
it gets proven without a shadow of a
doubt that these things cause he, he CTE.
Do you think the government
is going to ban them? No,
I don't think they can really.
How could they be?
Are they going to ban the government?
Like banning everything they really do.
They like banning things that cost them
money or the cost people who don't end
up to them money.
Fair enough.
The banning of the drugs is really tied
to pharmaceutical drugs more than a year.
They're not banning it because
they're trying to save us.
They're banning it because someone's
putting pressure on them to ban it or had
put it in the past and they're,
nobody's banning a skateboarding.
No one's trying to ban BMX ride.
Those guys kept fucked up. I mean,
I was watching this video the other day
of those guys doing the ramp with the
skateboard and the guy got to the top of
the ramp and didn't catch it right and
fell like a hundred feet awful.
Oh Jesus Christ.
I mean they get beat the foot that's up.
That's another one where the
damn book chasing soup man,
or being superman mad at something.
Nothing. Superman coding. Superman.
I decoding superman was called
the coding superman. Yeah. Okay.
So like if you go back and watch the
original x games when I, you know,
I was a kid, I don't remember what year
it is, nineties at some point. And uh, oh,
the rise of the Superman, decoding the
science of ultimate human performance.
This is a, this is a freaking fantastic
book. I mean it's like, it's so awesome.
I'm so, I'm obsessed with sports psych.
Like I said, I'm sure Steven Kotler. Yeah,
that guy's interesting.
Yeah.
But so if you look at like the original
x game stuff and then you go to like the
x games today. Oh yeah. It's different
world. Yeah. Totally different events.
So much more extreme because you there,
it has to be this advanced, advanced,
advanced, advanced, but then all of a
sudden people are getting left up. Yeah.
You get to a certain point where you can
only do so many flips in the air with
your bike. Apparently they tried to
go more. I would do one rotation.
Everybody go, this is crazy. Yeah.
Somebody that comes along with two
and then now they're doing three.
Wasn't there?
The movie about a Tony Hawk was like the
first one did the seven 20 or something.
But now they go way
more, don't they? Yeah.
It's and going to be more in every year.
And if you watch any of those par core
kids that are building to building and,
and we've had one of them are in
here. What was his name? James.
He's a
find it. I don't know. I'm sorry.
That one I listen to mostly
you're a political ones.
I think some of the people you bring
in are highly fascinating. Yeah. It's,
it's an interesting time. W I get
labeled outright. I know it's bizarre,
but everybody's so quick to label
people today. It's such a strange time.
Finger pointing and putting people
in boxes. Disingenuously it's,
it's more divisive. They, a lot of
these leftist, they want to, uh,
you know, they want to say, well, I'm
trying to make people less racist,
but what they're really doing, they're
being very divisive. Yeah. You know,
and like I would,
I think you identify as libertarian.
I W I identify more as a libertarian
than Republican or Democrat. But yeah,
a lot of people say, I'm all right
or love Trump so much and it's, well,
I'm more libertarian than anything.
I think less government,
less invasion into our lives.
But people want to put you into a little
box because you don't agree with what
they're saying. Yeah. It's
a weird time for that.
And W I think what you
were saying about shaming,
they tried to shame you
into this racist or shame,
but you're not doing that if you're
pretending someone's racist when you know
they're not.
Or if you're pretending that someone
is a sexist or homophobic or whatever,
when you know that you're just,
people are,
they're ignoring nuance.
Yeah. And what, and what's,
what they're really doing
also is they're making,
they're making people afraid to speak
their minds. Right. And really how,
if you and I had a
disagreement on something,
how we would come to a common ground
is by discussing it. I'd say, well,
I think your result person, what do
you believe? Then you'd say, well,
I don't agree with that and this is why.
And eventually we would talk it
out and maybe we still disagree,
but we'd come to a common ground. Right?
But instead the people on the one side,
they're not saying that they're saying,
what'd you say you're racist or sexist
or homophobic, nay, nay. Name one. Right.
And then ended discussion. Then there's
no discussion at all. Right? Yeah.
They're trying to win. Yeah, exactly.
They just turned on when they're trying
to label you and then get the upper hand.
And yeah, I think there's a real problem
with people not being reasonable.
And I think that you should be able
to have conversations like I've had,
people have criticized me, uh,
even in person I've taught,
like why would you have that
guy on your show? Which one?
Any guy like a Milo Yiannopoulos,
perfect example. And I'm like,
well look what happened.
I mean,
we got to see how the guy
thinks God got mean all,
all of his weird issues that came
up and his book deal falling apart.
A lot of that had to do with
conversations I had with him. Yeah.
It's like now you get to chance to
see how the guy actually thinks.
And I don't think there's anything wrong
with the way he thinks. I think it's a,
he's a provocateur. I mean
it's not how I think. Yeah.
But I think that everybody
has this perspective on who
he is that is exaggerated
because of this public persona
that he does that to be outrageous.
So I think that's a double
edged sword because I think,
I think Alex Jones does it as well. Alex,
where way crazier than well, but okay.
But same idea, right? Is like, yes,
part of their persona is a show is a show.
It's making it more extreme because
they want to say that one thing that's
totally effing crazy. It'll catch
a headline somewhere. Right.
And so they have these beliefs,
but then they kind of go beyond them
because it is a show and because they will
make more money if they get more
followers or more people clicking on the
articles. Are there videos or whatever.
So I think it is, but then you know,
you go to someone like the Bret
Weinstein Guy, I think he's fascinating.
People calling him a racist and you know,
he was strong liberal and he's
as progressive as it gets.
He's as far from a racist as you
could ever get. Yeah, yeah. There's a,
there's this need to label people.
Well Alex is,
Alex is a showman and
but also like he says,
some things that are pretty fucked up,
like the sandy hook stuff,
you know what I'm saying?
The Sandy Hook was a us.
He's looking for conspiracies everywhere.
Everywhere.
He finds them some places.
So sometimes he's, right.
Exactly. Sometimes he's right.
Yeah.
But the problem with looking
for conspiracies everywhere
as you are going to,
you're going to make people feel terrible.
Yes.
There was an article that I read about a
guy who was a conspiracy theorist until
his son was killed in Sandy
Hook was people were telling
him that his son wasn't
killed and that is some sort
of a government actor and
this guy was devastated.
Yeah.
You know,
of course the people that are really
the nutty conspiracy theorist, Oh,
you're spoken undercover still.
You're still under Grover.
There's people out there that look
for conspiracies. Yeah. Everything.
And it becomes a real problem because
it muddies up the water. But I think,
I think at the same time,
you, at least for me,
and I think we have
similar thought processes,
you can't just take what mainstream
media tells you and say, well,
I guess that's how it happened.
Right. So as an in some situations,
but in Sandy Hook, you have dead kids
of people grieving. You have bodies,
autopsy reports. Yeah. It happened.
Yeah, absolutely. I know had guns.
You had a mentally ill person
who had access to these guns.
Then if you take that same
thought process on say,
Stephen Paddock in the Las Vegas shooting,
well we still don't know
how that turned out, right?
The Las Vegas shooting is complicated,
but as we know,
one guy did do that well now
coming out with new stuff,
I think there was other people involved
and he might've gotten help from people,
whether it's willingly or unwillingly,
but or wittingly or unwittingly.
But I don't think there was other
people shooting. They've said that.
So I don't know. Right. And that's
what the law of these conspiracies,
you'd have to understand that you're never
really gonna know what the real truth.
Right? Right. You have to keep it
open mind and you'll say, okay,
well this person says this. What does this
person say? What does this person say?
Do these things,
check out with each other.
And it's like how many different times
have they changed the Las Vegas shootings
timeline?
Right.
And then it was kind of weird that
it went way out of mainstream media.
Like I'll send you heard about it for a
week and then you didn't hear about it
again. Sign of the times, I think the new
cycle. Today's about Tony Hours. Yeah.
But you would think people want answers.
I mean
that's the largest mass shooting
in United States history.
I think we'd want some more clear answers
on what really happened and how it
happened and why it happened. Um,
and we never really got those.
And I know there's been a few new
articles on it recently and so maybe we're
going to find out more information,
but it's an incredibly confusing story.
Absolutely. The guy was clearly
a psycho and clearly fucked up.
I'm clearly planned this out
for a long time. I mean he,
he got hotel rooms overlooking music
festivals and other places. Yeah.
And like was planning out how
to do this for a long time.
He had a note in his,
uh,
in his hotel room that had all the
ballistics calculation, so he knew like,
like bullet drop from x amount of yards
and he was calculating how to kill all
these people.
Yeah.
He was on some weird antidepressants
and anti not anti anxiety medication,
which does all kinds of
weird shit to your head.
There's a guy that was prone
to fits of rage. He was a,
a calculated professional gambler. There's
a lot of weird stuff with this guy.
The fact that he accumulated
these weapons over years. Yeah,
and maybe did it knowing that he
was going to do this so you don't,
there's a, whenever there's a mass
shooting or anything, that's crazy.
You have two things happen.
One,
everybody wants answers and to everybody
forgets about it really quick because
some new shit happens in the news and
if it wasn't your family that got shot,
it wasn't someone that you're
close to that got shot.
I know people that got shot there.
I know people that I met them.
I met people in Vegas
that that got shot there.
I talked to them after it was over.
It was complete and total chaos and
when there's complete and total chaos,
you get all sorts of conflicting reports.
People were running into other casinos
saying that there's a shooter because
they ran out of that area and so then
people were calling and police reports.
There's a shooter in the Monte Carlo,
there's a shooter in this.
And so those things get reported as
fact when many times it's a part of the
confusion of a chaotic mass shooting.
Like that Vegas event.
I don't know what happened other than
the fact that this one guy definitely
killed a bunch of people,
but whether or not someone was helping
him or whether or not there was other
people involved or I think they're still
investigating as to, yeah, and it's, but,
so I guess my, my greater
point there would be that, uh,
if you're an intelligent individual,
you can't just take what cvs tells
you to be complete fact, right? You,
you go do some investigation yourself,
you try to read from different
sources and then, Hey, sandy hook,
I think there's like a 99.999999999%
chance of Sandy Hook was real.
Right.
Is there some crazy in the impetus of the
small chance that didn't happen? Sure.
Right. But I think, I don't think
there is, I think it's very unlikely.
And this a Vegas was a 0% zero.
Sandy, Sandy Hook didn't happen.
So I looked into it pretty, you know,
it's just sad to me. And you're a dad,
you know the idea of your kid going to
school and getting their school getting
shot up by some psychopath.
Yeah.
Imagine if someone was saying that that
was fake. Yeah. After your kid's dead,
you'd be frustrated,
infuriated,
you wouldn't even know where to turn.
And these that's actually happening
to these people and they're,
they're getting labeled as, as frauds
and people are emailing them and saying,
how could you do this? You're, you're
defrauding the American people.
You're a part of the Illuminati or,
yeah. So, well, I think so. I
think there's obviously those
people who are on, right.
The way one side of it,
there's so there's, so if you
go a spectrum for me, right?
There's the American who's drinking
diet coke and eating frozen pizza and
listening to every CPS says, right? And
then in the total opposite of spectrum,
there's the group that thinks every single
thing that ever happens in America as
a, as a planned conspiracy by
the new world order. Right?
So those are two ends of
the spectrum right now.
We can fall anywhere in the middle there.
But I,
so I think as an intelligent individual,
we look at situations independently and
say, well, there's some sketchy things.
They're not sketchy things there.
That's probably true. Right.
And kind of independently think
about stuff by ourselves and that's,
that's how I do it. And so, you know,
that's a wise way to approach it. Yeah.
And uh, I think CBS or NBC or you
know, any name, your new source,
they're run by people.
And if they weren't there,
they only have access to a
certain amount of information.
And sometimes they get bad information
and sometimes they don't necessarily know.
I don't know how much of it is a part
of some grand conspiracy rather than how
much of it is a part of
the chaos of these moments.
The lack of information and
people drawing conclusions and,
and then also witnesses on the scene and
people on the scene of something that's
crazy. They give all sorts of
weird accounts and they're just,
they're filled with adrenaline. They
don't know how to handle the situation.
People, you know, the people don't
handle chaotic events very well.
Yeah. But I don't think the earth flat
if that's fair. Well, good for you. Yeah.
What do you, what do you possibly
believe in? That might be crazy.
Can I take a piss in it? I'll tell you. I
got to go fast. Go ahead. No worries man.
I wonder if there's something wrong with
my bladder that you can hold it. Yeah.
Do you think I've trained
it? Yeah. I mean, sure.
I just had guys going to try to shoot
himself to see the flat earth and a couple
of days.
Oh,
you guys shoot himself up into the space
and don't take March 2nd James Kingston,
James Kingston. Thank you. Sorry
James. Yeah. Bam. Yeah, it's a Dunbar.
There is Dunbar's number, brother. Uh,
you can only keep 150 people
in your brain at any time.
Look at that fucking picture.
We're looking at a picture for the audio
folks of James Kingston on the top of
this tower. And I don't know how
many fucking stories he's up there,
but it's insane because below him,
and I mean way below him are skyscrapers.
That's probably like Dubai or something.
Right.
Do you think that Dunbar's number could
apply to other things besides people
like websites or numbers of
instructions? Exactly. Yeah. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Yeah, I think so.
You know, I think it, uh, it
applies to too many things.
Uh, it applies, I just think
for names, names and people,
I'm,
I'm struggling.
I think I'm getting like I have
a overflowing pot, like, um,
um,
shame Burgos
and Calvin cater. We're fighting this
weekend and I called Calvin Cater,
Chris Cater after he won, even though
I'm a fan of his, like he wanted,
I went Chris Cater and then I'm like,
it's fucking name's Calvin dumb cunt.
Like I just don't, I think I'm running
out of space in my head for names.
So my apologies to Calvin cater.
I'm running out of names and my,
we're talking about Dunbar's number,
how you can only keep so many people
in your brain. My brain's overflowed.
I don't have any hard drive space left.
I didn't know.
So I thought it was a is that the guy
says you can only like keep track of 150
people like what's going on in the
relationships and that kind of stuff.
You only have so much room in your,
in your hard drive space. Yeah.
It's based on a tribal societies.
Like our brains are sort of designed
to keep track of 150 people.
That's how we evolved and
then over the last, you know,
x amount of hundreds of years,
now all of a sudden you have to keep
track of many, many multiples of that.
Especially if you're someone like you or
I that runs into so many people who you,
you, you meet on a regular basis. Got
to keep those people all in your brain.
But is it, is it, so I guess I haven't
read that. Read it an edge. A bunch.
Is it that you have to just
know their names and faces,
or is it that you have to know
like what's going on in their life?
I think you're supposed to be able to
track them, like have a, some sort of a,
whether it's intimate or
personal relationship with
these people know them. Yeah.
So it's like there's only something like,
especially if you think about
a commentating on fights,
I have to pay attention to these guys
and what they're doing and their career.
And there's hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of 500 fighters now,
500 fighters that's active. And then how
many of them get re new guys come in,
old guy go away. I still keep
them all in my head. Hey,
what's Sean sherk up to
these days? They're all still
in the head and it's like,
there's not, there's only so much room.
And after a while you will, you'll wonder,
you're like, wow, where are
all these people going? Yeah.
And I found that obviously with the, it's
sad, like, you know, college friends,
it's like, yeah, you know,
and it's good because you see him and
it's like no time has passed. Right.
But it's like I, if I, if I know
if I was live in two minutes way,
we'd probably be best friends
still. Right. But now I
get to see you once a year,
twice a year maybe. I can't keep up
with you, dude. It's super challenging.
I totally agree. And you're now max
and I run the rest of the academies.
My brother,
we have three in Wisconsin and it's like
this fall was my first wife fulltime,
worked at one and so now I'm
really immersed in the one academy,
whereas I was kind of loosely
keeping track of all three.
But now that I'm kind of
totally immersed in the one,
I find it a lot harder to keep track
of what's going on at the other two,
whereas kind of bed read it before
when I wasn't so immersed in one. Yeah.
I can only imagine Eddie Bravo is a
hundred schools. That's crazy. Right?
It's 110 plan. Jujitsu's worldwide. Like
how he can't keep check all uncanny.
I don't know. I don't know. I'd have to
ask him. I know he travels to all of them.
He travels, he's constantly traveling.
I traveled all a travels constantly.
He's doing seminars at all of, oh
my gosh. Always traveling. Yeah.
Once he is so easy to do like
one time year for each facility.
Right.
I don't know. It's a good question. That
would be the Columbia he's going to,
he's going, I mean you probably
wouldn't even be once a year. Yeah.
He's three years Singapore
now. Yeah. He's everywhere.
He was out in Singapore when I was there
and uh, one of my fights this year,
it was maybe the, maybe the
May fight. Yeah, I think, yeah,
he was out there doing is a 10th
planet seminar and now that,
and now they have a 10th planet
program at evolve is crazy.
Evolve is supposed to be an amazing
facility. I've heard some amazing, yeah,
it's Fab. I mean the, the
nicest MMA facility I've ever
been to. And so they have,
they actually just opened their
fourth location. Justin Singapore,
which Singapore is a city state, right?
It's 6 million people in a, on a really,
really small island.
But some of their,
some of their academies are only a mile
or two apart. Like they're not far apart,
but the population density is
such that, you know, they listen,
they start classes at I think at 6:00 AM
and they end class at 11:00 PM and you
can freaking stop in anytime of day and
there'll be a class there that's full
with Muay Thai or Jujitsu, whatever
you name it, it will be going on.
That's great. Yeah. Well Manhattan is
kind of like that in a lot of ways, right?
Manhattan is how many Jujitsu schools are
in Manhattan? I mean obviously Marcel,
yeah, there's hundreds, but really
nick one's Hendel has got a huge one.
Marcel has got a huge one, so
yeah, there's a lot right there.
Handles is huge. And that places enormous.
Hundreds and hundreds of students.
I thought that, no, I thought it was
thousands. That's what somebody told me.
Hanzo has over a thousand
students in the main New York
City location. And I think it's,
you know, it ain't cheap
cause you got to pay for rent.
Mm. And so they're probably paying a
couple hundred bucks a month. Yeah.
Of still have of all right.
Is I think $350 a month.
Wow. But obviously,
so Singapore is one of the most
wealthy countries on the planet.
So you have to take that new account
approach. Everyone that lives there,
it has a, a decent amount of wealth and
you know, it, they spend it differently.
Singapore is a fascinating
country. If you, I, I, you know,
I was there 15 times or whatever,
so I got kind of immersed in the culture
and then ended up reading the books
about Lee Kuan Yew, the guy who
started the country. And so, you know,
there was a whole bunch
of those Asian countries,
they got independence in
the 1950s and sixties. Um,
and Singapore I blew was founded in 1965.
It could be off by one year
there maybe. Um, but you know,
a lot of those countries are not doing
super well economically and Singapore is
like,
this is freaking stand out country who's
like top five world per person wealth
and why, why, why are they
doing so much better? Uh,
and so this is me from an
outsider's perspective. So um,
they really do a lot of kind of, it's
kind of like self tracking, right?
And so every month a Bungee, your
check comes out to a, you know,
like we would pay taxes, right?
Bunch of mine comes another check,
but so they can spend it.
This is fascinating.
They spend their money on three things.
It goes, it goes in it, it's fun, right?
Education, healthcare and housing. Okay.
And so if you want cheaper, if any one
of those, if you want the cheapest of it,
right. It's very government subsidized
and it comes out of your fund, right?
So only a little bit of mine comes out.
If you want the nicest healthcare
or the nicest housing are nice,
then it's only a tiny percent
government subsidized. Right?
So the more expensive the stuff gets,
whether it's education or housing or
healthcare, the less subsidize it gets in,
the cheaper gets, the more subsidized it
gets. And so everyone Kinda, you know,
they pay,
they painted this fun so everyone has
this personal fund that they can use and
then you know, into those three things.
And so I think a lot of people have,
I think they feel like they
have more control over their
lives and, and you know,
obviously it is very strict
regulations and laws,
but from what I've seen and
I've spent a lot of time there,
everyone seems pretty happy.
That's interest.
Yeah. That's an interesting
way to go. I mean,
I don't think there's any one good way
to government to govern people. Yeah.
And I mean I think we have a
pretty good system over here,
but it's obviously filled
with bureaucratic bullshit
and right. Too much weight,
too much government.
There's much,
there's way too many people doing stupid
jobs getting paid too much or doing
them. And I mean it's, and
then the shit like, you know,
trying to chase down medical marijuana
in 2017 trying to stop legal marijuana
and like why? Like what, who's
paying you to do this? Like why you,
why are you doing that?
That doesn't make any sense.
It's not what our tax dollars
should be going towards.
You know, it's funny when you go
all the way back, I think about it.
So we talk about that process of who's
keeping them from doing this and you have
like the pharmaceuticals with,
with weed, which I think is true.
You know what a funny one I think about
is John Mccain and mixed martial arts
who was sponsoring John Mccain,
Budweiser who was like the
main advertisers of her boxing.
It's like you cannot make an argument
that boxing safe for them and May,
you can't freaking do it. So like
it's impossible. It's impossible.
But John Mccain's over here getting paid
by Budweiser and saying MMA is awful.
Let's ban it.
And the same time he's promoting boxing,
essentially it's fricking mindblowing.
Well in his
fence. It was MMA from a long
time ago and it wasn't, yeah,
it wasn't really the same as them may now.
And he's turned the corner and
now he supports him. My man. Yeah.
But also you've got Budweiser and
bud light or sponsors now of MMA,
so it's like, but that's a real problem
with politicians. They're dirty.
There's so many dirty politicians.
I don't know what percentage is,
but it's high 97. It's probably,
it's probably a fucking high.
Know what crazy shit that, what could
crazy conspiracy do you believe in?
So the one that got me started really
like independently think myself was nine
11, which I think that was, that was
for a lot of people. Yeah. Yeah. What,
what do you think about nine 11. Oh,
I know. I don't know all the answers,
but I know the given explanation. I
don't believe what, give an explanation.
Uh, the one that came, what's
the damn report that they wrote?
The NIST report? No, that wasn't what
it was. Was it? Yeah, we'll, NIST is a,
the one who did the report on,
um, tower seven collapsing.
Now, what was the other report that
came out with right away? Um, anyway,
so I had my buddy that right by the
airport and he played loose change for me
and I said, you are out of your Gd
Mind, like you are insane man. Right?
And then I started thinking,
well that doesn't, maybe, maybe,
maybe I should think about it. You
know, that it was an inside job.
I'm not totally, I mean, I,
so I think obviously the planes
flew into the buildings for sure.
If there's no doubt about
that. But um, that maybe the,
there was inklings inclinations that ha
that was going to happen and that not
enough was done to stop it.
I think, um, this is one,
this is another thing where you have
a gigantic tragedy and because of a
gigantic tragedy,
there's a lot of people that draw these
conclusions based on witness a testimony
and things that are happening.
But I think you have to realize
that any time there's some,
some thing that happens,
people start looking for all these
different correlating factors, right?
You start saying, well, hey
look, you know, there was a,
there's local tests that were being done.
There was, they were looking out for, uh,
planes that were potentially
gonna fly into building.
Like they knew this was
going to happen in advance,
but if you talk to anybody that
is in intelligence, there's,
they're dealing with that shit every day.
Just one day something happens.
There's always warnings
about terrorist attacks.
There's always warnings about things
happen. And a lot of times they,
these warnings get towards
like the FBI stop that. Um,
wait, there was one, there was
one in San Francisco, right?
They had bombs and they stopped in
the ledger, security, whatever. Yeah.
And this has happened many times.
Yeah. Now when, when it doesn't,
when they don't catch it and it goes
through, then people start thinking, oh,
there was some sort of a conspiracy.
They allow these planes
to fly into buildings. The
missile hit the Pentagon and
look, there was a video came
out of that last week, but I,
I might've been fake news,
the Pentagon thing.
There was a video of the Pentagon
or something. He ended up Pentagon,
which looks like a missile and not an
airplane, but I don't believe it was,
you know,
I was like this instincts,
I've never seen this video before and
obviously there's no video evidence of
what hit the Pentagon.
There's a video of something.
I know there was one, yeah,
the camera thing or a security
camera video that was released,
but what they did have is all sorts of
pizza pieces of aircraft all over the
fucking lawn in a blown up building
and a plane that's missing and all the
people dead. Like, I'm going to guess
it was a plane. Yeah. You know, I just,
I think people look for conspiracies
and everything cause it's exciting.
Well, I mean stimulating about it.
There is, but then obviously be, I,
I know that you don't believe
that everything we're told
is the truth right away.
Right? I mean if we go to something like
a Gulf of Tonkin incident, right? I mean,
perfect. That's been proven to be false.
Or the fact like the banana republics,
right?
Where Dole asked us to go take out one
of their dictators because they were
going to nationalize all of the
banana plants and that country. Yeah.
I mean those things have been now proven
to be totally factual that the United
States government went and did that
stuff. So the fact that, and you know,
in 1960s or seventies those things
were reported the opposite, right.
We can't obviously take
everything that we've
been reported as truth.
While there's definitely been conspiracies
that have been put together and
executed and these conspiracies have
greatly affected the American people.
The Gulf of Tonkin is a perfect example.
Another one that they were planning on
was the operation Northwoods operation.
Northwoods was one that they were
planning on blowing up a drone jetliner
blaming it on the Cubans that were going
to arm Cuban friendlies and have them
attack Guantanamo Bay.
And they were gonna sacrifice American
troops and American lives and they were
going to do this in order to get people
to be excited about a war with Cuba. Yes.
Was, this is a real thing that was
signed by the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
It was released by the
freedom of Information Act
and it was vetoed by Kennedy.
So we know that there were people,
at least in 1962 they were
planning on shit like this. Yeah.
So that's a real thing.
And the idea that that just went away
and no one does that anymore. It's crazy.
I don't, I don't believe
that. I think there's,
there's most certainly evil people
in all fucking sectors of life.
Yes, absolutely. Yeah. So it's
good to have an open mind,
but there's also a lot of
fucking conspiracy loons
it looks they get consumed
good. That's, that's the
issue they get consumed with.
Nothing that I've been told is true,
which is obviously I said that
one far end of the spectrum and I,
anyone who is dead end is crazy also.
Yeah.
There's people out there that think the
satellites are fake and they think that
real and that the earth is flat is once.
Why I just shake my head like the
moon landing one's my favorite.
I got balls deep in that for
years I was complete complicit.
You think they did not go to the moon?
No, I don't. I don't think that anymore.
But you know what I think now I think,
I don't know.
But I do think that it is one of the more
fascinating conspiracies that between
1969 in 1972 they had seven,
seven,
seven to attempt six of them successful.
But they went to the Apollo 13 was the
one that they didn't apparently make it
and they had to come back.
But that was the only time in history
that a human being has been more than 400
miles above the earth's surface.
All the space station missions,
all the space shuttle missions, all
that stuff is, is within Arbonne. Yeah,
it's low.
That's all very low.
They went 260,000 miles out
and back into deep space,
but they'd never even flown a chicken
out there and see if it can live.
Like we really, really? Yeah. No, I'm
not into this. The space travel and so,
and they did a couple of flybys
went around the moon. Oh,
early before they landed on the
moon. Yeah. But other than that,
I mean without unmanned drones, like what
we have on Mars and things like that,
we've never really sent a living
thing out through the magneto sphere,
through the van Allen radiation belts
into deep space, have it, you know,
I mean there's all these possibilities
of solar flares and anything that would
have killed him instantly and they just
did that and then we haven't been able
to do that since 1972
that's the one way I,
I've never looked into that moonlighting.
I think it's kind of Goofy, right?
Well it's, it's weird. It's a weird
one. Why have we never gone back?
It's been fifth.
Surely our technology is far superior
to what it was in 1969 right?
The technology is far superior except
that they're not using that technology for
man space, travel into deep space
like that and then go to the moon.
So it's like our technology and
all these other areas is superior,
but they haven't really worked towards
that because they haven't been funded.
So the big issue is in many
ways it's money, right?
There's how much money is
there and going to the moon,
and it's also very risky
to send humans out there.
Maybe we're talking about
manned missions to Mars now,
which may or may not take place by
2030 they're talking about doing that,
but it's way cheaper and safer
to send robots out there.
Like why risk human lives. It's
very retro the moon. Right,
and if it robots on
Mars. Yeah, the rovers,
rovers on Mars or most the, that's
the most interesting because they're,
they're sending these really
high resolution photos of
the surface of Mars and
they're running tests and checking
for biological life. It's really,
really interesting stuff. But between
69 and 72 when they did all this stuff,
I mean there's,
the technology back then was nothing
compared to what they have now in terms of
calculations and computers and,
and it's also, there was a,
there's unquestionably some stuff that,
whether it was images or video
that was faked and I think really,
yeah, I do. Like I said, I
never looked into this at all.
Gemini 15 is the big one because
there's a photo of Michael Collins.
It shows him in deep space and they use
it as a press release saying that he was
on a space walk when it was really an
image of him from a test run where there
was all this stuff in the background
and he was on his harness and they just
blacked out the background and tried
to sell it as him being in space save.
You find that my Michael Collins,
you,
I was looking at how much it cost to send
somebody to space though. It's insane.
79 70 million for ash and [inaudible]
not to fly on a Russian shuttle.
Those private guy's trying to sell
tickets to places that mean days.
I'll just try and do it Musk
obviously. But that space, that's just,
that's just low earth orbit.
That's,
that's still inside 400 miles
or trying to go anywhere? No.
Well they might in the future.
Branson. Well that's all same thing.
It's all the way through but,
but,
but they are talking about future
visits to the moon and to Mars.
But a lot of times I feel like
when they say that, you know,
George Bush senior said that they were
going to go to the mute back to the moon
again and like fucking one was that
1990 or whenever the hell that was.
But people have always said,
we're going to go back to the moon,
but we haven't been back since 1972
does that mean that we never went? No.
But Dennis gets weird when you find out
that Wernher von Braun was a fucking
Nazi. Who? Wernher von Braun, the
guy who he was the head of NASA.
He was the guy who organized the the
moon landings and though he was the head
rocket guy, he was, he,
that guy was a legit Nazi
like he's wanted by the,
the Simon Wiesenthal Center
said that he was alive today.
They would prosecute him
for crimes against humanity.
They would hang the five slowest workers
every day in front of his Berlin rocket
factory. Oh yeah. No, 100% I
mean, that's what they did.
What they did was they took this
thing was called operation paperclip,
where when we won World War II,
they took all the top Nazi scientists
and they secretly brought him over to
America and they did it on the down low
so that no one would think like, hey,
why do we have a guy named Wernher von
Braun running the American space program
was because the, the Nazi scientists
were insanely advanced. Hmm.
So the question is like,
well,
were they really Nazis or were they
scientists that were under the boot of the
Nazi administration? I mean, well, I
don't know. I mean, I'm not around that,
but I do know that these are the people
that were the head engineers and the
people that designed it,
Wernher von Braun's himself was saying
how impossible it was just years before
they did the moon landing and years
before operation paperclip that it was
impossible to go to the moon or how
ridiculously impossible would be.
But technology advanced from then to
when 1969 happened to when they did it.
I stopped saying that we never went to
the moon because I really don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about. And that's,
that's a big part of the understanding.
These conspiracies is hard.
You have to,
well you have to really know how
much do I know about rocketry?
How much do I know about
aerospace? Zero. Yeah.
So if I'm running around
saying I don't, I, you know,
I don't believe people went to the moon.
What is it based on?
It's based on mostly on ignorance,
speculation and the exciting
excited feeling that comes
with trying to uncover a
conspiracy.
Sure.
But a,
and I think you do have to be a little
bit discerning on what you hear and, and,
but it is frustrating and that's
where a lot of these conspiracy guys,
they think they know more than they
do because you have to come to the
realization that you're probably never
going to know the real answer with a lot
of these things realize, I mean some
of them come out many, many, many,
many years later we're talking about
like Gulf of Tonkin writer or operation
Northwoods. Many years later
it comes out, but you know,
there's a good likelihood that
I'll never know the truth on stuff.
I had read a lot about,
I think with the moon landing, it's way
more likely that we went to the moon,
but that some of the footage is fake and
I think they probably did that because
it's incredibly difficult
to film things on the moon.
And I think they filmed some stuff in
test runs and then tried to pass that
stuff that I iPhone,
they didn't have it back then.
They had these cameras that they
had in the center of their chest.
I think they were been taking a Selfie
on the moon. They had the snapchat,
snapchat, you'd have to take your shoot
off then you would die. There was theirs.
Yeah. They didn't have a camera
that you could put in front of you.
Well,
maybe they have one of the clicker buttons
they could have with their big gloves
on and they, they, you know,
they put the thing out and then
click it and then boom, snapchat.
Why fight in the moment?
Well that's what they said. Well,
it was that they did it remotely.
That's how they captured the
video of the lunar module,
leaving the surface of the moon and
panned up and watched it go that they did
all that remotely. Hmm. It's all
this some squirrely footage ever.
See the video of them
jumping around and it like,
they're on trampoline
and I see that we like,
they're just bouncing straight up
in the air and you're like, well,
what the fuck is that? How
come the physics are different
in different flights?
Like in some,
some of the flights like Apollo 11
they're barely getting off the ground.
They're walking, but they're kind
of to do. Yeah. Like that. Well,
there's ones like that and then there's,
we'll also ones where they fall down.
It looks like the getting
yanked up by wires. Hmm.
I think it's entirely possible that some
of that stuff was fake. Huh. But I don't,
I think it's way more likely that they
actually went to the moon than they
didn't. But it's way sexier to think that
they faked the whole thing. It's fun.
It's fun to think they faked the whole
thing and everybody was quiet about it.
And you know,
Neil Armstrong gave this real cryptic
speech on the 25th anniversary of the Moon
mission saying that, you
know, there are hidden truths,
uh, the, the, the, that, uh,
what is, what is the exact
quote that he said? Um,
some of the great truths
that could be real revealed,
removing some of truths, hidden
layers, like he was giving her away.
It was real cryptic. It was like,
what do you see if he could find it?
I got the video, the play, the video.
He might have been given it away. Well,
it seemed if you were conspiracy theory,
this would give you a rock hard
boner cause lesson. Listen to this.
Armstrong, middle rare public
appearance. Next generation of taxpayers.
No, no, no. Just play the whole thing
so you don't confuse everybody. Okay.
In 1994,
Neil Armstrong meter rare public
appearance and held back tears as he spoke
these brief cryptic remarks before the
next generation of tax payers as they
toured the White House.
Today we have with us,
my group of the students,
some on America's best
to you.
We say we have only completed a beginning.
We leave you much.
That is undone.
There are great ideas.
Undiscovered breakthroughs are available
to those who can remove one of truths,
protective layers.
What the fuck does that mean? I
mean, what do you supposed to say Yo,
I went to the moon bitch. Yeah,
that's what's to say breakthroughs.
He's giving it away.
Truth,
protective layers like I don't
even understand what that means.
The vig caught the press conferences.
One of the more fascinating things,
if you watch the press conference again,
I was balls deep in this stuff for years.
The press conference from 1969 when they
were returned from the moon is one of
the most cryptic weird
things you'll ever see.
These guys look like they just stole
something and they're being questioned.
It's, it's, it's,
I've never seen a video where people
look like they're more full of shit.
Then that video of the press conference
from 1969 it's weird, man. It's weird.
They're like fidgety and looking nervous,
like they getting away with something
and then they might have done it right.
They might have a been forced to say
some things that they didn't want to say
and that could be part of it.
Yeah, absolutely. You know,
they could have done it,
but there's a lot of weirdness
with the moon landing. It's, it's,
if you wanted to have like a conspiracy
that to wrap your head around,
it's exciting. It's one of the best
ones who benefit, who benefits from it?
The United States government did because
it showed military superiority over the
Russians and we were able to
do that. It also, you know,
it was the Nixon administration people
would just flat out full of Shit.
Well I mean they were just lying
to people left and right back then.
The government though. Yeah, but even
more so than cause it was unchecked.
There was no media,
there's nothing that would expose
them for this and this stuff.
They would air it on TV once in 1969 you
never see it again unless you watched
it on film.
There was no youtube.
We can go back and watch the
astronauts on trampolines video.
That's my favorite one.
You watch that and you'll,
what in the fuck is happening there?
These guys are bouncing up in the
air like how are they doing that?
Like they never did watch Apollo 11 when
they were moving around on the surface
of the moon.
It just like they're moving in slow
motion and then you go to whatever it was
like Apollo 14 or 15 when they
were doing the trampoline thing.
They fucking flying through the air.
Have you seen it?
I've not. I know I had never
gotten to the moon thing.
The flatter watching is ridiculous.
This
and like their feet are hidden.
Look at this,
watch these guys bounce up in the air.
It's like they're on some sort of wireless
being yanked up into the air. Oh yeah.
Like what the fuck are they doing?
And they're playing like falling
down and it's very weird.
But it could have been that they were
really on the moon and these guys were
fucking cowboys and Yahoos and
they wanted to bounce around.
Oh, you're a pussy. You're
posting those videos.
Posted those videos back in the day.
Yeah.
I had a debate on Penn
Jillette's radio show with uh,
a guy who was an astronomer and he
wasn't willing to admit a lot of stuff.
That was a fact, like the fact
that Wernher von Braun was a Nazi,
the flag looks I was still there.
Well the flag out of wire,
first of all on the top of it that
stiffened it up to make it, but there was,
there's videos of the flag
moving in a nonexistent breeze,
which is weird too.
And yes,
they try to make some logical explanations
for why the flag could be moving in a
vacuum and some of it makes sense,
but some of it doesn't like the,
the wires. One is weird. If
you watched them fall down,
like go to that one right there,
Jamie. You like if you watch,
like sometimes they're falling down and
when they're falling down it looks like
they get yanked back up. But I think
it might not have been real footage.
What they might've done is use some test
footage like right there at Jamie right
there.
Let it go.
Like homeboy falls down and then
it looks like he is yanked back up.
Look at this.
Oh, he did not that him
standing up. Yeah. What is this?
That's not even standing up. You
can't stand up like that. Right,
but you're on the moon. You realize
you're on one six earth's gravity,
but there was no, there was
nothing to make him go like
this. Right. You can't get
up put.
Exactly.
Now we go back to MMA because that's what
these freaking folkstyle wrestling is.
The next generation of MMA,
you turn to your base to get up.
You can't look at it.
There's nothing on the ground.
How's he going to get the momentum of
the yanked up? He would have super abs.
He would have to be like a break dancer
because, okay, maybe a break dancer,
maybe a break dancer, but you can't get
up without putting a base down. Right.
Yeah. That was really weird. I never,
I never saw hard watch it again.
Watch him get yanked up. Yeah. He's
got no base pieces played in reverse.
Almost does it almost does that.
He couldn't stand up like that.
But the thing falls down right
afterwards so it wasn't reversed.
I think it's entirely possible that
some of the footage was bullshit,
but it doesn't mean that
they didn't go to the moon.
It means it overzealous people in. He only
has one sweat on the ground there too.
Right? Yeah. Well that's
true. Look at this watch.
So he stood up like that's ridiculous. You
can't do it. What is right? Floods down.
His left, what's up and he just goes
straight up the air. That's fake.
But I've never been in one six earth's
gravity and neither of you fake dude
that that says we never went to the moon.
I saw that video is fake.
Not to put the video is real.
That's from television.
The video that guy standing up
like that he got helps on that.
Can't stand up like that very well.
He could have been on wires.
It could have been that they were using
that to simulate what it would be like.
Cause they definitely
filmed a lot of simulations.
They get a lot of that because they
wanted to prepare the astronauts.
It's entirely possible that some of those
simulations gotten passed off as being
an actual video of them on the moon.
Sure. Yeah, fair enough. Or the fake,
the whole fucking thing. I wasn't there,
so I'm pretty used to it as a privilege.
I think folkstyle wrestling is the next,
that's the next genesis of MMA, right?
We go, what's next? Like that guy
standing up. People don't realize it.
If you watched the Lima Roy Fight,
it was,
it was incredibly frustrating
to watch for me, uh,
because Lima was literally just laying
on his back and guard and guard is almost
nonexistent effective in MMA now. Unless
you're Brian or Tayga. Okay. There's,
there's a few guys, tiny amount, but I
think those, but those guys are like, you,
like your wrestling is so
highly effective and MMA.
Some people could say you can't get
by just with Breslin. Well, well, hey,
I don't just wrestle.
I'm a black belt.
In Jujitsu you use on a lot of
wrestling. Yeah, primarily. Yeah.
I mean it's not that
Brian Ortega can box too.
You can do a lot of other things to
strike. I mean, he's a good solid striker,
but his guard is so dangerous.
It's just another level of dangerous
as opposed to most MMA fighters,
including Lima. Yeah. And so,
uh, you know, people actually
going back to their base,
right? Which has been, it's been
a no, no, forever. And it may,
you don't go back to your base
because you expose your back. Right.
But then again,
you know,
what percentage of guys who are sitting
in guard actually get submissions from
the guard? No, the number's
really small. Really? Well.
So you're going to have to out now.
Okay. Like this. So it's so fresh. And
so in the, in the, in the Lima fight,
Roy wins the first two rounds. It's
competitive, but he wins pretty clearly.
But the leg kicks her state.
I had never been kicked as
hard by anyone's Douglas Lema.
He kicked me one time in the
leg. I freaking it and walk
right for a week. Really?
Oh my God. He kicks so hard. He
kicks so hard, so hard. And so, um,
third round there's this accumulation
of leg kicks and all sudden Roy's leg is
really EFT. Up from getting
kicked a handful of times. Right.
And he's doing that low calf.
Yes. Chicken, I'm kind of
all over. But the EEC Roy,
Roy start are tending to do this one
and you know, instead of checking it,
so Lima starts taking
control of the fight. The,
I think he wins the third
round in my opinion.
Fourth Round in the beginning he like
kicks him once and Roy falls down and he
hops in a mountain, starts beating
him up. You're like, holy crap,
this fight might be over. And then so
Roy recovers, but then the fifth round,
Roy goes out and shoots like a single
leg, double leg. Like immediate.
We're talking first 10 seconds.
Right.
And going into that writing to take shit.
He might get finished this round.
I mean he, he can barely
walk, look at his leg. Right.
And so they make us take it
down 10 seconds into the round.
He literally stayed in guard for four
minutes, 50 seconds. And you're like,
at some point is he going to
try to get up? Cause he has to,
if he gets up in the lands
weren't too more kicks it out,
getting taken down the fights
likely over. Wow. You know,
but he refuses to turn to his
base because this is anti Jujitsu.
You shouldn't turn to your base in
Jujitsu cause you're getting choked. Yeah.
Fuck it Joe. At that point you're losing.
Right. What else are you going to do?
Well,
he never made to sweep him.
He never did try to submit them on the
fact butterfly sweeping a couple of times.
But so at this point, I mean
even if I thought it was
two, two rounds, two rounds,
right, right. He was in the fifth round.
He's got to try to get up at some point.
So that was the did it for Rory.
So he won.
He won 49 46 on two
scorecards in 48 47 on one.
So what it was three to one.
So then even more, right.
Even more reason to get up at right. If
you're losing by that much. Um, but yeah,
Lima refused to get up. So at
that point I'm think, well, hey,
maybe Lima thinks he won or something.
I Dunno.
But yeah,
so a lot did you do to,
people are struggling with this fact that
in modern day MMA you're going to have
to try to get up because God is no
longer that affective and you just get
punched in the face over and over
and over again. And that's terrible.
What are your feelings on going to half
guard and like going for an underwriter?
Same side. And yeah, try it, but it's
not, you know, again, like as me as a,
as a top guy, I would rather be
in half guard than full guard.
I'm going to land a lot of damage
from half guard. And then you're also,
if you're in half guard,
you're me trying to work in your ESL tired
and you're very unlikely to sweep me.
Right. So I think half guard is
better than full guard. But I think,
I think eventually where people are going
to have to get to is they're going to
have to actually get up.
You're gonna have to get up and putting
your feet on someone's hips and kicking
them is no longer a great solution.
It works every once in a while,
but it's not like you can do that
every single time. It just does.
It's pretty rare. Pretty rare. So he
rarely, everybody's so aware of it. Yeah.
So bottom bottom and folk style wrestling
I think is the next genesis and MMA
where people are really going to have to
have a deep understanding because once
you do get taken down or once you get a
takedown, um, and there's some, you know,
Yoel Romero was the perfect example and
he never did folkstyle wrestling and
American, right. He's a very,
very elite freestyle wrestler,
but he gets these takedowns and you can
only stay on top for like 15 seconds.
Right.
It's like you did all that work to get
the guy on the ground and they use let
them back up. Like what was the point?
Right. What was the point of it?
Well,
he's,
he smashes some guys in the ground like
Machida when he got him down on the
ground and some of them,
yeah, put them away. He's um,
he's a freak athlete too.
It's hard to say, Hey,
do what he does because it's like
no one's built like that guy.
That guy's the weird, he has the weirdest
body I've ever seen. Really? Why?
Because he looks like he's 230 pounds
and he weighs one 85 when he weighs in.
It's like how the fuck is that one
85 I always look at him, I'm like,
I don't even understand it.
Like where's the weight
going?
And you would think he's,
well those guys did some PD is by looking
at them but then when you look at him
like he won a world title
in 98 99 somewhere in there.
He looks the same. It was the same at
age 18 or 19 that's four test out yet.
What's it crazy? You know, it's
incredible because then you think like,
well if he is on pds it had to be prior
to age 18 cause he looks the same.
Well, what are your thoughts on like
Karolin cause you know the carets yeah,
but they used to call him to experiment.
Yeah. And his parents are tiny. You know,
his parents are like five, five, five,
seven and then he's six foot whatever
the fuck he is a guru of a man. Yeah.
And I always wondered like
one day in the future,
whether it's five years from
now or 30 years from now,
they're going to be
genetically manipulated people.
You're right, he watched
ICARUS. Yeah, sure.
Yeah. And that was fascinating.
And that pretty much just,
I mean cemented the Russian,
that anti-doping program or
they run every single person,
state sponsored doping program
where everybody forever.
Yeah. For everybody. Yeah.
It's crazy. And it's like you had the
hint that they were likely cheating,
you know, but then as someone
who competed against them, man,
that's a tough pill to swallow because
they wouldn't make you feel, I mean,
now it's like, well shit, I guess I
should it be one way or the other.
But to know that you are a leg down and
like going into MMA now I it MMA I do,
everyone was cheating for sure.
Right.
So I'm going to fight them whether they're
cheating or not. I like to pride days.
It was essentially sanction that was
sanctioned. Like they would tell him like,
hey, you know, when this contract
that says you can do steroids. Right.
And how does one IFC handle
that? Uh, so they don't,
they don't do drug testing yet?
Well, yeah, I mean I should be fine.
I've been pushing them to do so, uh,
you know, in my time there and their,
their thing is that, um,
a lot of these countries,
it's not prevalent in Indonesia
or Manila or wherever.
And so I'll just skip to find out,
just get the fuck out of here with that.
That's my,
that's not my style.
That's what he's saying that it's almost
Joe Rogan saying that. Get the fuck out.
So there, but there, I know you've saw,
you've, you've talked a couple times,
I've heard you about their way and program
and one of which I think is fantastic
and I think every, every MMA organization
should do it at the high level ones.
Could you explain it? Yeah.
So it's really simple.
You do hydration and you do
wait, oh ski on scale, same time.
So you can't cut water out. Right, right.
So to piss hydrated, get on the scale.
Literally moments later, like you
go in the bathroom, you pissed,
they test the specific gravity
you go get on the scale. Right?
So essentially everyone
moved up one way class.
Every one of their champions
bumped up a weight class.
So like over there I fight
one of the five. But you know,
it's essentially wealth or they even call
it welter weight because it's the same
thing because I can't cut any waterway.
They adjusted it. So they just,
they moved every day.
So I was the welterweight champion and is
still the way to welterweight champion.
They just move. The weight
class is different. Um,
so there's the day of the fight. The day
before the fight. Cheers for the fight.
If you make the two days before the fight,
if you make both the
weight and the hydration,
you do not have to wait test or
hydration test on the last day, you're,
you're clear. So if you make it both
those days, cause you're not going to be,
there's not going to fluctuate
and for 24 hours and listen,
if you can figure out how to cheat that,
I can't figure out how someone
could possibly cheat that test.
Because when the first incident I said,
well how is someone going to cheat
on this? Or how could someone cheat?
You know what it's like they look
at, they watch a Piss, you know,
you can't have like a wizard or on
or anything. Right. Uh, so I don't,
I don't know how you achieve. I don't
think you can. I don't think you can.
I don't think you can.
So yeah.
So it's fantastic because like fight
week then instead of making this,
and so what I would fight one 70 I
would be one 83 to one 85 to start my
waterway cut out.
Cut The waterway to one 70 or one 71,
depending on title or non title,
and then I would hydrate back up.
So now I don't have to do that.
That dehydration process,
I'm literally the exact same size
I was prior. And a, you know,
media obligations during week
are obviously a lot easier
because I'm not worried
about cutting my weight or I'm not
feeling miserable or whatever. Um,
and it's a lot safer.
And then so if someone misses,
so mrs obviously they're fine.
The same as in America.
If you miss what you're fine. If
you miss hydration, uh, so say Joe,
you're wanting any five and you weighed
in when a five, but you're dehydrated,
you didn't really make it right.
You have to get hydrated and make weight.
So if you miss, wait, if you miss it, so
it's the last day you haven't made it.
You have to keep drinking
until you piss hydrated.
And then whatever you way
there is what you weigh.
So what's the parameters when it comes
to hydration or not hardware? It's the,
it's the same skill that you use for it.
Uh,
in America at the beginning of the
college wrestling season or high school,
you have to do specific or every test,
I believe I might mess up a zero,
but I think it's 1.0 to five
is this specific area which
I know is the same they
use for hydrated,
not hydrated in wrestling in America to
anything under that you're dehydrated.
No, you're good. So you want to be
bullet. So 1.0, zero, zero, zero is water.
So you want to be close to that, right?
And so there is like you do have to just,
you have to drink some water, right?
If you drink a whole bunch of water,
you piss it out perfectly hydrated.
But if you know,
there have been a couple of times
like so in the early days they did,
they did tests.
This is the first two days we're actually
just testing to see where you were at.
The third day was the one that
counted. You know, it's like if you,
if you ate a bunch of
like meat or something,
you might show up as dehydrated even
though that's what you walk around.
And every single day, so you'd have
to make sure you drink a lot of water.
So it's coming out nice and clear.
That's an interesting way of doing it.
And I think that's a great idea because
I think that is one of the biggest
problems in MMA. The Uriah hall and
Vitor Belfort got canceled last week.
Uriah hall was like literally having
seizures on his way to the way and crazy.
Right. It's fucking insane. It does.
And I think it's one of the worst parts
of MMA because I think MMA shouldn't be
about who's slickest in being
able to deceive the weight system.
I mean it should be your skill versus
your opponent's skill. You both the same.
Well,
the whole,
the whole point of it is the whole point
of the way it's to fight someone our
same size. Yes. That's the
whole point of it. Yes.
And so why people would fight back
against those system that one fc is using
this beyond me because listen,
the most miserable part of my weight cut.
I'm fine dieting and that's all good.
Right?
But when you got to cut that last
12 1314 pounds of water weight out,
it's miserable. Everybody
knows is miserable. Right.
And it affects your performance
the next day. Yeah. I mean, so my,
my thought process was it affects
them more than it affects me.
Maybe that's just me being positive
about it. Right. That was, why is that?
Because if you were wrestling pussy and
I'm not right. Or maybe it's just me,
my me psyching myself up.
So my thought process on everything is
anything that goes wrong will affect my
opponent more than it will affect me.
Oh, that's a good way. I am more stable.
I can deal with shit that goes wrong.
Most people affects them.
And so maybe that's just
me telling myself that,
but that makes me feel good about it.
Well,
people feel that way about awakening,
the lightweight cutting because they
think that the other is not gonna be able
to handle it as well.
Make them go through some adversity
and then the next day he's gonna be
troubled. Sure. Exactly. So, but I
think if you take that process away,
I think it makes media obligations a lot
easier. It makes people a lot healthier.
And yeah, I mean, how many fights have
you, just from a business standpoint,
how many fights have we had canceled
this year because of the weight thing?
I mean,
quite a few.
Did it change your performance?
How physically, how do,
how would you feel the neck?
I, I think I felt, you
know, honestly for me,
I know they said those studies that
you don't really fully hydrate. I've,
I believe it was 36 to 48 hours after man.
I've always felt fine.
And so I, so when I graduated college, um,
the way class in the United States for,
for the Olympics stuff was one 63 I would
weigh roughly one 75 on a day to day
basis and then water cut down to one 63.
Um,
and then when I was fighting at one 70,
I would say between one eight three,
one one eight, five and water cut down to
one 70. So my water weight cut was very,
very similar. Every single time. You know,
I was disciplined in that manner. I want,
I didn't want to be fluctuating.
And so my goal is actually to get down
to my target weight six weeks prior to
competition, right? So I'm walking around
one, eight, three, two, one and e five,
six weeks prior. So I'm the same
exact person every single day.
Whereas I think the part that
a lot of these people f up,
and it's because they're
not disciplined enough,
is they try to descend while they're
training, right? So, you know,
maybe I get up to one 95,
which is, that's a small bump.
Some of these guys are really
undisciplined. They get way,
way, way, way overweight,
right? And so during that last six
weeks, or even the last couple weeks,
they're trying to bring that body
weight down, right? And so in my mind,
there's two ways to lose weight. You can
dye it and lose body weight, right? Fat,
mass, whatever. Um,
and then there's the waterway where we're
sweating and we're taking that out of
us, right? There's the two ways. And so
I think a lot of guys, and I, you know,
I don't know if you've ever
cut weight show, but I know.
So for me it was in college in the summers
I'd get really fat and then I'd bring
my weight down in the fall.
And you feel it when you're not,
when you're losing more
calories than you're taking in.
It's like this weird feeling in your
body and you feel like shit all the time.
And so I think a lot of fighters are
doing that really close to when they're
fighting.
And so now the waterway cut makes you
feel terrible and now they're cutting
everything out. Calorically also and
said that's like a double whammy.
That's what I think about it.
There's another thing that benefits
wrestlers and the wrestlers seem to take
pride in being able to push
through discomfort. Yes.
And the more miserable you are,
the more you just fucking bite down
your mouthpiece and deal with it. Well,
cause you, you get used to
doing that all through camps,
all through college and high school.
You're always dehydrated.
You're always losing weight.
Well,
I mean the cod dressing that is not that
the way cuttings not that bad anymore.
So they had the system and people are
starting to change a 97 I think couple
died and a change it. But
you know what? The name
institute the same thing as one of,
see that's sort of a,
so it's once you do it in the
beginning and find your minimum weight,
but I think more than anything what
people are, it's, it's a one our way in.
So you, so if you're dual me does at
one o'clock everybody weighs in at noon,
right? So what people have found out,
you can't cut, you can't cut weight.
We wrestle like shit.
So
problem with fighting doing that though
is brain injuries. So that's, I think once
you the best. But in college wrestling,
you're talking about the discomfort
thing. Part of that is that, you know,
when you go to a college wrestling
program, again, it's very structured.
You can't skip, right? You have to be
there every single day. Right on time.
And then it's like you have
40 boy, you know, black belt,
right digit two black belts.
Well,
and not even just black
belts like worldclass 19 to
23 in their physical prime
ready to fight each
other every single day.
And so you get used to this grind
dealing with people, battling people,
discomfort every single day. Um, you know,
and a lot of is also dealing
with injuries like you know,
and chill son and talks about it a lot
that hey and I was talking to my casual
is less.
Listen,
the national tournament for the NCA is
March 15th through 17th and you cannot
guarantee me you're going to be
totally healthy on that date.
You cannot guarantee meet your
and be, uh, not sick on that date.
You're going to have to compete March
15th through March 17th no matter what if
you want to enrolled, you
know, a national title.
And so wrestlers get used to this grind
where you just don't see that in other
sports.
Yeah.
I think that that aspect of wrestling is
one of the biggest tools that they take
into the octagon. The mental toughness and
that, that ability to, I mean the grind,
it's again, it's, it's a,
it's a badge of in wrestling to
be able to handle the grind. Yeah.
It's not really in kickboxing
or in Moitai or any others.
Well then not really forced to, I
mean how many, how many kickboxing or,
or Jujitsu schools you name where there's
literally 40 black belt. I mean it's,
it's been borne out through
high school wrestling.
You go to all these national
tournaments and stay terms,
you find out who the best are,
the best of the best,
get recruited and they go
to these institutions to
train with the other best of
the best of the best, you know. And then,
and then addition to that, the other,
the post-collegiate guys who are trying
to make the world teams and Olympic
teams,
they're sticking around training.
So you have this like melting pot
of freaking really great wrestlers.
They're trained with each other every
single day for five to plus five years.
If you're going to world
championships, right? Yeah,
yeah.
There also seems to be like a much more
systematic approach to training people
and a lot more drilling, you know, and
a lot of Jujitsu schools like gosh,
should the arm bar from the guard here.
We hooked the arm. Okay. I go on to here,
my legs, I make my leg, I lift up. Okay.
You practice, everybody get together.
It drives me insane.
It drives a few times.
Like I'll go to Jujitsu classes
sometimes and the literally go over to
techniques.
You drill it twice and then the last
rest of the class is just people rolling.
Five minutes. Yeah, five, five minute
goes. Maybe it drives me insane Joe,
because I come from this
wrestling background and
then I also like sports psych
in this study of high performance
is like, that's what I love. I love,
I love studying people who are the best
in their field at whatever they do.
And we know without a shadow of a doubt,
just saying go for five minutes is not
the most effective way to train someone
does not happen. So in wrestling there's
a whole bunch of different, you could do,
some days you might do matches,
some days you might do a 30 minute ago,
some days you might do a
group of three women, it goes,
some days you might do situations.
I started on the single leg,
I started a high crotch, I
sent a friend Doc. Right?
And so there's all these different
scenarios that we might try mean if I'm
coaching my academy right
and we're working on it, we,
we drove front headlocks or
we called Mantis position,
we've grab both armpits and bounce and
go for Joel on that. We don't just say,
okay now go five minute
goes cause how many,
how many tries are they going
to get it going in the math,
this position there are the front
headlock, maybe one, maybe two.
But essentially most people if
you say go for five minutes, they,
they are not disciplined enough
to make themselves do new skills.
They revert to whatever they do best and
then he's doing over and over and over
and over again. Right. And so if I want
a kid to be good at a for a headlock,
which if you're going to wrestle at a high
level, you need a good for a headlock,
period, factual, you have to have it.
I'm going to put him in there
50 times in that practice.
He's going to get it over and over and
over and over and maybe the next day it's
single likes and then maybe next
day it's double legs, right?
And then maybe Sundays you say, Hey, go
for 10 minutes, go wrestle. Right. Right.
Cause you want to change
it up on a little bit,
but saying go for five minutes every
single day is very much not the most
effective way to do it.
And it's so insanely frustrating
for me to have that happen.
And almost every Jujitsu
school on the planet,
Eddie Bravo is talked about
this a lot. And one of the
things that he says, uh, um,
Jujitsu, so fun role that people just
want to get to the rowing part real quick.
I don't care what they want. It could
be wrong. Like I freaking Care Gel.
I want them and my kids tell me all kinds
of stuff. I said I'm running practice.
I went to the Olympics,
I want to hunch trophies.
You're at my school cause you want to
learn how to be the best dominant help.
You beat the best. Yeah. Yeah.
I don't care what you like.
I don't care what you like. Some
days, every once in a while,
hey you guys don't play game wireless
play game right every once in a while just
to keep it fun. Just to keep
it fun. Right? Hey you want
to do this? Let's do that.
Every once in a while I'll indulge you.
But most of the time you're
here and so you know, we
don't, for our, for our young,
we don't really push our young
kids too hard, but like especially,
well I'll tell about high school guys.
You're telling me you want
to be a state champion.
You're telling me you
want to go to college,
you're telling me all of
these things you wanted to,
I know what it takes to get there.
I've been there myself,
I've seen many other people achieve
those things. And so, you know,
and there's a lot of,
you know,
it's really funny cause people choose and
this even go Emma May, we can get life.
People choose what they value. Right?
And I'll just give you a simple example.
I get this, I got this one kid who's
probably listening to the show right now,
cause I know he loves you. Uh,
what's his name? Oh I can't,
well I can't give one of my kids a
shout out and not all of them. So,
but he's probably kind of
who you are. He's got to know
who I'm talking about. He,
he goes freaking hard. Just
boom, grind, grind, grind.
Just I couldn't, I couldn't ask
for a kid to work harder, Joe.
But when I started teaching technique,
he tunes me out and then we go to the
national tournament and he places but he
gets, he gets scored on a
whole bunch by the technique.
We were just drilling and then I say,
hey bud,
you just tuned me out
the last three weeks.
We were just drilling that thing and
you just got your ass kicked by it.
And so I love the fact
that you want to go hard,
but you need to also value
the technique, right? Yeah.
And then there's some people who value
the technique too much and they all do.
I do this technique and then
when it comes to going hard,
they don't go hard enough. Right.
Because in wrestling or in any,
in any venture you want to take in life,
there's not just one way to be successful.
You need a bunch of different attributes
to be successful and so if you
overvalue one or another and
you devalue other things,
you're not going to be as successful as
you could. You might still be successful,
but you're not going to reach the pinnacle
because you're not putting yourself
into the right situation.
It's funny because in a lot of ways
it's like what you were talking about
earlier,
the two sides of the coin of a fighter
being a wild person who doesn't care,
the cowboy and then the other
guy who's like super systematic,
everything's controlled.
Yeah.
You almost have to have everything and
the fighters that have those really
strong attributes just have to be aware
that those attributes are strengthened
even further by technique.
Yeah. 100%. And, and, and again,
it's both sides of the coin in me.
Another one would be, uh, you know,
something I called beginner's
mind and then know it all right.
And when you come into,
when you come into practice,
you need to have a beginner's mind.
I mean,
I got to work out with three or four
time world champion Olympic Champ Jorn
Pearl's last week.
And he was asking me questions.
It's like this guy really cared about
learning from every possible source and
he's already, he's already at the
pinnacle and still trying to learn.
Interesting thing to
Dominick. Cruz said, uh,
during the broadcast about steep
immuno chick that Steve Bay,
when he went to alliance and
the man was asking everybody,
you have to. Yeah. But
then when you go into
a competition, you can't have the same
mindset and thinking, I don't know,
I need to ask. Right.
And so like kids who,
kids who have just the beginner's mind,
they'll,
they're great in practice but then
they go into a mash and I coach,
watch I do here, what should I
do? What should you do? It's like,
well just go wrestle, wrestle, you know.
But then kids are coming to
practice like I know it. All right,
well that's a very unhealthy mindset
also cause you when it's great,
when you compete, it's great
when you compete. So you got it.
You've got to balance both those things,
right? Like you can't have just one.
Cause if you're, I know it all. I'm a
bad ass. That's great for competition.
But you come into practice,
you're going to stop.
You're learning right now
when you're coaching kids,
how much time, if any, do
you spend on mindset? Um,
and so every, I added my Facebook
every Monday, do this mental Monday,
and then I usually repeat repeated or
something fairly similar to the kids at
practice. But I also think
it's a lot, you know,
I think competition is
where you get your really,
really good teachable moments because
that's when kids care the most.
And so like the kid I was talking about
when he loses it because he didn't want
to listen to me, I can say, well, look
at, look at this. This is a great example.
You know, I, I did this, I do private
lessons with this fourth and fifth grader.
They're brothers and, uh, and like five
weeks in a row you're doing this wrong.
You're doing this wrong. You're doing
this wrong. You're doing this wrong.
They don't want to listen.
Right? Right. Then they do it.
They have a match last week they do it
wrong and it didn't cost him the match,
but it almost cost them the match.
And,
and now I can say every single time I see
you're doing this wrong. Or I can say,
remember that time in that match when
you got put it in your back because you
did it wrong and you refuse to
listen to me. So I think that, uh,
matches create great teachable
moments. You know, like, Hey,
you remember when you wilted under the
pressure because you weren't tough enough?
Well, you need to practice a little
harder. So you get used to that pressure.
Remember when the referee made a bad call
and you flipped out because he made a
bad call and they didn't think about,
well,
I still have to wrestle the rest of his
match, right? So there could be all these,
there's all these teachable moments
within competition where you can say point
to something very clearly and say,
well,
look at this and see how this affected
you and see how you would have been more
successful.
So I think from mental aspect that
comes a lot more on one on one basis.
And sometimes I'll use it in front of
the whole team. I don't, I don't like,
like really picking on people, uh,
every once in a while I will. Um,
but so I think the,
I think there's competition provides a
lot of teachable moments for athletes to
see, well, am I stronger here?
What do I need to work on?
Because we, again, we can't,
you can't say one mental aspect
makes the guy successful.
It's this conglomeration of many,
many,
many mental aspects that'll
make you highly successful.
Now when you're coaching,
whether it's coaching wrestlers or MMA,
final coach, movie theaters anymore. None.
Zero. I how, okay.
I help a couple buddies but I don't
consider it and really just help us.
Let's say, just say, when you're
coaching restaurants, do you,
do you concentrate it all on strength
and conditioning or is it from the
wrestling that you get most
of your strength conditioning?
So we only got them,
you know, an hour and a half,
three or four times a week.
And so we don't do a lot of strength
conditioning. I know I read,
especially with the older guys, I
recommend they do some on their own. Um,
you know,
for a college program,
for High School program where we're
getting them Monday through Saturday,
maybe twice a day possibly. Obviously
we're in to do that, but you know,
we're an academy, uh, you
know, we're kind of on our own.
We get them three or four times a week,
so it just doesn't Trump what we
need to do in that short time window.
How do you balance it out though?
Like,
how do you know how much strength and
conditioning to do versus how much
technique and skill work?
I mean at the college level are we
talking about are because we do not,
we do know strength conditioning and I
recommend kids do on their own and you
know, and if I had 12 hours a week with
them, I would do that. But we, you know,
we don't, we don't have that ability
to, um, I think, I think it's important.
I think it's really important.
I don't think it tries.
I don't think it trumps
especially knowledge.
And then if kids wrestle really hard
against each other and kill HUD that one
saying like wrestling is the
best strength conditioning.
I can't remember he said something,
something,
if you wrestle really
hard against each other,
you're going to develop those things.
And it's like,
I think like people went when I grabbed
people are squeezed people, they're like,
oh my God,
I've never felt anything like it.
And I think that comes from that doesn't
come. If you put me in a weight room,
I can do nothing abnormal. I am not
abnormally strong in any exercise.
I'm actually like on a
college division one costume,
I'm significantly less strong
than most people. Right.
But then when they wrestle me
and they're like, Holy Shit,
I never felt anything like that.
And I think it's because a lot of
those things that I do are very, very,
very wrestling specific.
And I developed that strength
because when I grabbed some impacts,
like freaking grab him as hard
as I can when I squeezed them,
I squeeze him as hard as I can as an now
from doing that thousands of times I've
developed that squeezer that strength.
Um,
and so I think the strength
conditioning is important,
but I don't think it
trumps doing other stuff.
And if I had all the time in the world
and these kids didn't have to go to high
school or Middle School, I'd probably
put them through some. But you know,
we don't have that luxury.
What did you do when
you were finding an MMA?
How much did you devote to
strength to get conditioning?
Twice a week, ish and maybe three
sometimes. What kind of stuff?
So I had a personal trainer since I
moved to Milwaukee. I actually ended up,
I actually, I helped him
open up a crossfit gym. Um,
and it wouldn't be that
specifically crossfit workouts,
but kind of that type of
work. Nothing slow. We're,
I'm doing three sets of 10
and two sets, a, you know,
nothing slow like that potentially,
you know, one, one or two days.
We might do like a slower start and
then, but you know, I think fighting,
you need to be very highly active.
You know,
you need to be in really good shape and
need bill to move a lot of things really
fast.
So kind of cross it type stuff I think
is probably the right direction to go.
And now when I go back to college programs
besides like the heavyweights that in
season stuff for college programs
is mostly higher pay stuff,
which I think is, you know, very
relevant to both wrestling and fighting.
So did you do,
when you were saying like you were
doing like crossfit style workouts,
so are you doing like kettle
bells box jumps, like everything?
So when I said that, I just
meant that we, you know,
we are moving at a high pace
through a lot of stuff, you know,
and it would be like, he would tell me,
hey Diego, do some no. Do sled pushes.
Do this. Do that. Do that though.
What about like your diet and
nutrition and supplements and things?
Those have never
been, uh, that much into
nutrition. I saw it.
I said I don't. Okay. I was fat
when I was a little kid. Right.
K Too much at age 11. I said,
I don't wanna be fat anymore.
So I went from 130 pounds, 100 pounds
in Tam, you lost 30 pounds and 11.
Fifth grade, sixth grade, six one year.
100 pounds. That's a lot of weight.
That's 30% of your body. Well, yeah,
I was fat. I was fat as shit. Oh,
you eating everything and you were
wrestling into, yeah. Now you know, I was,
I was having some success because when
you're fat or there's not as many people
to compete against, right. So anyway,
so I lost 30 pounds, six grade.
So I stopped drinking soda.
I had this whole whole list of stuff.
I just cut out discipline at 11. Yeah,
I know. And that's uh, that's an,
I want to look at kids. I think. I
think the mental maturity is huge in,
in longterm success. Being
able to make, like, see,
see the future and make decisions on
what you want to do at that young age.
So I lost 30 pounds and so now I have
slowly started like reintroducing a lot of
stuff by, it's like sodas gross. I haven't
drank a soda and forever, you know what?
They're growing fast food. I cut out
fast food. I don't, I don't ever like,
they haven't eaten fast food in 20 years.
I mean, it's just disgusting, you know?
And so like I eat generally healthy.
My wife and I cook at home a lot.
We make really healthy food. Um, and so,
but I don't take any supplements. Zero, no
multivitamin, nothing, nothing, nothing.
So you get all your nutrients from
your food. And I just figured like I,
so I called, I tried a couple of
supplements in college. I never,
I never felt anything from them. Like
I didn't feel any different, you know.
And so I'm like, Eh, I didn't
feel anything. Why am I,
why am I going to take that?
I don't need to take it. And then so
then obviously I became like this, uh,
anti p e d crusader it, you know,
by chance. And so then it's like,
well now I really can't take anything
because if I go take something and I pop
hot because these idiots
or putting something in
supplement supplement should be
there. I'm, it was like a total
asshole. So I literally, I don't,
I didn't even take protein. I met,
took nothing. Wow. Yeah. That's crazy.
So did you make sure that you ate
the proper amount of vegetables?
Green leafy vegetables, eat some
food and Latin script? I mean,
you know, like it's like healthy food.
Like, we're eating salads and of course,
you know, I'm not eating cake and ice
cream and pizza and that kind of stuff,
and we're eating healthy food at my house,
you know,
but I'm not measuring the grams of this
or ground to that or so I really think,
what am I?
And I,
this has been proven by science that
you only have a certain amount of time
every single day to have a high
amount of mental focus on stuff.
And so I think like my training is more
important than focusing on nutrition and
stuff.
And so I want to really like really
zoning in really high level focus when I'm
training and stuff. And so I think
if I worry about all this stuff,
it'll take my focus away from
that. Right, right or wrong.
That's kind of how I thought about it.
And it was a smart way to approach it.
And it never really affected me.
I mean, uh, like I said, you know,
even when I took the supplements in
college, I never really felt them at all.
So it's like, well, if I don't feel
it, why would I do it? You know,
kind of ironic though,
that you were an anti-drug crusader
and you went to the one place,
it doesn't drug test. I know, right? It
really hurt me. It hurt me. A crazy is,
you know, and it is, if you look at,
so we talked about like Singapore being
so fantastic and having a really high
GDP. A lot of the countries
over there, uh, Indonesia,
Manila, they, Manila, Philippines, um,
they don't have huge high GDPs, right? I
mean they're not super wealthy countries.
And so when we think about,
you know,
how much it costs to buy a lot of the
steroids that are readily available in
America, they're just not as available.
And so I think they do have a point.
And if you look at the athletes,
there's not a lot of athletes
that look like Yoel Romero.
Now you'll notice probably not using,
like I pointed out earlier,
while he's tested clean,
except once it was tainted supplement,
but they proved that it
was a tainted supplement.
So when you look at their athletes,
maybe except a few of the Russian ones,
they look pretty normal.
Like it's probably unlikely
that they're using from my,
for a few Russian ones, let's say
for rocks and they can't help it.
It's like part of the culture. I
can't help it. Yeah. That one Russian,
the one Russian guy that I fought in
April of 16 he was freaking enormous.
And you know,
the other thing that I think a lot of MMA
people are using some type of uh oh my
gosh, I'm blanking. What, what gives you
endurance, EPO, EPO, that type of stuff.
Because if you watch a college wrestler,
that's how tired people get in seven
minutes and then we're fighting 25 minutes
and you're not going to get tired.
Like that's not normal. Well,
people definitely tested hot for that.
And the UFC,
who's the guy that fought mighty mouse?
Yeah. There is a routine of Russia. Crazy.
Yeah. So, but I think more people are
using that. And I think if you, you know,
you don't,
I don't have any conclusive evidence,
but if you look at when you sort of
started and then how somebody is,
people fell down straight down.
Their bodies are different.
They look different,
they're competent, you know,
Johnny Hendricks would be one
that comes to mind. I mean,
what's his freaking record since
you saw it ain't very good.
I'll tell you that much. And all of a
sudden he can't make weight. And you know,
if you remember, so obviously I
watched Johnny because he was,
I couldn't stay on Johnny.
He beat me when we were 17 and
then I tried to wrestle my senior,
so we were different.
He was one 65,
I was on 74 and I want to wrestle
wrestling for the all star classic.
And I called the, the people who put it
on and said I want to wrestle him. And uh,
they turned the match down.
So that's, I've kind of like,
I wanted to get that one back and I never
got to get it back from when I was 17
so I've been falling giant pretty closely.
If you watched Johnny like a constant
fight and prior to that he gets so tired
in like two rounds. Right?
And we just felt exhausted,
exhausted and then all of sudden he's
going these five round fights and you're
like,
Whoa,
how are you going to get tired and that
exhausted in two rounds and now you can
five for five rounds. Johnny, like what's
going on here? I mean in his defense,
I don't got to improve team take down.
They,
they implemented a pretty
fantastic program over there.
I mean they spend a lot of money on it.
That was the whole thing where they were,
they were paying him then they
wanted 50% of his earnings.
I got the same offer right out of college.
You? Yeah, we were both Grad Joe Seven.
How does that work?
I felt like he was betting it's myself.
They pay you $100,000
a year for seven years.
They got 50% of your career earnings.
And I said, my thought was, well,
if I ever make it really big,
I'm going to make $1 million a fight and
I'm going to pay him back in one fight.
You know, like it's, it's a,
it would be like hedging your bet against
yourself and I don't ever bet against
myself. Yeah. But for them I get it too.
It's like they have to have some sort
of a reason to put out there and it's a
big bet whether or not you're
going to be able to be. Absolutely.
Plus if you think you suck, it's
good to take that bet. If you think,
I don't know if I'm going to make a dog,
I'm okay with making it a little bit
of money. Yeah. Then it's a good bet.
It doesn't seem like the best strategy.
It doesn't seem,
I mean it's interesting and I think,
I think there's probably somewhere
in there with, you know, I,
I know a few manage it and
it's where you go pick out,
it's pretty proven that hello
call adjusters are going
to make really damn good
fighters. That's pretty proven itself.
Going to try to find a couple every year,
spending some money on them and then
getting a percentage of their earnings.
It's probably a pretty,
I don't want to say a safe bet for the
people putting out the money, but it's,
you know, take down team, take down,
had Jake rush Holt who was an amazing
wrestler and for whatever reason he just
didn't transition great to
fighting. Right. And you know,
he was good but he wasn't great and it
was like for as good of a wrestler's he
was probably 30 it can be a little better.
Yeah. What do you think is the factor?
Like if you had to look at it,
the Mosler cause there's not
a lot of outliers like that.
Like where you don't like [inaudible].
And so when we talk about how good Jake,
right, he still made the UFC,
he still won some fights.
So it was like he wasn't a bad fighter,
but he's a three time NCAA champs.
So you expect him, Hey, he'll probably go
challenge for a UFC title. Right. So I,
you know, in his case, I don't
know what the factor was. Um,
but there's not a lot of outliers like
that where it's there are a really high
level wrestler and then they don't have
any success. MMA that's really unique.
You don't see it a lot. Yeah, it's,
it's interesting like I've looked at
it from striking from if you see like
really high level kickboxers some have
a style that would readily translate to
MMA and some are fantastic kickboxers
like maybe Peter Hertz is a good example
or a Nesto who's where I wouldn't really
think that they would translate that
well to MMA.
Whereas Mirko Cro cop who might've been
like a slight notch below them in terms
of kickboxing translates perfectly to
MMA cause he's so explosive and quail and
I would want them decent takedown defense
too. He still kept it for a while.
They developed it.
But the thing about Mirko was unbelievable
power and speed and he could just
close the distance quickly and blast.
Yeah.
And I think that is w difference between
that and a guy who's like methodical
set things up. Those guys didn't do as
well. They didn't translate as well.
They get tooken taken down to what,
what would you think
would be like, well, it's,
it's very different guns you don't want,
the other things I think benefits us
wrestlers is the fact that Jujitsu people
are stuck on doing Jujitsu,
the Jew two way, right?
Strikers are stuck on striking
when we come into MMA,
we know we can't win a match just by
wrestling. Right? So we know, we know.
I've got to add striking. I gotta I gotta
add Jujitsu and I'm open to that idea,
right? I'm open to those ideas that I
have to add those things into my arsenal.
Where'd you'd, some Jujitsu
guys are like, well,
I'm just going to submit them and
they don't, they don't develop their,
I mean there's, there, you can
literally not name me Joe, uh,
a Jujitsu guy or a striking guy.
Well,
maybe Jose Aldo who has
developed high level wrestling,
but you can name a lot of wrestlers who've
developed high levels, something else,
right? I mean, when you see the cross
over, like Jon Jones was a wrestler,
he can strike with pretty much
anyone on the planet, right.
It means steep meo chick was a wrestler.
He can pretty much track when
they don't on the planet. I mean,
so you have these wrestlers who are
becoming high level at these other skills,
but you don't have a lot of other skills
becoming a high level of wrestling.
And I, and I'm, for me,
I think it's the stubbornness of people
who come from those other backgrounds or
too stubborn to want to work a lot in
wrestling where it's wrestlers are like,
okay, teach panel strike.
Yeah. I think it's a,
it's a recognition of what's important.
Like George Saint Pierre is a
perfect example of a garden.
Started off with a killed
Christian background,
didn't wrestle in college or high school,
became a fantastic restaurant.
He's good. Yeah. And just
figured it out and realized,
realize what a critical skill
it is too. Yeah, absolutely.
So there's a handful of very small
handful. Jose Aldo would be like, eh,
he wasn't an offensive wrestler,
but who'd be like,
he was so ridiculously hard to take down.
I mean fantastic takedown defense.
And so there, there's a handful,
but there's not a lot. And then,
but then if you go to wrestlers going
opposite direction into Jujitsu or
striking,
you know,
you can name quite a few that were able
to do those things really well. You know,
it's interesting when you see a guy like
Khabib number Grumet off and you see
these fantastic fuck yeah.
And his,
his mauling wrestling.
I mean,
you see what a massive factor it is.
Fights like the Edson Barboza fight.
Yeah. That to me is one of the
perfect examples. When I say, look,
the ability to take guy down and
control them on the ground is the,
it's the bottom of the pyramid.
It's the most important foundation
because he dictates where the fight takes
place. Yeah. You might catch him when
he's coming in and trying to get you,
you might, but if he gets you, he was
like a fricking terminator though.
He was just like, I'm just
going to come get you. Yeah.
He just ate kicks for each address and
there's no hope constant chasing him
around chasing him. Right. It was. It was
insane. Yeah. No, he's fantastic. Yeah.
But no,
I would totally agree that at the bottom
of the pyramid it's like the is the
Trump card. If like if you fighting a
wrestler and you can't stop a takedown,
you're going to lose 90% of the
time. Yeah. You know, and if,
if you're the wrestler and you can
go get a take down really easily,
you're going to win 90% of the time.
The only wild card in that equation is
a guy like Brian or tig fights so well
off his back. But how many
people get submissions from
garden? How many of those?
Yeah, it's me. Even like any,
any Anthony Pettis who got
a lot of submissions regard.
A lot of that was transitions off of I
body kick, Benson Harrison, I body kick,
Ben Sanders and Benson.
Harrison hates getting body kicks.
So he dives in for a take down. It gets
arm armbar right. Or Guilt Melendez.
Getting Guillotine
choke cause he got jacked a
few times. Right. So there are,
there's a handful of those but
just strictly like I take you down,
you're in guard,
then I submit you right.
Maybe for Bri silver doom every once
in a while. Maybe Brian or Tega.
But the numbers pretty damn small.
It is very small.
It's smaller now than I think ever before
because people understand the takedown,
the guard defense.
Yeah.
Even like this guy that I,
so one of the things that frustrates you
the most more than anything else that
may is bad strategy. She was like,
drives me up the wallet, that Lima thing.
But this freaking knucklehead that fought
Michael Chandler on uh, on Saturday.
I didn't see it as names. Uh,
Gordy Gordy. Yeah. Moo Cheer.
I don't know his damn name is.
So the first round he pulls guard like
fast gets frikking hammered on for like
four minutes and then he ends up
on bottom again. The second round,
third round he gets taken
down and I dunno, 15 seconds.
Did he try to get up one time?
No,
he just laid there and I was asked
what performance in 45 seconds.
Like everyone's while to try a comer.
Everyone's while to try to triangle,
but it's like, dude, you're
getting your ass whipped.
You're down two rounds and nothing.
Try to get up, try to do something,
change your strategy.
If your strategy is not working,
you can't just stick with the same
bullshit and get your ass off for another
four minutes or 45 seconds.
I give me a break.
What do you think's going
to happen down there?
Well, I think some guys get
locked into a defensive position.
Like they realize they're
getting overwhelmed and so
they just try to survive.
You think so? Yeah. Really? Yeah.
You don't think that way because you're
a champ and champions don't think that
way.
But for some people there's a,
there's a acceptance of their, their
fate, asphalt pennys. This is just,
they're getting their ass whooped and
so they just try to stay conscious.
They try to just protect
themselves as much as they can.
Kind of like Edson Barboza but
then you know, it's an instrument.
Edson Barboza you saw once he
realized he was going to survive,
like when it was like two minutes
left and third round maybe ish site.
The first round he's like, I'm getting,
I'm getting fucked up. Just kind of,
I'm just going to survive. Right? But
then when there was a couple minutes left,
he's like, no. And he was like,
okay, I'm going to fight again.
I want to make it through this shit.
I might as well,
if I were to make it through this, I
might as well just fight back. Right.
So he started fighting back really hard
like the last two minutes f I tried.
He certainly tried,
but there was a period in the middle
where he like had resigned to just taking
an ass hole open.
Well, I think he was just,
body was just not responding.
He was getting so fucked up and you could
see the pace that Habib put on a hard
day. First round, like halfway into
the Round Barboza is like Jesus Christ.
You see the look in his eyes, got that
thousand yard stare. It's like, Whoa,
did I signed up for? Yeah,
this guy's on another level.
I mean he really is on another level.
I'm fascinated by him
fighting Tony Ferguson and
apparently they're going to do
that now.
It's sitting happened April.
I don't know if it's going to be for
the interim title or the actual title
within. They're going to strip
Connor. They're in a weird,
I caught it beats up Tony.
That's just my [inaudible] and I've
underestimated Tony before so I could be
wrong again. I just think, I
think it's again, Trump card.
I think Tony's kind of one of those guys
where he's pretty good everywhere is
pretty damn solid wrestling,
high level Jujitsu. Uh, but I
Khabib's wrestling,
I mean better than Tony's wrestling,
so it's going to end up on the ground.
And I think Tony's going to think he can
submit him because his Jujitsu is very
high level,
but I think it'll be one those things
where it could be just good enough not to
get submitted. And then he's going to land
damage and land damage, inland damage,
inland damage.
And Tony's going to get close to a
submission and close to a submission,
close to a submission,
but not quite get it.
And then all this damage is going to
just accumulate and accumulate and
accumulate. That's Kinda how I
see it going. It's fascinating.
And I also think it's
fascinating now that could be,
but has changed his training
and has a real nutritionist,
had no problem making weight.
Yeah.
So all of the factors that played into
him getting removed from the last time
they were supposed to fight, pulled out
of the car. That was kind of overblown.
He only missed weight one time.
He only missed w wait one time.
But his body shut down when he's making
me wait for the Michael Johnson fight in
a similar way. But he still did
the Michael Johnson fight. Yeah.
But it was the same thing happened
on the way and it was a rough way in.
But there's been other guys who
missed weight many times. I mean,
if we go to a Johnny Hendricks,
Johny Hendricks, Melvin
Gallard, Calvin gasoline,
and they missed it by a long way. So I
thought the cube thing kinda overplayed.
He missed weight one time. He had some
injuries which sucked for him. Um,
but it was, that was happening
for a world title fight, you know,
fighting for the interim title.
He misses for you. Yeah, I mean,
and so it one of those
where he probably just like,
it was like okay for him to make it but
be difficult and they just got just a
little bit too big.
I said,
was it for world interim
title when he was supposed to,
I don't think it was the original
time. It was Kevin Lee. Right?
That was for the world time.
Yeah. Yeah. Or interim title.
Job Title. Yeah. The whole,
that whole division is kind
of fucked up with Conner.
Not even knowing whether or not he's
fighting it. They're going to strip him,
right? Yeah, mostly I think
so. I would imagine. Unless
Connor says, fuck it, I'm in,
I think the best comeback.
Fuck it. Fuck it. Fuck it.
I want to keep me belt. I know the best
course of action strip Connor let, let,
could be even Tony fight it out and
then it Kinda of was going back.
Give him a title shot that's
going to happen. Whatever. Well,
I think what would be the most
lucrative thing is Connor versus GSD.
Joe Ought to fight GSP. Oh you
do? I want to be number one.
I don't want to fight Tyron cause we've
been your friends for 20 years. Uh,
I wanna fight GSP that
that's who I want to fight.
Do you think that they would set that up?
They would try to set up GSP versus
Tyron. Right. That would be super fun.
GSP doesn't want to fight anyone who can
hit hard because he's worried about the
brain damage. Yeah. I
don't hit that hard. Right.
Interesting way of looking at it on
a train with GSP, I've never changed.
So I've trained with almost every top
what the weight of this era except GSP.
Really. Yeah. Well GSP
and Rory, but uh, shields,
Fitch, Diaz, a couple times tire and
obviously, um, you know, go down the line.
I've trained with pretty
much everyone in this era.
What do you feel like if you do wind up
retiring, what do you feel like you'll,
you'll wind up doing? Just coach and
coach wrestling. I love doing it.
Really enjoyed a lot so I could,
I don't think I'd go back to the
collegiate level. It's obviously
always an option. It went for the four
years I coach called dress and I loved it,
you know? And then it was like, Hey, I won
the belt. Hotels making a lot of money.
I should probably try to be good at
this instead of just doing it halfway,
you know? Right. And so I
did that and then, you know,
we opened the wrestling schools
and now it's going a little on it.
I really enjoyed that a lot. And you
know, there's positives and negatives.
Like I love coaching at the highest level,
being able to talk about his
level to the college guys.
So I missed that part a little bit.
But then obviously if you go
work for a institution like that,
there's gonna be a lot of bureaucracy.
And I worry about that. I don't like that.
I love owning my own business and having
my own freedom and not having to worry
about what I tweet or what I say or
heaven with telling me what to do or where
to be or where to dress or whatever.
Like I don't like.
So I love that freedom obviously.
Then running your own business
has its own challenges also.
So I think I will coat dress
on for the rest of my life,
whether I fight once more where
they don't fight once more,
I'll probably call Jonathan for
the rest of my life. Awesome. Yeah.
Well listen man, I'm glad we finally got
a chance to do this. It was fun. Really,
really fun. And um, tell
people about your podcast. Uh,
so I have a wrestling podcast
called the t Rowe and funky show.
It's another t Rowe and funky show,
t Rowe and funky shows.
How do you spell that?
T dash row. Okay. Funky.
So tire tire.
Uh,
Tommy Rollins is two time
NCAA champ for Ohio state. Uh,
made a couple of world teams, was really
close to make an Olympic team. And, um,
you know, we were just on the phone one
day and he said, I want to do a podcast.
I'm like, Eh, I want to do a podcast
too. Let's just do one, you know?
So it's not like a job for us.
We just do it for fun. We enjoy,
we love talking about wrestling. And you
know, for me it's really nice. Like, uh,
you know, no one's on the same schedule
as me now that I can talk wrestling with.
So to be able to get on talk for an
hour a week about wrestling, it's,
it's a blast. Awesome. So
that's on iTunes and soundcloud.
People want to find you.
It's Ben Asker on Twitter or Instagram.
I like, I'm on Instagram, but I don't
really get into it. I don't know.
I don't know. I can't, I can't get an,
Instagram is just pictures. Like I get it.
There's no banter back and forth. I
trouble, I post every once in a while.
But you like Twitter of have Twitter.
Oh, that's fun. Yeah. Ben Aspirin,
ladies and gentlemen. Thanks brother. I
appreciate it. Yeah, it was fun. Yes sir.
Okay.