Doo doo,
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo,
bom,
Bom,
Bom Bom.
We're going to have are going to get
back to that.
Ladies.
Gentlemen,
the Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net and click on
the link for the flashlight and enter in
the code name Rogan,
you will get 15 percent off the number
one sex toy for men
with that sad college boy John Heffrons
in the motherfucking house.
Joe Diaz on the way.
We're rolling.
Hey everybody.
What the fuck?
What's going on?
My Pal,
my neighbor winner of last comic
standing.
The Great John Hef.
Ron is in the house.
UHM,
if you don't know,
has his own podcast now with another
hilarious guy,
John Reape,
who also is a winner of last comic
standing.
So to last comic standing champions
together on one podcast.
What do you guys call it?
Oh,
we're calling it the last podcasting,
the last podcast on.
Yeah,
we configure it.
The name like I,
I didn't want to kind of have like a
silly name.
Kevin Smith took the rubber off your,
your stuff it back on.
Yeah,
he's real particular.
It was really.
I mean I think these things are good.
The spit yields,
you know,
people like that pop and shit in their
ear.
But uh,
Kevin Smith likes to hear it raw
because,
you know,
Joe,
so I'm sorry.
So what do you call it?
The end.
What's the podcast?
Last podcast?
The last podcasting,
the last one.
Are you claiming this is it?
No one asked.
That'd be good just because it's
obviously playing on last comic
standing.
We didn't know if you want to call it
where you get a clown horn behind it.
Is the last comic standing like such a
big thing in your life that you would do
that?
It mean,
is it like,
is that like when you look back at your
accomplishments as a comic,
is that like the number one thing?
I don't think she'll personally,
but yeah,
it's one of those things you don't know
where your path would have went.
You like you.
So if I didn't do the show,
what I would just be just that headliner
who makes nothing just with a couple of
special things.
Kind of different than doing standup,
isn't it?
Because you're doing stand up and these
little short bursts for an audience and
you like trying to get them to vote for
you.
Did you find yourself like altering your
material?
What?
Because I'm long,
not long winded,
but my,
my jokes are are long so I'll stick with
the same subject.
Didn't have jokes every couple of
seconds.
Right.
So to do a four and a half,
five minute set is really hard for me.
Yeah.
And I did on my feet and I did 12,
five minute TV sets,
not repeating stuff.
So my brain doesn't click together.
Small sets like that.
So that was you that that must've been a
difficult counts.
Twelve I did five minute sets and other
other sees a whole hour of almost.
Yeah,
cause every material I got challenged
almost every episode.
So you perform then the next show and
for that don't understand why
that would be a big deal.
Here's why it would be a big deal for a
guy like John or a guy like me.
We have similar writing style so that we
we go into a bit and that bit will will
squeeze every thought out of that bit
and use it to transition to another bit
and those segways are kind of difficult
to do,
but it's very important to make sure
that the material flow seamlessly
together.
If there's a hiccup in the subjects,
then the audience can pick up on it and
it doesn't click with their brain as
much,
so it's really hard to do these little
five minute sets and break them up
because oftentimes one bit will lead
into another bit and one bid by itself
may only be like two minutes,
but it causes a 10 minute bit because
it's the catalyst for all this other
stuff that comes after it,
which you really just can't get away
with in a five minute set
like that.
It's real.
And then if you're used to not memorize
them but telling stories that way to go.
So what's with Mcdonald's?
I was in a car recently.
I hate flood and do that.
Your brain doesn't usually,
it's harder for me to say no or,
or remember perfectly a four and a half
minutes at then.
It would be for an hour and a half.
So do you think like as it's so
disjointed for me.
So do you think that that must have
helped you to,
as a comic?
Just the challenge of doing that.
Why did I.
So yeah.
So it was all those sets and then the
very literally the next day when I,
when I was performing when you a bunch
of theaters,
I felt the need to write a new hour as
fast as possible because people wouldn't
want to hear what they just heard for
nine weeks of Network television of
course.
So,
but so out of the 15 years leading up to
last comic,
I wrote what I think was a funnier our.
And I've gotten more out of that hour as
far as development deals and pitching
stuff to networks,
uh,
in probably two or three months just out
of sheer fear of I need to come up with
new material to survive or this is going
to stop.
Louis ck just had a video that I found
on the Internet.
Somebody posted on the message board
where he's talking about George Carlin
and how George Carlin inspired him that
after like 15 years he was doing the
same act leg literally for 15 years.
And then he was listening to Carla and
talk about how he does comedy,
how he does it,
and he throws the whole hour away every
year and starts with a new one.
And you know,
in the Louis thought it was so crazy.
He was like crying in the car while it
was listening to this because he was
like,
is it a moment where it's like,
I fucking hate what I'm doing.
I stand up.
I said that,
that challenge.
Look how good he is now.
And it's funny.
I think habits are definitely
contagious.
You hang out with certain people that do
certain things,
you'll do that.
I just saw a Louis in San Francisco at a
show and then I went to his midnight
show and watched him and I left in the
week after.
I just saw,
there's a couple of weeks ago onstage,
I think I did 15 minutes of new stuff
just because the ceiling was raised.
You like you can go.
I do really well.
I crush it and then you see somebody who
is working on a new hour and for my hair
from the club.
He went there Wednesday,
figured out some stuff from my Sunday.
They go in those days,
his stuff became so tight because he can
go home and he'd.
Right.
So it inspired me to go,
right.
I'm going to do that.
I'm going to.
I'm going to do the same thing and in
some restructuring everything for that
reason where you just get
board onstage.
Yeah.
Getting inspired by the comics is the
greatest fucking thing ever.
It's a humbling thing.
You know,
you see someone who's really killing it
and it's like just how like a regular
person watches stand up and they can't
really quite believe that someone can do
that.
There's a lot of people that watch stand
up and they can imagine themselves doing
it well.
That same feeling,
you get kind of get that same feeling
when you watch someone who's really
great at it.
When you want someone who's really great
at you,
like,
oh,
this mother fucker just hitting heights.
Like you don't even want to know if you
can do that.
You know what I'm saying?
Like you don't even.
You don't even want to think about it.
All you want to do is just get to work.
Yeah.
It's Kinda like the one that guy ran the
first four minute mile.
Yeah.
And then everybody else started falling.
They're like,
oh,
there's a whole nother level.
Yeah,
except you can't.
You can think about running fast.
You can't think about getting funnier.
You know what I'm saying?
You just have to work.
You just have to work at it.
But when you.
When I say you can't think about getting
funnier when you can,
that's,
that's wrong.
I mean you can be unhappy and decide to
improve,
but that you can't be thinking about it
while you're up there.
I have to be funnier.
I have to be funny.
Or You just have to be in that fucking
groove.
You know what I mean?
You can't be thinking like that's a
thing that people don't understand.
Like you can't think I'm going to try to
be funny.
You can't.
Yeah,
no,
you're right here.
Right.
And I always tell younger comics,
the,
the guys who hang out with like open
mic,
her's with notebooks at get at coffee
houses.
He kinda learned to write that way and
they kind of stay at that weight.
I tell young guys got an advice.
Yeah.
Every Friday night come here and watch
somebody who's been doing it for 20
years and see what you don't like.
See what you do like it.
Start figuring out that way.
You know what I mean?
You know?
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a tricky game,
the standup comedy,
but it,
it,
it for me in this last week,
this happened after 23 years and how do
I write a solid Louis got motivated in a
sense of,
okay,
I'm going to start challenging myself
there.
Um,
and then I decided to rework the entire
act,
like in this crazy.
No one will know the system that I have,
but yet it got me really,
really excited.
You stand up.
So this whole week when I was in Tampa,
no one will know the system that you
have.
What do you mean?
I won?
I did know.
It sounds like if you were watching,
you would never know that this went
down,
but I want to construct my whole act as
the hero's journey.
Like in every movie you see about 10
minutes into the movie,
something crazy happens to the character
that spins them off in the movie while
I'm trying to put my whole act together.
We're at 10 minutes in I,
I tell you I don't,
I don't know if I got to make a
decision,
I might want to get divorced.
And then suddenly the crowds like what?
And then it's my journey and then the
thing I got this huge master plan,
it's how I've always done my act,
but I'm really going to try to hit beats
where suddenly you're going to have a
romantic part in the middle of it to
take
no,
but listening,
you're just going to laugh.
Can a romantic.
What is this Jim Carrey movie?
It's something called like Philip
Morris.
I Love Philip Morris and it was a
Netflix film.
I was like,
wow.
I like Jim Carrey and it here in
Mcgregor.
And then I'm like laying in bed last
night after watching red state.
And I watched it and I was like
disgusted.
There was parts where Jim Carrey was
fucking guys from behind very violently
and you,
he has a shirt off,
he's got to come in me.
And I'm like,
what?
This is not a crushed ice.
Ventura is now a fucking whatever.
And so then it.
Then there's a part where it Ian
Mcgregor and he's got this horrible
bleached hair and half of it's spent in
jail where like there's just a bunch of
gay sex going on in jail and then make
it at the beginning of the movie they
say it's like this all happened like
this is a real story or something like
that and it is the most craziness.
Craziness.
Moving.
Try to censor myself.
It's the gay ass movie I've ever seen
because I don't want to hurt his gay,
but he's feelings.
I don't want hurt.
Retards feel you're not having sex with
each other.
It's pretty good.
That was a joke.
I'm just kidding.
No,
but it was best to be on a shirt.
It was really.
It was the weirdest thing.
Seeing two guys just making out that
you're like,
like with like bag for comedy on mouth.
Mouth to mouth.
Like you're making out with the jet.
I what the fuck are you doing
greg?
It was just making out with dudes.
Yes.
Tongue.
Jim Carrey was just fucking stupid.
Were Gay and it was neat to see that as
often.
You know how like when most rated r
movies,
you never like see a girl's pussy,
like they never left over and show you
their pussy,
but yet you'll see them naked.
It's like,
it's okay.
I understand.
I understand that this is going on.
If there's a guy kissing another guy,
I feel like you don't have to show me
their tongue touching.
I believe you.
That's when you reach.
You're going to the refrigerator to get
some Bagel bites.
Start Microwave and those look down for
it.
Yeah.
You want to freak me out,
get good touch and tongues that I know
our street.
That's why it's so hard when you got a
straight actor and another straight
actor and you're making them make out.
What kind of game is this?
The whole movie is based on dirty,
Raunchy,
gay sex,
brokeback mountain.
They were like,
dude,
we're going to go times to now we're
just going to have Jim Carrey and a
fucking jet.
I just fucking everywhere.
But Sex and sex.
Was it a comedy or is it a like?
Absolutely not funny.
The whole time I was sitting in there,
I'm asleep so my girlfriend wouldn't
think I was gay watching this movie.
Was it like,
what?
Is it supposed to be a funny huh?
Is it supposed to be a comedy?
Like tomatoes gave it a 71 percent.
That's pretty God damn strong.
They're all cock suckers.
That rotten tomatoes.
Damn.
I need to see this.
Actually,
we don't know everybody.
We know Roger Ebert loves man in a
woman's sex.
I need to see this
officer turned.
Con Man who made the leap to white
collar criminal after being sent to
prison.
Don't need to see it,
man.
The whole movie.
Jim doesn't say anything about crazy
buttocks in here.
The whole movie.
Jim Carey's a looked so weird.
I couldn't tell if he was wearing a wig
or if he just had the creepiest hair
ever.
Like if he was in character like because
it was kind of like forrest gump for gay
people or something like that.
Like he's like,
I've been to prison.
Decided to suck that guys Derek,
you know,
like he had like a.
It was from Texas that it took place in
Texas and it was like they all had that
little time bubble shrimp,
you know,
but it,
it,
I don't remember what I was talking
about tech.
You were talking about bud sites and Jim
Carrey and.
But Jim Carrey looked really crazy like,
like he had like this weird for La,
like headline.
I can't tell if it's really his hair's
receding or he had like a weird dumb and
dumber kind of haircut and it was creepy
on top of already a creepy movie carries
a good actor.
Yeah.
It's a lot of people that don't give
that guy credit.
He can fucking freak you out.
That,
that cable guy thing.
Remember when we played the cable guy?
That was a weird role,
man.
He,
he played that good.
He can do some shit,
man.
I'm a big Jim Carey Fan.
I know a lot of people.
You know,
there's something that people think
about him being like real big and silly
like ace Ventura,
that somehow no,
there's something wrong with that.
Like it's pandering or it's low brow or
whatever.
I just think he's funny.
I don't need to be intellectualized with
my funding.
Imagine in sucking a dick.
Watch this movie.
Even has that hair to where it was down.
Like kind of like reversing the dude.
He was sucking Dick fucking guys in
assets.
He was like,
not showing it obviously,
but it was very good that did show him
kissing.
Oh,
they shut them.
Making up tons of respite sling between
the guys levels.
I'd rather see a dude fucking the guy in
the ass and kissing,
kissing,
kissing is disgusting regardless.
Well,
I know a dude with a heart on it was
very confused as it is.
You know,
dealing with a heart on is basically
just a sperm machine.
You're just managing this fucking
unstoppable sperm machine that's on
autopilot.
That's what a dude with a heart on this.
So if you just woke up and you find your
deck and a guy's ass like God dammit,
now what to do.
There's a big difference by kissing.
That's like a thing.
Do I go in first?
So I kept my head.
You're really thinking about guys,
fuck guys in prison,
but total kiss too much.
You know,
probably not.
They made it sound like they made it
sound like the whole thing with the
prison system was like,
you could either get,
you know,
soap or you can get a sand to clean
yourself and that shower,
you get soap if you suck my Dick,
you know,
things like that.
Like they made it seem like the prison
system was all completely about sucking
Dick.
Like if you want your mail,
you have to suck my dick and
I,
I just,
I want to know if this is one a true
story.
I don't think it is or not,
but,
but to the guy,
if I,
I want to know
what the Jews movies I wouldn't to.
I was too tired,
was like 6:00 AM.
I was too tired to like Google the guy's
real name to see if it was a real story
or not.
I bet it is.
I get the fuck happened at the Abbey and
just look it up.
Look it up.
See if it's a real story.
That's what I want to know.
What the real story of just a guy
hooking up with a real guy about scam
artists that just love to suck.
Dick screenwriters,
Glen Feet,
cholera and John.
Sorry guys,
if I said your name wrong,
Benson,
well these guys are.
PSYCHOS was bad.
Guy Goes,
oh,
I need to see this man.
Hey,
they're probably just sitting around
like,
let's see.
Jim Carrey sucks Dick.
Dude,
I need to see this.
I did not know that this was such a
fabulous movie.
Never.
Yeah.
Would you imagine you're sitting going,
oh,
I'm going to write a script.
You know what?
Let's sit down and your first thought is
Guy Sucking Dick.
Oh,
it was.
It was be like,
how could I do an action movie where
guys,
why not?
Dude,
listen,
if you only make a really good movie
about Guy Sucking Dick,
good for you,
man.
Maybe this movie,
this is Brian disagrees on a lot of
movies.
Maybe this is an amazing human because
look is 71 percent on rotten tomatoes
and tomato 71.
I think the biggest thing was saying
good,
Jim Carrey doing mcgregor tears like
big.
Here's the big tests.
Ready,
here's the big tests.
Okay.
I say I trust rotten tomatoes.
I say rotten tomatoes generally
represents how I feel about movies.
Pretty accurate.
So let's type in
boondock saints
and this will discuss this.
This will be it for me.
Type type in red state.
Oh,
I wrote boondock saints.
John,
have you seen this Jim Carrey movie?
No,
I have not.
Will you watch it?
Not,
not after that.
I just know I'd rather see a 17 percent.
Okay.
Yeah.
Look rotten tomatoes is on point.
Rotten tomatoes is on point.
All right.
Type in [inaudible] 71 then that moves
in red states.
Don't do it yet,
but you'd love to read it.
And that was like the best movie ever.
I haven't seen.
I don't know what it is.
Forty percent.
That's.
No,
I really liked that movie.
I thought it was way better than that,
but I've talked to people in line.
I didn't like it,
man.
Rotten tomatoes is not accurate.
One hundred percent.
I think it is and I think Phillip Morris
might be the best but fucking movie in
the history of the movies.
I think I got to go with that.
I wish rotten tomatoes was just tuned
into what you like,
you know,
you could say,
what's giving your favorite movies?
Maybe there's a program like that you
can say,
give me your favorite movies.
What?
What music do you listen to?
You married,
single,
divorced.
How old you are you healthy?
Do you exercise?
Throw that shown that you're sleepy
every time you want to watch a movie,
tell me what's good out there,
man.
Do you go to cheesecake before the movie
and get the full?
Do you do that problem is that you'll
never expand.
You'll never become someone other than
who you are.
They'll just keep giving you the same
influences.
Their genius.
They kind of do that with music.
They don't dope and a lot of times it's
pretty.
You Go,
yeah,
I would have put together this playlist.
I just got appletv Oh yeah,
I've had it.
I've had it for years.
Fucking awesome.
Beautiful.
No.
Have you done that
thing where you've,
uh,
you've filmed video with your phone and
then just push a button and it
click it.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
That the,
uh,
the,
the ability to play songs from your
phone,
one of you guys podcast on [inaudible],
there's a podcast thing popped up and
just hit play.
The most amazing thing is I went to
documentaries just so I'm thinking,
you know what,
what do they got?
They got fucking page after page after
page of all the best document to watch.
I got red state,
I rendered red state.
Do they have everything?
The corporation they have like pretty
much every documentary of mainstream
documentary I've ever seen is on this
apple thing.
I watched the man on the night and
dungeons and dragons.
I mean there's a lot of your,
there's a lot of obscure documentaries
that don't make it to there I'm sure,
but they had driven the Jens pulver
documentary,
which is pretty obscure even in the
world of mixed martial arts.
I don't know a lot of people who know
about it,
you know.
No.
You have your vimeo channel on there
now.
I just sit there and watch all the
fucking podcast that we do at death
squad from on my apple TV.
That's the whole thing on there.
And,
and the,
the only thing I liked about Roku that
was better,
which was the exact,
it's the exact same thing.
Pretty much ones.
Apple.
When did you say you have the,
your death squad podcasts on Vimeo.
How do you have
just upload them onto a vimeo?
Every time we do one,
we should do that with them.
This to.
Yeah.
Why don't we do that with us?
I don't know.
Okay.
Let's do that with this
mother fucker.
But you had more of a statement than a
hey,
what do you think we should?
Yeah,
why wouldn't you do that with this side?
Uh,
well the business stuff or I'll tell you
later.
Oh,
business stuff.
Uh,
okay.
If you want to talk about it on air
weekend,
it might be,
it might be tricky.
Uh,
yeah.
So anyways,
um,
but you know,
episodes on your,
you can watch the death squad and listen
to it.
I'm just watching the VIMEO channel.
You watch it and listen to it.
It's,
you know,
you're just laying in bed.
And so you're filming your stuff on
Vimeo as well as putting it on ustream?
No,
I'm just taking my seat.
What happens is you use stirring for me,
uh,
crashes all the time because I have ads
and commercials where you got privileged
to get all that taken away.
Uh,
for my watchers,
they hate using this service,
which is understandable.
It's some of them,
some of this stuff.
A lot of people complain about those
ads,
so I stopped the whole screen.
You miss a chunk of the podcast,
right?
So I took all my stuff after it's
broadcast live,
I take it off your stream and put it on
Vimeo just because I have a pro account.
I never used vimeo and now that apple TV
started vimeo on the apple tv,
I was like,
you know what,
I'm moving everything to vimeo now
because Vimeo,
my youtube accounts always get canceled.
They always get busted.
Like I had a director account,
which I don't know you when you first
signed up for Youtube back in the day
view made longer videos that were like
over 10 minutes,
which is what the limit was at that
time.
You could apply for a thing called a
director account,
which gave you access to put movies on
there,
like Youtube was trying to reach out to
small independent directors.
I got that account.
They stopped that a year later and now
the only.
You have like 15 minute limits on
youtube.
Nobody has any longer and Listeria
company.
How come I see that though sometimes
because all the director accounts got
grandfathered.
Oh Wow.
So Youtube recently took my director
account away so I can't do that on
youtube anymore.
Yeah.
We used to be able to upload longer shit
and I remember I tried to upload one of
the podcasts video blogs that we do on
Vimeo.
We have 10 of them up there and what we
do is after we have an interview,
we sit down and we videotape like,
oh that was fun.
We'd shoot the shit for a little bit and
get to just whatever.
It's just something else to do.
Just fine,
you know.
So we started putting those up on Vimeo,
but they're like way better quality than
Youtube and they let you put like 15,
20 minutes.
I don't give a fuck,
you know,
like do it as long as you want.
Youtube is like smaller and shittier
quality.
I guess some.
Some of the youtubes or a nice hd now
too.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah,
but that's why I use
vimeo just looks better,
doesn't it?
Well,
vimeo actually from testing used to be
eight.
Youtube does a great job,
but their hd stuff,
if you do it right and you follow the
right code x,
they're perfect and they're in more
devices.
Smartphones,
they actually have it down.
Pat.
Vimeo is kind of cool.
It's a smaller company.
I wouldn't say.
I think they're up to par now that,
but for awhile I thought Youtube hd was
actually a lot better,
but our shit looks better on Vimeo than
it looks on Youtube.
Well,
you might see the.
One of the things that youtube is,
when you're watching a video on youtube,
it always defaults to like a lot of
times it defaults to the lowest
resolution and so if the research,
like vimeo always put you in hd when
you're on their page,
so a lot of times that's what it is.
It's just a simple thing like that,
oh fuck you.
Youtube.
Well,
youtube has a lot more users.
They're definitely trying to save
bandwidth settings.
There is settings in your youtube
account that makes it so it's always
playing hd and always the best,
but it's not defaulted to that.
Speaking of Youtube,
did you see that video that they just
put out of the chimps that were locked
up?
They never saw sunlight for 30 years.
They want to believe they were stolen
from their mothers at birth and taken to
Austria and they were used,
uh,
in the labs where they were shot up with
hepatitis and HIV and then they released
them from this.
And then the,
uh,
the,
they let these chimps outside for like
the first time ever.
It was crazy to see.
And if you see that,
you still think people should be
experimented on champs.
You're a sick fuck.
Those fucking things.
Getting think man.
Those things can think and they feel and
they have emotions.
They're smart.
And when they got outside and they
started seeing the sun,
they started jumping up and hugging each
other,
making each other and looking out and
trying to figure out how to.
How to walk on the grass and touching
things and hugging each other and
laughing.
That is.
That is the craziest thing that we
justify is taking intelligent animals
and holding them captive.
Whether it's dolphins or chimps.
That is a fucking weird thing,
man.
I mean that is like slavery.
It might as well be slavery.
If you know how smart champions locking
them up like that,
you,
you might.
It might as well be slavery.
Imprisoning them,
stealing them from their mothers.
Like,
whoa man,
that's,
that's pretty fucking rough.
You're causing some serious pain.
So real emotional pain.
And these poor animals.
Smart fucking animals too.
Because it's a weird video,
man.
It's really creepy.
It makes you feel bad to be a person.
It makes you feel bad at someone's doing
stuff like that.
You know?
I know there's a lot of people out
there.
Fuck you,
man.
If it wasn't for those
really,
are you sure?
Yeah.
Vaccines are awesome.
Don't get me wrong,
it is awesome that they figured out a
way to cure a lot of diseases.
You're absolutely right,
but at what cost that cost?
Is that the only way to do it?
I'm down with you doing shit to a
rabbit.
You want to fuck with a rabbit.
It doesn't really bother me,
but when they can think,
when they're smart.
I know rabbits get scared.
It sucks to be them,
but they're fucking rabbits.
All right.
The new people don't want to hierarch
animals,
but there's a reason why some animals
just sit around and eat and shit and
that's it,
and then there's other ones that are way
stronger than eat those motherfuckers.
That's why those motherfuckers are
there.
Their food,
they might not know it.
You know?
They think they're just grass eaters.
They all serve a little piece,
a little piece in the pie,
but chimps,
chimps are so close to us to lock them
up like that and see them come out of
this thing.
It was really heartbreaking.
It was really confusing.
You know?
It's like,
wow,
this.
This doesn't seem to be something that
we should be doing in 2011.
It doesn't seem like we should be doing
any studies on chimps at this stage.
It's like we know enough about human
beings.
We know enough about feelings and
emotions.
We know enough about how close they are
to us and yet we're still willing to do
this.
That's fucked up.
I'd be better.
I'd be happier if they were doing it to
murderers happier if they were doing the
shitheads rapists.
You know what I'm saying?
There's a lot of confirmed out there.
Some confirmed jailed up cons.
Have you learned through experiments for
real?
Why don't we do it on them?
I mean,
people go,
you can't do them to voluntary.
I know,
but you know what?
So is rape and murder.
If someone's acutely,
if someone is guilty of rape and murder,
then the question is how do you know for
sure that they're guilty?
They didn't just get fucked by the
system because they have no money and
they couldn't afford a good lawyer,
but that are that go.
No,
I.
I killed all 12 of them.
They were sleeping in their beds.
Yeah.
Came through the window and I killed
them off the articles.
Yeah.
Fucking experiment on them.
Leave those chimps.
Chimps never did shit to nobody.
You don't have to steal them from their
mother's little baby champs and final
white discount on them and ship.
But why don't we?
Why?
Why can we?
Because people are pussies.
That's why we're going to kill them.
You should like that week ahead of time,
she'd be all exterior Jason Bourne and
look how that worked out.
Well,
I was a member of the Ted nugent message
board.
I tell you that.
What the fuck the problem is the God
damn liberals,
but they're right.
I mean there's the liberals is the idea
of constant compassion and the need to
to treat all human beings is absolutely
equal despite their past and what
they've done.
Listen man,
if you're some fucking religious person
who's completely recanted from your
horrible life and it seems that you've
done,
you know,
like as much as possible to,
to make up for your shitty actions in
the past,
there's people that have made mistakes
and they've turned their life around.
I completely,
totally believe that.
But then there's also cons.
Yeah.
You know,
it's,
it's up to us to figure out who they are
and just experiment on them.
Man.
You're on your fourth trip to Aruba.
Coming back by yourself even though you
and your girlfriend went,
yeah,
you should get hooked up to your net.
Why does it always happen in a room?
But I know.
I know.
What is it?
Is it people saying no?
Is it girls turning guys down and the
guys being mad?
Is it someone getting jealous?
Is it just cycled?
Last one was a guy who met a girl online
fluor to.
They're on vacation.
His girlfriend.
His most recent missing.
Yeah.
That I,
I think he might've said that she's
probably dead now for that guy.
He said she's dead.
Yeah,
I think,
but I would just any girl listening,
if anyone says we should go on our
senior trip or maybe go to Aruba,
uh,
there's other areas you could go.
So weird man,
but that is something that girls have to
really worry about.
They have to worry about being killed by
a guy like that's a,
that's a,
that's a possibility.
It's a rare possibility.
But out of the 300 million people in
this country,
that's a big number.
Every now and then one or two is going
to pop up and God damn is it
heartbreaking.
Some fucking person who's attracted to
the opposite sex but doesn't get what he
wants so often and it's so psychopathic
that he becomes angry at women and wants
to kill them and they're out there.
They're out there.
Can you shed any city you go to like
Vegas or Cam?
Girls let their guard down and I'll see
maybe because I'm older now and just
about all of them could maybe be a dawn.
Not,
not really,
but you look and you see them,
they're drunk and they're.
And they think that bitchy voice that
they have is going to be the protection.
You know what I mean?
Did that kind of.
I'm that drunk chick kind of noise will
examine their boss,
I don't know where you are.
And they're like in an alley in the
middle of Tampa.
You're like,
what do you do it?
Especially if they're like little
children too.
It's like,
you know,
you see some girls that are drunk and
Vegas and be like 20 years old and
hammered and you're like,
wow,
that's like a little child.
She's just out there catching deck.
I know I was in a,
you know,
you don't think of them as little
children when you're 20,
when you're $20 checks now you see them.
But when you're 40 and you look at 20
year olds,
you go,
wow,
this is like the like childlike,
you know,
some of those poor girls,
man,
that Shit's going to program their life.
Bad experiences when you're hammered at
20 around animals,
that's a program your light.
And it changed the way you behave or
wherever.
You know,
just a few shitty decisions around the
wrong people in the wrong crowd and just
changes your opinion.
I saw I've,
wherever I was performing two weeks ago,
the bouncer guys driving back to the
hotel,
there's a big huge dude which some
really drunk like woman.
I bet you she was 55 but kind of still
sketched out and she was with another
woman and the woman looked at the big
guy and says,
I don't know her.
I have her cell phone.
I'm going to call her first thing in the
morning to this big huge guy.
And the guy didn't look at this.
Other woman goes,
come on,
I'm not going to rape or whatever.
He just looked at or whatever like that.
And then this juncture chick got into
the car and then they drove off and then
that woman got got into the car.
Wow.
You're like,
dude,
what do you do?
I mean,
I think it was a guy picking up a drunk
girl,
but it was Kinda one of those.
I had a moment where I could have stolen
somebody's girlfriend recently if I was
that type of guy.
Stoller.
Well it was,
it would've been a cool movie thing.
There's this girl at the gas station and
she's got a tub of aloe about this big
and Vera.
Yeah,
Kinda big thing of ice and she's icing.
The guy has one of those krautrock at
motorcycles and it was about 110 outside
and she obviously Burton her leg on the
exhaust,
so now they're,
I think,
you know,
sitting by the gas pumps,
the guys putting all this stuff on all
this aloe.
He's got his leather jacket,
motorcycle.
She looks so pissed like.
But we've all seen pissed off girls
before.
But the look of just any come out even
came out with one of those roses.
Huh?
And she got it and just set it down.
Like if I was like one of those Douche
bag you guys,
all they would have had to done is this
stick out my hand.
Like every moving go take my hand and
put her in my jeep and drove away.
That guy would have been left right
there.
That's ridiculous that you would think
that.
Yeah.
Right.
What do you think you are overconfident?
You friendly?
You know,
you're like one of those guys like
watch.
She's going to turn around and look at
me.
No,
no.
The deal is
I had a car though.
She doesn't have.
Didn't have to get back on that moment.
Probably when the girl is putting aloe
and ice on the inside of her leg.
Yes.
That's what I mean.
I could have sold a right then you're
delusional.
My hand could have been a very good
relationship and a guy just got a
motorcycle.
Motorcycles.
They had a great time riding together
and unfortunately she burned her leg,
but she loves him and she loves being
with the look on her.
Just come along and like my hand.
I would have said it way better words
to,
okay,
Lin is not enough movies.
I could trust me and if you want to live
I could have said no,
you need something better than that.
But that would have been the time we
have four wheels.
No,
because look,
he just made a mistake and the guy came
back.
He was being nice.
He brought a rose.
It's a nice gesture is obviously a nice
person.
He feels bad about it,
of relieved that mistake and you come
along and just try to steal your
ridiculous.
It's never gonna.
Relive that mistake.
You might have an Faq of cocaine and
$100.
That would have worked more than than
that shit.
That doesn't work.
It just got off a motorcycle and cocaine
in $100.
She's like,
I have a burn on my leg.
I don't want any cocaine.
She wants air conditioning and didn't
you know,
pants and not have to ride outside.
Hey,
I got a cartoon to start watching.
If you want to show you a little kids
like a cartoon that they can fall in
love with,
but it will be awesome for you.
That fit while being stoned.
It's the best for the double.
A level double level cartoon.
It's called adventure time and it's just
ventured time.
Yeah,
it is the most ridiculous fucking
cartoon I've ever seen in my life and
I'm so addicted to it and it's great for
kids.
Kids will just fucking sit there and
love it today because it's all about
princesses and princes and adventures
with dragons and horses.
But it is trippy as,
what is it on a,
it's on cartoon network.
It's on all the time.
Like I,
I just dvr it like a schedule it and I
think I got seven yesterday.
So
is it an animation one or.
Yeah,
it's animation.
It's kind of put to the same animation
styles that game called Catamari,
but it's very simple but very trippy,
like a lot of dragons and swords.
And when you say that it works on both
levels of the,
like peewee's playhouse kind of,
but not the new peewee's playhouse?
Yeah,
they have to have it on showtime and
that he,
what he did is he did like a live thing
throughout,
you know,
like Los Angeles for a while and then he
took it on the road.
I think he went to New York and he had
like a live show of the playhouse and
they filmed it for I think showtime or
Hbo.
But I try watching it and it's like
completely a weird.
Now,
is it weird because you know he was
beating off in a movie theater watching?
No,
it's weird because it's like,
it's like he still looks pretty good,
like he still looks pretty much like
peewee,
but it's just off a teeny bit where
you're like,
wait,
he has a double Chin now.
That's so,
uh.
Oh
yeah.
Right.
He's got this sloppiness to them.
They just kind of.
I don't know.
It's kind of weird.
I would like to see go see kits though.
And it's Kinda the same.
Yeah.
I would like to see the video of peewee
herman getting busted beating off.
Do you know how awesome that would be?
To have the video of him on his tongue
out slow motion.
I'm over and tell him to put his fucking
Dick away and get up.
Why would you?
You would have been even bigger than he
was proud of him.
I know,
right?
Well that's the funny thing about that.
A lot of times when things like that
happen,
there's a backlash,
but it was sort of like an anti backlash
with peewee Herman.
They like liked him more,
you know,
now he
would have made more money if you go in
route and you know why they liked him
more because he's gay.
He's a gay guy that got caught jerking
off in public.
This is my theory and he was he a
straight guy that got caught jerking off
in public.
It might be a little more creepy because
it's a gay guy,
like poor little fella got nowhere to
beat off.
It can't be open about it and he's got
to go watch string people.
Fuck and concentrate on the Dicks,
you know,
can't even go to a gay place because
he's famous.
Well,
when that happened though,
didn't he lose his show and actually
knocked him,
you know,
he was really popular.
That happened and then people took,
took them off to shell lake.
So we kind of lost it.
I might not know what the fuck I'm
talking about.
I'm talking about what happened in the
court of public opinion
maybe in the financial world that
devastated him.
I don't know what the court of public
opinion.
I felt like he did better.
I don't know what other shows.
Did he have a show still?
Because it was not that.
It was a long ass time ago that when was
the last movie?
House was on.
He had the two movies that came after
that.
Oh,
this was probably in the late eighties
where he got arrested.
No,
but like we're at its height of
popularity and pee wee's big adventure.
So Papa got rested in the early
nineties.
I remember I went to see peewee's
playhouse with my then girlfriend at the
time who was also very silly.
She was a silly girl.
She was a good person.
Go see movies with and we were fucking
car riding,
laughing.
I thought it was the funniest thing I'd
ever seen.
I was like,
I was a huge peewee Herman Fan,
you know?
It was just so ridiculous.
Large Marge Center.
We do that all the time.
Yeah.
You just have all these random away.
He would like be in love with the girl
and bring her flowers and stuff.
It was so bizarre.
It's like,
God,
what a fun.
Like a fun,
silly.
Do you know?
Do you know our friend Jeff Scott is the
number one peewee Herman and personally
I used to remember watching pm magazine,
which was a show and I think the
Midwest,
I don't even think I would imagine.
And I had it in Detroit.
Okay.
Yeah.
And they interviewed him.
I remember watching that episode and
then written.
Now we'll just find out.
That was back when,
uh,
there was a show called.
Kids are people too.
That's incredible.
You remember?
What was the other ones came on right
before the right.
I was always a real no real people.
That was the original youtube.
It was really incredible.
Was the original Youtube think?
I love that.
Remember the old Ed Mcmahon,
a peep practical joke show that used to
be really big.
Oh yeah.
It was a TV bloopers and practical jokes
and had the cartoons from the game show
with the whammies.
Yeah.
What's that called?
No,
whammies.
No whammies.
Stop.
Press your luck.
They used to have those whammies.
Yeah.
And that.
And for some reason those whammies were
so popular that when that game show was
canceled,
they were like,
we're going to use the whammies on this
show now.
It was just like,
was just like,
wow,
you're just using cartoons from a
different games.
Just continued the family tradition.
Yeah,
it was.
I looked at my
watch real people episode on Youtube
recently and it was all just,
it was all just crazy.
And then we're going to go to Wisconsin
when this guy may can jump 5,000 feet
into cheese.
It was like all just random random
stuff.
And if you look at it like it's this
person has every coke can ever make the
all would have their own shows.
Now if you look how crazy these people
and every one of them would have a show
on discovery or an a and e,
there'd be a reality show about every
story with the people that Byron Allen
was like,
what the fuck is with these pawn shops?
They're all.
It hit the bottom when they were
following guys who are driving on
slippery roads.
Yeah.
Ice Road truckers.
Road is slippery.
You did a truck seven years.
Nobody's falling in the same fucking
show every week.
The guys on the ice road.
Oh,
was getting slippery.
Yeah,
I mean I thought that was dumb until I
watched one of these auction shows the
other day.
No pawn shop.
So rather where the dude wasn't even a
pawn shop.
So it was like a bargain sort of a show.
He shows up,
a guy's got a sign.
He goes,
how much you want for this sign?
Oh,
I'm not looking to sell it.
What if I give you 500 bucks?
No,
no,
I don't think that'd be enough.
What if I gave you a thousand bucks?
Well,
now you're making me think.
I'm like,
what the fuck?
Really?
This is the show with the two brothers
and one guy.
One guy buys it.
I didn't get that far.
They were just trying to buy a coca cola
sign from some dudes.
I wanted to punch the screen,
but it's 100 times better than that show
on true TV.
The pawn shop show that's completely
fake,
but yet everyone
was like,
the only thing in it for the person
watching was you want to find out how it
ended.
How did it get resolved?
It's like this,
but it's like the lowest level
entertainment ever.
It's guy give you 100 bucks.
No bugs.
No,
no.
I'll give you 500 bucks.
Well,
no,
you're making me think like you're
sitting there with your mouth open,
waiting to see things.
Doing
boom
days.
When the pond pawn shop owners had a amp
and that was all the went down through.
All creeps right in.
They all have an expert.
They're like,
well,
luckily I called the expert of 18,
22 bullets.
No,
you don't punch punc guys don't have a
team of experts.
Most pawn shop guys are kind of creepy,
right?
But I've known about pawn shops is pool
hall dudes who always would sell stolen
shit.
The pawn shops.
Yeah.
They don't have a guy going in there
showing you trying to sell pool cues to
buy crack and I know I do do it.
A housekeeper and they caught the
housekeeper selling shit.
The pawn shops,
they found a shit at trace some of them.
One of their things and turned out it
was sold at a certain punch up there
fucking housekeeper.
We're stealing their shit and bringing
it to pawnshops.
Oh Shit Dude.
Can you imagine having a pawn shot that
was also a check cashing place and how
much that would be.
It'd be robbed and.
Well they give you a cashier so it's
technically actually it'd be the wrong
thing.
You will want to check crush in place
there now,
but it's like
it doesn't make sense.
It's just a all for one and I don't have
any money.
Look,
my,
my dad does not go to cash checking
places or pawn shops.
So it seems like the people,
the clientele,
those two places seem like they would
enjoy a place that they can go to do
both if they have to.
I guess that makes sense,
but it doesn't make sense because it's
two totally different things.
Like you're totally broke.
You have no money coming in.
So you sell a stolen TV.
Right?
To cash.
Because my time is spent,
I'll give everything in a bar on one.
Didn't you say you got your dad?
Hi once
talking about that?
No,
I didn't get them high.
I just saw it was when I had a thing of
weed soda and it tastes like Cola and he
was like,
you're already taking a drink.
And I gave him some weed.
Soda.
Do you ever know what happened?
He was having a great time laughing and
telling funny stories and giggling.
It was,
it was awesome.
Did you tell him you tell him that you
could have a day like this everyday now
because we were drinking wine also.
So I,
uh,
I think he just probably thought that.
Wow,
that was something good wine.
Why don't you just tell him that gave
him some weed.
Soda will come on man.
That's great.
Now why do you think that generation?
Why don't you tell him?
Huh?
Why don't you tell Him Dad?
He had a great time because you were,
you drinking weed soda?
Because he has a job and if they knew
the contest you are.
Everyone lives in California.
We'll do a lot of places.
Don't pee test their employees.
I don't think.
I don't think it's a majority to fucking
pee.
Test that work at gateway.
Definitely test to work at starbucks.
Not Any starbucks people.
They can't smoke week because I get
tested.
Hold on a second.
Stop it.
Yes.
You're talking about burrows.
Most.
Most major jobs.
You have to pee tests and I do not think
you're right.
I do not think you have to pee.
Test.
Hold on.
Just make that up.
I had to pee.
Test twice the work at gateway.
Did you say that about starbucks?
No.
Google it.
We have google right here.
Starbucks employees.
That's incredible.
If it's true,
what if it's true?
I'm going to start going to coffee bean.
Any major company has to do it for
insurance reasons though.
Not really.
Yeah,
it's,
it's a,
it's like a rule,
you know,
for,
uh,
for most big companies that their
insurances are so high that they have to
do shit like that.
At the starbucks where I worked as a
Barista,
there was no drug testing.
No drug testing was ever performed.
Thing is working at it,
it certainly did not do random drug
testing either as far as drug testing.
If you get injured while working.
I do not know what the policy is,
but starbucks is not really a laid back
place to work.
Um,
okay.
Well starbucks doesn't.
But what the fuck kind of places do
though?
When I,
when I worked for Brian saying that
starbucks does to work as a fucking
Burrito
is a ridiculous thing and you like you
don't say stipe miocic invoke with
starbucks.
What I was talking about is most
companies nowadays do require drug
testings.
I worked,
I worked at a lot of places.
Joe Not long ago,
seven years ago I was waiting tables.
I worked at a lot of companies that drug
tested.
I had to do it all the time and they got
some terrible news today,
by the way,
fashion Irma's.
What percentage do you think what
percentage of companies drug tests
they're out of like the last five real
jobs I had,
I probably got drug tested at three of
those five jobs and these are defined
divine search search by going what?
Fortune 500 because they would have the
money to do it.
That's not.
No,
it's pretty normal for companies that
drug test outside of California.
It.
That's all I'm saying is that I wasn't
saying starbucks as starbucks.
I'm saying companies like starbucks and
things like that.
Main major companies.
I would.
Are you ready for reality?
Okay.
Here it is.
Major Laboratory testing company offered
the cheery news recently that the
percentage of American workers who
tested positive for illegal drugs last
year was the lowest ever.
So people are testing.
The cheery news is that
people aren't used to be drug as much
because they're buying shit at waterbed
stores like myself called waterbeds and
company and it was a $20 talking about
drugs.
$40 investment and people aren't
watching it.
That quote saying that is that he,
that he's as good news that people
aren't testing positive for drugs.
What are you talking about?
Waterbeds?
Uh,
they sell at head shops in Ohio and in
the midwest they don't have head shops
like marijuana store.
So they sell,
like they have companies like waterbed
stores that sell head stuff,
supplies in it.
There's a place called water beds and
stuff in Ohio.
Didn't expect anyone else to know.
I was explaining it.
Then you stopped when you were.
I was,
I was just getting to this point anyway.
And they sell for $40.
He so feisty.
Today is your fucking sativa six.
I got a no,
you need to learn how to handle it.
But,
but,
but uh,
they sell this shit that you drink,
that you drink right before you take a
drug test.
And so what you're pretty much doing is
you're pissing out this shit that's kind
of like they just did a big thing in.
Can't answer this question.
I'm answering this question.
What percentage of companies drug test
their employees.
I pumped this into Google.
Give me an answer,
bitch.
It's funny how long Google questions.
How now when you first came out,
you pick up two words like drug testing.
Go,
screw it.
I'm just going to write an entire
paragraph from see what happened.
But in Florida they had,
um,
the,
they tested everybody on welfare and uh,
you know,
like that's a big thing is you have to
get tested drug tested before you get
the welfare check.
Ninety eight percent passed.
Whoa.
Hold on a second.
Listen to this shit.
And six survey by the Society for human
resource management found that 84
percent of employers required new hires
to hirees to pass drug screenings.
Sad.
He's been in California long,
just 39 percent random
early testing employees after they were
hired.
Holy Shit.
In addition,
73 percent tested workers when drug use
was suspected and 58 percent required
testing after accidents on the job.
Whoa.
What the fuck,
man,
that's a lot of new hires that you do
trouble.
That is a horrible thing,
man.
Eighty four percent of employers were
crying.
We're crying paper to take drug tests.
Wow,
that's incredible.
That's so discriminatory.
You know,
especially for things that stay in your
system but aren't as damaging.
Like we'd.
Whereas cocaine is out of your system.
You take it on a Friday,
you'll,
you'll pass a drug test on a Monday.
It's a quick thing,
it gets out of your system quick unless
I think they test your hair.
I think if they test your hair,
they can find it a little longer
and at the waterbed store they have a
shampoo that you put on their hair if
they do test your hair and that's
really.
It's crazy that this water pet store in
Columbus,
Ohio,
still in business and waterbed,
not waterbed and stuff.
I love that store.
I love water beds and stuff.
You got to go do it.
Next time you're in Ohio,
I don't think I do pass on that stupid
fucking store.
They have shipper.
Every drug test.
Your waterbed would actually smelled
like bong water and be kind of crappy to
sleep or the water.
The worst thing ever is you have a
waterbed and the power goes out and then
waterbeds not hot anymore and it fucking
polls heat off your body like you don't
realize.
It's actually kind of dangerous man.
Like you don't want to have a black and
white,
furry a bedspread.
Think everybody who I've ever met that
had a lot of my probably done at one
point in time.
It was a good waterbed though,
but they suck for fucking.
My cat popped mine while we were fucking
and fucking look at book,
but what happened is we both woke up at
the same time,
but you said we're not.
Me and my cat were fucking.
No,
I wasn't finding the cat,
but the cat popped it while I was
fucking a girl.
It was like something like tweet.
There was so I didn't know it was the
second I'm is
trying to bring you back to reality
wasn't the waterbed.
Ips was just pushing all the pis out.
Brian,
you need to go to adult.
Brian.
That's what you're telling you.
Put it off forever.
I rewatched the last Joey Diaz podcast
last night and that's the funny thing
because when Joey Diaz is going crazy,
you kept on going,
you need to go to a doctor,
you need to go to a doctor
like a yelling Dr. crazy doctor need to
talk to somebody.
I want to go to a doctor to have the
funniest vsd in the video where he was
going,
pushing a cart to target.
I laughed.
So yeah.
Mad flavors.
World,
if you will.
I was laughing so hard.
If you go on Youtube,
is it mad flavor world or mad flavors?
World.
He's mad flavors.
Road.
Okay.
Let's find out because people need to
know.
It's so,
so funny.
She's walking around and talking to
people in target without them knowing
you're going to do it.
Show Friday.
Mad flavors.
World.
I don't know why you asking me on the.
On the air.
May do it on Friday.
I may not make it mad flavors.
World.
It is on Youtube.
You got to go and check it out because
what joe is doing is he's just doing
these little videos,
putting them up every now and again.
Didn't do it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's awesome.
More content from Joey.
Anything.
Anything he does is awesome.
You know,
he's such an enigma,
such an unusual person.
I've never met anybody that I'll let you
yell at me like Joey,
but he's like,
it's all.
You just weather the storm.
It's like,
you know,
it's not even,
it's almost like,
not even real.
Like,
all right joey,
you still mad at me.
You done.
Tell him when he died.
I watched that video.
You posted
that video.
Posted what you were doing.
What?
You're fucking.
You're fucking
gets crazy mad over a vaporizer will
start screaming.
You fucking pussies.
Which a vaporizer
to be healthy.
It's fucking weed.
He'll get mad at you.
Man.
Was that the guy that you didn't,
was it a radio show you did?
Were you invited him in?
I saw that color.
The Alex Jones show.
Yeah.
What happened after that?
But like after that,
when you said the dude was baffled.
Oh,
stones sat there in a pile of rubble
until what the fuck happened to his
show?
I mean,
could you imagine man,
if you've got to doom or gloom doom and
gloom show and those of you who haven't
seen it,
just google did some dude.
Dude did a good fellows version of it,
which is fucking hilarious.
I wish I knew the,
the,
the um,
the youtube and look up goodfellas.
Joe Diaz.
Alex Jones.
I don't know,
you could find it in any way.
The um,
the,
what was hilarious about it is houses
too,
so serious.
It's all doom and gloom and the
government and the CIA has been spotted
in Nicaragua with tons of cocaine and he
just like fuck.
And to have a guy like joey come in and
just wreck shop,
just completely ridiculous and going for
the laugh,
you know,
I thought I had Karen.
My left balls bigger than I write.
I thought I had cancer and to do it in
just this guy's got his fucking empire
of doom and gloom.
He's got this empire of the fucking end
of the world is here and this is what
he's selling.
This is entertainment.
And he's my friend and we just walked in
and just gave him silly is this is,
this is,
here's some ridiculous motherfucker.
Here's a human cartoon.
We're both high as Brian is.
So Hi,
Brian is sitting there with little
esther.
They're sitting on the floor watching at
the,
on the bottom.
I'm like under the desk,
like we'll just sit here and watch it.
They wanted to be inside watching.
And Brian's filming it and him and
little esther,
a giggling dude.
That was one of the greatest moments of
my life.
That was one of the funniest things I've
ever seen.
He was alive at the time.
He was doing that?
Yeah.
Oh,
so we're on the Internet.
That's how all these videos are over.
And he said there's a dump on.
I know when I did radio dump or.
Oh No.
So he doesn't have anything dumping when
he's online.
When he's online.
The online version is uncensored,
wasn't he?
Wasn't he broadcasting?
No,
live to like tons of radio.
That's why I told them where he was,
why I was on the first 45 minutes while
I was on.
It was just me and him.
And then we will.
Okay.
We're going to do this next one.
We're going to live on the internet,
but don't swear if you do,
it's okay.
But that's what he said.
Say that I hope he's okay.
By the way,
if you've been watching the news about
Austin and all the fires is bad.
Oh,
it's super bad.
Like tons of how I saw Dale Dudley
posted something on twitter about it,
that it took them like two and a half
hours to get home and it's scary.
I get a lot of people are losing their
houses in Austin,
right to wildfires are fucking nuts.
I've been in a few of them now.
I've been evacuated from my house on
three separate occasions,
twice in this house,
twice in my other house.
It's fucking scary as shit.
How do you decide?
Because I just had a conversation with
my wife because we have no exit plan for
zombies.
Earthquake,
fire,
nothing.
We have nothing.
Now.
How do you know what to grab?
That's the one thing that you need to
grab anything,
man.
Grab your fucking kids and then forward
and don't stop thinking about your shit
because it's over man.
You could reaccumulated shit.
You know you need to get the fuck out.
When you.
When you get to a situation like that,
you know what you need.
You need your credit cards.
You need your fucking a laptop.
If you can get it and some clothes for a
few days,
just fucking run because they swarm on
you so fast.
This is how fast those fucking fires
are.
Man.
We were in lake t han,
which is like over an hour north and you
have to take the five past Santa
Clarita,
so I'm on the five up near Santa Clarita
and the fire is right there.
It's like Razah.
I'm driving to work.
It's like 10:00 in the morning as I'm
going to work.
It's like right down.
I'm like,
Whoa,
fuck.
Like this.
It looks bad.
I mean it was a big fire.
So I'm at work.
We're filming fear factor.
We filmed for about three or four hours.
We get done with the stunt and we see
smoke coming over the mountain.
Now this is over an hour and a half of
driving 70 miles an hour.
The fire got to where I was and just a
few hours,
so I leave.
I get on the fucking highway and the
entire way home,
the whole right side of the highway is
ablaze like a horror movie because it's
nighttime and it looks like a scene from
the Hobbit,
like I'm waiting for demons to come
riding black horses with fiery eyes.
I mean it's fucking terrifying man.
And I tried to take some photos.
I saw we also saw a dead guy there too.
I think it talked about that.
So I got to get hit by a car.
Mac units actually saw one of the
producers of fear factor.
He saw the guy's body.
He didn't.
I don't think he actually saw the
impact.
I think he just saw it right after it
happened.
I thought I felt somebody you hit one.
I still had that vision in my head.
You can't try to want to cross the
highway,
man.
People can't stop that fast.
You gotta be able to gauge how fast a
person can stop.
You know,
like a race car can stop 96 feet from
like 100 miles an hour.
You know,
that's a race car.
That's a lot of fucking a distance man.
Ninety six feet screeching coming
towards you,
a giant hunk of metal.
That's if two people are actually paying
attention.
Texting or something like.
Yeah,
no shit.
You gotta be careful.
There's people who do tax on the
highway,
which is amazing that I see it a lot now
you see I'm just looking down and just
Kinda motherfuckers motherfuckers,
you know,
someone that Jon Anik from a at espns
mma live,
you know that show the van.
Okay.
Yeah.
He always says don't text and drive.
It says at the end of every show.
It's such a good thing to do.
Just put it in people's heads.
Don't do it like Bob Barker.
I think texts and drives better.
Depends what a fuck.
But that's an unfortunate.
But Hey,
Bob Barker is a good guy.
Just trying to make sure there's not any
unwanted puppies.
Trisha little messages.
Little little.
Uh,
yeah.
You just gotTa people have little tags.
Goldie has one.
When I work with my Goldberg,
when it fights over,
it's always over.
Yes,
sure.
Do you know who tyler the Creator is
who?
Tyler.
The Creator is your wrapper?
Yes.
He's really young.
He's like 20 years old and uh,
I've been falling as twitter for a bit
now,
but I guess he just wants something at
the video movie awards is.
Twitter is pretty funny.
Side Fuck Tyler on twitter.
But uh,
he,
he's just this little young kid,
but he has those rafts.
Twitter is called Fuck Tyler.
Yeah.
And he has this type that right.
You're really weird.
Like it's going to pop up.
I,
I just,
I'm a big fan.
I think you might like,
um,
check out his raps.
He w what's really cool is he's not one
of those guys that come and he's got
545,000 followers.
He's fucking brilliant.
Really.
I love the students.
I love this guy.
Damn.
How do I not know about this guy?
He's like,
what he's called like horror rap is what
he gets tagged as with horror.
Horror.
Horror monsters are heart.
Yeah.
One note kind of like,
I guess scary rap.
Like I saw one of his videos were like,
everyone's has guns in her hands and
stuff.
Kind of like maybe like,
like a new version of Nwa,
you know,
kind of like a scarface.
Remember when scarface and Geto boys
were,
they were considered horror.
Kind of like,
I've never heard the tester wrap,
I guess horror,
horror.
Romp.
Yeah.
Remember the Geto boys was out there
kind of like,
you kind of believed that they were like
a gang almost,
you know,
and every fucking bullets in their eyes
coming out of sockets and tried to kill
himself,
didn't he?
I don't remember.
I thought he got shot in the eye or
something.
I don't know.
I think he didn't.
He what happened?
I don't know what happened to that guy.
I'm going to.
I'm just sort of trying to think of the
horror rap,
but there's a,
there's a sweet 16
killed them.
Tried to kill himself.
I think he was high on everclear and Cho
shot himself in the face.
There's a really cool video that,
that you need to see if tyler,
the creator,
it's called Yonkers,
need to know the answer to that Bushwick
bill shot himself,
but you got yonkers Joe.
See that guy.
That is not going to be saying that
because I'm a.
I'm a fan.
You know what sucks about liking people
like tyler,
the creator though is like they have a
live show in la,
but I'd be too scared to go there.
I got.
I got beat up by all of you guys because
I feel like a hanging around with black
eyes.
Well I can't.
I believe that the,
probably the majority of the people that
like them are probably like,
you know,
like a little bit rougher than me.
They,
they would see me and tried to rape me
or something.
I was at Curtis blow new edition wizards
everywhere.
Utfo concert in Detroit to when I was 16
and we got beat up really?
Okay in 1991 in Bushwick.
Bill,
either in a suicidal funk or a drunken
rage or as a scheme to have his mother
collect on his insurance policy.
Uh,
he began goating is 17 year old
girlfriend and shooting him.
Wow.
Reports say he had threatened to harm
the child they had together if she
refused to go through with the deed
would actually transpired.
Has never been divulged by either party
involved,
but either his or her hand by either his
or her hand build.
Caught a slug in his right eye.
Whoa,
shoot me.
We're going to make some money.
And insurance policy.
Holy Shit to a sex tape was before that.
Wow.
But he had already had like a bunch of.
Didn't they have like hit songs already?
Who could he not do shows or something
like where's this money going?
I needed money that badly.
You it to get shot for insurance money.
I mean they were famous.
I didn't really think.
Yeah,
you really didn't think that through.
And by the way,
I don't think,
uh,
the,
the first sex tape I think was that dude
from Hogan's heroes do it.
I'll always be a Bushwick bill fan from
that song.
Fuck a war.
You know that song?
The only play that on the podcast once.
Yeah.
It's a great fucking jam.
Bushwick bills.
Fuck a war is just,
just for that alone.
The dude gets my respect forever.
He can go shoot himself.
Go ahead.
So did you ever one of those Coca Cola
that were popular,
that Jersey Jersey cocacola shirts that
were really popular?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Do you notice your.
I don't.
Jersey.
Did they sell it at chess king?
No.
Maybe that was wholly country.
They used to have these jerseys that
just had like the stripe across it.
They said Coca Cola and it was a stripe
on the arms and the striking.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Like hockey,
Jersey or basketball?
No,
Not Jersey.
Like Sports Jersey.
Like polo shirts kind of remembered.
That was a phase where people wore a lot
of.
Yeah,
like Coca Cola just started making
clothes.
How you would actually let become
popular.
I think there's someone knocking on the
door.
Was that someone not going to donate?
What do you.
What Patrick?
Is that Joey know that you heard that
right?
Yeah.
Maybe he's knocking on the front girl
from door knocking up a girl and just
ask if someone's talking in the front
door.
Joey Diaz is on his way over here.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Is it?
Oh,
is that.
That window is outside the door.
Hold on folks.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Did you know they're making a sequel to
knocked up?
Hey John,
did you know that they're making a
secret that knocked up?
No,
I didn't.
Sorry about that guys.
We were trying to figure out where you
are now.
A burglar how to jump the fence.
Joey Diaz.
This now just walked into the building.
We're high as fuck and fucking
headphones on.
We had no idea where that noise was
coming from.
You.
We're not going to do what we were
looking.
I don't want to call.
It was a waste of time.
What's happening?
Hey,
hold on.
So just to cover what we're talking
about,
Brian was hypnotizing us with some story
about jerseys were you wore Coca Cola
Jersey Hook a cooler shirts in the
eighties that were really popular.
That was like kind of like a polo shirt.
A red shirt.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I remember the red shirt.
Yeah.
You guys remember?
We have no idea.
They have no idea what I don't know
about the hypnotize.
I was never hypnotized by it.
Now I know the show you're talking about
the Rick Coca Cola hypnotized by his
story because it was so ridiculous.
I was like,
no,
it's crazy.
I walked in.
I'm glad you're here to defend him.
Otherwise,
really good attack.
We were just mounting up or attack right
now.
Motherfucker.
What's Joe Diaz in the fucking house
pitches Malibu and got hit in the
fucking leg.
This rock,
those eight foot waves.
Oh,
bring them in fucking rocks though.
Yeah,
that thing knocked me over.
I mean it was.
I was.
My foot was on the Rock and a rock
squished my flux and fung Geico.
My uncle lives on the Jersey shore and
um,
he got a.
He made a video of waves fucking up the
Jersey shore.
Like how bad a irene crushed everything.
Holy Fuck.
It's nuts.
It's Newark is really bad.
Middle New Jersey is fucking bad,
man.
It's crazy.
Vermont got fucked up.
Vermont.
You know what the really crazy thing was
looking at the satellite image of how
big the hurricane was when they talked
about it was going to take two days to
reach Vermont from Florida and North
Carolina.
I remember looking at the picture,
I'm like,
that is that what the.
The scale tree,
that's a country of a storm flying
overhead.
It looked like bigger than most European
kind.
Like bigger than Germany or something
like that.
You know,
like what's a small European country?
It was way bigger than that.
It was huge.
Some of those countries in,
in,
in Europe,
very small and very close to each other.
You know,
these fucking,
this,
this hurricane was bigger than a couple
of countries.
It's fucking nuts,
man.
It ain't no,
but I think we'll get one this year.
That'll damage at least one.
Is that the biggest one of all time now
on that side of the country,
what's the biggest one of all times,
Gloria,
because I remember when I was a kid,
Hurricane Gloria hit.
I don't remember.
Katrina wouldn't be the.
The biggest one was the one of the most
devastating,
but that was also because we're it hit
it hit New Orleans,
which is really crazy that no,
no big ones ever hit New Orleans before
and it's running a fucking.
You just got lucky.
It's like you talk about like living
anywhere tornadoes hit.
It's just like totally like playing
craps.
One day this guy becomes an angry
monster and destroy an town.
You see those pictures they had in
Tuscaloosa,
Alabama on fucking believe in Joplin.
The whole place is gone.
God Don,
that's Joplin,
Missouri.
Yeah.
They always get fucking whack,
bro.
They get whacked,
hard,
crazy,
crazy man that people choose to stay in
places like that where they can
economically.
Yeah,
I mean there's no quick in the east
coast,
not.
We're not safe anywhere where you are in
tornado alley,
earthquake or hurricane alley.
That's true.
You know,
I was,
I was at Malibu area that I'm looking at
these waves and I'm looking at the
intensity and for one second I thought
about what if there is a fucking tsunami
and malleable.
What if I was sitting there going,
what if a little fucking earthquake.
That's a wild ocean out there and the
ocean is just wild.
It's,
it's the blood of the earth,
you know,
it's 60 percent or whatever.
The fucking coverage is more than 70.
Baffles the fuck out of me since I was a
kid,
so I don't fuck with it.
Almost drying in coney island and almost
drowned as a kid in coney island and I
was out there,
you know,
up to your waist,
playing with a ball and all of a sudden
you know,
something just sucks you in,
you don't know what.
And next thing you know,
you're in a fucking toe and you know
what man or what do they call him?
Mr. But yeah,
undertow or riptide?
No.
Undertaking a rip tide or under both of
them.
The same.
I don't mind pools and shit.
I know people pissing them and shit,
but the folk that oceans are different
items,
you know,
I didn't even know.
Look,
I got clocked by a rock.
That's a creepy feeling too.
When you feel the undertow or the
riptide,
whatever the fuck it is.
Pulling you back.
Yeah.
We used to go to the ocean trying to
pull you into it.
Remember you look back and see your mom
finally,
like,
get the fuck in and you're like my wife
and it's sucking you in and I'll send
you.
Just go from five feet to 15 feet and
now you're caught in that fucking a.
it's a very,
uh,
scary actually when you're being pulled,
swim,
don't fight it,
you know,
grateful and save somebody.
Some girl,
he was on vacation and Greg Fitzsimmons
is not like the most fit guy.
He's a small dude.
And he said some girl got pulled away by
the,
by the,
the time.
And she started screaming and he
realized she couldn't swim very well and
he went,
oh fuck.
And he had a moment to decide what to
do.
And he jumped in.
Oh,
she didn't.
When he was there with his family.
You got to be careful about that man,
because you know what happens.
People drown you if you don't really
know how to rescue someone,
grab a hold of them.
They panic and they drag you under.
That's fucking dangerous shit,
man.
Rescuing someone.
It's very hard to do.
You gotta really know what the fuck
you're doing.
That's about the ocean.
The first time I moved to California,
I went wake boarding.
We went out in the thing and a huge way,
but I missed it.
I didn't know to go under,
I didn't know that shit.
The board under in pop up,
so I rode so it took me nine feet in the
air and threw me backwards and then pin
me and ever since then I haven't done it
again.
We are too afraid to like,
cause I just got my ass kicked so bad
that one particular time.
I'm like,
man,
I'm gonna hear from the land.
The rivers up there
fucking mosquitoes.
It's the worst thing you run into.
Got a pontoon boat.
Somebody that's a different fucking he
mosquitoes
on the leg.
They're pretty bad.
They,
they'll pick you the fuck up man.
Pick you to fuck up and put you
somewhere else.
They got those blanket.
Just Rub Bacon.
Milk
water on the east coast.
I used to,
there was A.
Charles River was near my house in the
east coast and I went into the bushes
one time with this chick and we're
fucking around and we had her pants
down.
We had to stop because we're getting
bits so bad.
It's like our legs were just covered
with welts.
The mosquitoes just swarmed on you.
They smell all that pink,
17 year old flesh.
I just dove on us.
It started fucking.
I was like,
it was brutal.
I remember the next day all my legs
covered in little tiny scabs.
He just got attacked by a swarm.
I still remember some of the worst
nights when that one mosquito would get
into your bedroom and your dad didn't
put on the air,
so it was probably your sleeping and 85
year old weather and you just hear the
one fucking step one and you can
Rudel I rented a house once and nobody
had lived in the house for a couple of
years and uh,
they had left all the water in the pool.
So I got there and the pool was fucking
green man.
I mean green like pea soup.
And I looked in it and I see like these
schools and I go,
what the fuck is that?
Schools have these little tiny bugs
swimming.
I'm talking hundreds of thousands,
hundreds of thousands,
20.
When the guy goes,
oh shit,
I go,
why?
He goes,
those are mosquito larva are going to
look what?
What?
We had a problem.
I go with you,
so when is this going to hatch?
It goes,
this could hatch any day.
Now I'm like,
Holy Shit.
So this has just been providing
mosquitoes to the entire community for
years.
This big pool of mosquitoes,
man.
So this guy had a pump gallons and
gallons and gallons of poisoning.
It took like two weeks to clean that
fucking thing out.
He had to pump the filter and pump all
the chlorine and gallons and gallons of
Korean.
Then drain all the water out because it
was too poisonous and put new water in
it it because you couldn't just drain it
and you have all these fucking bugs
floating around in the water.
I'm talking literally hundreds of pounds
of mosquitoes.
It was crazy.
No,
it's crazy.
We're not all fucking as old as I am,
but what about having to off that shit?
Don't work no more.
Somebody told me about six years ago I
went somewhere and they don't work no
more brothers and for eighties
mosquitoes,
David Galligan the back routes.
Now they don't even push you off.
All fucking come.
Remember when we were kids,
you could like the thing,
you don't like the thing and then you
can hang out and I miss citronella
candle.
No,
the one made by all off was a wave.
It was a circle,
so when it burned at the end,
you knew you had to go in.
That's when you got to go in.
Now those mosquitoes,
that's like nothing.
They're like fucking off.
You're going to put off on you.
They don't even advertise it no more.
I think about it.
What happened off dot these mosquitoes.
Those don't even respect off no more.
It's like off.
That's old bitch.
Don't go out until you got you got it.
Smells like nobody uses off no more.
It's still there because I checked it.
Just people know that shit.
Don't worry.
That'll even if it doesn't work,
it's probably poisonous.
You pour in your pouring something on
your body that makes you unattractive.
We use the spray.
Probably not good for you to fucking
little skin is the biggest organ in your
body when you're spraying stuff.
Says the man with tattoos all over his
fucking talking about.
I got increments.
Kin,
but spraying anything on your skin like
Alexi,
even sunscreen is going to be absorbed.
Those chemicals are going to be
absorbed.
It's used to run behind the.
There used to be a truck that is a
little bit older.
Me,
the truck would drive down the street
with just poison.
Shoot it into there to kill all.
Oh yeah.
I guess like maybe our grandparents,
but the kids used to follow it like an
ice cream truck and just run down the
street behind the smoke.
That's what I do.
There's some guys in my neighborhood,
I don't know what the deal is,
what they're killing,
but they were walking around the other
day with fucking masks on their face
with these white suits on and they had
these little plastic spray jugs and
they're spraying this shit on the side
of the road.
I'm like,
what the fuck could you be spraying in
the road that I want you to spray on the
road while you're wearing a gas mask?
You know,
do you have just an excess amount of
this shit need to kill weeds?
Was somebody getting hayfever?
You know,
come on man.
I mean,
you want to hire somebody to cut it
down,
then you're making new jobs,
but spraying poison on the side of the
road.
Is that really necessarily with who the
fuck says okay to that?
Isn't there laws against that shit?
What are they doing?
You couldn't be bugs much and if they
have to still do it,
they must do.
Well,
I saw them do it,
but what we mean,
what are they doing?
What are they spraying and spraying for
weeds?
I think it's mosquitoes scheme side of
the road and read about you.
You right on the side of the road.
I think that in the middle of the night
it used to just a thing.
Right?
I don't know.
I'd say weeds over bugs.
Weeds.
I don't think it's bugs.
Yeah.
There's no way.
Don't have it or they don't really kill
that many bugs because the problem with
killing bugs,
it's some crazy ecosystem out there,
man.
There's a whole sort of a cycle too.
And if you squash one thing like
mosquitoes or bugs did,
you might fuck up some other part of the
ecosystem along with it.
And my kill birds,
you see the guy,
there's a guy who made an entire
ecosystem in his house and that's how he
keeps spiders and flies away from,
I don't know the exact number.
He has hundreds of different bugs
species that eat each other and he has
perimeters in his house.
It's an entire.
So he leaves a flies but then the
spiders come and make the thing.
But then despite.
Or is it,
I saw it.
I think he has an entire.
That's his bug system and they don't.
And he has perimeter set up and they
don't leave the perimeter.
So by the time you were in his house,
nothing will look man,
if you look at the animals that eat
other animals,
the thing,
but he's got it all figured out.
It sounded supposed to be set up.
So there's a,
there's a,
I guess if you paid attention to it and
you find out what the prey and what
things eat
and what they get from everything.
He knows the whole system.
That's fascinating man.
I want to.
How much effort he has to put into.
It was crazy.
It was like a whole,
like something you'd see at a zoo,
like that's his life's work.
It's like a hip bone connected to the
joint bone.
It's like there's something always
fucking doing,
you know,
somebodies always eating somebody.
Yeah.
That's why I don't have hormones
anymore.
I had the personas are a pain in the ass
man.
First of all,
you have to clean that tank like every
couple of days because they,
they eat massey.
It's exciting when they eat the messy,
but they're only exciting when they're
eating,
when they're eating.
It's crazy to watch them and I would
feed them goldfish and they would go on
a rampage.
It was incredible.
It was a goldfish.
You think you're going to some little
kid who's got an idea and you're going
to fly around the.
You know
what?
I would them.
It traumatized me as a kid.
I used to fish for goldfish.
The goldfish in the New York.
The weirdest thing because you get to my
luggage and river,
which is murky.
You put them into clean water and they
died.
What the fuck?
You been living in that shit?
Water for 10 years.
I bring you home,
I'll give you a love of Goldfish in the
central park.
When I was a kid in central park bench,
I'm just a little fucking thing or that.
Oh,
there were probably part.
Yeah.
You probably like the little paddle
boats and central park and you probably
know those are other goldfish.
Goldfish,
goldfish and go,
you don't want to catch nothing.
None of that fucking Hudson.
I seen a friend of mine either
eels heart one time on the Hudson.
I bet that motherfucker glowed in the
dark when I was a kid when I was a kid.
It was funny because Puerto Rican lived
in the bronx and Brooklyn.
It's so weird how the the nationality
thing goes,
but Puerto Rican big weekend out in the
old days was to go to Jersey.
If you watch cop land,
you catch the black people under the
bridge of salons,
given them a ticket and they're like,
that's the last time we'll come over to
Jersey because that was a big thing.
As bad as people put Jersey,
it's got a little couple of sightseeing
things,
especially like some people rent the car
to go to Jersey on the weekends.
How fucking crazy is that?
Puerto Ricans would drive over the
bridge,
got under the Hudson in that disgusting
murky water.
They will dig up a fucking barbecue pit
that had been there since 1920 and it
was business as usual.
You know,
they pull up with a car and Puerto Rican
is a famous,
you know,
I come out of the car,
tend to a car.
That's no the thing,
it's the shit that was in the car.
The grill,
the couch,
the 12 piece and Mumbo fucking band.
I mean,
they're amazing.
And you go under the Hudson Bridge and
here these people on this disgusting
water is life is.
They're just making the best of what
they had.
They came from the fucking bronx in the
seventies,
which had nothing.
You know,
they just dug the Bronx river out.
Did you read what they found in?
No buildings.
Why?
Like people were throwing buildings and
cars and they're like,
that Nino,
the Hudson,
the,
all that shit is.
So they have destroyed that.
The pollution levels.
I watched the show,
the idea by plastic.
I did not know.
Do you think it's inevitable that if you
get 7 million people living on an island
like Manhattan,
that you have to just put it to do when
you just look at any random stall at a
public restroom that's only 10 people
going in and not giving a shit,
you know,
it's like your animals.
Like,
like no one knows what.
I think guys just getting like a pop
song.
Go.
I'm just going to piss all over the
place.
What the fuck is wrong with people
people's last week.
And Anthony Bourdain?
Yes.
Beautiful City.
How about the garbage?
Yeah.
They don't pick up garbage can imagine
living your life with garbage out.
You know what that smells like after a
week or week,
this fucking weather Japan to Harlem to
play one pocket.
My uh,
my friend Johnny B and Mount Vernon and
Tommy and this dude won.
We all went to Harlem to play,
uh,
some pimps,
pimps would be gambling,
playing pool and so they would spend a
lot of money.
So the word got out,
it was like 125th street in Harlem,
maybe even higher than that.
We got there and there are apparently
some garbage strike and the garbage was
seven feet to eight feet high for a
whole block.
I mean a whole block dude.
It was nuts.
People would just step outside and throw
the garbage on a pile and there was a
rat everywhere.
Every rentable,
because there's bags of food,
there's bags of things that rats can
eat.
I'm talking literally a block of eight
foot high piles of garbage.
It was horrifying,
man.
My friends worked for hunt chemical and
it went to India.
They all got transferred to India and in
the early nineties they came back and
they were telling me stories about how
they don't kill rats there.
You pull up at night with your car,
you know how you see a raccoon or a
fucking cat.
It just be wrapped and your garbage.
You have to sit there for 10 minutes and
let them run out of the fucking garbage
before you get out of the car.
I can't deal with that guy.
He's just going to rap.
They found the bronx.
I know you've seen that.
I saw that fork now and how big the
fucking rat work.
How many were.
They were a mess.
They said there's a lot of them.
The guy looked at me and goes,
he thought it was kids in there.
He thought it was like kids.
They will fuck.
He pulled them out.
They were like a cat.
The back legs.
Cat picks his legs up.
He had it like three feet.
What was the biggest rat I've ever seen
in my life?
It was fucking enormous.
It's body looked like it was almost two
feet long.
His body,
his body was clearly more than a foot
long.
His body easily could have been a foot
and a half,
maybe even two feet long.
It was a big rat and this guy said
there's a lot of them there.
You said there was a lot of them.
That whole.
You know,
it's so weird.
Like I,
I grew up on Adhd for awhile when I came
from Cuba and we would kill rats.
You know,
you chase her.
I hit him with a stick.
Light them on fire,
throw rocks at you,
make sure that motherfucker's dead.
Then I used to spend my summers on 140th
street.
My godmother had three buildings so I
could walk underneath.
I seen a rat under that one time that
his eyes was so fucking big.
His eyes are so fucking big that I was
like,
no,
you know where I've seen a big rap too
at the La Jolla comedy store.
Fucking condo.
I've seen a rat in that motherfucker.
I packed my bags and got back on that
five.
Oh yeah,
I see the big wrap there.
I think they're living in the ocean.
God Damn it.
I can't deal with that.
So fucking durable.
They can compress their body and get to
really small holes to like a big rat can
smush his body and get through a fairly
small fucking hall.
It's really kind of crazy to watch.
That's a fuck is you think guys back in
the day,
like 400,
500 years ago were afraid of rats or
adidas looked at us food like we're
lucky that we don't have to deal with
the rats,
but it just mentally like it.
They're afraid and if you go back like
neanderthal days they were.
They didn't give a fuck about a rat.
Anything small digression.
I live up in the hills too and I have a
privacy fence and you'll see them just
running.
My dogs would try to it and then I'll
jump every time I see one and I'm like,
when you get over that dude,
I used to have them in my.
I had to bring in exterminators.
I used to have them by Anik.
You would hear them.
It was like,
like literally like two dogs fighting up
there.
I would hear like they would screech and
squawk at each other sometimes because
they would be mating.
So I'd hear.
I would hear a scream,
fuck yeah,
in my house.
I hear it in my attic.
It had hire a guy to come in and kill
them all.
How?
It was nuts,
but they weren't that big.
They were regular size,
but you know they're.
They're fucking right.
Wanting in your ceiling,
running a slamming things and fighting
over pussy.
They're screaming and fighting over
posing.
Isn't that weird?
I don't know if you were there,
how they.
A friend of mine called me once,
how they would do arson in the old days
that we get a cage and put myself and
pour gasoline on the mice and the mice
on fire and pulled the thing and the
mice run into the walls and big.
That's the way the your house on fire to
do that.
Fucking insurance scam and new Rach
would go into the walls and burn the
wool.
That's the way that you do old adage.
Brilliant.
That's how you do it.
As long as he had enough rats right now,
fucking places going down because while
they're searing,
they're still going in your walls dying.
So that's starting more fucking things
in your walls.
I mean,
what gasoline be enough?
It has a really dip 'em in there and you
have to dip them in the old days when
everybody was in on it.
The fuck.
Look at Bushwick.
Bill got shot in the fucking head.
Did he?
You didn't hear about this earlier.
Bushwick bill.
We were reading a story.
It's an old story happened in 99.
He told his girlfriend is shoot him in
the head because he wanted to get the
insurance money and they don't know who
did it,
whether he shot himself in the head or
she shot him in the head,
but he got shot in the eye,
so as he alive,
he's alive because somebody send them in
Houston musical.
John Westlink Bush would have been a
long time.
Okay.
Oh,
it's.
I think he's on the cover of one of his
fucking.
We can't be stopped.
I think the Geto boys with the patch
over his eye.
Where it shows.
Is Iowa all fucked up where he shot
himself?
Yeah,
isn't it?
Yeah.
It's on Wendy albums where he's coming
out.
Would that be to shoot you?
So when you were high on everclear?
Apparently
everclear is like some super powerful
alcohol.
First Time I got pulled over,
I was on seven shots of everclear and a
copy of his 16.
Oh Man.
I used to hang out.
I used to work at this movie theater
with all these guys that
were like 18 or 19 and know would go to
this military base and by everclear.
And so,
uh,
they thought it was cool because they
were the ones who first introduced me to
weed and everything.
I have no military,
no,
no.
These guys that hang out with these
older guys and so,
uh,
I would,
they thought it would be funny to like
get me fucked up on it by like a Gimme
shots and I wanted to act like,
oh yeah,
I'm cool.
I can do shots of this.
Not knowing what ever clear was,
I just heard it was like a strong
alcohol.
What is the percentage of alcohol and
everclear?
I wanted to say it was 127 of them
proof.
And then they let you drive?
Well,
no,
they,
uh,
thought I was crashing there,
but I,
I lied to him.
It's like he got the fucking car bitch,
motherfucker
with you when he's dressed us all
alleged by the end.
The coolest thing was though,
is that I got pulled over right down the
street,
like literally like two blocks.
I got pulled over and the cop goes,
dude,
you're wasted.
All right.
Here's the deal.
See this Udl,
which is a like a gas station.
He's like,
you park your car in there,
you sit there.
He's like,
I want you to go inside by a cup of
coffee.
I'm coming back and four hours if you're
not here,
I'm giving you a fucking Dui.
I'm going,
I know where you are.
And everything like that would have been
sort of.
And really you shouldn't go to jail.
He even gets better.
He even gets better as I was like,
he's like,
go in there and get a coffee.
And I'm like,
actually I have no money.
And he goes,
he goes and he gave me money to buy a
cup of coffee.
And then,
uh,
so I sat down
commerce.
There's good cops out there,
man advaclear in Boulder,
Colorado.
There's a Mexican restaurant.
I don't know if it's still there.
It's pupusas.
Yo,
it's on melrose,
melrose,
on the whatever.
The main pro.
You're in boulder.
Go to pupusas.
Fucking tremendous.
But the secret of this place was that
Margarita is,
were made whatever.
Clear.
Quantro wow.
So you were only allowed and then they
asked you to fucking leave and go,
fuck that.
I ain't Queloz three of those and you
just be like this bro.
I think El Coyote,
they allowed to do
that.
And last name,
green limit three Margarita limit bitch
at for lunch.
They had a one margarita limits.
You could have two little ones.
They had little much for a little
champagne wedding things he does that.
They don't tell you what's in it like
that.
They win all the Margarita contest,
you know that like almost every year and
they won't tell you what the secret
ingredient is,
but every time I go there,
if you just get the one on the rocks,
I'll get to and I feel like I just
fucking did.
Ecstasy something.
Yeah.
We need to film this.
We need to film us going to El Coyote
and having some.
Marguerite is,
let's do that.
Boys don't drive.
You don't want the craziest thing.
We're going to hire someone to drive.
We'll get a little caught.
One of the craziest things I've Tequila.
Just kidding.
It depends what mood you're in.
If you drink enough tequila,
bro,
it becomes something different.
Yes.
It becomes a different animal than vodka
or Tequila is a kind of tricky mother.
I don't know if you motherfuckers ever
rate the warm.
I made a mistake one second,
but swapped and ate a warm Tequila.
Makes me,
uh,
I think,
yeah,
there's a difference between Tequila
draw.
It sounds ridiculous.
It does,
but it's true.
And Sheila Drunk whiskey drunk.
Whiskey drunk is more like fucking
aggressive Tequila.
Tequila drunk is more like we've got to
find the vampires.
Oh,
I'm angry.
I'm
angry on Tequila man.
But to Jack Daniels is questionable
choice.
I mean,
you never seen it.
Never been.
You never seen me angry as a drug
dealers.
I think a lot of it that you go into.
So if you think I'm an angry drunk and
it was dangerous and you start drinking
because you're weird reaction.
I'm not an angry drunk though.
I don't believe in that shit entirely.
I feel like if you're an angry person
and you get drunk,
then you become an angry drunk.
If you have some fucking resolved
issues,
then it become an angry drunk because
most of the people are not even ready.
Sing,
angry.
I guess.
It's just crazy.
Like Tequila makes you a fucking like
Robin.
You're a silly drunk.
You become silly when you're drunk
because you're a silly person and it's
for you.
It's you just.
Your inhibitions loosen up and you
become more like.
Like that podcast that we did with burn.
You were fucking hammered and you were
really funny and one of the reasons why
you really funny because you were.
You were giggling and silly because you
went into lose your inhibitions mode
right now.
That was Tequila would have had sex with
Bert
was
crazy.
Like,
well,
let's say I drank a beer.
I've did blow.
I will go home and just want to fuck.
But when you do Tequila,
do blow,
you get old,
creepy,
really like to put a cape on and you
start looking at a chick thinking about
maybe she could do a somersault and land
on my face.
You know,
like you just got spirits in it to kill
this spirit.
Something I get fucking creepy on
Tequila.
Willing be.
Well,
it's made out of a plant.
You know,
there's something in your toes.
Really.
Yeah.
Get it would blow you.
Blow the thing.
Tequila gets.
It becomes a difference.
It's such a fine dance though,
of having too much Tequila where your
Dick don't work.
It's like,
this is fucking.
You got to get just enough so that
you're crazy,
but you have enough food in you and
you've taken your vitamins so you'd.
Dick still works because if you're like
unhealthy and you get drug off Tequila,
good luck with your Dick.
Good luck.
You just,
you just put yourself in a great
position.
You got your ready for wild,
crazy times.
Everyone's game.
Oh,
we'll look at your deck.
Also.
Sad.
Have you ever had from booze guy from
booth Redman,
from Bulls you've had?
You haven't,
no,
but you throw that in the powder.
In the old days you dead,
it shrinks into the nut sack.
That is amazing when you want to fuck.
But there ain't nothing there.
Nothing there.
It's deep,
deep,
deep in the nut sack and they got to
keep sucking and they got a nice Dick.
But
like they,
it starts off like this,
like they got hold it fucking bottom of
it and then it gets bigger and bigger
and then you think about doing a line.
It goes back in the cocoon with a
fucking nightmare doing that shit.
You want to eat that?
But then you're like,
okay,
I'll just eat your pussy like you just
fucking all the I had in my mind.
Fuck it.
I'll just eat your fucking.
The most embarrassing ones that I've
ever had was when I was drunk and I
started the fuck and then as I was
fucking,
the alcohol really kicked in and then I
completely lost my boner so it lost it
while I was already having sex.
So it's like for the girl,
it's like a terrible feeling.
I just puked once dude.
To have been,
have a hard Dick,
put it inside you and then in life you
don't even keep them interested enough
to keep the hard on like,
and then it was just pathetic.
I just felt like I was trying not to act
like you were and then you reach down
buyer to almost like a whisper and I
turned my head and threw up and tried to
like do it like a barf bag where I kinda
kept that contained in my back.
And then she was like,
did you just throw up my computer?
Yeah,
you tried?
Yeah.
You ever throw up and you don't give a
fuck.
You fuck that.
Look the other way.
I'm still going to give you a stabbing.
She don't give a fuck.
And that smell is.
And you're like,
Oh,
is that hillary?
And they say to me,
kiss me.
I'll kiss you full shoot this fucking
loaded that dead snatch and alcoholic as
Audi.
Dirty fuck.
Because once Johann Johann de,
that's what happens is a fucking date
written on dumping them.
This bitch literally go down.
You know we don't condone it,
but that's what happens that date.
You just got to catch yourself with.
The worst is when some chick pukes in
your car like language Speaker Grill,
and you want to beat the fuck.
Fuck.
That's the worse.
Your car smells like Puke.
For 11 months.
I was in my car with a toothpick.
Picking out each little hole in my
speaker grill.
Just pulling out red bull.
Yeah.
Well listen man,
I had a girl puke in my car back in the
fucking eighties and they didn't have
good cleaner.
You couldn't clean the car out.
They didn't have all that good
stuff back then.
You basically went and used that shitty
ass vacuum would always catch on the
carbon go.
Remember it would catch on the carpet
and you cannot fucking Donald.
I go to the carwash.
You tried to do the entire car with
twenty five cents.
It was like the fastest I've ever moved
to my town.
You would have to go to one of those
full service car washes and get done the
shampoo your shit,
but you don't want to do that because
those monkeys,
whether shampoo and your shit,
they get fucking suds in your wiring and
then your fucking car shorts out.
You know,
I didn't want to do that.
I knew those dudes.
I worked at a car wash.
So when I thought about getting my car
washed,
I'm like,
I'm not going to bring it to these
fucking guys.
These guy's gonna.
They let me drive a porsche.
Okay.
I didn't even know how to drive a stick.
I hadn't zero stick knowledge and I got
into fucking Porsche.
That's how the first car I ever drove
stick was a porsche at a fucking,
at a car wash.
I don't even know what I was doing when
he told me I go,
how do I drive it?
He goes,
just push the clutch in,
put,
put it in gear and then slowly let your
foot off the gas.
So I come out of this car washes,
16 year old faced kid driving a porsche,
you know?
And the guy said,
why did you drive it if you didn't know
how to do it?
I'm like,
why?
They let me drive it.
I didn't have anything to say to him.
I'm just
like,
I'm sorry.
They told me to drive it.
The Guy told me I would know how to
drive stick,
stick the thing in gear and it'd be no
problem.
They didn't give a fuck.
I got busted last week washing my car
and coin Burbank Boulevard.
Brian.
There's a little car wash.
Then I usually go in there and just hit
it.
But I had to fucking pee dog.
I just had a piece while I was washing
the car.
Nobody was watching you know me bro.
Out per a phone booth.
I got a really A.
I'll pull over and make believe.
Now nobody has phone booths no more.
But in the old days I make believe I'm
on the phone.
Take my pick up.
Even as traffic is driving by it,
they don't think you're pissing.
I'm pissing on the fucking thing.
You just can't do it in the window.
Can steam comes out there,
bust you in the fucking winter?
So Damn,
washing my car,
it's 9:15 in the morning,
I gotTa pee bad and I said,
fuck,
I'm going to take my dick out ready?
And I took my dick out.
I'm old and I'm watching the car and I
just went into this fucking thought and
next thing you know,
I look over and the owner,
the thing was right there.
He was like,
are you fucking serious?
Like a dog?
I had to fucking pee and it's going into
a total.
He was doing me a favor,
put the hose down and get the fuck outta
here.
He drew me the fuck out.
He goes,
I'll call the fucking police.
I watched a guy,
I didn't say anything.
He told the guy who comes to my house
and uh,
it's actually what it's called,
the poop Butler because I travel it,
but he picks up poop basically from your
dog for,
for my two dogs.
And I didn't clarify that.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I know I had,
I paid a service.
Are you serious?
Yeah,
it's a service.
It's the best thing that I could ever do
because.
Or I'd have five days of shit to pick
up.
So my,
so he was peeing like a big gold thing
and I'm like,
is that guy peeing?
And he's a little creepy because they
think he's always steering into try to
see my wife,
like walk around or something,
who wouldn't?
But I look and I see him with now he's
got a big gold thing that he just pissed
in front of my house.
So I'm watching him because he doesn't
want to move so I can pull in.
I'm like,
where's it gonna throw that.
If he throws that into my bushes,
I'm going to be pissed.
Watch to my neighbors and just acts like
he's,
you know,
takes the big gulp,
throws his piss onto my neighbor's yard
and then leave.
That just happened.
I.
So now I'm like,
well,
it's such a good service and there's no
other competition.
So if I,
if I call and say,
hey,
tell them not to throw piss on my
neighbor's yard,
that then what happens?
And I got to pick up poop.
So it was a weird sacrifice.
I'm well,
is this a company where the guy that
owns the company or is this an employee?
Hold on,
hold on.
The p thing is just one thing.
This looking at your wife,
you just glossed over.
Why don't you tell us a little bit more?
What is.
What is the reason for that?
Well,
we don't.
because if you stare at and he comes
early in the morning,
you can get a glimpse at 9:00 AM of
maybe her popping up.
Like why?
Why are you saying that?
Did he do that?
We,
she gets that feeling that he is,
but we've never actually caught.
She's like,
I think he stares.
I think he,
you know,
my wife doesn't sound like that once
she.
Why does she think stairs?
No evidence.
Just a guess.
Just thinking in that you'll see him
walk by.
So she's like,
was he just stay?
You don't,
we don't know.
We should maybe just videotape it.
Wants to set up a camera and see if he
hangs out or if he pisses in my backyard
yard.
My whole house has cameras.
I
am alerted whenever somebody enters each
one of my rooms on my iphone,
somebody crazy bitches,
bro.
You to keep your shit locked out and
black wizards attack me.
Be careful.
Black was it the guy robbed him,
put a fake ones,
fake beard on like a wizard and he had a
hood on.
It was like a black wizard say did he
fucking made magic and made your money
disappeared of my flat flashback when
I'm at JC penny's and I see a black
Santa Claus at the mall or something.
And when was the last time you've ever
seen a black Santa Claus at the mall?
Bron.
I've.
I've seen black Santa clauses.
He never seen black.
I've never,
never seen Santa Claus.
I mean I've seen one on TV.
Oh No.
I've seen in real life there was black
Santa clauses.
There was William Northland Mall where,
which mostly blacks.
I think that's why that has kind of suck
for being a black kid.
I told you that when went to to a planet
of the apes in an all black movie
theater in Philly that I really started
thinking about what it must be like to
have every fucking movie that they were
preview was all these white people,
white people,
White.
Everything is white problem,
white movie,
White Silliness,
and I'm like,
wow,
let's say you gotta be fucking weird as
Shit,
man.
The only superhero he got was blade
fucker for a couple of years.
It really was that movies back to the
boat.
First will be is there's a lot of black
comics who dress up like chicks.
Like that's the one part.
Like why that so,
so funny.
Yeah.
You know Chappelle talk about that.
Dave Chappelle had like a.
He was on like one of those shows like
inside the actor's studio,
we just like what?
What is it that when a black man becomes
really famous,
they want to make them dress as a woman
and they showed.
They showed all these pictures of
Richard Pryor doing it and all these
different comics doing it all throughout
history.
Martin Lawrence doing it,
Jamie Foxx doing it and like,
wow.
Yeah,
that is weird.
Why do all these prayer is what?
What is that?
Why?
Why is it like.
Was it flip Wilson the first flip
bullshit.
Fuck.
Is that about.
What does that.
That funny though.
I know it's,
to me it's got to be like the ultimate,
like a black man trying to be as like an
aggressive towards women as possible.
What's the most,
the most unimpressive thing you can be
is be a woman.
Dress up like a woman.
Oh God.
What you talking about?
Like that's not a guy trying to get some
pussy.
It's like the complete polar opposite of
what white people are afraid of in a
black guy.
Well,
white people are afraid of in a black
guy is a fucking big muscular black man
with a giant Black Dick.
Some big football player,
Nfl Stud athlete that wants to fuck your
woman.
So what is the polar opposite of that?
What's a black man being all silly and
address dressing like a woman?
Well,
he's not even trying to get some,
get any pussy.
Look at him because he had lipstick on
and makeup and shit.
He makes me relax,
you know?
He's like,
well,
what'd you say?
That's not a black eye trying to get
laid at all.
I think that's what it is.
I'm going to check.
It's white.
People are of black dicks
so forces these black people to try it.
A little bit of a black planet bitches.
That's right.
I get one point.
If it's a black dude,
I just can't.
What's wrong with you?
Because he doesn't have a black dick and
somebody can get into the fantasy.
It's nothing about me being raised.
This is.
I think it's gay.
If you watch a black guy fucking a white
chick if you're a white guy because.
Because now you can't even pretend that
to you.
See,
if you're a white guy,
you can pretend that your desk,
you could beat off and watch a girl give
head and pretend that she's given you 10
shit.
Man,
I can't.
I'm not.
I know I'm looking at a laptop.
What I like to see though is like a
fucking black check.
Like really a black chick or black dude
really pounding a little white chick.
I think that's because you know it's not
fake.
That's what you want.
No,
no.
Because you know deep.
You want that power.
You know what that dominant do you want
him to see a real fucking hard fucking.
You don't want to see if making love.
Okay,
burn.
I love listening.
I was just trying to make a joke.
Dude.
I don't really believe that there's
something gay about watching black
dicks.
I was trying to go in a little comedy
rap videos.
So if you want to go on with your little
freak shit and talking about like
watching a girl get fucked in a way that
you're not capable of and that's what
really turns you on.
Or you go for it buddy.
You're like legit trying to take.
I do like bulge of.
What the fuck is that about?
Getting head pretend to get my dick
sucked.
You can print.
You liked the whole thing of look,
I listened.
Some girls are good at sucking Nixon.
It's awesome.
I like to see a woman snack for a little
while,
but I really liked the art of seeing the
chick suck a dick.
I'm going to be honest.
Why do.
Why is it shocking?
Let me explain something to you.
Ah,
yeah.
You print a tenants your Dick.
That's why you don't want to watch black
ones.
I was in county jail and I've never
looked at a black cock.
No.
Do I want to see one?
When I popped on that Kim Kardashian and
tape and I seem a little odd.
Jay's fucking Dick.
Stop.
I turned that mother fuck off.
Understand me and I remember telling my
buddy,
I'm not fucking.
He was like,
you're prejudice,
prejudice a black Dick.
I'm just prejudice a dick.
That black one was like fucking jaws.
It didn't stop fucking stop,
but even had the jaws music.
I thought that that was the worst thing
I ever seen him.
Like I looked at that tape to see how
hot she was and I hit it off from the
fear like I had flunked.
It was his dick harass her.
Awesome.
She got fucked.
She got.
I only watched it,
but what she goes,
I want to come again as you sweat and
I'm like,
this is a fucking pig.
This chick is a fucking amazing how far
she's come with that and we don't give a
fuck.
I shit got fucked really hard.
People loved it.
You got it.
It will.
It has to be accidental.
You can't put it out yourself.
You can't make a video and go hears me
fucking because no porn star is ever
reached the status of Kim Kardashian.
She's done is accidentally have it and
put it out and that's why she's about to
start making God.
But that's,
that's how she got 50 million already.
She got,
she got into a back door.
She did something amazing guys,
but she did something amazing.
Can we pay for porn?
We paid the see a black guy fucking a
white chick chick,
black guy.
She fucked that mother fucker out of
clear love or whatever the fuck it was.
Oh,
she fucked his brains out.
It wasn't like pulling.
That's why it shocked [inaudible] right?
Boys and girls,
it was like,
you know when you do pull,
you show up at one.
This gave us something different and
dog,
whatever the gave gave us.
I told Joe,
you know,
we wake up in the morning where like,
where are we doing a set plan that bitch
wakes up and says,
how am I gonna?
How am I going to be the number one
trending topic on yahoo and Google and
if you look at Google and Yahoo,
she's number one three days a fucking
week.
I don't know what the fuck she does,
but she's a genius.
Whatever she did because she can't.
She's a genius.
Attention whore.
Yeah.
She.
What she is is the Michael Jordan of
attention horse
and now she's dating a super tall guy
with probably the biggest dick.
Oh.
And he's worthless.
That sees that fucking monster alive.
Then they just told her the other day
that she was married before he.
He's like,
really?
Shoot that fucking Momma thinks he's the
first one that fucked up.
You don't know that she's been
swallowing pickup and fucking calabasas.
She was 15.
Well,
he's probably just excited to be with
someone famous public guy.
What does he do?
He plays basketball.
He looks like he plays basketball so you
play huge and like his dick was just
like curl up in her.
But like a snail or something,
movies focused on,
you know,
they let that a max hardcore guy out of
jail.
Speaking of like levels of shit if you
don't know who he is.
He's a guy who got arrested in Florida
because Florida has some crazy laws were
like if you ship things to their car,
they have like very strict ideas of
what's offensive and what is uh,
what's the,
what's the word?
Obscenity,
you know.
And this is what the guy was arrested
for because the porn was obscene.
He's got some hardcore shit where he
pisses and girl's ass holes,
holes their asshole open sticks a straw
in it and makes them drink the piss out
of their asshole.
Yeah,
I mean he goes deep for that fucking
giving me me want to Luci who?
What's that crazy guy that my buddy sent
me a link and that like I thought it was
okay.
Joe,
who's the Italian guy to fuck bitches.
That's my.
Goes about Kupong.
Fuck that shit.
You let her keep her ass.
He fucking fuck him.
And he asked to make some fucking suck
his dick while they're eating a slice of
pizza.
That's gangster right there.
He's one of the first to fucking life
from the seventies.
He's been.
He's got sideburns and one video I seen
that says drop it out.
That said something
gay about being into a male porn star.
Like what do you got?
What's the recent Rocco?
So Freddy elected with that guy fucks
something.
Something.
There's something real weird about like
being a fan of an actual break.
I've depor and trying to deepen my life
a little bit.
Really keep trying to cut it back.
Only because it just you as a comic,
you go back and you watch it.
My brain now I watched 30 and then that
damn
search.
I'll go wonder if there's Asian girls
with black socks who work at starbucks.
Click,
click,
Bam.
Oh look at that.
Oh,
I wonder if they.
And then you just find yourself.
How many did I watch?
I watch at maybe 10,
15 second increments and the my brain
moves onto the next thing,
some done a porn add.
I'm done for a little bit,
for a little bit and people write
comments about porn and then in urban
environments I've ever been spanked or
any
requirements about porn when he's
talking about on the process and it'll
have comments about the porn and I just
get pissed at the people going,
oh,
I would,
I would fuck away better than this guy.
Her face is a bit.
Just be happier watching porn.
Like people are so desensitized now.
Upset.
Yeah.
I get mad at the kids are
born at all.
You only saw that I've been on is the
one my buddy linked me to for the Kim
Kardashian because I looked on my own
and couldn't find that on my credit
card.
And I would tell Brian and Brian's like,
I got freedom.
I don't know about the computer.
And I'd been on Youporn youporn.
You know,
I've told it a thousand times the chicks
of filthy,
but you know,
they,
they have dirty feet and they suck Dick
and all that dumb shit.
But tell you what,
the fucking pisses me off by you for
that.
They live.
You don't like hot Asian chicken.
It's a fucking Mexicans don't get your
nationality straight.
That fucking pisses fuck around with
you.
I'm in the mood to see a nice little
Chinky will show that little fucking
hairy monkey.
And they show a Mexican from fucking no
central.
Sure.
It's a Mexican bitch.
Nah,
the Thai ones are Brown.
I got those brown little men,
maybe Indian,
Asian and he's a fucking real dark.
Like those Asian media,
right?
They have like the edge of roast beef,
like it's really dark and it could be
yellow,
like the skin is like a beige,
but they're fucking noodles.
Nipples.
That doesn't bother you.
A dark doesn't bother you,
does it?
No,
I like that.
You scratch got the little light soy
sauce that comes to the green container.
Not The red one.
Less sodium.
You know what I'm saying?
I like a chick at either thing I did a
couple of weeks ago.
Shoot guys,
this Asian was so fucking hot,
but she had that soy sauce thing going
that she was real Chinese from San
Francisco.
His speech was bad and I could tell she
was a dirty freak.
I just couldn't tell.
I could just smell it.
Look at her.
I could tell.
Yeah,
you could just tell she was flirty.
You could just tell.
She sat one time and I could see her
phone.
Once I see that done,
that's it.
I can tell they're filthy animals.
That's just a.
You could close them,
but I ain't got nothing to offer.
I got nothing.
She's 22.
Am I going to give her drama?
I can't deal with that shit.
You need big victim shit.
Shit.
Take my hand.
And Mr.
John heffrons stealing bitches out there
out in the wild.
So to hear about the UFC.
They just made Alistair overeem versus
Brock Lesnar December 30th at the mgm in
Vegas at
a five round fight.
He's not going to show up when you talk
crazy.
You're not be Talkin Shit.
Why are they showing up?
Why do you say he's not showing that?
The berkey locis is making a comeback.
If diverticulitis,
he had surgery.
Apparently they think that sees cured
one percent.
They
fixed it because the the area that he
kept having a reoccurring diverticulitis
area,
they just cut that area out and you
know,
they think he's 100 percent,
but they left the central nervous system
and it's still fucking reflecting.
The shots came,
gave him fill the fucking head.
It's still spreads those testicles out
of body and that gives them the
diverticulitis all over again.
Diverticulitis,
whatever the fuck it is,
it doesn't matter.
We'll make some guys got balls if he.
He just,
he think about what he's done just to go
from pro wrestling with no striking
experience whatsoever.
Enter into mixed martial arts right into
the thick and the game.
First fucking fight in the UFC.
Takes on Frank Mir who a former UFC
heavyweight champion gets knee barred.
You know,
second fight I believe you took on Randy
Coture,
right?
Who is it?
No,
Keith haring that he took on Randy
coture.
I mean,
dude,
but brock Lesnar is a bad mother fucker
can help.
We might not be able to beat Cain
Velasquez,
but brock Lesnar is a bad motherfucker.
Beat heath heights,
whatever his name is.
He's herring out of the business.
Well,
that's not necessarily what he's
hearing.
He had a lot of fights,
man.
Yeah,
but you had a lot of.
but he was at a crossroads in his own
life.
Nothing bad.
I'm just saying we went to that fight.
You're right there.
When he punched him,
he did the fucking somersault.
Yeah.
I just think it's a little
disrespectful.
People say that before that retired
heath herring routine.
He's hiring retired three retired.
He was.
I talked to heath herring recently.
He's in fine shape.
I saw him in Vegas.
He's not.
There's nothing wrong with him.
Like you look in his eyes.
He's 100 percent there.
He looks good.
He looks healthy.
You know he's had some tough fights and
they fought cro.
Cop and he fought fade or any fun
Noguera he did.
He did.
He fight fader.
Can I just make that up and I believe he
fought fader.
I may look it up,
I don't know,
I forget he just never fought a guy,
but I think he started doing
a bunch of other stuff.
It's hard,
man.
Those for,
for guys who aren't a name,
it's fucking hard,
you know,
it's hard to make real money,
because you got to be putting asses in
the seats so it's,
you know,
you got to beat someone big and when it
came to beating the big guys,
he came real close with Nogueira and his
UFC fight.
He fucking head kicked him and dropped
him.
No girl look done and he turned,
didn't finish him off.
He had a chance,
but he didn't finish them on as a reason
for that dope.
No Garrett's toughest fucked.
But he was hurt.
Keith haring a left.
Oh,
was he the first fight in the UFC was
going Jayco Brian?
Yes.
When he was hurt,
he had a depot Garrett.
Right.
He knocked him down and he didn't know
Jacob.
Brian out wrestled them and he just had
a really fucked up knee and he came up
to me and talk to me about it afterwards
because he was like,
you know,
hey,
listen to commentary.
You always very supportive,
but what the fuck?
I was like,
dude,
you got to watch the fight.
I mean you just took you down at will
and it's like my knee was torn.
I had to take the fight
and he just decided to just fucking be a
tough guy and fight anyway and he
thought he could win.
He's like,
I can catch this guy,
and he just couldn't.
Couldn't get it going man.
Having a knee tear and then trying to
fight a guy like Jacob Brian,
a fucking professional mixed martial
arts fighter in the UFC.
She has Jacob.
Brian,
I'll buy a man.
A boy,
a boy.
A Matt Hughes Against Josh Koscheck.
Is it signed?
It's signed.
It's on wikipedia was.
Well,
I know that.
I'll find out for cute look we're
telling him,
but I think I saw linkedin said they're
waiting.
They're waiting to go.
It was just cool with everybody.
Fucking creepy fight for,
for use because it's a totally different
kind of trained for Diego.
Sanchez is not nearly as dangerous on
the feet as cost check is at least
theoretically because Diego Sanchez will
swore on motherfucker.
He can be very dangerous on his feet,
but the idea was that diego would not be
able to out wrestle.
Matt.
Matt's a big welterweight dig.
It was a fairly small welterweight and
also encaustic steps in who's a really
fucking good wrestler and is a big
welterweight and has been thinking about
fighting at one 85 and was actually
campaigning to try to fight in the San
Jose UFC in November.
So here you got a guy who's a,
a guy who can fight it,
one 85.
He's big.
You know Diego can't fight it.
One 85.
I mean he did.
He did on the ultimate fighter,
but I mean competitively in the UFC he's
this physical frame in my opinion is too
small.
He could do it and you can beat a lot of
guys just by hustling them and
outworking him,
but his best way is probably like one
slash 65.
But Josh Koscheck and carry one 85.
He's a strong character.
He's got,
you know,
he's got a good frame.
He's a tough dude.
He's a serious fucking wrestler and you
know,
and he's dangerous on his feet.
Man,
he's got big power in that right hand.
So it's a totally different fight for
Matt Hughes with three weeks notice.
What do you think the shelf life,
a shelf life is getting smaller,
smaller from a fighter,
like where you have five,
let's say from the time you start
sprinting,
I,
you get a big fight and then why you're
taking him a lot.
He's getting smaller or will eventually
be lasts longer.
What are you talking about?
The shelf life of?
Do you mean how many fights you can
have?
Yeah,
before you start to deteriorate.
Yeah.
It depends on your style.
You know,
some guy,
the other guys go with that really good.
Three year run and then physically
something has gotten like machita.
Here's a perfect example.
Garlic machida takes very little damage.
So garlic machita,
he'll run for longer than a garlic
vander.
And who's got this wild attacking style?
You know,
and it's maybe not vandalize a bad
motherfucker,
you know what I mean?
Vandelay has been stopped a few times
now,
but it's because of annually style
randomly played it safe.
You know,
you saw like in the Michael bisping
fight,
he's still there.
You know what I mean?
Maybe his chin isn't as good as it was
back in the day,
but the truth is that back in the day he
got dropped a bunch of times too.
He would come and wild and reckless.
Dan Henderson dropped them.
A lot of people dropped him before Dan
Henderson knocked him out and their
second fight,
Dan Henderson dropped him and had him
fucked up in their first fight.
He closed his eye.
His eye was like one big giant fucking
baboons.
Vagina.
It was,
it was bad man.
So vandelay has always been in there
with guys that uh,
you know,
that have put them in danger,
uh,
dropped him or heard him.
Mark Hunt dropped him.
But when he got in there against real
good strikers,
that's when he had real problems.
That's why cro cop fucked him up.
If you go back to watch that fight in
pride,
man,
he,
he beat cro cop in their first fight,
or maybe it was a draw I think because
they had weird rules like if you only go
to the ground for like 30,
but
vandelay took a lot of hard fucking
kicks to the body.
That was when cro cop was in his prime
cro.
Cop didn't have a,
a sprawl yet though he wasn't confident
enough with his take down defense to
have a full mma fight,
but by the time they fought,
the second time man that was cro cop in
his prime,
that was the heavyweight Grand Prix and
he fucking head kicked vandelay into
another universe.
Man.
That was when cro cop was the best.
So vandelay without wild styles always
had a problem with guys like that.
You know,
bro,
I mean,
but he's awesome though.
Talking about fighters here,
you're as much of a fan of his.
Even more than I am.
Vandelay fighting carried.
Yeah.
Find my huge vandelay fan.
Longevity now is what you make.
Look at the guidance.
Joe Rogan turned me onto that.
I met,
I had the honor of meeting and talking
to him and he just fought a fight.
Bernard Hopkins fought the fight of his
fucking life and he fought it and it was
customed to him.
I'm 46,
Bro.
I'm not going to get into a band with no
body,
but I'm going to throw punches,
get the fuck out of there.
I'm like,
well,
actually,
this,
this fight was very different than the
first fight.
This fight.
He actually got in and mixed it up with
this guy and he took it out of his game.
You know,
whatever they do,
it's what they take care of,
how smart they are.
GSP is fucking genius.
He takes care of himself at all.
Well,
you know what he is,
he's honest,
he's honest about what's at risk.
There's a lot of guys who aren't honest
about what's at risk,
you know,
and that's one of the things why he says
he won't fight a friend.
You know,
he talked about it,
that I could do this if on top of them
and I see an elbow again,
I deliver it and give cerebral damage.
You know he's,
but he's right.
He feels he knows what the fuck he's
doing because he's had it done to him.
Man.
When Matt Serra mounted him and was
dropping bombs on them and Matt,
Sarah can fucking punch.
Let me tell you something.
That little guineas got bricks in it.
He's got bricks in his gloves.
I never seen anybody that Matt Serra
didn't.
He punched clean that didn't get put on
Queer Street.
He hit fucking hard,
you know.
So when he clipped George in that fight,
you could tell George was like,
oh shit.
Like he,
he can tell his functioning,
drop,
like he knows what it's like to get
really clipped and you know,
he doesn't want that to happen.
And he's a very fucking smart dude.
He's completely honest and aware about
the entire game.
That's one of the reasons why he's so
good.
He'll tell you exactly how he feels.
I am nervous.
This is a very important fight for me.
This a fucking champ,
one of the best pound for pound fighters
in the world and he's nervous and he's
talking about being nervous.
Then he gets in there and just fucking
shines,
gets in there and just
lights.
You both know and you and you.
The day you stop getting nervous before
you go on stage is the day you just go
home.
No.
The worst thing you do with George St
Pierre Man is talk some shit to Bj Penn
when Bj was talking about that shit man.
You could see the determination grow and
George's eyes and George is a
disciplined motherfucker and one of the
things about guys that are truly,
truly disciplined and really in amazing
condition like,
like Nick Diaz as well,
is that these guys know that they can
push a pace that most people will drown
under so they'll fucking force it
because they know you might be talented,
you might be talented,
but maybe you didn't get up early
enough.
Maybe you didn't sleep enough.
Maybe you didn't eat the right foods.
Maybe you didn't take the right
vitamins.
Maybe you didn't fucking put in 100
percent and stack your training
correctly and have a professional,
a physical trainer working with you,
monitoring your heartbeat will.
George does or he knows he can run you
out into the middle of the fucking ocean
bitch,
and that's what he did with Bj man.
He just put him in,
put him in a position where he forced
them to work real hard from the
beginning,
tired his muscles out and started taking
him down and beating the fuck out of
them and the way he did it was genius
man,
and the way he did it was fueled by that
determination that was brought on by
that shit talking.
I thought he'd did it.
The fucking Katya.
Katya kind of wore a monocle for a
fucking year and he might don't walk in
that room with a fucking Monaco.
He check out of that with the Jack the
fuck.
Not Ten Times 30 times.
If I fucked it up,
I'm going to keep punching because I'm
going to fuck it up again.
Every time you look in the mirror and
blink motherfucking comes under GSP,
a simple.
I went to this thing the more to
professional Moitai league MLP or MPL
and it was in Long Beach last weekend
and I got to see really high level
kickboxing like live in person as a
fucking rare man.
It's rare that you get a card like this
bull,
a cow bull count,
a tie guy with a 198 victories.
He's not even 3,198 victories find every
other week.
Oh,
he's in Thailand,
man.
They fight them young.
They fight them when they're little
teenagers.
13 and 14,
15 sec documents.
The only guy,
I think he's a less than 20 losses and
198 fucking victories and he let this
dude up.
Apparently this dude was from Canada I
believe,
and he was talking all kinds of shit and
pushed them at the weigh ins and the
ties are very respectful,
like they don't do that kind of shit.
They they like,
they have this dance.
They do rather why crew in the middle of
the ring before and they did all this
too.
They played the music and these guys did
their dance and they went through their
thing,
but when,
when fucking,
when Booyah cow did it,
he was doing his dance to the guy like
got like right in the guy's face.
Does that pushed him at the weigh ins?
It was bad ass man.
He was like a,
it was like a movie fight.
Like he got in the guy's face and was
doing like pooling arrows and stomping
on the ground and doing his little dance
and the dude didn't know whether he
should give grounds.
And the dude was like backed up in the
corner while blue car was standing in
front of him doing this little dance and
then the fight started and dude came out
strong.
He came out trying to blast but bookout
198 fights.
He's so calm and I need you start
chopping with those kicks and you feel
the fucking leg kick over.
And we were in the front row and you
could just feel that.
Think of that fucking shit.
Oh,
and you could slowly see his legs
starting to give out.
And then he was going high with them and
just beating his ass,
flying Needham Front kicked him,
finally front kicked him and knocked him
down and the referee said,
that's enough.
That's enough.
The referees saved them because let me
tell you something,
they hit boycott
was just starting to break the guy down.
They were in the fourth round and the
guy was just starting to stumble and
fall apart.
And he kept hitting those fucking lazy,
whack,
whack.
It was crazy to watch live,
man.
It's awesome.
And you see that level of stand up and
it's like the difference between cost
check and George St Pierre in that
fight.
Cash check is a very.
He's a very good athlete.
He's got power and his punches,
if he hits you,
you're really fucked.
But in,
at least in competition,
he has never shown to be a really
technical striker.
You know,
he's been caught by Paulo,
Tiago.
He's a very tough guy,
but you know,
don't get me wrong,
but he's not like a guy like blue cow.
You know,
there's a certain level of striking
where a guy gets to where they're like
always safe and they're just lighten you
up.
They find your timing.
It's like when Anderson did the Chanel
Okami,
he finds your timing and then he safe
man,
you're in a fistfight and he's not.
How about that?
How about you're just a fucking target
and he's standing right in front of you
and bang,
Bang,
just firing off on,
you know,
and when you see that happen man,
and you see a guy figured out another
guy's timing like that,
man,
that's,
that's a,
that's a wild shit to see.
And there's guys that can do that to
George.
There's guys the strikers that could do
that to George and a straight kickboxing
match,
but just can only do it when they find
out that takedown.
No,
they can't.
They get scared of that takedown and
then they can't pull the trigger.
And that's what happens because George
hits you with that power double that
comes straight from fucking Mars.
He pushes off that ground and covers
distance in a way.
You can't believe this guy can move that
fast.
For a white dude.
How is this dude moving?
So fucking fast.
Fucking girl.
Have a baby.
Just let them move back just a little
more.
Just Bro.
Just stay back there dude.
Do your little gymnastics in your mind.
So is that boy gets released.
I want your rather tackle that we'd take
down.
Oh Guy like GSP.
You could probably do that.
And
back then.
Coverage.
No coverage.
Just leave them for now.
For today.
We're going to next year and watch what
he fucking does.
Then full.
You ever see him jump those hurdles,
but I was watching them on Google this
morning doing gymnastics.
I'm tempted to go a look place on
Vermont.
Enjoy it for the month and walk on my
hands like a mobile.
That's how good that gymnastics shit is
for you.
And he's taking it.
He's so smart.
Dude.
Georgia.
So openminded you know he's so he'll,
he'll,
he'll try ballet.
If someone tells them valley and make
them a better.
I am to do ballet.
Fucking step in there.
The rest with your belay.
It doesn't give a fuck.
He will fucking do it,
man.
He,
he's,
he's got an open mind.
Me,
he actually asked me to teach them some
shit,
you know,
to go to the commentator of the UFC and
so you know,
this,
show me how to do it.
That's the most people would just go,
what the fuck?
You're the talker guy.
You do the talking now.
But Doug did when I taught him how to
throw the spinning back kick correctly
when we're training,
so it's completely openminded has no
ego.
It just wants to learn.
Just on our level.
When you talk to other comics and you
always have like a new guy go,
do you have any advice and you to tell
them,
you go,
oh yeah,
no,
I don't do that.
I don't know what's your.
And and you go,
really?
Really?
Yeah.
Got it off.
I'll listen to anybody.
Man.
Louis C,
k came up to me once after one of my
sons and gave me all these notes that he
wrote down while I was on set.
I'm like,
this is the fucking coolest thing ever.
I had a King Kong bed.
He was like,
what of King Kong on a wife,
a wife,
and he's given me ideas.
I was just thinking this while you're up
there like,
fuck yeah man,
give me advice.
We you,
you accept tags.
I've seen you.
We like all the time.
All the time people come up to you and
say,
Hey John,
I love that bit.
Have you ever thought about this?
And you're like,
oh yeah.
It's funny how many guys don't do.
I mean,
I'll even take.
I had some guy wants him to go.
You talk too fast during this particular
thing,
just slow down and people.
And then the very next show,
slow down,
got laughs.
You're like,
oh shit.
I didn't even see it from that point of
view.
Dude.
Taglines are a gift.
You know,
when a friend gives you a tagline,
like,
here's the tagline that Kevin James
wrote for me when,
uh,
you know why I was doing that?
Anna Nicole Smith bit where like,
it's time Kevin James wrote for Rim job.
Kevin James wrote that because I was
already like,
looked at ask.
You don't get that.
Oh,
he's had this bit about him dying,
you know,
about Anna Nicole Smith's husband forced
her and Kevin and I were just riffing on
it and Kevin came up with it's time for
a real job and I became like one of the
big punchlines in there and I would say
it and it was cool because I would say
it on stage.
I would think of him like,
oh my friend hooked me up with a good
solid laughing here because a lot of
times you do this not to the same bit,
but you're just so close to it that you
don't see it from that little bit of an
angular.
So you're,
you're taking.
It's right there.
If we're both going to write a joke
about anything,
whether we were both going to write a
joke about coffee,
you would come from one place and I
would come from another.
Even though we're both comics and we
both would see like some obvious points,
you know,
like,
like there was a joke that I did that I
found out that Ellen Degeneres had done
a joke just like it years before.
And I had never seen Elon do it,
but the premise is really obvious.
And the premise was about penguins being
monogamous and the premises,
while they both look the same,
they all look the same.
Like what's the,
what's the big deal about them being
monogamous?
But that's something that anybody would
see if you're looking for the point,
you know,
you're looking for like comedy in,
in,
in like a,
an obvious sort of a situation like
penguins been monogamous,
you know,
you were probably come up with the exact
same thing.
If I said write a bit about penguins
being monogamous,
you would probably be like,
well what's the big deal?
They look exactly the same.
You instantly go to it.
Ninety percent of comedians would
instantly go to that,
you know,
but it's like your take from there on,
once you get that,
then it's going to be like,
some people go,
like Duncan would get real weird with
it.
He would find some fucking weird
spiritual angle.
And will they say in the Bhagavad Gita?
And he would be like coming out and you
would have a different.
And it's funny,
I have a different angle.
When somebody gives you a tag it,
it feels like somebody sometimes just
give you a $500 bill,
like sometimes you have the same,
like that's the date you,
if you couldn't have wrapped gift or
bought something on Amazon that would do
the same feeling.
I had a friend,
Brian Frazier,
who,
uh,
at the time was a,
he needed some money and I was making a
lot of money and he had
a heckler line and I like,
dude,
this is the greatest fucking Heco line.
Every goes,
oh,
Salazia.
So he sold it to me for 500 bucks.
This is the,
this is the heckler line,
because I never used it.
But because it felt weird,
but this is that he said,
because this is what happened when God
made you.
Oh,
and just a dash of content.
Oh No.
The cop pull off the top,
fell off too much,
gets great line.
I just had this past week,
it was just,
I was trying to think of situations back
in the day when guys were preparing for
battle,
but their wives were still in their
brain because I was trying to go ladies,
every once a while your guy gets a look
on his face,
just leave him alone.
He's trying to and I act like I was a
guy sharpening my sword and did the hand
thing.
Like the wife was right in there.
A kamiko you should have her bitch
about.
Really you can leave a shield right on
the table like Paul.
That's all for today and then the very
next show did it,
but it adds a whole different spin to
your act when you get that little fun.
Thanks for the layup though.
Yes.
Yeah,
yeah.
Thanks for the insight.
Sometimes that turns it into a bigger
bit that turns it into something you
weren't even thinking.
What's really funny how some comics will
take attack,
like I'll take the tag from somebody.
I definitely trust it.
Somebody gave me a tag once and it was
fucking stolen.
Adab spinning the guy's fucking face.
Fucking careful.
What time I like when a comic comes up
and sees me,
it gives me a different angle and and
years ago I remember watching Chris rock
the one special and it was pretty funny
and then he had the second one that I
remember seeing him at the store on a
Monday and he had jenny and the Apollo
with them.
I didn't know what the fuck they were
doing.
They were just talking and then the next
night it was at the Improv and then he
is Louis,
cK,
and Apollo.
And what he was doing was he would get
this advanced or major beyond.
Give everybody a taste and go during the
week.
I Want Jenny to Paolo and you,
you guys each come up with 15.
I'll do 15.
We got a party.
You know what?
I'm getting 200 grand.
I give everybody 50.
I keep 50 for an events.
I got to fucking pilot.
I get the best of what they had and
gather perspectives on styles of doing
the punch and you could see the
difference in the specials.
You could see the difference in the
specials as early specials in the ones.
Later on,
you could see the Paolo,
you could see the precision of Richard.
Jenny.
You could see the wackiness of Louis C,
k.
let me tell you something.
Not a lot of fucking comics could do
that because of their ego.
Couldn't do that.
A lot of comments.
Well,
there's also comics that want their
standup though to be from their own.
Like Louis,
I could see doing that way,
man.
Look,
if you have to do an hour,
there's nothing wrong with hiring a
bunch of people for writers and coming
up with some good material and there's
nothing wrong with that.
As long as it fits your sense of like
minded.
Yeah,
it doesn't.
I never like.
Let's think about like Chris Rock,
Chris Rock's not really that good
because he had guys writing for him,
which is ridiculous because he's one of
the greatest of all time.
Unquestionably.
Unquestionably one of the greatest of
all time.
And the stronger voice you have,
the more you can have other people are.
I mean,
looking at any of the,
the uh,
blue collar guys,
but it's funny how teams of guys that
kind of fill those,
those models,
you can
take credit.
My point is you can take credit for your
own work,
but to think that somehow or another
your work is better because you come up
with a completely on your own as opposed
to someone who hired a bunch of writers
is kind of silly,
right?
I mean he's just trying to get a
different point of view and perspective,
but ultimately it's coming out of his
mouth.
It's going to be his voice and he,
he assigned those writers to help him
with this.
You know,
it's just different.
Especially if you have,
if you're the type of actor who's gotTa
create a crank out a just a.
You don't have to,
you can't do an 80 percent fun job.
It has to be out of the park every time.
And if you do that once a year,
here's where it would suck though.
Where it would suck is if everybody got
an equal say in what you said on stage.
See if you were a team,
say if you were a band and it was the
three of us and we had to construct a
set and then maybe Joe Diaz wants to put
some shit in the beginning.
Oh No,
no,
don't do that.
You got to the end that we're going to
put my shit here,
and then you're like,
why would I put it?
Look Bro,
I don't have confidence in that.
What the fuck?
And then you would argue over how the
material gets delivered as long as Joe
Diaz was in charge of you went out and
hired a bunch of stuff,
they brought you things and you're like,
okay,
this is good.
That's good.
I feel comfortable.
This is.
I would say this and I'll put my own
flavor into this,
my own spin on that.
As long as you.
It comes from a singular voice.
Sure,
sure,
sure.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
You guys are just enlightened me.
I built around you for 10 years.
You might.
You know what I'm saying?
Your best friends that you get open mic
with.
Some of them are writers now,
some of them,
but Chris Mcguire,
some of them fucking came up to you a
couple of times and said something.
You're like,
this motherfucker militiaman yeah,
yeah.
Sometimes it's better just to settle
down and take and you might not use it,
but he might open up a door for you
where your voice fits.
Yeah,
and that's what I'm saying.
Sometimes you have to learn how to,
you know,
collaboration is a very important thing.
It's a very interesting thing,
but no,
I mean that's.
These podcasts are essentially 100
percent collaboration.
The little rants sweet.
Go on little rants things come out of
them and stuff like that.
That wasn't normal.
Exactly.
When you're talking about nervous,
I do.
You get randomly,
I get nervous in the craziest things.
What you'll be doing a television shows
zero nerve and then it's second show
Saturday.
For some reason my heart,
I feel like it's pounding out of the
chest really.
And then a Friday first show,
no nerves.
I do a little bit of rituals,
estate,
state kind of focus to get me in like a
really good mood.
So when I get on stage,
I'm not phoning it in,
but as far as physical like I need to
wear one of those,
a body bugs,
I would like to split those up to get
those things.
Now you can do your heart rate,
calories and stuff and you hook it up to
your computer real.
You wear it for like all week and it
gives you.
Is it.
Does it work while you're exercising?
Because one,
I was stupid.
It goes around your waist in snow.
They have new ones that go on your bio
that are supposed to be really good and
you could fully exercise.
Like I got punched the bag and shit with
that.
Yeah,
it's,
it's like A.
Yeah.
I like to wear one just to see what my
heart rate does before shows and see
what kind of calories you burn.
Do you ever look at it while you're
looking at pictures that no,
I want to do it.
That was a goddamn good line.
Joey talked right over on the stock.
I liked it,
but it wasn't.
What was it said?
Do you ever look at that while you're
looking at pictures of caulk and see
what your heart rate does?
It's all right man.
Don't worry about USB on a horse
I guess.
Yeah,
I guess you can use it.
Seeing it with you're watching porn.
Just
gymnastics.
Horse is not even a real horse behind
me.
I look at things and look at when there
was a time when the store became second
nature to me.
Joe would call me and go,
you go on up before me and there was
like a fucking store and I would go down
there and I wouldn't feel anything.
I would go up on stage and literally
fucking bomb bomb bomb and getting my
car didn't give a fuck.
And then it's times when the audience I
feed off the energy.
It's like one them to the ocean near
that you're sitting in,
these waves are hitting you but there's
some shit coming at you and sometimes
you get to a show and I got to see the
audience,
like seeing the audience and let me know
these motherfuckers paid.
They get in and gets me fucking on fire
and just get.
I see people on the plane sometimes I'll
psych myself up.
Now I'm throwing different point.
Like now I want to go out there and die
on stage.
We were in Milwaukee.
Let me just tell you ever had a heart
attack on stage.
I'm ready.
But if I do it,
I'm doing it because I like what's going
on right now with comedy and my wife and
with us when we go out and if I'm not
nervous bro,
it ain't going to be real.
I don't want it to fuck around no more.
I want to be nervous to the point where
my palm sweat a little bit.
I get that way and then the second year
and I check about leaving the door like
where's that door?
Maybe I don't want to do this.
We were in Milwaukee.
The place is packed where this fucking
awesome theater and joey is in the bag
and Joe,
he looks out and he sees all the people
in the audience.
You got this like fucking murderers look
in your eye at all.
These mother fuckers,
Joe Rogan.
He goes to,
these motherfuckers are going crazy,
and then he goes,
we're taking this to the next level with
taking this to the next level.
Joe Rogan,
and he'd just had his murderers look in
his eyes and went out and just smashed
it,
but it's like the excitement of the
crowd all come in there
Somac battery than you see the guys that
get on stage.
You have their notebook.
They're like,
oh,
hey,
what's up?
I'm tired page.
Oh,
alternative comedy.
This guy,
stupid page paid where I literally my
new little move before each show.
If no one does well I'll even do it for
crowds looking.
There's a scene from one of the star
wars were [inaudible] about to fight the
system and there's a force field in
front of him and he's.
And he's rocking like just get the.
I do that to myself now before.
Well I was just crazy pump up like I was
going to ask you this because you do
that neuro linguistic programming,
right?
Yeah,
and you,
you have like a certain thing you do
right before you go onstage.
That puts you in a,
like a perfect state of mind was at work
always.
Yeah.
What I do,
it's,
it's um,
yes,
and then I was doing it wrong.
We're a buddy actually say you shouldn't
make it rich.
Which realistic,
whatever that word is I was talking to
you shouldn't do it or now you're
developing.
And so what I do is I imagined the
greatest show ever,
just literally because your brain
doesn't know,
uh,
something that didn't happen to you.
If I was asked you tell me about lunch
you had with your family yesterday and
you told me you couldn't really tell me
the way the launch actually went down.
You've deleted distorted and generalized
every situation in your life to what's
important to you.
Right.
Where I could ask,
let's say your wife tell me about lunch
and she would almost give me,
it'd be similar,
but maybe she was paying attention to
the TV that was on above you and in your
store.
You didn't tell me about the TV.
It's kind of what people are,
what you're looking out for because you
have a.
This is wrong numbers,
but like $70,
billion bits of information your body's
trying to figure out.
Right.
And you narrow that down to seven plus
or minus two pieces of info at any given
moment.
Okay.
Like if I was asking you what's the
temperature like in here?
How's the temperature?
Unless you are focused on it,
unless you were sweaty,
the temperature might not even been in
the equation.
Why we're having this conversation.
So with that,
I imagined the greatest show ever,
like my greatest show ever.
And I kind of remind some last comment
because there was that feeling of big
light shit falling from the thing when I
really felt eh and right when I get to
that state,
I squeeze my thumb.
I put my thumb in between my fist like
spiderman and squeeze it yet.
Or you're shooting on a web?
Yes,
exactly.
That's exactly.
You put it there.
How did he do it?
Now?
You did it like two fingers like this,
right?
Yeah.
Well My.
Because you don't let them enter the.
Yeah.
He went like this.
Or if I had the things as a kid who
needs prayer,
but I put it here and then I imagine
that you get that feeling because now
your brain imagines that awesome thing
and I lock it in like a speed dot.
Then what happened?
Just covering your thumb because you
want it,
like fighters use it.
Sometimes fighters have a thing.
You do it in a.
In a movement that you don't replicate
on a normal basis.
We don't do it.
I it.
So I squeeze my thumb and then sometimes
when I'm in an awesome mood or even if I
come home and my dogs,
they're,
they're tag,
their tails are wagon and I'm like,
oh this is great.
I'll squeeze my thumb and when I'm on
stage,
if I get a big laugh and get an a or say
something that was really funny,
I'll squeeze my thumb.
So it's like a bank account.
You put happy feelings or good feelings
into that thumb.
So then the for the days when you don't
feel like going on stage or you got into
an argument right before you went on
stage,
like self up gnosis is squeeze that
thumb and it puts you right back to that
place.
Just like a song.
It's called anchoring.
Just like if you hear a song from back
in the day,
you can remember a girlfriend or.
Yeah.
So what you're doing is you're adding
your sp dial to tyricine.
Whether here's the deal,
if,
if you,
if you think it works,
then it completely works,
which means you just have to convince
yourself that it works.
I see you're not wearing your balance
bracelets.
And when I was at the mall the other
day,
some guy was trying to sell me on it and
I asked if you've got a balance bracelet
on both hands if it's better.
And he said yes,
well this is recorded,
but there's people that actually believe
in that shit.
Shane Carwyn believed in that shit.
But here's the crazy part about it.
One of the things that are ropes of
Judaism from the forum,
you know,
filled the English dude.
He posted on the forum an interesting
observation that this guy had where
people have done studies and showed that
they actually did help athletic
performance and the reason
is because people thought they helped
and that is somehow enough even ready
for this.
Even if you know it's bullshit.
Even people that knew it was bullshit
and knew there was no physical way that
this bracelet could give you better
balance and make you athletic.
Athletical athletically performed
better.
They would give it to people and they
would still find significant benefit in
it like somehow or another.
Just opening the door to something
making you better can make you better.
Or what happens is a lot of times when
you start talking,
let's talk about nerves or shitty.
If we keep it the show,
you're starting,
oh,
the show sucks.
Oh,
but that person's probably going to
heckle.
And what happens is as you talked
yourself into a really shitty show,
like do that.
You talk yourself into people that are
going no,
but I will play scenario scenarios out
in my head.
You you play like,
like heckles fas having,
but I'm not saying just for a second
because Brian,
you're,
you're really new to the game or you've
only been doing comedy like a little bit
now.
I mean really over the last couple of
years.
Over this nine years off that you had,
do you ever before you go on stage,
you should be nervous as fuck.
Do you ever go on stage and said
nervous?
Nervous anymore?
You're fine.
You just go out there and do it when
they're nervous to tell you so much.
Brian did.
I mean people will say that Brian had
like a shortcut and Brian,
you know,
all he had to do
was just start doing open mics and we
had them in front of packed houses.
Brian went up in Austin,
fucking Texas after Joey Dad
was a steel.
You have to have a fucking complain.
I've never looked at me and I'll tell
him to his face.
Never gave me a look of go after joey
crush rushed and he would tell me to
crush if crush,
crushing,
like get out there and I can work
tonight.
Fuck what I'm saying.
One time we were in,
we were in,
we were in Austin one night and he came
up to me afterwards like I and he's
like,
that joke didn't work and I'm fucking
Howard because that's fun and I didn't
give a fuck.
It's true.
That joke didn't work,
but it's.
Brian has balls of steel now.
Lane never complained to me.
Never ever.
He had been off for nine years.
He had an any six years,
six years,
no standup at all.
He got up at a midnight show in Atlanta,
Georgia at a UFC punchline in Atlanta.
That's a fucking.
First of all,
that's a bad ass old school club.
To have that club,
to go up for your first time and on a
sold out show on a fucking Friday night,
a late night show,
midnight show.
Fucking goes onstage and kills.
Not only did he kill,
he pulled himself out of a downward
spiral like you did.
Really good in the beginning and then he
started bombing and he figured out a way
to pull himself out of the bombing.
You know why?
Because he doesn't have a lot of ego.
When you have a lot of ego,
that's when you can never pull out of a
bombing person who like takes themselves
super seriously and then it gets
devastated onstage by,
by a joke,
joking those.
The people that can't pull out a
bombing.
Come to a point in my life when I got
another fucking email about standup one
another twit and you put me off
or people come up to you and talk to you
and put you off.
I'm at the point.
Stand up.
I want to just say get the fuck away
from me.
So whenever I see somebody like Brian do
the standup Brown and gold bottom ball
lists,
you know,
because it's completely out of Brian
where he just goes up.
I love him.
Just for that.
I give them that respect because I know
how hard it is and I know how many
exclusives we've all heard and we don't
give a fuck.
All I want you to do is be happy.
If you come up to me and say you want to
get on stage,
I'll give you all the love I can to get
you up to that stage,
but don't let me see your three months
later and you still bullshitting me
because I did that too.
It took me six months,
took me six months of canceling at the
comedy works and then show it up and
finally doing it.
Then you get hope,
but I do give you a lot of love for that
brand.
Probably one of the reasons why he
talked to this,
because you don't give a fuck when it
comes to stand up and as soon as he gets
to a stage your walk at them and say,
where's the drink ticket?
Bitch?
As a kid I used to do open mic nights
with back in Boston.
Route was kind of half ass in it.
In the beginning I was into it,
but it wasn't into it because I was
still fighting at the time and I was
still working full time,
so still fighting kickboxing tournament
and shit,
so I was training I pretty much every
night and then trying to go do standup
afterwards so I was fucking tired all
the time.
I was burning the fuse at both ends and
some fucking kid that I did open mic
nights with goes,
you're pretty funny when you first
started out man,
but you seem to have kind of fizzled and
he's being honest with me and I stopped
and I thought about it.
I was like,
Shit,
you know,
he's just like saying it like you're,
you're really funny.
In the beginning he kind of fizzled and
I didn't argue with them back,
which is what I normally would have
done,
but I'm like,
fuck you.
And I thought about.
I'm like,
God damn.
He's probably right.
What the fuck am I doing?
I didn't.
I had a guy say,
he came and saw me in Austin,
a friend of mine,
and he did show it and I thought it was
a good show and he goes,
I've seen you like a bunch of times.
He goes,
you've done comedy for 23 years,
you need to rip it every time,
and then I immediate,
you need to rip it every time to rip it,
like,
just crush.
He goes,
you know why?
He was probably saying that his
girlfriend wanted to fuck you or
motivated me because then I started
going know that crowd just kind of then.
And then I'm making all the excuses.
You know,
I,
there was a point where I switched off,
maybe start phoning it in and then.
And then that's when I choose my thumb,
but some shows,
I mean,
when you do 500 of them,
you're going to have to suck your thumb.
Do I suck my.
I never did.
No,
you suck it up.
Don't.
I was a kid.
I was when I was a kid,
when I was a fucking kid,
I was hooked on pacifiers do.
I was like six years old dog,
big time.
I used to hide them from my mom and hide
them all over the house and I used to
play ball in the house.
My mom would see you gonna fucking break
something of mine.
One guy.
So she had these Japanese girls with
different fucking ways.
They're like 10.
Jesus had broken.
My Mom's like,
you're done now.
You gotta pay me all the money you owe
me.
You got to get a day job.
I was like,
fine.
I'm like,
she's like,
I need like 30 fucking,
Geez,
you know you can make $50 a week or you
can start sucking.
Those pacifies dog stops are going to
stop sucking them.
And I'm like,
because I would suck.
I'm like the way people smoke
cigarettes,
I get into a fistfight and run home and
syringes to hide them outside in the car
and you just see you in the corner.
Just I want to talk about that thing
that we talked
about before the show,
but I don't.
I do,
Yeah,
right,
right.
Should we.
We should.
The electronic thing
folks,
you want to know what level they're
kicking it here in California.
Do you want to know?
Do you want to really know they have
electronic cigarettes?
Look what Brian's holding up that are
all weed there too.
How many hits $200?
200.
200 hits in those.
Do you know how ridiculous that is?
That one thing you could carry that
around for you for days for you.
You could carry that shit around for
days and just get bullied.
So you put the weed in there.
No preloaded,
preloaded,
and it's like a poll.
That shit for preload and it has all to
about $200.
When you draw it for two to three
seconds,
two weeks,
you got to charge it and it's.
This is amazing.
This is.
You don't need a lie.
That is a super blue dream.
Where do you get this from?
The shop?
The only two or three seconds.
It's called an m,
e,
d.
A stick as tea is amazing.
It doesn't smell at all except for when
you you you have it.
The problem is you can never smell weed
when you're smoking weed.
You don't smell it plain.
I don't think you could do it on a plane
because something's coming out and
that's something we'll probably set up
the alarm.
So what I did here,
it's water vapor,
water vapor,
back.
Why do we need to do the water?
Vapor is for the cigarette.
They do it so people get the whole
thing.
You see the fake read,
you go in and then you see the fake
reds.
Hilarious.
Yeah.
You see the and then you blow it out.
So people who want to not smoke,
they that you've gone through the whole
motion,
you see that,
you light it and stuff like
fucking bat flew into Burbank.
I had a talk with a competent Joe Rogan
Joe Rogan.
It's over Lucille.
You.
Why are you so greedy,
man?
Joe
For
starbucks.
Have random drug testing.
Joe Rogan.
I talked to a cop,
Burbank,
uh,
bob hope the motherfucker said.
He goes,
look,
I don't care where we don't care where
the fuck you flying no more.
Please check your wheat.
He goes,
we get people checking.
Weeding now for three ounces on the
conveyor belt for security purposes.
We don't give a fuck no more.
Really.
That's how bad it's getting lax to.
They don't give a fuck.
Used to be there.
Didn't give a fuck if you're going to
somewhere in California now they just
said,
just check it.
You're on.
Really?
So you can bring weed through the.
The,
the fucking PSA.
Don't hold that.
Brian,
what are you going to have all the
information?
Make them get on a trip.
Put It,
put it on the sick.
You got to put your weed on the belt and
let it go through.
Fucking the thing.
Real.
So you tell them this is weed.
Yeah.
They know.
They know they keep that thing going
and taking his ball and gone home.
So listen,
this was near the end of the podcast so
I gotta get the fuck out of here because
I'm going to the premiere of warrior
tonight.
Brian counts me.
I'm going to go see that.
That's going to be interesting.
Or you don't even fucking permit them
all.
Bucky loss and bullet points.
Darn Lucky Larson going to be a porn
star.
What's that movie?
Yeah.
Me and what's the play?
What's the part yet?
The porn producer,
they try to show me because it's like a
big dirty bitch.
It's Watson and a bunch of meetings.
Next,
but when is it coming out Friday,
but it goes,
gets contagious.
I'm in no danger.
Danger.
I'm adult day job against contagious.
Do you meet Stephen Dorff?
Yeah,
we were at the party.
What sort of fucking body together?
All of a sudden you forgot.
Then I take it.
No,
you invited to the party.
Stephen Dorff came with Gina Richie and
Ben Owen.
Owen Benjamin came at the end.
I left you at the party with the drunk
chick from fucking playboy.
You forget now,
Brian,
I need to take you to a doc.
That's it.
Body weight the week to meet with the
stakes on Donald Wooster.
You need to run to my wife.
Went to the wrap or at least a quick
little brain cat scans
pussies turning your brain to mush in
goodfellas.
Cocksucker.
I saw him at the grocery store yesterday
and tried to get a picture of how bad
does he left?
He was in one of those little carts that
isn't even the fucking mob.
Whoa.
This shit smells like weed.
I know exactly what it looks,
but he was at the grocery store and that
little part that they'll go,
yeah,
this smells exactly need.
I was trying want to get a picture with.
I told my wife,
I go,
just take a picture.
I'm going to sandbag.
Don't you should have gotten up to them.
Told them you will hold it.
Missing something here from.
Because it smells like weed.
Smell that.
Can you.
Is there something missing off the front
or is it supposed to be like that?
I think that's right.
Smell though.
Shit.
You can smell the weed right through
that.
That thing stinks.
Like wait,
I can't take that nowhere.
No,
no.
That's the same thing.
You're trying to get me arrested,
Bro.
This thing stinks like crazy.
Let me show you what some lights on it.
Just know that shit.
Joe.
Brian,
because Brian's doesn't switch.
You smell the mouth part.
Now I want to just did the smells like
cheese and bread and everything that
goes in my mouth.
You know what I'm saying?
Relax.
So I went to on the constant over here.
Hey,
to get done.
So this is the question that I had.
I'm thinking about.
I'm thinking about opening a comedy club
and been thinking about that for the
last couple of weeks.
I've been telling you that for years.
You're right.
You have been.
You've been telling me about.
We talked about buying the ice house at
one point in time when they were trying
to sell the ice house and like maybe
what,
what would it be like to buy a comedy
club?
What city would you do it?
I don't know man.
I would have to have somebody fucking
run it though.
Somebody that I trust to run it.
That's the real problem because I ain't
got the time to really blessed to have a
club where we all had a vested interest
in and we all worked out there all the
time and we set it up the right way.
I mean essentially like the comedy store
was one of the greatest creative moments
for you and I and a lot of other
comedians,
but why was it?
Well,
it's because there was a lot of great
comics hanging out there and basically
running the show.
I mean,
that's what it was.
It was a fun little club where we all
got in and fucked around and people knew
that they go there pretty much any
weekend and see some fun shit.
We need to recreate that.
We can recreate that somewhere.
It wouldn't be that hard as long as we'd
all like small,
like $200 to $15 even.
That's too much.
We don't want to compete with nobody,
by the way.
What's going on?
Mad Dog.
We have lots to talk about.
What we love to talk.
I want them to the Improv last Tuesday.
That shit is fucked up.
What are you talking to?
Mom went to the Improv last week and
Judy Brown was.
There was the last time you went to the
Improv on Tuesday.
So I'm walking around shaking people's
hands and all of a sudden as I'm walking
out the door,
get a tap on the shoulder.
I got a newspaper article drawn on me.
Have you seen the news print button,
front page of the business section in
the La Times that caught our boy with
our hand in the motherfucking cookie jar
talking Robin Hartman sued by Bud
Freeman,
stealing like a motherfucker double dip
and 15 percent.
And owning the club.
It's in there.
You know why you ready for this one?
What?
The Guy told the story.
They told us that they're going to open
up three new clubs called levity.
Yeah,
but said enough is enough.
Enough of you motherfuckers robbing me.
The reason why they call them level.
These don't have to pay the fucking
franchise tax.
And they've been doing it now for a long
time.
Stand up,
live there,
having a good time with the funny bones,
but came out of that coma already.
Cut like eight Jews together and he
goes,
we're going to get honest.
They've been out.
Mark Lynas has been down there.
It's over.
The cat's out of the bag.
Are you sure about all this?
Look on that fucking newspaper and see
what it says right there and I don't
want to read it.
Pay Out while you're getting worked up.
I'm bosses the Impreza and been good to
me no matter what I'm saying that every
fucking dog has his day.
They accusing you.
You know where there's smoke.
There's fire,
but what I'm saying it's a small place.
I'm not saying anything even close to as
big as the employee.
The club that I started off in Ann
Arbor.
That basement.
What is that 150 people?
You can have that place at 200 in the
room or even like Wendy's clubbing in
death,
but that's,
that's like 300 for sale.
I don't know if it's still
that new side room where we did that.
We did the death squad comedy show last
week.
That side room is fucking bad ass
people.
New sound system.
New seats.
You have to have a show there.
Friday.
My one man show that also my most likely
yes,
I'll
be there at all.
Depends on where we're shooting for your
factor that day.
Most likely
stage I need to get on stage because a
lot of dates coming up.
Ladies and gentlemen tomorrow.
Um,
the,
uh,
the tickets go on sale for our show at
the verizon theater.
October seventh,
Joe Diaz and Wa and we're gonna.
Um,
we're gonna fuck that place on the case
in Texas.
We haven't been in Houston,
Texas in a long time.
Five years.
We're going to.
God Damn.
Yeah.
It's been a long time and that's the
place where I recorded my first CD.
That's the place where I first got
recognized as a comic.
Really those,
the place where I first started selling
out,
I never sold on anywhere in the country.
Houston,
Houston
had this whole history of that kind of
comedy,
wild comedy and Joe Diaz and I went in
that place and when the.
When my cd got released,
we did a fucking free show there and
advertise it on the radio and it was one
of the most fun nights I've ever had in
my life.
And the Columbus like,
oh,
we gotta charge.
Remember Mark Babbitt was like,
we've got to charge.
We got to charge.
And you were you,
you said it best.
It's not in the spirit of the thing.
It's not in the spirit.
We were high as fuck.
We were like,
we should do a free show.
And he's like Joe Rogan.
That's genius.
Do a free show on the fucking building
in La.
Do that sometimes.
Yeah.
Again,
on a building and start playing.
Fucking show up that in the spirit of
the thing.
Do you have enough money?
So sometimes do a fucking free show rock
that will.
This one ain't free bitches.
Okay.
Maybe this one because it's at the
verizon wireless theater and they're
charging me.
And that's October seventh and Houston,
Texas tickets go on sale tomorrow.
If you look on my twitter,
it's twitter.com/Joe Rogan.
It's on today is while we're recording.
This is the sixth,
the seventh.
They go on sale.
I kind of just something that.
Yeah.
The password is speaker.
There's a presale tomorrow,
September 17th.
Myself and the flying jewelry should fee
at the town ballroom in Buffalo,
New York.
I got to give you a shirt,
Joe Rogan,
who's Fidel Castro with a Yamaka on
smoking a fucking blunt.
Did you make this your shirts?
Some guy fucking design them for us on
twitter and we need two more shirts.
We need one that says stay black and
winning one that says,
oh Brian,
that's quite shit.
And we needed a desk.
Yeah,
but you want to do desk while you're
gay.
Cat does not just broad logo.
Some people do.
They're just words.
So just,
you know,
can mean whatever they want.
Yeah.
You know what should be typed.
I'm going to split up.
It's not in the spirit of the word death
squad.
Where,
how want the cat?
I know that's not a good sound.
A good idea.
That kind of has Hitler mustache.
Not The itunes version.
No.
Okay.
Good squad.
Can I plug my new?
Want me and job?
John reape called last podcasting.
We do it every couple of weeks,
but it's underneath the,
uh,
your guys' big podcasts.
Labeled domination.
Powerful.
We'll be back on Saturday and Sunday.
Saturday we have um,
Tim Ferriss,
the author of the four work week.
Yeah,
it seems like a really cool guy.
He's coming on Saturday and then.
No,
I have not.
I'm going to have a chance this week to
pretend I'm gonna.
Read it,
so I'll skip through some summaries
online and then Sunday is Anthony
Bourdain,
so the 10th and the 11th.
Our next live podcast that we'd be doing
on the Internet three weeks in a row,
we've had the number one podcast out of
all of itunes and that's because of you
guys and thank you very much.
It's cool as fuck.
It's not like gives us anything.
I mean it's just bragging rights,
but it's cool to know that people are
interested in the.
That you guys are doing it.
We love you.
You love us as black.
We need Joey Diaz,
dates,
books,
blogs,
videos,
domestic slave,
a world
with doing it all over the map flavor
where we proved that already on youtube.
Go see that mad flavors world on
youtube.
I got my game back this week.
We got a lot of shit going on.
People are.
You're slipping,
you're all coming with us.
Thank you to the fleshlight logo.
Does Joe Rogan.net and click on the link
for the flashlight and entering the code
name?
Rogan.
You will get 15 percent off the number
one sex toy for men.
That's it.
Go follow the death squad on itunes.
It's a series of podcasts.
John Reap and John have from.
We got Thompson.
Gora is on that label.
We've got Ari Shaffir,
we got Freddy Lockhart.
All great comics.
All interesting dudes.
It's big fun.
Follow that shit.
Alright,
we love you and I.
we'll see you on Saturday.
They kiss.