We smoke weed,
we're elaborating.
I asked should we smoke weed right when
Jamie gave me the.
The,
the gun sign.
What's up,
brother?
Good to see you,
man.
Yeah,
you too,
man.
It's good to.
It's good to be back.
It's good to have you back.
Yeah.
This is warm time though in Toronto.
Like you didn't really want to leave
that,
but you know what,
but I kind of felt like today out here
was almost the perfect weather anyways.
Like not too oftentimes I'll come out
here like I'm not a guy who needs to be
in the heat,
you know,
I'm not one of these people when it
snows or whatever.
Like I'm complaining I can handle it.
I feel like genetically I'm built for
that environment where you're a
Canadian.
That's right.
Canadian born and bred.
They can deal with it.
So yeah.
So I'm not,
I'm not,
you know,
I don't mind.
I don't mind a little bit of the little
bit of the cold,
but today,
here in La,
this is God's.
Whether this is like,
I think if every day could be exactly
like this out here,
there'd be a compelling argument,
but it's those hot days getting into the
car and burning.
Am I?
Am I fired up today?
Am I fired up?
This is coffee number three.
All right.
Blame,
blame the caffeine.
Did the argument.
There's two arguments,
right?
There's the argument is if it's really
cold out,
you can always dress for the cold when
you can't really dress for the warm.
Yeah,
right.
Undressed,
but you could freeze to death.
It's super hard to heat up to death.
Really fuck up to heat up to the desert,
the desert,
the desert and kill you.
Pretty good to go to death valley.
Yeah.
Actually no dude that died like that.
Really?
Yeah.
He went on like a sort of a spiritual
walk about and kind of a thing.
This Guy Evan Tanner who was a UFC
fighter,
former middleweight champion to me.
I've heard that.
Yeah.
He was into,
uh,
these,
you know,
these long periods of solitude and
spiritual quests and he decided to go
out into the desert and,
you know,
just try to find himself or whatever.
I don't know exactly what his purpose
was,
but when you get out there and it gets
to like 120 130 degrees,
you,
you get disoriented and he couldn't
figure out where he put his water.
Wow.
Yeah.
He couldn't find where his stuff was.
Funny.
How about that stuff in movies and
whatnot.
Cartoons,
where every time somebody is in the
desert,
they're seeing a mirage.
What is that about?
Well,
you can definitely hallucinate before
you die.
And do you think that that's what that's
predicated on is an actual history of
people having seen these oasis
situations?
Well,
you know what it is.
You know how when you're driving on the
road and the road is really hot,
it looks like it's wet and it looks like
there's water on the road right from the
heatwave.
Exactly.
That illusion on the road can recreate
itself,
I'm sure in desert situations and it
only makes sense.
Right.
And it's what you want to see.
You're like,
no,
you're in rough shape.
You create what you need to see.
Can you manage?
If you did your manager,
if you like almost dying and you find
water,
he'd be like,
yes.
I mean I think that's the.
Those are the kinds of moments that make
people really truly appreciate life.
And I think that's one of the reasons
why people in la are so fucking spoiled
and ridiculous is because they don't
experience real.
Whether it gets a little warm and then
the worst thing they have to do is turn
the AC on,
but they don't have to shovel their way
out of snow.
They don't have to drive on slippery
roads,
they don't have to.
And there's a certain amount of
community that comes with everybody sort
of bonding together because it's a
blizzard.
Right?
You remember those?
Oh yeah,
sure.
You need experienced them all the time.
Yeah.
It's kind of a is the kind of situation
I think where any time as a human being
you kind of you have,
you lose a little bit of control over a
situation,
whether it's the weather or something
else.
You kind of take yourself outside of
that realm of,
of how we like to compartmentalize
things.
We'd like to like the epitome of self
centeredness is being in control of
absolutely every experience you have and
never letting go and the rest of the
world around you as well.
Yeah.
Just your experience.
No,
exactly.
You try to control kind of situation and
choosing to live in a place where where
you know,
shit can go wrong or or you can have a
snow storm or whatever is a.
it's kind of.
It's kind of an element in that is he
says it's an aspect of losing control
over the space and so what ends up
happening,
you've got people slip sliding around.
You've got a essentially people coming
to the realization that the planet can
come kick the shit out of you.
If it wants to know.
I guess an earthquake would work that
way.
Earthquakes do work that way.
Um,
even a horrible thing like nine slash 11
works that way.
It did when I was in New York,
we filmed fear factor in New York like
less than a year I think after nine
slash 11.
It was pretty close to when it happened.
And Man,
it was just such a different vibe.
Everybody was so friendly.
Everybody was so friendly and so nice.
And uh,
I had a friend who a blacked out.
We were all hanging out in front of this
bar and we stepped outside and a couple
of them smoke cigarettes and uh,
I pulled out a joint.
I go,
who wants to get down with this?
And the.
And they're like,
oh good,
let's go there.
Like these producers like agreeably,
we're doing this right,
right.
One of them,
I guess she just doesn't smoke pot or
she just,
for whatever reason,
she took a hit and then you see like her
eyes rolled behind her head and her legs
go down and she almost fell like we had
a catcher passed out.
Yeah.
She blacked out from weed.
I mean like,
do you think it was the weed or it was
just in conjunction with kind of the
drama of the whole event having
happened?
No,
no,
it was definitely the weed because she
was from La and we flew into film fear
factor there and she just.
Oh,
okay.
I just had a weird reaction to pot,
whatever it was,
fucking space we need to go.
Anyway,
so we called the first responders,
right?
We call the whatever they call.
I don't know who they called,
paramedics,
firemen up and I swear to God these guys
were treated like fucking superheroes,
a fireman and then cops came behind them
and everybody was so nice and so
friendly to him because it was at that
sort of honeymoon period after nine
slash 11 when you realized,
Hey,
when when shit gets awful,
we need these people,
we have to count on these people.
So people were more friendly in the city
in general and then like really thankful
when the firemen showed up.
Yeah,
there certainly is a kind of reset
button effect when some kind of disaster
happens where we,
where people feel like they've lost
control even for a moment.
It is,
it is dude,
like I'm out here on the highway in la
or anywhere for that matter and you kind
of have those moments where you're
sitting around looking at all these
vehicles and wondering how the hell this
shit is staying together.
Like what is like,
how is everybody on this path because it
only takes one asshole one.
What percentage of individuals is that
to like,
screw it up for everyone else,
whether you're flying a goddamn plane
into a building or swerve in the wrong
way or looking at your text messages or
whatever it is.
I think uh,
you know,
often we kind of take these disasters
and we,
we kind of hold them up,
you know,
cnn style,
like where you play it over and over
again when in reality there's an
argument to be made that the amazing
part is that it's held together as well
as it is half the time.
You know what I mean?
That's the argument.
There's a lot of arguments when it comes
to that,
but one of them about gun violence,
you know,
there's so many.
Showed me a chart the other day of how
much,
how many people have guns,
how many people actually get shot by
guns and who are the people that are
getting shot by guns and how many of the
people that are getting shot by guns are
involved in gang violence or criminal
activity.
And then it boils down to how many P,
I mean that your chances of getting
shot,
your actual chance of getting shot.
Like do we really have a gun problem or
do we have a numbers problem?
And it really,
if you look at the hard raw facts,
it's way more of a numbers problem.
It's a 300 million people problem.
That's what it is.
And if you look at the actual number of
guns versus the number of gun incidents,
it's shockingly low.
But it's just we're dealing with so many
human beings and that those numbers just
seem.
When I don't,
I just don't think human beings are
supposed to have access to 7 billion
human beings on earth.
Worth of drama and stories,
you know?
Yeah.
You know,
when,
when it comes back to the,
to the gun situation,
I think that there's,
you know,
the issue there,
the way I see it as like,
it's a communication issue in that I
think you've got these different groups
picking a side on it.
It is sort of relative to their
personal,
their personal experience and how
they've been affected by it.
Sure.
As opposed to big picture like what's
actually happening.
And inevitably what will happen is
you'll have some kind of a,
some kind of columbine situation and all
of a sudden everybody cares because of
the type of people affected by it
of course.
But then half the year when it's a
different,
a different group of people shooting
each other,
then it's not making headline news in
the same fashion.
So I think it's a lot more segmented.
I think that those issues of affecting
certain communities are more community
issues than they are national issues.
You know what I'm saying?
Oh,
they definitely are.
Yeah.
Like look at Chicago and Chicago is
close to you guys.
Yeah,
very much so.
Um,
and,
and the thing,
the weird thing about Chicago is it's
really nice,
like beautiful if you're in the right
spot.
Yeah.
It's like it's one,
one set of circumstances and then on the
other side of some imaginary line,
it's a different set of circumstances.
Murder rate is up more than 70 percent
this year from last year.
Last year was insane.
At least that's what I read.
I mean,
it sounds,
I,
I keep hearing about it.
It's terrible.
There was some kind of a blog I was
reading which was like based on
infographics and all this guy does the
entire blog is just following Chicago
violence as the whole thing.
And he had it all mapped out.
He had a every single shooting fatal
shooting where the person was hit.
It's like an amazing amount of detail
that went into,
on this particular blog.
I'm 72 percent is soared.
Seventy two percent.
Two thousand 16 shootings up more than
80 percent.
80 eight percent.
Wow.
That is insane.
So murder up 72 percent,
shootings up 88 percent the first three
months of 2016 compared to the same
period last year.
Fuck man.
There was a video that this guy did.
He was live his neighborhood and he got
shot on video.
Did you see that?
It's fucked up.
He just hanging out there,
you know,
walking around and I don't know what he
was saying,
but he was filming something and all of
a sudden you see him drop and then you
see the shooter standing over him
shooting at somebody else.
This is fucking crazy.
Yeah.
Know we look at it like Juarez.
Mexico.
Here it is.
It.
So this guy is hanging out here.
At least I'm going to duck for cover.
Is that what he's saying?
So he's listening to music.
Hey pops tobacco for the kid.
So He's wandering around.
Yep.
Someone just shot up what?
The Sky on loaded the whole clip.
Crazy.
And that guy survived.
Now that guy's dead as fuck.
Oh right.
Well that's weird watching somebody die.
Not really into that.
I mean I assume he's dead.
I felt like if that guy kept shooting
like that,
it's probably,
his work was done.
That's what it sure seemed like.
But the weird thing is it looked like he
was shooting over top of him.
Did he die?
He was in critical condition.
Oh.
So by now you might be,
but you might have also survive.
That place is a war zone.
Yeah,
it's,
it's weird.
And I think,
I think at this point we've got enough
evidence to realize that at some root
level we are still animals and when it
comes to vengeance or revenge,
everybody's susceptible.
If you brother,
your neighbor gets killed or you're
somebody you care about,
you just want to go and do the same
thing,
you know,
and whether it's in Chicago or it's in
the Middle East or wherever it happens
to be.
People who have been doing it.
You know,
I was,
um,
I don't remember who I was talking to
about this,
but uh,
it was,
it was regarding whether or not more
humans were responsible for killing
other humans in modern history or
disease.
Like which one was the bigger figure.
And I'm sitting there thinking about it
like I couldn't,
I didn't know,
but when I looked it up,
it was like shocking figures in the
direction of humans killing humans.
If you're including all the wars that
have ever happened,
millions of people that have died.
But this is modern,
modern history over time.
Who knows?
But I don't know if it was on a
wikipedia page or something.
No,
the craziest,
craziest statistics I've ever heard
about a human's dying was that half of
all the people that have ever died,
ever were killed by malaria mosquitoes.
The most dangerous animal on the planet.
Fucking malaria,
man.
I know a dude is added more than twice.
Justin's got it again.
Justin wren,
who got it again,
got layer.
He lives in the Congo,
he spends time in the Congo.
He's got this foundation called fight
for the forgotten.
And they go and they build a wells in
the Congo for people.
And uh,
he's been over there many,
many times and this is the second time
he got malaria.
And one of the things that he was saying
is there's different forms of malaria
and some malaria will last six months,
some malaria last five years,
and some malaria last 30 years,
30 year malaria.
That's Kinda like.
I'm Kinda like that.
Lyme disease hangs around.
Well,
lyme disease is devastating.
That's some really bad stuff,
especially if you don't catch it quick.
There's a gigantic amount of people on
the east coast that have lined to stuff
just stays in your system,
whether it's from deer ticks and they
have to figure out what to do about that
because there's a lot of places in the
east coast that are just overwhelmed
with deer because they don't have
predators.
So they have all these deer and the only
predators that they're having now,
the coyotes have kind of expanded their
range.
And there used to be a,
an animal that was more in the,
in the west and the prairies.
There's this amazing podcast right now,
if anybody's interested in this,
um,
my friend Steve Rinella has this show
called meat eater and it's on the
sportsmans channel and there's a new
podcast are not new,
but he's been doing it for awhile.
It's called the mediator podcasts and
he's got this guy on named Dan Flores
and Dan Flores is a historian and he was
one of Steve's a former professors and
he has this book coming out about
coyotes and it is fucking fascinating.
The knowledge that is guide drops about
coyotes will blow you away.
First of all,
coyotes or wolves to kind of wolf.
They used
to call them prairie wolves.
That's what they used to call them,
but it's like a type of wolf and they
breed with wolves.
Most wolves except gray wolves because
gray wolves have a different genetic
line.
They had left North America millions of
years ago and then came back like
within,
you know,
x amount,
thousands of years.
And so they kill coyotes when they find
them,
but red wolves and some other North
American wolves that still survived
those wolves bread with coyotes,
and they're creating this thing called a
coil wolf,
which is like a hybrid of coyotes and
wolves.
Let me ask you something.
Is this where geographically
all over the world,
all over the country,
rather all of this country,
this country,
like I said,
it used to be a small range of coyotes,
but due to persecution,
they've expanded their range and part of
it,
the persecution is not by humans,
but by the gray wolves,
because the gray wolves are killing
them.
So what?
What coyotes do.
This is so fascinating.
Coyotes,
when they call out,
when you hear coyotes and then other
ones call out.
What they're doing is they're doing a
roll call.
They're making sure that everybody's
there and when coyote to get killed,
when coyotes are under pressure,
when carbs get killed,
there's a reaction in the mother or the
female.
Coyotes have larger litters.
So the normal litter,
if nothing's disturbed,
is between three and four pups.
But if they get killed,
if they noticed that their numbers are
dwindling,
they're numbers jack up to as many as 13
to 14 puppies per litter per litter,
and doing that as a result of being
persecuted,
realtime upgrade realtime upgrades.
So one of the things that they've been
studying,
this is in yellowstone park,
because yellowstone park for more than
70 years,
had no wolves because they had
eradicated wolves.
They had extra paid them from
yellowstone park.
Then they reintroduced them in the 19
nineties.
So they.
The population of coyotes during that
time was exactly the same.
It was completely steady until they
brought in wolves.
And when the wolves started killing the
coyotes,
they're gray wolves that they brought in
from Canada.
The gray wolf started killing the
coyote.
The coyote is expanded like crazy and
multiplied like nuts.
And now the initial thing that happened
when they brought in wolves was at the
wolves killed a giant percentage of the
coyote and the coyote population dropped
by 50 percent.
But then once the coyote started having
much larger litters because there will
be killed off by walls,
their numbers went as high as they were
before and now even higher and now
they've expanded their range.
So thanks to the reintroduction of
wolves in Yellowstone Park.
We've got coyotes all over the
continental North America now.
Wow.
Fucking courageous.
Interesting.
You
brought this up.
I had a very weird experience recently.
I was,
um,
I live,
uh,
I live just north of the city in
Toronto,
like still completely urbanized area.
It would be like here to downtown La,
let's say.
And um,
I was going to visit my parents house.
They live roughly in the same area and I
went past a place where I went to
elementary school in a neighborhood
houses everywhere.
A wolf came straight in front of my
vehicle,
limping,
looked right at me and continued on into
the back of that elementary school,
a legit wolf.
I was like,
is this a coyote?
And I'm sizing it up as I'm staring at
it.
So sure enough,
I'm like,
this couldn't,
this can't be true.
I'd never seen a wolf my whole life in
this area,
and then so what I ended up doing is I
went online and I typed the town name
along with wolf and sure enough people
have been spotting wolves coming into
that area.
Look at this.
My friends live outside of Edmonton,
Alberta,
and the big ones,
a big wolf was in front of my friend's
truck today.
Just walking around the fucking thing.
They just sent me this this morning,
just walking around the street,
staring at him.
Fuck that.
Yeah.
That's a different kind of animal.
The way they look at you is there.
They're fascinating,
but coyotes are almost more fascinating
because their ability to adapt.
You know,
they tried to wipe out the coyote during
the 19 thirties.
I don't want to give too much of this
information because this is all Dan
Flores is a information.
It's all really much better distributed
by him off of this mediator podcast.
You really should.
It's not the most recent mediator
podcasts,
but the one before that,
and today's date is the 20,
20,
30th,
30th of April.
So find it,
find it,
listen to it.
It's amazing.
You might not be into hunting and I get
that if you're not a hunter,
not a hunting podcasts.
That one is not about hunting.
It's all about the wild west and about
the animals that used to exist on the
planes and uh,
they're actually trying to set aside a
gigantic chunk,
I think it's in Montana or something
like that where they're trying to
establish a new yellow stone type of
situation where they bring in a lot of
these animals and allow them to live in
a natural way and some large sort of,
um,
you know,
like a savannah type area.
Like,
like that,
like recreating sort of the African
savannas.
Wow.
Yeah.
What now that sounds dangerous to me.
Well,
they're just talking about animals that
already exists of animals like wolves
and bison and like local,
local with.
They're trying to have whatever would
have texted large wild protected area
where they can't develop and no one can
frack.
And you know,
that kind of,
you know,
this is a video I put up the other day
from a,
I think it was in Sweden,
I forget what town it was in,
but they were lighting lighting a lake
on fire.
The lake has gotten so fucked up from
fracking that you can light the lake on
fire.
So they go up to this lake with a blow
torch and they blow it on the lake and
the whole lake lights on fire.
That's like,
that's like a bigger version of what the
people were doing on the taps,
right?
Yes.
I don't know much about fracking.
I know the tap thing is controversial
only because some people say that some
of that
natural gas that got into that water had
already gotten into that water.
And this is a common phenomenon that you
could.
You could actually document back,
you know,
decades before fracking every assistant.
So it could be that the natural gas,
which was already in the water,
right?
They're already trying to get.
That's what they're trying to get out
when they're fracking.
Right.
That it was already leaking into some
water in some places,
but that doesn't remove the possibility
of fracking making more of that shit get
into people's water supply.
So it's real tricky because they want
these people that are anti fracking,
um,
they,
they want to point out the dangers of
fracking and the people that are pro
fracking,
they want to pretend that there's no
danger and it's like there's no middle
ground.
It's like the documentary on Netflix,
merchants of doubt.
Have you seen that?
Amazing.
Yeah.
It's like it's all about the agenda.
Any amount of money you have to further
that agenda and how much you can
extract.
If you can push your agenda,
you extract the money and then you put
it back in to continue to lobby or
whatever it might be to continue that
conversation.
And it's like when he talks specifically
about how individuals,
they only need a fragment of information
in order to,
to,
uh,
confirm their preexisting bias.
Yes.
Like you don't need a whole story,
just like just have to present the
alternative argument.
Make people think it's an argument in
the first place.
Yeah.
And then they'll pick the side that's
more convenient to them.
Like climate change.
That's a perfect one.
I mean there's this young Republican kid
from my Jujitsu class who's like,
somebody brought up climate change.
It was,
it wasn't even a conversation that was
involved in.
And he goes,
that's the cycle.
So there's always been a cycle of
change.
Are you a fucking earth scientists do
like,
what do you do?
You know,
you just got out of the marines and you
know,
I'm pretty sure you weren't studying
earth science in Afghanistan.
Like come on,
man is like a super complicated issue
that a lot of people that are,
they have decades of science behind them
and they're researching the,
the numbers.
They're trying to figure this out.
They got a consensus.
Yeah.
How come you're not with them?
You know,
I think a part,
I think part of it is the fact that the
way we've sort of been conditioned via
media is to feel empowered.
You know?
It's like you watch this,
you watch this clip and you think you're
getting information.
But in reality you're getting a
headline.
You know what I mean?
Because that's the flow that will keep
you engaged where you feel like you're
getting smarter,
but there's no way in hell you're
putting in the time to be educated on
certain subject matter.
He getting just enough to,
as I said before,
confirm kind of what you thought already
and then go out and pretend that as you
mentioned,
you're some kind of authority on,
on the situation when there's other
people out there that have invested so
much more in their perspective,
but instead of admitting like,
Hey,
yeah,
I don't know too much about it,
or it is a complicated issue or there's
more to the conversation,
there's something empowering about
picking aside,
even if you don't necessarily
know.
Well,
I think there's something very
problematic about headlines to like
these Gotcha clickbait headlines.
Like there was a headline recently about
Bill Nye the science guy,
Bill Nye Bowtie.
I grew up on that shit.
Well,
Bill Nye,
the science guy has done a fantastic
child.
No,
no,
no.
It's not a bad thing about him.
He's fine.
It wasn't him,
but Bill Nye the science guy.
He's done a fantastic job of trying to
make science interesting to people and
trying to educate people and trying to
make science something that's compelling
and make young people drawn to it.
So Bill Nye the science guy was having a
conversation with this guy and the
article,
the topic of the article or the,
uh,
the headline said,
Bill Nye favors prison terms for climate
deniers.
So you're like,
what the fuck?
Because it was bill Nye lost his fucking
mind.
Is he gone crazy?
So I,
I read this piece and then I watched the
actual interview with Bill Nye.
He never said such a thing ever.
Someone suggested that climate deniers
should go to jail because these energy
ceos and these people that are spreading
misinformation or directly harming the
people that are,
that are going to be affected by that.
They know that they're saying something
incorrect.
They do it to,
to distribute.
And there's other people who are going
to be affected by.
So Bill Nye says,
that's interesting when you're talking
about these energy ceos and these people
are making choices that are going to
directly affect our quality of life.
What do we do about it?
That's all.
I mean,
that's literally all he said.
The headline says,
Bill Nye favors climate deniers going to
jail.
It's clickbait bullshit.
So when you read that,
you're like,
he's a fucking fascist,
you know,
you don't even have scientists,
Gino,
where he got his degree and who's and
who's the type of personality,
who's most inclined to pick that as an
individual who doesn't want to invest in
discovering even the article they'll
just take because it's easier.
It's easier to take the headline and
form your perspective than it is to
invest into.
Also because the people that are putting
that headline out,
all they want to do is make people read
it.
That's it.
Yeah.
Watch it,
read it,
get the clicks to get the money.
That's where they get the ad clicks.
Impressions.
Yeah.
I mean that's the only thing they're
trying to do and they're trying to make
it as salacious and as inviting as
possible.
Yeah,
and the thing is,
the only way to really combat that is to
bounce,
is to get out of there as quickly as
possible because.
Because the way I understand it,
not necessarily an expert in the field,
kind of done a few things on youtube,
but like as far as the Google page rank
is concerned,
if you,
if a site is getting a quick bounce
rate,
like if people are landing on it and
leaving really quickly,
then it would,
it would,
it could potentially be ranked lower in
the future because of that.
Oh,
okay.
So you have to have a certain amount of
time that you hover on a site before.
So the money.
Yeah.
So no,
no,
not for them to unlock money,
but for them to surface in the future.
Like Google will penalize sites that
have low retention.
Oh,
just like videos that have low
retention.
That's very intelligent.
Yeah.
But the problem is that you probably had
to read the whole damn thing to get to
the conclusion that he didn't say it.
Well,
I watched the interview itself.
Oh,
it was video and yeah.
Was opposed video and there was a.
there's text along with the video.
Let's,
let's,
can we,
we should name the site the piece of
shit site that ruined your day.
Well,
it didn't ruin my day if you can find it
on Jake because I defended Bill Nye on
twitter and I said this is not his
words,
it's not what he was saying,
but let's watch the video itself and if
we watched the video itself,
you can see how deceptive it is to say
that he favors people who deny climate
change to go to jail because it's not
what he's saying at all.
Essentially he's saying that we should
look at people that are ruining the
earth,
like these energy ceos that wantonly
pollute these areas in order to gain
profit.
Here we go.
Just it so we could hear it
near the environmentalist here at the
people's climate march in 2014.
However,
he said that the climate deniers,
his word entity ceos belong at the Hague
with three square meals and a cot with
all the other war criminals.
What is your thought on that?
Do you think some of the rhetoric on
your side,
as I'm sure both sides,
but some of the rhetoric and just had to
get too carried away?
I mean,
you know,
what's your thought on jailing skeptics
as war criminals?
We'll see what happens.
Uh,
was it appropriate to jail the guys from
Enron?
Interesting.
Okay.
Right.
So we'll see what happens if was it
appropriate to jail people from the
cigarette industry you insisted,
insisted that this addictive product was
not addictive and so on.
And you think about in these cases,
for me as a taxpayer and voter,
uh,
the doubting,
the introduction of this extreme doubt,
will you go with extreme doubt about
climate change is affecting my quality
of life as a public citizen.
So I can see where people are very
concerned about this and are pursuing
criminal investigations as well as,
uh,
as well as engaging in discussions like
this.
That is a very measured response.
And he's essentially talking about
people like the BP people that fucking
polluted the golf.
That's what he's talking about.
He's not saying that you know someone
who like the kid from my Jujitsu class
that thinks it's a cycle of life,
you should go to jail.
Yeah,
and even even if you look at the very
end there,
he made sure to say,
I can see why people might think
something like that instead of
necessarily confirming that that's the
outcome he wants to see.
He's making good points and you if you
do like that merchants of doubt movie,
which is amazing movie.
If you watch that movie,
you realize that the same people that
were working for the tobacco industry
but they were denying the
addictive effects of tobacco are the
same people that are denying climate
change and human beings like not the
same kind of people,
but the exact same people.
Yeah,
that's a little bit much.
Well,
that's what they do and they get checks.
There's direct checks from these tobacco
companies as direct checks from these
energy companies.
They're getting paid for this.
You know,
coming back to the click bait subject.
I don't thing they click bait is always
bad.
No,
it's not always bad.
Like I think there's a difference
between click bait and lying.
Right?
You know,
like I think sometimes click bait gets
too much of a bad rap.
Like I'm in a sense of.
I think a headline should be intriguing.
It should Pique your interest,
should compel you to click yes.
Which you could say is bait,
you know,
but like I feel like navigating the real
world is full of clickbait.
Oh,
coffee is clickbait.
And when you see a girl on a tight skirt
that sounded Toyota Click Bait,
click bait.
Yeah.
So,
so in that sense,
I feel like,
you know,
there's a place for it,
but I think people use the technique to,
to essentially lie and it gives the
whole kind of system of bad rap.
Well,
in that Bill Nye situation,
there's not always a clickbait.
I think it's like he should fucking sue.
I mean,
not really,
but he goes,
not employed anymore.
It's not to get the ball rolling in that
direction.
But so many people on my timeline,
we're calling him a fascist and these
fucking left wingers are so far left now
they're right there.
Nobody had watched the video,
nobody had read it,
nobody had.
It was just immediate reaction with his
little information as possible for you
to be upset.
Yeah.
Again,
I just the knee jerk,
they need jerk response of the web,
you know,
there's like a lot of stuff going on
youtube right now.
I'm kind of immersed in the youtube
world in a social media world,
whenever there's like a lot of drama
that's getting,
getting rewarded recently.
Like what kind of drama?
Um,
in like without going into too much
detail,
there's like a,
there's a lot of,
is a lot of channels that popped up kind
of kind of hating on people.
Yeah,
that's all they do.
Yeah.
And that's like the entire agenda is to
use other people's content as the
vehicle for you to have a channel.
So like today I'm going to shit on this
video and tomorrow I'm gonna Shit on
that video.
And so there's this kind of conversation
about,
about whether or not that like is that
still fair use in that environment
because the understanding of meaning.
It's not definitive,
but the understanding I have a fair use
is that like if you're compelling people
to go look at the original,
like you just did with the information
about coyotes,
you,
you took a moment and you said,
okay,
this is this guy's research or whatever,
like,
so go check him out.
You actually did him a service there
instead of the alternative have you
could have just talked about and so on.
Well,
in the case of these types of videos,
people are using actual clips from these
that they're shitting on and that's
making up their channel.
Exactly.
Yeah,
and maybe more importantly there's,
they don't,
they don't compel you to go look at the
original because essentially they're
hating.
Why would you go as a viewer and go
source out this thing that this person
that you like is telling you is a piece
of shit anyways.
You're not going to go watch the
original,
right?
You're happier to,
to listen to this guy shit on stuff.
And so anyway,
the problem is that a algorithmically it
feels like drama cells,
right?
Just like,
just like in the regular world and so
some of these channels are rapidly
growing rapidly growing on the backs of
essentially making fun of people.
So there's some,
some sort of feeling in the community,
um,
that youtube has changed or you get a
lot of these people that are like make
youtube great again,
stuff like that.
But I mean I don't necessarily agree
with that,
but I think that there is maybe a
conversation to be had about,
um,
about how much freedom were willing to
give individuals to essentially build
their product on the back of other
people's will.
That is a,
an important issue when it comes to free
to fair use.
Like if someone just decided to make an
unbox unboxing,
unbox therapy channel and all their shit
is just shitting on what you do.
Look at this fucking dummy talking about
watches that.
Yeah,
that's not really fair use.
I mean they're kind of stealing your
content and becoming something with your
content only exclusively or other
people's content.
Like they don't really have content
there.
Content is other people's content and
you get a few layers deep on that.
And you realize it's kind of like,
it's kind of a fucked up scenario and
you wonder about what it breeds like a,
there was this issue with the,
the fine brothers.
Do you know who they are?
The fine brothers.
I've heard the woo hoo.
So they have just really popular
channel,
maybe like 10,
11,
12 million subscribers or something.
Jesus.
Yeah.
And they do react videos.
So.
Oh,
so they watched something and then they
react to it?
No,
no,
no.
They don't personally.
They have people on.
So it'd be like kids react that it'll be
like grandparents react and then it'll
be like famous youtubers react or
athletes react,
somebody reacting,
but essentially the core of their being,
they've been doing this for a long time.
The core aspect of the model is that
there's this thing you're reacting to
whether it's a viral video,
a trend,
whatever it might be.
While recently they tried to trademark
the term react so that anybody who
uploaded a video with the term react in
it,
that they could claim it and earn the ad
revenue.
Oh my God,
they must be stopped.
If you do know about this,
Jamie,
I tried to,
I think I told you about this at one
point when it first maybe like started
online chat,
kind of fucking cunt thinks that they
can own the word sentence.
So they launched this video so they
launched this video where,
um,
where essentially they're explaining how
this process will work for people.
They're like,
they're telling you that like you can
sign up with us today and we'll license
will license it back to you.
So you.
So who the fuck are these guys?
So they're out of their fucking mind.
They are out of their fucking money,
but here it gets better.
Yeah.
But here's the thing though,
real quick.
They're not the only ones.
So there's other companies out there
that have already been doing this in
quiet.
Um,
there's a company called Juke and media
and there was a story.
This guy,
uh,
what was his name?
Devin.
Supertramp.
He makes like action action videos.
I don't know what you would call them.
Action Videos.
Sure.
He used,
he used a title called people are
awesome.
That was the title of his video for his
demo reel for them.
I've seen that.
Yeah.
And,
and he,
he didn't know that you can mediate,
had already trademarked that title.
People are awesome.
They own it and have our own people are
awesome.
Exactly,
exactly.
Because whoever's got enough money to
pay the right lawyer,
God knows how it happened,
but they,
the,
the idea that you can trademark those
three words together,
that is so insane.
So they were able to issue a copyright
pulled down on his video and oh my.
And uh,
and so that was acting as his demo reel
to get jobs and stuff like that.
And so he did a follow up kind of
explaining what had happened.
But,
uh,
so anyway,
getting back to kind of the drama
component,
it's like people are kind of looking at
youtube now a little differently.
Like wow,
maybe here's this completely open space
where people were allowed to do whatever
they wanted,
but like,
what are the consequences of that?
Well,
it's,
you're putting out a certain type of
frequency,
right?
I mean,
that's what you're putting out.
If you're putting out a frequency,
what you're saying is you want to own
all the react videos.
That's the greedy can frequency
throughout the greedy combat bat signal
and you're letting everybody know you're
a piece of shit.
You're a piece of shit and you want to
steal money.
Well,
you know,
the best part is that stealing money,
right?
I mean,
that's stealing money.
If you make a reaction video,
you want to watch two girls,
one cup or guy getting run over by a
buffalo,
they want money from you watching that
video,
that stealing.
What they've done is they've used
lawyers to circumvent the system.
They've jacked the system and they're
going to try to steal.
Have they actually copyrighted the word
react.
So is this valid?
So they,
they,
uh,
they retracted.
What happened was the Internet lost its
shit as you would expect.
And these guys,
there were videos on youtube which were
live streams.
These were so funny when this was going
on.
Essentially what they were is the
subscriber count of their channel
shortly after the controversy had hit
and it will just like fell off a cliff,
like it should go to zero.
He never went to 100 percent,
go to zero.
It should go to zero.
It never went to zero,
don't deserve anything.
That's what they want to do.
You really want to reach out to everyone
using the word react and the video and
you want money from them.
Fuck you.
You're everything that's
wrong with distributing content over the
internet.
That's everything that's wrong with it.
You've taken one of the sneakiest most
diabolical fucking tricks and all of the
legal system and you've applied it to
this open free world of the Internet and
you're a piece of shit.
That's a parasitic behavior.
Let me ask you something.
That's cancer.
I agree.
They came back,
retracted it.
Apologize.
Fuck them.
Fuck them for even thinking that showed
the,
okay,
now you're going to give them a second
chance.
Fucking chances.
You can't think like that.
You can't do that.
You can't.
You can't go after people.
For some it's not like it has anything
to do.
Anything that you create,
you're just stealing.
There were,
there were some stories going around
that they had effectively shut down like
these small time channel,
Walmart completely like people who had
the chance.
Again to define bro,
you can't do that.
Man is probably some lawyer talked him
into doing that is going to be amazing.
God,
we got it.
Dude.
We have the copyright fuckers.
It's a weird.
That's so gross.
The idea behind going after people.
It's not like this something that you
created and you know they came along.
Something completely unique where you
want to copy.
Right.
Then what happened was that they were.
They went so far as trying to go after
ellen because she did.
She did reactions on TV.
Oh mine.
She would have kids,
kids reacting,
but you know what?
The crazy Chicago jail,
you should go to jail for that.
Crazy.
It's fucked up.
The whole legal system.
They didn't have format exist before
that.
Bill Cosby do that today.
I did a react to two girls,
one cup video,
like in 2003 or way back that Brian and
I did.
It should have copyright.
So gross.
It's so gross man.
But anyway.
Anyway,
I don't know.
I think um,
It's scary both ways because at the same
time you're like,
well,
do you really want youtube to come in as
this massive governing body to stop
stuff like this from happening?
Well,
that,
yeah,
I agree.
There's some clear cut shit like the
word react.
You can't use react or people are
awesome.
Fuck you,
man.
People are awesome.
It's still there and still functioning.
If we titled this video right here,
people are awesome.
We're gone.
Take it down.
They're ripping us down instantly.
That doesn't seem right to me.
That's just,
that's like saying love the copywriting,
the word love or you know,
or action.
Well,
people are off,
wasn't it?
Didn't designate.
People have said that.
Disney copyright a happy birthday.
Right?
Well happy birthday to you.
The song was copy written for a long
time,
but it's since been dissolved now
because he used to go to a restaurant
and they used to have to sing their own,
like happy,
happy birthday.
He couldn't sing happy birthday to a
song that we all know the iconic song.
Somebody owned it.
So if you wanted to sing that song in
your restaurant when someone came
in,
they were celebrating a birthday,
you would actually get fined.
You'd actually have to pay money.
Let me ask you this,
I mean,
just because we're on the topic,
how do you feel in general about like
digital rights and whatnot?
Like are you,
are you really fancy about it?
Like let's say you had some content.
I know you sometimes you have like
musicians on here,
right?
And they kind of seem to me to be like a
little bit out of touch with the
Internet space.
Um,
and I'm just wondering like if a person
is,
is purchasing or streaming or buying
something that somebody's trying to sell
digitally,
do you like how do you feel about that?
What does that,
how do you think that should work?
Selling things digitally well,
like let's say for example,
you had a record and you and you found
out that a bunch of people were pirating
it.
Would you go at how hard would you be
willing to go after them?
Well,
see,
it completely depends upon whether or
not what your business is.
So I,
I,
my feeling is that one of the things
about music and you could use the same
argument for standup comedy,
is that pirating in a lot of ways
empowers people.
Like,
like when someone puts up my stand up on
their youtube channel,
I'm not into taking that down because I
think that even when I was selling it,
I'm just not.
I'm not into taking that down and the
reason being is because I think the more
people see it,
the more people will come to see your
live shows,
the more people will come to support
your standup,
whether it's on Netflix or comedy
central or whatever.
They'll pay more attention to it.
So it's,
in a way it's kind of free advertising
in that way.
Music companies don't tend to think
about it that way and we had a recent
problem that was pretty fucking
disgusting.
Well,
we had an act on and uh,
the musical act played the,
we played a small section of one of
their songs and then the music company
that own that section,
the song wanted all the ad rights for
our show for that episode.
And so,
you know,
we contacted the artist and the artist
said,
well I'll,
I'll get that taken care of.
The music companies decision was no,
just tell them to not dispute the claim
and we'll take the ad revenue and then
it will be fine.
We won't take down the video.
You won't take down the,
it's a fucking three hour video.
We paid 15 seconds of a song and you
want all the ad revenue,
fuck you.
And I told them,
I'm like,
look dude,
you get this taken care of her.
I'm going to delete the episode.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Like this is ridiculous.
Like that's some greedy,
sneaky bullshit that record companies
are still trying to do because record
companies have to justify the fact
they've got x amount of employees and a
giant building on sunset.
You don't need that anymore.
Okay.
You're building.
Your Business is dead.
Okay.
It's sorry,
but this is what you got.
You got itunes,
music,
Google play,
and that's it.
That's it.
That's your business.
Now the real business is artists getting
their shit out on youtube and on on
social media,
and then doing concerts.
That's where they make the bulk of their
money.
The map.
They used to be the opposite.
He used to be artists made the bulk of
their money from the record sales and
then they made some of the money from
concerts.
So what happens was the record companies
would rip them off for record sales and
they would come up with all these
elaborate accounting methods too fake to
to fix the,
the profit.
So that made it look like all their
expenses had to be paid first before
they counted the profit that they didn't
take into consideration.
The artists learning how to play,
going on the road,
doing all these gigs,
creating this song all the time spent
writing,
they don't take that into consideration,
but they do calculate all their
employees,
all their expenses,
all their advertising revenue,
how much it costs to rent their
building,
how much it costs for insurance,
how much it costs for errors and
omissions insurance,
all those different things they do take
into account before you get paid.
So the artists,
we're fucked like there's a lot of
artists that got unbelievably bad record
deals,
like the reason why prince had changed
his name to a symbol because they
fucking owned his name,
so that crafty bastard just decided to
make his name some sort of a weird
symbol and become the artist formerly
known as Prince and they couldn't do
shit about it.
It was a really clever workaround for
prints,
but it was essentially in response to
these devious practices by these fucking
record companies.
Right?
So in that sense,
I think like if someone,
if you have an album and everybody loves
it and then people start pirating it and
then it gets all over the place.
Like some musicians.
I had Paul Stanley from kiss and he was,
I heard that one.
That's kind of what I'm referencing is
super adamant about it.
But he's so old school man.
He sold,
squeezed,
super adamant about it that it's still,
I get this vibe from those conversations
that like,
it's almost like these people are kind
of.
They're wishing that an ecosystem
existed still.
That doesn't of course.
Well he made fucking hundreds of
millions of dollars through that
ecosystem.
But I think the truth is the hard truth
is that at least on the economic side,
music isn't worth what it used to be
worth.
Absolutely.
And I,
and I don't like saying that because to
me it matters and like I,
I engage with it and it hasn't like an a
in a non economic weight.
It might mean more than ever now that
more people have access to it and you
can be exposed to so much more of it.
But unlike a purse song basis,
it's a supply and demand situation now
of we have an abundance of potential
music to interact with.
So there's no way that each song can
possibly be worth what it used to be
worth.
Well,
there's no way because it's so easy to
access now.
That's one thing.
And the other thing is the sheer numbers
of songs that get put out every day,
they all exist now.
You could go back and listen to some Roy
orbison from the 19 fifties or you can
listen to some shit that some new band
that you haven't heard of just put out
last week.
They haven't stopped making bands.
They haven't stopped making music.
It's all just adding up.
So let's say collective pilar music is
massive.
I would say
accelerating because the barrier to
entry in actually creating continues to
be lowered.
Yes.
Like actually the equipment you need
laptop,
that's it.
No laptop microphone.
When you can create music on Garageband,
100 percent,
you really can create a good.
Have you ever heard of tone,
Netta?
You to Annetta?
No tone.
That is an interesting cat man.
He's a guy who lives in Toronto and cool
link up.
He's like this weird androgynous guy in
his fifties.
He's got a kid who makes his own music
and he got famous for these songs on
Youtube.
This is a him.
He makes these videos were just puts up
a curtain behind him and he makes these
youtube videos and he sings these songs
and some of them are fucking good,
like,
pull up a really big cock that's uh,
that's one of my favorite place to
start.
But here's the thing,
it sounds like ridiculous,
right?
But it's actually a cool song.
Like,
listen to the.
Let's,
let's play it.
Give me some volume.
Jamie,
look at this guy.
There's no money in this forum.
It was just some Weirdo hanging out.
Good songs.
So of baseline.
But look at this video.
I mean,
this could not be any more geo
cities.com.
This is so low rent.
He does it in his apartment in Toronto.
He just has a camera pointed at him,
like really primitive.
He's got a bunch of different weird
dresses and he puts on outfits and it's
just really strange.
But this guy,
he does it all himself and he's got this
massive cult following from doing this
all himself.
I bought his vinyl.
I have A.
I owned this stuff.
I bought it on itunes and I bought the
vinyl of it too.
Support
and you know what?
That's a great point you make there.
I remember reading something recently,
don't quote me,
I don't know the figures,
but that artists,
a lot of artists are actually making
more off the vinyl than they are off the
digital even though the volume is so
much lower just because the actual per
unit cost is so high.
So like big bands are doing special
edition releases on vinyl and such to
kind of get back some of that lost
revenue that's existed because of
digital.
So that's an interesting angle to take.
But I think people are like you where
you're,
you're kind of almost doing it.
Not because you really need to have it
on vinyl,
but because you want to support
something you like a.
unfortunately,
I think there's a small percentage of
people that do that.
Most people,
if they can get it for free,
they get it for free because most people
are constantly worried about their
bills,
you know,
and if you can get something for free
and download it and no one's watching,
I mean that totally makes sense.
Yeah.
Artist making more of vinyl sales.
The streaming services.
If the article will streaming services
are the worst,
but are they?
They are and here's why.
They're owned by the record companies
and they have circumvented the whole
selling album system.
Right,
but is it,
isn't it,
isn't it the demand from the customer
that is always going to drive the
marketplace.
If people want streaming services,
sorry to break it to you.
That's the reality.
We have what they want free money to.
If you could just hand out from under,
that would be great as well.
But I mean in this particular case with
music,
doesn't music work better when you can
just launch any source process on the
planet?
Streaming services are profitable and
they're making a lot of money now.
The streaming services are making a lot
of money.
The artists aren't making artists and
artist doesn't need to be on spotify
plant.
There are plenty of examples of people
who pulled their stuff.
I'll spot Taylor swift.
Oh,
my podcast won't.
I won't put my pipe.
That's easy.
Yeah.
Well it's because of the amount of money
that they pay you is fucking
ridiculously low.
Right?
It's insane.
Taylor swift pull that shit off.
Spotify when you get a big art,
it's like Taylor swift pulling their
shit off.
Spotify,
I don't know how much you made off
spotify.
The figures maybe could discuss a couple
million or something,
but no,
she didn't make a couple of minutes.
Maybe 500,
maybe $500,000.
No,
no,
no.
It was so low.
It was insane.
I think it's somewhere in there waiting
for the biggest.
That's the biggest artists that exists
on the platform.
Well,
there was like we went over this before
where we put.
We looked at the one song that got
played the most on spotify and how much
that artists got for it and it was like
2000 bucks.
A fraction of a penny per play.
But see,
my,
my feeling though is is the spotify
audience,
are they a crossover of the itunes
audience or are they a crossover of the
pirating audience?
I think there are radio audience because
it's like instead of tuning into what
I'm saying is in the absence of spotify,
did those millions and millions of
users,
do they turn to itunes and give you the
ninety nine cents or do they give you
nothing?
Because if they're giving you nothing
and stealing it right thing.
Isn't spotify better than that
alternative because at least you,
if it's the pirating audience.
Exactly,
and this is the fear that this is the
thing that the music business doesn't
seem to want to address,
is that when napster hit,
everybody was a pirate.
I don't care who you are.
I walked around and talked to him.
He was a pirate.
It was so superior to any other method
for discovering music.
You even if you wanted,
you didn't want to steal things.
It's like,
fuck,
this is too good.
Right?
But the problem is this is not pirating
because pirating,
nobody benefited from.
Everybody got free stuff,
but no one profited with this recording,
these training service three,
would that be.
Well,
again,
this is not a direct,
but hold on,
let me finish my sentence.
Go ahead and record.
Companies created a platform of
financially profitable platform to
stream from.
That's a big difference between
that and pirating because pirating
doesn't have any central location is
just they're just floating around.
The only central location was napster.
Right?
So Nat Napster got taken down because of
that,
but napster was a really profitable like
these spotify is.
They've figured out a way to sort of
circumvent this whole downloading
situation,
make things streaming.
They stream everything.
There are alternatives to spotify,
like Jay z's service title.
Yeah,
and there are equally criticized.
except that one is owned by artists and
record labels and they have.
They have similar issues in trying to
pay actual artists because at the end of
the day,
if they raise the price of their
service,
if spotify goes from 10 bucks to 20,
people aren't going to have it.
Well,
what are the percentage of people that
use spotify that actually pay?
I bet it's way less.
I bet most people get the free spotify
go quite fast.
Majority.
Let's see.
I'm sure that the data is out there.
It's a good question,
but I don't think.
I don't think people are paying for it.
I guess what I'm trying to get back to
it was just this idea that music just
simply isn't as valuable as it was and I
think that it's tough as an artist.
Again,
like I can sense I consent.
I feel the pressure of artists right now
way you're saying,
yeah,
I know it's problematic in the way you
economically,
economically.
I'm not saying the value,
the inherent value in expression,
like maybe a better way to say it as the
market is completely changed and
dissolved there you can see it's not
that the work is less valuable.
It's arguably more valuable and
troubling times.
These are certainly troubling times and
music is a massive source of info
inspiration and yes,
and mood and enhancement and that's why
I also occurred it by saying like it's
more.
It's arguably more important emotionally
and all the rest of it,
but I'm just specifically talking about
that I think until I think artists need
to recognize that and then they can use
whatever system comes forth for how to
deliver,
uh,
the future of how we listen to music.
At least they're involved in that
process instead of just being like
participating in the current one,
like it's like you need to be on spotify
for a number of different reasons as an,
as an emerging artist because that's the
way people are discovering music.
So there's a lot of pressure there to
participate even in the,
even though you're not getting rewarded
for it as an emerging artist,
but as an artist that already is
established well and established making
money and you realize that spotify needs
people like you in order to legitimize
its company,
then it becomes an issue.
Right?
Well,
our subscriber growth in the last six
months or two felt it was,
what does that mean?
Okay,
just 10 million paid subscribers,
apple music,
10 million quota stats.
Now,
spotify just crossed $100.
Million total users paying number could
be more than $30 million.
Why don't they tell you that?
But what does that mean though?
That's not a real number.
They're saying could be more whenever
someone says,
could be more,
could be three people,
could be more than $30 million,
but it could be like five dudes.
Doesn't spotify announced as $20 million
paying subscriber.
Okay.
Back in June of 2015,
spotify announced as 20 million paying
subscribers with an ad based fee free
user base of $55 million.
Okay.
That's a pretty 75 million total and $20
million paying subscribers.
Huh?
See the problem is to.
They can.
They like if you have a podcast on it
and they can get rid of your ads,
they could put their own shit on it.
They want us and I can't.
I'm not making an argument for spotify.
I'm just like,
I just peaked my interest in a number
of.
A number of times that is being
discussed is like I think yeah,
big artists,
they can take a stand.
Taylor swift can take a stand.
She doesn't need the 500,000
bucks,
but if you look at those numbers,
those numbers,
that's a lot of money.
Yeah.
You're talking about 75 million people,
so 50,
whatever they are.
Fifty dollars million.
They're using ad revenue and then the
other $25 million,
they're actually paying for the service
and bucks.
That's an insane amount of money.
Yet 75 million people paying $10 a
month,
but you can see 25 million people paying
$10 a month and then the other 50 just
getting their ad revenue from.
That's a lot of fucking people.
Yeah,
but you can see that.
You can see the breakdown.
It's not like a.
it's not like hand over fist.
They're making money,
but it's still the record companies,
the record companies,
the ones that are in charge of this,
like they're.
They're massive contributors to these
shows.
Companies.
Yeah,
of course.
So they figured out a new way to not pay
artists and to stay open.
Stay valid.
Yeah.
Artists appear to be people that get
taken advantage of have been for the
last 15 years.
Jay z things,
a great thing to have artists doing it,
but see he see he was charging more and,
and that's why their user base there and
they're in trouble.
Uh,
he apparently they're in trouble because
they couldn't build a substantial user
base at the cost they wanted to get he
charging well,
what is it,
like 20 bucks?
Yeah,
but a higher quality.
You're getting to your higher quality
audio.
Yeah.
Lossless audio,
higher quality audio 20 people don't
care about that though,
which is the issue it for free or get
they just get the 3:20
kilobyte because I can't hear the
difference.
It's really hard to.
Well I had an amp once that I attached
to my ipod.
I had an ipod and an ipad amp.
I set it up once,
never using it again.
It was bullshit,
like it's barely better.
Convenience.
That's,
that's the thing.
Convenience.
In many ways,
trump's quality.
The trumps your uh,
well that's the beauty of itunes.
And then apple's music streaming
service.
We'll see.
But in the case of Itunes,
you can make the argument like apples
then involved in the promotion of your
business.
Right?
Because they're getting a huge chunk of
the biggest distribution of music right
now.
If you wouldn't break it down that way,
no cds are being sold at like best buy.
Unless you can really search really hard
and find the one best.
Buy The house.
Know who the fuck has cds anymore
through a Ct.
I had a white stripe cd in my office
that was cleaning out my office and I
was sitting on my desk.
I'm like,
I'm just gonna.
Throw this out.
I have it on my phone.
Why would I want.
I want a stupid copy of it that I'm not
going to plug in and where's the thought
on that?
I've been having a lot recently because
I've seen some things happen.
If all of the musiC,
like let's say
speak your 10 favorite albums of all
time,
you Don't have them a physical copy of,
but you have like the.
You have them saved on your apple music,
whatever it is,
whatever service you pick,
if it's all in the cloud,
they can technically go change that
music whenever they choose to change it.
Yeah.
Kanye west has been doing some really
recently right now where he put out an
album on title last month and for about
a month they were kind of tweaking it.
They were changing the mastering on it.
They were changing the featured artists
on it even on one song.
So while it was up,
he was tweaking.
He's gone back on another album that's
already been out for a long time now and
change some of the mastering on two of
those songs and some people think he
might be doing more.
No one knows what,
but it's a thought that I've been having
that.
Um,
one of my favorite albums I went to go
back and find that the track little
orders out of it's out of order now.
Some of the songs are missing and it's
because that artist has decided not to
have to the portion of that album up on
I or on spotify the way it originally
was.
So if you wanted to have that album,
you need to own It.
The way,
the way he put it out in 2011 where you
never have that actual album you have
with whatever they have existing in the
cloud and that's some deep shit or
that's some deep shit.
See,
I support someone being able to do that
because that's kind of interesting like
what he's doing by changing the
mastering and adding new tracks and
fucking around with things.
It actually is compelling like it makes
you want to kind of tune into it and
it's very intelligent on his part.
I think he does like as dumb as that
dude is egocentric [inaudible].
That dude Is.
He's so ridiculous,
but he makes some really good moves.
Like when he goes on this massive rant
about bill cosby being innocent right
before it releases his shit.
I mean it's,
It's a classic role.
Yeah.
It's a little too much for me most of
the time,
but he's so entwined in the world of
hate though.
He has so much hate coming at him.
It almost makes sense to cultivate that
hate and use it like judo,
which in the right direction.
He knows what he's doing for sure.
One hundred percent,
100 percent.
It happened when he tweets something
crazy.
I mean,
look,
do you really Think he thinks bill
cosby's in a sense.
Get the fuck outta here.
Nobody thinks bill cosby's innocent.
Even bill cosby sitting around with his
one fucking good.
I going,
maybe I did rape those girls.
Even he Is like coming to terms with the
fact that you might be a piece of shit.
His wife left him.
I mean even that crazy wife,
uh,
his smile through all those interviews,
she's like,
I'm ghost dark.
That's dark.
you look at those interviews and you
watch her.
Like she's smiling.
She knows,
she knows something's up.
Well,
she's been protected by royalty for so
long because he existed as a celebrity
in a strange time when an artist can get
away with almost anything.
I mean you Were in a bubble.
You were different.
And I think that being in a bubble.
And also I think for a guy like you were
I to try to even understand what it's
like to be as famous as bill cosby.
It's impossible.
I think it's probably an unmanageable
level of fame at a certain point in his
life,
you know,
especially when he had bIll cosby
himself and the cosby show and nbc.
He was fucking royalty man and during
that time he was inviting these girls to
come over and read scripts and suck his
dick and fucking drugging them and
they'd wake up with her panties down by
their ankles and,
and their hair.
They dIdn't know what the fuck was going
on and he just got away with it over and
over and over again.
And because he got away with it because
of the way people treated him,
it's sort of fostered this rear really
crazy sociopathic behavior that he had.
Did he.
Where does that stand?
Oh,
he's going to jail.
He is.
Oh yeah,
they're going to.
They're trying him and he's got the
criminal case is gonna go,
go forward.
The judge already ruled that she had
signed some shit saying that she
couldn't testIfy against him,
that she wouldn't bring charges and that
she wouldn't reveal the details of the
case.
But then she did reveal the details of
the case.
So you know what he did?
He sued her,
so he's suing her for going back on her
deal because he paid her off.
I think he paid her like several million
dollars to keep her mouth shut and
because she is now talking about it now,
he's suing her for that money back.
And the argument was that because they
had made this deal,
he shouldn't be able to be prosecuted,
but unfortunately for him the deal that
he had made was a verbal deal only.
There was nothing written down.
This is one of the things that the judge
had said like,
you got to get this shit written down,
dude,
we're going to trial.
So he's.
He's going to be charged.
And it was recently announced it over
the last couple of days that they're
charging him.
There's a criminal case on me and he's
an old old man with half an eyeball.
Would that be a jury in that case?
That's a good question.
Or a judge?
I don't know.
That's a very good question because you
gotta wonder being a juror up against
bill cosby.
I don't think anybody would think that
he's innocent at this point in time.
I don't think anybody thinks he's
innocent.
Right.
I think it's the water's completely
tainted in a way.
Kanye west,
he believes that.
I think in a way what they're doing.
Well,
chuck d,
that was one of the fucking sad as shit.
Chuck d was calling him dr cosby.
Why is that?
Because of the show.
Was he a doctor on the show?
Because he's a doctor,
lIke an honorary degree.
They retracted.
Oh,
so he was calling from public enemy.
What does with those titles?
You know,
like you're a doctor,
so everywhere you go everyone has to
call you doctor.
He actually wanted people to call him dr
cosby.
That was one of his things.
He's so fucking weird guy,
man.
I've told this story before,
but I'll say it again just for you.
There was a show that I did in seattle,
the seattle area,
this casino,
and one of the people that was working
there said that cosby used to have these
people sit down before the show.
He had the.
All the employees like the ushers,
the door people,
they sit down and watch him eat dinner,
who sit there and eat curry and they had
to watch him stand in the room and watch
him eat well before the show.
Watch him watching me.
It's one of those things you want people
to watch him eat his curry so you'd sit
down there and eat and they would all
just stand there and say nothing.
They weren't allowed to talk.
They sit down there and watch them eat
and he also had security guards tuck him
in bed at night like you'd go and lay
down in his bed and he wanted them to
tuck him in.
Shut the lights out.
Let me ask you this.
Is this the case of justIce?
Severely fucked up individual or it's
just the case of have a relatively
normal individual getting fucked up by
circumstances like being this super
famous theorist.
You're responsible for getting fucked
up.
If you're a normal person and you get
super famous and you become fucked up,
you are responsible.
It's like a high percentage do though.
Yeah,
but not in that way.
That's an extreme version.
It's a different kind of way.
Ego ego might get in the way and trip
off a lot of people who might trip over
the dick of ego.
That's comment I saw when,
um,
when prince died recently I signed
infographic.
I don't even know.
Maybe you tweeted it about the average
age of male pop stars when they die.
I dunno,
I dunno who tweeted it.
It was how he was the exact age,
55 or whatever age he was.
Fifty four,
somewhere in there.
That that's the average age for a male
pops are female.
Wasn't too different either.
Well,
his situation was he was addicted to
painkillers,
pink pill pull out.
It just recently recently came out that
he had overdosed by.
He had been refusing treatment for aids
as well.
Is that true?
I don't know if that's true.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Let's,
let's look that up.
But I know for sure he had a hip issue,
like a severe hip problem that he
probably need hip surgery and he was
taking pain medication and he had had
overdosed on pain medication.
Yeah.
No,
he was definitely addicted to pain
medications while I just realized I just
remembered a story coming out shortly
after about hiv that he had believed
that,
that he wasn't going to take treatment.
Print suffered from aids,
but refuse treatment.
Believed god will cure him.
Us tabloid claims.
See?
Yeah.
See,
that's a us tablet clamps.
But he was a christian scientist.
Wasn't near a jehovah's witness.
Jehovah's witness don't use the medicine
medicine,
right?
Isn't that what's going on?
Because he.
Cause he got it back in a minute.
Then how the fuck is he taking pain
pills then?
Supposedly he was on opiates too,
so I don't think.
Well that's pain pills.
Yeah.
That doesn't make that logic doesn't
make sense I suppose.
Well,
people are just fucking convenient with
their logic on thing.
yeah.
The things that weird guy,
man.
First of all,
prince was like androgynous and is all
about free love anymore.
High heels,
but he didn't like gay people.
Do you know,
one of the things that prince prince is
like a known homophobe and one of the
things that he said in a recent
interview,
and I hate to disparage him in his death
because he was a brilliant artist and
all that good stuff,
but he was talking about how one of the
problems with the world today is that
god said all these rules and then people
just decide they want to stick their
dick and this whole with that hole and
just do anything they want to do and you
can't do that.
And they were asking them about gay
marriage and you know,
he was saying that this is not what god
wanted.
This is not what god asked for.
Like see if you can find the exact quote
because it was pretty disturbing coming
from a guy that you expect because of
his sort of androgynous nature and how
weird you think he's like going further
in that direction because he's getting
older.
No,
no,
no.
I meant just maybe because of his actual
personal experience,
like,
like in a way,
you know,
some people they overcompensate on one
side.
Honestly,
I think with prince was based on what
I've seen of his interviews,
I think he was insanely sheltered
because he was so famous in that he
could basically say anything and nobody
would disagree with him and he he
cultivated some really fucking wacky
opinions.
First of all,
he believed that the government was
spraying things in the sky that made
people fight in the ghetto.
I remember that.
I heard that interview.
Yeah,
it's insane.
It was like everybody would be fine and
then they would be spraying the sky and
then why is everybody fighting?
Why are we all fighting?
Because you're poor.
You're living in the ghetto and there's
crime and that's just what happens.
Crime riddled areas.
There's violence.
It's not the government spraying the sky
like what a random thing to do.
The government just decided to spray the
entire city and then hope that everybody
beats the shit out of each other.
For what purpose?
Very convenient.
They have money in ambulances,
like what?
Where's the.
Where's the profit margin in this?
Millions of dollars a spraying the sky
with anger,
chemicals and what fucking chemicals
have been proven to make people angry
when you sprayed from the sky?
Um,
yeah.
Whiskey vapor probably be more fucking
and hugging.
I mean,
what percentage of people actually get
angry when they get drunk?
There's another one because think about
all the people that go to bars,
right?
Yeah.
You get up fucking bar filled with
people.
You've got a thousand people in there.
How many of them become angry when
they're drunk?
It's not even one.
It's a small percent.
It's a very rare thing that people get
super angry and violent because they're
drunk.
Most like,
I get happY.
Same when I'm drunk.
I'm hugging and laughing and I might get
a little obnoxious,
but I'm not mean.
I'm definitely not looking to start
fights.
So yeah,
that's a weird one.
I think,
um,
some people will say like,
hey,
that's,
that guy is an angry drunk.
Like you've heard that people are.
Yeah.
You've heard that before.
But is that just maybe who they are all
the time?
I think there's a deep seated.
Yeah,
and then the alcohol sort of course is
it out of them?
Maybe the alcohol releases your
inhibitions and you're angry.
What does it say?
Prince denies anti gay rights remarks.
New yorker stands by story.
This is from 2008.
Yeah,
but see,
the problem is they quoted him.
It was like there were direct quotes.
He.
Well,
as far as this story came out,
I'm assuming when he died,
a lot of coats came out and stuff you
said in this,
this story which I traced back,
which was when he was still alive,
obviously he came out after the story
came out,
the new yorker said he was grossly
misquoted and they took everything I
said out of context.
right?
Stood by their story.
However.
Well,
let's read the context though.
I mean even when you read the actual
quote itself,
here's the quote.
It's a little bit higher.
There we go.
Sponsor.
He goes,
you got the republicans.
Basically they want to live according to
the bible,
but there's a problem with
interpretation.
uh,
and you've got some churches,
some people basically doing things and
saying comes from here,
but it doesn't.
Then you've got the opposite of the
spectrum.
You got blue,
you've got the democrats,
and they're like,
you could do whatever you want,
gay marriage,
whatever,
but neither of them is right.
I'm asked about his perspective
on social issues.
Gay marriage,
abortion.
Prince tapped his bible and said god
came to earth and saw people sticking it
wherever and doing it with whatever,
and he just cleared it all out.
He was like,
enough,
okay.
That's hilarious because a lot of people
fucked each other in the ass listening
to let's go crazy how many people,
how many people suck?
Cock,
because it was like,
we're going to party like it's 1999.
And they just said,
fuck it.
I'll just do ecstasy in my asshole.
You know?
I mean it's,
I think he's sheltered or was sheltered
and I think he's a brilliant,
like,
like the outlier of outliers when it
comes to brilliant artists and I think
that you just,
you by yourself to luck too much.
You don't,
you don't get to mingle,
you don't get to hang with.
You don't have real conversations.
But that's why I say like even in the
case of bill cosby,
are we looking at a condition of the
circumstance because if we have data
that says,
hey,
pop stars are dying,
I'm 30 years before any regular public
on average like these,
these people obviously have an unusual
enough circumstance that it's affecting
all of them the same.
Unless the type of people drawn to that
career in the first place are already
substantially different than the rest of
the public.
Well,
they're definitely substantially
different than the rest of the public in
that they've developed as an entertainer
from their formative years.
I mean prince was an artist and a
musician when he was very young and then
when he came out with,
I want to be your lover.
I think he was only like 20 years old or
something like that.
How old was he when I wanna be your
lover came out?
Yeah,
definitely.
that was a fucking jam too.
God damn,
that was a good song because I remember
I was living in boston.
I'm 48.
He was 55,
so he's not that much older than me.
When he died and I was living in boston
when that song came out and it was a jaw
dropper,
I was like,
who is this guy with no shirt on and the
cover trying.
You're trying to figure out what the
hell it is,
20 or 21,
20 or 21 and that is a fucking beautiful
songs to this day.
I'll play that song out of nowhere and
it's just,
it's who was an amazing artist.
So if he was that good at 20,
21,
I mean he was involved in music from the
time he was a small boy.
So he developed in a very bizarre and
strange way and was under the microphone
at an incredibly young age.
Went to be that huge at 20 years old and
also to be such a revolutionary guy when
it came to style and fashion today I had
an overcoat when I was like 21,
a long overcoat because I saw principle
just to listen to prince music.
I loved prince when I was a kid.
He was so good.
It was so different and interesting.
You know,
with so many good songs like
controversy,
you know,
he had some and then also like some guys
sort of like came along with him like
morris day and the time because they
were in purple rain.
TheY sort of came along with him and
they got famous for a brief period of
time too.
He was amazing,
man.
It was amazing.
But I thinK I've always said this,
that I think you can't.
There's,
there's a balance in this World that you
can achieve when you achieve greatness,
when you achieve that kind of greatness.
I think it's at this,
at that is that the sacrifice of
balance,
whether it's balancing your social life
or balance in your,
your ability to have a,
a healthy and a objective perspective.
I think in order like,
and I think that's what we're seeing
with kanye west to in order to like
really go after something and just be
obsessed with it to the point of just
carving out this magnificent diamond of
art.
You got to be a fucking nuts man.
You've got to be richard pryor.
You know,
you gotta be nuts.
You gotta be out of your fucking mind to
make something perfect,
and what he made was perfect.
I mean,
purple rain is god damn perfect.
He was perfect.
This is shit that he did that you just
to this day,
you just go,
god damn.
He was so good that all the other stuff
is probably a symptom of a lack of
balance and development and his overall
life that led to this incredible
brilliance and his art form.
Right?
So there has to be.
It has to be.
You have to sacrifice,
you have to take from somewhere where
they say james cameron's out of his
fucking mind frame.
They say,
James Cameron is out of his fucking
mind,
and if you're on a set with james
hamman,
like if someone's painting a wall,
he'll fucking take the paint brush away
from you.
I can do it like this.
And they'll start doing it.
Right.
It's got to be like this because he's a
madman.
And that's why,
I mean James Cameron made a fucking
submarine and went to the bottom of the
ocean with it.
You know about all that I heard about
that.
He was researching for the record,
for know for his new movie.
It's going to do avatar to underwater
this crazy fuck his filming shit under
water.
I mean he's not just like a
groundbreaking guy.
He's like the groundbreaking guys are
calling him up for advice because he's
way ahead of everybody.
He's a maniac.
He's making a fucking submarine to film
a movie and he's breaking world records
in a single manned submarine.
Look at this.
This is him.
I mean this is.
He fucking went to the bottom of the
ocean by himself in this fucking thing
that he created.
I mean,
he's revolutionizing the science behind
filming underwater things so that he can
make movies.
You think anybody tells him what to do.
Who the fuck?
Tell him what to do.
Like nobody,
like none of nobody.
He's wife better shut the fuck up to
everybody,
but shut the fuck up.
You're James Cameron talks when they're
about to make a movie and he goes in
there and it's just like they just write
the check and get the fuck out of.
They don't even write checks.
No,
I bet he probably writes the checks and
then they wrote a check to and what
after it's all over.
He's insanely wealthy,
insanely brilliant and some of his
movies are some of the greatest movies
of all time.
I mean he's just,
he's just knows how to do it big.
Like,
you know,
there's some people that thought like
avatar was both pocahontas and spoons
like stop,
look,
yes,
there's iconic themes that exist in a
bunch of different mediums,
but that movie is fucking amazing.
And if you
overthink it and you say over the soil
food,
this is fucking wow.
you mean you could say the same for a
lot of the classic stories,
but he just,
he nailed this insane version of that
genre.
It's like a rock and roll song.
Like there's some classic rock and roll
themes that you would,
you'd see if you heard this song is like
themes and songs that you can just kind
of accept because it's cool to hear them
in songs and that's essentially what
he's done on a grand scale or an avatar.
Yeah,
no doubt.
No dispute.
Yeah.
Cameron's a bad ass pad motherfucker.
To be that bad of a motherfucker.
You got to be crazy.
He's making for avatar.
Sequel.
Yeah.
You got to be a bad motherfucker to do
that,
you know,
but I imagine the stress,
the stress of having that project.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Moving people around.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
GeTting location and go to the bottom of
the ocean and that's the only way to
make a movie.
You can't make a movie by yourself.
No.
You got to have actors.
You've got to read the script.
Todd.
I have a guy who points the camera.
I hate the whole.
All that.
All the baggage.
All the people.
it's a nightmare.
It's weight.
That's why I'm a comedian,
dude.
That's really simple.
Well,
that's why I'm on youtube.
So simple.
Just do whatever you want.
I had a bit of a nightmare situation out
here.
Out here.
Yeah,
out here.
it's why I'm out here.
I'm ouT here to be here on this show
right now,
but yesterday I was,
you know,
it was on.
I was on set.
I had to shoot this day.
I'm not gonna mention any brands or
names,
but it's like fucking 100 people on set,
of course.
I mean,
you don't need them and then they want
to try the ges and the soup.
Yes.
Yeah,
that's the best way to put it and it's
just.
How about if you wear a different suit
for every different segment?
It's like I've made over 850 fucking
product videos that millions of people
choose to watch,
choose,
choose.
This is not one of these situations
where you've got to stick it in front of
their face on the way to where they're
going.
This is something people like,
like let me look at the god damn thing
and get excited about it.
Well guess what?
News flash.
We don't have to fake it.
They fake shit that doesn't need to be
faked because it fits the protocol of
the machine.
You know what I mean?
It's like it just sucks the life out of
all of it.
Like I think there's this thing that
happens.
I mean,
and granted whatever,
james cameron's brilliant and the shit
they do in hollywood is fucking amazing
and all the rest of it.
But I'm in this weird situation where
like,
I'm the guy.
Yeah,
I'm not acting right.
I'm the guy.
So if I go on this thing and I don't
look like the guy,
well that's not why I'm here.
like what are they trying to change?
Like what are they specifically fucking
with?
Oh man,
all of it.
You may love it.
You name it.
That's so great.
Okay,
so here's an example.
Like when I do my videos,
I want everything to be live.
Everything we shoot three concurrent
angles.
If we catch it,
we catch it.
If we don't so be it.
That's what it was.
Right?
So it's authentic.
Yeah.
Because I want to capture like,
you know,
I feel like your relationship with the
product is a lot like a relationship
with another person.
Now you can.
You guys think I'm perverted at this
point.
I don't mean in tHat way,
joe.
Okay.
I didn't say anything,
dude.
You just,
just the way you're looking at me
looking at you that way all the time,
but I'm saying it's like,
it's like this process of like getting
to know the thing and well,
as a person who watches you,
sorry to interrupt you,
but yeah,
that authenticity comes through and it's
one of the reasons why your videos are
so compelling because like when you open
up a video and you're checking out a new
phone and you're going over the edges
and you're experiencing it for the first
time with the person that's watching the
video.
Yes.
I want to be you the proxy version of
you.
like how would you engage with this
thing?
And in many cases the defacto standard
for these types of videos was like a
person who had,
um,
was,
was more sort of journalistic.
Like they had it.
They're,
they're,
they're expected to make a report on the
thing.
And he's like,
that's cool.
I respect that.
That's part of it too.
but at the same time it's like it
doesn't,
that part of it doesn't necessarily
capture the excitement associated with
the thing,
the oohs and aahs and and all that kind
of natural reaction,
which is impossible to fake all the rest
of it.
You can all the rest of it when it comes
to like,
let's do that line again because I don't
know,
I didn't say you didn't say the spec,
right,
or whatever.
Like that would be the equivalent of the
situation I was in yesterday.
But it's like I'm willing to sacrifice
some of that to get the intangible
stuff,
which is the oohs and ahs that will
never happen again.
Not in the same way,
you know.
No,
I,
I agree with you and I think that you
understand what you're doing and you
understand the appeal of what you're
doing and to sacrifice that,
to polish it,
to make it more professional or to make
them.
That's actually going to lessen the
appeal of it.
And that's what they don't understand.
It's a fine line.
It's like those fucking videos where
people have these edits every five
seconds they say something is a cut and
they say something as a cut,
you know that style of youtube video
cut,
that shit is gross man and there's a guy
who did that recently.
It was a video about bow hunting and
he's trying to do that style and bow
hunting,
which is one of the most organic,
visceral,
primal things you could ever engage in
as a human being.
You're going to go out and collect your
food with a sharp stick,
you know,
and so this guy is using this like this
common thing that you see like these
girls do,
and then I was like,
there's got to be a better way.
A little app,
but I'm not bouncing around the screen
that was in this corner.
Then I wasn't doing that.
He was standing right in front of the
fast cuts.
Like there was no pauses and it was
disconcerting.
It's like throws you off.
That is the opposite of authentic
because you know that there's all these
edits and those edits take you out.
Also,
those edits treat you like you're a
like,
you're so fucking stupid.
You can't even listen to a guy talk.
Here's your attention span is so short.
I can't listen to louis open this vr box
and go to this thing in real time and
inspect the overall.
To be quite honest with you,
I'm kind of,
you know,
you mean you have this platform here
where people sit down for hours,
you know,
that's,
that's becoming not,
you know,
that's not the status quo on the
internet.
The internet keeps chopping it in the
other direction.
Getting shorter and shorter conversation
has to move faster.
You got to jump to the bowhunting guys.
Got to jump around the screen and so on.
And I mean if you get obsessed with the
analytics and stuff,
you can see like how,
how often an average person watches for
and so on.
And there's no,
there's no denying the fact that
people's attention spans are shrinking,
but it's like,
do you want to contribute to that or do
you think that there's enough people
that are willing to accept the
alternative because you know,
you've got.
You've got an example here,
which is unusual.
Why do you think,
what do you think happens here?
That people stick around for three
hours?
I never thought about it.
That's what happeNs.
I just said I like talking to people,
so let's record it.
Right.
You know what I mean?
But man,
I took a lot of heat in the beginning.
You were telling me I had to edit it.
Oh really?
People.
Oh my god.
It was like some of the earliest
comments were like,
why is it showed three hours long?
This is bullshit.
No one's going to listen to three hours.
Like even my friends were telling me
this like,
dude,
you to edit it,
make it an hour.
I go,
why go after an hour?
People just shut it off.
If they don't want to watch more than an
hour or listen to it was listened back.
Then you don't want to listen to more
than an hour.
Just shut it off at an hour.
Who gets interesting?
Yeah,
but it was a who gives a fuck thing?
Like,
I'm going to do what I want to do.
I'm not trying to make money off this,
I'm not trying to do anything unusual.
I just like having conversations with
people,
so let's bring in someone interesting
and let's talk because the art of
conversation,
like just having a conversation for the
purpose of having a conversation is lost
in a lot of venues because what you're
gettIng instead is interviews.
You know,
like you and I are friends.
We've been friends for a couple of years
now.
When we sit down,
I'm super confident that we're just
going to have fun and we're going to
talk and we're going to have a
conversation.
That's why this podcast,
I left my hoUse today and I was like,
I'm going to go have fun with lewis.
We're going to have a good conversation.
It's going to be cool because that's
what I want to hear.
I want to hear people having a
conversation and so for me it was just a
matter of,
well,
I'm going to have this conversation.
It gives me an opportunity to sit down
with someone for three hours,
which is super rare in this world when.
Sure.
When do you ever get a chance to put
your phone aside and just sit down?
We'll just look at a friend in the eyes
and just talk about it.
I've before.
I mean when I was,
you know,
I've been here for a couple of days and
know I'm telling people,
okay,
you know,
saturday I can't hang out,
whatever.
I'm gonna be on the podcast.
And they're like,
what do you guys do to prepare for that
and on your podcast?
I'm like,
no,
nothing.
Like you actually just sit down and you
just start talking and they're like,
how long for three hours.
No,
come on.
How do you do it?
You don't like this some kind of magic
to it when it's,
when as you said it is the simplest
thing.
It's like it's like,
or it's maybe it's a forgotten thing of
just being able to
do this well if you actually are
interested in life and you find another
person who is actually interested in
libraries,
I think the hard part is ending it three
hours,
three hours.
We're talking.
We haven't even talked about a million
different things.
I've been watching your videos.
I got a lot of fucking questions.
You know,
there's a lot going on in the world.
I mean,
there's so much to talk about.
I just,
I don't understand people who don't have
anything to say that.
That to me is perplexing.
When someone says,
how can you find things to talk about
for three hours?
Like how do you not talk?
Yeah.
Well in that sense,
I think that this kind of like a,
a service being like it's surprising to
me how many.
Like when I'm saying,
okay,
I'm going to be on here and I put it on
my twitter or whatever,
like how many people are pumped about
it,
pumped.
Like,
oh thank god we're amazing.
Right?
Like they love the idea of it.
For me,
it's a departure from the way I normally
communicate with them.
Right.
For you it's the standard,
so I think you're really aware of it.
It gets,
it gets personal in a different way when
you're using this medium where there
aren't these definitive parameters that
exist in your,
your typical youtube video,
your typical sweet or vine or whatever
it is.
Like those ones are all,
so it's almost like every social media
is,
it has it's kind of structure that it
landed on for the standard,
the status quo,
but you,
you've been doing this for a while now
and you've been on many different
platforms and you just kept in here the
same essentially like as far as the
format is concerned.
But I think there is something to be
said for.
I think what ends up happening,
we end giving people that access is that
it means more to them like they,
they,
that you simply can't get to know
somebody in a three minute segment that
you can in three hours.
It'S impossible.
So what would they actually end up
getting here is,
uh,
is something that matters substantially
more to them.
Will they kind of get like digital
friendships?
That's what I'm saying.
Yeah,
I think that's exactly.
I think how it's looked at and I think
in,
in a world where we,
we realized that there is an
increasingly short attention span.
You wonder how much of this kind of
stuff here actually replaces the real
world version of it.
If,
if people can't be in a movie theater
without being on their phones,
if they can't drive without being on
their phones,
if this thing,
if we are literally building new
pathways in our heads for how we,
how we look at spare time,
then is this thing in alternative to
that like,
is this,
is this where people get it?
Well,
you know what I think a lot of people do
with podcasts is one of the things that
I do with podcasts,
it replaced radio in my car.
Oh,
for me,
200 percent.
When I drive around,
I don't listen to the radio anymore.
I listen to different podcasts and media
or radio lab,
ted radio hour.
All my friends like joey diaz,
his podcasts and ras and dunkin's.
I listened to all my friends podcasts
and different people's podcasts.
I just think it's an amazing thing.
I love the fact that at a red light you
could just go to your thing,
press
play,
find it.
Oh,
there's a new episode of this out.
Boom,
press play,
and it goes.
So it stimulates you.
When you're in your car.
it gives you interesting conversations
when you're on a plane or when you're at
the gym and it replaces a lot of
traditional standard media in that way.
Also because there's no ads,
there's ads in the beginning and if you
want you fast forward through those
fuckers,
but the three hours of the podcast is
totally uninterrupted.
That's unusual though.
Well,
it's my choice.
I was unwilling to do it any other way
because I don't want it to be
interrupted.
They try to get you to change.
Yeah,
they still do.
Really fuck you.
It's not available.
It's not.
I'm just not doing it.
They want me to interrupt the middle of
the conversation and go,
you know,
I don't know if you know about
squarespace lewis,
but squarespace is a platform against
squarespace.
Squarespace.
They're awesome,
but I.
It wasn't squarespace that was asking me
instead that the agents,
right sell these course,
they zero fucks about the content
itself,
about the actual important part.
It's this.
There was another thing that I had to
fight with.
They were like,
there's no way you're going to get ads
unless they do it in the middle of the
show.
I go,
well then I'm not going to have.
That's like,
this is not like my primary source of
income.
So for me thIs is a labor of love,
if you will.
I mean,
I want to do it correctly and making me
feel special here,
what it is,
but I don't have anybody on that.
I don't want to have on.
There is no one that tells me what to do
is know producer.
So if I have someone like you or
anybody,
it's because I think it is going to be
an interesting conversation.
I'm looking forward to having it.
That's it.
That's the agenda.
That's the whole thing.
So I'm not interrupting that.
yeah,
I don't,
I don't have any.
I think it's a great message.
I gotta be honest with you.
I don't think there's a lot of people
out there pushing that particular
message in the space I'm in.
I think,
uh,
you know,
especially since he's a particularly on
the video side,
on the youtube site,
it's emerging as a real business,
real enterprise.
What'S.
Because there's so much money in it,
there's so much money in it.
It's craziness.
Yeah,
it's bonkers.
But at the same time,
there's no rule book on it,
you know,
there's no parameters.
There's nobody out there saying,
hey dude,
like you're taking a risk on that one.
Here's what's going to happen in
[inaudible].
I seen it because I've been there.
And like,
um,
I think to hear somebody like you who's
had success in this space to say,
hey,
fuck it,
I don't compromise.
I'm going to do it this way.
Even when a million people are telling
me to do it.
Otherwise,
I think for a lot of people starting out
that might have a youtube channel,
they might whatever,
to,
to be empowered by knowing that like,
you can do it.
I got steve rinella to do it.
The mediator podcasts,
I don't interrupt the podcast anymore.
Oh,
he used to.
They used to interrupt it.
Like if you listen to the dan flores
episode,
there's no interruptions and that's what
makes it good.
Here's my ethic.
Number one,
don't do anything.
Or do you do your best?
Obviously.
Do your best to make it entertaining.
Don't do anything that would compromise
the quality of it just for profit and as
long as you just do that,
do your best.
Don't completely honest here.
Like I fucked up on number of occasions
like in,
in,
in completing what you just said.
There are times
where I get too deep,
too deep and then I'm in it and I'm
like,
holy fuck,
this is a.
This is a nightmare.
Like how so?
Well,
I mean with,
with a brand or a sponsorship or
something like that where where it'll be
like,
I'll know it's a nightmare once I'm in
it,
but even though I've been sold a bill of
goods,
that isn't the thing that I actually
signed up for.
It happens frequently with mean I'm
dealing with the biggest brands on the
planet and they're like,
yeah,
it's going to be completely
conversational.
You're jusT going to discover the god
damn thing or whatever.
And then you get there and it's like,
here's your script.
And I was like,
what the fuck?
Oh,
so you like for a certain product they
actually do if you're there for a launch
or something to give you scripts.
No big.
I don't read a script.
I never read a goddamn split.
They tried to.
Exactly.
whoa.
And what does that conversation like
when you tell them?
No,
it's like a bunch of producers
pretending that it's impossible for me
to say that.
Oh,
how about this?
How about them trying to change your
wardrobe to try to change your wardrobe?
I'm like,
dude,
I've been in his hoodie forever.
I got the hat on,
like people know how I look.
Right.
It's this weird situation of like
advertisers and the business side of the
thing not being used to.
The idea of people have of basically
disrespecting the audience is what it
is.
Because you're going to come at it from,
from a respect point of view.
I'm going to come at it from a
respectful point of view,
but they're used to like inserting
things that nobody wants.
So they automatically assume if they're
working with you that they got to that,
that nobody wants what you're talking
about in reference to that project or
whatever.
So they come at it from a negative,
from a guilty point of view as opposed
to like,
hey,
people like this guy,
the way he is like,
leave him alone,
you know,
that's what they signed up for.
Why are we trying to rewrite it?
Because they want to in the soup.
That's what it is,
is like if you're going to have that
environment,
if you're going to have this situation
where there's like 50 or 100 people to
get this piece of content,
everybody in there needs to carve out
that.
That grew for themselves,
a place to fit well and they look,
they look for some way that they can
tell everybody.
Like lewis was going to wear that hat.
Yes.
And I told him,
look,
yes,
see this,
I feel like you must have encountered.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
And how do you deal with it?
well,
luckily in the podcast I really didn't
encounter that much.
Countered it outside of the podcast and
it's one of the reasons like doing fear
factor was a big one.
Like sometimes I would show up with
stubble and they'd be like,
you got to shave.
I go,
why?
Why do I have to shave somebody's gonna,
wash your show and go,
this motherfucker didn't shave today.
I'm changing the channel.
Mike,
stop,
and we would have these arguments,
right?
I'd have some stubble on my face and
they would tell me,
you could really got to shave.
I'm like,
you can't tell me how to look.
This is what I am.
Don't look ridiculous.
I don't have a fucking big dildo poking
out of my forehead.
Like there's.
There's nothing unusual about how I
look.
You don't.
You don't get that right.
It's really fucked up when you think
about it.
Imagine right now if you and I were
wearing makeup,
looking at each other like powder and
shit,
like regulars awake.
Make regular guys having a conversation
in makeup.
That's so fucked up to think about.
Well,
let me tell you something.
There are podcasts where they put makeup
on the podcast.
That's a fact.
I've seen a lady standing there and
she'll powder your forehead.
I know she'll.
She'll just go,
I'm going to put some anti shine on your
nose.
How?
How pissed off must make people in in
the makeup hollywood makeup business be
at like youtube and online media as a
numbers.
When they get the numbers and they
realize it's not.
You don't really have to make someone
that put a cartoon.
Yeah.
In fact,
you could make the argument that if our
goal is to connect with people on the
other end form these relationships,
better to look to just in every way to
be as close as you can to the real you,
because that's how you form
relationships in real life.
Unless you're never going to see people
in real life unless you're like one of
those instagram girls just it puts
filters on and it takes pictures.
Oversight.
I know a dude who does that.
I know a comedian dude who does that
filters on his fucking pictures and you
look at them and you go,
whoa,
whoa.
What's going on with your face?
You're a cartoon.
Yeah.
You know what that is?
That's the,
uh,
that's the beauty mode,
but it's on,
it's on a lot of korean devices,
korean devices specifically.
Really.
I like samsung type things,
samsung type things,
lg type things.
They have a beauty mode while you know,
you know what the situation now over
their vision,
regardless,
they do have a situation when it comes
to plastic surgery that's streamline.
Yap.
So that's where I'm going with it.
I'm very bizarre.
It's a.
It makes.
So this beauty mode,
it makes your eyes bigger,
smooth into your skin.
It changes the color.
The complexion can lighten it up.
It's very bizarre.
Is it only work on lg and samsung ships
from.
I'm sure you could get an app on any
phone,
but if you get like a korean model,
a korean version of pretty much any
flagship,
it's gonna.
That's the default camera app is gonna.
It actually is going to have beauty mode
on by by default.
What?
Yeah,
it's going to be like default.
Yeah.
You're going to be like at like level
five out of 10 potential beauty mode,
but you know,
you see these selfies or whatever it
looks like the person is painted.
You've seen them.
I'm sure it's,
uh,
I,
there was one famous situation where
that chef.
Who's the chef,
mario batali.
No,
the one who's always yelling.
Mr.
No,
no,
no.
The one who's yelling at people like,
get out of my kitchen,
gordon ramsay,
gordon ramsay.
And the mom of the kardashians.
Oh,
jesus.
What a combo.
So she took the photo filter out.
They each took their own.
And one of them,
somebody did like a comparison.
Oh,
that's right.
Because she of course had a filter on.
Oh,
being time made her look like an angel.
Big time.
So yeah.
It's a good point though.
It's like,
what?
As we continue to progress into this
digital realm,
which one is the real you?
What?
We're hiding that we're hiding that
reality with these filters.
And I.
That's okay.
There you go.
Okay.
There's her look at her face.
Look at his.
Okay.
That is so bizarre.
There's the reality.
Oh jesus christ.
Wow.
What a difference.
She's like in a fog.
They're repeat.
That mode of photographing people is so
creepy.
But I,
like I said,
I know a male comedian.
he used that.
Well,
I don't know man.
It'S all of it is weird.
Like I need to kind of in your head,
he needs to set up some rules.
That's what I want to do.
We need the rule book.
We need the social media rule book.
You definitely do.
You kind of have it,
you know,
we,
we kind of have it in a way where a
personal qri there's a clear rule book.
We look at that one outta here,
but it's unwritten.
It is undermining to write it down.
Why,
you know,
and I know everybody knows that's true.
It is kind of,
it is kind of fun that way,
but I feel like we could,
maybe we could maybe save the situation.
We can saying no,
you don't want to save it.
You want to leave them to be able to
still do that.
Yeah,
it's true.
Do you want people to look like a
fucking cartoon?
Okay.
Joe,
how many,
how many times can you,
how many times do you take a selfie
before you post it?
Um,
what's your maximum?
But not that many men come joke.
It was.
The truth is,
and I'm a 48 year old guy who's not that
good.
Look,
there's not a whole lot I'm doing to
make it look any better.
I might look for the best like smile or
like this one,
this one looks best,
taken a few,
but it's me.
Every one of them has this weird filter.
Are we capping it at some point?
Like,
oh,
you're going like fuck,
I just took it.
Someone you're trying to do,
like maybe trying to get everything in
the background.
It's really dependent upon what you're
trying to do,
but it's never more than like a couple.
You ever gone over 10?
I don't believe so unless I was trying
to achieve something very strange.
I love how everybody's like a fine art
photographer.
Now that we have phones.
I mean,
what else would I.
How would I ever get to 10?
I don't.
I don't know.
I,
I'm kind of joking around to be quite
honest,
but like I catch myself sometimes like
what the fuck am I doing?
I'm a grown ass man in this place here.
Like what am I taking,
you know,
I kind of um,
do you do duck lips ass out the arch?
I might break the internet.
Joe pussy out arch.
it's a but then and then I think about
it.
I think put okay.
If I catch myself fairly confident guy,
you know,
I'm happy with myself to a certain
degree if I catch myself at 10 or
whatever the number is.
How many goddamn photos are these
professional instagram girls taking
before they pick one to post the very
good point.
Could it be 100?
Some of them it's probably shocking
numbers and then some of them what's
really weird because they're taking
these really like supposedly clandestine
stein photos.
But like who's taken the photo?
Like why do you,
why you like looking off in the distance
whimsically like,
no one's around.
It's a fucking guy right there with the
camera.
You lying bitch,
what are we doing here?
What are we selling?
In the early days of instagram,
one of the unwritten rules was only
phone photos,
like if it's,
if it didn't come off your phone,
you just broke the rules of instagram.
Oh,
I didn't know there was a rule.
It's again,
if I had joe,
if I had the book,
you would know it.
It'll be on amazon.com.
There'll be kickstarting it.
Actually,
that's crazy because that guy that sent
me these wolf put pictures.
Yeah.
It should pull up his,
uh,
his instagram.
So we could give this guy some.
No,
no,
no.
See.
See,
in his particular case,
those obviously aren't phone photos and
he and he has broken the rules.
But that rule went away a long time ago.
Everybody did go because photos from
real cameras look amazing.
Yeah.
But this.
Okay.
That's okay.
I see what your point is.
Yeah.
But why?
Why would there be only photos from
that?
Because it's kind of like cheating,
like insta,
instagram.
It should be like in the moment.
Okay.
And,
and what you just described,
like this model overlooking cabo or
whatever it is,
that's not instagram.
I mean,
it is,
it is now,
but in the early days it sure as hell
wasn't so.
Did people get upset when they saw like
a professional photography in days?
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
They,
they would,
uh,
amongst some of the tight knit groups on
there,
some of the bigger,
a photo pages that emerged.
It was kind of like,
it was kinda like,
hey,
I had to,
I built this business on the back of a
stupid cell phone camera and then some
person comes in with all these heavy
duty equipment and kind of interrupts it
and I don't know how much of it was just
them being competitive and how much of
it was them thinking,
believing in the ethic of,
of it being instant friend meg has an
instagram page where it's all just
polaroids.
A photo of polaroid photo of a polaroid.
It's kind of cool.
Yeah.
That's all she does.
Just take.
Or maybe she scans them.
I don't know if she scans them for the
record.
I'm not like,
I'm not of the opinion is the cjm
underscore photographer.
His name is chris Montana and uh,
he,
he sent us these photos of this,
uh,
these wolves.
See that wolf down there?
That's one of the ones that he sent us.
I mean,
that is a fucking amazing photograph.
Looking right at number wolf.
Yeah.
He uh.
Oh.
It says he did.
He got it.
He's got a promo code right now.
Promo code rogan.
Um,
so if you go to chris Montana,
m o n t a n o j.r.com.
Chris Montana jr.
Com.
And use the promo code rogan.
You get 20 percent off your entire
purchase.
I guess he has these prints for sale,
but let me pull it up so people could
see it here.
yeah,
that's amazing stuff.
I mean,
I think anytime you look at a
photograph,
when you go,
how did he get that shot?
That's a good sign.
So we're going to put these on the wall.
I'm getting tired of looking at elvis.
Wow.
I'm going to decorate the back wall.
The thing is,
it's made out of metal on metal.
That's wild.
You know,
if I had one thing that I could look at
forever,
like if I had only one kind of art,
it would absolutely be wildlife art.
Like wildlife art to me is the most
compelling.
It's just something about,
especially like predators,
like eagles and wolves.
Did you see that video was making the
rounds of the eagle today?
The cat.
okay,
fine.
You can probably tweeted it then.
I did it.
It's funny when,
when you come up,
when I come on here,
I'm like,
every time I'm referencing something I'm
like,
did was posted that or was it somebody
else?
But yeah,
that's,
that's uh,
it's weird how people have that kind of
a,
how they have that perception of like
nature only applies to stuff that I
don't recognize.
Exactly.
Know what I mean?
Like you're not a part of it.
It's like eating a salmon is fine,
but an eagle capturing a cat and feeding
it to his chicks [inaudible] not good.
And then he had to,
I guess I was reading through the
article there and they had to say like,
oh,
the cat was probably already dead and
bullshit.
Bullshit.
They fucking scoop up cats all the time
or why not?
That's a lie.
Yeah.
Why not?
We're weird.
We have a hierarchy of animals and
things like cats and dogs.
Are they more favorable?
That's why that yulin dog festival in
China is so problematic.
Dog eating.
Yeah.
My brother ate dog.
Yeah,
he.
Well,
he was hit China here and there and he.
He said that there was one point where
they were at a restaurant that all he
had was dog,
so he was all they had.
It was a dog.
It was just dog restaurants like
Kentucky fried chicken,
but dogs,
Kentucky fried dogs.
But anyway,
I don't know.
It just is problematic.
I think it comes back maybe full circle
to the whole.
The way that we started this
conversation just about people,
whatever the convenient,
didn't want to compartmentalize certain
things.
Like that's the way that's going to be
and it's not a.
Yeah,
well it's a similar thing to what the
coyotes and me seeing a wolf here and
he's like,
whoa.
Right.
You get this reset of like,
holy shit.
That's a natural.
It feels small and you can probably even
more so because you go out,
you actually go out in the wilderness
and whatnot,
go hunting and whatnot.
I mean,
could you.
It's a humbling experience.
I assume it's very humbling.
It's very psychedelic and people think
that that sounds crazy like going out to
kill an animal psychedelic,
but what psychedelic about it is its
boundary dissolving and that you enter
into a truly wild world and there was
these large animals that live in this
wild world and you feel their world.
There's no cell phone servIce out there.
You're in the woods with the trees and
the animals and you're a part of this
natural environment for a very brief
time and you know people like,
well,
what would you want to go there and kill
those animals in this?
There's all these weird arguments that
you could have back and forth about
this.
These conversations you can have about
whether or not it's okay to kill these
animals.
What
I've.
I've made these conversations with
myself,
believe me,
like before I started hunting for the
first time,
my thought was I am either going to go
hunting and I'm going to never eat meat
again.
I'm going to become vegan or I'm going
to be a hunter,
and I decided to be a hunter and one of
the reasons why I decided to be a hunter
is I realized I don't like factory
farming.
I think it's fucked up.
I think the way we get our food,
I think we've made a huge mistake.
It's a great decision,
but a huge mistake at the same time in
that we've all.
We've decided to live in these gigantic
urban areas in these urban areas that
becomes our natural world and in that
natural world,
we don't see tigers.
We don't see wolves,
we don't see bears.
We don't see these animals.
So our association with these animals is
very unnatural.
Our world consists of streets and cars
and buildings and elevators,
and that's our natural world.
That's the natural world that we live
in.
When you go out into the woods and you,
you see the actual natural world,
the tooth thing and claw natural world,
and you find mountain lions shit that
has hair in it and you look around and
you know,
you see an elk at the top of a ridge and
he's,
you know,
trying to fuck all these other cow elk
and trying to fight all these bowls that
are coming in.
And I mean we last time was elk hunting.
They had found a dead elk that had been
killed by another elk is thousand pound
animal that died because this other
animal with fucking a tree grown out of
it's head spirited in the side and
killed it.
I mean,
it's really wild to see like these
things kill each other so they can fuck.
And you're,
you're out in that world.
And when,
when you do it makes everything seem,
uh,
the,
the whole predator prey experience seems
very intensified.
Like your,
your connection to your food is very
intense.
It's the whole thing is like.
And also from a wildlife management
standpoint,
you kind of what we're talking about
with lyme disease.
The reason why they have lyme disease,
because they have too many deer,
they have too many deer,
they have these ticks,
these ticks get on these deer.
They developed this disease and this,
these ticks get onto people and it's
because of an over abundance of dhea,
the overpopulation,
they can nip that shit in the bud if
they could figure out how to dwindle
down the population of deer.
When you have too many animals,
too many game animals,
too many,
too many wild animals,
and the balance gets over run.
Whether it's too many wolves are too
many bear or too many deer like wildlife
biologists understand what the correct
numbers are better to keep that harmony
and you have two options.
One option number one,
hunters,
they pay money.
They go out there and the money from
those tags is responsible for the
protection of these wildlife areas,
protection of habitat,
or option number two,
they hire snipers.
They hire people to go out there and
kill these animals and that's what
they're doing in Zimbabwe.
With lions,
they,
they're killing us.
They're killing 200 lions rather this
year because they have so many lions now
because of the the what happened with
the dentist or the dentist went over and
shot.
Cecil.
The lion became this big thing.
Well,
they had control of their population.
They had this sort of ecosystem balanced
out and the hunter's got scared and
hunter's got scared.
They moved off.
They don't.
They don't go there anymore,
and so now they have all these lines
that are destroying this undulate
population,
so they made a wildlife biologist
decision to go in there and killed 200
lions to lessen the impact on the
undulates.
It's all in north America.
They do that with bears and they do that
with mountain lions in most states.
They figure out what is the healthy
number or all these animals can coexist.
Yeah,
well it's.
I mean it's one thing to have an opinion
on that matter and it's a different
thing to actually have exposure and then
maintain that opinion.
Know what I mean?
It's one thing to be on twitter,
sitting on your couch watching tv,
saying a couple words about how you
think about the planet,
the wilderness and so on.
He say,
but to maintain that perspective when
you're actually in it.
Yeah,
I would.
I would have to believe in speculate
that that's a difficult thing to do.
Well,
there's a deep respect that comes in a
deep love for an animal that is going to
sustain you and feed you,
and
the thing about it is these animals,
they're not going to live forever if you
don't do that.
Their life is incredibly brutal,
incredibly short,
and what you're doing as a hunter,
as you're going into that world and
you're dipping your toes into it for a
brief amount of time a week or whatever
it takes to find an animal and the
animal's going to feed you for months.
And to me it's so much more.
It's so much more ethical than buying it
from a store.
I mean that not even can't even be
argued,
but from a vegan perspective,
like they don't want anything to die.
They want everything to live forever,
but it doesn't work that way because
first of all,
if you don't shoot animals,
if you don't like,
if,
if you don't control bear populations,
the berrigan and decimate the moose
population,
they're going to decimate the deer
population.
They eat all the calves,
they eat all the fonz.
That's just what they do.
That's what they've always done.
Not only that,
they go in,
they eat each other.
Bears are all cannibals.
I mean there's a massive amount of
cannibalism in in the bear world,
the cubs.
It's one of the first things that males
do when they come out of hibernation,
and if you don't control their
populations,
they will do that to every fucking thing
that's out in the woods and the only
thing that can control their population
is another predator and the only
predator for bears is people sit and
that the people will go.
What about people?
People who are over populated,
man,
why don't you fucking shoot people,
but why don't you kill yourself?
How about I start with you?
Sounds about right.
You non human loving.
Fuck yeah.
I mean like life eats life and that is a
weird reality.
There is a part of it though with the
complicated part of it is that obviously
everybody can't do that.
Exactly.
I mean,
well that is true,
but that doesn't mean that everybody
can't survive on the amount of money
that you make every year.
That doesn't mean you should give up
that money because everybody can't make
the amount of money that you make.
Are you singling me out here for
anybody?
I mean,
look,
if you make more than $35,000
a year,
you're in the top one percent of the
world.
We live in a very strange time.
I just mean like I think.
I think some people,
people's perspectives are formed by in
some ways their capabilities.
If all they ever knew it was going to
mcdonald's or whatever and it's just,
it's a hard thing to break.
It is a hard thing to break and it's a
hard thing to recognize that it can't,
you know?
What will people say it's not
sustainable for the entire population?
Well,
I'm not the entire population.
Not only that,
what we're doing is not sustainable for
the entire population of the world.
Actually,
I don't know.
I'm kind of optimistic about it.
I don't know if it's sustainable or not.
Sustainable.
Hunting's not.
There's not enough animals.
There's just not gotten pharma.
Yeah,
I mean if you wanted to eat the way
people eat today,
there has to be some sort of farming
going on.
If you want to eat it,
the amount of meat and people find that
problematic and that's for good reason.
There's a way to do the farming part
better.
Maybe there's certainly as,
but there's also problems with just
eating vegetables just to your
vegetables.
First of all,
to this place is massive amounts of
wildlife.
Second of all,
when you buy grain,
you're.
You are responsible indirectly for the
death of thousands of animals.
There's just no way around it.
Those combines are indiscriminate and
they,
they grind up deer fawns and rabbits and
rats and mice and groundhogs and
everything else.
Then on top of that,
pesticides,
you know,
I mean if you,
unless you're buying absolute organic
where there's no pesticides used,
your for sure going to be responsible
for the death of millions of bucks.
If you live in a house,
you display.
You know what I mean?
Like everybody's fucking with animals
and on top of that,
there's some very real and compelling
evidence that plants have a level of
intelligence.
We don't want to think of them as
sentience because they can't communicate
with us.
They don't say anything to us like out
on chop me down.
It hurts,
but they communicate with each other.
There's something that plants do now.
This is,
this is a crazy thing that they found
with giraffes,
that the plants that giraffes eat,
if they're downwind.
So like if the giraffes are eating this
plant and the wind from the plant,
they're eating goes downwind and catches
these other,
these other plants,
the plants will change the chemical
composition of their leaves and become
more bitter,
making them less attractive to
predation.
So they're communicating with each other
like telepathic.
I don't remember what planet was that
does that,
but they have proven that plants do
calculations that plants are doing some
sort of some kind of strange mathematics
that they're communicating with each
other.
They know and other plants are being
chopped down.
There's some shit going on with life and
we don't.
We don't have the capability to
understand dolphins.
Okay.
We don't know what they're saying.
When dolphins communicate with each
other,
they have a complex language.
They have dialects,
they sound differently in different
parts of the world.
They recognize each other.
They have a very bizarre way of
communicating that we have not been able
to decipher,
but we recognize that that's going on
because it's close enough to our own
kind of communication that we say,
oh,
these things are smart and they're
talking to each other.
Well,
there's something going on with plants
too,
and this is a recent thing with a
science behind it is starting to catch
up.
Whether it's emerging,
whether they're doing these tasks and
they're running these numbers and they
go,
look,
they're not.
They're not wooden in the sense that
it's not like you're not talking about a
rock like a plant.
A living plant has some sort of
awareness.
There's something going on and different
ones have more awareness,
but in there's some sort of
communication through the actual,
the actual ecology of the ground.
I mean,
the ground itself is a living thing.
Dirt itself is some sort of an organism,
right?
Mean it is a like a.
Like a person is like a person is an
ecosystem.
We're responsible for the lives of
untold trillions of bacteria that live
inside of us.
Right?
Well,
that's the same thing can be said of the
dirt itself.
The dirt itself as some sort of a
strange balanced ecosystem were worms
and bacteria and all of these different
funguses and all these different
lifeforms all exist together and then
the plant feeds off of those life forms
and the plant in some respects relies on
the death of biological things like
mammals and rats and bugs.
It relies on them for the very nutrients
that it needs to make a plant in the
first place.
It's all very,
very complex.
All connected.
It's all connected and to deny that your
eating life some strange life form when
you're having a salad is the height of
convenience.
There's nothing wrong with eating a
salad,
but I don't think there's anything wrong
with eating and elk steak either.
Life is consuming life and it's just
more obvious when you shoot an animal
and you're there when it died.
What about.
What about when humans find a way to
grow meat in a lab,
it's going to be very interesting and
they kind of.
They're right there.
It.
I remember reading something about they
had the.
They had the meat ready to go,
but they couldn't actually consume it
because the governing body or whatever
for for food and beverage or whoever the
hell it is,
said that it would be illegal to consume
it for some reason.
I can some probably some food lobby or
something,
but,
but theoretically,
right.
We could find a way to manufacture all
this shit.
One hundred percent.
Yeah,
we can.
Where there's going to be away and then
what do we do?
What do we do at wildlife?
Then?
It's a good question.
Well here's a.
Here's a better question,
what do we do when we have robot fuck
dolls and there's no,
no need to date to what would happen.
I don't think we're,
that.
I don't.
I think we're already there.
We're pretty close because,
I mean,
it's not a robot fuck doll,
but you have,
you have porn already.
Which many people,
many people consider to be one of the
sort of uh,
uh,
stone building blocks.
That's where I was looking for building
blocks of the web,
like the reason that the web was adopted
or vhs or dvds or whatever.
Html five and it all goes the way of
porn.
Porn adopts that.
Everything.
Everything else follows the sort of
fundamental needs that people have and
so on.
And so yeah,
I mean you have to wonder how
disconnected from other people we can,
we can get as this stuff continues to
improve.
We were looking earlier at this,
this hollow lens development kit.
I was recently playing with the htc
vive,
which is,
that's probably the vr headset to get
right now and it's like,
man,
these experiences are getting,
they're getting closer and you look at
the camera that facebook just came out
with,
I don't know,
it's like 60,000
bucks.
Facebook buying oculus has to be one of
the creepiest things on the planet like
to know that they see where that's going
and that they were interested in that
and what their sort of agenda and
objectives are currently.
Well,
virtual communities,
that's what's going to happen.
We're all going to be able to sync up
together and some virtual place and
we'll all be like low calorie takers at
that point.
We're all going to look like asian
supermodels,
text.
That's what we're going to be.
You're going to go there and we're all
going to sync up with each other and
we're probably going to be able to fuck
each other in some sort of a virtual
environment.
Yeah,
it's like total recall,
man,
but the thing is it's actually tone that
is going to be playing.
Got a really,
really,
really nice guy.
The thing is like the physiology part of
it is only part part of the conversation
does also the psychological part in that
for the most part I feel like there's a
trade off.
I feel like women in my life make me
different than I would be if they
weren't in my life.
One hundred percent and in many ways I
think they make me a more,
a more,
a more moderate person.
Like about the way I think about a lot
of things because you want to fuck and
you want whatever,
whatever,
whatever the reasoning is the biological
part pulls you in,
but then there's a psychological
aftermath of you now being a different
person because of the.
Because of the moves you made in the
first place and then there's a
compromise you have to figure out how
much do you compromise?
Like do you become some sort of henpeck
bitch?
Yes.
Because we know a lot of guys that are
bitches because they've given in to the
aggression of their mate like they're
made is the dominant one in the
relationship.
You know,
I have a relative like that.
I have an uncle like that,
he's got a wife,
it just runs the ship and everybody just
gets the fuck out of the way.
So part part,
part of me worries though that like in
the absence of those interactions,
what happens to the psyche of males and
females now just kind of allowed to
bathe in their own perspective over and
over and over again and never have to
make those adjustments and never have to
make those compromises because
historically that's.
That hasn't really been a good sign.
You send a bunch of guys into,
into jail without any females or you
send them off to war without any
females.
They become fucking savages,
pretty god damn quickly.
So is that what's going to happen is
just it's the digital onslaught going to
create some kind of hyper aggressive
male.
It may do the opposite.
Oh,
it may do the opposite because all of
your sexual needs will be satisfied so
easily,
so easily that you'll be satiated.
So your,
your need for sex is not going to be
there anymore.
So maybe your need for posturing and
aggression won't be there anymore
because the need for like for you to be
preferable to the other men,
you don't have to posture,
you don't have to,
you don't have to peacock.
And if you could just put on your
facebook virtual reality headset and go
fuck the asian supermodel and another
dimension like why would you be with you
on that?
But what about never having to
compromise?
That's a problem.
See,
because we talked before,
but all these people that suck because
they want to control everything about
their lives because they don't want to
interact with people.
All got to be their way.
What the fuck is this lineup?
What the fuck is this car in front of
me?
What the fuck?
They said that they want to complain
about everything.
I want to sue this person over here and
do this over there and in an environment
where we take that a step further and
now we never compromised for other
people.
When we do emerge,
emerge from our headset world,
what?
What is our personality?
It's a good question because like what?
What does our personality based on most
of our personality is based on the long
running equation of your life,
all the interactions you've ever had
with other people and how they've
reacted to you and how you've adjusted
your personality accordingly.
Yes,
there's a cool this,
this is reminding me of something.
There's a cool a channel on youtube
called smarter everyday.
I don't know if you've ever,
ever heard of.
Okay,
it's a guy,
he's a scientist and he does these,
uh,
he does these videos that sort of a,
I don't know,
a attack sort of everyday things that
might seem obvious but then break them
down a little bit and what he did a
video about a bicycle.
And what happened was this was a bicycle
that was,
had a,
had a gear in the steering.
So that left was now wright and wright
was now left.
Oh,
I remember this.
Maybe you've seen this before.
And what he did was he took this bicycle
around various talks that he was giving
a different universities and stuff.
And uh,
and he made a bet to people in the
audience,
but you $100 that nobody in here can
ride this bike.
And of course every time he got somebody
coming up going,
I'm going,
I can do it easily.
Whatever they get on the bike,
they couldn't pedal it once,
even even though they are completely
aware of what change has been made to
it.
And so he spent six months before he
could actually get down the street on
his bike.
That was reversed.
And what he talks about in the video is
about how he has the pathways that he
had created in his mind for how to ride
a bike.
Right.
Were,
were very difficult to rewrite that.
Once they're in there,
they're in there.
And so he did an experiment where he
took his eight year old,
I want to say,
who had just recently learned how to
ride a bike the right way,
gave him the same bike.
And in a couple of weeks he had it down
the kid.
The kid could write either bike,
he could ride the reverse bike or the
regular bike.
And so he was building this kind of,
um,
perspective that like,
but potentially when it comes to
language,
when it comes to learning,
when it comes to everything,
that the absence of those pathways for
young people actually makes them more,
uh,
flexible.
Yeah.
A greater ability to change their way of
thinking on a more frequent basis
because he was looking big picture at
it.
And the funny thing is when he went back
to go back to the regular bike,
he couldn't ride the regular bike.
Hm.
Wow.
That doesn't make any.
Maybe he's retarded.
If that's possible.
I doubt it though.
He's a really smart guy.
He talked to a bunch of.
Might just be on gordon dated.
I mean it's like I would like to see the
bike.
We're getting you the bike.
I like to see the same thing with an
athlete that they could figure it out.
Well they might have a better
understanding of how their body works.
It's true.
I don't think that.
I don't know how critical the test was.
I think he had,
he had a number of test subjects
because I just feel like it's like a
boat,
you know,
like when you're steering a boat,
if you want to go right,
you turn the rudder left.
You know what I'm saying?
Like if you have an outboard motor
behind you and you want to go to the
right,
you have to go again.
Conceptually it makes complete sense.
It's the fact that it's actually,
there it is.
Here it is.
It's actually not the fact that you
don't know how it's working.
It's the fact that you are keep
triggering back into that state of mind
of riding a bike.
When you're riding a bike,
you're not thinking about riding a bike.
You're just writing it.
Yeah,
you can watch it.
Please send a bunch of people fail in in
the actual video.
Well,
it makes complete sense because pathways
that you've developed are incredibly
difficult to break and one of the things
that when I was teaching martial arts I
found was it's way easier to teach a
person who has no martial arts
experience whatsoever.
Then a person who studied a different
style where they might be using bad
mechanics,
so they developed bad mechanics and then
they came to a really good school.
It was incredibly difficult to break
them of their bad habits.
Whereas if I could get two people and
one person was um,
they save one person maybe even had a
black belt in one style and one person
was a white belt.
I feel like if the black belt had bad
technique and bad form and bad,
bad mechanics,
if I could watch the two of them
progress over a few years,
eventually the white belt would surpass
the black belt and move forward and be
able to reach their full potential where
the black belt with bad mechanics,
even though they might know how to fight
good because they might know what they
can do and even though what they're
doing is not optimized with the most
effective technique.
They know what,
how it works and how it fits in the
language of the community.
Like I think fighting is kind of like a
language.
And even with like your shitty words and
your bad grammar,
you could still form a sentence and
still talk and communicate with people
that's similar to the articulation of a
real polished technical martial artist
versus a person with a very limited
vocabulary with street knowledge,
you know,
you can,
the person with the polish vocabulary
will be able to express themselves more
clearly and expressing yourself is what
you're actually doing when you're
fighting a really cool way to look at
it.
So the person who starts out with
nothing is better off than the person
who starts out with shit technique.
Unless the person who starts out with
shit technique is super open minded and
has no ego and is willing or is it very
good control of the ego and is willing
to try to completely learn everything
from scratch and not go into it saying,
hey,
I'm already blackballed.
Already know my shit.
Right?
Yeah.
Most people do.
It's a,
it's an interesting topic.
I think it applies across the board to
be quite honest.
Know I,
um,
I started working with a couple of
people in,
in my,
uh,
for my channel.
I have an editor now,
he's a guy who I've known for a long
time,
but he doesn't have a background in
editing at all.
He didn't have any kind of preconceived
notions of what these videos should look
like,
but I,
but I liked that when,
when he came in because I was like,
you know,
I can kind of finesse this idea of how I
want things to look and how I want them
to be and he can kind of learn starting
with this,
these parameters,
the ones that,
you know,
as opposed to somebody coming in who
would have been like a professional in
this space.
And I think,
um,
that particular perspective is something
that a lot of startups are doing as well
when it comes to hiring new people is
it's like,
are you hiring a person and their
skillset or are you hiring a
personality?
Are you hiring potential?
And what is the difference in each of
those decisions?
Sure.
If you hire a professional,
it probably,
you're gonna be able to snap your
fingers and be and be achieving things
immediately.
But in the end is that person that's
capable of flexing and floating along
with the needs of that business over
time.
That's good point.
And also do they come into that business
with a preconceived notion of what their
future is going to be based on,
like I'm going to move from here to
there and then I'll get a corner office
and then blah.
And they have this idea already mapped
out in front of them and then when
things aren't that way,
they may be disappointed or don't know
how to react.
Yeah.
This is the equivalent of the bicycle
pathway thing
mapped out in like a different scenario
and.
But it gets me thinking about myself too
in the,
in,
in what are my pathways that I can't
break in.
Went in thinking about subject matter in
looking at the way I behave because I
feel like I feel like the not being able
to ride the bike the other way is the
perfect example of how we,
how we treat a lot of things like our.
I think our perspective should always be
floating.
We should always be able to,
you know,
in politics and stuff they're always
done,
but that guy,
he flipped flopped.
He used to say that.
Now he says yes.
Says,
well,
isn't that normal?
Isn't that life will flip flopping and
politics is hilarious because it's the
one part of life where you're supposed
to have a preformed decision by the time
you enter into public office and that
never changes.
Like you can't evolve.
It's weird as a society
seems that we,
we value for some reason a person who
doesn't change their opinion when in
reality it should be the other thing.
Well also some of these opinions,
it's not like murder is bad,
you know what I mean?
I mean there are complex issues that
were under a lot of consideration.
Yes.
You know,
I mean especially when it comes to
things about maybe the economy or things
about what should and shouldn't be a
crime and you know,
and what,
you know,
is it actually a crime to make people
prisoners?
Is that more of a crime then then
selling drugs?
Like what is the crime here?
No,
it should be dynamic and it always has
been dynamic.
That's the thing,
but I don't know what it is exactly that
holds it back.
I also,
I think it's a fine line because on the
other side of it,
if a person's bouncing around from day
to day on how they feel about something,
it can be a fucking nightmare as well.
Well then they shouldn't be a leader
mean that sort of even need in your
life,
in a relationship.
It's like it's like there's this really
this groove somewhere in the middle of
like committing to certain things,
but being open minded about others.
It's like kind of a balance to it.
Isn't that the case with pretty much
everything in life,
that life really doesn't have a whole
lot of real solid black and whites that
there's a lot of room for consideration.
There's a lot of.
A lot of variables that you're managing
on a daily basis.
Definitely comes to many things in life.
Definitely,
and that's why a lot of things when you
look at them to go,
oh,
well,
okay,
well there's a lot of ways to look at
this and when someone wants to come at
it from a real hard black or white
perspective,
that usually is either someone with a,
like a deep agenda or someone who
doesn't have a considered nuance
perspective of the subject of hayes.
One of them
most.
It's one of the most frustrating things
about like living a substantial part of
my life on the internet is that,
and I don't know if we talked about this
previously or not,
but it's like,
it's this idea of everybody having kind
of a,
a,
a microphone.
Everybody being able to blast out there.
They're kind of a perspective.
Like,
I don't like the comments section on
youtube and my comments are not that
bad.
Okay?
But I don't like the way it works.
The idea that you could,
you could create this video,
put all this effort into it,
uh,
formulate a perspective and then
everybody's going to scroll to the top
comment and this dude put in what,
10 seconds a knee jerk reaction and he
gets to occupied at real estate.
I don't like it.
I think there's a better way to do that.
What is the better way?
And then the person who published the
thing has to have a little bit more
control over kind of like in a forum
traditionally how you could have
moderators who had certain abilities
that others didn't.
You should be able to promote people in
your community to be kind of the
authority figures,
just like everything else you have to
manage in life when it comes to.
But doesn't that censorship?
And a lot of ways.
I mean,
no,
I don't think it seems to have the
option.
Have not have comments.
Okay.
But that's not,
that's not a good look.
It's not a good look.
You have comments turned off if you're a
feminist.
Yeah.
Like if I come to your video and you
have comments turned off,
I'm like,
oh,
I get it.
You're probably talking bullshit because
you're not even willing to have the to
have anybody saying anything here.
Well,
they can say it.
They just cannot say right underneath
your work.
Yes.
See,
I wish I'm thinking it would be cool
that if it was that way it would be cool
and trust me whenever I engage in
anything slightly more artistic or
subjective online,
I'm like,
I'm thinking,
man,
it'd be cool to turn off the comments
and let it just let it breathe a little
bit.
But at the same time I'm like,
this is the format that has been what
everyone's accepted and and,
and,
and expects now.
And so I feel like probably the
healthier approach is this idea of
tweaking it and what are the numbers
like what percentage of people actually
comment fucking dominate the goddamn
perspective.
That's the problem.
And the ones with the shittiest points
of view are the ones that are the
loudest,
most black and white.
Just like the headline science we were
talking about before.
There's a reaction that you have to
really negative aggressively shitty
comment,
yes,
or I'm going to reply to that and now
now there's a whole thread underneath of
that guy single comment which then
pushes it to the top because it's
creating conversation and this is stuff
that like on the highest level,
the biggest businesses in the space.
If you're google,
if you're facebook or they're having
board room meetings about this stuff,
you hear about what clinton's doing.
Know hillary clinton is spending
$1,000,000
to combat forum trolls and people on
reddit and twitter and social media.
Yeah.
What with her own mercenaries,
who was going to do it?
They have a hundred people that are
working for her that actively go out and
correct people that are saying negative
things about this fucking career
criminal and might be the president
United States day.
I don't like that either.
You know when I'm talking about maybe
tweaking the comment system.
Hell no to that,
but look at this like,
do you have a junior?
It is bizarre.
Yeah,
it's creepy,
man.
This is the first time anyone has ever
done this before.
Done it opened the way that politicians
have been able to use social media,
paying online trolls to attack anyone
disparages her pay.
Who?
Who's the guy who wrote that?
Isn't that the guy that twitter guy who.
Oh,
cool.
We're complaint is the white guy.
That does be black.
It's not easy.
It definitely is.
I don't know.
I haven't fallen it.
If you'd follow it,
there's no evidence whatsoever.
There's any african american in him at
all.
You'll get his brothers and his sister.
They all look like him.
His dad's white.
The whole thing's a mess.
His mom's white.
Yeah.
Don't ever pull up this guy's articles.
There's a lot of other articles on it.
That guy's a fucking fraud.
It's weird that that guys employed to.
He's employed by like the daily news or
something like that.
Jesus christ like.
Do you guys have google?
Like what are you doing daily news?
It's probably because you can promote
the article and tweeted out.
I assume he has a following I guess,
and there's a lot of that going on that
that is a lot of what's happening with
with these newspapers too.
They've.
They've sort of fallen into a state
realm to have to survive on that.
Do you remember when they used to try to
make you pay to subscribe?
They,
some do.
New york times is still pay.
Well you can still do that and articles
and then you had to pay to continue
beyond news papers.
I mean those institutions and the most
entitled group of people that still
exists.
Then maybe radio.
I can't wait to be honest for every car
on the planet to ship with android auto
or,
or apple car play because then it's a
wrap android art.
But the problem is like I've seen a lot
of cars that have google car play.
I haven't had one of my cars.
Okay,
cool.
But I don't,
I don't recall ever seeing a car with
android auto,
but it's an android.
At least 50 percent of the smartphone
market.
Oh yeah.
Probably more.
Um,
maybe not in the us globally.
It's more than 50.
More than 50,
but it because in emerging markets
nobody can afford iphones.
You know,
you,
you could tell me this,
like the latest samsung,
the galaxy s seven.
Yeah.
It's basically a wrap right there,
a wash,
you've got pros and cons,
but they're both pretty goddamn camera.
Yeah.
Oh,
100 percent.
I wouldn't have a problem recommending.
Yeah.
An s seven.
Any of the nexus devices?
Uh,
what else?
I mean,
the one that I didn't really like that
much.
I haven't made a video about it.
Sometimes the problem with me is
sometimes if I'm not into something I
just don't make a video about it.
And so people are like,
well I just got what you so fucking
excited about everything.
It's like,
well shit,
I want to make video,
but that stuff I'm excited about trying
to be positive.
Yeah.
Like I understand how that can look
like,
you know,
you're just always taking,
you're not taking a strong position,
but it's like if I put my sim card into
a phone and I'm not feeling it,
it's not going to last very long,
you know?
So anyway,
I had some issues with lgs.
Latest phone,
even though I like some stuff about it
that [inaudible] it's a modular phone so
it's like,
I don't know if you remember,
there was this thing called project aria
project or a project I remember it was a
modular could like.
Anyway,
That obviously never happened,
but lg kind of a took,
took the approach of like trying to make
what the consumer version of that would
look like.
So tHere's modules,
so the battery compartment you can pull
out the battery and then re insert like
a camera module which is going to give
you a better grip,
different attributes to the camera.
You can pull this fucking thing up,
you can pull that out and you could put,
put in,
put in another module which is a better
headphone amplifier so you can run
better headphones off of your phone.
Yeah.
So.
And I like that kind of shit.
Turns me on.
I liked that stuff.
So when I see it I'm like fuck,
I want to support that.
Even if it's not 100 percent polished.
Yeah.
So here we go.
If you scroll down,
you'll,
you'll see if you can see how the
battery pulled out on the bottom and
that picture there so that they call
them friends as a bit of an issue with
translation there.
But,
uh,
the different modules are called friends
and you'll see here he can slide it out.
Hopefully he does in this clip here,
there so that pops out.
And you could even just carry around
another battery,
which that's becoming a tougher thing to
do with phones.
Obviously you're getting killed here.
Fucking hit.
I'll look at the options.
I don't want to save.
I want to be a loser.
Can I click on,
I want to be able to.
So,
so anyway,
um,
I hope,
I don't know if they show any of the
other modules here,
but they're opening it up to third
parties as a port.
So essentially if you're a in audio
maker and you want to have your own amp
or,
or if you're a god knows what accessory
you might want to have utilized,
that may be a bigger battery,
you know,
maybe uh,
um,
who knows,
whatever,
whatever it is that you might want to
improve that you could access that and
do so what an uphill battle it is
though,
for these cell phone companies to come
up with something that you can get other
people to jump in on and make
accessories for because people look at
and go,
man,
I don't know if this is going to catch
on,
do we,
do we use our resources and our
engineers to develop something.
This is Lg platform when we can just
make some shit for the iphone.
And it's gonna sell for sure.
Yep.
And this is a problem.
This is why there's such a huge
abundance of accessories for that
platform.
And it's something to consider for a
person.
There's some of the modules,
wow.
The module and the,
that brown one is that the camera one
that what the fuck wouldn't grip.
So you get a real shutter,
like a regular camera.
what does that upper left one that was
like a speaker that's actually lgs
camera one.
so that's a camera.
So basically what it does is it gives
you a bigger battery first of all and
then it gives you some control over the
shutter as well as a wheel now under
professional camera that we'll normally
it would be mapped to like shutter speed
or something more professional style of
interaction.
So it wouldn't just be clicking go,
you could get more control over the
manual functions of it.
and uh,
that went in the middle I think is a,
a digital analog converter.
So headphone amp from,
I think it's bang and olufsen some high
end audio company.
So you can drive bigger headphones.
But anyway,
I really liked the approach.
Another thing they did on that phone is
they put two lenses on the back and a
lot of people think on the next iphone
we might see two lenses as well.
Among I'll ask,
I'll ask you this before I get into this
next part.
Did actually know what,
I'm going to get to that in a second.
I'm going to go do dual lens,
but uh,
the dual lens on the,
on the lg,
one of them is super wide angle so you
can capture a really wide frame.
This is one of them,
that's one of my pet peeves about a
phone cameras and you can see both of
them there if they're not very wide.
So like you want to capture like a group
or architecture or beach or something.
It's always like this really narrow
field of view.
So in this particular case one of them
is super wide and one of them is a more
standard field of view and so it's like
having an interchangeable lens system,
but it's always in your phone.
So right from within the app you can
switch between lenses.
That's interesting.
Yeah,
I like that.
So the iphone might do something
similar.
What do you not like about this?
Okay.
So what is it?
I don't know how fair it is,
but really the way I evaluate a phone,
he's how it kind of interacts with all
the other devices that I expected to
interact with,
so for example,
if I get in my truck and I wanted,
I want this shit to seamlessly connect
via bluetooth,
start playing my podcast and so on.
ThIs phone,
for whatever reason,
it had no problem linking up the
multimedia portion to play the music,
the podcasts,
but the headset portion and for whatever
reason it wouldn't connect for answering
phone calls via my bluetooth.
Again,
this is anecdotal,
this is my personal experience.
We shouldn't.
It's tough to even put that out there
because who knows?
It's just the way that's talking to my
my truck,
but that that issue doesn't exist with
any of the other flagships,
so that's something that I'm going to
consider.
Another thing is build,
so a lot of people were upset because of
the way that that modular portion fits
in.
It's not completelY flush.
It's a little bit rough around the edges
and so again,
it's so competitive in this marketplace.
Any lIttle inch you're going to give up,
it's going to have a drastic impact.
Then lastly,
I don't like their software,
their skin that they put on android,
but we talked about this before.
I'm a purist when it comes to that and I
usually modify that anyways,
but there was some weirdness from the
get go about not just the skin they have
on there but.
But how hard it is to really switch it
around too much to the samsung theme
store is a little bit more elaborate.
If you want to change the appearance of
the way your touchwiz touch with has
gotten a lot better,
but I still have a nexis in my pocket
right now.
So now the nexus phones,
what is,
what's the service aluminate this.
There's something where with google you
can pay google and that becomes your
provider and you are.
Your phone will work on everything t
mobile not as.
Not everything?
No.
What is it?
I don't think so.
No,
no.
I think it's just a select carriers
because I don't think the verizon bands
are different or their cdma.
Right?
Yeah.
I think the thought that cdma and gsm,
like most phones will work on cdma and
gsm,
like the iphones will like if you travel
overseas and you're in a gsm
environment.
Yeah,
I have.
Iphone is actually one of the few.
I'm not sure if nexus does or not,
but that seems crazy that they wouldn't.
It bounces around.
I think it might be t mobile and it can
bounce to sprint and a t and t.
That's cdma and gsm as well.
Then they're going back and forth
between two different types of.
They are.
I'm not 100 percent sure that service is
not available where I am.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
Just in Canada.
No,
so I'm not 100 percent sure on that,
but with nexus devices in general,
you do whatever you want with them.
They're completely unlocked,
so even if you just went to the google
google play store and ordered a nexus
six p or five x,
any sim card you put in there is going
to work and nexus does it that way so
they can give you the pure google
experience.
You're buying it directly from google
witHout skins?
No apps,
no touch with no bullshit and the tough
part about that is there's so few people
who have ever even experienced it
because you can't pick it up in a
verizon store and att and t store.
That's got to be frustrated for the
google people.
Yeah,
I think so.
But at the same time it feels like they
could do more from a marketing
perspective to build awareness around
the brand.
I would definitely because um,
I mean I'm barely aware of it.
I know most people are.
I think part of it has to do with,
it's kind of like,
uh,
the oil business and the highway
business and it's like you don't want to
piss off carriers.
Carrier still pull so much weight and so
it's weird that the carriers would want
to just all over the soup we are back
there.
Yeah.
Now the carriers on the,
hey,
I mean there's tons of evidence of
verizon and comcast and fucking,
you name it,
they're all trying to protect this
really this really strange business.
I mean they started out as what cable
companies and give doing home phones and
then it was like all of a sudden this
whole thing was mobile and we've seen t
and we could and we could bounce around
and we had and it's like a really.
The busIness has changed but they've
continued to try to lock you into this
bundle,
the bundle of things that you could have
the tv package that's $200 and you
watched four stations and I mean their
banking so hard that I can understand
why that,
what they're trying to protect,
they trying to lock you in.
Anything you buy that they going to lock
you into a contract and it's a few
hundred dollars.
I mean it's pretty obvious there's a bit
of a play there.
Yeah.
People are wising up to a lot of people.
A lot more people are buying their own
devices now.
So jamie,
see if you can figure out what exactly
that nexus service is,
how it works.
Well,
google project five.
Yeah.
It does not saying anything on here
specifically about which network
networks.
Click on the network button.
It just says that judas is the best
network and it goes from lte to fly back
and forth.
It doesn't say which carrier.
They're actually in an lc to wifi.
Yeah.
It bounces back on lte.
Lte.
I'm sorry to wifi.
Um,
so,
but how is it using wifi?
This two to four g lte networks to
networks.
I don't remember who they are.
Phi access the best of two,
four g lte network.
So you can connect to more towers and
get fast speeds at more places.
I'm nearly positive that one of them is
t mobile.
It doesn't say on here.
Why wouldn't not say that?
Seems crazy.
That might have a white paper somewhere
on the internet to get.
You can get your hands on.
But listen,
this connected better wifi.
There are lots of wifi wifi hotspots out
there,
but not all of them are high quality.
Project fi automatically connects you to
more than a million free open wifi
spots.
We verified for faster.
How does that affect you while you're
walking around?
Is it really going to go from why spider
wife?
That sounds ridiculous.
They had a little graphic on here to
kind of just shows it,
but I mean it's just graphics.
I don't.
It's not.
It's not real life application.
Right,
right,
right.
It's not giving you actual data
experience.
Yeah.
Calls and text over wifi for more
coverage.
Seed.
This sounds good in paper,
like maybe 10 years.
calls transition seamlessly from wifi
and cell phone networks.
Tell it to people.
Their phone drops off left and right and
they're yelling at you.
I'm switching networks.
Going back to the mobile.
The movement of a nightmare,
but I don't know.
I mean,
again,
this is kind of,
to me,
this is kind of along the lines of that
modular phone.
It's like,
I like it.
It speaks to me in some way at least
this idea of,
of innovating in this space,
but that doesn't necessarily mean it's
all the way.
There was jamie cv you can find instead
of this commercial cartoon,
they're showing us actual data of what
networks they're using and how it works.
Probably can.
YeaH.
Because chris ryan,
dr chris ryan,
the guy wrote sex at dawn.
He was the one who first told me about
it and that's why he bought the phone
and he's like,
I love it because everywhere I go he
just finds the best service and I was
like,
oh,
okay.
That sounds like a great idea if it's in
paper who,
who's a partner,
sprint t mobile carriers in the us to
launch our service.
But you know what man,
that's.
So,
that's exactly what.
That's what tim does.
Yeah.
Ten years.
Uses sprint t mobile as well.
They use a t mobile for gsm and sprint
for cdma.
And so you would get the same coverage
that you get with t mobile or with um,
with ting.
But with ting yOu only pay for what you
use.
Like ting has a great deal where,
you know,
if,
if you barely use it,
like I barely used my phone before and
I've got a $10 bill.
Yeah.
You know,
the one thing that they have there is
that wifi transition thing.
Maybe you're using less data.
I don't know where,
where you have to log into wifi
networks.
That's what I don't understand.
How could that be verified?
I know and they're like reliable.
I don't know about that mean,
but this idea of free why spot wifi
hotspot if you go to starbucks and use
their hotspot or just coffee bean,
you have to log in so you're going to
have to pre log in to all these places
unless they have some kind of clearance
maybe where those numbers could somehow
have access.
I'm not 100 percent sure.
That sounds fishy.
I'm not,
I'm not 100 percent sure how that works,
but,
but wifi calling and what night is cool
because generally speaking,
even in your own places like the places
you frequent,
like your office and your house and
such.
I have laughed calling on my phone and
exactly.
It's amazing.
high quality.
You have a great connection.
So it does make sense in theory the way
they were showing it on that graphic is
probably overstating it,
right?
Yeah.
But anyway,
so,
so in,
in the android space,
I think it's pretty easy.
I think right now for me it would be
probably an s seven or the nexus six p
keys in my pocket,
which I like.
Can I see that?
Yeah.
Pull up this,
um,
this again,
what you're seeing a lot of now you're
seeing the fingerprint scanner being
moved to the back of the device,
so you could just do it as you're
holding it,
so.
Yeah,
exactly.
You'll notice it sort
of fits in there.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's nice.
I like that.
That's actually really clean.
I've actually got a skin on it.
It's,
oh,
this is a skin.
Yeah.
It would look a little different.
It's a little more grippy like that.
I like it.
Yeah.
This is really thin and nice.
It's a 6:00
PM,
6:00
PM.
It's the bigger brother.
So the five x is pretty much identical
to screens,
a little lower resolution on physical
buttons on the outside.
Just over here on the side.
Yeah.
But no,
no,
they're all digital.
Well,
if you look at like an iphone,
that giant,
that giant home button increases the
size of the bezel substantially.
Yeah.
Another thIng that,
that phone makers,
I think,
I don't remember if I talked about this
before,
it's like forward facing speakers.
It's such a huge thing.
The fact that we don't have that on a
lot of devices yet.
Yeah.
The iphone has a little dinky speaker in
the bond,
the bottom.
It's kind of,
it's like from a design perspective,
you can't imagine ever doing a drawing
where for any reason you do that,
unless it was an absolute necessity,
but the thing is a lot of filmmakers
keep trying to slim down the devices.
It has to be thinner every single
generation and so that usually means
they're subtracting things rather than
adding them,
which is a problem for people who were
like super into tech,
like are you complaining about the
thickness of that?
That could be a little bit thicker if
you got better battery life.
Say a better camera,
right?
Yeah.
Do you need it to be that thin?
No,
I'm good with it the way it is.
I like it.
Yeah.
Battery life is fun.
Like the six plus has a huge battery.
It was pretty pretty fucking get it has
a huge battery.
Was actually okay with the six.
The six was okay.
The battery life was not bad.
It just.
I picked up one of these again and I was
like,
oh,
like the screen better?
Bigger screen?
Yeah.
Especially for like going on a website
or something like that and reading
emails.
The only argument,
the real argument against the big screen
is one handed use.
Right?
So you're.
If you're a person who takes public
transit,
you're on the subway and they got a
coffee in one hand and then you can make
the argument that like any of these
giant phones,
it's difficult to interact with them one
handed.
Well then the argument is the new
iphone,
the one that they've come out with it
the old four inch.
Yeah.
That sucker fits right in your hand.
It's timeless.
It's so easy to text one handed with.
Oh yeah,
definitely.
I kind of,
I was kind of lukewarm about it just
because it's like going backwards.
It's like what do we,
you know,
this stuff I get excited about is,
is the innovation and the sort of the
people behind it,
the research development and such.
And it's like anytime you see a company
kind of going back,
but then again,
I thought about it when I made that,
when I made a video about it,
it's like,
well if you drive a porsche,
they don't look all that different.
Like,
well not only that,
a porsche small suv it give you invented
of suv and you're like,
I don't want to drive an suv.
I want a little shapes around.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's kinda what that phone is.
It's like a little sports.
Yeah.
You could make.
Yeah,
because it's fast.
It's fast.
They upGraded the camera.
I just,
yeah.
I feel like I feel like we could've seen
a new design.
That's all.
It would have been interesting.
They've had a lot of time to figure out
what they wanted to do with a smaller
phone,
but the edgy of that old phone,
super grid,
big grips.
It's got us a angular sort of edge.
That one right in your hand.
One of the slippery as phones is.
Exactly.
Well,
that's why I like this scan.
I gOt the skin.
It's got texture on the outside and it
would.
Yeah,
you're,
you're gripping.
Yeah.
So the issue with the Next iphone,
this is what I'm going to ask you,
joe.
There's a rumors.
They're probably beyond rumors that
they're going to give up the headphone
jack.
Yeah,
that's gross.
You're not happy about.
No,
I think that's gross.
Uh,
cut the shit.
What if you're going to get improved
audio,
how much improved?
What are you doing?
You just making things proprietary,
like they're trying to sell a fuck ton
of beats.
Headphones when they're trying to do.
And then also the problem with that is,
are you gonna be able to charge it at
the same time as listening to music?
Is it gonna be one of the little things.
So here's the thing,
I had an idea,
I'm just gonna put it out there because
I'm not going to do it.
I'm too fucking busy,
but like up for a set of headphones that
use that port that actually have a
battery that charge your phone while
you're listening because you know,
a lot of people carry around backup
batteries.
Anyone?
Yeah,
anyone that's not a bad idea.
I'm not going to makE it.
Like I said,
I'm totally a bad idea,
but anyway,
the point being is it's not universal,
so you couldn't just be over at your
friends and grab it.
Any pair of headphones,
all this stuff you may be already
invested in.
A lot of people have invested a lot into
audio.
Everything fits with this three point
five millimeter universal jack and it's
been that way for god.
Fifty years,
more,
more than 50 years.
It used to be a quarter inch jack like
this stuff here,
which could be adapted,
but essentially it's been that analog
connection for as long as there's been
audio equipment,
so this is a big move.
If the leader in the marketplace gives
up on that and goes with the strictly
digital connection,
you can expect all the other people to
follow suit because apple just has that
kind of pull.
well,
they were the first ones to abandon the
floppy disk.
Remember that,
and then they abandon everything.
Yeah,
I mean the new ones,
this new laptops,
they don't even have a usb.
They just have the see usbc port to
provide power to interface with it.
It should really should have to.
Most of the pc manufacturers with
competitive products to that mac book
have to usbc ports.
Yeah.
Do you think that they're trying to
establish the cloud?
Is it to try to encourage people to
upload data to the cloud?
And part of it,
that's part of it,
but honestly not to be too pessimistic
about it,
but apple does have a history of this
sort of planned obsolescence and I,
I fully believe that at least with the
next generation,
a lot of people were hoping it would be
this generation.
You'll just see that second port and
they'll go now wIth two boards and
everybody runs the lineup for it,
you know.
But anyway,
um,
the two,
the most controversial thing on the next
version is certainly going to be this
idea of giving up the headphone jack.
Is that confirmed is pretty fucking
close question about that.
Wouldn't they still be able to let that
little port the to have headphones that
plug into the charging
port in a day in adapter?
Humans are new headphones.
Everyone has to go by,
but that doesn't completely kill
headphones,
right?
yeah.
Oh yeah.
They could totally
sticking,
adapt,
but then you'd have to have some new
thIng in your pocket that you'd hold
onto
and have to be an adaptive,
but they could put out just like they
put on ear buds with every iphone.
They could just give you new ones that
plug.
Oh yeah,
no doubt.
No doubt.
Right,
but the problem is you wouldn't be able
to charge it at the same time.
You would have to have one or the other.
I'm saying that wouldn't be wireless.
ThE new ones they give you wouldn't be
plugged into the port we charged into
now.
Right.
That's what I'm saying is the exact
charge.
And can I get you on that?
Yeah.
I know there's going to be some drawback
and people are gonna lose their shit and
then everybody's going to buy the
fucking iphone.
Well,
it's so convenient that it works so
seamlessly with your laptop and max do
make the best operating system for home
computers.
In my opinion.
You know what?
We're going to try some window shit out
because razor is gonna.
Send us.
I heard about this laptop.
Am I invited to this party or what I
getting on the doom party?
We're going to have a doom loop.
You know what you're getting into here
and what went well?
I don't know.
I mean how elaborate will this thing be?
What kind of systems are you getting?
What's happening?
We're probably going to use razors.
Laptop systems.
They have gaming laptops that are pretty
fucking financial definitely.
And so the razor blade,
I actually was one of the razor
developers like early back in the day,
in the nineties.
Excuse me,
I was the one,
one of the guys who helped them with
their mice.
Get out of town.
You know how much credit you're getting
right now.
Your original raiser guy,
robert krakoff was a friend of mine and
he was trying to figure it out.
I met him,
I think at e three.
Think I met him there.
I forgot where I met him,
but uh,
you know,
I was friends with like the software
guys,
like way back in the day I met john
carmack way back during quake too when
they were developing quake three.
I got to play quake three,
like the early developer model.
You would deep man that was deep.
They had their original.
The razer mamba,
the original.
I know that my sensitivity house and
ergonomically people didn't like it.
They love the fact that it was like a
really super sensitive module inside of
it that would the sensor that would pick
up the movement and it was super
sensitive and high,
high dpi,
but we didn't like the ergonomics.
THe shape didn't seem right.
what was wrong with the shape?
Too flat.
It was a really weird shape.
I had like a hump in the back then it,
it leaned forward to a flat front,
like a duck's foot.
It was real weird.
Do you remember the early shane?
I'm trying to remember it right now.
I don't.
I don't think I can pinpoint that in my
head.
Well,
obviously people have different shaped
and sized and also some people employ
the claw.
Yes.
They have a different grip and that's
how you would,
I guess you'd want a different shape
depending on the grip,
but there's a lot of the,
there's a lot of variables,
right?
One of the variables is do you rest your
arm,
the rest your arm or you were hover and
you guys go with high sensitivity or you
do low sensitive and quick movements and
do you use,
um,
do you use a mouse sampling?
Like,
you know,
there's,
there's like a mouse acceleration.
Do you know what that is?
Yeah,
of course.
So like if you move quicker,
the mouse actually moves quicker than
that.
It like,
it,
it works on some sort of like a
gyroscope or that's probably not the
right word,
but like excelorometer accelerometer.
Whereas if you move quicker,
it actually covers distance quicker than
your movement.
It,
it helps you move quicker and then we're
in find slower movements.
It slows down.
Some people like that,
some people don't like that ending on a
game depending on how you play.
But for me it was first person shooters,
so,
um,
me and um,
my friend lou morton who is a hardcore
gamer is one of the writers for news
radio and a bunch of friends that were
in my clan at the time.
We got together with the razor guy and
we had a land party and we all
discussed,
we brought in a bunch of different
shaped mouse mice and we all showed
which mouse we used and why we used it.
And I believe at the time I was using a
microsoft mouse and uh,
I really liked laser mice because they
were,
there were,
back then they were,
they were not quite good enough for a
pre games.
There were a little awkward.
They weren't a sensitive.
They would,
they would miss things,
but they wouldn't require cleaning.
And the ball mice required clean not.
Yeah.
Right.
And so we all had these different ones
that we would would use.
And so they compiled all of our
suggestions and then created their next
generation mice.
So this isn't a nine days.
So I was like one of the early guys that
help them with a shape.
So imagine all the kids out there right
now with a razor mouse.
I was just one of them.
There's a lot of people don't get
carried away.
Yeah,
I wouldn't.
I wouldn't do that because it was a
gaming mouse that one of the logitech
logic tac had the best shape.
I love logitech mouse.
I use one right now.
I use the,
uh,
what is it called?
The performance mx love.
It wouldn't use anything else,
but they had one that was specifically
designed for gaming and it only had
three buttons,
but the shape of it,
the logitech gaming mouse just fit
perfectly.
The 5:18.
That was a super popular gaming mouse
back in the day but could be.
I mean they just called it the logitech
gaming mouse.
Yeah.
It was mostly a gray mouse.
Didn't have any buttons.
Three buttons might be earlier than I'm
thinking.
It was kind of crude and primitive,
but people really loved It because it
was set these buttons for different
things.
Like some of them would set one of the
buttons for a jump.
Some of them would set one of the.
By the way,
I would have it,
I would have the index finger would be
my trigger.
That's how I would shoot the middle
button,
would be a rail gun and the far left
button would be a rocket launcher,
so if I wanted a rocket launcher or I'd
hit that far button,
who would come to me instantly and I
could shoot it and then the rail gun
would be the one that I would count on
for like a long range sniper shot and so
you have all your keys.
Keys would be in fronT of uwa,
s and d for movement and then various
weapon keys which are really close,
like lightning gun was up here,
a c you would hit that,
this and that for that
and you would configure it based on what
you would like.
And so there was.
Yeah,
that was one,
but that was not the one.
This is a,
this is probably right,
but it's a fun one from the 90th.
But yeah,
no need but pretty.
That's pretty dope.
That one right there,
the.
They have tons of buttons now.
Like the performance mice now they could
have it.
Nevermind the ones for those massive
multiplaYer games.
Yeah,
those guys are crazy.
Those mice can have like 30,
40 buttons on it to trigger certain
behaviors.
I don't know.
I'm not an expert in that space.
Those game scare.
The shit out of me really is massive.
Multiplayer games are the ones that just
suck your life on.
Oh yeah.
Those.
Those people would just vanished from
the world.
You know what is going to happen with
those people when they get a little
something like this to this box that we
have in front of us.
Louis and I were playing with this
before the show and we had the gentleman
in that helped work with it.
yeah.
Let me give them a shout out.
This master of shapes on twitter.
These,
these guys,
they create mostly vr experiences,
but this headset here is actually an ar
headset and you may have heard of it.
It's caLled the microsoft hollow lens.
Essentially you've got a lens in front
of you in a fairly narrow field of view,
but what ends up happening is you have
this digital representation that's
overlaid on your own physical space.
That's how I would describe it.
You tried it out,
joe,
why don't you,
uh,
give us some feedback?
Well,
right now it's kind of crude.
Um,
there's some holes in it and these are
just developer kit so it's not meant to
be a polished consumer product,
but it's pretty,
it's pretty revealing as far as what the
potential is and we're in for a wild
ride in the next 20 years.
What we're Seeing with this is a kind of
a crude version of virtual reality in a
video game where things are coming at
you,
but you know,
they're bullshit.
They don't look real,
you know,
you're pressing a clicker.
You can shoot them out of the air.
It's kind of fun.
My interest in gaming perspective,
I still think uh,
the vr experiences are a lot more
immersive than,
than something like this where you can
still see your surroundings.
Exactly.
When you put the headset on and
everything is gone and you're doing like
some zombie game or some shit.
And I was a.
So I was playing with the htc vive
recently that most people are saying
that's the one to get for vr headsets.
Really?
Yeah.
Over oculus rift.
Just the way the tracking is done.
It's,
it's a very smooth experience.
They've got controllers that come With
it,
that map against the headset itself.
There were,
they're wireless.
You're still wired into huge gaming pc
via your head,
but it's kind of cool.
Some of the demos I did have a,
they have these digital walls that you
bump into so you know,
the sort of limits of where you can go.
But some people have done some really
interesting things.
Um,
if you can bring up jamie into the void.
Have you seen this yet?
Okay.
Should I say anything or should we play
the clip?
Okay.
Play the clip into the void.
Yeah.
I'm curious as to if someone is going to
develop something like those laser tag
warehouses.
Oh my god.
How the fuck did you just nail it?
How did you just nail it?
That's what we're about to watch.
Somebody in salt lake city built this
experience where you have this pack on
which if you get shot,
it's like a.
It's like an actual physical.
I think we have talked about this
before.
Did this come up?
I feel like this came up and one of the
red band podcasts I'm looking for right
now.
Or just void.
Something called the voice.
Yeah.
That might be it because if you can
establish,
if you can get a place where you have
this enormous warehouse space and then
in that warehouse space you said it like
if you ever play paint ball.
Of course I played paintball wants in
boston.
There's this place in linn that had
these black lights and it was a
warehouse you would run around.
There's boxes and those barriers and
shit.
So here it is right here.
Okay,
here we go.
We're dream because we become reality.
Okay.
So this girl is walking around and
there's actual walls and she turns the
corner and she's in some fucking magical
land.
So the computer in this case is in the
backpack.
So you're completely untethered.
oh my god.
And so they've constructed all this
stuff,
unparalleled visuals and body tracking,
and so you're wearing a suit like an x
men type uniform and it's got sensors on
it.
Virtual worlds built over physical
environments.
I do believe we've talked about.
This looks a little familiar.
Yeah,
we're getting to this part of it.
I don't feel like it looked like.
No,
I feel like this dated version of what
we've seen that I think they've actually
launched now.
I think you can actually go do it.
It's not just a concept for d
environmental effects.
So you've got air that blows on you yet
know to go along with what's happening.
Wow.
Water,
rain,
explore with and play against others.
Whoa.
So they wouldn't have to be mapped in
that physical space as well.
Well,
at least you're going to move around a
little and get some exercise.
I kind of liked that.
I liked the idea of actually holding a
physical gun and being have,
having to aim a physical gun.
Give me some hand eye coordination.
And by the way,
of course this is how they're going to
train soldiers now.
Oh yeah.
Big time.
They're going to get people that are
really good at doing it this way and
they're going to train them for the
battlefield.
This is wild man.
Oh,
jesus christ.
Doom.
Yeah.
You can imagine if when that thing
grabbed hold of you and your vest is
gripping you tighter and you're feeling
the physical surroundings,
that's going to hijack our our sensory
system.
Big time,
especially when it gets better and
better.
Whereas like it's more and more reactive
like you could feel it in very specific
areas of your body.
If something grabs your shoulder from
behind you turn it actually has his hand
on your shoulder and the thing is after,
you know,
people grow up with those kinds of
experiences.
How the fuck are they going to go to the
movie theater and just sit there?
Then not.
Well,
the move is going to have to ramp it up.
That will be.
Yeah.
That'll be the equivalent of what it is.
Maybe disney,
maybe the neck,
maybe some star wars down the road.
You'll be in it.
Well sometimes though,
you just want to go to the movies.
You know,
you want to go on a date,
eat some popcorn,
and sIt down and relax.
Although I think that,
I mean those experiences,
who knows,
who knows if the next generation will
give a fuck about any of that.
They don't need a date.
They don't need the popcorn.
They don't even need a date.
No,
that's what I'm saying.
They got it all figured out,
man.
They don't need to leave the house.
what is our personality like?
The collective personality,
human beings,
how much is it going to be affected by
robot sex slaves on hundred percent.
One hundred percent.
No one will compromise for anYthing.
We will.
We will be such ugly motherfuckers,
dude.
Or be like completely uneasy.
No,
not at all.
I do not think so.
well,
where are you?
You want to weigh in there?
We're getting real close.
demolition man.
I feel like all the things that are
happening with that taco bell is going
to become everyone's favorite meal.
We're going to have to be what it was in
the movie.
Oh,
three shells to wipe our Asses and no
one knows what that means.
StIll.
And go ahead.
Yeah,
or the matrix or whatever scifi film you
choose,
but under ultimately I think we're just
becoming.
We continued to have a smaller slice of
the pizza and the digital realm,
the internet,
the data realm continues to have a
bigger slice of the pizza,
so as long as that continues in that
kind of a direction we're going to,
we're going to become more and more
passengers and less and less drivers
know.
And of course that that's happening to
look.
I'm sure you heard about the model
three.
Like they,
they moved so many fucking unit sight
unseen.
Like can you imagine buying a car
without seeing it?
These people teslas are so proven though
and it's elon musk.
He's like literAlly tony stark.
Exactly.
But all that stuff,
all that hype around it,
right?
It doesn't come easy.
It's all part of kind of a perspective.
They represent somethIng bigger.
Like in so many ways.
tech is like our god,
we worship it.
[inaudible] like this is evidence of
that in my opinion.
If you're gonna buy something without
seeing it,
that's the ultimate fucking cult,
the ultimate coercion,
but you're only buying it from an,
a massively proven brand,
100 percent,
100 percent.
But it's like,
do you have many people do that with
porsche as well?
Listen at with iphones,
with porsche has a model are that's
comIng out and it's actually very retro.
the porsche model,
our is so spoken for.
It's a nine slash 11 with a gt three
engine,
but a six speed manual transmission and
no,
uh,
none of the terminal.
What am I looking for?
A aerodynamic like spoilers and shit
like that.
It looks like a regular nine slash 11
and all the aerodynamics is sort of
built into undercarriage of the car in
order to keep it down at weight.
Interested in what they've done is made
a very retro type experience.
what about our electronics?
Like,
well,
you could shut all that stuff off this
car there.
There's so few of them that they're
selling this car now for a million
dollars.
This is a regular fucking nine slash 11
that just has like retro capabilities
and it's going for,
people are selling them sight unseen for
a million dollars,
but I understand it at the high end
because at the high end this is not car
number one for most people.
You know,
this is like,
yeah,
on a whim,
whatever.
I have some fucking money burning a hole
in my pocket.
In the case of the model three,
that's a $35,000
car and he wasn't that more
understandable then.
How so?
Because there's less of a risk.
No,
no,
no.
I'm talking about volume.
So I looked at their numbers and then
went and referenced it against like what
about honda civic?
What about,
how significant is this number?
Like I'm sure porsche is only gonna.
Make 50 of those,
you know,
I don't know that many.
Many for north America.
Yeah.
so in those cases you understand it like
it's super exclusive and probably make
like 911.
That's probably what they'll do.
Exactly.
And number one and number nine slash 11
will be worth the most and whatever.
But in this case it was like,
like there's not as much as it can be
learned from a sort of small experiments
like that,
but there's a lot more that can be
learned from when you're,
when you're moving half a million cars
because then it's like holy fuck,
this is now an industry trend.
ThIs is not like some outlier.
And so when I saw the numbers and I'm
like,
holy shit,
like honda only sold this number of
whatever last week.
Now we have this significant.
We kind of have proof of concept in a
different way now.
Yeah,
I definitely agree with you there.
I think that the proven brand of tesla
has gotten people so excited about what
this guy's capable of with a smaller,
less expensive car that like the price
of entry for like the model s or
whatever it is,
expensive run 80,000.
A little too much.
Yeah.
So when you come around with $35,000
version of it and it looks pretty dope
and it has that big laptop screen just
like the other ones do.
Like people just jumped in.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
One hundred percent.
but the part that brought me to tesla in
the first place was just the autonomy of
them [inaudible] they're completely
capable right now of driving themselves.
They do.
I have a buddy who does it.
He gets on the highway and texts.
Oh yeah.
One hundred percent is drives and.
Well apparently the bmw seven series
does the mercedes benz,
but they might want you to have your
hand on the wheel.
It actually asks you to have your hand
on the wheel.
To me.
Still a little bit of sentence.
I know.
See that's the thing is obviously
there's gonna be some friction between
where we're going and where we're at and
how much control we're willing to give
to these two d systems.
But,
you know,
getting back to the pizza thing,
it's like that's a huge one if we're
willing up to,
if we're willing to give up control of
our vehicles,
I think we're also probably willing to
give up control of a lot of other
things.
And you know,
uh,
I'm not sure if we talked about this
before,
but there was this really interesting.
Was it where did they,
I don't know if I read it or if it was
on a podcast or how he was relating to
facebook in the early days and how one,
the biggest issues they had with people
getting tagged in photographs that
didn't want to be tagged and so they had
a.
They did this kind of test where they
were like,
well,
how the hell do we get?
Allow people to get taken off the
photograph without having to go to their
friend and saying,
I don't want to be tagged in that
photograph because that was an
embarrassing thing to do.
Right?
And so what they did is they put in the
stock answers like that you can send off
to your friend,
like select abc,
like I don't,
I don't want to be in that photo,
or I look stupid or whatever.
And the second that they made it a
multiple choice way,
more people began,
began to use it because they didn't have
to come up with their own reason.
They felt like it was more accessible.
So humans are low friction,
like we're lazy as fuck.
And many times we get overwhelmed at the
prospect of having to come up with our
own,
I don't know,
our own method for dealing with the
awkwardness of life.
So if you can imagine in the future if
these things are phones and the systems
we interact with,
get really smart at figuring out the
correct responses for certain inquiries.
Let's say a girl texts you and she's
like,
hey man,
meet me at 8:00
PM or call me later.
What if your phone knows better than you
are than you do at what the correct
response is?
If you want to sleep with her later,
like here's the 50 percent likelihood if
you say this,
this might be the outcome,
but if you say that you understand where
I'm going with this most sorta,
but that doesn't take into account
personality and the playful nature,
the people engaging into account,
how that's attracted it takes into
account nothing of that.
Okay,
but you and I are fully aware of that.
Facebook has this exorbitant amount of
data to say people aren't doing that.
People prefer to have the fucking stock
response.
Look at emoji.
Where the fuck did emoji come from and
now everybody's like,
it's like there's a face for everything,
right?
Used to make your owN fake ones on your
character and Before that you didn't do
it or don't do that.
I don't use a mobile as well.
A way they blew up.
Everybody's using them now as this
alternative form to expressing yourself
with the tools you have available
beCause they're defacto.
So tHere's something accepting about
seeing,
answering a multiple choice question
versus one that requires more input from
you.
The same reason people jump to
conclusions when they're building a
response or a perspective on any of
those issues.
And I,
I envision a future.
I mean if you've ever used any of the
wearable devices,
I'm not wearing one right now.
The fucking bother me way too much.
This is just a g shock.
It's a plane watch because these things
like I don't understand how that's
helpful to be quite honest.
It and interpret it interrupts more than
anything else.
It's like the objective was what to get
me to look at my phone less,
but now I'm,
I'm,
I'm flashing you in the face every five
seconds.
Like they'd really didn't solve the
problem.
Maybe we have to figure out how to use
them better,
but one thing I noticed immediately on
the apple watch when I was experimenting
with it was the auto responses for
questions for text,
for anything,
it would have five or six options.
How to get back to that person and maybe
none of them are perfect,
but just the easiness of it is why you
want to interact with it.
You're like,
oh fuck,
maybe I'm not late because I'm at the
grocery store,
but it's easier than pulling out my
phone and telling the person where I
actually am.
How far away do you think we are from
entire conversations take place with
predetermined questions and answers.
This is what I'm talking about.
I'm saying that pizza is shrinking and
our involvement in any of this,
the meaning of any of this is becoming
less evident.
Eventually it'll be computers talking to
computers through us and then we'll just
be the vehicle for the delivery and what
will be the thing that helps it get to
that point.
Well,
isn't that the thing that people were
worried about more than anything anyway?
Is artificial intelligence and what
better way for artificial intelligence
to emerge then to convince us to stop
using our own?
Yes.
It's an interesting.
It's an amazing hack that didn't get
plays on our own inability to put in
work well.
It also,
it reduces variables and it cuts down
the unlikelihood of success.
It cuts down on all the possible
pitfalls and mistakes and chooses a much
more potentially successful scenario.
Yes,
and this is what's going on on the web
on a daily basis when you're on youtube
and that next recommended video comes up
and it catches your attention that this
fucking thing,
inaction and it works and they are the
smartest people in the world of
engineers sitting around day and night,
ab testing what works on joe rogan,
what works on this other person,
and then hyper focusing in on the
success stories and finding the things
that are universal and ultimately what
we ended up finding out is that we.
We all think we're so fucking unique yet
our behaviors sake,
the complete opposite.
We all do.
The shit we're expected to do was so
fascinated that no one saw any of this
coming either like 10 years ago.
no one thought that that was gonna be a
real issue,
that you're going to have a bunch of
predetermined answers to a phone call
coming in.
How do you respond with a text?
Yes.
It gives you a bunch of options.
Yeah.
Nobody.
Nobody thought that.
That was like a slippery slope.
How about this?
How about how do you trust that?
Anything you're going to be like,
fuck,
is the robot talking to me again,
or is it actually you this time?
You know what I mean?
You imagine having those conversations
with your loved ones,
your turn,
your robotic responses off,
right?
Because what about getting back to
people?
Right?
I suck at it.
What about robotic robotic responses
that mimic the way that you talk?
Yes,
because they're analyzing your keyboard
in real time and making suggestions
already.
You're already pulling the data know,
but the thing is,
we know we're lazy to begin with.
Now if we can get this system in place
to auto response,
I can't even get to all the emails I
have right now,
so if I can turn this guy on when I'm
not available,
this responder answering emails for
bingo.
Oh,
if you could download your consciousness
into a robot assistant that knows
exactly what you would say.
Robot version of me.
Is it me saying it though?
Nope.
I don't know.
What is key here?
then you're getting into like the whole,
what is consciousness thing is like,
I don't even know if it's transferable.
If it is transferrable than it would be
you,
right?
Is it essential?
Yeah.
Is it necessary or are these emotions
and all these things that we're clinging
to we hold onto so dearly,
or are they just artifacts of our
ancient primate ancestors?
One hundred percent.
Definitely.
I think the cool part of this,
like the weird thing to identify is how
our physiology has been kind of the
system for the distribution,
like our own.
We talked,
we started off the podcast talking about
entitled people talking about that self
centric emerging kind of way of living
and you look at these things.
That's what they needed.
They needed us to develop into those
people.
We had to become dependent on them.
We had to have everything we wanted to
see available on a win.
For us to become the person necessary to
continue this distribution process,
we had to rely on it.
We had to stop relying on ourselves in
order to enable the reliance on
something else.
We shut down our own sort of our own
sort of response mechanisms for a lot
of.
I wake up in the morning and this
fucking thing.
I pick it up,
yeah,
I pick it up and I look at it and my
fucking neck neck is cranked up and I'm
in pain and why have I not had a coffee
yet?
Why am I not on my way to work?
Why am I not making something that I get
incredible amount of fulfillment out of?
There are,
and again,
I think a lot of people aren't willing
to admit this.
Nobody ever wants to in it and it's
something has control over them,
but like in this particular case,
there are plenty of times where you go,
why am I looking at this right now?
And I'm still looking your check.
SomeThing else booked size and a lot of
ways.
Well that's why a lot of people are
flipping a flip phone.
Great transition.
I have a phone in my office right now.
It's called pumped.
Bring up a picture of this thing.
Pumped.
It's made by a company in Denmark.
It is the intentionally modern,
nice to look at dumb phone for people
trying to get off the system,
bring it up,
whatever happened to discipline c.
Is that fair?
Is it fair?
Sure it was.
You leave heroin out.
Are you going to shoot heroin?
I don't shoot heroin.
Well,
here's the finish shoot heroin.
I have discipline.
Yeah,
I'm sure it's wonderful,
but the heroin addicts,
it's right there.
You can't have it right there.
What happens?
What happened when they put a.
What was that study?
That cocaine in the mouse studies.
No,
good.
no.
Here's why.
Because it's in an artificial
environment.
Oh yeah.
They were pissed.
They were depressed to begin with.
Well,
they're in a cage and they're in.
They're being stared at by people.
If you take those same mice and you
leave them in the woods,
they wouldn't be at be happening.
Woods,
mice,
but here's the thing.
You have data and you have opinion and
in in big,
big fucking digital companies,
they value one way more than the other
data and the truth of the matter is that
people can't,
can't keep away.
Right?
Whether,
whether we want to argue it to the,
you know,
it's like we are the proof.
The evidence is out there.
It's hijacked or curiosity and with
every click,
something fascinating may come.
Even if it doesn't.
There you go.
Even if it doesn't,
there you go.
So it's like discipline over what?
Discipline over the way we think about
everything.
You know what I mean?
It's like we just have to recognize when
it becomes a problem,
stop using it that way.
Yeah.
But I,
I again,
I think that's like a.
That's not going to slow it down.
Slow it down for everybody.
That's for sure though.
Were most people the sort of mass,
the mass movement continues on and find
this punk thing and we find it.
Oh,
it's p u n k t,
sorry.
They're getting fancy with.
What can I say?
They're from Denmark.
Maybe that's how they spell it.
Yeah,
it has.
It has battery life for like two weeks.
It doesn't make phone calls,
you know?
Anyway,
that little guy right there,
punkt phone launched at the london
design festival,
let's you call and text.
It also has nice buttons and it's easy
to hold and that's about it.
Okay.
But the texting even is that old school
method of so you're not going to want
to.
Yeah.
You press four times to get a z.
But see,
the weird thing was for somebody who
wanted to make this statement,
you had to go by like literally some old
device.
Well here's a new one.
It's a modern design,
but it's intentionally done.
Yeah.
You know what this,
you know what the designer is saying
about it is like they're not trying to
convince people to quit what their
smartphone.
They're just saying,
hey,
put a sim card in it,
set up,
call forwarding when you go on vacation
and don't.
And just don't take this.
If somebody really needs you,
they can get in touch with you,
but otherwise you're not going to have
that poll.
And so I haven't cracked it open yet.
I'm going to do a challenge.
well,
I'd like a flip phone better than that,
honestly.
Just as flip phones,
you can shut it to hang up,
which is called hang up.
It's pretty cool.
Yeah,
I mean that was.
I missed that click.
Yeah,
her couch flip phones are cool.
Don't get me wrong,
I had,
I had a flip phone too.
I don't know why they took that
particular approach.
I just think they're interesting because
they're the.
They're making that statement as opposed
to like the flip phone marketplace,
which is just like old leftover phones.
You can have discipline.
Maybe I'm old school,
just one such thing and I like it.
I use discipline.
Listen,
I think discipline is fucking
incredible.
It's one of the which one of the
greatest characteristics a human being
can have,
but I didn't say.
But you were ready to use it.
But no,
I mean when it comes to phones,
I think we have the evidence.
We even you,
I believe you have that moment that I
spoke of.
Oh,
100 percent.
Yeah,
definitely do.
So where's the discipline that when I
realized that I put it down right,
but it's too late.
He already got you already clicked,
but joe and then I realized the next day
and I don't do it.
I check my text messAges when I wake up.
I look people I care about that actually
I have my number,
I look at that,
check my emails or anything super to
have to get to and
then I put that fucker down and then I
go about my day.
You know what?
I think I'm coming off kind of harsh
here.
I'm a guy who like talks about
technology all the time and it sounds
like I'm shitting on technology.
You're just recognizing a real issue.
That's all.
And so I'm going to do an experiment.
I have the punk phone I'm going to do.
I'm announcing it here.
Okay,
so the first time anybody's heard of it,
because all you have to live on the punk
phone.
This is what I want to ask.
I'm going to send you text messages.
Nothing but youtube links would be links
to websites.
I want to rick roll.
You just sabotage.
This is a real question for you.
Coming from your perspective,
how long do I need to do it for?
To really gather the insight necessary
to say,
hey,
this is how this thing is changing me.
I think you should talk to someone who's
done it.
Like what you should do is you should
have a conversation with ari shaffir,
so he's had a text phone or a flip phone
rather for over a year now still.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
He decided he was an addict and he said,
look,
I'm not going to change it any other
way.
I tried to say we'll just have some
discipline.
Nope,
not gonna do it because I'm an addict.
And so he just got a flip phone and
that's all he is is he has a flip phone
thing that flips two ways so you could
flip it sideways and it actually is a
full keyboard.
He can send a reasonable text message.
Yeah,
that's what he does.
Yeah.
I talked to him and being some people
have told me that in order to some
study,
like in order to build a habit,
it has to be 30 days gets 90.
Uh,
shit,
I ain't going to happen.
You can't do it for 90 days.
Dude,
what am I to do on my channel?
What'd you do it for 30 days?
Thirty days.
Thirty was the high end of
consideration.
I was thinking two weeks.
Yeah.
Give it a shot.
I don't know,
but for me it's hard because like it's
kind of my business to say it's a
different what's mine as well.
With comedy,
I rely heavily on information I rely on
in podcasting as well.
I rely really heavily on like finding
out what's going on the world,
what's,
what's the new latest shit that's going
down right now.
I mean,
so many times during this podcast,
jamie will pull something up as the
podcast is going on,
like breaking news.
Check this out.
Paris just got attacked or this just
happened on that,
right?
You know,
conor mcgregor retired.
We got to end this pitch.
We're at a time.
Okay,
great.
Well we flew by through three plus
hours.
Why we're over three hours.
We when dude seed so easy,
like we were saying before,
it's really harder to end it than it is
to just.
I mean it's easy to keep going.
Keeping going is the easy part.
Glue is from unbox therapy.
Ladies and gentlemen,
enjoy it on youtube that most.
A really intensive,
a comprehensive breakdowns of technology
from a cool dude.
Thanks brother.
I appreciate it.
Thank you more often.
You get it.
Fuck.