Shazamm pitches. Yes. We're
back four days a row this week.
That's how crazy. That's a crazy, we live
in out here on the west coast. Holla.
Let me see. I just made it an
east coast west coast thing.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight.
There's no different way to do this.
I've done it every possible way. Um,
I'm just gonna say it. Uh, what is
the flashlight Joe? No, I have not.
I actually reused it.
Yesterday I was watching my girlfriend
on camera was another girl and I used my
flashlight. Wow, buddy.
He had a little personal what the
whole rest of the world right there.
There's a lot of people that they're
not comfortable with someone that they
think is their friend,
like little Brian red band,
telling them about fucking
and watching things.
Have you ever done when there's that moral
degenerate, like you bad for society,
have you ever seen one of those webcams
house? Yes, I have. It's pretty cool.
When he sent me to a link the other day
that was a he, he goes, what the fuck?
The mother load. And, uh,
I go to the link and it's this some crazy
cam site where it's all girls that are
topless. They like playing with themselves
and it's all free. Yeah, it's weird.
It's like,
like you can,
there's the one I used as stream mate
and you can go to and just have a
conversation for the girl while
she's like sitting there topless.
And then she's like,
you want to go in a private room for $10
and then you do whatever you want to in
the private room. And, but
this was all virtual. Yeah.
Like this is like webcams and stuff.
And so,
but there were so many old ladies and
fetishes that that was just creepy to look
at. Like at an old lady. Like
there was like an old lady.
I was like maybe 75 years old.
Let's get through these commercials so
we could talk about this flashlight.
I want to hear about this,
but let's get through these stupid
commercials cause that sounds too good to
just be delegate adult.
The adult industry has always
been pioneers of new technology.
Whether it was like home, video, you know,
and then like on the Internet, I mean,
they've always been the first.
And when we have virtual reality,
I bet virtual sex will be pioneering.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. All right, let's go.
We're gonna get to that.
We're going to get to that,
but let's get this out of the way.
Flashlights sponsored Joe rogan.net
entering code name. Rogan get 15% off.
It's a,
it's a solid product.
The best fake vagina out there really
is way better than mass period.
There were also brought to you by
[inaudible] Dot Com oh andN I t makers of
Alpha brain, the cognitive
enhancing supplement that I use.
I didn't take one this morning,
so let's see if I stumble,
if I stumbled over my words today. I
don't have any more. You took all my dude,
I gave you something. Did I give
you some of the new stuff? No, no.
I got some new stuff for
you. Need to get on it. Oh,
and what is this shit? What is
it? What are you talking about?
We're talking about nootropics
and when nootropics are there,
vitamins that are designed to
enhance the function of your mind,
the way you're thinking works,
and they work,
they work if they're only going to
get better. Yeah. Do you try stuff?
What do you do? I have
not, but I'm a, you know,
David Pearce who wrote the hedonistic
imperative talks about, you know,
how nano technology eventually it's going
to be used to like design vaster and
more broader versions
of human intelligence.
And I'm sort of all about tinkering with
ourselves in order to sort of improve
ourselves. We're the ultimate art project
is us, right? So it's kind of like, yeah,
why not? I got to get you some of
this just to see if you like it. Um,
I have some people have gotten it,
are completely
addicted to it. It's, it's fascinating
stuff. I like it. Some people,
they're the most, the most important
thing about this product I should say,
is that we have for the first order,
for your first 30 pills,
there's a money back guarantee. 100%
you don't have to send the product back.
All you have to do. Say, you know what,
the stuff didn't work for me and
you get 100% of the money back.
We are way more concerned with having
people feel like they're not ripped off.
Then with making money, so a check
out the stuff. It's all on a.com.
We have a sports related supplements,
immunity related supplements.
We have a new mood, which is a five HTP
supplement, which boosts your Serotonin,
actually makes you feel happier. It's
great stuff. It's all healthy for you.
It's all, it's all explained online
is a frequently asked questions.
You can go into it in depth and and
Google nootropics and try out all the
different stuff that's out
there and just check it out.
But go to [inaudible] dot com
if you're interested and uh,
under Alpha brain entering the code
name, Rogan, and you get 10% off,
not just the first order, but
every order. All right pitches
Jason Silvas back.
He's slinging experience.
Try by day Joe Rogan podcast all day.
Jason Silva come back to
sling more cosmic Dick.
You said we are cosmic revolutionaries.
I say, you're a cosmic Dickson.
I love that.
Wow. Well, thank you for having me
back, dude. Last time. It was so fun.
Thanks man. So funny, a great time.
I just a shout out to all these amazingly
engaged listeners and followers,
dude, that the response was so positive
and so yeah, we have a really light,
totally positive
propositive group of people that follow
the show and it sounds ridiculous. Um,
how do you do that? I mean, how
does that ever happen? I don't know.
But if your authenticity, man,
well, if I'm, I'm honored.
If that's what it is, what it, whatever
it is. I'm honored. Comes across, man.
When we go to clubs,
that's the thing that the waitresses
are always saying that our crowds are so
nice and that they tip really well
and it just makes you feel so good.
It's like the most,
the biggest feeling of accomplishment
that I've ever had is someone who listened
to the show once and said, your show
makes me want to try to be a better way.
This is the kind of feedback that we've
been getting about our MindMeld. Dude.
It's been insane.
Like some people have created these remix
videos where they've taken highlights
and sound samples from all we've talked
about to imagery and set them to music.
And that's kind of like
what the creativity and the
whole remix culture is all
about.
It's not about where you take things from,
it's where you take them to see
that. It's just like, oh my God,
there's a bunch of those out there now.
There's so many guys that
are really good at that too.
There's so much creativity and most
of them have like regular jobs.
They're just like regular
dudes. So they're doing it
out of pure passion. Yeah.
Like says there's a kid,
he calls himself the paradigm shift
on Youtube and I met him and you know,
he's a man, he's just really fucking
talented. 90 he made this thing for me,
the American war machine. And uh, I
mean it's like, it's, it's humbling.
It's humbling because you, you, you
hear the words that you say and they,
the kind of the words seemed just kind
of obvious things that you've thought of
and set up a hundred times.
Right. But then when you,
this kid puts it to
images or video and music
and you see the power of an idea of the
power of an idea to live on beyond its
inception, beyond the moment that it came
out of your mouth. There was this guy,
the thinking primate is
the youtube name and bay.
They did a remix of us and I
thought it was glorious. Honestly.
I thought it was glorious. Yeah, there's
a lot of those guys out there and yeah,
we're, we're super honored
that they do that. It's a,
one of the coolest things of all time.
It's so weird.
It's a weird thing going on right now,
man.
I think the Internet is kind of
ushered in a whole new culture.
I really do believe that.
It's, uh, it's, well, you can't
get by on bullshit anymore.
It seems like a culture of massive
collaboration and cooperation.
And even that recent example of that,
a viral video that they made about
Joseph Kony in Africa and it reached 100
million views in a week,
you know, and like,
and I think that just what
it shows between that and
also the Anti Sopa movement
online. I think that what
it's really demonstrating,
it's just the ability to create viral
swells that have massive impact without
having used like mainstream media
for example, let's just make a video,
put it on Youtube for free and have
a voice in the national conversation.
Like everybody can do that.
And the price points keep going down and
down and down exponentially. And it's,
there's no reason not to think
like, God, what comes next?
Well, yeah, well this guy,
I don't know the whole store and the
guy who orchestrated the whole Kony
campaign, and I've seen some
criticisms about him, but it did,
didn't really make much sense to me.
I mean,
it seems like this guy really is a war
criminal and what this guy's doing by
exposing that. And it was like, yeah,
we're exposing a really, a guy has tons,
some terrible, horrible
things. Oh, no, absolutely.
I just think the success of the campaign,
it's amazing.
Game Changing, game
changing, viral success, uh,
also is going to invite a
scrutiny that comes with that.
But whatever the controversy is,
that's a whole separate conversation.
I think the real conversation is, you
know, people, democracy, social movements,
revolutions, take note. This is
how you join the conversation.
This is how you get your voice heard.
No need to like take up arms,
no need to be violent. Like you want
to get something heard, you know,
have a good video editor and a good
sense of aesthetic presentation. Yeah,
no shit. That's kind of amazing, isn't
nothing. You know, I saw that the tweets,
they started coming in,
you know, this Kony Kony,
Kony and I knew who the guys want. The guy
was, I, I'd, I'd read about his, uh, his,
his move with Africa
and you saw Peter Pan.
It's all exactly the same
as Kone. Really? Yeah.
Then the Peter Pan is still the kids that
go to an army and isn't that horrible
though, that that actually
is happening at someone.
They're stealing children and forcing
them to become soldiers. I mean,
it's just terrifying stuff. It's really,
really horrifying. Horrifying stuff. Yeah,
no, it's terrible. But I
do think that, you know,
we're seeing violence is going down
across the world. I mean this guest,
Steve Pinker, and he has a Ted
Talk, the myth of violence,
we might have mentioned it last time.
We'll say that if violence is down
across the world and the chances of a man
dying at the hands of another man or
the lowest than they've ever been,
now granted there's more people in
the world and there were in the past.
But proportionally the violence is a
lot less. And I think as these people,
you know, the rising billion in certain
parts of the world coming online,
getting smartphones,
joining the global conversation,
all of a sudden can
have their voices heard.
And the first step to addressing
the problem is, you know,
making an awareness that
the problem is there.
So the importance of it
can resonate with people.
And so I think there's reason
to be optimistic about even
the worst of the worst.
I agree.
Getting,
I think less worse automatically go
pessimistic because things aren't perfect.
You know, we look at it and we go, God,
well why is there so much
fucked up shit in this world?
Why is there so much crime? Why is it so
much violence? Why is it so much death?
Why is war still here? Why is corruption
still here? But what you don't realize,
if you really stop and think,
it's like this is the best it's ever
been ever by a Goddamn long shot.
Absolutely.
Who's driving on the way over here today
on the highway and it was a nice day
here in Pasadena. There was nobody on
the highway. It was like easy traveling.
So nice and beautiful. It's sunny
out and I was thinking how fucking,
how much it would have sucked to Jill
live just 500 years ago to totally just
500 a blip in time.
Like nothing.
No cars to fucking horses. There's
no, not even trails out here.
You know you,
you need to see there's a,
there's a presentation by this guy called
Hans robling, his website gapminder.
He does this thing where he shows all
the nations across the world over time,
and how the indicators of quality of
life and infant mortality rate and income
and all these,
all these different things,
he shows that all the countries of the
world, even in the worst of the worst,
are rising. So the rising tide does lift
everybody else. And it's unbelievable.
And I think the reason that most people
don't realize that things are always are
getting better is because of the Amygdala.
Peter Diamandis did a presentation about
this at the Ted conference just a week
and a half ago, and he has this book
called abundance. And he explained that,
you know,
because our brains evolved in a time
where we had to have fight or flight mode,
the Amygdala is always looking for
danger and it supersedes everything else.
And so the media gives us danger because
that's what we're drawn to. You know,
if it bleeds,
it leads and we're always going to
be paying attention to what's wrong,
even when there's infinitely
more things that are going right.
And because the media wants to
just get viewership, you know,
the mainstream media will
feed us what we want,
which is to see all the horrible things
that are happening across the world.
Right.
Although eventually that's actually going
to be a good thing because if we can
see what's wrong,
we'll try to address it and try to fix it.
But even when we remedied 99% of
the problems that exist today,
our brains are still going to be seeing
the new problems because that's what the
brain does.
The amount of time from us running from
Jaguars to to to being a guy steps into
a Jaguar and turns the key that
the amount of time is so small.
The biology has never had a
chance to catch. It does not.
We have pretty much the same brains as
we did a hundred thousand years ago and
that's,
I mean a hundred thousand years ago,
kind of everyone is agreeing unless
you really go extreme that there was no
sophisticated culture which has nothing.
A hundred thousand years is nothing.
It's a blame. What the fuck happened
man? Language language guy into it.
Last year we did get
into [inaudible] playing.
You really believe that that just made
everything changed because we could
exchange information. Yes. Well, because,
because the moment that we invented,
and this is where Terence
Mckenna gets into, you know,
kits Kurzweilian and Kevin Kelly ish and
his comments is that he said that when
we invented language,
uh,
biological evolution stopped playing
the key role because it was replaced by
this, you know, a cultural
epigenetic type of evolution,
which goes faster and faster and faster
because it accrues knowledge and it
builds on itself. And it's not
limited by the hardware of the brain,
which would take billions and
billions of years to change, you know?
And so this cultural thing,
you know,
all of a sudden each brain became a
neuron in a vaster global brain of a crude
knowledge and intelligence that was
bootstrapping on its own complexity,
which is why over the last hundred
thousand years it has been ex the,
the cultural evolution has been
accelerating exponentially.
It manifested as technology,
technological evolution.
But what's most interesting is that this
telescoping nature of it gets faster
and faster and faster. So over the last
hundred thousand years. Yeah. Crazy.
But over the last hundred years even,
it's gotten crazier than the last
billion. No, they say that a thousand
years ago. No one could read silently.
Right. There you go. They
had to read by talking.
They had to say the words
no one could read silently.
And it was actually one of the ways
that some, some guy, I don't remember,
some religious figure,
Hamas Aquinas,
maybe it's him not sure proved that
he was a saint because he can resolve
because he could read silently and
then he would recite it. Amazing.
He would look at it and not say anything.
Look at the scripture,
not obviously not reading,
cause he wasn't speaking aloud.
And then he would recite it.
Wow.
And that was his master of the
scripture was unparalleled.
It's cause he could read silently.
He was like the only guy. Yeah.
I don't think it's that guy though.
It's like it's one of those
other religious people that
may or may not have ever
really existed or might not
have been Thomas Aquinas.
I didn't want to ask Sam Harris if he
believed that Jesus was a real human.
That was the end design guys documentary.
I remember as it,
he said that he probably
never even existed.
Well cause he shares all the same
attributes as all these other gods and all
these other cultures,
they all die in the same age.
They're all born at the same like,
but isn't it also
possible that it could have
been just a real person,
but they attached all these
other attributes to him
because of ancient mythology
I suppose. And it just says if you look
at it open, just completely open. Right.
But I don't know if it was a real dude,
but man,
you want to talk about one guy just
kind of dominating religion for like
thousands of years, you
know? Yeah. It's like know,
well he became a meme. If he was at
wasn't, it was no longer a person man.
He became a meat, which, you know, and
Richard Dawkins' book the selfish gene,
he says that there was this
new replicator, you know,
just like jeans where the replicators
they could multiply and they could evolve
over time. That there was a new replicator
that was born above the biosphere,
new kingdom, above the biosphere
and the Denisons of this kingdom,
more ideas.
And so he said ideas in the form of memes.
They're like organisms. They've
retained the properties of organisms.
Even though they rise above the biosphere,
they replicate,
they complete each other, they mutate,
they leap from brain to brain. They come,
they compete for attention, you know,
and he goes crazy. And you know,
James Gleek wrote the book,
the information says that the most,
the primary building block of
reality might be information before,
before you know,
it before matter itself.
So he actually says it
comes from bit matter,
comes from information and
that information is really
what's at the core of
reality. And uh, it's just an
insane idea and endless cause.
That goes back to the whole thing about
the power to change the world. People,
ideas,
passions can change.
The world because ideas have done
more than jeans over the last hundred.
Well, Mckenna would always go on about
the world being made of language. Yes.
Which is really hard to wrap your
head around, man. That was a,
that was a real mind fuck because sort
of, not really, but wait a minute,
because two people have to communicate
in order to create something new.
And then you know, you thinking
about infrastructure and cities,
that is all a factor of language. Without
language, none of this would be there.
It's just, it's so hard to wrap your head
around that. And I think that the, that
he was spot on and I think that the reason
that he was spot on is because when I
think when he says, okay, the
world is made of language,
what he's saying is we create a mental
model of the world in order to understand
the world. In order to speak about
the world and react to the world.
We create a mental model in our head
and then we label those pictures in our
heads, you know,
symbolically. So we abstract,
defy reality and therefore the way that
we interface reality through the prism
of our language, our thinking,
our preconceptions are
stereotypes. Our culture,
which is what they say.
We don't see the world as it is.
We see the world as we are, which
speaks to exactly and directly to it.
I think Mckenna was saying
reality is made of language.
It's almost like it's why like they say
that like even like thinking a happy
thought, we'll start to
make you happier. You know,
like essentially the world changes,
you become happier about the
world simply by thinking. It's so,
and it sounds kind of
like new agey and stuff,
but like not really because even the
object of description I think does
something to influence
one's perception of reality,
which is just how you interpret electrical
signals going through your brain
anyway.
And so if you're aware that reality is
made of language and that we're like
cocreating it with our intention,
um, and something of course,
which is magnified with psychedelics.
That's why I've talked about set and
setting being so integral to the trip
because your thoughts about the
trip effect the trip itself.
So thoughts become reality,
but we should think of our
lives as one big fucking trip.
Our normal baseline waking sober lives
is one big heroes journey and, and it's,
and it should be up to us
to think of it so and so.
If we're all on a hero's journey,
if we're all on an extended
lifelong mine manifesting,
which means a psychedelic trip,
then we have a responsibility to sort
of use words to map our reality the way
that we want to be authors of our reality,
of our existence,
to make a masterpiece out of life.
One that we would willingly live again
and again for all of eternity. So it like,
like what we're doing now,
our conversation,
it's changing the reality
inside the synapses of those
that are engaging with us.
Just the same way we're changing each
other's reality right now. You know,
this is a different reality
than where we were an hour ago.
We're literally interfacing in a
different, yeah, it's university.
You don't think about it that
way though. You think, well,
we're just doing a podcast,
a podcast in here talking shit.
Yes,
but your portions of your mind,
the output of your mind,
whether it's immaterial or not,
I'm still creates tangible impact in
the world. Because think of light,
especially like the one or five or 10
people that you might inspire to create
some work of art that came out of
what they heard in this conversation.
And that worked of art gets licensed
by a brand to create a campaign for
creativity that then the government
of Finland adopts in their,
in their policy for education
for the following year.
And it should transforms the lives
of the next generation of students.
The Butterfly effect and transformation
triggered by ideas is more powerful
than, you know, I think, you know, uh, uh,
then then that then of the physical world,
I think you're absolutely right,
especially in the age of the Internet.
This is,
this is the time where the ideas really
can go viral almost instantaneously.
Like this Kony video and there's,
I mean we do,
I don't even think we've really fully
examine the impact possible through,
you know, through, through
information, especially with with the,
what are kids going to be
like, man, what are you know,
20 year old kids going to be
like 20 years from now. All Dude,
just growing up in more
advanced and empowered. Yeah.
Way more aware. Way, way harder
to bullshit. Yeah. Enabled kids.
There's no crazy,
they're going to look back on the
nonsense that we believe today and they're
going to be laughing at us. Ma'Am. Yeah.
I think even the way that you know
how things are voted in, you know,
how people resolve issues. I think the
idea of having representatives, you know,
over there to,
to carry our voice to Washington is
obsolete because we are post geographicals
beings at this point.
We don't need somebody else to represent
us necessarily because we can all
represent ourselves and have
a voice online. In fact,
there's people that are talking about how,
you know,
we could reform or upgrade or reexamined
like how government is run and how
people are represented. I mean I'm
talking like a little farther out,
but there's this guy who's starting
this thing as a friend of mine.
His name's Micah and uh,
he used to actually be with students for
sensible drug policy and now he's doing
this thing called dynamic democracy,
which is about starting a conversation
and exploring new ways of how the
Internet, the human extended nervous
system that's connecting us. All right.
Cause we love saying that we are
all connected, we are all empowered.
Well how about we upgrade the
way the world is run, you know,
like on a mega scale. Well we
talk about it, you know? Yeah.
Yeah. I mean that that essentially is
what the Internet is doing, right? Yeah.
The Internet.
I mean I've heard people be down on the
Internet and I guess you could see some
negative
points to anonymity and there's a few
aspects of pornography that are a little
unseemly.
It's definitely accelerated pornography.
I'll tell you that things
have gotten really weird man.
If you want to look at like what happens
to human beings when left alone to
their own devices and when,
when allowed to expand in a,
in a contained market like pornography,
there's only so many different things they
can do. So they, they, they, you know,
you know what the big thing is lately
that I keep seeing man is girls getting
guys to come in them and then they squirt
it into a champagne glass and drink it
and you're like really? Or a Martini
glass really will look, just always ask.
Just because these digital tools
extended the range of our creativity,
it doesn't mean that people can't use
that creativity in ways we don't agree
with or perhaps in bad ways because just
like we use the power of fire to cook
our food, we use the power
of fire to burn other people,
which is always a double edged sword
of any expansion and extension of human
reach.
But that's,
that's still what evolution is probing
for because we're all seeking out
complexity. It's just going
from single celled organisms,
multicellular organism to beings to
thinking beings to beings who create
technology. And so on and so forth.
So it's all happening anyway.
So people say it's not going to stop.
It's part of evolution. But yes,
we have to acknowledge that these tools
are double edged sword and that's fine.
That's part of it. What makes
people really like doing
that? That's possible too.
Right?
I like Billy,
a woman out there that actually likes
to get dudes to shoot loads and,
and then she squirts them out
into a glass. It is very possible.
And who am I to judge right now?
Shit. Shit that you like. Hey,
people can do whatever they want as long
as they're not hurting anybody else.
It's, you know, it's just weird
that porn is accelerated to this,
to what it is today.
A porn was not just porn for a longest
time and know you'd heard rumors of like
snuff films or something crazy,
but no one ever saw one.
Did you ever see a snowfall, Brian
and uh, yeah, it seems snuff films.
We've seen people die on the inner war
now. Real life. Yeah. It's disturbing.
But I don't even know if those
are real half the time now.
I remember when nine inch nails had a
snuff film out called broken. It was like,
they advertise it like as this bootleg
video and you'd rent it and it looked
like somebody murdering somebody else. It
was kind of like faces of death. Oh Wow.
And that's terrible man.
And everyone thought it was a snuff film.
There have been real films, man, for real.
There was a documentary on it a while
back. Um, and that's terrible. Yeah.
And the guy who was the, uh, one of the,
one of the people that were interviewing
was talking about watching this film.
And as he's talking about watching
the film, he starts crying. Wow.
That's pretty intense. Yeah. He's, he's
obviously a pretty fucked up by it,
you know, I remember maybe he didn't cry.
Definitely got choked up. He was like,
just thinking about watching this.
He just a broad spectrum of
human behavior, man. It's got a,
we've got a five piece stata.
Is there a way or is it necessary to
have negative in order to influence
positive? I mean, is that
a know if that's necessary?
I think that was know that the there that
has been something that perhaps has
worked for some people you know to to you,
you got to know what bad is in order to
know what good is. You know, the contrast.
But it doesn't mean that we come up,
come up,
come up with some more novel solution
that allows us to live, you know,
cause if according to that idea that we
need the bad in order to know the good,
it means that it implies
that we're always,
we need to have suffering to appreciate,
you know, when we're not suffering.
I don't think that's the case
too. But if you look at
things as being natural,
you look at everything as being natural,
like wolf behavior,
be behavior or look at all this
stuff as being natural and, and in,
in and positive towards
whatever their goal is.
Whether their goal is to create
this beehive that they create,
whether their goal is
to create an ant hill.
When you look at human society may be
what we're doing as natural as well.
And maybe we're so fucking chaotic and
so crazy because you sorta have to be to
be working with technology that's so far
and ahead what your biology is capable
of processing.
So we have this fucking wacky tribal
monkey shit going on while we have nuclear
power,
while we have Adam,
there's there, there's a
lot going on. And you know,
increasingly people are moving into their
own personal universes and soundscapes
and when we have virtual reality,
then we each become the God in our
own universe at that point. You know,
an infinity of combinations
and permutations of
lifestyles will be explored by
individual individuated nervous systems
living out in the atmosphere of the
inner web. You know, um, so
who the fuck knows? But uh,
but at that point we won't care what
that person does in their own virtual
universe.
Like the porn is going to be awesome.
It's going to be gross gross ever properly
grocer balut ponds where it's like
it's shoved in the vagina for a week and
then pull it out and somebody eats it
or something. Why? I
hope not. I hope, I hope.
I hope it actually becomes about like
composing and creating the greatest dream
we have ever dreamed to make greater
art than we've ever experienced.
To create better designer,
designer drugs,
engaged with our senses and make us
appreciate art and ways that we couldn't
have before to merge with our lovers
to become one with them. I mean,
we use language to connect and
say how we feel to one another.
That's one emerge all the time. What
do they want to, you want to do, man?
What he like? You want to go hang
out with your boy? It's gonna.
You can't want to go play pool,
but what if your boys want to merge?
The boys want to merge
with you and your wife.
You won't be playing pool though you
and wants to merge with your lunch.
It's like, hey man, can I merge
with your wife? That's weird.
So I see what it's like to be heard.
They want to merge with your kids,
whatever they can copy and sexual
life. It's not sexual. No, no, no.
What do they want to merge with a dolphin?
Because they want to know what
it's like to be a Dyson. Timothy
leary settle the fuck down. Merging
with dolphins and people. Yeah.
What if right.
That's this guy.
We have to define like once
if we do create something
that allows like the human
consciousness to merge,
to interface with something,
we're going to have to like really define
what's happening there so people don't,
whether it's going to be Hershel interest,
I just don't see.
You can see like Nancy Grace on TV.
Who is this man that he's merging
with a 14 year old girl in Florida.
Three tickets.
You tell me that's appropriate
that this man is merged.
What does a grown man haven't calm and
with the thinking of a 14 year old girl,
she gets a little wetter every time
there's a dead baby in Florida.
Every time something happens
in Florida, she's like, Oh yes.
More programming,
more material.
You know? I have to say the
fact that we see so much,
can't she find nice things?
Can Nancy grace please?
I'm not picking on you because
I have to them a comedian.
K You just find one nice story. Yeah.
Need, we need, we need more programming.
That's uplifting.
Yeah.
Isn't it nice to see stuff that
makes you feel good about humanity?
Good to have people go after bad people.
Don't get me wrong,
they're stopping the crime and
preventing getting along. But absolutely.
As far as like what we project our issue
is that there's 7 billion people on
this planet and if you only want
to pay attention to negative shit,
you can find enough to fill
every second of every day,
every second of every day of every
moment that you are on this planet.
It's someone's getting Jack.
Yes.
But I'm saying I think people are
reacting to that by creating more and more
really inspiring content.
And I think corporations now all,
I want it to align themselves with
having a sort of a positive impact on the
world.
You know,
they're saying there's more to to a
corporation than just making money.
How about wanting to make a social life,
but I think it is becoming part of it,
part of our consciousness.
Our increasingly like this
is what you're hearing.
I mean, you had Pepsi do that campaign
last year and they, they're, they're all,
they're realized. I, my
point was that, hold on,
but my point was that you have to manage
your own interaction with this kind of
information. My point was that if you
so choose, you can be around it all day,
every day or you can just not,
and you can force yourself into more
positive places and the options available
that both options are
available. Absolutely. You,
you have to be kind of careful and how
you manage your consciousness because you,
you really can freak yourself the fuck
out if you only chose to concentrate on
all the negative things in this world is
too much information. Totally. You know,
and, and you, you could
drown and information,
especially because the new
limited resources our attention.
But I think it's interesting.
There's a book about this,
it's called the information diet and it
says that it's really up to us to take
responsibility over our information diet,
to set up curators,
to set up certain filters
to, to sort of, you know,
to have a significant say in
how we interface with media.
And we have that opportunity now that we
didn't have before when it was just two
channels, it was on or off. Now there's
a billion options. Curate author,
create an experience and information
diet that will keep you mentally
invigorated.
Just like there's also food diet will keep
you a lot of experimenting on too. You
know, there's also a lot of people trying
different things out and focusing on
different things and there's a lot of
misses that seemed like they were hits.
Like you remember when everybody
was into the secret? Yeah.
You remember that and everybody was
convinced that all you have to do is think
positive and just draw a picture
of the house you want on your wall.
And one day it'll sort of manifest
itself in yes. Secret fans. Yes.
I'm just paraphrasing. Yeah. But
don't you think that an example,
like the way you said it is probably a
lot of people literalized the message
without really thinking about it a
little deeper and understanding how,
it might not sound like just bull here's,
but here's the problem with the
secret. Some of it's real. Okay.
There is a certain amount.
It's one of the ingredients
and making something happen.
And one of the ingredients is vision.
It's 100% there's one of the ingredients,
and you talked to anybody that has
some sort of a great success and a good
percentage of them,
at least some of them are sorta
gotten their vision along the way,
but a good percentage of them had a
vision and followed it. Right. Push.
That is true. But there's so much
other shit involved. Education,
hard work, discipline.
It's not a set thing.
Cuing because it's like everything.
Everything out in the world. Everybody's,
you know,
the most magnificent artifact from the
iPhone to the jet engine is actualized
from a thought, from a dream, from
a design, which means to say, we,
we constructed the virtual version
before we constructed the actual virgin,
right? That's the same thing as
visualizing something into being. But the,
into being part is when you say,
okay, I'm going to go execute on this.
I'm going to go like, you know, I'm
going to move through space and time,
move my atoms through space and time and
go construct the thing and go lobby to
build the thing, to build the
dream, to actualize the goal.
And I think maybe people who read the
read the book without reading as deeply
enough into it what they
thought it was like, okay,
I'm just going to sit on a couch and
dream something that's going to come
knocking on my door.
So the problem is that they're dealing
with a bunch of people who have had
success and when people have
had success and you know,
they all tell you the same story,
Oh, I knew it was going to happen.
And I dreamed it. Well, but that's
because it happened. You know? I,
you know what I'm saying? There's a
lot of shit that comes along the way.
You could've gotten so
random car accident.
It could have got hit by a fucking media.
Absolutely.
I'm not exactly sure if 100% of your
success is based on the fact that you
focused on your dream. Right. I think
it's a percentage of the sec success,
but there's a lot of luck involved
there too. Oh yeah, 100% Oh yeah.
There's a lot of,
there's a lot of luck involved in every,
I mean like the fact that each of us
is here, we beat out billions of sperm.
We've already are.
All of us are living against the odds.
Every respect for luck I think is one
of the reasons why people get lucky or
respect for luck. You know, you
gotta respect. Luck is, you know,
fortune good fortune is
unquestionably an ingredient.
There's an ingredient in there and I
feel like if Karma is real in any form,
I believe that's where the most evidence
of it being real is. That to me.
Then the people that I know that are the
most fortunate or also the kindness are
the most generous.
Those are the people that are the most
fortunate because if one's a win for
themselves as well, which is
a very critical point with
a lot of people mess up.
They're super nice to other people,
but they treat themselves like shit
that to their body, like shared no good.
They don't go after their own goals.
They don't trace their own dreams.
They'll let people abuse them
because they're too nice. I mean,
there's a lot of people that
are not nice to themselves.
You've got to be as nice to yourself
as you are to other people. I totally,
that is a huge part of the equation
that a lot of people miss out on.
They're like, I'm a good person. I'm nice
to people. Yeah, but you hate yourself.
You know, you hate your body. You
hate your mind, and you can do,
not everybody can do you. You can do
more for her, for the world, I think.
Um, by treating yourself with the same
kindness that you treat other people and,
uh,
once a sickness not to absolutely.
Food is fucking delicious, but you
shouldn't eat yourself to death, you know,
I'm not saying you have to look
like Kate Moss in her prime.
Where'd I put out that reference from?
Where was that? But you know, you know,
you don't have to,
you know,
you don't have to fucking eat yourself
to death either. Right. You know, that's,
there's a lot of people that
eat themselves to death.
Like the human mind can go terribly wrong.
It can go on a horrible path and just
get stuck there. Just get stuck. Yeah.
Yeah. But the thing is, when we have
that problem with software, you know,
software gets corrupted or if it gets
a bad virus in it, you know, we can,
we can upgrade and reboot the system
and we're not so lucky. Biology.
What if someone did something horrible
like a, there was a, you know,
a mall shooting or something
and some guy goes to the mall,
just shoots random people. Okay. Then you
reboot them. Would you allow that guy?
Do you think that's okay in a civilized
society? Do you think we have to reboot,
reboot him and that's a
great philosophical question
to ask. I mean that's,
that's a different case study.
I was doing blame society and allowing
him to get to a point where his software
failed him and how do we approach that
if we, if it's effective, if it's real,
do we blame the tissue that's left
after we remove his consciousness?
Do we blame that tissue and say,
I'm sorry,
this tissue has to die to make up for
the 16 people who knows? Maybe, maybe,
maybe there will be some form of light.
There will be an ethical dilemmas like
a virtual reality psychedelic experience
where you take him down the rabbit hole
and he has a Joseph Campbell's hero's
journey and he collides with his own
cosmic nakedness and then emerge is
rehabilitated. Maybe we'll have like,
sounds like it'll download rehabilitation.
Yeah. Electronic Iowasca use
that Ag. You tweet across that.
That would be a way to,
you should grab a criminal and he should
put him in an Iowasca session with a
shaman to stare into the nakedness
of his own soul. This is my new show.
My next show that I'm working on, nobody's
bought it yet, but I've got some hopes.
It's called Douche bags on
mushrooms and that's the show.
We chose the lunch bags throughout the
world and we just bring him somewhere and
dose up with like five grams a mushroom.
It was to let them see themselves.
I mean,
nobody's going to die.
I think psychedelic therapy is so spot on,
like in terms of the,
the psychic read justments that can
happen in one session could take years
and given it to people. Yeah, giving it
to criminals as part of a rehabilitation,
if that would be very interesting to
explore. It just sounds very fast.
Not even just criminals, but people
that have issues like alcoholism.
That's obvious.
I mean they just came out with a study
just now that said that LSD could help
people get over Alco as in one session.
Yeah.
It doesn't have to say about the
Russian doing tests on this. In the 60s,
in the 1960s for they had determined that
500 micrograms was enough to cure like
more than 70% of chronic alcohol,
uh,
patients that came in and tried acid
just from like looking at the situation
just completely differently being
separated from the nonsense of what you're
engaged in. Yeah. We get stuck in these
weird patterns. It's very strange.
It's almost like a byproduct of our
ability to focus on things, right?
We have this ability to become intense
and obsessed and focused on things in a
positive sense.
But there's a byproduct of that
and that by side effects obsession,
it's a glitch. Yeah, it's a,
it's a possible, you know, it's,
it's like if somebody gives you a
fucking Ferrari but you don't know how to
drive a stick shift and you sort of
figure it out along the way and you're
jamming gears and fucking things up.
Sometimes it's working well and some
things you don't understand how to use the
system and they could be just that.
You know when you see a kid that becomes
obsessed with jerking off, you know,
get them into a sport, maybe become
a fucking world champion. You know,
maybe he's just one of those kids
that just whatever he focuses on,
he focuses on insanely,
it does a lot of kids out there and
I'm not saying you're wasting your life
playing video games because
video games are awesome. They've,
they didn't improve one's brain but
a bunch of studies about how gaming,
like coordination and cooperation.
But what I'm saying is that these kids,
any kid that gets really
good at a video game,
you can get really good at anything.
You can get really good at it. If you,
if you put that kind of focus that you
put to get fucking awesome at call of
duty, you could really, you know, you
could have, you could have a better life.
You could imagine you getting tricky
unification on nurses where you can play
these games to address real
social challenges in these
gamers will probably find
solutions to problems that engineers
couldn't in the real world that this is
happening more and more now to use the
resources of gamers to gamify a real
world problem. How does that
work? Well, because the reality,
they'll create like some some interface
and some some problem and they're just
like a game and you get points for
solving issues related to the gamers
discovered like some antibody
for some crazy virus.
People can Google this for gamers.
Gamers solve some illness like crazy
stuff and you're going to be seeing that
more and more. In fact, they,
they did this crowd sourcing
crowd sourcing experiment
about a protein folding
and you know the world's best protein
folder is who can fold in design proteins
in the virtual space is like a woman who
does it in her free time in the UK and
during the day she was like a receptionist
or something and she is the world's
best protein folder. She used to do it
on her computer at night. Yeah, yeah,
cause you crowdsource that what clay
Shirky calls the cognitive surplus.
It's all this extra brain activity,
protein folding. What is she doing?
It's some kind of craft
source softwares thing.
They less people like fold
proteins and you know,
and you can figure out how
to do it in the virtual
space and then it can
be applied in real life.
And it turns out that the best one in the
world was this woman in the UK and all
the scientists in the world. Yeah, yeah.
She's just a lady with a regular yeah,
yeah, yeah. And you're going
to find that more and more.
There's going to be some Gamer,
you know in Budapest who was going to
fix world hunger. You know like wow,
look at, look, look, look at like,
like hackers hacking community.
Like these little 13 year olds are
hacking fucking Microsoft. Yeah, exactly.
13 year old heck the UFC. Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. They're bad asses.
Did you hear about Lola Sec guy?
Is that how you call Lowe's turn?
He ratted out like all
these anonymous guys,
like 26 anonymous cause he just
grabbed it out everybody to the FBI.
Just just because like I guess the FBI
was playing dirty and it was like saying,
hey, we're going to arrest you for ever.
You never got to see your kids ever.
You know, and they, the FBI actually
admitted to it and I interviewed at that.
That's what they used their kids again.
So what are the, what were they guilty of?
Hacking, you know, digital terrorism
May, you know, and they were like,
they broke it into some serious websites.
Right.
That's like somebody said recently it was,
it's a higher form than terrorism.
Oh, that does cyber terrorism second
to higher than somebody's like, well,
I have a good friend,
this guy, Mark Goodman,
he's at singularity university over in
Silicon Valley where they look at how
these emerging technologies are, well
this, there's a singularity university.
Hell yeah, dude, you need
to go, man. I just did their
executive program here in La.
It was at Fox studios and it was hosted
by the head of Fox, the chairman James,
Jim Giannopoulos. And it was the
founder, Peter Diamandis and Kurzweil.
They have people from all over the world,
like the most interesting, smart people,
diplomats, actors, technologists,
business people to learn
about exponentially emerging
technologies and how they
can be addressed to solve humanity's
grand challenges. And you know,
like the homework there,
everybody that comes out has to come
up with an idea that can help a billion
people.
Cause the,
the notion is that technology and our
tools now allow individuals to knew what,
what to do, what at one time
could only be done by governments,
you know what I'm saying? Or, or, or
people with extreme resources. But yeah,
singularity university had
an executive program and,
and they had talks about all
the amazing stuff going on,
but also this Guy Mark Goodman talked
about like cyber terrorism and new forms
of obviously synthetic biology
used in bad ways. And the,
that it's a conversation that needs
to be had because human nature,
human beings have a good
ability to foresee problems.
And so we should start addressing those
problems before they become a serious
issue so that we can enjoy all the
fruits and benefits that are coming from
these emerging technologies.
But at the same time take responsibility
for obviously what is a double edged
sword as always,
or the aliens land first before
we'd get our shit together. Right.
Well and then we've got a problem.
Actually we should talk about aliens.
I have a fucking crazy idea to tell
you. Okay, Tom, ready for this?
You guys heard of the trends sension
hypothesis? No, I have not. Okay,
so I just found out about
this last night I knew was,
it's a hypothesis by this
guy called John Smart.
He's an accelerating specialist futurist
over in Silicon Valley that tries
sension hypothesis hypothesis
is an answer to Fermi's paradox,
which is if the universe is so vast and
there's all these other plan is to have
added so much more time to
develop intelligent life,
how can we don't see it everywhere, right?
Like that's Fermi's paradox I'm told.
And the trend hypothesis says that
if you look at what's happening with
technological progress as we head
towards the singularity is the
dematerialization and miniaturization of,
of complexity so that there's more energy
per second per gram going through a
microchip than there is
in the surface of the sun.
The most complex thing in the universe
that we know of right now is the human
being. So complexity gets more
complex but also gets denser.
So what they call stem, right?
And so what does stem again,
tell me what it stands for. Uh,
anyway, I'll remember. But anyway,
his brother. Yeah, no, no, no.
But what happens is he says that
eventually this exponentially growing
technology and when we start talking
about nanotechnology and putting
intelligence into the nanoscale,
that we're going to eventually create
an artificial black hole and disappear
into it and slingshot into the future
because there's going to be so much
density and so much complexity is so
much information that eventually is going
to create a rupture through space time
and we're going to disappear into it.
So we're just going to do that
just by density of information.
Too many hard drives in
one spot at one time, yo,
because he says that the computation
event works by shrinking things and
complexity gets smaller and smaller and
smaller as the computer chips get faster
and faster and faster and more powerful.
And we look at the complexity that's an,
an iPhone today is a million times
cheaper, a million times smaller,
thousand nine more powerful than half
a building in size was 40 years ago.
So in a hundred years,
imagine the complexity that is going to
be in something smaller than an atom or
even scales beyond that.
So when our minds,
when intelligence is
residing on those scales,
basically they're saying that eventually
we're not going to colonize outer space.
We're going to go into the interspace,
we're going to go smaller and smaller
and smaller in density until we literally
create the ultimate universal computer,
which is a black hole.
Does everybody have to do this or can
we, can we opt out, compete people off?
Raise the idea. I don't know if I
explained it very well. Sidelines.
I've been saying for years that I think
the people responsible for the big bang.
There you go. There you go. Well,
the big bank could have been birthed
from a previous universe that eventually
achieved the transection and disappeared
into a black hole. So recess.
I think that's why we're so
fascinated with technology.
We eventually hit a point where we figure
something out and we press a button
and we disappear into a black hole,
which is worth as a big
bang in a new universe.
The whole idea of the big bang is really
fucking amazing because it's amazing
that science ever would come up
with a theory like the big bang.
It's almost like they had to have
a theory. So this was the best one.
The universe is constantly expanding.
There's um,
there's some radio waves from 14
billion years ago. We're detecting,
we believe that it was a big explosion.
Let's just run with this. Yeah.
And the idea that at one point in time,
14 whatever billion years ago,
the universe was so small, it was more
than the head of a pin. Everything.
Higher universe. That is
that is that, well that,
but that was going the other direction
and I just remembered what the stem
acronym stands for. It's space,
time, matter and energy. Space, time,
matter and energy. Shrink, stem.
Then space, time, energy and matter.
Oh, okay. My bad. Yeah. Spacetime energy
matter, man. Compressor compresses.
As technology
progresses,
so there's less space and less time and
the things are smaller and a and less
energy going through that
matter and also less matter.
So that's the move towards density.
It's like a reverse big bag.
Giving me a fucking headache. Yeah,
it's, it's, it's really ridiculous.
If I was correct,
I have,
I'm sure I'm not the only one who's
ever thought this up by the way.
I think when you look at,
you know,
look at nuclear bombs and need just
nuclear power in general, the fact that,
you know,
where we control most of our power and
major cities is controlled by these nutty
fucking nuclear explosions that they've
contained of exposures with it. Yeah.
Could reaction that they've contained
in the area. And if the power goes out,
like if it goes to Japan, everyone's
fucked. Do you have to run?
Everybody said get away from that and
it's doom for a hundred thousand years.
This, that alone, just that
alone makes me think like, wow,
like I know I don't have any
better options. No I don't,
but this is all you guys.
Got You guys. I mean in the 1960s and
seventies this is what you figured out.
You figured out how to make nuclear
power that if the power goes off it just
eats right through the earth and then
everyone's fucked anywhere near it. No,
but isn't it mind blowing?
What a mind,
what minds can do?
Like that's incredible.
I think of the scale that we are like
how small and dense a mind is a thinking
being.
The amount of synaptic connections inside
of something as small as the brain is
as many galaxies as there
are in the universe,
like that amount of complexity in
something so small is what we are.
So it's like people say,
Oh, we're so insignificant.
I think we're like really significant.
You know what I mean?
Like we're the cutting edge of design.
We'll get to that has emerged from
the university. I agree and I don't.
At the same time I
said, yes, we were very,
we're very significant if it
comes to change on this earth,
but the earth is just so God
damn small and the big picture,
it's ridiculous to say that were
significant, were so fucking timing,
but just talk about the whole universe
and literally play back the evolution of
the universe in our heads.
A capacity,
a capacity to understand events
that have occurred over deep time,
not just plain it, right?
So we're creating internet,
we're creating models on
the scale of that universe.
The universe that you're saying
is so much bigger than we are.
We're creating internal models
of it inside of our heads. True.
We're fitting the universe in our head
as far as brought virtual conversations
about it, or that's what's fucking
crazy, which means it fits in our heads.
That design fits in our heads.
If we understand it correctly,
the smartest people in the world,
Einstein among them,
could probably contemplate it in his head.
And you know,
people who take psychedelics say that
they experience the entire universe at
once. Maybe they do. Yeah. Maybe they
do. Maybe it's all inside a mushroom.
You could see the whole thing. You
just got to take enough home. Yeah.
Well cause the universe expands outwards.
But it goes inwards to you. This, this,
this scales get smaller. There's an
entire universe inside of us. 10 trillion,
trillion, trillion atoms.
And apparently the scales,
the scales go smaller in the most
Adams. It's just space. Like give her,
you know, when you look, you've already
told me about that the other night.
Most of,
most of everything is mostly empty space.
Most of us parents mostly up mostly empty
space, which is patterned integrity,
man pattern integrity's.
It's so insane to just even try to wrap
your head around how complex the whole
thing really, truly is. Right?
Which is why people like sticking to
neighborhoods and watching the same shows
they want.
Anything that calms down this bizarre
feeling of never ending complexity,
you know, that it's impossible
to understand or be in
control of your universe.
Well,
it's frightening to live in the mystery,
to live on the edge of knowledge,
to live on the edge of thought.
Well there's a reason we call it the
edge cause there it looks like there's a
ravine on the other end. But I still
think even though as individuals,
some of us find that frightening
and to each his own as a collective,
I think mankind is always restless
and never afraid of the edge.
I think mankind always pushes at the edge
and that's what makes me ultimately so
optimistic about humanity.
We're still here and it's getting crazy
and look at the stuff that humanity is
talking to itself about.
Yeah, about bombing Iran
to man. There's, it's going both ways.
I hit correcting global organisms,
so maybe we're just self, we're
self correcting. I agree with you.
I don't grow share and your optimism
because I'm continually fascinated by the
stupidity of the human race as
well as the intelligence of it.
I think you can't ignore it.
I mean you cannot ignore that.
There's a lot of dummies out there,
unfortunately.
Totally a big percentage of the
world's a fucking mess right now.
And a lot of those people,
a big percentage,
but I just think that what is a mess gets
magnified and brought to our attention.
Well, it's more than 1%, right? More than
1% of the world's in mass, I would say.
When you say, when you think
about Iraq, Afghanistan,
what's going on in Syria,
which has happened in Libya,
what's going on in Egypt?
There's a lot of things about this
that are very exciting, right?
I mean what happened in Libya and
Indonesia, no, don't get me wrong,
but I'm saying you're saying it's a mess.
There's a at one commission, right? Yeah.
We're,
we looked at more than 1% and you've got
a hundred people in a room and one of
them is fucking crazy. I think
we live in disruptive times. Yes.
Fueled by these accelerating technologies.
But I think disruption,
it's like going through the birth
canal. It's like, it's like, you know,
when Timothy Leary, it says that we're
about to like, you know, shed our skin.
You know, we're in the larval stage.
We were pre larval of men were larval,
and then we're just, we're about to
spread our wings potentially. Potentially.
That's where this conversation comes in.
If some new age,
Hitler doesn't step into the
equation. Fair enough. But damn it.
But a good conversation to
have. Yes. Oh yeah, of course.
It's amazing when you really
look back at World War II,
that it was such a short amount
of time ago. It's terrifying.
It's hard to wrap your head
around that. I'm Jewish. I know.
It's w did you have family? That was
my family fled from Europe. Yeah,
my mother's side Polish and Russian.
Yeah. Um, there was a Venezuela,
Ari interviewed a bunch of, wasn't as dad
and, well, I don't want to say, let's see.
But yeah, it's, it's incredible
that that's inside. That could,
that could be your grandparents. That
could be our lifetime. That's within our,
within our grasp
right now. While you know this
chain of life is going on,
the Holocaust was happening,
World War II was happening.
I mean the storming the
beaches of Normandy,
that's like the most savage
shit in human history. You know,
cutting people down with machine guns
as they run through the sand. I mean,
that is, that's our lifetime man. It's
amazing. Some really truly amazing.
When you stop and think about
how crazy that seems. Yeah,
yeah.
There was a really interesting article
that I read because obviously everything
you're saying is very upsetting. It was
informed policy, man. Just stop talking,
dude. It's cool. No, I'm
saying no, no, no, no, no, no.
But there was an article in foreign policy
magazine, it was called V end of war,
and it was one of those counterintuitive
articles that you read it and you're
like, okay, there's these interesting
academics that are saying, yes,
this was tragedy. Yes, there've been
horrible things. Yes, these numbers,
these scales are horrific,
but put it in context over deeper,
longer time, and what you see is
that things are getting better,
less wars happening. Just before
we couldn't cover every war on TV.
There were too many
conflicts zones in the world,
but he talks about how
there's less and less.
It's just it's important to get the
other side that we don't forget that
I'm sure that it's better now
than it has been ever, but as a,
I think human beings as just naturally,
we look at the errors and the issues that
we have and we see a lot of them that
are sort of legacy that aren't there or
aren't corrected and they'd been going
on for so long. Like war. Yeah. I
remember when I was a kid I was,
I dunno maybe like I think it was
like eight or something like that.
When the government pulled out of Vietnam
and the Vietnam War was over and I
remember thinking like,
it's good. It's done.
We're done having wars because now
people realize that we don't like war.
No one's going to go to war anymore.
Look what I remember as even as a child
with the idea in my head that I was
watching the culture evolved past war.
I had like a real sense,
especially I think when you're a child
because as you're growing and you're kind
of experiencing life and it's being
sort of explained to you along the way
through experiences that you,
you start getting an idea that
that's how the whole world works.
That things just get better over time.
Things get smarter, they improve.
Cause that's what you're doing.
You're eight years old,
you're smarter than you were when you were
five. Right. You know what I'm saying?
I may not have a significant leap over,
you know who you are when you're,
so I think that's how I viewed the world
and our member in whatever year it was,
91 or 92 when we, uh, when we went
to Desert Storm, what year was that?
91, right? Ma, maybe whatever.
Remember might even been 89,
but whatever year it was.
I remember watching that happen.
I remember me and my,
my buddy Jimmy that I used
to live with my roommate Jim,
to tell yo what's up to him.
Uh,
we were sitting in front of the TV and
they were showing missiles like firing
over into Baghdad. And I remember
watching that call, what the fuck?
And he looks at me and he goes, we're
a war buddy. We're at war. Like, well,
that didn't even make sense.
Well,
because it seems obsolete compared to all
the great things that are happening in
the world. Right. The massive
collaboration, the massive
cooperation, you know,
people doing things increasingly
for free for one another. Online
people coming together,
people protesting against dictatorships,
Twitter being used as fueled for
dissent and discontent. I mean,
there's so many encouraging trends.
Yeah.
Whenever use kind of contemplate the
fact that there's still bad things out
there.
You really well you want,
the contrast also makes you realize
why there's aspects of us that are so
obsolete. We need a firmware
upgrade, but we're fucking,
we're getting there. You're there to
universities. What you need to go, man,
I'm sure they loved that. You need to
go. Yeah, we had, we actually will. I am.
Was there really? Yeah. And Him
and he did a talk in a panel.
We had this company that does a, wait
a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
We'll I am, gets to talk at the
singular singularity university.
Haman the head of Fox. What does
he's talking about the head. Well,
because he was talking about using these
technologies and her bitches on the
creative and good uses of
these technologies and how
we need to spread these
technologies to those that are less,
uh, less lucky than we are and whatnot.
I'm sure he was talking about nice things.
So I just,
I was at your jokes and we saw it too.
Paralyzed people walk this bionics
company who makes these like exoskeleton
scene though demonstrated to paralyzed
people standing up and walking. I mean,
it was, it was really intense. I've
seen that very much. So skeleton,
it's fucking nuts. Again,
it's like something right
out of a marvel comics man.
Hopefully.
Right?
It looks like a trailer for a movie
that takes place in the future.
That's showing you how we got there.
Archival footage from the future.
It just totally makes sense, right?
I mean it's, it's the future.
They're going to figure out, well, they're
going to figure out artificial bodies.
Absolute for sure.
They're going to be able to put your
head on someone else's body. Dude,
on an artificial avatars,
what?
Isn't there a wired magazine story about
the man who wants to build the real
avatar?
Could you imagine if they get so good
at surgery that they build an artificial
you and the the head is open and they
just have to sew it up and stuff.
Your brain in there,
but they only have like a certain amount
of time where they could take your
brain then reattach it. They open your the
good eye. Good Eye, Mr. Jones. Boom. Oh,
cut up. Next thing I see you're going
to be 20 years old and invincible.
They cut open your fucking brain,
suck it out real quick and they only
have a couple minutes and then they screw
it into this new brain. What it
turn it on? Fire Up is to Jones.
You hear as Mr. Jones 37 seconds. We're
good. We're good. You got a new life.
Mr. Jones made the trip into a synthetic
body with his biological brain? Well,
I think by the time that we can do that,
we will be non biological in the sense
that we'll have far greater than human
intelligence and sentients residing in
decentralized non biological substrates.
Do you feel like that about the
Nano scale? Do you feel like that?
I've never felt like we're
going to go to other planets.
I feel we definitely are.
We're definitely are.
We're going to go to Mars and less
than 10 years. And what did he like?
Elon Musk and his one which was saying,
let me in office. You hear that?
Yes. New Greenridge said
if you let me an office,
but a second term we'll have
a base on the moon. Well,
we don't need governments for that.
See,
that's the difference of where we are now.
It's going to happen by
private space flight.
It's going to be the techno
philanthropists like Elon
Musk who have the vision
and the resources to make it happen
and they benefit from the emerging
technologies because something that was
that the cost was impossible 20 years
ago. All of a sudden he
gives me to miniaturize is
infinitely more affordable. Uh,
we're,
we're going to space and then we're
going to send artists into space and that
will transform the human.
Can we have to decide like
who the artists are cause last thing you
want is shitty poetry from outer space.
Well imagine you. It's got to be like
really analyzing it philosophically.
A podcast from space. How that would
influence your thoughts, your ideas.
How about we just get a green screen,
it puts some space behind me and maybe
that will work and we'll pretend to be
the same NASA suits. Do you have any NASA
soup, Brian? Yep. Minds in the trunk.
Yeah, I know. I don't know man.
I don't know what the future holds but
I think the big bang machine may come
before space travel. I mean I'm
just guessing the big bang machine,
they might press the big bank button
before we figure out how to get to other
planets.
And I hope
all man, we have to at least
figure out how to back ourselves.
What if you fucking fly out to bars?
But if you fly out tomorrow's and it's
just like the shittiest parts of Arizona,
it's just like the shittiest parts of
the Arizona desert and you're like,
you know what?
The spots like this that suck on America,
I could have just driven there.
I didn't have to fucking fly in a rocket
ship to some place with no air to see a
shitty part of the,
of the universe that I could've seen an
Arizona rock desert areas where there's
no one
for 100,000 fucking square miles.
Yeah, Dude, fair enough.
And I think that those that go are not
going to swim on Mars has beautiful
beaches.
I think they're going for the feeling
that they will have when they look out
that window and see
another celestial body.
They're going there for the wanderlust,
the awe.
They're going there for the all that.
That's their religious feeling
getting off on God. Anybody that does
that who really,
if they'd really do choose to give up
essentially years and years of their lives
to for the scientific adventure,
I mean that's what they're doing.
What's going to take like six months to
just to get to Mars. That's a real hero.
And there's going to be a lot of
one way tickets, like you're saying,
that's a real hero. And
who knows, by the way,
what the fuck happens to your body out
there and radiation and deep space,
how unhealthy it is to be in the
atmosphere and, and you know,
and then what are they going
to do? They're going to
have to do some sort of, uh,
what, what is it called when you change
the atmosphere of a new planet, uh,
with terraform? Terraform. Oh
yeah. They'd have to tear a form.
So they would have to build machines
that actually create oxygen and yeah.
And then hope it stays stable,
although,
but you want to go a little crazier
man a little farther into the future.
That will all be done with nanotechnology.
The physicist Freeman Dyson says,
we'll be able to have the entire biosphere
of the world decoded the genome of
the entire biosphere,
of everything that's living on planet
earth and something that's a few micro
grams in weight and at the Nano scale.
And we'll be able to
send those nanotechnology
instructions to self replicate
and seed the universe and a whole rant
about it because she's a physicist
talking about this. Like this is a
thing. It's not like some like, you know,
hippie tripping. This is a
physicist who's, you know,
at one time was probably
a hippie tripping.
It makes sense when you think about
how small data holding, you know,
little little, little hard drives now
and what they're going to be liked.
I mean they've, they've got computers
that are as small as a grain of sand now.
Oh Dude.
Quantum is going to be
doing super position, which means like
being one in zero at the same time. Yeah.
What does that, what is that exactly?
Does anybody, do you understand it? Uh,
I'm no expert but super position means
that can be in motion and still at the
same time it's just a novice. Yes.
Yeah. Two different places at once.
Something could be a particle and a
wave at the same time. And so it can,
something can be at the same time in
two different points in the universe and
simultaneously and communicate,
and this is not horse shit, right?
This is all of this stuff.
This is all proven stuff at least accepted
in the quantum physics communities.
Doesn't that make you want to toss all
previous notions about reality aside?
When you look at something like that and
you go, wait a minute, wait a minute,
wait a minute. The very foundation of
everything that we see, touch, feel,
observe,
no exists is illusory.
It's a goddamn program. Yeah
Dude. It's the fucking matrix.
Yeah. There's my friend.
Rarely. Rarely is real.
Matrix didn't go far enough.
The Matrix didn't go far enough.
It was so brilliant and that's why
inception was similarly on those same,
the same.
There's a make a friend has a shirt,
it has these two guys sitting
in a chair and one of them says,
are we just graphics on an imaginary
tee shirt? And the other guy says,
that's ludicrous. But you could extend
that and extrapolate that to us.
Or we just like two dudes and some
virtual simulation that somebody else is
playing with and then you're like,
Nah,
and then it zooms out and it shows like
that were playing on some screen for
someone else's energy.
The game was really good,
which is what's happening right now.
When you,
when you're playing like a really
good game of quake, you know?
You know when you're in the zone you're
not thinking, Hey, I'm playing quake.
Oh no, he's real. You're locked.
Hopping and moving. You're a part of it.
We can be in multiple realities,
dude. There's no doubt.
We're already doing it with flat screens
that are not even that immersive and we
can lose ourselves in. It is artificial.
It could be just so good it feels.
Yeah,
which makes sense for a lot of shit.
I said so many times that the world feels
like a piece of fiction that the word
they, the reality when a guy like,
you know what? When I yelled,
shut the fuck up at the TV when that
Anthony Wiener guy got caught taking
pictures of his deck, I'm like, come on
man. This is shitty writings. Shitty,
right Sitcom. I'd get mad. Well,
you know that's a movie. Yeah.
Movie about a guy that's criticizing the
screenplay of life starring you would
be really fun. It was. It wasn't,
it wasn't that I was criticizing it was
that it was like Coen brothers ass. Yeah.
It was so preposterous that it seemed
like all of a sudden we're in a movie.
Come on, dude. But the six
pictures of his cock to,
they're just lose the money and clues are
everywhere, man. Row, row, row your boat.
What does that mean? Well, the last
line of row, row, row your boat,
it says life is but a
dream, but a dream. Yeah.
But they're early in their life is but
a dream. They'd probably had a write,
make something wrong.
Not The pursuit of a dream.
Life is not the pursuit of a dream. And
there there's clues everywhere, man. Yeah.
Or someone could have been really
high when they wrote that. Yeah. It,
Jesus wrote that
song. Yeah. I've written a lot of shit
high that I embarrassed about. Yeah.
Like your one joke. Yeah, it's true. I
really did write that. That's funny. Um,
so what, what do we do
to, to sort of, I mean,
I guess what we're doing is what you're
doing right now, what we're doing,
what we can do as in worked
creating memes. Yeah. And we,
what we can do is retweet things
that resonate with, absolutely.
Talk about things that you,
every time you retweet something
600,000 mines are potentially, yeah,
potentially potentially. Fair enough.
But 600,000 is a very big number. She,
so even if only 10 if the tweet that you
sent out triggers a butterfly effect in
his thought,
that opens up a whole new stream of
possibilities for that person that will,
that's real transformation.
So it's natural selection playing out at
a faster and faster rate because things
are happening.
So you're creating artful change in
the world using the power of your mind.
Somebody listening to this might
invent, might invent, you know,
some new poem that becomes the
campaign for some brand that, you know,
transforming the world. Like I said, the
butterfly effect, but we're talking to,
it's on scales and numbers
where that's possible.
I've seen the engaged inspired
audience, you know, interface with you.
Like I've seen it.
So it's like it's kind of what
they're responding to you too man.
They're responded to your ideas and you're
passionate about it. And W you know,
one of the cool things about having a
podcast is someone right now could be
anywhere, you know, doing some, some
tedious work around the house or whatever.
Right?
And they were in a certain state of mind
and the conversation that you brought
up and the way we've
explored these topics,
all of a sudden their mind is fucking
racing, you know? And that is,
that is a real cool thing.
That is a really cool thing that
we can do something like that.
That that to me is one of the
most satisfying aspects of this.
That you can entertain someone and
engage them and literally put them on a
little bit of a mental journey where
they start to hold Hodor looking about
these different subjects.
Yeah, absolutely.
Nano technology and you start exploring
it and seeing how bizarre it is.
Some of the references that you use,
you go and look them up and holy fuck.
So many people ask for book
recommendations after our
session. So many, yeah,
I've got to eventually like make like a
thing on my website to my favorite books.
Favorite documentary. So there's, there's
documentary thread on the message board,
but you know,
I'm such a big fan of Joseph Campbell
and the sort of mine as well,
the hero's journey. See, think of the
hero's journey. We think so literally.
So we're like obviously
a geographical journey.
Like if you go on a safari and
then you climb Kilimanjaro,
you will go through all the steps,
a departure from the ordinary,
overcoming obstacles, having a catharsis
and realization and making the return.
But we need to apply
that metaphor internally.
This podcast session is a Joseph Campbell
Hero's journey person puts on the
headphones and it's dosed the prints
and who's the princess? No, no.
We don't mean on a hero's journey. No,
but think this is the hero's journey.
It follows the steps.
It's a departure from the ordinary.
We're partaking in conversations that
are maybe not your everyday conversations
work,
overcoming obstacles,
the sense that we're
challenging preconceived truths
and questioning ourselves
and asking difficult questions
and thinking new thoughts.
So that's what the obstacles and then
we're transcending and overcoming the
resistance that we have to change
and to new ways of thinking.
And then we're having
hopefully the catharsis,
hopefully sometime during this journey,
we have a moment of profound realization
that changes us both and somebody
listening to forever. And then we make
the return, which is to say, I love that.
I want to share that with my community.
I'm going to tweet it,
I'm going to Facebook it. So if you apply
that metaphor of the hero's journey,
you try to make parts of your
life significant hero's journey.
I'll wake up in the
morning and we'd be like,
today I'm going to
depart from the ordinary.
I'm gonna put myself in
uncomfortable situations.
I'm going to transcend those boundaries.
I'm going to have a new realization.
I want this day to mean something
and then make the return.
Right?
Come on.
What if that day you got to like a
bunch of shit you need to get done.
You listen to this podcast.
I don't want it to happen because it
didn't happen in your brain to write.
I'm going to read this book
tonight, I'm going to, you know,
check out this interesting documentary.
It is definitely an hour a day.
Is it expose yourself to different things.
That's why I really get
into finding big foot.
I've been watching that a lot lately.
Brian,
probably it's one of the things I have
and why it's just a waste of time for me.
Fuck yeah, that's wasted time. But
I'm trying to write to new material.
My doing my special, by
the way, it's confirmed,
it's going to be happening Atlanta on
April 20th at the Tabernacle Theater and
um, most of the tickets are
sold out for the first show,
but we're going to do a second show. So
we're, we'll have the, the first year,
I think it's an eight,
the second show be 10 30.
And the second show tickets will
go on sale sometime this week.
Probably today's Monday sometime. Probably
Wednesday I would guess. And, uh, uh,
it'll be me and Joey Diaz
and Duncan Trussell Hala,
and I'll be recording my, uh,
my news comedy special and releasing it.
Lucy Kay style on the Internet for five.
Brilliant Dude. Yeah, it's
really good to call it.
So you got to call it
looky [inaudible] style.
And you're going to be in New York
too at some point, right? Yeah. Yeah.
What Day is that? A, I'm going to be there
all of April, man. So cool. Yay. Yeah.
Actually I should tell you
this, cause this is really
cool. I mean, actually fifth,
May 5th, May 4th. Okay. So let's link
up. Okay. But actually next week,
man, I'm heading up to, or this
week at the end of this week,
I'm heading up to the bay
area because on the 20th,
I'm speaking at Stanford Design School
and showing some of my crazy ecstatic
videos. Oh Wow. And then
on the 27th of March, 27th,
I'm speaking at Google,
I was invited.
Oh yeah.
Show us some of the videos.
And then on March 28th I'm going to be
speaking at the economist Ideas Festival
on innovation at Berkeley is going to be
sick all, all about showing the videos.
It's about talking about inspiration,
creativity,
new ways of packaging
and disseminating ideas.
Then I go to New York and on March 30th
I'm speaking at the PSFK conference in
Battery Park and then
said, I'm making people memorize
this stuff cause most of them won't.
What does your website, where's
there? This all uh, oh yeah.
Well in some of a.com if you go to this
as Jason silva.com this is Jason Silva
Daca. Yes. But the best
thing honestly is Twitter,
Twitter at Jason Underscore Silva,
s Lva. And if you can't find it,
it's on mine.
Uh,
talking about this podcast and that way
I keep people updated in all the talks
and April 20th,
the National Arts Club in New York
City and he's speaking as well.
This is amazing when this was all because
of your videos and you punished for
the Internet, which are really amazing.
And if you Google Jason Silva, Vimeo,
there's a whole page with a gang of
amount of Vimeo is a nice high quality
visual too. I love Vimeo, man. They're
amazing. It's very high quality.
Like when you can go full screen with
it on a large screen, which is great.
They get it.
And the design it's made for like artists
and this beautiful Vimeo is awesome.
We put all of our podcasts up
on Vimeo and we also put a, a,
a video blog up and put that on video
Vimeo as well. Um, but yeah, um,
I think, uh, that's incredible
man that you've given all this.
It's worked just from those
videos popping up on the Internet.
How did you get started in this man?
What'd you,
what is your background as far as
like education and Shit, man? Well,
I grew up in Venezuela and I went to,
we talked to him about international
school and of course factor of it as well.
I was in film school and I did current TV,
which was Al Gore's TV channel
like the last five years.
But it was really when I left last year
that I wanted to do my own content.
Do you ever get massages with al?
No. We did go to a hotel. No, no.
Really banking did now get some
massage problems. I don't know. But um,
yeah,
the short videos were just,
I wanted to like apply in principle
what I was believing in intellectually,
like I want it to,
to make content that was mimetic because
I believe we live in a world where a
short form content disseminated through
the Internet can effect, people,
can transform minds. We don't need the
sort of the old gatekeepers, so to speak.
Everybody's empowered.
And so the reason short videos are easier
to consume through small devices and
this and that. And you don't ask people
for too much of their time, you know,
a c that's a big thing. Well, until you've
won them over, like you and then people,
I know that people love to
listen to you for a long time,
love the podcast because most people do
is they listen to it while they're doing
other stuff. So that's the best way to do
it. That's brilliant. That's brilliant.
It's a real genre. You know that it hasn't
really been addressed before. You know,
I love coming here with you because it
gives me a chance to talk about these
ideas in a space in which is it just
bigger and people are listening to it,
but you know from,
for my situation to initially get to
avoid the word out about the videos,
it just worked to do with really short,
but what I think people respond to them
is whether or not they're into the ideas
of exponential growth and technology
and transforming the human condition.
People are into the idea that inspiration,
it needs to be reinvented how we package
and disseminate big ideas and needs to
be reexamined because we
have a new substrate. The
Internet is a new substrate.
When we invented the printing press,
we came up with the format of the book
and there was like rules and parameters
and this is how it works. Best Television,
we came up with the Sitcom film.
We came up with the length of time
that a film should be before people get
restless into theater
and so on and so forth.
And I think on the Internet
we're still figuring it out.
What are the parameters of work,
what are the lengths of videos that we're
literally look at the statistics and
get the information and find out how long
people pay attention to stuff and this
and that.
And um,
and so I'm just starting to raise ciders
when I find long form documentaries
available on like Google
video and youtube.
Sometimes we go to each of the people
pay people don't do it yet on their
screens.
We're going to have that more and we have
the merger of TV and with Web TV cause
then you're on the TV,
you're on the couch watching TV,
watching web content and it's different
experience. It's not just a small
screen right. When the screen's
merge I think we'll have that.
That's entirely going to happen.
You don't think that it will be still
have the separation of computer and
television? I think software
software's going to eat the world.
That was a great article.
So do you think that networks like NBC ab,
that's like legacy,
it's all gonna like be like VHS tapes
someday I think we'll be going to be
interfacing.
I think the apple TV thing is coming
is my feeling and that is going to make
everything intuitive. And I read
an article yesterday, uh, from um,
Nick Bilton from the Times
where he was saying that uh,
he gets anxious when he looks at his
cable and TV box because there's so many
buttons that it's so complicated and he
doesn't know what input is connected to
what the best and most of the stuff,
he doesn't want to watch it.
There's so many over and he says that he
looks at it as like iPad and everything
is so neat. Then he can press what he
wants and get what he wants in real time.
Moving in that direction. I mean,
have you guys checked out Hbo go?
It's really cool. Awesome.
Yeah, I mean on your computer,
watch anything anytime on demand.
All eight years. Hbo Subscribers,
premium. Beautiful. You know,
I experienced that shit.
That's another thing that's a future
which is it's still clunky today and I
can't believe it's so clunky.
Like the other day I wanted it to
find a show on a channel and I'm like,
I don't know what the channel is.
I have a thousand numbers.
I'm like going through each channel,
like where the fuck is this channel?
You know? It should be a search. No, it's
just going to be Siri. It's going to be,
it's going to be turned to the
cartoon network. You know? It's,
and that's all it's going to be. The
remote control alone. It's just such,
it's like looking at an old payphone.
Yeah. When the UFC moved to a fuel TV,
when they having some fights on fuel TV,
how to find fuel TV forever.
Fucking luck. Good luck. It's sucks. Yeah.
It's like six 18 on direct TV. Especially
when you have like HD channels now too.
Half the time you're watching,
you're not even watching the HD
channel and you're like, oh shit,
how long I've been watching this. There's
so many channels now, man. It's amazing.
It's really, that's why I think the
apple TV, when it does get released,
I think that's just going
to change everything.
I think everything's gonna be on
the cart. I think, you know, yeah,
NBC was going to be around, but they're
going to be like any other channel.
It's gonna be like, you know your channel,
you strike people like shows though.
They're like,
like lost the like things that are going
to be produced by a production company
that you might not be able to
replicate. You know, the, the home user,
you know,
even with incredible software,
people will always want the premium
experience and they're willing to pay for
the premium experience.
I mean,
I don't care to pay $20 to see an
imax three d film in a theater and be
completely immersive experience like that.
So did you like Avatar?
I thought it was beautiful. Did you feel
any avatar depression when she left?
You know, I think that's fascinating.
Don't you think? Love it. That idea.
Like there's a great book called
the art of immersion by Frank Rose.
It used to be at wired,
who says that?
The future of immersive storytelling
in an example is Avatar is such an
immersive three d experience and he says,
we all long to go back to Pandora even
though we've never really been there.
We miss something that wasn't really
real. But then again, everything
is not really real because it's all
an illusion, but more and more dude,
immersive experiences like
that. Yes, we're going to,
we're going to get sad when we fall out
of the game or out of the movie or out
of the virtual space cause
it's increasingly becoming
more interesting than
reality.
Well, Gut Avatar, depression, really,
they got depression that they weren't
one of those blue things because you
wouldn't want to have,
you don't wouldn't want to be
living in Avatar if you are a human,
you just a little fucking bitch.
I think it was so pretty.
I got jacked left and right.
Yeah,
but humans like didn't even have
a chance in the avatar world,
but you can't have habit.
Our depression,
you essentially have depression about
your species. You don't want to,
you want to be one of the Navi.
Well, if you want to be larger than
life, that can be what you want to live.
That lifestyle that they're living in
the love and honor. And I was little,
I used to carry him fly Indiana Jones
depression when Indiana Jones ended.
I used to get sad.
I want to dig for treasure in my backyard
and I want it to have my life to be as
fun as Indiana Jones. So I remember
that feeling as a kid, you know,
I really remember leaving films and,
and wanting the,
the luster in the law to
sort of come home with me.
But usually we, you know, you buy
the [inaudible] Max and you watch it
Avatar though,
that the culture of Avatar was missing.
Everything that we're missing or
rather than the culture of Avatar,
the culture of the Navi had everything
that we're missing that are lost society
that are materialistic,
ridiculous to, you know,
society where we're not taking
responsibility for our own actions.
We all act collectively as a gigantic
group or corporation that this tribal
life, this tribal life
that were all these people,
like they're forced to told
her own weight. And celebrated
and loved each other.
But that trial that,
that
tribal life that
supposedly was so advanced,
I mean they still had
hierarchical systems.
There was still an angry boss that told
everybody else would do still warriors.
Like they hadn't really transcend
our store, our savage in fact,
but they're happier than secretaries.
There's an interesting, uh,
thing that Kurzweil had mentioned that
he thought it was really interesting that
you use the world's greatest technology
to bring our imaginings into being,
to make that movie, to then
criticized technology in the movie.
So you use the most powerful computers
and digital tools to realize that dream
into screen.
And then you tell a story inside of
that technologically mediated reality.
You tell a story about how bad technology
is and how we should all go live in a
forest.
Again,
not really what they told the story
about was about greed and about the
willingness to fuck over cultures and
kill a entities that also get lot of inner
came out of that and said it
was an indictment of technology.
What was the mineral impossible
Bahrainian or something like that.
It was some stupid fucking name. I
was like, what was it called Brian?
And they saw the movie once obtained IOM
in obtaining them like and hip possible
to obtain something along those
lines. Like, oh, you silly goose.
There's a great term called comp with
Terrainian that I recently learned.
And I think it's when we've,
uh,
leverage all the matter in universe
or in the galaxy into computation.
So all the atoms,
we put computation into
everything and then becomes a
computronium. Well, I'm not,
I'm not sure if I'm explaining
it correctly, but yeah.
This idea that a civilization
will eventually get advanced,
that it can leverage all the matter in
the universe and put computation into it,
harness all that matter and energy in
the universe. What does that even mean?
Could you use that word computation?
Well, you know how there's, you know,
our computers are bunch of materials
and we put computation into those
computation, into the
stars. Yeah, that's, yeah.
How the fuck would you do that?
I'm not a physicist,
but this is stuff that you can find
physical articles that you know,
speculate about the future and how society
will cross a scale and then it will
harness the energy of its star and put
computation into matter and terraform
other worlds. And yeah, I mean it's,
it's, I mean we're over. I mean,
we already do it inside of computers.
I mean computation and
complexity inside of a microchip.
The only other thing is
complex is the brain. You know,
what have nothing else in the universe
has that complexity I find fascinating.
When I go back to like some 1980s
in 1990 science fiction movies,
I like watching like what they thought
a computer was going to be like,
like the movie alien.
I watched that again the other day,
one of my all time favorite movies and
amazing movie and still holds up as far
as like, let's be excited about
prometheus's. Oh fuck it. Oh Man.
It's on the three d trailer and a theater.
Anything Ridley Scott comes up with,
I'm down for the first alien movies. One
of my all time favorite movies. But God,
the computer looks so fucking wanky and
shit and it was fascinating that like,
you know, when you look at like some of
these uh, older movies, they'll be like,
they'll take place in 2017 and it's
like nothing looks anything like today.
Everything super futuristic,
flying cars and shit.
Like when was blade runner is
supposed to be taking place in?
How far in the future was it?
That's a good question.
I don't think it was that far.
I don't do it to you.
She anything close to what you would see.
Some of the little flying robots
that they showed at Ted this year,
I saw some of the choreograph,
choreograph flying little helicopters
that could do a dance and go around
obstacles and objects
and there's going to be,
have HD cameras and they can map rooms.
The Google self driving cars,
200,000 miles.
They've driven with zero accidents.
1 million people a year die in road
accidents. Okay. 1 million people a year.
When we switch over to
those self driving cars,
which we already know after 200,000 miles,
no accidents,
they're only going to get better. That's,
I mean that's what cars are going to be.
Of course self driving cars, airplanes,
man. But then you went there too.
Unreliable. He never be able
to go sideways or on a corner.
You can do it in a sport track.
You'd have to go to the track. Yeah,
it'll be a sport,
but not in a place where you can hit
a pedestrian or hurt somebody else.
You know? Of course that will
be, but that's, yeah, that's
coming man. It's amazing.
It goes Google guys. God their
genius. Yeah, there there are.
So no one saw them coming.
I mean if there was a sky net and skynet
wanting to sneak up on society and just
sort of integrated self completely.
I mean it is Google is there
like a website is skynet.com
or something like that.
Yeah,
but I think at this point their
ambition of don't be evil is so true.
I mean, I think that, I love
Google, don't get me wrong,
but I'm saying it's
amazing what Google maps.
Google fucking voicemail and Google
g-mail all freeze this Christ all free.
Yeah,
it's credible to crap.
There's a whole book about how everything
is d materializing and it's becoming
for free.
We used to have a camera but now camera
doesn't exist because it's inside your
phone.
You used to have like a notebook to
write things down that that disappeared
cause now it's all on your phone,
which by the way is dematerializing
and going into your device.
Have you seen this new device that's just
come on as a new droid that came out?
This the Samsung Journal.
Oh,
have you seen this thing Penn one to
know dude, it's fucking five inches.
It's huge.
It's the biggest one ever.
It's like a cross between a tablet and
an iPhone. It's amazing. Beautiful.
But the battery lasts about 35 seconds.
Totally not full brightness.
You've got about a half a half a minute.
That's pretty crazy.
It's pretty crazy that that new iPad
three a has the same battery life,
but yet the screens HD and that's
exponential growth right there.
Those battery life, the battery
life on those iPads was amazing.
Their first batch already. Dude, is
it, the demand is unprecedented, dude.
It's pretty shocking how long you
can watch a movie on those things.
Watch a three,
four movies and you look at it.
It's not even like halfway choose to with
a battery and I can't wait for the eye
mind. You think they're already
working on the I mine does that.
It'll be like a synthetic mind,
you know directly I can trust.
I can't wait for the high car. They
need to make cars. I need to make a car.
They'll do their counterparts of Google's
self driving android cars and then
apple needs. It's aicar
cheeses. How long before?
We see self driving cars on the
street very soon. Very soon.
Because Google already has them driving
in California and there's been over
200,000 miles. Yeah. The
driving in California right
now, like, oh yeah, you can,
you could be rear ended by a fucking
zero accidents and 200,000 miles on it.
I'll be the first one. The Sun, they map,
they map three dimensional maps of what's
in front of them. Dude, it's insane.
They can see like they can see and
they can notice people walking.
They'll adjust accordingly. It's in, you
know, it freaks me out. Meet the scene.
We got onto this through the
idea of robotics and flying
drones freaks me out as
those, uh, those things that
walk, that have like 10,
15 legs and you kick
kick 'em and they adjust.
It looks like a dog with that thing.
Man,
that's incredible.
You should have seen the Ted talk,
the head of Darpa gave a Ted talk to
and she was the most poised, elegant,
articulate,
attractive woman dues and that the
people from last Darpa is the defense.
Advanced Research Dharma. I
know. Dark. She was amazing.
She was talking about
dreaming the impossible.
She actually reminded me of Jodie
Foster's character in contact.
Is this really elegant,
poised our ticket?
You actually felt comforted
to know that somebody,
that intelligence seeming is like
running Darpa and her ted talk was Ugh,
belligerent talking about,
she was talking about
dreaming the impossible and
we have to challenge what we,
what is in order to dream about
what could be and you know,
and she's speaking on behalf of
the agency who has a lot of stuff.
So it's kind of a main thing.
I don't know.
But a lot of stuff that we take
these short today cutting edge stuff.
Are you sure? I'm pretty sure if you
don't know, how can you be sure? Well,
cause if you read about dark all the
time and they do the advanced secret
research project, wow. I
wonder what they're working on.
She showed a hypersonic planes. We
still haven't got to aliens. Uh,
we didn't get to alien. No, we went
to you went out and took me out.
I told you about trends. Sension why
we don't buy, we could never see them.
FERMI's paradox.
So you don't think we'll ever see him?
Only when we build our own
black hole and go into it,
then we'll meet them at the end of time.
Whoa. Cause it's sling shots you at.
So it's not terrible that they could just
be like roaming through this universe
in galactic that if they did that,
that would influence our evolution.
US discovering them and being
influenced by their technology would be
influencing our ultimate
evolution [inaudible] battery.
It will get a butterfly effect.
And the,
the thing that John's smart says is they
wouldn't want to do that because that
would be akin to incest to influencing
us in some way. And then changing the,
how we unfold devil's advocate, this is
through our understanding of genetics,
right?
It's not through theirs.
And if there are a thousand or a
million years more advanced than us,
maybe they know a lot more about
how to work that shit. Right.
And maybe that's why he says it's a,
maybe it's not that they would
think of it as incest at all,
but they've completely gone past the idea
of gender and replication by means of
sexuality is just what we had
replication from the primate form.
But they wouldn't want it to
replicate their technology. Alien,
large almond shaped I form.
Right.
They wouldn't want us to replicate their
technology says who I mean. Well maybe,
maybe there's a some sort of thing
that will lead to the most amount of
diversity and if we're not influenced by
them they'll be more diversity because
we'll get there ourselves.
It's just beginning to get
the end of the day. Anyway,
that's what he says.
I got a deal that people really love
to share when it comes to a wacky alien
theories is that aliens have genetically
engineered human beings in the first
place of that. I mean, I
mean you can't unproved that.
So the next five years that's a problem,
right?
You can't improve leprechaun throw.
You know why that's,
that's the thing. That's the dog
thing. We're watching those, the, the,
the nuttiest thing about this, this
weird looking robot things and it moves.
It has like sort of like, oh,
like an insect like leg set up,
kick it, it adjusts and it
doesn't fall down. Yeah.
Look at adjusting to the sand and
the toad and walking on a beach.
And if that thing starts saying hi to
you and smiling and drooling and it was
totally fall in love, know what I'm seeing
to put that thing on one more second.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm seeing that thing storm out of the
back of a giant battleship and missiles
flying off of it.
That's what I think.
I think if they make one
of those fucking things,
they make it to send over to countries.
Could you imagine a whole army of these
motherfuckers heading into your town
shooting missiles? I, you tell me.
I'm imagining them as pets for
rocket launchers on that bitch.
It's always a double edged sword.
I have to admit,
it's always a double edged sword.
But look,
what do people start riding
and they become the, they
will become the new horses.
There'll be our little pets. Look, it's
wagging its tail. It's wagon to say,
oh gosh, you feel bad for it when he
kicks it. You feel bad. So humans, yeah,
but think of how quickly you feel bad
for it.
I do.
But what's amazing is this thing adjusted
and it seems to be adjusting the, the,
the movements seem organic.
Yeah, totally. Totally.
Biomimic we're going to have one of
those and we're going to ride them like,
yeah, like a, like a goat
down the side of a mountain.
That's what he's going to be like.
You know those,
those crazy goats that can they,
they're,
they're incredibly strong and they climb
up the side of mountains. They never,
she never, she plane. Yeah. They
never get tired. They don't have ache.
Yeah.
But then they would probably run on solar
power to eventually it's solar power
is going to get to a point where it
can power everything. Right. Of course.
Then when we get 10,000 times more energy
from the sun than we need this fucking
thing. Slow Shit doing a better way,
better ways of capturing that energy.
I'd be pissed if I was writing this
stupid thing right now. I'd be like,
come on bitch. Free Energy. That gives
us free energy to heavy Brian for that,
for that. You know how it's going and
say, oh wow. It's making it through.
So fascinating.
That's incredible.
It's walking down to the snow and there's
a bunch of different designs of them
too. I've seen other ones that have
like many more legs. Wow, that's crazy.
Look at this things. Dancing, robotics,
robotics is going to be such a huge, well,
robotics and AI, artificial
intelligence, robot rice. Look at that.
That down to the bare skeleton of a thing.
This is incredible stuff folks.
I know we're just talking right now.
Unfortunately for a lot of you folks
that are listening to this on Itunes,
just go, which should they Google
Brian so they could watch this.
This is Boston dynamics,
but just say new big dog robot,
new big dog robot video, and it looks
like a spider when you're looking. Really,
it's a must and it's the one that has
700 plus thousand hits on it. It's,
it's a must. See you. You need to know.
Amazing. Yeah, it's, I mean, what,
what does the future hold that we're
not prepared for? What is the next step?
You know, I mean, the Internet I think
caught most people by surprise. Well,
there were in her a robot dog.
Oh my God,
Brian just put on a robot dog and this
thing is moving around like an animated
dog. This is insane.
The thing is, there was,
there was a guy at Ted that showed
his, uh, oh my God, that's the same.
That dog's insane now where there's
been this guy ted, no, no, no.
There's going to be,
there's going to be more of those kinds
of robots and the more that they, uh,
interface with us and they look
cute, we'll be, we'll start.
It doesn't matter if they're conscious
or not as once they cross a certain kind
of perceptual barrier that we have
and they're like, they seem real.
We'll start to interface with
them as they're going to be hard.
Just like your dog, you know,
when you come home and have a car,
I come home and have a
conversation with your dog.
It doesn't matter if you
understand the way the feedback,
and we'll have the same thing with robots
do it as long as we can get past the
idea that something that's a metal and
wires and you know that that thing can't
have some sort of a soul because
you're interacting with it.
You know if you're interacting with
it as long as plenty soul in it,
what is your fucking
computer gets needy like,
well maybe you might want it to get
needy because it'll make you feel like
you're,
you're important to site.
Maybe that's a part of like what
it's like to have vagal butt fucked.
All that erode fucked all the
really good ones. So like the look,
they're really dangerous. Like this
pitch might burn your house down.
Like you can't fuck other girls. Like
she's really, she's going to be the best,
hottest robot fucked off ever.
The robots will whatever you want and
that's the only way to make it hot.
The only way that they get hot,
she has to be super jealous.
She can't just let you just
treat her like shit. I mean,
why aren't you sharing
your location services? She
becomes, she becomes a robot,
an angry psycho jealous robot,
and that's the hottest sex you can get.
And so that's why
everybody just accepts it.
You'll be able to do whatever you want
the robots, robots are going to be,
there'll be Asian Robo fucker.
I was telling us no questions,
just take care of business son. Right?
They'll always be the exotic Asian robot.
Fucked dolls. Yeah. W you
know there's interesting,
we talking about all these exotic,
all these exotic technology and it's
sounding like we're talking about Asians
were not.
So it sounds a hallucinatory,
even though it's very quickly emerge
and it just takes you back to that whole
thing about computers as the
modern version of the psychedelic.
Just want to say if you're an Asian girl,
I'm just joking around.
These are just jokes or
just throw things out there.
I don't mean anything by him. Okay.
But what do you think of that?
Like to told Timothy Leary,
computers are the LSD of the nineties
and people took drugs and they're like,
we can expand our minds and
now computers expand our minds.
Well relationship is very fascinating
to me. It's absolutely fascinating.
Well right now, just think this, what's
this interface it's happening right now.
This is all live, right. You
know, and right now there's,
there's only 2000 people
aren't sinked up live with us.
But eventually this, this feeling
of this conversation and these,
these ideas explored. I'm going to branch
out to about a half a million Pete,
but right. Throw half a million
in mind. Our thoughts. Yeah.
And out of that half a million,
who knows how many people are gonna just,
you know,
I read this Tony Robbins thing once where
he talked about Tony Robbins actually
very positive.
You know,
a lot of people think that Tony Robbins
is full of shit cause he's kind of like
made a loud noise. I think he's brilliant.
He's, he's up. We've got a lot of very,
very good points. And one of them was to
change your life to make huge changes.
All you need is a small change in the
direction and over time that small change
will lead you so far apart of where your
initial direction was. Absolutely true.
The idea is that if you have two cars in
two parallel lines and one of them just
takes a slight turn to the right
and they keep driving straight,
the one who slight turned the
right, it's going to be, you know,
a hundred miles from now,
it's going to be way the fuck
away from that other one total.
And that's sometimes really how you
have to look at it. We especially,
I mean I'm a super impatient person.
I want things now too.
Even when I go to the supermarket,
I'm like,
you bitches don't have any
grass fed beef seriously. Right.
But I mean like what I proposed to his
headset that I think that I can just go
to a place and they've killed an
animal for me, raised it on grass,
only killed animals and there's
plenty of meat. I can feed my family.
I can stay alive from this dog,
this food here.
And this is what I'm planning because
they didn't get the shipment of organic
meat that day. Well, think about it.
I have no grass fed beef to fuck.
But what about when you're having a Skype
conversation with somebody on the other
side of the planet and you're just like
taken for granted that you can see their
face and they could see yours. You know,
you're talking in real time for free
and then like all of a sudden it might
freeze. You're like, Oh God
damn man, it's freezing.
Why is this freaking computer freezing?
Why is but like think about what you
were just enjoying two seconds before you
totally take it for granted.
Now we assimilate man. He
dynamic adaptation. Yeah.
That is what it is. It is an
adaptation. You know, it's, it's uh,
it's amazing though that we have this
urge in this push to make things bigger,
faster,
quicker,
and that that urgent push
is also responsible for one
of the reasons why people
get accustomed to things and want more.
And you used a quote you quoted Mckenna,
and you talked about how something about
the astonishment and not give it to the
astonishment,
astonished that give into it,
but definitely seek it out
because I think most people, well,
he's talking about DMT though.
Yeah. Dm The beat the truth and DMT.
DMT have not, but don't you
think that, for example,
it's astonishing that you can do this
podcast and reach half a million minds and
very rarely does one marvel
at the astonishment of the
things that are every day
that are Morag,
how many hundreds of thousands
of Aircrafts are flying
through the air right now
communicating with one another,
flying safely,
individuals in other to
other parts of the world.
We don't experience that astonishment. I
don't wake up in astonishment. We should.
Yeah, you're absolutely right. I mean,
if you had pulled someone out of the
cave man error and put him in modern
society, it would be just a psychedelic
as a lot of pot trips. Yes. Yeah, yeah,
exactly. It'd be so
bizarre. And outside of the,
the wha what you conceived of just seconds
ago as being possible. Right. You know,
you take someone from, you know, a
thousand years ago, 500 years ago,
a blip in time means nothing to the
universe and then put them in today or put
them in a garden movie theater
making watch Harry Potter and Shit.
His pants shit is bad.
You imagine what a garden out of a fucking
dragon when I was Harry Potter Dragon
will own fire out flying to the fight.
He would just dive on the ground
screaming in the car. Right?
That is so amazing. The fact that that it,
that is that we wake up in the morning,
we don't think about that
because that just is,
we're onto the next thing and onto the
next thing to be looking forward to or to
be complaining about.
And maybe that's the part
of our evolutionary makeup
that makes us always probe
the boundaries of the adjacent possible
and always want to keep pushing because
maybe if we were in astonishment of all
we've done, we wouldn't keep progressing.
We're obsessed with innovation.
Human beings are obsessed with innovation.
You mean, you know, every
year sports cars get faster.
We're getting to a point right now where
like regular cars are doing like race
track numbers. Even though we have
speed limits, even though we have that,
like we still push the performance limits.
I'm fascinated by by sports
cars cause just cause I'm,
I'm fascinated by extreme engineering.
Yeah.
It's fascinating by the idea that there's
a bunch of people out there that are
trying to get something
to the handles faster.
I was better geometry moves better sticks.
And the newest nine
Porsche nine 11 goes around
the track as fast as the nine
nine six cup car. So the,
the Newburg ring, which is like this
really twisty turny track in Germany,
a really high end sports car can go
around it today at about seven minutes,
30 seconds, seven minutes, 40 seconds.
That's like a nine 11 a real high end car.
That's with race cars would
do just a decade earlier.
So it's getting to this crazy point
where regular modern street cars aren't
like,
like fucking cup cars.
So how much faster do you need these
fucking things? Like you know Dubai,
but you got Ebay, Ron,
they have a Bugatti Veyron.
It's like a thousand fucking
horsepower. We do it just to do it, man.
Just that's crazy is to see how
much complexity we can pack into it.
How much performance
you can get out of it.
It's like modern jet engines do operate
at half the temperature of the surface
of the sun because he's more of a modern
jet engine. Just if you, I mean it's,
it's insane. Okayed spins
at 500 miles. But I mean,
I don't remember the speed but a jet
engines or if really feats of engineering.
I mean it's, I mean, you know,
we, everyone's scared of flying.
Jesus Christ is 30,000 flights a day
and nothing happens. It's incredible.
So safe. It's amazing. Yeah.
But the way you'd go is so terrifying.
Just slamming into the
fucking rain forest.
That's why I love Virgin America so much,
dude. Cause they got brand new planes.
They really rock,
brand new state of the art fleet.
Well because most other airlines in
this country, countries have fleets.
They're 20 to 25 to 30 years old.
Scared the fuck out of me right now.
I need to go. No, no, no. Listen,
that doesn't make them any less safe.
These planes are still certified and well
maintained. Nonetheless. Nonetheless,
on Virgin America,
you're getting a brand new fleet of
shiny gated yard with the best of
everything. With Internet.
No, you're not getting a brand
new pilot, let's say, dude,
we're ready. You know, it's just,
but it's nice [inaudible] it's the years
2012 you want to fly on an airplane
that was manufactured, you know,
in the last year or two or three.
It's just makes you feel
better when they're shiny.
There's less stress fractures. It's, yeah,
it is kind of an interesting thing about
air technology is that we essentially
have the same tech.
It's really one of the only industries
that has the same technology, you know,
general principles.
But the engines are far more reliable
and far more advanced than they were
before. What, what? When did they start
getting much better? Oh, well, yeah.
At the same Moore's law
that applies in computers.
I mean the engineering of a modern jet
engine and the computers are jets from
like the 1970s and 1980s.
Well, no, they make,
they make revisions that are pretty
much like an entire new model.
I find wine still worry engines. They
change everything. Yeah. I phoned one.
It'll work as long as you don't have to
take the software. Right, right. But, uh,
it's kind of fun to go on the new ones.
They have far more technology.
That robot dog, you know what
that's going to be in the future.
Check the screen out right here.
How crazy is this?
Somebody posted this on your message
board, but uh, hold on. Episode two,
attack of the clones. Uh, here
we go. [inaudible] my God,
that's the robot augmented placed
in there or well, yeah, yeah.
But imagine there at ads,
you know, from Star Wars,
those robot dogs are the exact same thing
as an ad. Oh Dude, you're totally right.
I mean, it looks exactly the same. Oh, so
what is that? That's just the added that,
yeah. Somebody just put a funny video
together. Well that's, that's amazing.
You're totally right. Yeah. That's exactly
what it is. Yeah. It's fast. Brian.
Stupid fucking cat clock. How dare
you. Oh, is that the cat clock? Yeah,
that's the, uh, the famous
cat clock. He likes,
he likes things to meow. Um, you know,
future of medicine, man. Are you
excited about that? Yeah. Well,
I'm excited about the idea of keeping
people alive long enough to figure out
some really crazy shit.
Oh yeah.
The idea of people staying long enough
to overpopulate the planet kind of freaks
me out though.
It was the most people cluster around
only like 3% of the surface of the world,
which is the city states. Cities.
Yeah. Know the world is still mostly,
and it's mostly water and technology
is more like a resource liberating
mechanism because scarcity
is just contextual.
Things are only scarce until you create
technology that makes them into things
that are abundant.
People talk about water wars,
but the mini not worried at all about
overpopulation. Oh Man, no, not at all.
In fact,
the more developed and educated people
become and in developed nations that the
rate of having children
goes down significantly.
Mckenna has the best cure
against overpopulation is
to educate our people and
put more in technology into
their hands, but also, um,
also like desalinization for example, you
know, once we perfect that technology,
this, this is called a blue planet.
It's a water planet. It's mostly water.
It just needs to be converted.
But they have anything right
now that can their deals.
Israel has a lot of these ellipses
desalinization plants. Oh yeah.
Just got to get more advanced.
Just like solar panels.
It's just exponential growth.
Once they hit the tipping point where
it's actually cheaper to use those
technologies and to do it the other way,
then it becomes,
it'll become the main thing. Wow. Great.
You need to create,
incentivize to incentivize people to
innovate and we're such constant will
probably dry out the fucking ocean.
We'll probably pull all the
water out of the ocean. No,
I don't think we were plenty of water.
Imagine though, if we're so greedy,
we use up all the water and the ocean.
I mean,
nobody predicted that we
would have polluted the ocean
the way we have and just
a hundred years.
I mean we've done an incredible job with
fucking old nano technology will create
synthetic biology that eats
the plastic and we'll, yes.
Where's the evidence of that ever
having taken place in the past?
When have we ever fixed anything?
There is a,
there's an x prize contest that the x
prize is doing to come up to something
with plastics.
The technology there to clean up oil
spills or something like that. Yeah,
like you criteria that eats plastic
like that you want it is you create
incentive by offering these prizes,
like $10 million prizes
and teams around the world.
We'll spend $100 million to win a $10
million prize because of the prestige and
because the legacy or swamp thing
came from for what swamp thing?
Remember the marvel comics swamp thing
from a contest? No, no. From some porn,
some biological shit to eat up some.
Maybe I'm in fact, I don't know,
maybe it's another example
of that and the x prize.
They were the ones that did the
$10 million enterprise for space,
which became virgin galactic. Well,
they have one now to create a device.
That's the size of like an
iPhone called the tri quarter.
$10 million to do can make a device
that you can spit on or you can put your
blood on and that will diagnose you
with the equivalent of a 10 certified
doctors with greater accuracy than
10 certified doctors. I swear to God,
this is their new condos.
This is her net,
$2 million per $10 million
prize that they just put out.
It's right tricorder x prize. Is it
possible divorce is going to be possible?
I mean they're already have things that
you can put on your iPhone that you can
spit on that we'll like Beshar
your measure and analyze
your watts fluid. Yeah,
really? Yeah. They already have this
bid on your iPhone shots to it yet.
What's it called?
I have no idea,
but people can Google spitting on
your iPhone medical device. Wow.
I'd never heard of that.
That's amazing.
That stuff is going to get a lot
faster because now that that biology is
becoming information technologies
and information technology,
we're going to see the same progress.
Well,
it's so cool when you have contests
for good along those lines,
like with x prize and the fact that they
would come up with something along that.
Yeah, they're brilliant. Yeah. And
I mean, I would love to believe you,
I believe to believe that someone is going
to eventually figure out a way to get
rid of that giant patch of garbage
that's in the Pacific Ocean. We shall,
we shall. That's a big issue, huh?
Yeah. Well people talk about that a lot.
They're very concerned.
Although it's nice.
It's not actually like the size
of a country as people had.
I think it's the size of
Texas. I don't, I'm not,
I don't think it actually is
physical size of Texas. Well,
I think that they're so small. No,
I think the, you know how it is,
it's all caught in the current, there's
like a vortex, a vortex. Really.
That's where all the garbage piles
up and then all the garbage. Let's,
I'll look at it right now. Okay. Let me
Google this real quick. Powerful Google,
uh, Pacific Ocean garbage
patch. Pacific Ocean.
Okay.
Oh, it's fucking huge. Holy Shit.
Wow.
Although many immediate and advocate
advocacy reports have suggested that the
patch extends over an area
larger than the continental us.
Recent research sponsored by the National
Science Foundation suggest that the
affected area may be twice
the size of Hawaii. Wow.
Wow. That's fucking big.
But that's a lot of tracks.
I,
I'm pretty confident that we will create
nano technology that will literally eat
up the garbage. That's how we'll, that's
how we'll fix it. But then when the,
when it runs out of garbage, 10 it'd be
hungry and then it becomes swamp thing.
Maybe you don't, it doesn't want to
die, man. It doesn't want to die.
And that's how you know, like the
premise to a lot of comic book monsters,
it's a double edge sword fight get is we
better come up with a way to kill those
things before we feed them
plastic. Well, yes. Look,
it's important to look at all the possible
uses of technology for good and for
bad. Why the conversation
needs to be had though,
because the progress is not stopping.
When I think if we paint beautiful
pictures of how things could be,
we inspire the people to make sure that
that's what we actually, absolutely.
I completely agree with you and I think
you know the way you're doing it in
videos and online, it was really
cool and it's very close buddy. Well,
the way you're doing it, it is
amazing. But my question to you is,
what if we saw kangaroos evolving?
What if we saw Kangaroos?
They had found some flour.
There was a psychedelic flower.
They started eating it and
Kangaroos started building houses,
willing weapons and shit like that.
And some we saw some kangaroos welding,
we saw some welding. We
would. We allow that shit.
I think we go in and kick the Kangaroos
assets and you'll get the fuck outta
here. Wear your armor. We might, we might
make other animals smarter. Who knows?
Do you think so we might give them stem.
We'd be battling for resources.
I think we would just check on.
No, cause I ran out nuclear power.
What if Kangaroos came up
with a new x before I ran?
Would have kangaroos just started fucking
being really super smart man. Yeah.
Well, but I don't think that the resources
will be an issue because we'll be
harnessing energy from the whole galaxy.
There is an infinity of
reasons you say that,
but what if an asteroid lands in Australia
right near where the Kangaroos are
and some spores from this asteroid contain
a never before seen mushroom rapidly
accelerates evolution and within like a
hundred years they surpass us and then
what? Kangaroos are smart enough. What
do you do then Brian? What if, what if?
What are you going to do? You
Go, you're fucking cat clock.
I'll create a time machine and take the
words. What if out of the dictionary?
Well then I'm going to take a time when
she didn't take the word like out and
you won't ever be able to say anything.
What have I have a bitch?
Listen,
I believe that you are absolutely
convinced that someone's going to come out
with us. I just don't know. I see it. I
see it happening, man, and I know this.
Our brains.
What is the current plans to fix this now?
To fix with garbage patch. So
we were talking about, yeah,
well they're talking about creating
some kind of like algae or bacteria that
eats the plastic.
I think one of the big guys have a
synthetic biology is Craig venter who also
spoke at the singularity university
thing and he was seeing in terms of the
future fuels and the future of like
cleaning up like chemicals and absolutely
going to be using synthetic
biology. Wow. Yeah.
Cause we can program life to do
whatever we want. You know, so we can,
it's just like we can use
language to describe anything.
We can just author instructions,
you know?
And here you have software
that writes its own hardware.
See that's the thing about
programmable life. Unlike computers,
you write the code, the code
manufacturer's its own like phenotype,
right? Cause life, the genes
determine its physical attributes.
So the software writes its
own hardware into existence.
That's what's really exciting about like
synthetic biology and programmable life.
Especially if he gives synthetic.
Like if you give some
artificial intelligence access
to three d computers and
three d printers, dude, absolutely God,
you're going to imagine Raisie unlimited
intelligence and eliminate intelligence.
It replicates itself and three d printers,
but just the concept of three d
printers, having it aware of, oh,
now I can improve upon this design of
three d printers with trillions of time,
more ram than our brains, and
instantaneously, well, you know what,
Henry Miller's like 10,000 years of
progress and we need to believe that it's
coming.
Then Henry Miller said,
the day that men ceased to believe
that they will one day become gods,
then they will surely become worms.
Wow.
That was Henry Miller. So he
says, believe mankind, you know,
for going from ape to superman,
you know,
smack in the middle in a trajectory
between the born and the made. Right.
That's where we are, man. Yeah, we were,
yeah. We're in this word is in the middle.
Yeah. When there's this weird stage
where we're sort of conscious and we're,
we're aware, animalistic and
cellist, weird and savage,
Horny,
we're going to turn ourselves into the
most beautiful artwork we've ever made.
Men,
you really think so?
I definitely the aliens land
first or the aliens I had first.
So you don't believe that society's
ever gets to the point where they travel
from one place to another land and
affect things that doesn't? No,
I think that they do.
But the transection hypothesis says that
by the time maybe they reached the edge
of the solar system where the
edge of the galaxy at that point,
all the density goes back and it
goes into words, into the Nano scale.
So it's Kinda like we,
the complexity goes into itself and
goes and makes it a black hole and
disappears from the visible universe.
Is it possible that we should look at
the trend section hypothesis because,
cause it'll probably explain
much better than I can,
but isn't it possible that what you're
dealing with is something that's here all
the time,
but it's in another dimension?
Is it possible for dimension
string theory? Yeah.
I mean that is addressed in
that article. Yeah. Yeah.
So you could even go back
to Mckenna and say, oh,
so when Mckenna talks about hyper
dimensional beings and then uh,
well the transection hypothesis
says essentially our minds, yes.
Will break through the visible
universe into other dimensions.
It's like crazy stuff except it's
like written by an academic scholar.
Wow. Yeah. So no aliens and flying
saucers. Just landing. Yeah, that's,
that's what he says. He says, well
yeah, we'll go to other planets.
But that's like early stage stuff like
going to other planets over the next like
50 years earlier to get invaded were
essentially invaded by young punks that
the, the really high level aliens
wouldn't bother. It fails. Right. Totally.
You know, every time we do
that, the microphone picks
it up. Sorry man. It's fine.
It's good. But you know, someone's
going to be upset. I just,
I'm sensitive because people always
complain. I used to chew gum.
You can't shoot Mike Anymore. People
are like, dude, you're fucking sipping.
Can't sip drinks.
If you get up here and people get mad.
I guess if you got to think of as
somebody that's the reason why we put
headphones on and liquid
easily to his conversation.
But if you were in the gym right now,
you would hear that. I'm sorry Jim,
go please. Sorry. Sorry everybody. Just
wanting to keep everybody happy. Um,
I mean this is all incredible stuff and I,
I guess it all could come true and,
and come to fruition as long as we don't
fuck it up or as long as some gigantic
natural disaster doesn't happen
as well. Right? Yes. You take any,
do you ever take any care
and consideration? Well, yeah, I mean
that's super volcanoes, shit like that.
I think,
look,
we have to be paying attention and we
have to be cautious and we have to be
vigilant as we transitioned towards what
promises to be the most exciting time
in human history.
I mean,
we're already living in the most
exciting time in human history,
but let's not lose focus,
you know,
like let's address the grand
challenges of humanity.
We've never had such
tools with which to do so.
And I think it's like an opportunity
for us to pull our mental cognitive
surpluses together and fix
shit. Yeah, absolutely.
Do you think we'll ever get to the point
where we can avoid asteroids? Sure.
You think so? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
We'll get shoot them down.
You think shinning down with
lasers, single laser will
blow it up. It's going to,
everything is turning into star wars.
Yeah.
You really think the animal will do that.
Don't mean some asteroids are miles wide.
We get,
we already have lasers
that are pretty powerful.
I mean send nuclear weapons to them
like in the movie sunshine. Well,
the issue with that is actually that that
makes it worse because what happens is
instead of one big impact who have
hundreds of thousands of a little ones,
well they're not even little.
You know,
you don't need anything that big tech
giant crater in Nevada. You know,
it's one of the weird things
about all planets. Me,
every plan will be find is littered
with impacts. You know, we're,
we live in a very volatile source
system where we've been inhabiting a
goldilocks space for the Goldie locks.
At a time and we've just been very,
very lucky. Like I said, all
we were talking about this,
all of our progress man is a
blink of a blink of a blink,
of a blink of a blink in terms of cosmic
time. So it's like, it's not that we,
I mean we're lucky. Yeah. But it hasn't
been that much time that has passed,
you know, give it a couple
of million years and the
inevitability of getting hit,
it's coming. But that's why we got to
progress so that we can thwart that. Well,
they just found a very
recent evidence of an impact,
a big one about 13,000 years ago.
And what's really fascinating
about that is all the, uh,
ancient history theorists all point to
that point in time is one being the end
of the ice age, like around that
time, the end of the pleistocene.
And also also that's when a lot of people
point to the possibility of like an
ancient civilization like Egypt falling
apart and then rebuilding in the same
area. Sure, sure, sure,
sure. Yeah. When they,
when they hypothesize that something
went wrong, it's always around 10,000,
12,000, 13,000, somewhere around there.
I like, you know, the cycles. Yeah.
Well the idea is that, you
know, human life on this planet,
like the reason why there's
the myth of Atlantis and the
myth of, uh, you know, uh,
Noah in the Ark and the epic of
Gilgamesh is that there's all these giant
disasters just that frequently
hit, you know, and you know,
if something hit us today and wiped out,
we're wired to look for danger, man.
Sure.
The only way we survive.
So cautionary tales embedded in our
culture are just alarm system. Sure.
And it's kind of in a race.
I mean,
it's kind of a race between
technology awareness,
progress and the ability to at least
predict and prepare a slightly for natural
disasters. But some of them like Caldera,
volcanoes and things along those lines,
this is not need to do, man. It was just
nothing you could do. When goes it goes.
Unless you can figure out a way
to throw some ice cubes on the,
on the lava and maybe keep it from
fucking blowing sky high, no technologies.
The only way I think that
could be addressed, you
know, that's, that's, that's,
that really is the craziest technology.
I mean self replicating
things in an ANA scale.
It's like be mad that you'd be able to
throw those into the lava and they would
somehow or another crowd bill
everybody the fuck out. Yeah.
Change the structure of the
molecular structure of the lava.
I don't know if that fuck it freezes up
the planet and turns us into another ice
age. Jesus Christ. Jason, Jason
Silva. What are you doing?
The Butterfly effect issue is always,
yeah, it is. We don't care. Well,
no, it will have super computers that
can map out every possible possibility.
Trillions of times more than we can map
out different scenarios in our heads so
those ais will be able to
pick the best scenario.
They'll make mathematical
projection. There'll be like, okay,
there's a billion in one probabilities
of, and Annette, this is the best one.
Let's do it.
You spend so much time thinking about
the future and thinking about all these
possibilities. Is it, is it possible that
when you do this, or is it a difficult,
when you do this not to, not to ignore
the present? Is it hard to, you know,
is it like,
is it like a sort of a normal thing to
sort of ignore the present while you're
concentrating it entirely
on what the human race is
going to accomplish it? Well,
well I think that, you know how they
say that was phrase that very well,
but you know, no, no, I
think you know how they did,
we always talk about how
human beings need a purpose.
Purpose by its very nature implies
a reason to look forward, right?
So we can't help but look to the future.
It's what we do.
So your purpose is to create a purpose in,
to put the idea of purpose into people's,
gives me a sense of purpose is a
collective feeling that like, wow,
humanity has this unique opportunity
to sort of map it's road beautifully.
And we all have a way of
participating in that.
And what a wonderful sense of
collective purpose. It's just,
it's more interesting to me than like, oh,
well my purpose is to become, you know,
or get this job or do this
thing. It's like, yeah,
I want to get this job into this things
just like everybody else because I want
to survive, but I'm in the mood for
cosmic purpose. Cosmic significance.
Your cosmic dig slinger,
did I say they say it's the same reason
that religion always appealed to people
for the same reason that man can live for
a few, you know, few weeks without food,
a few days without water,
but not for a second without hope.
It's just the human condition.
You know, the minute we lose hope,
we commit suicide.
Not The minute.
Sometimes you can really suffer
for years before you pull the plug,
but when you lose complete hope,
you won't even wait around
if you're waiting around it
because you have a little
bit of thing of thinking that it
thinks might turn around. Yeah,
I think it's important. I
think it's important to to
look forward. I think it's,
it's huge.
I think it's the only thing that propels
our progress anyway because if we were
in a stupefied Lowell staying in the
present, we wouldn't do anything.
Yeah, of course. Um, what do you
see happening in your lifetime?
I mean we are right now in
2012 this was supposed to be,
if you're paying attention to time wave
zero novelty theory to supposed to be
wearing when the shit hits the fan.
When you on have found recently,
I've talked about this recently,
but I wanted to bring it up with you,
cause I know you're a mckenna fan as well.
He altered the end date to coincide
with the end date of the Mayan calendar.
Yeah.
Maybe he was a of the people that believe
that by creating a social movement
around these ideas, you more quickly
actualize those ideas. People were,
so you cited me for bringing this up,
but somebody had posted it on my message
board and then I went and read and he
apparently his initial
calculations was November,
November of 2012 to December, moved to
December 21st which is the, you know,
the end date of long count. But then
somebody brought up the other day,
there was like a Internet
meme going around where, you
know, calculate leap years,
did the Mayans calculate leap peers?
Cause if they didn't,
we know that all this shit all happened
700 years ago. Oh yeah. I mean I,
the specifics,
I have no idea what the sciences,
but I think what's interesting is that
if you create a viral swell 10 times the
scale of the Joseph Kony video with some
beautifully produced message about how
mankind is using technology to create
a global brain and it addressed the
problems of humanity and it's seen by a
billion people by December on Youtube,
then the idea becomes reality. Because
this is what we've been talking about.
You know, ideas are just as real
as the neurons that they inhabit.
So that's what's crazy.
It's a self fulfilling
propers Joseph Kony video.
We talked about this, but I remember
when it hit Twitter, when I saw it,
when I saw it starting to appear in
my timeline, I started thinking, wow,
what's going to happen here?
Like this is,
this seems like a very orchestrated
campaign and the idea to make a a terrible
person, very famous so that he's,
he's a target of five more. Yeah.
What a genius idea. Geez. And you know,
that really is just sort of tapping
into potential tapping into which no one
else has done before. No one else has ever
done that about a terrible person. No,
no. It's very, yeah, it's interesting.
So interesting. It's brilliant. Yeah.
And it just,
the use of media and understanding its
power and applying it for savvy social
impact. What are the
criticisms of this Kony video?
Cause I know there's a few
of the criticism I think
has to do specifically with,
with with the nonprofit operations
tales. But look again, that's something,
that's a whole other
conversation and we're in it.
We're not experts and
we don't know the facts.
But I think what's interesting is
what they've made with the video,
what that video means about the future
of how messages get spread that we were
seeing. We all realized, we all know
where we were when the Kony video hit.
It's one of those things where it's like
something has changed here and we're
all aware that, okay this is, this is
a new paradigm. It's a paradigm shift,
not even a paradigm shift. You know
what's really fascinating is Obama,
the Obama campaign is releasing. There's,
this is where they're so social media,
brilliant savvy. They understand
aesthetics in their campaign.
They had the director of an inconvenient
truth is about to release a documentary.
So like a well made film about Obama
and that's going to be part of their
campaign media materials.
So instead of like an ad,
like a normal attack ad like
the other guys are doing,
and these guys are releasing a film
made by a talented film maker. I mean
the brilliance of that, that's probably
going to go ridiculously viral.
That's the best campaign video
you could have ever done.
What is that going to come out?
I don't know the dates,
but people should Google the WHO knew
about whenever it's just a trailer.
I wonder if it's gonna
be free or like Louis Ck.
I wonder if it's going to be like a Kim
Kardashian reality TV show where you
know that they've created artificial
scenarios to move the plot along. Yeah.
Like Obama is Obama. We got
you at a carwash now. What?
It was like Mexican food.
I don't want Mexican food.
Now you're going to be washing the car.
Imagine if they actually did it. They
produce it like a reality show. Yeah.
What's happened is the most ridiculous
shit ever. I haven't seen it.
I wonder what it's going to be.
Something tells me it's going to be a
well made film with beautiful music and
well, it'd be nice to see him
talk outside of that fake sort of,
I'm giving a speech voice.
Yeah, exactly. You know,
she'd be like a documentary that followed
him and you get behind the scenes.
All the fake,
I'm giving a speech voice is very
disturbing because it's too smooth.
It's not real. It's too polished.
It's not. It's not. You know,
I know it's prepared and beaten down to,
I don't want that out of a leader.
You know what I want out
of a leader is I want,
I want to know that this is who
this is you. This isn't, um,
being a strip club Dj.
This isn't on the am morning
Chi on the zoo coming up next.
The same fucking voice.
When you hear a man give
a speech and you know the,
there's that way of talking. That is
so God damn fake. It should be illegal.
They shouldn't be able to stop you from
making campaigns in speeches and stop
you and go. You can't talk like
that. It'll be interesting to see,
to see how it comes across. And
speaking of, of politicians,
they just see the HBO movie
about a Game Change. What is it?
What's game chats about the Mccain?
Oh,
about Sarah Palin when he picked his
writing man watching the more Sarah Palin.
Well it's Julianne Moore was so
good in it. Dude. It's pretty hot.
She looks just like her.
Yeah.
But like the film is so upsetting and
really well cause it shows you the theater
of what a lot of politics
has become obsolete. It is.
And how accurate is it accurate?
The conversations,
I mean it's all been doctored up for
fucking dramatic effect. You know,
you need to see a man, I think
you still get the message,
you still get the idea of the reasons
that she was put there and her lack of
experience and well that became
painfully obvious. Right.
But here it's presented in a, the way it
would be like a film scholar, you know,
explaining something to you guys. It
just illustrates how wonky the system is.
And that could even be an option or
how could that be an option? Exactly.
[inaudible] would allow
that. Well, you know,
it's what I've always said is the real
problem is that there's really fucking
dumb people out there, a lot of
them. And they get to vote too.
And the problem with dumb people
as they don't know, they're dumb.
So when they see someone like Sarah Pailin
who may not be the smartest person in
the world,
but she's way smarter than them,
they can't distinguish between her and
Stephen Hawking's. When Neil Tyson speaks,
he sounds just as brilliant as Sarah
Pailin because they're both way out of
their fucking league. Most people can
barely string together a sentence.
And so these are the people that came
to her cause she represents simplicity.
She represents, I think today with
old fashion things and hunting,
well she's family cause safe danger
with her. She's dangerous. But because,
but she's also familiar. So
maybe that's why, but like fuck,
I feel like today man,
if you have access to the internet,
you have no excuse not
to be on Khan Academy.
You have no excuse not
to be watching Ted talks.
You have no excuse not to saturate
your brain with knowledge.
Like it's not like there's no books around
like the every book that's ever been
written is an internet click way.
And I feel like ignorance
is inexcusable these days.
If you have an internet connection.
So it's kind of like a, I don't know,
like it feels like the, you
know, the tools are there,
but it's up to us how we use them.
It's going back to the same
message and I think people really,
they need to need to get on this,
right? They need to get on this.
The representative government
ideas gotta go, that's,
that's not necessary anymore. We can all
instantly communicate with the, you know,
the government. We can instantly decide
what, what we agree with. We can,
we can have our voices heard.
The idea that we have senators
and congressmen or the other,
and they're in this position where they
get to vote for their district shop.
A fascinating idea. Yeah, that's a
ridiculous idea. That's not even that,
that's not, see everybody looks at it
at democracy as if like you get a say,
you get to vote, but you don't get to
say shit. You get a say in who you pick,
who gets you in a position. But
democracy needs to come online, man.
Like the whole hundred
percent needs to be revamped.
They need to throw out all
representations, sores.
The Internet needs to be voted on new
constitutional amendment and they should
people who have jobs, but those jobs
are to carry out the will of the people,
not to represent the totem pole.
The people can represent themselves.
When is somebody going to make a Joseph
Kony style video about legalizing
marijuana?
And if people say,
click here and play this to say
yes and if it gets a billion views,
they'll have to legalize. It could
already see just Google the union man.
Go Watch the movie of the Union,
the business behind getting high.
It's a documentary that I was involved in,
the my friend Adam score you produced.
It was like,
I don't know,
it was like four or five years
ago at least that we did this.
So one of the best documentaries on the,
the reality behind the illegalization
of marijuana and the reality behind how
how big of a businesses and how
many fucking people use it. Dude,
I have done my family that benefit from
its medicinal medicinal use and they've
benefited immensely.
It's been like a miracle for my aunt.
It's one of those plants,
one of those substances,
one of those elements of our culture
and society that if you were,
again, if you were looking
at life as a work of fiction,
if life was a movie and there was a some
plant in the movie that was incredibly
beneficial,
not just to the culture,
not just to instilling a
sense of camaraderie and
people not just to fort making
you inquisitive, main, uh, a turbo
charger for your imagination,
making sex feel better,
not just all of these things,
but then it creates a superior fiber
that you can make clothes out of.
It's way more horrible than cotton.
It makes a much more superior paper and
you could put it in an area, in a can,
in four months.
It can be ready to process.
Whereas it takes fucking years
to grow trees in the same area.
Plus it outproduces the trees in the same
acreage by something like four to one.
I mean, it's amazing. It has the
amino acids that you can live off of.
You can use it to make
fuel. You can make him, boy,
it becomes preposterous busters.
But imagine a video that's slickly
produced that the Kony video that gets a
billion views. Let's do it. Let's do
it. You and me do those 10 minutes.
Did you get your specialty? We'll
pump it up on new bill in California,
a Dui bill that they're going
to make it a zero tolerance Dui.
If you have any weed in your system
or in a marijuana and marijuana, he's,
he stays in your system does six weeks.
How could they do it?
That's like saying punishing you for
being drunk two days ago and it would
pretty much make anyone that smokes weed.
Well that's silly. They don't have to,
they're not going to pick it up to get
a urine test from you and they wouldn't
know what they would be allowed
to do if they pull you over. Oh,
that's so ridiculous. That's,
you know, the, the real,
the real problem with that as a
science is not the same. It doesn't,
the marijuana does not treat people or
it doesn't affect people the same way
that alcohol does,
period.
I'm not saying you should go out
and get high and drive around,
but I'm saying some people can drive
high and they're fine and that is a fact,
you know,
and you might not want to address it
because it seems like it's a taboo subject
and you know when people want to dance
around it, it is not getting drunk.
Getting drunk is something that really
severely impairs your ability to operate
machines that your ability to walk your
niche and are very different things.
Very, very, very different.
It's not a good idea to be in any altered
state of consciousness while you're
responsible for others. That's
all we get. The self driving cars.
That's why the Google self driving cars
are so perfectly baked as fucking a
Google car. Google car could be
Cheech and Chong to the Max. Yes.
Completely filled with smoke. So they
open up those side going door. Shoot,
everybody gets driving time. Yes,
and it'll be the self driving car.
It's perfectly safe. The computer
does, it doesn't get high, dude.
You're a Google fanboy a little bit,
right.
I'm kind of a fan of anybody who's pushing
the boundaries of the possible does.
Of course I'm a Google fanboy.
Yes, I'm lycos all the way. Whoa,
Bro. I'm Netflix. Netflix or no, no, no.
What was the other one? Net. No, Netscape.
That's it. Number. Netscape. Netscape.
Search. Search. Yeah. There was
like a search part of it, I think.
Does that make sense? I thought
it was always a browser. I didn't,
well there was the blue of the earliest
search engines before Google. There was,
that wasn't the first search engines.
I remember Alta Vista Vista hype.
I don't remember.
Light goes,
I remember liking this then.
So how did those go away and how
did Google just stormed the beach?
How invaded man innovative?
It is like natural selection.
It's like winning
because winning the game,
Microsoft is trying so hard with this
whole big thing. First of all, why being,
what does that mean? What do
you say? It's Google, bing.
It's probably the second best
one. It's pretty good. But
why being, why call it being,
why is it Google? Why is Google?
Because Google is a number, dude.
It's a very cool number. Actually.
I already know about it until recently.
That's like a term for like
a gigantic like twill. Yeah.
There's like a million zeros or some shit.
Well, let's, let's find out what it is.
What is it? Google here because
we'll, we should, uh, foreign people.
It comes from another term. It doesn't,
I don't believe that the word is Google.
It's a, it's a preview
of a term. Yeah. Google.
It's G. O. G. O. L. Yeah.
And it is. Holy Shit. How
many, oh my God. 100 zeroes.
It is the, wow. Uh, Google is the
large number. 10 to a hundred.
That is the digit one
followed by 100 zero.
What a great way to make a statement
about the depth and breadth of your
capabilities by using a number like that.
It's kind of beautiful. And how perfect.
What a perfect description. It's
perfect for Google. That is Google.
Then Google voicemail. Google
fucking maps. Google cheeses.
So I am so excited to speak there.
Yeah. What are you gonna talk about?
I want to talk about creativity.
I'm going to talk about innovation.
I'm talking about inspiration in awe.
I'm going to talk about using technology
to render the impossible into existence.
And I'm going to show some of the videos.
Actually my friend Josh Kaplan actually
who set this up is a huge fan of your
show. Oh that's awesome. He
loves your podcasts and so Josh
and he set up the invite to
Google. So that's amazing
that man, that's incredible.
You know,
Google is known as being one of those
companies that really treats their
employees well. You know, that's like a,
we got an invite a couple of years
ago when we were in San Francisco,
maybe a year ago.
So I'm someone from Google emailed me,
but I lost it in the shuffle. My,
my email gets clogged sometimes.
Like I just can't find anyone
because you get a lot of crazy,
you must get a lot of emails
in general, Huh? Yeah. But,
but the one thing that I was
fascinated by, what I wanted to see,
what it was like in there, cause
I've always thought like, man,
why can't someone make a company where
they treat their employees well? Like,
how much more does it cost to give them
really good food, take care of them.
It might cost like a little more,
but wouldn't make the atmosphere way
better and make connections. So yeah,
I mean that's like one of
the most important things
is that the environment be
positive.
Totally.
Nobody wants to work around someone who
doesn't want to work their creativity.
And productivity comes from allowing
people to have distractions.
So it's like they have ping pong tables,
bean bags and all these things because
you know, and some people might criticize,
oh, it's just a playground. Actually. No,
it probably makes the
employees much more creative.
You're creating spaces in which the free
association and their services can fire
and yes, that's, creativity
is about that. It's been,
I'm sure there are judged or at least
evaluated based on the productivity.
It's not like they're not going to
be in the law of God this job, Tom,
just play ping pong. Right, right.
And not the type of people that
will do that in the first place.
So it becomes a resource
rather than a distraction.
And it distraction as a resource.
And these are the postindustrial
revolution companies.
These are the most admired companies
in the world. You have apple,
you have Google,
and people are looking to these companies
as examples of how to run businesses,
how to have social impact, how to
make legacies, how to not be evil.
And they still don't like this is
new model against the core of, of,
of corporations are
going to be judged upon.
So all the new entrepreneurs
now coming online,
they're getting inspired
from these companies, right?
I want it may be the next Google
and change the world. It's not,
I want to make the next Google and
be rich. I want to change the world.
And what happens with like
Google video and stuff?
Cause I know they came
out against Sopa and the,
the Stop online piracy act and they kinda,
that all fell apart and they're trying
to rig come up with a new strategy,
a new new, uh, a new act.
Well, I think we need to,
we need to all have a new conversation
about content ownership in a world in
which everybody has the tools
to make mixed tapes. So, yeah,
but like what about Google
videos and stuff like that?
What if someone has a documentary
and the documentary is for sale,
but you go to Google video and there it
is and you can just watch it for free.
What is a no, no, you,
you do what Radiohead did,
which is where they put their album online
for free and they said donate money,
donate money if you would
like to pay for this music.
But if you think that that's how people
who want to sell DVDs should deal with
the fact that people
are stealing their shit,
they're going to have to
ask for donations. Well, no,
but I think that we're just,
it's an invited a lot of which
more because what happens
is everybody's going to
be making content for free and way and
the content for free is going to be just
as good as the content you charge for.
And I think people will pay because
they appreciate your content,
but I think it's going to be harder and
harder to like impose payment. Well,
how would someone,
like let's say for an example,
say if there's a documentary
on crocodiles. Okay, I told
you about it. Oh my God,
it's crazy.
You got to watch this.
Now you go to Google video and you
find this documentary or crocodiles,
how the fuck are you going to find
the production company? The website?
You got to search it out.
Are you going to go Google the name
of it and you're saying you were just
watching the website, watch it on youtube.
I mean if you really wanted to set up,
they had it set up where you could,
you know where you could donate if you
would like on their website. I mean,
well no,
they can.
So they can do a youtube channel that
supported by ads and if lots of people
watch the movie,
they'll get money from the ads that
they have on their page and then they,
in the description,
they can say,
we're putting this movie online for
free because we want to share the ideas,
but we're asking for
donations of $5 a view.
And I'm sure that a lot of people
would give it. A lot of people would.
A lot of people wouldn't as well though.
Do you? So do you feel like that is,
and then there's the audit.
The other argument is the
people that wouldn't as well.
I kind of see their point of view because
they would, they would say, listen,
I would've never bought this in the first
place so I'm not taking anything away
from them.
I downloaded it because it
was free because I knew I
could watch it and I didn't
like it. So I'm glad that it would get my
map. When you see a bad name, you don't,
you want to get your money
back. Yes. I mean there's,
I can see that argument as
well. You know, it is a weird,
it's one of the Zeros and it's just being
distributed through the Internet. It's,
it's a weird, because conversations only
have a price because of scarcity. Right.
Charged for something because
it's a rare commodity. No,
that also people things
have a price because you,
I mean there's no scarcity in
artwork. I mean you're not, you know,
when your work is yours unique,
so people pay for it because it's only
you did something that's unique to you
and if you have an audience, because
I say it for, that's what I'm saying,
but I think that uh, increasingly
scarcity stayed stating them for their
efforts. I mean it's not necessarily
just paying for scarcity,
it's you're compensating someone
honestly because you were efforts,
you appreciate the efforts.
But I think that it's just
the genie's out of the bottle.
It's just too difficult for
immaterial things to be contained.
Do you think that ultimately that's going
to lead to sort of a decay in the idea
of capitalism and the, you know, the
thing is going to be doing exams.
Everything is going to be reexamined,
but when they start getting into like
real high end three d printers and that's
how you order things,
you just ordered the formula transform
manufacturing as well, man. Yeah.
And then the,
then those people will get scared and
lose their jobs and we'll have moments of
panic and all of that transition
will change everything.
But you know that like 80% of the jobs
that people do today didn't exist a
hundred years ago.
There were jobs that didn't exist.
So there will be new things for us to do.
It becomes a real problem when people
hold on to the idea that they need to keep
a job and because the job
is a part of the old way.
And that is also one of the reasons
why marijuana is still illegal.
And there was a recent
article that I tweeted,
if you find it just a couple of
days ago or just Google the, uh,
the statement lobbyists are getting rich
off keeping marijuana illegal because
that's what's going on, man. Right?
There's lobbyists that are doing this
through a police unions. You know,
there's lobbyists that are doing
this and they're there. You know,
these guys are making a lot of
money off keeping marijuana illegal.
There's a lot of people
that their bishops, yeah,
well their business is
to arrest people for pod.
Cause I mean that's part of the job.
It's part of what keeps people paid.
It's part of what keeps us
strong. Police Force. But even,
but I think that in a country where most
of the population at this point wants
it to be legalized,
there should be no red tape or bureaucracy
between the peoples oil and it being
changed. I think it's also, most
people want it to be legalized.
They should be like a like
button on Facebook and if
100 million people click it,
it should be legalized tomorrow. And I
think she will eventually. Yeah, that's,
that's dynamic democracies. Things that
we'll need to get, one of the issues is,
um,
and I think this has to be stopped is
we have to stop treating police officers
as glorified revenue collectors.
Cause that's what they are.
And I think that's a really
disgusting thing because guess what,
firefighters and place, and I hope
we never have to fucking use them.
I hope those guys get to hang out at the
firehouse all day and cook and work out
and do fucking Chin ups and shit.
And I hope no one ever has to work.
I hope no one ever has
to deal with the faculty.
I would like the same thing
with police officers. Right.
It would be great if they
never had to take the guns out.
There was never anything for them.
The issue is they have quotas.
They have quotas they have to
reach. I had no idea. Oh fuck. Yeah.
Especially with speeding. You know, I've
talked to friends. They have quotas. Yes,
absolutely. Yeah, they have. They have to
make quotas as far as giving out tickets,
so that really raises a red flag,
like telling a firefighter that you're
only going to get paid if you put out a
fire or something.
I'm going to be looking to build fires.
Imagine what would happen if the entire
country decided that for one month,
which would fuck up the entire system.
That's all we need is 30 days.
Everybody in agreement where nobody
ever violates a single law as far as
speeding or driving traffic or stoplights.
We made a viral video for it.
Recruiting campaign. Don't break a law
for a month. Every cop and get fired.
It would be cas. Wow. Yeah. It'd be
crazy. They would lose all that revenue
that they count on. They
count on us. Never evolving.
I mean it's really
factored into the budget.
So we need massive system upgrades here.
Massive systemic system.
It's the idea that you have engineered
a system where we can never be good,
we can never get through because you,
you,
you're cops need to arrest
a certain amount of people
need to pull over rather a
certain amount of people and put out
a certain amount of tickets. The,
the state relies on that for revenue.
We're going to have to radically change
everything. Will radically change. No,
but there was a time when,
you know,
somebody's life was about making
saddles for horses, you know,
cause everybody had horses and that person
was probably really nervous when the
car started to become popular because
it couldn't make his horse carriages
anyone. Lucky for him. Lesbians are
still around and it's still like horses.
I wouldn't say lesbians, I'd say women
who used to like men but gave up.
Now they like horses.
I don't know man.
I live right in the question district
and I see him every day and some of them
are fucking high.
These are like spoiled little girls that
date like rich guys that by the models
and shit, you gotta fuck those girls
hard man. They ride horses all day.
They're used to,
they're not impressed by just like
regular sex riding a giant animal,
you must feel so feeble, you
know? You know what I'm saying?
They get on top of you. They're
like, really? This is it.
This is all you got to
their next level of Madison.
I always feel bad for the horses, man.
It's chains around their mouths. I'm like,
no man. Yeah, I don't like
it. It's gross. It's gross.
There's a lot of people in my neighborhood
and they're like super self righteous,
like you know, slow down. You can be like,
it's 28 miles, you know the speed limits.
25 you're going 28 slow
down, slow down. Just big,
big bull dyke on her fucking crazy animal.
It's a weird thing.
You're allowed to just ride around animals
in 2012 someone should come along and
you know, really just go to a farm
somewhere. You can't be just, you know,
I don't care if this is a question
you district. That's ridiculous.
It still Berbick you crazy. Fuck. We do
doing riding a horse my neighborhood soon.
We won't. We won't eat animals either.
I'm really convinced about in vitro meat,
man. No one's going to have
to eat those fucking animals.
That's a problem because what happens
then? What do we do? Eat, sterilize them.
What do we do to keep them from just being
everywhere? Like in India? What's it?
You know,
what does it like if you drive everywhere
in his fucking cows are like rats in
New York City. Just infesting the
landscape and we can't eat them.
Some of them have to kill him,
Bro.
And we're going to have to
deal introduced triceratops.
Maybe we want to get some dinosaurs
breed as many. I mean, that's an option.
What if we just let them go? Right? If we
let them go without eating them anymore,
we let them go. They're going
to fuck. They're going, fuck,
am I going to be like Buffalo,
Buffalo Plains?
Just grow the tissue where they're going
to be everywhere. System. Oh Man, I dunno.
I think, uh, if we want to stay human,
I think they're going to keep up.
They're going to keep breeding.
I think we're going to have to get,
predators are going to have to make some
robot predators like those dog robot
things that only just go out
and jack cows. Interesting.
They just do it to keep the population
down. Who knows, man. And we to be,
it's going to be dry. Just shook his head.
I'll have to add a new scenario now.
The new scenarios, we'll come in,
we'll find new novel solutions to
do, eat meal with them. Do eat meat.
I eat meat. Not every day,
but I'm a flexitarian.
Flexitarian. You're flexible.
I know I eat meat but I just,
I try not to eat it every day.
Did you ever consider the idea that what
you're doing is harmful to the energy
of the university or you know,
eating tortured animals? Uh,
never fuck with you ever watch like
food inc or I try to have organic food,
but I still,
you know,
that's like a cow that grows up in the
hippie community and they get shot in the
head. I don't know. It still gets jacked.
I would like to become vegetarian.
It's just, it's not the easiest
thing to do logistically. You know?
Now you can't always find it right now.
You're going to get a swarm of hate
mail from right now from sweaty little
vegans, vegetarians, they're warming up
their little fingers right now. Well,
I'm a flexitarian. I mean not,
not you. An open minded person.
Food twice a week is already
really good at you're making it.
That's the beginning. That's
decent. That's the beginning.
No, no, eight, no. Yeah,
I think animals are dumb and I think uh,
if they were smart, they'd be killing us.
I think we'd have issues.
I think every animal is playfully.
We get to where our empathy is
big enough to alleviate suffering.
Even co even suffering
if it's not compliantly.
I agree as a cycle of life
requires predators and we
have sort of can completely
hijack that cycle of life with the idea
of cities and civilization and a big
metal boxes were contrived through
fucking safari and be 10 feet away from a
lion killing a gazelle.
I mean we've got a crazy game changers.
Men were complete game changing
species for good or for bad.
I think more for good.
I think I'm more impressed with with
us than I am that I am disturbed by us.
I long shot much more
impressed with us though,
but it's nice to just kind of to marvel,
let ourselves a little bit.
I think we have kind of a,
what's it called,
a guilty cosmic complex where we feel
like we're small and insignificant and I
think we have a big role to play and can
play an even bigger role if we pool our
cognitive resources together.
I agree,
but I also agree the big is delicious and
so steak and a that you can grow bacon
out of like stem cells,
like a print ad to kill another animal,
print das to Bacon. You're never
going to be able to recreate venison.
You never going to be able to retain a
special no. Venison is dear me. Oh, okay.
Totally recreate. There's a
delicious Gamey, wild flavor.
Tell how much shit ones and Zeros you
think they'll be able to figure that out.
Yeah,
man.
He'll be like in the matrix when a
guy's eating the steak and he's like,
I know this is not real. I know it's made
of like code. He's like, I don't care.
It tastes delicious and
it puts it in his mouth.
So you gotta be satisfied with that. I
think we all say it's inevitable, right?
It's inevitable. We'll do it. I
mean, what are we tasting anyway?
Except our brain's interpretation
of something going in
through sensors that are
like creating a software that goes
in real time and tells us, Oh,
this is what this feels like.
I'm glad I got to experience
life with no answering machines.
I'm glad I got to experience no
cell phones when I was growing up.
So you could see the contrast.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
Does it make you appreciate
how much higher do you are now?
I appreciate how wired we are now,
but I also appreciate old school stuff.
I appreciate, I appreciate a good steak.
You know, I like a good steak. Hardwood.
Coles grilled is
amen.
Cooking with cooking with fire was
a technology to yeah, it is. Yeah.
So yeah, absolutely. I mean,
look what the appendix exists to.
It was an Oregon to break down fibers
we eat and all kinds of crazy shit back
then, wasn't it? I mean it
wasn't there. What it was,
we lost its use and that's
why a lot of people have to,
have you ever gotten your, uh, your genome
tested to see what percentage? 20 tall.
You are 23 and me,
the Google thing,
you were talking about it and it's
not completely, I mean it's not,
it's not like they can
understand everything.
Someone's a monkey and it's trying
to dump it on technology. Yeah.
It's one of those exponential
things where eventually they'll,
it'll be 100% tell you everything
about everything. Do you have to,
right now at least it tells you, did you
spit in a cup or something like that?
You said,
how do you do it?
What do you do is send you this little
tube twenty3@aol.com yeah, 23 minutes.
Amazing.
I'll tell you if you have like a precut,
a precondition of some sorts,
or if you have a likelihood of developing
something like high blood pressure,
if your genetic profile says
you're going to get Parkinson's,
are the percentages of a
chance of developing something.
So for people who get stuff
that's preventable, you
know, if they're like, oh,
I have a 70% chance of high blood
pressure, I can start addressing that now.
I've been told that I'm more likely to
get it in another person so I can change
my diet now because some people are just
genetically so lucky that they can eat
shit. Nothing will ever
happen to them. Fuckers. Yeah,
that's always the case until we all
upgrade our genes, but for everybody else,
this is a chance to see what some of their
vulnerabilities might be and how they
might address them.
So we start to hack our biology.
How cool is this idea that we
all start hacking our biology.
We're upgrading ourselves by hacking in
and getting back door and are we short
cuts and forcing?
Are we delaying the inevitable
brilliant next stage of existence?
Are we in this light?
You mean that may be will be something
after this stage is way better and that's
the natural progress. The natural
progress is to move from this to the next.
That could only be the case.
If this is a simulation and we are went
to the waking up from the simulation.
If this is a lucid dream,
if this is limbo from inception,
you know that you spend 80 years in limbo
and you get old before you wake up and
become a young man again. But if
that's the case, great look, awesome.
I fucking hope so man.
I'm just not fully convinced so I'm
going to fight for my survival as
passionately as I can now because I have
the evidence that there's anything else.
No evidence. It's pretty
hopeless. Fair is pretty vivid.
It might be the big sleep
it turned any on both ends.
Why can't any of the universe is
eternal? Why can't we be? That's my,
I think consciousness probably
goes to sleep forever,
but I think you should come a part of,
is it maybe consciousness is
really a tool to create action.
Maybe it's a tool to move things forward.
There's no doubt that it is,
but it's a tool that found out that
it enjoys it so it wants to proceed.
It likes blowjob. Joy's itself
drunk. We're self referential.
It's that recursive feedback loop.
We know that.
We know that we know and
therefore consciousness.
If it was a fluke or if it
was by like emergent design,
it has decided that it likes itself.
Sure.
It likes like, you know, it likes free
time. It likes to make art and sing songs.
Not everything that it does is to
build things and to be utilitarian and
functional thumbs things are pure
pleasure. The robots in blade runner,
pleasure of being alive as well. There
you go. So that could be what it is,
right? Yeah. Rutger Hauer. Remember? He
really liked it. Yeah. Who's bummed down?
Yeah. Crazy kangaroos.
Kangaroos. Kangaroos.
Who eat a flower. That came from
another planet. I'm telling you, man,
it's super intelligent kangaroos.
Would that be the shit of Kangaroos?
Started yelling at you for
fucking polluting Kangaroos?
Started talking to English like really
quick a couple of years and they were
Catholic school growing and amazing
about Kangaroos is that they continue to
raise, they have that thing, you know
the pouch, the pouch, little babies,
but it's almost like when the baby's born,
it's almost like not ready to be born.
And so they kept him in there
and that's kind of like, well,
they live in a terrible environment.
Yeah.
I mean they have to protect that
fucking thing. It's kind of amazing.
They live in where there's
crocodiles everywhere, right?
Kangaroos or that's a bad spot. Yeah.
Australia's those shady fucking spot.
The most venomous snakes. Oh, they
got all this shit that can kill you.
And most of the country, you can't live
in most of the country. Nobody lives in.
Well, they live or on the coast for that.
It's happening more and more, more, more,
more people moving to cities.
Man,
most of the population lives in cities
and will continue to live in and they
found a reef of ancient bile.
Ancient like a simple organism.
Shit that is like some,
it's the 650 fucking million years old.
Some insane.
So it predated the,
the idea of life on this planet and they
founded in Australia. Yeah. Australia is,
it's a crazy spot. It would be fun
to go. Yeah, I've been a few times.
I've been to Sydney, Sydney twice.
Great people. Really Nice people man.
I said I hear and they have
no ozone over there man.
They got real cancer problems like all
over their billboards are these pictures,
they have like these uh,
skin cancer campaigns.
So there's photos of people with big giant
stitched up scars talk about getting,
cause everyone's getting chunks taken out
of them. But you go out there and the,
you know, in the, in the sun
with no sunscreen on, you
get fucked up man. Sunscreen.
Yeah. It's another level
son with the ozone layer.
This giant hole in the ozone
over that long to get there.
I like 17 hours or something. Not
Quite. I think 15 something like that.
I want to go, it's a lot want to
go. But you know what, if you,
if you can deal with that just one day.
I mean, you know what you do is man,
get a bunch of podcast,
get a bunch of podcasts,
get a few movies on your iPad and just
zone out and just goes in and say,
this is what I'm doing. And don't
freak out and don't feel like, fuck,
I got to get up, move around. Just,
just deal with it. Ain't no big a deal.
And then once you get there, Holy Shit.
It's a beautiful, beautiful country.
It's so gorgeous.
It's so amazing when you think that
the people from England cause that as a
prison colony at one point in time, you
know, like what a, what a silly idea.
Fascinating. Now all their
actors win all the awards. Yeah.
I wonder why they're so good. Yeah.
Australian and British actors, man,
they bring it end ups to Jim Jefferies.
Really funny. Standup from uh,
Australia. Yeah. And there's a couple of
Americans that do really well with their,
like Eddie aft and Arch Barker.
They go over there and they're the arch
Barker's fucking enormous over there
apparently. Yeah. Yeah. And they just
really, like when I was in Australia,
I was talking to people like, what do you
do? I'm like, Oh, I'm a comedian. Like,
you know, ODG Parka immediately.
Wow. Yeah. Yeah. It's uh,
it's so close to like,
it's nothing like America,
but you could totally hang out there.
Like you could live there.
Like you wouldn't have to learn a
language. People are very friendly.
You'd have no problems. It feels
slightly alternate universe. Yes,
they speak English, but it's
just another, another reality.
It's so far away that they drive on
the other side of the road. Right.
That freaks you out. Right? Totally.
That whole England thing is a trip,
Alison Wonderland. It's like, why are you
on this site traveling so cool though,
for shifting people's sense
of like reality. Oh yeah.
Expanding your consciousness because
you're immersed in a sort of mirror world
where it's like, well, most
things are kind of the same,
but they're a little off.
Yeah. So it's like reality has shifted
a little bit. I think it's a traveling,
so it's cool to see like culture like
Australia where w you know, socially,
you know, it was really kind of like
parallel to America, like really similar.
I mean not exact but,
but really similar.
Like if you go over there and you
meet an Australian guy who your age,
chances are you've got to have a lot of
things to talk about in common and it
won't be very,
it'd be different but not alien at all.
So it's kind of interesting that that
is happening on the other side of the
planet, right? There's like some
sort of, uh, you know, you're there,
you're modern civilization
and they're like,
these people live here and the dream
here and the wake up and they go to work.
I scrape living.
There are higher lines with a whole
different set of priorities that have no
bearing on my existence and that I didn't
know about it until they came here.
And what really makes you trip out is
when you watch their TV shows and they
have like really popular TV shows,
you fucking never heard about her though.
When a guy comes out
and the girl comes out,
you know who the fuck are these people?
And everybody goes crazy.
Everybody goes crazy. Number
one show in Australia, my,
I can't believe they're really on right
now and everybody will sit down and get
drunk.
It's amazing.
It gives you perspective also just you
from your reality on hinges you a little
bit.
The one thing that I consistently get
when I go to these places is how uptight
America is. You know when you go
and you, especially for Australia,
they're so fun and they're so easy to
hang out with and so generally friendly.
It makes you feel like why?
What does this law,
what's responsible for this
level of tension in America?
Well, he's responsible.
It's not everywhere by the way.
Of course there's a lot of cool
people in America. Don't get me wrong,
I get a lot of Douche bag
dummy tweets like whoo, whoo,
move to have grooves doing viewed
America that I hate America.
Stupid is what I love American.
I think America should be awesome.
I mean it is awesome,
but it should be better than what it is.
It's possible for us to improve and what
holds us back? It's fuck heads like you.
That's what holds us back.
Tweet Twitter. We need this guy.
There should be no reason why the
cutting edge to be uptight about things
particularly like social issues that we
need to like completely legalized gay
marriage everywhere we need to
legalize marijuana. Rick Santorum.
Cause he disagrees. Rick Santorum had
have a really interesting point though.
I've got to admit, I mean I am a always
a 100% in support of gay marriage. I'm,
you know, I think she'd be able to
do whatever the fuck you want to do.
It's not as, it's not hurting me.
It's not a scam. It's not hurting me.
It's not like you're trying to steal
money means it's not her. Right.
So I'm completely in support of that.
But he had a really interesting
point that Rick Santorum,
cause he was talking about marriage,
has always been for over a thousand years,
has been defined as a man and a woman.
Now all of a sudden you're calling it
marriage, but it's a man and a man.
Can it be a man and two men?
And I was like, Oh shit.
Like he just flipped it on
its head like he really did.
It was a really good point because
a, and I was like, well yeah,
well why can't it be two men?
Why can't, why can't two,
two men get married to a guy? Why can't
everybody just bang each other? Why not?
Why not? Why not? Yeah, but, but he was,
the women in the audience were saying, no,
that's a different scenario. You're
talking about a couple that's in love.
And she's like, well no. What
if these people are all in love?
There's three of them would have, you
know, can it be two women and a man?
Can it be two men and women and then,
you know, he just fucked him up, man.
He just fucked them up. There's nothing
they can say then cause you know,
he's really right. Like first of all,
as a personal freedom, uh, issue,
I'd feel like you should be
able to whenever you want.
If it's not hurting me clearly,
clearly gay marriage is not hurting me.
So do whatever the fuck you want.
But if you want to call it marriage,
like maybe they should call it,
maybe it should be something different.
Maybe it's marriage, but it's gay
marriage. Oh, we're gay. Married. No,
like me and my partner,
a gay married.
You wouldn't be able to say regular
married while we're triple married.
Oh there's three of you.
Yeah, we'll get to it.
What would you call that if you made
that legal, what would you call that?
Domestic partnership.
Domestic domestic partners.
If they want to call them married.
This is my one to where they want to know,
but you know,
and then they get all the benefits of
society and they wanted like do tax stuff
together and all those things
that people want. Why not?
Corporations can have like a hundreds
of employees or thousands of employees.
Maybe marriages should be able to as well.
So 100,000 people in a marriage you're
down with like they can be many nation
states, married style polygamy.
I got a Time magazine. No,
that's different because those are
getting minors involved. Right.
And coercing people and imposing reality
tunnels and you'd have a tying access
to other media.
Like it's different.
I've got a Time magazine home
and there's a guy on the cover,
one of those last holdout old man,
Mormon dude who has a,
a gang of wives and uh,
still still rocking it is one dude,
nine wives and he's got 46 children.
What the fuck? What it would be
thrown in jail? What the fuck man?
Yeah, that's crazy. Do you know
that a lot of those guys, uh,
we talked about this before. Who Was
it? What did we brought up this, uh,
that they went to Mexico,
that a lot of Mormons were traveling
to Mexico and they were having problems
with the cartels. They established these
polygamous communities down in Mexico.
Oh Wow.
And I was having problems with the drug
cartels and someone was assassinated
lane. Remember that? I
remember who brought it up.
One of our guests brought
it up and I'm like, wow.
I had no idea that that
was even going down. Right.
They've set up these alternative
communities down in Mexico.
Do you ever think about that?
Like what if somebody just decided to
like turn Costa Rica and the Goddamn
Paradise? Everybody said
they're just trying to do it.
The world's all fucked up everywhere else.
But here's the deal.
We have a limited government.
We were going to establish the best
schools possible libertarian. Yes, yes.
Social, you know, a care
possible. The best healthcare,
the best community centers
where we, you know, we, we
have people who are, you know,
set up to take care of stray children
and really create a society where
there's a guy called Patri Friedman who
had this thing called the seasteading
institute,
which is a organization that,
and they're backed by like Peter Teal
and everything and giant island. Yeah.
To make these artificial manmade
islands where we can do practice runs a
futuristic versions of governance and
they can be an international waters,
but now they're doing something with a
Central American nation where the nation
has given them a chunk of land to let
them set up their own autonomous zone.
Where was his wares in Central America?
It was Nicaragua or Guatemala or
one of those, but they're going to,
they're going to try.
It has been all these articles about it
and they're going to test out futuristic
cutting edge forms of government.
See,
I'm,
the only thing I worry about is one of
the beautiful things about doing things
in America,
even though you're under the shadow
of the military industrial complex,
is that it's fairly safe. You
know it's fairly safe. Yes, yes.
And every month you can't, you, you,
you know, unless you're, I mean,
where are you going to recreate that?
We're going to recreate that.
You're not going to go to an open waters
cause if you do it in international
waters,
what are these Somali pirate dudes?
You hear about that shit every day and
what do you, what are you going to do it?
You've got a bunch of peace
fucking floating spot out there.
The big concrete floating
Django with what? Paul?
The security guard who patrols the
perimeter. They shoot Paul on the head.
Fucking tig over. God dammit. Jason
Silva got to be ready for war. Yeah,
I know it looks,
I mean I think that is
obviously logistical things
that have to be addressed,
but it's a very ambitious idea to begin.
It's very ambitious.
You would have to have guns, a emote.
We have to have laser beams, right?
You get that trash pile it and live in
the middle of it. That's not a bad deal.
One wants to get near that thing here.
Hear people come in to,
but then we're going to get
your water from your water,
from the ocean desalinization course.
It's going to be a,
they're trying to do dean Kamen who
invented a lot of these water purification
systems,
man that you can put in like hearing
bacteria infection like poison almost into
the water and it comes
out like ready to drink.
Why we have this new unit that they're
going to be taken to like rural parts
around the world,
um,
to these little villages and that's
like the number one cause of disease and
illness and dirty water.
Right.
And these things that get these small
little self power devices and they last
forever and it's like Dean
came in and his water products,
water filtration stuff. People should
Google. He's a genius. No, no hit to,
he already has an like this new design.
I wasn't going to say that.
I was going to say how far are they on
the island thing? That artificial island,
I don't know.
I think funding,
they need funding to build a car so that
I going to pay for that. Like pitch.
Well, philanthropists, Internet age,
billionaires, they'd be resources.
It would have to be a lot of money.
How much would it cost to build
a fake islands? I have no idea.
Probably a lot of fucking money, man.
Probably a lot of about a lot of money.
I was watching a documentary
on the uh, Japanese, um, uh,
airport that they had
created and that is a,
it's an artificial island and an
artificial island they've created,
but there is slowly sinking into the sea.
So they have this elaborate
system of lifts that as it sinks,
they raise it up to keep it level.
It's fucking nuts to me.
What a marvel of engineering, you know,
what engineering is this a magnificent,
when you think about it,
it's, it's, it's incredible.
I love looking at engineering in nature
and comparing it to engineering made by
man and you see how they certain patterns
that that aligned and we, here we are,
we're like, oh, you know, we thought
of this. But then it's like, oh,
but matches this pattern that nature came
up with to realize is that a good idea
is a good idea.
Whether you came up with it blindly like
nature or whether you came up with it
consciously like, man, good idea's a
good idea. If it works, it works. That's,
that's what's amazing.
Have you ever seen when they take a,
a colony of leaf cutter ants and they
expose their entire underground structure
by filling it with cement technology,
they have their own technologies
yet that's their extended phenotype.
It's really kind of a fucking disturbing
thing to watch though because it's kind
of ant genocide. You're like looking at
me and eventually cemented everybody in.
It is very sad. I mean it's, uh, I
don't really give a fuck about ants,
but it's kind of crazy that
they're willing to just
cement the shit out of their
houses just to find out how
big the houses. Yeah. If
you haven't seen it folks,
you could just Google it. Uh, well what
does it Brian Leaf cutter ants. Just pull,
pull that video up because
it's astounding to look at.
Just pull up a leaf cutter,
ant colony exposed.
Um, and these, uh,
these scientists say they found out that
not only do they have these intricate
structures,
but they have events set up.
So where they bring in like a funguses and
things that are, that are, um, that are,
that are rotting. Yeah, there's
an ability for the, the, the,
the fucking gases to rise out through
the air pollute their little tunnels.
There's so much emergent
intelligence in the design,
but you know what the most amazing
part is? There's no one in control.
It's all decentralized.
It's all a bunch of individual local
interactions happening simultaneously that
together exhibit emergent
phenomenon and emergent complexity.
It's like bi Pi walls, tree
beehives, exhibit self,
organization that emerges when all these
billions of bees are working together
to create an intelligent behavior. But
no individual bee itself is intelligent.
That's amazing. Now they're saying
that our neurons are the same,
that we're not like a
singular consciousness,
but billions of non-intelligent neurons
that together create synchronous like
transcendent effects.
That a consciousness emerges from the
interactions of trillions of neurons,
individual,
local relationships happening in different
parts of the brain and then together
make sense. Our brains aren't
like the vigilante. Our brains,
our neurons are like the ant in the
ant colony and then us is the emergent
behavior. It's what comes out. Yeah.
I've always said that it's ridiculous
to think that human beings can ever be
separate because that's the worst thing
they could do to you in prison. Yeah.
The worst thing they could do to you in
prison as separate you from the general
population and put you in solitary.
Yeah. Nobody can talk to you.
You're just by yourself.
That's crazy for people. Yeah.
Well that is cutting your arm
off. Yes. It's, it's alien to our,
our goal and purpose and on our
desires on earth. 100% yeah.
So it's obvious that we are engineered
for a reason or at least for feedback.
Yeah. For Interaction, interaction
and feedback. Everything
is feedback loops, dude.
Everything. Well that's why these kind
of conversations, it's so exciting. Yes,
exactly. Cause you, you know, you, you,
you turned my brain into an area that
you know, might not have gone into. Like,
then we start expanding in that area.
There's a book by Matt Ridley called
the rational optimist and he coined the
word idea sex. And he says that ideas
coming together and open liquid networks,
open channels of communications are
akin to genetic recombination in nature.
It's genes being in the primordial soup,
mixing and completing each other,
interacting and good. It's all a
giant Al's happening with ideas. Yeah.
Ideas are intermingling and
having sex with one another,
but they're creating more change in at
a rate that is unheard of by the gene
pool. If we could look at
the interactions of, of,
of human behavior and
thought and language,
if we could look at all that
stuff as like numbers and,
and look at it as like energy and,
and,
and something that can be
quantified instead of looking
at it as our own product.
Yeah. And instead of looking at it
as something that we have done right,
if we could just look at it entirely
of its own and we will see a completely
different picture away. Well if you
take the long view and Caterpillar, man,
we're a caterpillar about
to become a butterfly.
We're making some crazy
fucking cocoon right now.
We don't even know what we're doing,
which just transform everything and
we just bought, we know it's possible.
Caterpillar's did it. Caterpillar's
do it. So you know it exists. It does.
It's not beyond the laws of physics
for completely have radical self
transformation.
You've
couldn't blow my mind again man.
You blew everybody's mind again.
This podcast, I essentially,
I got to think we should stop right
there cause that's about three hours.
Oh well that was crazy. Wasn't it? About
three hours. Somewhere in there. Yeah.
Two hours, 40 minutes or something like
that. Thanks again brother. Thank you man.
You're very, very stimulated. Soc Two
thanks. So it's one of those are you?
So are you guys these conversations
and it just, you know,
you walk out to drive home. Just going,
what the fuck man, thanks for having me,
man.
You're so awesome at uh,
like passionately and fusing these
ideas and other people's heads.
Thanks brother. You know, you, you
have like a, a way of uh, you know,
like when you get fired up
about shit, like everybody
around you is like, oh yeah,
yeah, yeah. Thanks man. It's infectious.
Very effective. Thanks brother.
And if people want to find you on Twitter,
it's Jason Underscore Silva if they
want to find you online. It is.
This is Jason silva.com and uh,
all of his upcoming lectures and all.
Is there anything that people can see,
like there are any places where are the
average person go and buy a ticket and
watch you perform live.
If the economist ideas festival happening
in Berkeley and March 28th is on
innovation and people can Google
economist ideas, anyone can go to that.
You can buy tickets for that and you
don't have to work at Google. Yes.
And a on April 20th, when I speak at the
national arts club, they have a website.
You should be able to look it up.
But I think it's about like dreaming
unlimited or something like that and then
all the New York
City mission is on.
This is Jason silva.com or tweet about
it all the time as the talks come up,
the PSFK conference in New York at
Battery Park on March 30th you can buy
tickets to,
I'm going to speaking at University
of Pennsylvania April 2nd actually.
Beautiful Fun. This class on psychedelics
and visionary arts and stuff.
Keep doing what you're doing on
it. Love it. It's very exciting.
Thank you everybody for
tuning into the podcast.
Thanks for all the positive tweets
and messages and w we loved you too.
Thanks for everybody who already bought
tickets for Atlanta April 20th it is.
The first show was pretty much sold out.
It will be when I record my next special,
so if you want to go,
there will be tickets to the second show
that will be available sometime this
week. Like I said, probably somewhere
around Wednesday and I got a lot,
a lot of other shit going on in the future
to Louisville, Kentucky. That's soon.
What does that Brian, any ideas? Then
me Vet Kentucky, the June, January,
March 30th through April 1st is
Louisville, Kentucky, and then, uh,
we're in Hermosa beach
is actually before that.
March 23rd and 24th at Hermosa Beach,
the comedy Magic Club,
one of my favorite clubs ever. And
uh, then for 20 in Atlanta for 20,
is what I'm going to do.
My special, it's so cliche.
It's so cliche as a corny pothead,
I couldn't,
couldn't resist a thank you
to the fleshlight for tuning
in and saving our souls
with their plastic vagina.
Does that work? No.
I need to come up with a new commercial.
Thank you to the fleshlight for being
there for lonely boys being easy.
Thank you for being, yeah, but not that
easy to clean it. A little complicated.
It's,
yeah,
you gotta you should at the end of
it should be like a garbage disposal.
It just eats loads and then turns it into
love and sends it out to the universe.
It's really easy. If you'd like to
sucker. I'm come out of it. So, oh Brian.
So not necessary. Jason Silvas
here. He's a serious man.
You don't need to do that in front of him.
And you fucking freak.
Thank you to [inaudible] Dot Com oh
and oh yeah. Oh, uh, what did I say?
A fleshlight entering the
code rogue and 15% off.
You already know that you heard the
first half of this fucking podcast.
Go to [inaudible] dot com enter into
Qa rogue and save 10% there. It's over.
It's done. Tomorrow we have Aubrey, Mike,
Marcus, uh, formerly known as the artist,
formerly known as Chris, who's our
friend who changed his fucking name.
That's how hard he tripped.
He went to a Peru Dude Iowasca and changed
his fucking name. You know, I have,
I have a friend who did that
to my friend the line. Yeah,
that Iowasca Oka fuck you up son.
And Aubrey just got back from Costa
Rica where he went through a series of
Ibogaine experience and now his
name is optimus prime. Yeah.
Now he's Mr Manhattan. And uh, we'll,
we'll get to meet him tomorrow and he's
going to explain to us what the fuck is
really going on with this
crazy universe we're living.
Everything that has not been covered
today will be covered tomorrow.
And then on Wednesday, we get
Matt from a hoarder's, uh,
is clutter cleaner on Twitter,
and he's the guy who cleans
up the crazy people's houses.
And I'm really fascinated by that because
I've got a bit of a hoarder in me.
Just a pinch. You do as well? Yeah. Yeah.
So we'll find out what that fucking
psychosis all about. Jason Silva,
you are the man, sir. You
are the man. Thank you guys.
You, everybody. We love you.
Dirty bitches.
Oh,
two shows this weekend in Pasadena because
I'm gearing up for my special freaks.
So, uh, this Friday and Saturday, Friday
night, what are we doing it Friday,
nine o'clock Saturday 10 30 ice house
comedy dot. Yes. And it's the annex.
It's a small room.
It always sells out in advance.
So if you want to get on this shit, a
icehouse comedy.com is that it? Yeah.
One Friday night at nine o'clock,
nine o'clock, 10 o'clock. Friday,
10 30 on Saturday. It's it
sober. God bless America. Jihad.
Okay.