MMM.
And we're live.
Dave Rubin.
What a time to be alive,
Joe.
I am so excited to be here because you
could have selected anybody.
I mean,
it ends tomorrow.
It does end tomorrow.
Supposedly.
Allegedly.
Unless,
uh,
maybe Jill Stein wins.
No,
no,
I'm talking about the world.
I mean it is over.
I don't mean the election.
I mean the whole game is up tomorrow.
You could have had anybody.
You,
you're a pretty powerful guy.
Powerful Joe Ryan.
Enjoy your company,
sir.
Well,
I appreciate that.
But you could think of all the
philosophers you could had the thinkers,
the artists,
too much work.
Instead,
you went with me for the last show,
so I'm going to bring it.
I already,
I have notes.
I busted out the notepad.
I believe that end of the world is
tomorrow.
So you're the preview to the end of the
world.
So I feel like you're going to offer
some pr.
Well,
hopefully.
What together we're going to offer some
perspective and a,
we're going to get a look at this thing.
Well,
I already pounded two of these bad boys,
so I am ready to this fucking thing of
270 milligrams of caffeine.
Well,
it sways in a small cans,
so I thought it was all right.
It seems like it seems small,
but if it was that much acid and think
about what we're doing to you,
you really have to think about it that
way.
Yeah.
I did acid once.
Only one time.
I did it once last week.
That did.
He really did.
It was awesome.
Yeah,
I've done it three times.
I only did it this year for the first
time,
but I've done it three times this year.
Really?
And you feel like all the doors,
the hinges of the brain,
there's still going because I don't
think we're any good at all before.
I think I'm going,
I'm out.
It's like cock for my brain.
Yeah.
I shrew many times.
You know,
over the years I did acid once,
did not like it at all.
I,
every time I closed my eyes and he's
like three dimensional triangle is
flying at me.
Like could not,
you know,
when you just can't stop your brain.
Like I felt that there was no end to it.
Shrooms until he's like very natural and
nice and pleasant.
Yeah.
The concern is the potency of,
of acid.
I hadn't heard it described by Terence
Mckenna as like molecularly,
if you looked at it in scale,
it's something the size of an ant that
can break down the empire state building
in 30 minutes.
That's a bit much for me at this point.
You know what I mean?
I,
I turned 40 this year.
I don't need to break down the empire
state building or any other building at
this point.
Now it's really about keeping the mental
faculties I have adding in a little more
occasionally going from there.
Yeah.
But you know what I mean?
You have to function right?
Like you have a show,
you're doing comedy,
all this stuff.
Like at some point the expansion of the
mind is like,
I still gotta be on earth.
You know,
if you got to do the show,
you definitely have to be there.
You have to be there.
But,
um,
Duncan and I did a show on acid.
We did our last podcast with full
disclosure.
We were on acid cheeses.
Yeah.
I'm sitting in a room sober with these
beans.
Well,
it's less is expected of me.
I think you,
you're expected to be rational.
But being a standup comedian slash cage
fighting commentator,
you get a lot of wiggle room.
Yeah.
You can,
you could,
you could say some pretty stupid shit.
People go.
Yeah,
that's right.
Probably got hit in the head.
Exactly.
Yeah,
exactly.
So you know,
obviously we're going to do election,
but I,
there's a couple updates so I haven't
been here in about a year,
a little more than a year.
A couple of things I want to tell you
first off.
So I got a house last week not too far
from here building a home studio.
I'm very excited.
Cool.
Might,
my fans are funding it,
which is amazing.
Oh,
a ton of stuff has happened since last,
but I told you last time that I would
know that I've hit a certain level of
success when I'm not sitting on an ikea
couch and did not have ikea stuff around
me everywhere.
Now,
I did bring all the Ikea stuff,
but I made one purchase for the new
house.
Only one purchase.
We've got a real couch.
I got a real couch.
That's nice.
I had a real couch.
I mean,
I'm talking people delivered it and I
didn't have to put it together.
It was act.
Did you?
I didn't even know that that was a thing
that they come put together.
Did you know that Kia stuff is bullshit.
If you just charge 10 bucks more and put
it together,
everybody would probably cost more than
10 bucks.
All right.
Isn't that the whole thing?
It costs more than 10 yeah.
If for them to put it together for you,
did they put it together for you?
Will they do that?
They will,
but it's going to be more than 10 bucks.
I don't even mind putting it together.
It was just time for me not to have to
put together furniture desks together
once and it's,
you know,
I was like,
I forgot it.
If it had an estimate of how much time
it took,
but it took me four fucking hours.
[inaudible]
answer.
Was this an acid situation?
That would be something different.
Shit.
Ikea assembly on acid.
I bet you do it better.
You know like talk Willis,
the guy who pitched a no hitter,
he was fucked up all day.
He was doing acid and then you got the
call and didn't know he's supposed to
play that day.
And it's like,
oh no,
they want me to play today.
He like got his shit together for good.
Just pitching.
Just imagine getting your shit together.
Getting there.
Just that in and of itself.
Well it depends on the guests,
your biological makeup,
how it hits you,
you know,
cause I know a lot of friends who just
can't smoke pot.
They just,
it just doesn't work with them.
And with me it works great.
It's my favorite.
What do you like indicators?
Sativa or hybrid?
I'm prefer sativa,
but if someone's passed around the end
to good joint,
I don't say no.
See,
all my comic friends like Sativa,
I like Endeca because for me at this
point,
and I guess this goes back to the doors
and the main thing,
like I don't want to think anymore if
I'm smoking,
I don't smoke pot to think or to write
or anything.
I smoke pot because it's 1130 at night
and I'm going to take one puff and watch
Seinfeld that I've seen 3000 times
already or simpsons that I've seen three
and that's it.
You know what I mean?
Like I don't need,
I don't smoke to like,
like all my concrete smoking,
right.
Or that.
And I'm like,
no.
So it's a decompressing.
Yeah.
Agent purely.
Purely.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
people get real wary when you started
talking about pot or acid or even
alcohol because there's a lot of people
that everyone knows that it's kind of
fucked her life up doing that.
But 35,000 people died driving every
year.
It doesn't stop us from driving,
you know?
I mean,
and obviously if you're doing acid,
most likely you're not going to kill
somebody else.
So it's the responsibility of driving
out of a window like a Helen Hunt did
that.
Did you ever see that inform word,
that kid's thing?
They showed it at my high school.
They showed it in high school.
How?
When I was growing up,
I think it was helen,
how you know which one I'm talking
about.
What they should know.
That education will video where they
showed these high school kids and it's
Helen Hunt.
It was like a 15 year old and she's on
acid and she jumped out a window and
breaks the window.
It just kills herself at school.
Fucking old Bill Hicks bit.
Remember that Bill Hicks,
bit young man on acid thought he could
fly,
jumps off the building.
What a tragedy goes.
What a Dick.
He thought he could fly.
What did he tried taking off from the
ground first and as we lost a moron,
man,
we need a hex.
Don't we need a hicks?
Every day I wake up and I go,
man,
I wish we had is still,
because we still,
you know,
obviously there's plenty of good comics
out there and there's so much,
there's such a plane,
this stuff to,
I don't need to see Helen Hunt to talk
about.
Um,
you know how many times that it's been
said before,
Hey,
a lot.
That's the best Paul Riser.
It's not his business card.
I think he wakes up in the middle.
I like,
what the hell was I talking about?
Acid?
No.
People dying.
No,
we moved on all the good comics.
There was something there.
Oh,
well one that,
just imagine what George Carlin would be
going through if he lived right now,
the politically correct age we live in.
If you took any of his old stuff,
he would be being attacked by all sides.
But dare I say he'd be hacked more by
the left these days for the shit that he
would be talking and saying about women
or about minorities or anything.
You know,
it's so,
it's such a shame the way things have
turned.
Well,
yeah,
he had some mean stuff that I think
like,
I remember this one bit that he had that
even at the time I was like,
whoa.
It was like anorexia and he's like,
dumb,
rich doesn't want Tucker,
but we need that now.
That's the point.
You know what I mean?
It's not,
he wasn't saying this specific girl who
may have anorexia that you're going to a
lot or died from anorexia and you heard
that you'd be like,
whoa man,
you would,
that would upset you at that moment.
And then you know what life goes on.
You know George Carlin,
there was one issue with Carlin and that
one issue was that he had a plan to do a
whole new hour every year.
And so he would put together this hour
and he didn't work out at comedy clubs
either.
He would just sort of write it and then
go and perform it and you know,
do little tweaks here and there,
but that doing that one hour every year,
like you don't have enough time to like,
you can't sit around and go,
hmm,
I wonder if this is a good bit,
you know,
I want to,
am I committed to this?
Cause I believe in it.
Like if I explored all the possibilities
and all the ways that this is going to
be interpreted,
is this the most effective way to convey
that idea?
But he was also so,
so loved and so awesome that he just
wanted to shock the shit out of people.
That was half of it was like he tired of
all this.
Talk about Anorexia and you know,
maybe if he was alive today and you were
talking to him about it,
he would,
he would change his opinion on that bit.
Yeah.
Look,
I'm sure if we went back in the however
many years you've been doing standup
there things that you've said there
probably that's probably not,
as you said last week.
Yeah.
But,
but we need that idea of people just
saying shit and letting it upset people
and other people are going to laugh at
it.
We so desperately need it now because it
has led the inability to do that these
days has led to everything that's
happening in our country right now.
What related to politics and media and
everything.
You're right,
there's a blow back,
right?
If you go too far left though,
the alt right emerges and I think the
more looney we get in terms of like
gender pronouns and that there's 58 now
it's 58 gender pronouns.
Yeah.
I didn't have to,
you know this morning I think the only
recognize 31 in New York that you could
be sued.
$250,000 for it.
Or you find if you pull it up,
it's fucking fiasco.
It's wonderful.
It's one going to look back at this and
laugh as long as you're not one of the
person who gets fined $250,000 and I
don't think anybody's ever been hit with
that yet.
I think that's more more like horse
shit.
But it's not even,
it's not even about the fine as much as
what it does to us as people.
Then it puts the idea in your mind,
look,
if I was walking down the street and I
saw a guy and I said,
hey,
how you doing man?
And then I realized it was a woman,
I would kind of feel bad.
But that's life.
That's life.
We're trying to through words and
trickery.
And now legal means we're trying to dumb
everyone down to the point that we can't
even think for ourselves.
If you look at somebody and you think
they're a man and you say,
dude,
that's not evil.
Right?
You know what I mean?
And,
and not every person that transitions
transitions perfectly and someone might
be in the middle of it or whatever and
you know,
or there might just be a guy who looks
like there's,
there's guys that look like women and
there's women that look like guys.
You know what's ironic about this is
it's not really a trans issue.
Cause you know,
talk to trans people.
Most women who transition to men want to
be called men.
And most men who transition to women
want to be called women.
Like they're there.
They assumed gender pronouns.
Like the guy who becomes a woman wants
to use he or once you,
she or her.
Right?
So it's not them.
It's just nonsense is what it is and
it's nonsense that comes out of
universities.
It's this weird Marxism thing that's
going on.
It's this very strange leftist bullying
because it's so deranged.
I went to,
I know you've had my on here and he's
become like this cultural thing.
It's like he's,
he's sort of become something beyond
himself at this point.
What's the streisand effect that keeps
silencing him and when you silence the
guy who,
first of all,
what they silenced him for was so
unwarranted because when you,
when you remove someone on twitter for
just a harmless joke that's very similar
to the jokes that Leslie Jones makes
about her own self.
You know,
she's got a
God damn commercial.
Yeah.
She pulls up a Geico commercial,
I think it is.
Well,
what does that,
what does that commercial was?
She pulls up to someone.
I don't know who it is,
what it is,
but she pulls up to a guy,
she's like,
do you want my number?
You guys who get the fuck out of here?
It's like an obvious joke about her
being unattractive.
She's perpetrating that joke.
That is what it is.
I mean,
if that's,
say if you do that same joke with,
you know,
fill in the blank.
What's a girl for Sofia Vergara or
something like that.
The joke doesn't work.
It's just hot as fuck.
And then the guy would be like,
but when Leslie Jones does it,
the reason why that joke works is
because they're implying that she's not
attractive.
So all Milo said is something about her
being a man or looking like a man or
something like that.
And that was enough.
Well,
what's particularly interesting about
what happened to him is that they
claimed,
I think when,
when twitter finally said a little
something about it,
that it was because if targeted
harassment that Milo had unleashed his
followers on her.
Now first off,
you're not.
You don't control all your followers.
You know what I mean?
If you got into a fight with somebody,
Joe Rogan got into a fight with somebody
on twitter,
uh,
you can't control what your followers
do.
And so that's number one.
Number two,
she,
she had done that before.
There are instances,
people had screen captured things where
she had gotten into fights with trollie
type people,
not public people and said,
guys,
get them.
So she had actually instigated mobs.
But it's okay for all the politically
correct reasons,
it's okay when she does it well not only
she had,
she'd done that,
she had said things about white people
specifically like white people,
you know,
and it was specifically mocking white
people are saying things about white
people where it's like you can't do that
the other way.
The,
you know,
there's this also this very bizarre
thing that people keep saying is that
black people can't be racist against
white people because racism only works
when someone's in a position of power.
Guess fucking what?
If you have millions of followers and
you're super famous and you say things
about,
you know,
any white person,
you have a position of power.
Not only does she have a position of
power,
but she think how much by doing,
by that fight happening,
she got more powerful her,
her star rose.
Yeah.
So by damaging free speech,
whether you like my lower,
not she,
she then elevated her own status.
I actually,
I've never interacted with her.
I've never even seen ghostbusters.
I don't,
I don't even watch this.
And now I don't even know what she's
really done or anything better.
But when the whole thing was going down,
I went to tweet at her to say,
come on my show.
I'd be,
I,
I like Milo buttom all that free speech.
I'd love to have you on.
She has me blocked.
She blowouts.
I Dunno.
It's like a mass block thing.
Maybe you block people associated with
Milo or something.
But the point is,
I have nothing.
I have nothing against her in any way.
We're just talking about this specific
thing and I was going to invite her on
my show and it's like,
well,
well you're a nice guy.
That's so cowardly.
It's so foolish.
I,
and I like Leslie.
I think she's funny as hell.
I think she's hilarious.
I even enjoyed her and ghostbusters
I'll,
although Milo is correct,
most of that movie,
it was a piece of shit.
Yeah.
I thought the movie started out really
funny,
but what he was saying was that it was
like,
it was a ridiculous feminist version of
ghostbusters where all the men are
complete buffoons and failures and all
the women saved the day.
And it just wasn't a good movie.
It wasn't well designed and it was sort
of a kind of a slap in the face to men.
And that was his whole commentary on it.
It was very eloquently written.
Maybe a little bit bitchy,
but that's his whole thing.
Yeah,
it wasn't,
it certainly wasn't targeted harassment.
It was a review of art will look,
the point is that even if he had been
harassing her and said,
guys,
get her first off,
but if he did do that,
I can understand them saying we don't
want our platform use for that.
Sure.
So that's up to their terms of service.
So I'm not,
so there's obviously a difference
between,
of course,
the First Amendment,
which is the government stopping you
from speaking of what a private company
can do.
Ironically though all these people on
the left that we're thrilled or had no
problem with Milo being banned,
they're the same people that want it to
force that Baker in Indiana to bake the
cake for the gay wedding.
So they're okay with private companies
doing things when it's the things that
they want them to do,
like get rid of,
uh,
a conservative,
right when they want it to force that
bay.
I'm gay,
married,
right?
So I wouldn't force that Baker to do it.
Why?
You know,
what's fucked up about,
why would I want the government?
Why would I want the government to say,
you have to do something with your
private business.
No,
I'll go to another fucking baker.
Of course.
And not only that,
that's,
that wasn't an organic situation.
They'd set that up.
They went specifically and targeted
bakers to try to make a case for this.
Right.
And then you went to a Christian Baker
and finally found one who said no,
and that was the one they went after.
You know,
I mean,
look,
I don't agree with that guy and not
being able to make that cake.
I feel like you shouldn't go and do
business at that guy's place.
And that's the kind of person he is.
But what they're doing is,
I like trying to target that guy.
But would you for,
would you want the government forced him
to do well?
I would think,
I think the market should dictate
whether or not someone does.
I mean,
I think alerting people is a good thing,
but having the government dictate to
these people have to make that case.
That's kind of,
that's kind of crazy.
So that's the,
that's what's happened to the left.
Basically.
The left has gone from liberalism using
logic and thinking and uh,
an information basically to make
decisions to inform your decisions.
And usually liberals err on the side of
the other.
So in this case they're trying to,
they think they're protecting the gaze
so that,
right.
Like we want days to get cakes where
everyone else gets cake.
So we're going to help the gays.
But what they've done is all they're
doing is expanding state power.
They're extending,
expanding control.
Let the market decide.
Sure you want to,
you want to use your free speech,
protest outside,
tweet about it.
It's,
they don't go there.
There's a baker to two blocks over goes,
especially if you're gay,
you know,
use your,
use your money wisely.
Support people that support your
community.
Of course,
that's a,
but that's a thing for everything.
That's for rude people.
That's for,
you know,
for assholes,
for people who are Shitty to you.
For people who are,
you know,
it's just for people who will rip you
off.
I mean,
it's kind of along the same lines.
Let the market decide,
let the market decide.
Of course,
if you don't like Joe Show,
you don't like Reuben's show.
You don't watch,
don't watch.
Tell people that you don't like it.
And that's quite all right,
but,
but don't try to shut us down.
Don't try to go to youtube and strike us
or whatever other thing there is.
But that's what the left
is doing this now.
And that's why I talk about the left all
the time because I have liberal and I'm
watching my guys band speakers,
I'm watching my guys d platform people.
I'm watching,
my guys tried to close restaurants and
it's like you're now you're moralizing
the same way you've mocked the
Christian,
right.
For All these years.
Yeah.
It's,
it's just,
it gets to a point where you,
you wonder if it's to swing back the
other way.
I've been saying for a while,
we'll find out tomorrow.
Yeah.
Right.
And that creates tomorrow.
I've been saying for a while that I
think Caitlyn Jenner created Donald
Trump.
Not really,
but it created this thing.
I mean,
I think there was a thing,
there was a tipping point.
And for me it was when they gave her
woman of the year and Glamour magazine
and then Espn has gave her ass a athlete
of the year.
And when we're that ridiculous thing
that they did where they circled or
House with the helicopter and she was
hiding behind the curtains and there was
all mysterious,
like,
what in the fuck are you selling?
What is this?
And for people at home that are like in
Indiana and they're drinking beer and
they like football and they went to
watch the sps to see,
you know,
like who won best quarterback in the
year?
And they're seeing that kind of shit.
They're like,
what the fuck is as we need a make
America great again.
You know,
I never linked it that specifically,
but I think you're totally right.
Even right now,
when I've been watching,
you know,
nba season just started and I love
basketball.
Every time I turn on TNT now it's
Barkley and Kenny Smith and Shaq and
Ernie Johnson talking about race.
They're not talking about basketball,
they're talking about race.
They're talking about policing.
Those are all important issues to talk
about.
But people go to sports for the release,
they go to sports because they care
about that leads and what's happening on
the field and in the,
in the boxing match or whatever it is.
And now everything is becoming
politicized.
So espn is giving their athlete of the
year to Caitlyn Jenner.
It makes no freaking sense.
Well that was the NFL ratings down.
You know,
it's because people are talking about
Kaepernick and politics instead of
sports.
Does that make the ratings go down?
Really is the ratings down.
The ratings are hugely down in the NFL
this year.
And a lot of people are linking that.
I don't know it empirically,
I wouldn't be shocked.
There's a lot of people in this country
just have zero tolerance.
I mean,
it's almost like separation of church
and state.
They would like their sports to just be
sports and about sports.
Yeah.
You know,
and I,
I kind of appreciate that in a certain
way because it's like if you were
watching a comedy show and all of a
sudden during that comedy show they
started deeply discussing religion,
like really like discussing deep
intricacies of different faith based
cultures.
You'd be like,
what the fuck am I want?
This is not comedy.
Right.
Do is funny.
Sure.
But once you heard that thing and now
you're doing something else right,
you're doing a different thing but
you're not doing sports.
You're doing,
you're doing race relations.
Are you doing?
But I don't understand that.
It's also,
they look at it as a platform for our
culture and that's what Kaepernick did.
He said,
look,
I have this platform.
And in some ways I think what he did
kind of worked because a lot of kids in
high school now are doing that.
They're taking knees and the national,
you know,
when they do the national anthem,
it's,
it's strange,
but it's also like the black,
uh,
when people have the black fist at
the Olympics,
when those dudes that did that and the
1960,
seventies,
I think it was 71,
[inaudible] 71,
something like that,
whatever that was.
I mean,
that got people talk and this gets
people talking to,
and maybe sometimes you need to kind of
inject some sort of something to think
about during sporting events.
I'm not,
again,
I'm not telling them not to do it.
Of course I would knit cabernet and
wants to do that.
Go ahead.
These guys,
if Barkley and all they want it,
if they're tnt bosses are okay with it
may go,
well,
you know,
you can do that.
Instead of talking about how many points
to ran head then,
so be it.
But I'm just saying what I think most
people want from sports is an escape.
And I can tell you for sure in the two
or three weeks at the NBA season,
it's been gone.
Every time I flipped by TNT and they're
doing that,
I change it where I used to.
I love those guys.
I think that show in many ways is an
incredible social experiment,
not just as a sports.
I don't know what the show is.
You know,
it's the after show on TNT where they'll
watch Barkley.
So it's Barkley who's obviously
completely outspoken and an incredible,
and Kenny Smith who also is in shack,
uh,
and,
and Ernie Johnson's the token white guy
in the white guys,
but they're all really great and their,
their rhythm with each other for four
guys to sit there and do it.
They've been doing it for probably 15
years.
Shacks newer to it.
But anyway,
uh,
I go to espn or tnt for sports and you
want to hear,
and there's so many to talk about in
sports.
It's all these players.
All these plays,
all these games,
so much is riding on each event.
Yeah.
So I'm not a grudging them any of the
legitimate things that you're talking
about.
Of course they,
the athletes can do whatever they want
to express themselves in any way.
But once that starts becoming more of
what you're talking about,
then the sports,
that's why people start tuning out.
Well again,
the market's decided right and if their
ratings go down because of this,
I guess maybe someone in the head office
will go,
hey guys,
what the fuck?
Right.
You know,
and that's how it should be.
I mean that's absolutely how it should
be.
Yeah,
it's,
it's a fascinating time and I think this
is a side effect of everyone having a
voice.
Cause we all have voices now.
You know what I mean?
This is the new world we live in.
The new world we live in is anyone can
broadcast,
anyone can get on periscope and just
start talking.
Anybody don't tell everybody that anyone
can.
Anyone can get on twitter and just make
a post about something.
I mean,
I've been telling my people,
I'm the only one that can do it.
You remember that woman?
What was her name again?
The woman who wrote the post about aids
on twitter.
I'm going to Africa.
Hope I don't get aids.
Lol.
Just kidding.
I'm white.
Yeah.
She was just a nobody pr person.
Nobody knew who she was before that.
I can't remember her name.
Justine Sacco,
right?
Yeah.
I think that's it.
Yeah,
but that,
that sort of event it was,
it's like that's the beginning.
It's the first pop of the colonel when
you start making popcorn and you hear
that first pop,
pop,
pop up,
blah blah,
blah.
We're culturally about to fucking Jiffy
pop the fuck out of this thing.
That's what's happening.
You're going nuts.
You know?
I remember when that sacco thing
happened and so basically she said that
she said that joke,
she gets on a plane,
she disappears for what,
eight 10 hours or something and then she
gets up late.
Her life is destroyed.
She has to leave her job,
blah blah,
blah.
She's publicly humiliated.
I remember and look,
I tweet all the time.
I love twitter and I love the way you
can communicate through it.
But I remember I didn't tweet anything
about it intentionally cause I was like,
wait a minute,
it's good for you,
please.
I was like,
wait,
wait.
Let me get this straight.
A woman who I've never heard of before
who's not a public person per se,
tweeted a bad joke,
basically really tasteless,
stupid thought.
Her life is going to be the short.
Why would I add to that?
So I really tried to make a conscious
decision to just be like,
you know,
and I do that now and again,
we're certain news things where I'm
like,
this one,
I'm going to sit out because we this
gang mentality like no one had,
you'd know you didn't know who that was
before.
Nobody knew who this woman was before.
But so one random person said something
that I didn't like,
we must destroy her.
So you're right,
it is.
That's the first pop and now they're,
these pops are happening all over the
place.
Which by the way,
is what I,
why I think what Peter Teal did with
Hogan and Gawker is fucking phenomenal.
I agree.
Nominal.
Right,
great.
Because there,
there's some,
there's some violent and aggressive
invasion of privacy that's going on with
companies that are trying to make a lot
of money by doing that.
And that's one of the things that a lot
of people thought about Gawker.
Yeah,
I'll do,
I did read an incredible piece on Gawker
from May,
I hate to say this about donald trump's
hair or they are investigating donald
trump's hair is a very expensive,
I read it and they had like a diagram of
showing how beers around and like that
there's an office in trump tower
does that.
That's one floor below his and the
office doesn't have any,
it doesn't have a website anymore.
And they've been doing this procedure
for like a long time.
Yeah.
And it's like they essentially,
they take a hair and then they,
they find whatever hairs you have and
they sort of tie this hair onto your
hair one hair at a time and it's like
some crazy eight hour procedure.
And the speculation is that the entire
business revolves around maintaining his
hair in that manner.
Now as someone who,
uh,
is bald,
his balls going to try to do thing
violently challenge hair transplants.
I went to the
big smile scar in the back of my head
from you chop out a piece of the back of
your head and they tried to put it up
front.
Yeah.
The way I described it as like they take
some people that are really healthy and
they move into a neighborhood where
everyone's dying.
That's funny.
Yeah.
Well I,
I was,
you know,
when I did it,
I was in my late twenties and I was,
I was just on television and I was
panicking because my hair was falling
out.
I was like,
Oh my God,
I'm just,
my career is just getting started and
I'm going to lose it all because I was
thinking very probably correctly that a
lot of my success is predicated on my
appearance.
And I was like,
if this goes like if I go bald,
I'm fucked.
They want had shaved heads back then in
the nineties either.
If they did,
it was very rare and a,
so I went through all this,
but it helped.
It definitely gave me like thicker hair,
but
it was too,
it was too much work and eventually I
realized like it's so pointless.
And then when I shaved my head it was
like the most freeing feeling.
I'll say I like it better like this.
If I,
if I had hair right now at fucking shave
it.
Yeah.
I mean I'm holding ground and I,
when I looked wonderful,
don't,
don't go hard on your hair,
but I used to have hair over here.
You know that that's what happens is as
you age.
But I know for sure there were times in
my life when I was very stressed and I'm
not kidding you.
I could feel it.
Could you feel it when you were,
when you were losing hair,
could you feel it at times coming out?
Not like a,
almost like a,
not literally like each individual
thing,
but almost like a,
I could feel my tension there basically.
And as I,
that was just psychological.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Maybe your hair is completely connected
to your emotions.
Maybe you're one of them.
That's why I don't smoke pot anywhere
cause that's what I would think about.
I smoked pot and go,
wait a minute,
what's going on up there?
You know,
railing,
kind of,
yeah.
That's the,
that's the rub on the pot.
Right?
But it's fucking with you.
Yeah,
exactly.
Just comes to this.
That's why I like the Sativa Endeca.
I like pop for that reason though to go
to fucking with me.
I don't know.
It's like that old joke that Kennison
used to have about a,
they say every man's got a homosexual
fantasy.
He goes,
oh,
I'm sitting around the other day.
Go on through my fantasies.
Because if there's one on there,
I want to know.
I want to know about it.
Did you find yours?
I didn't have one.
So sorry for your people.
So when you see someone that is shaved,
that feels good about it,
as you said,
it's like a burning off all the time of
the dudes are struggling.
I'm like,
just shave your fucking head so that,
doesn't trump seem doubly ridiculous to
you in a certain way?
Well,
he's more than doubly ridiculous.
He's ridiculous.
In a million different wines just on the
hair front.
Really.
I mean that's cliche so we don't have to
spend too much time talking about,
but doesn't that like if someone who
shaved your head,
you feel good about it,
that he does this thing,
this whatever the fuck he did.
He always says it's my hair,
it's my hair.
Which is sort of a cop cause yeah,
they're probably doing something by
Harris.
Yeah.
But doesn't it seem doubly ridiculous?
And to someone like you like knowing
that you shaved and you feel good and
life goes on and then I get it from a
psychological standpoint,
I get it also is a person who likes to
have control of their life.
You know,
like you,
you feel like that's one thing that
really freaks people out about their
hair,
but it's like features and an appearance
is very bizarre.
Right.
Cause I know this woman who recently got
a nose job and uh,
she's beautiful and she decided that she
didn't like her nose and she got like a
little bit trimmed off.
It's kind of crazy,
right?
Yeah.
But there's a weird thing where people
decide that if my nose was one eighth of
a millimeter smaller,
I would feel better about myself.
I would feel better about my appearance.
But I've met people that have big noses.
No,
she doesn't look any better.
She looked great before.
She looks great now.
It's just a weird thing that people do.
They fixate.
But what I was going to get at is it's
really strange,
like what we decide looks good,
you know?
And that it's cultural and a lot of ways
because if you go to something like,
how bout those think it's Sir Siri women
who decide,
put those giant plates
in their lips.
Yeah.
And the bigger the plate,
the more cattle they're worth when they
get married.
There's like fucking really bizarre
cultures.
And it's an example of how human beings
when isolated for whatever reason,
what I mean,
there's scar scarf,
vacation rituals that many cultures go
through with a cut pieces out of their
skin to appear to look like crocodiles.
And you're seeing that where they do
their backs then do it.
Yeah.
They cut these chunks out of their back
and then they develop these keloid scars
that pop up and they see if you could
find that Janet men with crocodiles
scarring.
But it's,
there's so many different scarf,
vacation rituals,
and look at me,
I'm covered in tattoos.
There's like weird things that people do
to their body and weird appearances that
people choose to enjoy or not enjoy it.
And it just gets,
it gets very bizarre.
Like,
what the fuck is hair?
Why is that guy's back?
Oh Man.
Oh,
I have seen that.
Crazy.
Yeah,
and they just,
they cover their entire back with this,
that it makes it look like,
like a crocodile skin.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
joy bay heart used to say a phrase on,
on the view,
dare I quote the view,
but joy bay,
how are you saying that?
I always thought it was great.
It was really simple.
She usually,
they just say it's an inside job,
that everything really is just an inside
job.
So if you're walking around,
your friends walking around and she
thinks that this little,
you're a beautiful woman,
but she thinks this little millimeters
so it bothers her.
For some reason it's an inside job.
Now she may still have that same
insecurity after,
or maybe she exercised it,
you know?
Or maybe it actually did do what it was
supposed to do.
But most of us are walking around the
ship that we're walking around with is
just an inside job and it's your,
it's your job as a human to to exercise
that stuff.
And that's,
I mean,
I try to do it every day that that's
what you're trying to get better is all
about.
And then we fail at it constantly.
I fail every day.
But there's also like a certain amount
of you that should be upset with the way
you look so that you force yourself to
go to the gym and he keeps you healthy.
That'll west Hollywood.
We talked about this last time I was
here.
You know where every guy is,
but they're disgusting,
but they're actually disgusting.
Yeah.
How so?
Because they're just fucking each other
in the street cause they're not dogs
because you don't want to go to the
steam room.
I don't know.
I just left.
I lived in West Hollywood for three
years.
I never,
I went to the Locker Room in that gym,
24 hour fitness once cause I had to pee
so bad as Hollywood is the one I always
talk about.
My friend used to be the manager there.
I used to go to the 24 hour bastard.
I used to go to the 24 hour fitness and
woodland hills and there was a guy that
worked there that was my friend who was
a manager.
They sent him over,
he was at another 24 hour fitness but he
was like a really good well organized
guy,
well liked and they sent him to West
Hollywood to clean up and he said he got
there and dudes were just gone at it in
the sauna and they would have to mop it
down.
He said it was insane.
He said it was basically just a gay
hookup spot.
The whole
frankly is disgusting.
I made it really real,
but beyond just like that,
just the sex or whatever,
this idea that you have to look perfect
and there's never enough.
And that's why for me it's like that's
why gay marriage was so important.
Not because of the weather you want to
get married,
not is irrelevant.
But the idea that all these people that
could never get married,
they had to stay in the rat race
forever.
Imagine that if you always felt like you
had to stay in the rat race because the
same equality of being in a relationship
that was sanctioned by the state,
as silly as that may all be in at some
level,
but the idea that you just had to stay
in this race forever and then one day
you're 50 and you're trying to look like
you're 20 because you're still in that
race because you never found someone,
whether it's a guy or a girl or
whatever,
that you can start,
you know,
maturing into some other thing with.
Yeah.
And that's why your quality was
important.
Marriage.
Equality was important to me,
not whether someone actually gets
married and Milo and I have great
debates on this.
Um,
but that you got to get out cause
there's nothing sadder than,
than those people that never stopped
to you on the outside.
But if those people are on
antidepressants and cocaine,
they might be having a great time,
but maybe they're happier than me.
Hash the expendable income.
Yeah,
they got her hair plugs and there 10
beyond imagining they look good.
I'm not saying they don't look it,
but actually they don't look that good
because their muscles are too big.
You know,
they all just,
the shirts are too tight.
Like it's like settle down everybody.
Yeah.
Well there's,
there's a lot of that going on.
I,
you know,
I used to work out at Gold's gym on
coal,
which is,
uh,
you know where that is in West
Hollywood.
It's like right down the street from
sunset and Gower Studios.
We used to do news radio at sunset and
so there was a gold's gym down the
street and I'm like,
oh well I'll just make a membership
there that way over at lunch I can just
shoot over,
get a workout in real quick and get by.
Because I had just gotten used to like
set life,
like life on the set,
on a new sitcom,
you're working at a minimum.
If those sitcoms not going well,
like Newsradio wasn't really going well
in terms of like we're trying to find
its legs in the early days and we would
work 1214 hours a day and it was really
hard to do stand up at night and it was
really hard to work out.
I was like,
God damn man.
And same with like my hair.
I was like,
shit,
I got to stay in shape.
You know,
like there's a lot of scenes on news
radio where I had to take my shirt off.
That was like a kind of a part of who I
was.
I don't want him to replace me.
I better fucking keep going to the gym
and pus on vein.
So anyway,
I went over to this gold's gym and I
didn't know that that was exactly like
the 24 hour fitness West Hollywood.
It was just a gay disco.
I used to feel like a tasty little
morsel and a big homos.
I would walk in there like a wounded
antelope trailing up to the waterhole
and there was all these dudes with like
scrunchy socks,
like from fucking Olivia Newton,
John,
let's get physical and they would have
timberlands on and cutoff Jimmy's we'll
wearing animals.
It just fucking big yoked up,
steroid up dudes just gay or than the
day is long.
It was a,
it was,
it was interesting because it made me
feel like what it must feel like to be a
woman who's not interested in getting
hit.
Who goes to
the gym.
Yeah.
Well when I first moved to West
Hollywood,
I first was intimidated by it because I
was like,
you know,
I'm at this gym with all these like huge
muscly,
whatever.
And then as time went on,
I started enjoying it because I was
like,
this is actually ridiculous.
It really is a comedy.
So if you take it just at that,
which that's the level you are taking it
out,
you walk in there and go look at this
idiot and timber who worked out in
timberlands.
Right?
But you're not kidding.
They actually do with Jean shorts.
It's like,
what are you building a log cabin or
working out like spending,
they're sending rather a very clear
message.
They're looking for some Dick and this
is how you get it with Timberland's.
Throw that flag up.
Timberland,
the daisy dukes are important.
There's no,
there's no like subtlety and daisy
Dukes,
daisy dukes on whether you're a guy or a
girl.
You're looking for Dick,
right?
Well,
the universal flag of,
I'm looking for Dick,
I got to get some new shorts.
Daisy did something about the daisy
Dukes,
right?
Like,
and when guys started adopt them,
it's like,
whoa,
all right buddy.
But that's,
that all goes to like,
nobody cares.
Like all of this stuff about,
what are we talking about?
Gay Marriage or any of the stuff.
It's like enough already.
It's there.
It exists.
Like plot support,
I should say.
We want to say one thing.
I support you doing whatever the fuck
you want to do.
If you want to wear a daisy dukes and
fuck a bunch of dudes who cares,
go have fun.
This is,
this is a short experience.
I'm 49 years old,
so I'm almost 50 which is if everything
goes great,
I'm halfway dead and it's probably not
going to go that great.
All the accident pot and all that jazz.
I have a little faith in some of the
robotics that are coming in,
some of the gene stuff,
but I mean realistically I don't want to
plan on that.
And then I also got some dose,
so you're on the good side of it,
but on the good side of it,
but there's also issues like fucking
asteroids,
supervolcanoes Zombie invasion,
alien attack.
Who knows what the fuck's going to go
down in the next couple of decades.
But yeah,
my point is this is a short ride.
It's not that long.
It seems like it's a long time when
you're young,
because when you're 22 you look at 81
god,
it's so far away.
But when you're 50 and you look at 80
like Yo,
that's around the corner a year is not
that long.
It just seems long when you've only gone
through 20 of them in your whole life,
you're like,
wow,
it's so long here.
I can't wait until I'm 21 you know?
And then all the sudden you look back
and you go,
oh,
this thing happened in the blink of an
eye.
My from 30 to 40 which I turned this
year went so fast.
I mean I,
I remember my 30th birthday and I
remember thinking wow,
and now like I'm not a kid anymore.
Like,
cause I,
you can push it into your twenties
right?
You can get through your 20s and still
think you're somehow not an adult maybe
or but 30 then you go,
well shit,
now I'm kind of,
and now it's like wow,
I just turned 40 and it's like now it's
like this is real.
This is really real.
You're in now.
And I think the key is to not even
concentrate on that,
to be aware of it,
to recognize it,
to address it,
but just to concentrate on,
and this is such a fucking cliche
statement,
but I tried to say it as much as
possible,
living in the moment,
just being here in the taking care of
your
biology,
you know,
respect your meet vehicle,
take care of that thing,
but try to enjoy this thing and live in
the moment.
And the more you don't live in the
moment,
the more you get caught up in bullshit,
the more it gets away from you.
And then anxiety and nonsense and all
this stupidity and that kind of goes
back to trump with his fucking wacky
hair like you not living in the moment.
If you're a 70 year old guy and you're
spraying your hair down with a fucking
gallon of aquanet before you go out and
everybody knows what you're doing,
everybody knows what you're doing.
That's the piece.
It's like everyone knows some shame,
that fucking head,
you're worth $18 billion,
whatever the hell he's,
maybe he's not really worth that much.
Right?
There's nothing we have no freaking clue
I'd like to do with them.
Come on and do it.
I'll do it.
He did that today.
Imagine if he did it today,
one day before the election he went in a
landslide.
He would get there would be such
positive real towards him.
Like you guys would go,
he's wonderful.
Larry.
David would endorse him.
I mean it would be huge.
Well,
I'm curious as to the backlash against
trump,
not the current backlash against trump,
but when it's going to come from other
people because people,
when whenever someone is perceived to be
a bully,
whether he is or not,
you can make your own choice decision
about that.
But I think he is and a lot of people
think he is and I think that's also
probably one of the reasons why he's
been so successful is because he's so
ruthlessly competitive and he thinks of
himself so highly and those sorts of
traits like narcissistic,
narcissistic traits are oftentimes very
prevalent.
And people that are successful in
business,
like really successful like he is when
he puts his name on everything and he's
branded everything and everything's
trump this and trump that.
He has no notion whatsoever staying low
key.
Well w when you fight against like he's
really mad at Alec Baldwin on Snl for
doing what I think is hilarious and
very,
it's,
it's really well done.
Like that thing that they do grab him by
the Bougie,
you know,
he does that.
Alec Baldwin,
his best work I think since fucking
beetle juice.
Yeah.
Right.
Well what is the one,
the one glengarry Glen Ross,
probably his best work since the coffee
is for closers line has been this shit.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's funny and he gets angry.
Like Jon Stewart did a bit,
he was doing this,
uh,
um,
stand up for veterans for some sort of a
benefit and he did this bit where he
started reading off these twitter
exchanges between him and Donald Trump
that Donald Trump just started tweeting
at him in the,
in the middle of the night,
like a tweet from one 30 in the morning.
Have you seen this?
Uh,
I mean,
uh,
probably have seen some of the brand
new,
it's brand new,
this standup bit.
Oh,
you should watch.
No,
I haven't seen it.
So let's pull it up,
Jamie,
because I,
I think Jon Stewart,
I think we could actually play this
unused.
I'm friends with John Stewart.
I'm sure he would let us play it cause
it's,
I think he'd also agree that this is
kind of important.
Like it just shows you,
it's not whether or not Donald Trump's
conservative approach and make America
great again and not letting in terrorist
and all that stuff.
All the things you may or not agree
with.
We're just talking about from a
psychological standpoint,
from looking at him as a human being.
Like there's,
there's some thing off here.
There's something incorrect about his
thinking.
Well that's,
you're hitting a lot of the,
a lot of this stuff.
So we can look,
let's,
let's watch this because it's pretty
fucking funny
to find out somebody was tweeting weird
shit about me.
Okay.
So on April 24 2013 at 11:00 AM someone
comes into my office and says,
Donald Trump just tweeted,
I promise you I'm much smarter than
Jonathan Leibowitz.
I mean,
Jon Stewart,
who by the way is totally overrated.
Okay,
now I'm going to say something to you.
This is real,
okay.
And I don't necessarily disagree with
it.
Okay?
So,
so I said,
as you might say to yourself,
what the fuck is that about?
Okay,
so we're not quite sure.
We can't quite figure it out.
So
a couple of days later,
he tweets,
as I've said many times before,
Jon Stewart is highly overrated.
Okay?
I swear this is true.
He tweets again if John Stewart is so
above it all and legit,
why did he change his name from Jonathan
Liebowitz?
He should be proud of his heritage.
Yeah,
that,
that guy wants to be president.
Okay,
hold on,
let me keep going.
Okay.
Then he tweeted,
Jon Stewart,
he's a total phony.
He should cherish his past,
not run from it.
So I start to think to myself like,
Oh,
I think this guy's trying to let people
know I'm a Jew.
And I think to myself like does it my
face to do that.
Okay.
Honestly,
like where have you seen this face other
than a poster for Yentl,
right,
right.
What world are people like Stewart?
That's a Scottish name,
but there's something about that fella.
Okay.
That looks a little shmear.
Yeah.
It wouldn't be funny if it wasn't so
toxically fucking crude and horrible,
but so I decided to tweet back at him.
Have any people don't know this,
but donald trump's real name is fuckface
von clown stay.
Okay.
I wish you would embrace the fon plows
stick.
Yeah.
Awesome.
You remember by the way,
Lincoln used to get into this shit
all the time.
I swear to God this is true.
The man who will more than likely given
the FBI's preference be our next
president then tweeted
amazing how the haters and losers keep
tweeting the name fuckface von Karman.
Right.
They are so original and like no one
else is doing.
What happened is it turned out a lot of
people on twitter picked up on the name
fuck face and started tweeting at it.
Then you tweets.
What's funny about the name?
Fuck facebook.
Okay.
It was not coined by John Liebowitz
stole it from a moron on twitter,
so I do back.
We seem to have hit a fuckface von
nerves today.
Silence
radio silence.
Four days later,
I shit you not
perhaps the next president of the
greatest country in the world at one 30
in the mall.
Morning
tweeted little Jon Stewart is a pussy.
Okay.
Hopeless in a debate with me.
Vote wisely this November.
Well that that line at the end.
Yeah,
really says it all right there,
but wisely this November,
because this is where we're at now and
Jon Stewart is a pussy,
is that that speaks volumes too.
Like who fucking tweet?
Something like that.
Who's what?
Seven year old tweet,
something like that was running for
President John.
I'm going to do something.
It's very difficult right now.
Oh,
I'm going to try to defend Donald Trump
for a second on this,
which is he is using the system against
itself.
So he's using the trolling tactics.
He knew what,
what is his ultimately?
Yes.
That's all insane.
That's all completely,
utterly insane.
Strange like antisemetic dog whistling.
Although it's as if John Stewart hiding
the fact that he's Jewish.
It talks about being Jewish everyday.
Like there's so much bizarre lunacy in
there in the comments,
but what my best defense of him is not
that he look,
the guy's obviously a narcissist.
He obviously has some sort of
personality disorder and all kinds of
other shit and and shady business
practices and we don't know the taxes
and all that stuff.
The defense I can give of him is that
he's using the system against itself.
So all of this corrupt media bullshit,
all of this political correctness,
all of this,
the outrage culture,
all the stuff we've been talking about,
he purposely does it just to keep his
name out there.
So these idiots,
these,
the lapdog media just keeps giving him
free attention.
And then by giving him free attention,
he doesn't have to spend the money,
but all the other candidates do.
Hillary's outspending him.
I don't know what the numbers are,
but I bet you it's something like 20 to
one and it's like he's just using it.
So does he believe any of this stuff
he's saying and is that morally wrong
and ethically gross?
Sure.
But he's just using the system.
And I think,
you know,
when people are saying,
well,
you know,
if it had only been rubio and although a
lot of Democrats,
whenever we'd only been rubio or Romney
or Jeb Bush,
it would have been so much better.
All the shit,
whether they're calling him anti women
are anti gay or Antioch,
they would have been saying it about
them too because they did it.
I mean,
remember what they were saying about
Romney four years ago,
he had binders of women,
he hates women,
he hates him.
Or like I would probably vote for Romney
at this point.
He did say binders of women.
Right.
But it was just,
they took it out of context.
There's a talking point.
I mean that's what politics is all
about.
What's important to know?
First of all,
I agree with you and I think his use of
really ridiculous statements and stuff
is brilliant because he does force the
media to report on some of the things he
says.
But that was 2013 he was running for
president then,
right?
No.
So he,
he has always used it for his own
purposes just to keep his own celebrity
out there.
Right.
So everything he's done from,
from any point that I can remember him
from in the 80s to forward has been to
further his own brand,
his own empire,
his own money,
all of that stuff.
And now he's just,
he's doing exactly what the media has
demanded in a weird way.
You know,
like the media doesn't even wait for us
to get outraged anymore.
They,
they're sitting there,
all of these people at all of these,
you know,
daily beast,
all these sites that somehow we're all
considered legit and nothing personal
against daily beast.
I'm just picking one,
but like they're literally just waiting
for him to tweet so that they can write
the article about the outrage that the
tweet,
because they don't even wait for us to
be outraged.
They just start.
So it's like he's just feeding them.
He's feeding the monster.
Knowing it keeps getting more clicks.
The more clicks and views he gets,
the more they'll want to talk about him.
The more money it makes,
the networks.
It's like he really is just,
he's just playing the game really well.
He's playing the game brilliantly.
I mean he's a great,
he'll,
he does a great job at it.
Yeah.
Look,
he loves wrestling.
I mean he used to do stuff with the WWF
b because he gets that and that's what
people are missing here.
So we can talk all about all the
policies and whether he actually has a
personality
disorder and all that.
But in terms of the tactics,
he's just doing it.
He's just,
um,
they invited me to go on celebrity
apprentice back when we did the second
version of fear factor,
which I guess was like 2011 or 12 or
something like that.
I forget what year it was and I should
have done it.
I didn't want to do it cause I would
have had to move to New York for like
three months.
Right.
But my family was down when they are
like,
let's do it.
And I was like,
all right,
maybe fuck that.
I do that.
I'm like,
I don't know.
It's just this,
I don't like shit.
I don't like showers.
You know,
I don't,
maybe if it was a show that I've watched
and joy,
but I'd never watched it,
but I wish I did now because I wanted
it.
I would love to have some insight.
I love to be around that guy and pick
his brain because Jeff Ross was around
him when they roasted him for comedy
central and he said the guy was very
reasonable.
And this is when they roasted him.
He like,
he signed up for the roast and Jeff had
a conversation with him.
He's like,
you know,
when they turn to you and they're saying
jokes about you,
you should laugh because it looks bad if
you're just sitting there like you're
upset,
like,
or make you look better if you like.
He's like,
you're right.
Like he like,
he seemed very reasonable.
I think there's something about,
he's very concerned with perception,
hence the hair,
right?
Like he's very concerned with control.
It's very concerned with all these
different things.
So like in a lot of ways,
this is sort of a psychological profile
as much as it is a presidential race.
It's like we're watching two different
people that are extremely flawed.
Like she is not honest.
She,
Hillary Clinton is a very,
very dishonest person.
There's an incredible amount of data to
point that she is incredibly dishonest.
Whether it's dishonest about the Clinton
Foundation,
dishonest about the emails,
dishonest,
completely about Bengazi.
Do you remember when they were trying to
say Bengazi was all in response to a
youtube video,
which she knew it wasn't the proven
yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
And it's,
it's very,
very disturbing when you consider the
fact that it's not,
that's not,
it doesn't disqualify you from running
the government.
It doesn't like if you're going to have
someone who represents the people of,
you know,
as John Stuart said,
and I agree the greatest country in the
world,
you should have someone who's honest.
And he look,
even Barack Obama's turned out through
these wikileaks,
um,
uh,
releases that he lied about not knowing
that Valerie Clinton had that email
server.
Yeah.
He had,
you know,
he had commented on it and he had
emailed her on it.
So that's not true.
So it's,
the whole thing is very,
very sorted in many,
many,
many ways.
And you know,
Gary Johnson keeps fucking out.
I've had him on the podcast before and I
enjoyed them.
I liked talking to him,
but how do you not know what Aleppo is?
I didn't know where to Aleppo the way,
but I knew what was going on in Syria,
but I didn't know the name of the city
that was getting bombed.
Sure.
And of course,
look,
the media is disingenuous when they,
when they find that Aleppo moment with
Gary Johnson and suddenly that's the
lead story all over the place or for 24
hours,
it's all over twitter cause it's like
you guys ignored everything he says.
So now he screwed up once and now that's
the way you discredit him.
So I've had Gary Johnson on my show,
so I chatted with him.
Uh,
he was going on Larry King when I was
over at or,
and we had about a half hour before
we went on air in the green room.
The guy is,
he's a perfectly decent,
lovely human being.
He's not dumb.
He is a nice guy.
I would,
I would love to smoke pot with them and
go skiing.
But like,
but like,
but that said in August,
I did a video on my channel where I
said,
I will support this guy to get to 15% to
get him in the,
in the debates because we,
whether you like him or not,
we desperately need another voice.
Talk about limited government,
talk about why uh,
taxes should be low or whatever it is.
Now.
I failed at that.
Obviously I tried but from that point,
from about mid August to the debate,
he had about 10 horrific moments.
Like I actually think as much as I like
him personally,
he's done the libertarians,
uh,
and in a certain way the country a major
disservice by being so ill prepared for
this.
So many people would have been excited
to have heard an actual imagine if there
was a libertarian right now obviously
he's not going to win like a Ross Perot
type character,
Ross Perot type or just someone who had
a certain command of the issues because
Gary,
he's googling all of the reasons that we
like him,
but he's kind of goofy and silly and you
know,
he stammers a lot and he speaks in a
funny way in his body.
Language is kind of,
you know,
slide in a slippery or I dunno,
but the point is,
this was the year if there were,
if we're ever going to have a third
party,
a third choice,
something like that.
This was the year where it could have
made a real dent the way Ross Perot did.
And Gary could have,
it should have been the libertarian
candidate more than,
uh,
Jill Stein,
I think.
But Gary just at every opportunity to
show that he knows what he's doing can,
can speak clearly about the issues he
failed.
You know,
he's not,
he's for having the government forced
the India,
Indiana,
uh,
Baker to bake the cake.
Did you not?
He's a libertarian.
So a lot of these,
forcing them to bake a cake.
Yeah.
So,
so he isn't even a great,
but I even said this in my video.
I said,
look,
the guy's not a great libertarian.
I don't think he's a great candidate.
He was a republican and he wouldn't get
in New Mexico.
He was a republican and he was a good
two term governor.
Bill Weld,
by the way.
Yeah.
This is running mate,
who's the former governor of
Massachusetts.
Yeah.
So if they're both decent fellows,
you know what I mean?
They're both decent fellows and maybe
that's just not what makes you the
president.
But this was,
they missed a huge opportunity.
Imagine if there just been a well-spoken
libertarian who could just have elicited
what the points of libertarianism is.
I think it would look,
it's not going to flip the election,
but it could have done something and,
and I think he was the wrong guy.
It's a dirty business,
you know?
And that's one of the reasons why
Hillary Clinton is good at it.
She's a dirty person.
Yeah,
I mean I say that with no ill will.
I mean I don't hate that lady.
What she does is dirty.
And if you look at what the DNC did to
Bernie Sanders,
that's dirty and what she did,
as soon as that woman got fired from the
DNC,
she hires her immediately.
I mean it's so incredibly transparent.
So think how corrupt really how corrupt
this is.
And this is again why I talk about the
left a lot because they need to call out
their side.
We will be very,
it would be very easy for us,
for us to sit here and just mock the
right the whole time and we can get
further into trump and mock the shit out
him and talk about problem is,
I don't believe in a left and a right.
No,
I don't either,
but I'm just within the way we have to
sort of frame the discussions,
you know what I mean?
Like,
yeah,
the labels,
they're all ridiculous at this point.
But think about how corrupt the DNC is.
Debbie Wasserman Schultz was the head of
the DNC.
They find out she's rigging it for
Hillary.
She steps down in shame,
literally the same day or the next day.
She,
then we'll start same day she starts
working for the Hillary campaign.
Then Donna Brazil,
who's a,
who's a democratic super delegate,
right?
She's a democratic,
super dope.
Who CNN had on is a contributor as if
she could possibly give you any,
uh,
you know,
remotely honest answer on anything.
She then becomes the head of the DNC and
then now it's of course come out on Wiki
leaks in the last week that she was
feeding Hillary questions for the
debates so it,
so you may hate the Republicans for all
the,
all your fans out there that hate the
Republicans.
You still got to acknowledge that there
is something deeply,
deeply corrupt with the Democrats and
Hillary.
Hillary's the head of that simply simply
put deeply corrupt against Bernie
Sanders who's also a democrat.
It's like what?
What Hillary Clinton is is a hustler and
she knows how to put it all together and
she's got,
and the both of the Clintons,
they're hustlers,
they keep these people close to them and
they,
they make sure that everyone is taken
care of.
Whether it's people from other countries
that donate money to the Clinton can
foundation,
whether it's all these different people,
like when you know,
when she hired that woman for her
campaign,
that's not unusual like standard
operational procedure for the Clinton
campaign.
It's like how she's conducted business
and it's,
that's what we don't like about
politics.
What we don't like about politics is the
cronyism and the established roots that
they have developed over 30 plus years
in government.
So that's what's happening right now is
that because of wikileaks,
we're starting to see how the sausage is
made.
It's not just a theory anymore.
So for the last couple of years where,
where a lot of online people would be
screaming about the government's
corrupt,
the media is in bed with them,
you know,
they,
they are pitching softball interview.
So well now we're seeing that it's
actually true.
Like there's actual evidence in email
saying yeah,
give softball stories too easy.
Reporters at the New York Times don't
talk to this person,
you know,
Blah Blah Blah.
We're seeing all of it now and it's
coming to a head and then you throw
trump into it and you throw trolling and
internet culture and you get all of that
going.
And back to that popcorn that we started
with now it's all bubbling at once and
you know,
it all comes down to tomorrow.
And I also think there's waves of this
stuff.
There's waves of outrage and then the
people sort of get resigned to it all
because they get their own life calls.
You know,
like if you really wanted to delve deep
into the Clintons or delve deep into
trump and just that would absorb every
second of your day for decades really,
really would with both of those guys.
And you've got to live and it's always
been like that.
Do you remember Jeff Gannon?
Do you remember who he is?
It sounds familiar.
Gimme a little shop again and was a
embedded reporter in the White House who
actually spent time sleeping at the
White House.
He had slept in the White House and more
than one occasion,
and this was during the Bush
administration,
and he would ask the most ridiculous
questions that you would never think
that a reporter would ask.
Like,
uh,
like mister president,
when are the Democrats going to wake up
and come to their senses?
It's like those kind of questions,
like just completely ridiculous leading
questions.
Complete softballs.
Yeah.
Well,
it turned out that he,
this is like when the Internet was just
starting to emerge,
right?
It was during the Bush administration.
It turned out that he was a gay escort
and he ran an all military gay escort
service any more like fucking dog tags
and a towel over his dick.
And he was straddled on the ground with
combat boots on his,
in his online ad that I've seen him at
24 hour fitness.
And he's the manager that's the guy with
the mop.
So they realize that this fucking guy
was,
I mean this was how they got,
I mean,
this is how they got the questions that
they want to be asked and presented the,
you know,
the narrative that they wanted to push.
But this has always been the case.
He's always been ridiculous.
People who are almost like vampire
familiars who stay close to the master
and so they want to,
you know,
in one way or another,
feed off of whatever power that he has
and,
and capitalize on it,
whether it's Debbie Wasserman Schultz,
whether it's,
you know,
what does a woman's name that's the
attorney general that Clinton met on the
tarmac and his jet.
Oh,
a lynch.
Loretta Lynch.
That story.
It's fucking insane.
They had a private meeting.
I mean,
trump's been hitting that over the head
and he's actually,
every time he says it,
I'm like,
yeah,
wait a minute.
They had a meeting in the plane for a
couple minutes right before the
indictment didn't happen.
Like,
well,
that's why people like Scott Adams,
who was a very reasonable guy.
He's coming on soon.
He's great.
He will.
A little bit of what I said before about
the trump tactics,
he came on my show and he laid it out so
clearly,
and he at,
at that point,
he wasn't supporting trump really,
and I think,
I think he,
I think now he officially his,
but his whole point was,
it's not the policy.
Understand what he's doing,
the trolling,
understand the leading that he does and
then comes in after all of that.
He fully gets it.
You're,
you're going to love talking to them.
Yeah.
I mean,
I feel like what trump represents to a
lot of people that are supporting him is
they'll,
they're willing to look past all of his
flaws and all the bullshit and the
bullying and the craziness because he's
something completely unique that has
never run for president before.
What he is he,
what he represents is a guy who has been
inside but is also outside.
He is independent in terms of
financially and he's also independent in
terms of his connections and his
obligations to them.
One of the things about him being a
narcissist and one the things about him
being a guy who probably have a whole
lot of friends
is that in establishing that and
becoming the super successful guy who's
really concerned only about himself,
he's immune to all that cronyism
bullshit.
He's not going to do that and you're
seeing that like the way he's hammering
hillary on all these different things,
the way he's attacking,
I mean he got paid to be at Hillary's
fucking wedding or hillary rather got
paid to be at his wedding.
He paid
her donation for her to show up at his
wedding or fucked it up.
Um,
I mean,
this is a guy that's been deeply
embedded in,
in,
in politics,
but to his credit then he points that
out.
I mean,
in the first debate,
the first republican debate,
what was,
he said it within the first 10 minutes.
Yeah,
yeah.
I gave her money and she showed up to my
wedding.
That's how corrupt the system is.
So you're totally right.
What's happening is people are,
they're so frustrated,
they're frustrated about language and
all the bullshit and seeing all the
nonsense between the media and the White
House correspondence dinner where,
you know,
they call it nerd prom and all the,
they're supposed to be guarding the
politicians and instead they're having
dinner with them.
And we could go through the list of the
amount of people that are on CNN that
are married to public.
People are work for campaigns.
You know,
I just mentioned the Donna Brazil thing.
There's a good Jew,
Paul Begala for example,
he runs a hillary SUPERPAC.
He's on CNN as an analyst like this
show,
everyone is now seeing it.
There was the idea of it.
But now because of the Internet,
we're seeing all of it and people have
just had it.
Think about it.
Everyone wants to be close to power in a
certain way.
So if you had a,
if you had Barack Obama,
you're the president in here,
you can probably in your first interview
with him,
the first time you met him might go a
little easier hoping that he might come
back again because you'd like to be
around it a little.
Not Man Dude,
I hope,
I hope not.
You go hard.
I would show up drunk and high and I had
to go like let's kill it says do this
man.
Let's just do this.
I want to know what's up.
But he gets a chance to give you the
president.
Look,
can,
I don't want to be president,
but likely there would be like some
serious consequences if I didn't do
that.
Right.
So,
so that's the real concern.
So there's two things.
There's one is that he won't do.
If you ask if you are going to demand a
really hard interview,
I mean a really,
really high degree.
They'd be a hard interview.
What I would do if I had a chance to sit
down with Barack Obama because he's not
much older than me.
Yeah.
He's only a couple of years older than
me,
like I had essentially could hang out
with that guy.
I think in a lot of ways,
let's forget about what he's done and
the drones and the attacks on whistle
blowers and the attacks on the freedom
of the press.
There's been a lot of horrible things
that have occurred during this
administration.
It's been one of the wars
administrations in terms of freedom of
the press.
It's not,
that doesn't seem to say much about
that.
Not at all,
cause it's,
it's bullshit.
That's why I don't believe in this left
and right thing.
It's like the raiders versus the
dolphins.
You pick a team and your team can do no
wrong.
Yeah.
What I would talk to him about is what
does it like being a human being under
that immense amount of pressure.
And is that job even manageable?
Is it,
is it possible for one person to really
be for 300
and whatever million people there are
here?
Yeah.
Well that's right,
but that,
but that's donald trump's got to put it
into that.
People think we're voting for a cane.
They don't realize that,
you know,
there's simple civics things that people
need to know that they don't know
anywhere.
Stuff that you should have learned in
seventh grade social studies that we
have three branches of government.
The president is one branch,
he's the executive branch.
All he is supposed to do,
the president doesn't write laws,
right?
All he is supposed to do is sign the
law.
Congress writes the law that the
legislative branch and then the judicial
branch and the courts actually make sure
that they're legal and there's
separation of powers in a balance so
that they can,
you know,
checks and balances.
So they make sure no branch gets too
powerful.
But if you think about it,
think about what the last two years have
been like for this election.
People think we're voting on a king.
So Hillary,
I can solve this and all that.
And it's like,
wait a minute.
If you can do all these shit,
why didn't you tell brock these last
eight years?
I'll bring all the jobs back.
Well,
you were on his team,
so maybe you should have mentioned that.
So you know,
that's all bullshit.
And then when trump says,
I'm the only one that can solve
immigration,
I'm the only one that can make the
economy grading.
I know.
It's like,
well,
you're just a part of the government.
I get it.
You're a big part.
And we fetishize the president in a way
that we don't the other branches,
which is a problem.
Um,
but they're,
they're not a king.
And we have to remind ourselves of that.
And for the people that are really ready
to jump off the bridge tomorrow if
they're a guy loses or gal or,
or Gal.
Uh,
for those people,
the hope is that the system is,
can be stronger than either one of these
two people.
You Ha if,
if,
if we're not at that point,
then we're really in trouble.
You already established so that the
system itself is just,
yeah,
it's just busted.
It's just busted.
But that's why they're voting trump.
And that's the thing,
that's the thing with trump.
If you think about trump,
what of progressive hated all these
years,
they hate Christian conservatives.
Well guess what?
Trump's not a Christian conservative.
He doesn't give a fuck he had,
they're all supporting him.
I've oddly at the highest numbers,
but he doesn't care about that.
Do you think trump really cares about
abortion?
He's an old school pussy grabber.
Exactly right.
O.
S.
P.
He doesn't care about abortion each
Jesus tee shirt.
There you go.
You can have that one.
But he doesn't care about abortion.
He doesn't care about gay rights.
I think about it.
He gave the,
the,
at the RNC at the convention,
he talked about gay rights.
It got out of pause,
break.
He brought Peter Teal up there to talk
about being openly gay and they loved
him.
I mean,
so it's a lot of ways stablish that
Hillary Clinton was anti gay marriage
until 2013 when it became convenient.
She is on record many,
many times of saying that she believes
in a marriage between a man and a woman.
Yeah.
But that's what just incredibly
regressive of,
well that's what they all do.
They wait now,
even Obama,
it's like he waited,
waited,
waited until Obama,
Obama.
Um,
but even Obama didn't do it until Biden
was on meet the press and he like kind
of slipped.
And then the next day Obama was like,
me too,
you know,
saying Mo Bama,
Michelle Obama,
she ran,
she could probably fucking,
when you want to talk about a woman who
has been in the White House who has
shown an incredible resolve at her,
the way she speaks,
she's,
she's like a very intelligent,
very articulate,
very composed person.
I think she could win.
Well,
what does it tell you though,
that I have heard than Hillary?
How about that?
Yeah.
I would probably rather have 100% yeah,
100% so I don't know.
I don't even know what she thinks it,
but he'll,
being a president is,
ah,
I'm here.
I'm sitting here talking about I don't,
I just know she's not as compromised.
Maybe she would be if she got that job.
So is that ultimately where we're at is
that the system is so corrupt that all
they could choke out all the two years
of this bullshit could give us at the
end was these two.
Like I kind of think they just,
they perfectly deserve each other,
but if you want to look and find out
what went wrong,
you got to look in the mirror because we
all have to look at ourselves and say,
how did we all allow this to happen?
It was a joke at first.
The trump thing was a joke.
I mean,
I'll fully own up.
I remember when he first got in,
I said he's going to be in three debates
and that's it.
And he was definitely in three debates.
He was,
yeah.
And then he stayed for the fourth and I
went,
Oh shit,
he's better at talking to those people.
He's used to being on camera and he's
used to insulting people.
Like when Marco Rubio tried to insult
him,
he was terrible.
Oh my God.
He's like,
he's not good at that.
Like that's not something you just pick
up on.
It was like watching an open mic comic
half to like headline the biggest show
of their life.
You know,
he just couldn't get the words out
properly.
But,
but to that point maybe so far for all
the things that we're talking about,
it seems to me that trump,
the best sales job I could give her a
trump would be that he has a lot,
his family has a lot,
they have everything to live for.
They have everything that most of us
want,
material assets and what all of that
stuff.
And it's like,
is he really people that are like,
he's going to start world war three or
you know,
we're going to fight North Korea are.
But isn't that a real concern though
that with his hubris and the way he
treats opponents in business and the way
he treats opponents socially,
like Rosie O'donnell,
I go the way he does sort of conduct
himself that that is not something that
you can do if you want to talk to some
foreign leader.
Absolutely.
It's a con for sure.
I,
so I'm not diminishing that.
We don't,
as I say on the show with him,
I don't know what his moral center is,
you know?
I just have no sense of is this really
all about him or is this,
does he really feel does like in the
truest moment of him,
does he feel that the country really has
been derailed and is he just using the
trolling tactics to just get something
good out of it?
My point is that,
that he has,
well I was saying he has a lot to lose
and it's like maybe he,
this is the moment where he finally like
came around and was like,
I have no one's going to stop this
bullshit,
this corrupt,
all this awful shit that you're talking
about with Hillary.
And maybe he's like,
I'm the only one that can do it.
That's,
that's the best way I can frame it.
I'm not telling you that's,
that's,
that's a really fantasy based view of it
though.
It's not based on his actual words,
but it's impossible to base any of
those.
So.
Right.
So how do we base any of this on their
words?
We know that is lying left and right.
You know what I mean?
Well,
if you've seen the thing,
the difference between the s the FBI
director giving the description of what
Hillary did and then her saying what the
FBI had said.
Yeah,
and I mean it is so horrifically
inaccurate and dishonest.
This is like,
how does that not immediately disqualify
you in any other time?
It would because she was running
against,
let's put it this way,
if she was running against Obama and
these things,
and this is,
this was the Hillary Clinton that we had
been exposed to.
It's like our standards have dropped so
low,
but the media would have been all over
her because they liked Obama.
So that's what's happened here.
Trump has been the great unifier to take
all of these people,
progressives and liberals,
and we'll all these people and even,
you know,
the never trump conservatives,
all these people,
they're all unified in just their hatred
of trump.
And then that gets them to ignore all
the horrible shit about Hillary.
So like the stuff with the emails,
when she,
when the guy basically call me,
came out and he was like,
well,
it wasn't negligent with sort of,
he was like,
she's basically an idiot.
She didn't know what she was doing,
but it wasn't negligent.
Well,
that's grounds to be fired at most jobs
if you're,
you can't screw up something really,
really important and say,
well,
I didn't do it in purpose.
I'm just an idiot who's not.
Not,
not even that it's illegal and illegal.
Who would go to jail?
Right.
What everything she did,
if she was a sailor,
you know,
you know the story about the,
the,
the naval officer who took photos and
I'm not,
it wasn't even an officer as an enlisted
guy who took photos of the inside of a
nuclear cockpit.
He's facing 10 years in jail.
Just took photos on his phone.
Top secret shit.
Well,
did you see this in last two days that
hillary was having her cleaning lady
print emails?
Classified emails there.
Wikileaks is showing things where she's
saying have her print it,
have her print deal.
She'll over Anthony Wiener thing that
she had.
Huma,
huma forwarded her fucking classified
emails to Anthony Wiener's account and
then printed them up because I guess his
computer was hooked up to the fucking
printer in the house so he could print
his dick pics.
Right.
So then,
well he was he printing them?
Where do you send them once you find the
large,
I'm otherwise you get no traction.
You can't send actual size dick pics.
Say ask you this before we get any
further,
what do you want?
Either one of them to win and if you do
you have a preference or a you like Iti,
want to step back and watch this nuclear
explosion.
Go off and see what happens.
None of those three options.
I don't want this thing to blow up.
You know,
one of,
one of the things I say on the show all
the time is that our country is still so
good and we don't realize it.
We think that it's just this endless
fighting and this awfulness.
There's so much good here.
You wake up.
I know we're a little,
we're a little different as as public
people,
but the average person wakes up here.
They can say what they want to say.
For the most part,
you can say what you want to say.
You can get a decent job.
For the most part,
where we go to New York City and go on a
subway and be with literally every
single person from every part of the
world,
from every,
every ethnicity and nationality and
religion and race and sexuality,
and we're all here and we're not killing
each other.
That doesn't mean that we could do a lot
better.
It doesn't mean that the system's
broken.
It doesn't,
but it's still pretty damn good here.
Almost everyone in the world still wants
to come here.
We don't.
How many of your friends are leaving
America?
I know Lena Dunham's going to leave.
That will be all right.
She's going,
if trump wins,
you know,
like she said that yeah,
she'd going to Mexico or Canada.
He's got a lot of problems of her own.
Yeah,
right.
Let's not waste that.
He,
so I was at her butt,
but,
so my,
my overriding point would be I don't
want to blow the system up to that level
where it's really like,
yeah,
cause I didn't say,
I didn't mean like watch this nuclear
explosion go off.
I'm at an event like this isn't a
tomorrow's and event and we're going to
sit back and watch how this event plays
out.
Who are you?
What do you want to say?
Who you are
voting for him?
So look,
we're,
we're in California,
so,
so I haven't said this publicly.
I figured I would sort of wait until
today.
So we're in California here.
So we know Hillary's Wayne in
California.
So the two of us have a little bit of a
luxury to do something that might be
more principled than what that
independent,
yeah.
Then what the average person,
if you're in Ohio or you're in Florida
or Colorado or whatever your,
your votes,
Matt,
literally every single person's vote
match highlights how fucking goofy this
system is so completely does.
Right.
And I now there are people that trading
votes over state lines and all kinds of
crazy things.
Look,
my biggest thing this time is that the
system is just mangled and we need more
voices.
So I,
my,
I'm not totally sure.
My gut feeling is I'm going to vote for
Gary Johnson for all the wrong reasons
because I just want somebody to realize
down the road that four years from now
we should have somebody else.
But I think you can make equally strong
cases for trump and for Hillary and
equally wrong cases for both of them.
Yeah,
because everything,
cause it's funny,
I don't,
I'll ask you the same question,
but just from what we've talked about
here,
my sense is you're going to vote for
Hillary in the most begrudging possible
way.
I don't think I am.
If I was going to vote for Hillary,
so think about this,
I would have to,
I would have to have a way that I could
justify supporting her.
Not just a way that I didn't feel like
trump should be the president.
It's all in my mind for the system,
it's,
it's far better if
it's not even done,
it doesn't make sense.
I think.
I definitely think my options are either
voting for Gary Johnson or writing
someone in and I don't think Gary
Johnson should be pressing.
No,
I know.
Look,
he's not going to be,
so you can do that.
And clean coach,
he was president.
Look,
the guy did a great job as a governor of
New Mexico and I mean,
what would I find disagreeable about him
is so much different than what I found
disagreeable about George Bush and
George Bush was president for eight
years.
What I find disagreeable about him,
like his only,
his lack of preparedness,
but I think he's a very disciplined guy.
I just don't think he prepared well
enough about foreign policy and about a
lot of other issues.
And I also think the pressure of the
national media and the spotlight of that
uniquely.
Yeah,
the Gotcha.
Journalism is something unique that he
had not experienced before.
So I think how depressing
that is with everything going on here.
And for as much as you and I are in this
thing,
like in it in a,
in a public way that we're,
but we both may be will begrudgingly the
day before the election kind of be like,
ad we're going to vote for the guy that
definitely can't win.
I mean,
think about the shit that you've just
said about Hillary that is seriously
damning shit.
Really Damn Shit.
Now look,
Sam Harris,
who is one of my heroes who I know
you've had on a zillion times and I've
had him on and he did the best sell job
he could on Hillary.
He's,
he's supporting her.
And I think it just is not really,
well,
it's mostly trump's of funny little
article about the,
the,
the war,
you know,
to the best of two evils or I mean,
not a whole article,
a whole podcast about it.
Right.
And I think he makes some good points
about that.
He,
he absolutely does.
And look,
I hold him as high as I can hold
another,
another person.
Um,
but I think that the,
maybe the best way this could go down is
that if you don't want the,
if you're really afraid of what could
happen with trump,
that,
that it's just like the rules have just
changed forever and it just doesn't
sound right that trump would be
president,
United States,
this reality TV star.
If you're really,
really afraid of that.
I think the best argument for Clinton
then would be that get her in the system
basically keeps chugging along and then
good liberals and decent conservatives
and Libertarians and the people that
really aren't on the fringes that are
dragging everybody apart.
You know what I mean?
Like the real regressive left people in
the real outright people.
But everyone else kind of comes together
and says,
we're going to change things over the
next couple of years.
And I,
this is,
I'm giving you a real like kind of pie
in the sky.
Like,
you know,
let's try to spin this positively stuff
ABC after school special.
Like that's really what I'm giving you
right now.
Cause I got nothing left with one day to
go in this fucking thing.
But,
but that's what I would say is that it's
become obvious to me over the course of
this,
the average conservative who I may
disagree with on taxes or abortion or
whatever,
they're not my enemy.
They're not as a liberal,
And we can find,
we have to find room to be okay with
other people.
This,
all this whole election is just a result
of not being okay if demonizing
everybody to the point that they're
evil.
And then what did we end up with?
We got this.
So the best argument for Hillary I think
is let her have for years,
the whole thing is going to be scandal
written.
No matter what she's going to.
This is about not letting people just do
their own thing.
Like that's,
that's a big part of what this is.
What,
what do you mean when you say,
explain,
explain what you just said about the
whole reason why we're in this.
We're in this position because we've got
cause over the last however long because
of cable news.
Because a twitter,
because of all of that,
all everyone caters their news to
themselves and then demonizes everybody,
right?
So everyone on the right will tell you
that they're all lived hard,
left socialist,
Marxist,
Blah Blah Blah.
And everyone on the left will tell you
that they're all racist white
supremacist Nazis.
And it's like neither one of those
things are true.
And,
and there could be,
you know,
it's like when,
uh,
people argue about abortion and it's
like everyone on the left will say that
the people on the right,
they're against abortion,
they hate women.
And people on the right,
we'll say that people on the left are
for abortion.
So they hate babies.
And guess what,
it's not really true either.
One of those,
you got to realize that we,
there's much more in common that we all
have.
I know,
you know,
this is like obviously like that's not
rocket science and we have to realize
that people can have different political
opinions and that way you can still find
some room.
There is some place Democrats and
Republicans used to work together so
well,
civility and just common,
the common bond of being American and
being so incredibly fortunate to be born
on this awesome patch of dirt.
I mean that's,
that's really what we are.
We're the lottery winners when it comes
to the world and a lot of people
disagree.
Fuck,
you kind of does better.
And it was a lot of people,
but you know,
there be,
just ignore them.
And I suppose that's where I would live.
I didn't live here.
I live in Canada or Australia.
Those are my two spots.
Will Australia.
I've had a couple of Australians on
places.
The Shit,
I fucking love us to get the ball.
I love the people over there.
It's such a fucking great place.
Yeah.
I Melbourne is fucking fantastic.
Sydney is awesome sister.
I enjoy it.
So they have their problems too.
But yeah,
I had read up and [inaudible],
who's a writer for the Herald Sun in
Australia,
she's at,
born in Iran,
moved to uh,
Australia,
and now she's basically,
she's on the right in that she's,
you know,
she would be considered a republican
here and she's actually fighting against
immigration the way they're doing it
there because she realized how good that
country is.
She says,
Australia is the most tolerant nation on
earth,
and we're now a unfurling that tolerance
by allowing everybody and even if even
if they don't believe the things we
believe,
and even if they don't want to integrate
and assimilate properly and all that
stuff,
well,
they're very hard on illegal immigrants.
They tend to illegal immigrants.
They put them on a boat and the ship
into a fucking island,
which is happening all over the place
and they're sinking boats.
I mean,
there are videos of boats trying to get
to Greece and they're just literally
sinking.
Right.
Um,
but,
but Australia,
Canada,
yeah.
There's some other places that are,
that are pretty good.
But the fight against people who
disagree and the demonization,
I completely agree with you on.
I think that we have a real problem with
teams.
We have a really real tribal mentality
when it's a team of the ride or a team
of the left or even a team of the
independence.
I've been seeing so many people and I've
been so disappointed with so many people
ignoring all the things that Clinton has
done and using that Hashtag I'm with
her,
especially my friends that are women
that are really excited about having the
first woman president and like this one,
this,
this is the one you want like this is,
this is like if you wanted to have the
first woman president,
like wouldn't you want to have a woman
who was like Obama when he ran for
president was a perfect candidate and a
lot of ways and a perfect response to
George Bush.
I mean take away all the things that he
didn't do that he had offered in his
whole hope and change campaign and
there's so much that he went against,
especially really disturbing stuff like
the whistle blower thing,
like he was offering support for
whistleblowers and saying that people
were doing illegal activity and they
expose that there'd be protected,
which has been absolutely not the case.
That's to me is like super disturbing
and I think as many
people said,
he's going to be on the wrong side of
history when it comes to that stuff,
but I don't know how much control or
power they really have.
I don't know.
I don't know what kind of influences the
president really has in that position,
but my point is he was a great
candidate.
Hillary Clinton is not a great
She's just not.
She's a scary person in a lot of ways.
All this shit that she's been saying
about Russia being a part of the attack
and the hacks on her email server and
the DNC,
that's all bullshit.
Well think about improving,
but she keeps saying that she's offered
up the fact that she would respond
militarily,
militarily against Russia for her
writing a bunch of fucked up shit in
emails and getting caught for it.
Right.
So the way you know that it's actual
bullshit and you're not just giving
hyperbole there is that if they were
doing the things that now the hillary
campaign is claiming and they do it very
caring,
they're very careful with their words
where they never flat out condemn them
for,
you know,
it's both.
It has to be coming from the road room
and it's all,
it's all,
you know,
it's a magic trick to keep you off the
topics of the emails,
which is really the stuff we should be
talking about.
But the way you know it's really not
real is that if it was real,
let's say there was real evidence,
the CIA or the FBI or NSA or whatever
had real evidence that Russia was
genuinely rigging our elections either
with trump or without trump or whatever
it,
that would truly be an act of war at
this point.
That would be an act of war and Obama
would have to be talking about it
endlessly because that's an alley that
like the term rigging the elections and
interfering with the,
when you say Russia,
do you mean a guy in Russia?
Like,
cause that's like a guy in America could
have hacked into that sheet.
Do you mean Putin directly?
The government or do you mean Russian
hackers?
Russian citizen.
The person who has no connection
whatsoever to the Russian governor who
may have gotten your shit.
Yeah.
So what about this?
Have you thought about this?
So all this stuff comes out wikileaks.
Let's go on the assumption that Hillary
is going to win tomorrow.
What if,
and I,
you know I say this with a,
I always quote Carl Sagan on this one,
which was extraordinary.
Claims require extraordinary evidence.
But what if wikileaks or the Russian
government or whoever it is is right?
What if they're saving the real shit
until she's president when they release
it today?
No,
we're not.
If you really want it to blackmail the
president of the United States,
black male.
But yeah,
if they wanted to look,
they want money or something or they
want some [inaudible] global trade
agreements or whatever.
No,
no,
no.
That,
that you release enough so that she's
damaged.
Now she gets into the White House and
then either you start continually
leaking more.
Cause I suspect they've got plenty more.
You continually leak more to hamper her
or you actually then have some shit
over.
Like what if there's some real shit,
you know,
that she was,
she facilitated,
you know,
something worse in Libya or you know,
like some other thing and then they
could potentially have some shit on her,
which then could actually lead to a war
with Russia.
Again,
I'm just that fully,
I fully throw the Carl Sagan caveat out
there when I say that,
but you have to think like they have a
political motive.
They're not,
they're not an a organization.
Clearly they want to damage hillary.
So I think there's something there.
You're giving me the skeptical eye,
which is I,
which is great.
Yeah,
I think that's a lot of speculation.
I think.
Yeah,
it is for sure.
It had anything big,
it would've already been out.
I mean,
everybody got a couple of hours left.
I don't buy it.
I think they would have released it
yesterday or well,
maybe not on Sunday.
Nobody's paying attention,
but I just think that there's no way
they would've waited this long.
Look,
the FBI saying that they're going to
reopen the investigation was one of the
most damaging things and that came from
the investigation of Anthony Wiener and
had nothing to do with wikileaks.
Yeah.
It came from just them looking into this
other creep and finding out that he's
sending his dick pics to some 15 year
old girl or whatever the fuck he was
doing.
I just don't think there's anything
there.
I think what we've seen,
we've already seen,
so we have it.
We really have,
I think the most damaging thing,
in my opinion,
was Colin Powell,
his impression of her.
That was,
it was horrific because Colin Powell is
such a respected person.
You very rarely hear anything negative
about him,
and he essentially said that she's a
moron.
You mean or not not a moron and
intelligent person who's Hubris fucks up
everything,
which is a way of being a moron and that
you know hill.
The thing about bill out dicking Bimbos
hilarious,
you know,
and he still is.
And then when Donald Trump brought those
women than he,
you know,
he's allegedly sexually assaulted and he
brought them and even raped.
Yeah.
Allegedly brought them to the debate and
had them sit there.
There's a photo of a bill looking over
it.
Those women.
Have you ever seen that?
I've seen it.
What in the holy fuck was on his mind
when he took,
when the impression,
you know,
that he's giving while he's looking over
at those women like that.
So doesn't that go to why people are
voting for trump?
Yeah.
One of my best friends,
since I'm four years old,
he does not care about politics at all.
Could not care less.
I don't even know that he could name the
vice president.
He has been all in on trump.
I've never talked more politics with him
ever in our entire lives.
My best friends is a right wing guy.
He's completely a political,
he's not big on the government in
general.
He doesn't care if you,
he doesn't care what you do.
Don't hurt him.
He live and let live.
That's his whole,
I don't think he's ever voted.
I mean this is a great guy,
but that he just has nothing to do with
politics.
He's been all about trump because his
whole thing is the system is so gross.
We all know it and now the guy's
exposing it and he's willing to take
that risk of what that might mean.
Isn't that sort of what Scott Adams and
saying that that's basically the thrust
of it,
that people are just saying,
we all knew it was fucked up.
Now someone's showing it to you and
your,
but you don't like how he behaves.
You don't like how he talks about pussy.
You don't like that.
He says mean things to Rosie old,
old,
truly gross things.
I'm not defending any of those things,
but like when someone's actually pulling
the curtain and showing you the wizard
and now the wizards a little weirder
than you like and they go,
oh,
forget that.
Yeah.
Like let's pull the curtain back and get
another curtain and you know,
and that's what they were all afraid of.
They're afraid of this is their chance.
And if they blow it,
it'll never that the machine will just
swallow everybody up.
I don't think machine swole and
shit.
I think what we're seeing is the
inevitable demise of a system that's
wholly incompatible with the Internet.
Yeah.
I think,
I love that.
That that's what's happening.
That's what's happening.
This system,
you cannot exist in a world where I
think all communication within the next
20 years is going to be transparent.
Your emails to Jamie,
you know,
your tweets to your mom,
whatever the fuck you're doing.
I think it's all going to be
transparent.
I don't think,
I think what the Internet is providing
and what modern,
um,
communication is providing is almost
instantaneous access to data and to the
way people feel and express themselves.
And what we were talking about earlier
with these little pops of popcorn,
the,
that they're going to boil up to a
gigantic,
but
it's going to,
technology's not going to stop here.
It's not like what we can do now is as
much as we're going to be able to do in
the future.
No.
It's going to continue to progress and
it's going to get to a point where
there's not going to be,
the deception is going to be impossible.
So that's what it is.
That's what it is.
Cable News is deceiving everyone we
know,
they're deceiving everyone.
They're sleeping with the people.
They're supposed to be taken care of.
All you know what you're supposed to be
watching.
Sorry.
And now we're exposing it.
So think about just what we've done
here,
whether if we got one decent point and
the in the however long we've been
sitting here,
if we got one thing out 15 years ago,
you could not do this.
You could not have two people fully
unfiltered for this amount of time doing
what we're doing.
So if we manage one cogent point in this
whole thing,
that's more than you could have got out
15 years ago.
Well,
it's definitely more than you're ever
going to see on networks because
networks have an obligation and they
have an agenda.
And I was going back and forth and I
tweeted about this,
that was going back and forth between
Fox News and CNN.
One night I just sat in front of the TV.
My wife and kids were out and so I was
just sitting in front of the TV.
Stone is fuck flipping through the
channels going back and forth between
CNN and Fox and I was Goddamn
bewildered.
I was like,
I'm watching two different worlds,
two different plants,
like there's two different parallel
universes in a one parallel universe.
Hillary Clinton is,
you know,
the savior of the world and the other
one,
she's a monster and Bill Clinton is a
rapist and a sexual Predator and these
women are a bunch of Bimbos or just came
out against Donald Trump and they're all
puppets and Gloria all reds in on it and
all this craziness.
And I'm like,
what?
What?
What would a person think if they had,
this is their first exposure to human
beings.
If an alien came here from another
planet and there's first exposure to
human beings was looking at this process
to decide who controls the button,
then that has all the nuclear weapons of
the world pointed at various countries.
I mean,
this is insanity and this is an insane
way to communicate.
So how do,
how do we then as as the,
the neos of this,
of this matrix,
right?
How do we then keep emboldening?
I mean,
I guess we just have to keep doing that
for the building.
There's an inevitable process going on
and it's,
it's going to,
it's
going to,
it's going to overwhelm what we consider
to be normal communication.
It's going to overwhelm that and right
now I think we're at,
we're at a very early stage of this
technological progression and I think
we're looking at,
in terms of the Internet and devices and
phones and laptops and shit,
but I think new technology is going to
emerge that's going to foot look.
No one would have ever thought that you
would have people addicted to a phone.
Just 20 years ago.
No one would've ever even considered the
idea of being addicted to a phone,
that you would go to a restaurant and
80% of the people would just be on their
phone and no one likes it when you bring
it up.
If you say to them,
hey man,
want to get off your phone?
Like,
fuck dude,
I got important emails coming through.
Everybody gets mad.
It's like,
you know,
you like saying,
Hey,
do you really need that drink?
I fuck him off that track.
It's the same goddamn feeling.
People were responding to an addiction,
but this is just step one man.
This is step one of an ultimate complete
invasiveness.
There's going to be some new technology,
whether it's a neural implant or whether
there's some other device that we're
going to wear,
but there's going to be something that
connects us far more intimately with
each other than what we're experiencing
now,
which is pretty God damn intimate.
Yeah.
Wouldn't it be nice?
I had a guy who was running for the
transhumanist party [inaudible].
Yeah,
so that's what we talked.
I mean we spend,
as I'm sure you did,
we spent the hour basically talking
about all that,
that think about it.
We're not talking about it this look,
it's not that this shit's happening
tomorrow,
but instead of talking about grabbing
pussy and emails,
we should be talking about some of these
things,
some of these actual things that are
going to shape our lives and we don't
talk about any of this stuff.
And then the shit just happens.
And then instead of talking about it and
preparing ourselves,
we react.
But we need to do a little legwork so
that when this stuff comes,
whatever it is,
we have to be ready for it.
And we don't.
So one day the robots will be here and
we're going to be bound down to him
because we didn't do the Legwork to go,
Huh,
you know what they were gonna turn on
us.
We should have,
uh,
well,
I don't necessarily know if the robots
are gonna turn on us like the,
that's the big concern that a lot of
people have.
Stephen Hawking and Elon Musk,
the artificial intelligence.
I think before then we're going to
integrate.
I mean,
I think before virtual reality you're
going to have augmented reality and I
think that augmented human beings,
human beings that are augmented with
technology,
that's really going to be what's going
to separate us from what we are now,
which is essentially the monkey holding
the device.
I think the device is going to be in the
monk.
We'll look at all ten's got the chip in
him and he can open his garage door and
strength and he's,
he was talking about a guy that,
you know,
he knows a guy that wants to chop his
arm off to get the bionic arm to be
able,
you know,
and get Wifi in your arm and Ooh.
Yeah.
And then somebody hacks into the
Russians are going to hack his arm.
That's gonna jerk his own dick off.
Leaders going to do with this robotic.
Oh boy.
Yeah.
You think we're in shit now.
I think we should go into stand up.
I've been saying that for years.
It's a really good public speaker.
He's obviously fucked off.
He's got all the traits,
you know,
he's got everything going on.
They get them in stand up.
I think he's
probably pretty fucking funny.
He looks,
he looks funny.
Yeah.
He's a great face for it.
The wrong line of business politics are
essentially show business for ugly
people.
Guess what sounds comedy,
you know,
comedy,
you knows there's been some really not
very good looking people that have done
a wonderful job of,
uh,
telling jokes and becoming famous.
I think we look pretty good relative,
relative Max.
Yeah.
I mean,
I haven't been doing stand up much in
the last couple of years,
but I think relatively speaking,
we gotta be on the higher end of
relatively speaking.
And tosh is probably number one,
that handsome bastard bastard.
Beautiful Hair.
Fuck beautiful man.
There's a few of them like that.
Sebastian,
he's a good looking goddamn guy too.
There's quite a few,
but now more so than ever in the past
that was happened to the fat slob and
Lee comedian I would know.
But I'm talking to Lucy Kay embraces it.
Lou Anderson,
and he just,
I was happy that he wanted that.
Yeah.
That he won the Ralphie May,
right?
Yeah.
Ralphie may takes us to the whole new
level.
Yeah.
And he's like a Bruce Lee of,
well,
there you go.
Something you wouldn't say in front of
him.
No,
I would,
he knows what he is.
Yeah.
It's not the worst thing in the world.
Um,
well whatever.
I just,
I honestly believe that we're at a
tipping point in,
uh,
in human civilization.
And I think that what this election is
exposing is how ridiculous our processes
that our process was created by people
who used to write with feathers.
You know,
I mean,
it really was,
it was created by people who rode horses
to get around and you know,
they needed a representative government
cause there was no fucking way are you
gonna be able to talk to someone in
Missouri,
right.
It would take forever.
And so they needed someone to talk to
those people and then get the word back
to Washington.
We don't need that anymore.
It's an archaic system.
And then an archaic system is in many
ways being exposed.
Um,
I made a tweet recently or an instagram
post about this guy that was going over
the electoral map,
like a storm was coming.
He was like [inaudible] and all the
states.
And I was like,
this guy is like talking about storms.
He's talking about,
he's doing a forecast.
Like this is so bizarre what we're
seeing now.
Well you're,
you're so right.
I mean just on the technology front and
how we vote,
it's like every state has two senators.
And the reason they did it back then was
because they wanted to make sure that
the states like Montana that have nobody
living there had some sort of
representations.
So they needed to make sure that the
train with the president campaigning
would actually make it there or the
horse and buggy or whatever it was.
And it's like now it's all changed.
So everything being equal,
even though I'm not for changing a lot
of the,
I certainly wouldn't be for changing the
constitution,
but like the fact that Montana has two
senators and California has two
senators,
California has like that.
What is it like the 10th biggest economy
in the world?
Right?
Something like that.
So it's like,
that's not right.
Right.
You know,
technology has changed,
so it's not necessary anymore.
The people in Montana can hear all the
same shit that the people in California
have.
So there are things that are happening
now that the system,
because it's so ingrained and because
the people that control it and the
money,
I don't even think that's a conspiracy.
I think that's just the way things work.
It's just,
it's so grained.
You know what
we love about the constitution has
essentially already been violated by the
Patriot Act,
the Patriot Act to the NDA.
There's a lot of weird shit that's
already in place that kind of takes away
from the things that the founding
fathers had set up to make sure that
tyranny was never embraced.
That we,
we,
we have these things that we established
a long time ago that we think of when we
think of what the United States is.
Freedom of speech,
freedom of speech.
Um,
you,
you have a right to a fair trial when
you don't anymore with the Patriot Act.
And with indefinite detention that was
provided by the NDA,
they could kind of put you in jail for
whatever they decide.
They put you in jail because you
represent a threat or that you are on a
terrorist watch list or whatever.
And if they decide that you're a threat
to America,
you,
you really don't have the right to a
trial,
they can just lock you up.
I mean,
look at what the fuck they did to
Chelsea manning.
Yeah,
I mean,
to this day she just tried to commit
suicide again apparently.
Yeah.
This,
this whole,
I mean not to me disturbs me almost as
much as anything.
The Way Julian assange just like trapped
in a house in London and can't leave.
He's in an embassy.
So what does that tell you then about
the progressive's that we're all about
this right?
They were all about Chelsea manning.
They were all about getting all the
information when it was all breaking.
I was completely with them.
It's,
I'm all,
you know,
like look,
I believe that governments should be
transparent,
but there is some shit.
Are you with me on this?
That some shit has to go down that we
can't know of.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Like that's,
I just think it's when people want
everything to be fully transparent,
it's like put it,
the problem is who gets to keep those
secrets and why the regular folks as a
regular person get to keep those secrets
over the American people?
Well,
I dunno.
I Dunno what the right answer to that is
other than there has to be,
you can't have everyone walking around
with all the knowledge.
That's a problem.
And I think someday that's going to be
inevitable.
That's what I'm saying about technology
that eventually it'll just unfurl the
whole thing.
It's a bottleneck is there.
And I also think the bottleneck is going
to occur with money because I think
money right now is really just numbers
mean money isn't backed by gold anymore.
It's just numbers.
It's just numbers on a well.
So that means it's data.
So that means it's information and
information.
It's going in the direction that
information is eventually going to be
completely transparent.
You're gonna be able to share
information back and forth.
I don't know if we're going to be able
to hold onto this concept of money.
I think the concept of money that we
have in our,
it's connected to civilization and that
in itself is only a few thousand years
old.
I mean if you look at the invention of
money before that,
it was sort of like trading in goods and
services or whatever it was.
You're going back what,
20,000 years,
30,000 years.
Human beings have been around for a long
fucking time.
Culture's been around for a long time.
I thought like 10,000 years.
Human beings in this current state are
incredibly recent where we're not even
dealing with gold anymore.
Now we're just dealing with numbers.
I think the
next step is that you can't keep track
of that anymore.
The next step is going to be a resource
based economy,
meaning that people are just going to be
sharing and trading and resources and
we're going to have to figure out some
way to quantify those resources and
quantify your value and I don't think
it's going to be the way it is now where
you have these hedge fund managers and
these Bernie Madoff twats that are
fucking just essentially moving numbers
around and making ungodly sums of money.
I mean,
if you look at the Hamptons,
a lot of those fucking people that have
these castles out there and then in the
castles in Connecticut,
you have these people that have just
figured out a way to move numbers
around.
That's all they're doing.
They're moving playing tricks with the
system basically.
Yes.
They're extracting money from a broken
system.
Well,
that's why I think that,
you know,
even when people come after trump on the
money stuff,
you know the whole thing with the $918
million in the write off and all that.
Yes.
Now look,
we don't know.
We haven't seen his taxes.
He made it the election tomorrow.
He made it without John's talk city.
Do that because again,
it's just trolling the system.
But do you remember when,
when Howard stern was running for
governor and they were forcing him to
reveal his taxes and he went,
fuck you,
I'm out.
Oh,
I remember that.
Was that what happened to drop?
Basically?
Howard's a very wise guy.
So I would,
I would imagine that he knew that was
going to happen and didn't really want
to be governor anyway,
but when he was running for governor,
that was the heart.
That was a hurdle that they told him he
had to expose his taxes to Howard's
credit.
And I love,
love,
love Howard.
Um,
you know,
did you see a couple of weeks ago they
were,
people were asking him to release all
the trump interviews from all the years,
from the 20 years,
and he said,
no,
I'm not going to do it.
Because when people came and come to my
studio,
it's,
we're playing a game,
sort of we're talking about women were,
and it would add nothing to this.
And,
and Donald Trump is a good sport about
it.
So for me to betray that it would be
betraying my own self.
I thought it was a pretty great
principled statement by him.
That is great.
It's also taking it out of context,
the context of being on the stern show,
but didn't do,
they did use some of the stuff that he
said,
so they got supporting the war.
So I think somebody else had that video.
But I guess there's apparently archive
full of stuff that I guess he owns or,
Oh,
okay.
Well,
I mean there is of,
there's a time and a place for things,
but there's also,
you have to think that this guy was not
running for president back when he was
saying those things.
I was just being a silly man on a silly
show where it's all about humor and you
know,
being a good sport and playing a role as
Howard put it.
Maybe you're paraphrasing him,
but I think that's,
that's pretty accurate.
Yeah,
so he was,
yeah,
he was playing the game.
I thought that was,
you know,
look,
he would've had an opportunity to get
him in the mix again.
You know,
may,
you know,
more publicity for him.
And he said,
no,
that's not,
that's not what the purpose of what I've
built here for the last 40 years is,
and I'm not going to throw in on this
garbage.
So I thought it was pretty good.
Well,
you know,
I'm sure he probably realizes that if he
ever decided to run for government in
the form,
now the same thing would be used against
him.
But what does that say about an std?
Not Him.
You know who he is,
is you ask him,
what are your well considered opinions
on things right now?
And then,
you know,
the woe in 1989 you've said,
you know that this person's a monkey and
you know,
and like think how fucking dangerous
that is.
So from the,
from the limited amount that I know you,
I,
you seem to me to be an extremely
principled person.
You have a code that you live by,
you,
you care about honesty and being
forthright and,
and all of that stuff,
right?
Think of all the things that you've said
here about doing drugs or sex or,
right,
blah,
blah.
Someone like you would never want to run
for president ever.
We could,
you even possibly fathom running five
wouldn't want the job.
But if I did,
if I did run,
I don't,
I don't want to.
But if I did,
they would definitely use all that stuff
against.
And that's why context is so incredibly
important.
And this is also an incredibly new thing
with human beings.
Being able to extract little soundbites
from things that you've said and whether
it's a tweet from justine sacco or
whatever the fuck it is.
And then say,
this defines you this moment.
This one moment defines you.
This one moment where someone cuts you
off and you go,
you fucking cunt,
and you lay on your horn.
This is Dave Rubin that you want Dave
Ruben running your country.
What if that was your mom that cutoff?
Dave Ruben.
What if that woman was headed to the
hospital?
What if her baby was dying in the
backseat and Dave Ruben called her con?
I mean,
you know,
that's,
I'm trying to,
I'm just throwing little,
little,
uh,
whatever.
I just think that that's the problem.
That's the problem that you can't think
of.
I mean even I'm not,
all I'm doing right now is saying what I
think as it comes out of my brain,
right?
I'm not freaking me out.
Yeah,
it's,
it's wild.
But it's all freaking me out.
But that's all we're doing here.
But anyone,
anyone that doesn't like us or wanted to
discredit us or anything and you know,
not to bring it back to Sam again,
but you know,
the types of things that people with
really awful intentions have done with
misquoting him and all that stuff and
that thing needs to be destroyed.
That outrage monster that we'll find one
thing that you did or said once to then
destroy every other piece of goodness
that you've put out there must end.
And that's,
that is a big piece of what's happening
here too.
I also think discourse in particular
like discourse against Sam is,
is what a lot of people are doing.
They're playing a game and Sam has a
high profile and they're using their
voice to attack that high profile to
make a move on the castle.
You know,
it's like they're moving chess pieces
around and they're using strategy and
they're saying,
well,
he said this about Islam,
you know,
and do you understand how many billions
of people or a peaceful Muslims and how
offensive this is to say that they,
you know,
and that that's what they're doing
there.
They're taking these positions and
they're also taking these positions in a
weird way because there's something
about writing a blog.
It's a very cowardly thing when you're
attacking someone because they don't
respond.
They just,
I mean,
you want someone to respond back in a
blog,
you're requiring an incredible amount of
their time sitting there and formulate
another blog,
but then you know that,
that it's a one way dialogue.
Or if someone writes an attack blog on
Dave Ruben.
Yeah,
they,
that's a very cowardly
thing because what they're doing is
they're sort of forcing you to respond
by establishing a false narrative are by
portraying you in an unfavorable light
by taking things out of context and
using them.
And I'm,
I do people do it against me.
And it's,
it's almost,
it's funny when you read,
you read it,
you're like,
wow,
this is weird.
Or that someone split,
spent so much thought on extrapolating
something that you said that you didn't
either mean or it's like,
wow,
you really went deep on my psyche in a
way that had nothing to do that.
So you,
you know,
this Guy Mike Cernovich by any chance?
Yes.
Okay.
Have you had them on?
No,
I have not.
So I'm going to smoke some pot.
Yeah.
Smokes and is all freaking me out.
I'm kind of freaked out for a,
I can't smoked the sativa.
Sorry.
But,
um,
so,
so Mike Cernovich I've had on my show,
he's,
he's big within the,
he's the pro trump guy and,
uh,
I'll try to make this really deep.
So yeah.
Man.
Really appreciate it,
dude.
Um,
anyway,
uh,
w from having him on,
I got more shit than I've had than
anyone else that I've had on because you
had them on because I had,
because he was sort of a cause he's
thought of as part of the alt right.
He apparently he had tweeted like three
years before I had him on the show.
I didn't even know who he was until
about two weeks before I had him on.
But about three years before that,
he had tweeted something that sounded
like he was a rape apologist,
but it was either a bad joke or it was a
little unclear,
rewarded clumsily or whatever.
Remember what it was.
We,
it can put,
we can probably find it pretty quick,
but I don't,
I don't remember exactly what it was.
But then suddenly I got all these people
saying,
you see Ruben had a rape apologist on,
he must hate women or you know,
something to that effect.
And it's like,
what you guys are doing is just,
you're picking,
okay,
so should I let you pick who I talked
to?
You know,
and that's like you should have the guy
on,
you'll get a certain amount of hate for
it,
but you'll have an a really interesting
conversation with him,
haven't you had
people that you've communicated with
that you thought were one way and as you
got to know them better and better,
you found out some stuff they had said
and you might,
Whoa,
I'll call it.
There's some things that people say that
is just absolutely are inarguable.
You can't,
you can't support it.
You know,
there's,
there's certain things that people have
said that inexcusable,
right?
Of course.
And you,
you might come across those two.
So I could see the point of taking some
things and maybe they might be even out
of context and using that to sort of
like say at the very least consider
this.
Sure.
But as an,
as an interviewer,
you're not,
you or I are not held to.
If we had to basically vet every person
that we ever sat down with for every
thought that they had three years ago on
twitter,
we would be,
I have a pretty Brooke and lonely life.
I'm out some pretty offensive people on
for sure.
I've gotten a lot of shit for the Milo
interviews.
I've gotten a lot of shift for some
other people that have so do you,
so,
so Milo,
I really like my life.
I had him over for dinner.
I've gone out with him.
I think he's a good guy.
He's,
he say shit that I would not say it's
working.
That's why we're talking about a much
like trump.
Yeah.
And that's why trump has done.
Exactly.
And then when they ban Milo,
what do you do?
You make him stronger.
The strategy effect.
I spoke,
I did a speech at a,
at Ucla with Milo were just a little
back and forth chat thing.
They had all of these kids out.
So first of all there were hundreds of
kids trying to get in.
But then there was this loud 200 kids
trying to literally block people.
So they're not against walls.
They don't,
you know,
they don't like trump's wall,
but they're okay.
But blocking a wall for other people to
exercise their free speech and they're
dumping garbage cans and spitting on
cops,
getting in cops faces with cameras,
like just begging them to just flip in a
second.
Anyway,
we have this great chat.
Um,
it was really funny actually,
at one point,
this girl in the audience,
she just busted about halfway through,
starts screaming.
She got an a,
you know,
people weren't,
didn't know she was a protestor.
She gets in,
she starts screaming,
I hate you,
blah blah.
So I stopped and I said,
I bet you actually we were going to do a
q and a at the end,
but I bet you right now if you ask my
little one question that you really have
burning or make one point,
I bet you he'll respond to you.
So I stopped the show ready for this.
So I said,
do you have one point?
And the girl
goes,
hey yo.
And it was like,
well,
she's a kid,
but that's how stupid these people,
are they stupid or are they just kids?
Like when you're talking about these
kids that are protesting and stopping
people from going into lectures or some
of these crazy feminists that have uh,
with,
you know,
the scene from the University of
Toronto,
very famous thing where they had this
guy,
they completely misrepresented his
opinions on things and they had painted
this guy out to be anti female and anti
woman and as some sort of a men's rights
thing,
which is a very bizarre thing.
Like you have to deny that men's rights
are applicable.
Like it can't,
if you can't be a feminist and also
recognize men's rights,
it's very,
very bizarre of a thing going on where
it's as much as trying to get back at
the perceived winners of the world when
you feel like you've been a loser of the
world.
That's where I think white privilege is
coming from and a lot of this stuff,
not to deny that white people have it
easier than black people in terms of
dealing with racism,
but it doesn't mean that those white
people are racist.
There's a lot of white people that are
your allies,
like the,
the,
the real problem is the racist
themselves,
not people who aren't victim of the
racist.
It's like saying that these people are
lucky.
Yeah,
for sure.
But painting it this some sort of a way
like where these privileged people,
they're assholes for for allowing this
privilege to even take place.
Now the problem is always singular.
The problem is racism itself,
the racist themselves,
the problem,
not that people aren't victim of the
individual,
not the collective and this is what the
left is doing that is literally
destroying culture and it destroyed.
We've man,
I think it's going to pull back just
like waves always do.
I think there's cycles to things.
I mean I think that's why we went from
the 60 to the seventies in the 70s to
the 80s I mean I think this is what I
mean.
It also responds to the condemnation of
psychedelic drugs and sweeping schedule.
One Act that passed in 1970 which was
directly attributable to the Richard
Nixon realizing that a lot of what was
going on while the people are coming
after him or part of the psychedelic
movement,
all these Republicans started like,
we've got to stop this.
The psychedelic movement will destroy
our culture.
You go from this gold water republican
era to all the sudden you're dealing
with freaks and hippies and Jimi Hendrix
and Janice Joplin,
and they're like,
stop the fucking fire.
They just threw as much water on it as
they could.
It locked a bunch of people in jail and
they created laws that made marijuana in
particular and all these other drugs.
They demonize them so that they could go
after the civil rights movement that
people that were in charge of it,
they got them for drugs and so they
would go after all these different anti
war protest movements.
They would go after them for drugs too.
And that schedule one classification of
these things that weren't dangerous or
deadly or killing anyone was directly
attributable to a strategy where they
were going after people that opposed the
Vietnam war going after people that
impose the administration,
clearly lying to them about all sorts of
things.
And that was before they even knew that
the Gulf of Tonkin was a false flag.
The original thing that got us into
Vietnam.
So there's so many,
there's so much evidence that that this,
this way that people behave when they
suppress things that it has.
There's a direct response,
first of all.
I mean,
if you attack someone,
they're wounded,
they're damaged,
and then they rise up and they'd go
after that attack.
And that's what you're seeing with the
alt right.
And I don't know if there,
I don't agree with him on a lot of
things they stand for,
but I recognize it almost as if I,
I'm not objective,
right?
I'm a person,
I'm a human being.
Like all of us,
I have my own shit.
But if I was outside of it,
trying to look at it objectively,
I'm like,
oh,
this thing goes like this.
And then it goes like that and it goes
like,
it's like a fucking swing.
It's like a pendulum.
It's like a Yin and a Yang.
It comes in and it comes out.
And I think one of the things that's
happening with this alt right movement
and these people that are really super
conservative and the build that fucking
wall build a fucking wall,
what you're dealing with is a response
to what they perceive to be.
Too much openness from the Obama
administration.
This fucking look,
Obama care,
I don't know enough about it.
I don't,
I don't know enough about it,
but I have friends that are doctors who
fucking,
hey,
I got a friend in docker in Texas a and
they,
and they spit when they talk to you and
they get red in the face and then they
have to stand back and take a drink.
I mean,
I know people that lost a practice.
I know a chiropractor lost his practice
because of it.
So I think there's,
there's a lot of people that are upset
at anyone who's the president.
Anyone who's the president,
if you don't get fucking shot.
Miss is a joke that I have for my last
special.
Who Do we like?
Kennedy and Lincoln.
That's what you like,
but you didn't get shot in the head.
We were like,
you fucking sell out.
What did you do?
I think that that is just the natural
reaction when we always have,
and I think that's why we go left,
right.
Left,
I don't think it's a coincidence that we
go right from George Bush to Bill
Clinton to George W.
Bush.
I don't think that's a coincidence.
Yeah.
I mean I think that's a very clear
response.
Or The com,
the government's like,
Whoa,
now we're this.
And the people like,
well that doesn't fucking work either.
Let's try this.
And then they swing back and forth.
Well then what do you make of what's
happening now?
[inaudible] she's very hockey.
So you think it actually is a swing
back,
right?
I think there's two factors here.
There's the woman factor,
which is gigantic cause there's a lot of
women that vote and a lot of men are
fuck ups right there.
They're probably going to vote.
I would imagine that women out vote men,
I really think they probably do.
I don't know.
I'm just totally guessing.
Let's find out Jamie.
But I would say that there's a slight
advantage.
I would say that maybe it'd be like 46
54 for women in favor of women that more
women vote.
But I think that you're,
you have also is,
there's no good choice here.
So this is a very unique situation.
You have this really strong anti woman
feeling that a lot of these gals get
from Donald Trump,
especially now.
Right?
There's that.
There's the the again and that
conversation that he had on that bus,
I've heard way worse for some people
that I love and cherish very deeply and
they're trying to be funny and they're
saying fucked up things that are totally
ridiculous.
He grows and a lot of them are saying it
because it's just you and me and you and
me and we'll just talk some shit.
Yeah.
And I run a bus.
Words are not action.
And that's what people need.
Understand if he died,
there you go.
Women voted higher rates than men.
That might help Clinton in November.
See what the numbers,
yeah,
there you go.
But it doesn't say it has different
numbers here.
Okay.
There's not an overall,
yeah,
no.
So the idea though,
that words are in action,
so I'm not defending the grab them by
the Pussy and blah,
blah,
blah.
And he was sort of saying that he had
done it in the past.
So if,
if there had been evidence that he had
done those actions actually assaulted,
which is no evidence unless you know a
women's vaginas not made out of
playdough.
It's not like fingerprints that are
permanent forever,
you know,
so that's fully legit.
But you can't prosecute him for just
saying.
That's my point is that words he said
some shit that was gross.
Right.
But it might have been true.
Yeah,
true.
So words and actions are two different
things.
Now maybe you can't prove those things
cause yeah,
they're not made out of play dough.
But that's still until it's provable.
You can't,
you can get outraged by it.
I see.
I see your point with the problem is
that just relying completely on the
burden of evidence being like physical
proof.
You're dealing with an act of people
touching each other's bodies and it's
just,
there's not a whole lot of proof when it
comes to that.
So I agree with that.
But then what do you do and where does
that put us?
Because we know that some people when
they,
when they give a a rape allegation,
you know,
we know that there's gonna be a lot of
people that are telling you the absolute
truth as they remember it.
There's also going to be crazy people
that make things up.
There's going to be some spectrum in
between those two things.
Where are you going to have people that
exaggerate situations that I'm sure
you've had any conversations that you've
had with people that maybe you've had a
disagreement and they go to someone else
and they completely reframed a
disagreement,
like you're a piece of shit.
It's a common thing that people do.
We love to do it and we love to do it
for all kinds of things.
And I've been guilty of it and I'm sure
you have and everybody listening to this
thing I'm sure as we are learning the
very complicated game of communication
with human beings and how much is
involved in it,
the ego and personality conflicts and
where you are in your life and your own
stresses and frustrations and whenever
the fuck is going on,
whatever is going on in this big
struggle that we're all involved in,
right?
W there's not always a very clear
perception of how events went down.
Yeah.
So see you have to take that into
consideration.
You also have to take any consideration
the fact they might be telling the
truth.
We do not know.
So it's not that there's no evidence
because there's people that are talking,
it's just,
it's nothing you can put on a scale and
we don't know how to read minds yet.
And the problem is if you read minds,
man,
right,
I find some fucking memories of things.
Then I went back and looked at them
again like a video or something.
And I'm like,
wow,
I didn't even know when to,
they're like,
we just went over that the other day I
was talking about Tommy hearns versus
Marvin Hagler.
She's like,
one of my all time favorite fights.
I would have swore it was a second round
knockout.
No,
they went to a third round.
Hagwon knocked him out in the third
round.
I'm like,
how the fuck did it in my mind,
I would have told you,
I'll bet you $1,000.
It was the second round and I was wrong.
I remembered it.
I remembered it wrong.
There was moments in the fight with the
fights playing out and this is something
that doesn't have any attachment to me
in my life.
Obviously.
I'm not like saying that someone's going
to throw in memory.
I'm not,
especially someone who is involved in
some sort of a violent crime where the
victim,
you know,
I don't know because I think it's gotta
be absolutely horrific and it's entirely
possible that some people can go through
an assault or a crime like that and
remember everything.
And then there's other people that
cannot cause people that even black out
horrible things because the memory is so
disturbing to them that they have to,
they,
they blocked them out.
Especially molestations a lot of people
go through that later in life when they
realize like what they were trying to
suppress.
Your brain is like literally trying to
save you from these memories because
they're too fucking painful.
So what it does is it buries them,
I don't know how it works,
they don't understand it,
but this is real.
Then people suddenly at 40 they go,
wait a minute is a proven effect.
It's a proven effect.
So there's all these things that we need
to take into consideration.
I think there's also the very real
cultural benefit of having our first
woman president.
I think culturally what I do,
I just don't think that she's a good
representative in terms of like her need
for financial compensation for speeches
and the Goldman Sachs connection and the
connection to the Saudis.
I also don't have a fucking clue as to
what it's like to deal with foreign
policy and foreign leaders.
And I don't know.
I don't know if that's even a voidable
but that's the thing.
It's like,
you know,
people will say,
well the,
the she's in bed with the Saudis or
something.
Well guess what?
The Saudis,
whether we like it or not,
who do horrific things and explored all
kinds of Wahhabi Islam and real
extremism and or bombing the shit out of
Yemen and with our weapons and all kinds
of stuff.
Well she also took $1 million from
Qatar.
Qatar right now is using slave labor to
build their World Cup stadium,
which there may not even get the World
Cup.
So
it's like every,
why did they give her $1 million?
It's for something.
You know what I mean?
It's not for nothing.
You don't give $1 million for no reason.
So,
but that again goes to like,
we're seeing how all this shit is made
right now.
And the simple fact is if you're upset
that she has a close relationship with
the Saudis,
then you got to hate Obama for it to
where I think a lot of these people are
letting that slide.
I'm,
I'm not even making a judgment call on
it as much to say is this,
there are things that are going on at
extremely high levels for governments
and that we just have to try to decipher
some truth to it because we're not going
to get another way.
Saudi Arabia,
women can't drive.
They can barely go out without men.
They are stuck in,
as Bill Maher says,
beekeeper costumes in the Burkas,
right?
I mean all of these things,
well,
how could they possibly be our ally if
we're for women,
if Barack Obama is for women,
if Hillary Clinton is for women,
how is Saudi Arabia one of our most
stable allies that we give a ton of
money too,
if,
if that's what it is.
The only thing that I would take into
consideration is that if I was trying to
figure this out as an outsider,
I would see there's gotta be some
benefit to keeping people like that
connected to you and obligated to
communicate with you and oils and your
friend,
but not just the oil.
Also some other publishing,
a non combative relationship with a
very,
very wealthy Middle East country that
they're more could be done with honey
than with vinegar.
You know,
this idea of being connected with those
people,
there might be some sort of a benefit
because they're so alien to us and
they're so dominant in their control
over their environment.
Like you look at these dictators in this
foreign,
these foreign countries that we
supported for so many years and you can
make the argument that they're horrible,
absolutely terrible people that we
should have nothing to do with.
You could also make the argument that
that part of the world is so fucked up
that you have to somehow or another
maintain some sort of friendly
connection to the people that are in
power.
And then that might be the best way to
keep everybody safe.
While we figured out a fucking strategy,
how to deal with religious
fundamentalist,
crazy people that literally have
trillions of dollars at their disposal
to do anything they want from the
Saudis.
By yes,
but not just from the Saudis.
I mean there's a gigantic chunk of the
Middle East that has so much money,
it's incomprehensible and not everyone,
just a few people,
oligarchy,
monarchs and these people that have
looked at,
in Abu Dhabi,
they make it rain every week.
They make it rain.
Literally.
They literally see the sky to do cloud
seeding and they make it rain like it's
the desert and they use their money to
make it rain.
Like not a strip club and you're not
using one
is that wasn't hyperbole.
It was actual real well,
think about Egypt is the best example of
what you're talking about because Egypt
for 30 years had Mubarak,
this was a guy,
he was a military guy backed by the
United States.
Horrible on on a human rights and all
that other stuff.
But he kept control of the country,
basically kept their borders,
kept peace with Israel,
basically kept things under control.
I was in Egypt in 97 and it was pretty
disgusting actually.
Even go to the pyramids.
It was the,
the pollution was terrible.
Uh,
it was the people weren't friendly.
Like I would love to go back.
I have a friend there now who I,
uh,
who's a youtube or this Guy Joe,
who probably will show his face.
He's an atheist and a free thinker.
Um,
if I could ever get him to the United
States,
you should have me enter.
The guy's really,
he's great.
Freely and openly and Egypt.
Sometimes he disappears for months and
then the side,
he doesn't really publicly say exactly
what he's doing.
But when I had him on the show,
I said to him,
you know,
if you want to wear a spiderman mask,
you don't have to show your face.
You know,
you do whatever you want.
And he said,
no,
I want to show my face.
So anyway,
they had Mubarak for 30 years.
He kept the Muslim Brotherhood.
They were illegal under the time.
Then they have the Tahrir Square,
a revolution.
What happens?
They,
we deposed,
we partly,
they depose Mubarak,
they get the Muslim Brotherhood through
democracy,
and then a year later they realize these
guys are way worse.
So what they got from democracy was way
worse.
So then what happens?
The military then steps in and then has
a coup overthrows the democracy.
And now they have a military leader
again,
United States the entire time to support
it.
All of that.
So it's like,
this is the problem with democracy.
And we know this from Iraq too.
It's like you can give democracy,
but if the institutions aren't there
ready to support it,
you could get a lot of bad people then.
And then
it's over like what the Hell's going on?
And you mentioned Bengazi before we got
rid of Qaddafi who was obviously a bad
dude.
You have any idea what kind of
government there isn't it
fear right now?
Nobody knows is a scary state.
That's a state of chaos,
right?
So it was a state,
but you're more aware of uh,
Amber Lyon and a amber Lyon when she was
working for CNN and she did a piece on
bowel rain.
No notice I said bow rain like an
American,
not Bahrain Lane.
Um,
thank you for dumbing that down for me.
It's not that I just don't want to be
pretentious and puts born to check what
Obama says.
Bucky stun Pakistan.
Yeah.
Or Latinos or Latinos.
Well now you have to say Latin ex so
that you're not,
it's not Latino's that implies men or
Latino women.
Now you say Latin X.
Cause if you're a fucking,
why don't we call ourselves to Max?
I said a humanz genetics.
I like it.
I'm know.
Humanics that sounds dope.
Yeah.
Um,
what,
what kind of species are there?
Humanics yeah,
sounds like male,
female and female.
Who?
Max.
Whew,
man.
Right.
It's so rude.
It's rude.
Why not you?
Whoa man,
man.
When history,
what about her story?
I mean,
come on Joe.
Yeah,
man.
What about her story?
So amber lions,
because of her stories,
she does this,
um,
investigative piece on Bahrain and a CNN
completely turns it into like a vacation
and tourism commercial and they cut out
all the bad stuff aired it.
And uh,
I don't remember if she did.
Jamie,
do you remember she got fired if she
went up resigning,
do you remember anyway?
Um,
that sounds like a resigning.
It was.
I don't if she was fired.
If she resigned.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I don't remember.
But the point is,
she came on my podcast,
she wrote a book.
Um,
and um,
she sort of explained like what,
what would really go on when you tried
to put together these pieces and you
know,
in,
in defense of CNN,
they,
I know they had a rebuttal to what she
said and they disagreed with her,
her framing of it,
her memory of it,
you know,
I don't know,
but it sounds to me like whatever stuff
that she found that was very
questionable did not make the air.
And that's probably why.
I mean there was the CIA's talked pretty
openly about having people that work in
different news organizations where they
sort of framed the news.
Yeah.
Well look,
that goes to everything we've been
talking about this,
it all seems to be coming back to this
idea of the online world and the old
school thing,
they're like starting to have parody now
where what we're doing is as an
influential,
you,
Joe Rogan is more influential than
anybody on CNN in reality.
In the reality of,
yeah,
but not a Fox News.
That man,
she,
Megan Kelly,
so hot.
If you weren't gay,
Dude,
do you understand?
Still do it well,
it's still doing so hot.
She is.
She's so something violent about her.
God Damn.
Something violent like masculine.
Like you would think of her as a man.
So she,
I feel like she has a big Dick.
Wow.
Isn't it her brain though?
It's in her breakdown.
Externalizes oh yeah.
You know they're trying to give her $20
million and she hasn't accepted yet or
you go girl,
get that 40 you get 40 it's fucking
worth it.
The networks useless without you
wherever she goes.
I'm watching.
Isn't that crazy though?
I mean,
think about it like 20 million bucks.
Skipped perfect cheeks.
She does.
She deserves it.
She's very good talk.
She's good man.
She's very eloquent.
Did you see that thing that you went,
went at it with Newt Gingrich?
Newt Gingrich is a fucker,
isn't he?
He's,
you know,
I have a little bit of a love hate thing
with them cause I do the,
he's really smart.
He's very smart guy.
He's really smart.
He understands.
Like when I talked before about like
knowing what the role of government is
and all that stuff that we should know
more about in civics and all that.
Like that guy gets it in and out and
whether you agree with his politics or
not,
he did do some stuff with the contract
with America to with America to,
you know,
move the country in a certain way.
I'm actually surprised he hasn't run for
president.
Well he ran four years ago and they
basically remember at that point when
it's right.
That was the whole thing with his wife
and he left,
his wife was sick and had another bra.
In a weird way he was the precursor to
trump because you remembered that during
those primaries he would be,
you know,
he was really good with zingers and with
some comedy and he would get the
audience to applaud and cheer and boo
talking about the media,
the media and they boo and hiss and then
suddenly the moderators started saying
every time there'll be no booing or
applauding or,
and it's like sit there like a fucking
robot.
It's 1984 and eight press here.
Just stay.
That's American.
It's American.
They do it now in the debates door.
There'll be silence.
You know?
It's like,
cause she'd be in jail.
Remember that?
Yeah.
Oh,
you'd be in jail cause it should be in
jail.
That was in my mind,
the best bomb ever dropped on a
presidential debate next to I knew Jack
Kennedy.
You're no jacket.
Remember that?
Against Dan Quayle.
We don't even remember who the other
dude is.
Lloyd Benson.
Yeah.
Yeah,
man.
Politics.
That seems like something else.
You talked about parallel universe.
It doesn't that I watched,
this is going to sound,
this is going to be corny as hell,
but about two weeks ago I was sitting a
Saturday.
If you're going,
I'm just flipping the channels.
Cspan comes on and they're replaying the
1992 debate between George Hw Bush.
Bill Clinton running for the first time
and Perot and I watched about a half
hour of it,
I think three o'clock on a Saturday and
he really was like being in an alternate
universe.
It felt so different.
They were actually talking about
economics or Ross Perot with is try and
I'm going to do this and we don't know.
You're kind of me and Wilma and bill.
Good.
Oh I do.
And it was like wow.
There was actual,
it was about politics.
Maybe it was completely fucked up.
Maybe it was all bullshit and lies and
all that stuff,
but it was about politics and that was
only,
what is that?
That's 20 years ago basically.
Yeah.
This is a different era.
This is the reality TV show air.
You know,
I used to have this joke that I never
figured out how to get to work,
but it's sort of just an observation
that there's so many people with shows
where there's just a pr like this is
like when Jersey shore was around,
like we're going to have a show one day
where it's going to be a reality show
about a reality camera man.
And then we're going,
why?
We're going to follow that guy around as
he goes to all these exotic places and
films,
these people getting drunk on the beach.
And then one day we're going to want to
know who's the man behind the camera,
behind the man behind the camera and
then we're going to follow that guy
around.
He's going to get a reality show is
going to be a reality show about a
camera man who's on a reality show about
a camera man who's a reality.
Show.
Cameramen deeper and deeper and deeper
until the whole world is filled with
people on a reality show while they're
holding up a camera like two mirrors
facing themselves with infinite camera
man in each direction.
That's what we have right now.
I mean there's some good weed.
Well this is what we have though is
good,
but that's a,
it's an old bit that I never figured out
how to get to work,
but the point being is like this is what
we're experiencing.
This is what we're experiencing with
phones.
Like it's,
it might not be on a network on a bravo
coming up next at eight it's Mike the
camera man on a reality show.
It doesn't have to be by a network.
It is what you're having with something
like periscope.
It is what you're having when people are
alive,
facebook streaming from,
you know,
amusement parks or whatever the fuck
they're doing.
It's a reality show.
How do you,
how do you blend,
how much of your Joe Rogan,
actual human versus Joe Rogan,
the public person,
how do you,
where do you put that line in terms of
periscoping from home or showing I don't
do this stuff because they're not
public.
People know my wife and kids aren't
public people.
Yeah.
They don't want to be,
they're just regular people.
Just because they know me,
it doesn't mean I should drag them into
this nonsense.
I just think all of us could do better
with a little less interaction
digitally.
I think it's happening so fast that,
you know,
like we're talking about people at
restaurants that are constantly on their
phone and when you check them on it,
they get upset.
I've been upset.
People telling me to put my phone down,
I'm like,
I got to do this.
Yeah,
it's normal.
It's natural reaction.
I think we have,
I think,
um,
all of us are going to eventually though
step into that great divide and the
future is going to be everybody all the
time connected to everybody all the
time.
And it's going to be very weird.
It's going to change thought.
I think it's going to,
I think we really are going to become
like some sort of a bizarre hive mind.
Well they do.
They've done studies where the Internet
already,
when they look at Internet addicts that
they find that the,
the wiring in their brain actually has
changed.
It's changed certain synapse.
It's actually caused like membranes to
shrink into all kinds of stuff.
Last,
uh,
I think it was may I for eight days and
I never,
I'd never take off.
I don't remember the last time I took
like some actual time of,
I took eight days off,
went to Mexico.
I locked my phone in a safe,
whoa.
We're actually,
my husband did it lock the phone in the
safe.
I did not know the code word for eight
days.
I sat on a beach.
It was at like an Olympian.
It was like a digital moderately,
the dirtiest thing we've ever done.
Do you want that phone?
It was really,
it was why.
Um,
but for eight days I had no phone and I
kid you not,
I mean I felt my brain kind of
resetting.
I felt some things happening and also I
felt more,
I felt more patient.
I felt like,
you know,
in conversations where,
not like this,
but where you're constantly just
distracted by every little thing.
Like I got away from it and then when I
got back on the grid,
you know,
because immediately the second I got off
the plane and I was,
you know,
doing my thing,
I realize,
wow,
you know,
the world went on and it was all right.
It was actually okay.
Yeah.
I missed some shit.
Something,
something happened on my show that took,
that got a lot of news.
I didn't know about it for eight days,
but like,
yeah,
it was just like some shit happened.
Yeah.
I,
I mean,
like I said,
I'm not trying to judge people who are
using these things,
using these devices.
I'm just trying to talk about it as
honestly as I can because I think it's
almost inevitable.
But I think for your own personal good,
it has to be managed carefully.
I think you have to take audit of all
the stuff that's in your life.
And if you spend like I have an hour and
a half just reading through tweets about
like almost nothing and just looking for
something interesting.
Just constantly scrolling,
looking for something interesting.
Like step away from that thing.
Cause you're,
you're impulsively or me speaking to me,
talking to me impulsively checking
images on instagram.
What Cool Shit did people post up?
You know what interesting.
And my main news is out there right now,
but you know what is uh,
the,
the latest trending topics on twitter?
Yeah.
After a while.
Like what the fuck am I doing?
What,
how about my life?
What about me as a person?
Like what am I doing?
I'm not even paying attention.
Yeah.
Well that's why I framed it like that
between Joe Rogan,
the public person,
and then actually the human that has to
go ahead and live and do this operation.
And kids and a wife
and all those things.
Those are two separate things.
And yet you got to bring them somehow
into harmony so that they can exist
together.
A big ones.
Meditation,
thinking,
Meditation and thinking about what you
actually want to do versus what your
momentum is leading you towards.
And for me it's isolation tanks.
That's the big one.
You know,
I have one of my patients,
I use it all the time.
I think about things.
They're in an undistracted way and I
take an evaluation of like how I'm
thinking and I,
it was always like it.
And that's one of the things that people
don't like about getting high.
And it's one of the things that people
don't like about isolation tanks and or
yoga class too.
It was talking with my yoga instructor
the other day and you know,
she was saying it forces people to
examine their shit.
It does,
it forces you to look at your stuff when
you're struggling,
you know?
And Yoga seems so easy when you just say
the word.
It seems like something,
Oh,
you're just grabbing your feet and you
know,
it's fucking hard.
Man,
it's hard and everyone was 104 degrees.
Speaking of fucked up,
did you see that?
Uh,
Hbo,
real sports things with that be from
guy.
They interviewed beak from Yoga,
got holy Shit.
People are,
they're taking their name,
his name off the yoga studio now he's
killing people.
No,
no,
no.
He's just a like a crazy fuck.
Who was saying that all these women you
know have lied because he's been accused
of sexual assault and that people pay $1
million for one drop of his sperm.
He's like one drop of my sperm.
$1 million.
I mean he's,
he's a guru,
right?
Yeah.
He's uses Yoga Guru who's responsible
for,
it's one.
It's really an excellent sort of an
analogy to how weird and fucked up human
beings are that we are not perfect in
any way,
shape or form.
You have this guy who brought this thing
its beak from yoga to America and he
didn't create it.
It's been around for thousands of years
and he tried to sue people for the
patent and all the movements he lost.
He there was like,
you can't pat in Yoga,
but this guy has brought yoga and,
and sort of promoted yoga too.
Who knows how many millions of people.
He's like one of the most directly
responsible people for promoting this
stuff.
But then you see him as a person,
he's a crazy fuck.
He won't let people go to the bathroom.
You have to sit there and listen to them
talk and if you have to go,
you're going to go in your pants.
Like it's all like cult shit.
It makes them stay up all night and
watch bollywood movies.
It's like a fuck you.
He's a crazy man.
He's got rolls royces and shit.
And they busted him with all these cars
and he said that he was gonna open up a
school for children to learn
automobiles.
Oh yeah.
That's why I bought these Rolls Royces.
It's a school for underprivileged
children with Rolls Royce.
It's amazing.
But I think,
but that goes to the worship thing that
we were talking about and that's like
when we see these people worshiping
Hillary or worshiping trump and it's
like they are not going to solve all
your problems and not only are they not
going to stop weapons,
they shouldn't.
The president should.
The president should keep the road safe.
The president should make sure nobody
bombs us.
The president should make sure the
economy keeps chugging.
Just think about the shit jobs that you
just
said.
How does one person have those three
important jobs?
It's fucking crazy.
You get a guy for the roads.
If it's ridiculous,
you get the department or something.
I call him,
hey man,
you're doing a job.
Yeah,
got to go check these roads working sly
in Arizona.
Let me see the road.
But the road,
but that's actually,
that's actually the point.
Like they're not supposed to be our
guide.
They're not supposed to be our emperor.
They're supposed to keep the ship
afloat,
but as human beings,
we want champs.
We want it.
God.
We want.
Yeah.
We want to bring jfk back to life when a
clone them and even him,
he would never survive today.
All the crazy shit that guy was up to.
That's the point.
It's like he would have made wiener
looked like a Catholic school gave him
or that's Graham gram account.
I think there's so many people like that
that are complicated.
They're not that we have this narrative
that's been created by film and buy
books.
We have this false narrative of this
perfect human being.
This John Wayne care two rides off into
the sunset,
this clint eastwood who are,
you know,
Sondra Locke has always waving goodbye
to him.
He's your rides off and away from the
Indian.
It's like this is all a false narrative
and it's created in such a potent way
that our brains are stained by that and
we kind of expect that out of our
leaders instead of,
I think that's not the case in other
countries,
like in Europe in particular,
right?
In Europe,
like in France,
like politicians dare fucking affairs
and shit.
Nabisco running a brothel or something,
you know,
like,
hey,
we're having,
it's Italy.
Italy is another example.
It's a different world.
I mean we've developed a very strange
culture over here in America.
Very strange and and,
and a lot of ways confused culture both
in the positive and in the negative,
you know,
and bolt and the condemnation of things
that people like trump have said or you
know,
people like Clinton have allegedly done.
And also our reaction to it,
both of them were,
we're weird.
We're just fucking weird man.
And I don't,
I don't think we've really fully
embraced our weirdness as a species yet.
I think that's part of the problem with
being a president in the first place.
It's based on bullshit.
Like it's,
it's based on the idea that you can give
people power and they won't abuse it
because of an ancient scroll.
That's really what it is.
Someone,
many,
many moons ago before electricity,
they figured out how to make anc of like
bugs and shit.
Whether you use charcoal,
the fuck they used to make any,
I was going to buy the bugs.
That seems sensible.
They dip their quill into that and they
would write on a scroll,
which by the way,
it was mostly made out of hemp.
Most of these hemp paper.
Well look,
everyone is incredibly complex and it
has to do with we're all flawed.
We all fail every day and succeed at
other things.
You could look at,
look at Thomas Jefferson.
I was at,
my cousin got married near Monte Cello
in Virginia where,
and that's,
you know,
that's where his house was and
everything where he,
uh,
where he lived and owned slaves and had
sex with some of the slaves and one of
the slaves had sex with several of them.
I think he was having a good time.
Yeah,
he did.
But think about that.
He was writing the very,
that ultimately
freed the slaves while at the same time
in effect,
you could argue,
and I'm sure people have argued this,
that he was raping a slave because if it
is about power,
even if she was fully down with it,
she was his slave.
So,
so,
but at the same time he was also a
writing the very laws to free them.
That shows you how,
how flawed all of us are that you could
hate,
you could hate him for,
for owning slaves.
You could hate him for having this
relationship with this woman and all
that.
And at the same time he was instrumental
in writing the very laws that made us
all equal.
So that goes and you could,
that's why it's so dangerous when you
look back on a different time and you
try to apply our morality of today on
other people.
It's on other times.
It's so dangerous because you could look
at him and go,
fuck that guy.
Let's,
let's erase every bit of history the way
we did with the dukes of hazzard car and
all that shit.
And it,
that's crazy.
It's a thing that existed.
Confederate flags go back to generally
gets you to the generally,
yeah.
I just think it should be on the car and
TV.
Land shouldn't have taken the show off
the air.
You know what I mean?
Like Bill Cosby,
I told you this last time I was here.
Like that guy was my hero.
I went into comedy because I was five
years old and I saw bill cosby himself
when he's talking about chocolate cake
and Theo and Vanessa,
the whole thing.
And I thought it was the funniest
fucking thing ever and it changed my
life.
It changed the course of my life.
Now my childhood hero is the biggest
serial rapist of all time.
Of all time.
Yeah.
That's depressing.
That's another great example.
Holy should really think about what
goodness,
you could absolutely draw a line between
bill cosby and Barack Obama.
You can clearly draw a line that if bill
cosby and that shows
they're both black.
So there you go.
No,
but you could draw a line to say that if
that show had not been on NBC primetime
in had he not done that,
that middle class upstanding family.
But that was incredibly funny and all
the great stuff about cosby that that
led to eventually 20 some odd years
later,
Barack Obama being president and,
and at the same time he was a horrific
rapist.
Do you think that like a lot of his
morality,
and this goes back to the sort of tied
thing,
slingshot effect,
that a lot of his sort of projected
morality was to make up for the fact
that it was drug and chicks and rape.
And I'm so he was America's Dad.
Right.
And he was also like the ups down
upstanding citizen for the black
community to get upset if comedians
would swear that whole thing with Eddie
Murphy.
Yeah.
I mean,
and not just him or not just uh,
Eddie Murphy.
But I believe the same with Dave
Chappelle.
I think he had a problem with Chris
Rock.
You know what he,
what he stood for as was like this
really conservative,
really friendly,
you know,
don't we don't talk about Dick's and
pussies and all that stuff.
Like he had a whole thing about like
when he was really old to before he got
caught,
it was a whole thing about w w talk
about it,
but we don't hit it.
We don't hit on it.
W W we know what I'm saying.
Can every comedian do
a cause we can't even that impressive.
And probably the only time I've ever
tried it,
but it's pretty decent.
Thank you.
Yeah,
I need it needs work.
Let's be honest.
But the point being is that this guy was
the most vocal.
Yeah.
You'd never heard of the common,
like you never heard George Wallace tell
other comedians what they should do.
You know,
you never hear that from Paul,
you know,
Paul Mooney maybe.
But there's,
you know what I'm saying?
Like it's like you don't,
well,
I guess partly partly that may have been
because cosby became such a big
institution.
You know what I mean?
It wasn't like,
I love both those guys,
especially George Wallace,
I think is like absolutely hilarious,
but he never got the level of mainstream
success where what he says has some sort
of cultural significance right.
Within the comedy world.
Cosby got to the place of it.
It's something else.
It's beyond,
it's beyond what,
99.9,
nine,
9% of comics or any public figure
actually gets,
he gets a place in the scheme of
history,
so,
well,
yeah,
it's different.
He was,
uh,
he was the best example of like the
elevated person from this minority.
Like the best example,
very well spoken.
He got a doctorate.
I can't think it got a kind of a legit
one or you got an honorary one?
I pretty sure it was legit.
One was like from a paper that he had to
write and graduate school or something
like that.
See if you,
I think you got a legit one from New
Jersey.
He's actually an h cosby.
Write that out to me.
Yeah.
But I mean you can get an honorary
doctorate just for your humanitarian
work or cause people think you're slick.
Well,
heath cliff huxtable was a ob Gyn,
so there you go.
It must've went to school there.
I must have.
Yeah.
Um,
I think that you see,
you grab her by the Pussy,
but you'd give her a drink first.
Trump.
See now if you went to run for
president,
they go back to that.
They'd take that out of context and I
go,
what the fuck did that caused me
worshiping pussy grabbing.
You'll see.
But it isn't it.
Here it goes.
Is this is sometimes referred to as
doctor Cosby.
He has his doctorate in education from
the University of Massachusetts in
Amherst.
He earned the degree in the mid 1970s a
thesis entitled the Integration of
Visual Media via fat Albert and the
Cosby kids.
That's what I did my doctorate on.
How weird.
Okay.
It's a teaching aide and vehicle to
achieve increased learning.
That's interesting.
So,
so that goes to your point,
did a,
was the public person really just
defending the horrible actions of the
private person,
but also he clearly was trying to do
good work,
but here it says,
but how he got his degree has been
controversial ever since.
According to Michael Eric Dyson,
a sociology professor at Georgetown
University and acclaimed author of his
Bill Cosby,
right.
And numerous other books.
Cosby dropped out of high school after
he flunked his 10th grade three times.
He enlisted in the navy where he got his
ged.
They enrolled at temple where he dropped
out to pursue a show business career is
unfinished.
Bachelor degree from Temple was
eventually it bestowed upon him because
of his life experience.
Cosby enrolled in a part time doctoral
student as the University of
Massachusetts Amherst,
which awarded home.
See?
So that's it.
So he dropped out of high school,
came back,
got his ged enrolled in temple,
dropped out of that and got a doctorate
for writing about a cartoon.
But even the bachelor's degree,
they're saying he had an unfinished
bachelor's degree because of life
experience.
So he didn't get that degree reality.
Wow,
that's wild.
So both of them.
So it's not entirely true.
I mean,
he did get a degree,
but obviously there's a,
there's an asterick attached to that.
Yeah.
But,
but separating it from that,
it's like that,
that thing that you're talking about is,
is pretty powerful stuff.
That what you,
that he was doing this horrible shit
until and yet.
And yet he enriched so many lives at the
same time,
literally at the same time that he was
doing this horrible stuff to these
women.
He was bringing so much goodness to the
country.
That's,
that's deep.
You know,
there's fucking deep and that's people.
No,
I think the sooner we recognize how
flawed human beings are,
the the better we're going to be off.
And I think also on a,
this is another thing that I've talked
about on stage before,
but it's a real issue.
I don't think human beings are designed
to take in the data for media.
I don't think we can truly distinguish
the difference between false narratives
and fiction.
I mean,
I know we can,
you know,
when you go to see a fucking movie,
you know it's a movie you leave.
Lao is a good movie man.
God Damn,
can't wait for doctor.
Strange to,
you know,
we know it's a movie,
but there's an impact that that data has
on our mind that we have to,
even though we have to separate it and
move it around,
that impact is there were designed to
follow like the tribal leader,
this old guy with scars who's fucking
survived battles and he has wisdom and
he knows the poems and we sit around the
fire and we follow him because of actual
real live accomplishments in real life.
Things that we've seen him do.
And it's how he stays alive is I stay
alive.
Whereas only 30 of us.
Okay,
we've got fucking bear skins on and
we're living in a cave and we,
we don't have much time.
We got to follow that guy.
He knows how to stay alive and we might
not make it.
And this is a very real concern because
we know tribes that are gone,
right?
So this is how human beings develop for
fucking thousands of thousands of years.
If you believe in evolution,
when we went from being a monkey to
being a guy who's addicted to a cell
phone,
there was a lot of steps along the way.
And in those steps we developed a lot of
these human reward systems where you get
you,
you get used to and look forward to
certain things was those things,
those rewards will keep you alive.
Whether it's being attractive to
females,
the will spread your DNA.
That when you must be concerned about
this,
whether it's a overcoming the
adversaries,
because if you don't,
they're going to kill you.
Like you have to stay alive.
You gotta be,
you have to figure out how to stay quiet
when you're hunting is one of the
reasons today why women enjoy gossip and
men enjoy quiet and why the two are
sometimes incompatible.
Like there's a design,
women are designed,
they were trying to keep the fucking
tribe together so that sit around
washing clothes.
She got this dirty bitch fucks everybody
when we go to sleep.
Like that's,
that's
where it came from.
Yeah.
And with the men they were out of these
hunting parties and like shy,
everybody shut the fuck up.
What's pay attention?
We gotta be,
we gotta stay close here.
And this is the whole reason why there's
a difference in the way these to behave.
And this has all been like well
established by sociologists,
by people who have studied human
behavior.
I think that where we're at now with
movies and songs,
you're getting this data in a way.
We don't know how to process.
We obviously internally,
you know,
we obviously can rationalize and go,
well I know that's just a song.
Or I know that's just a movie.
And I know the Indiana Jones isn't a
real guy and he wouldn't just survive
every time the fucking bowling ball size
boulder comes his way.
He would,
he would get killed.
Then he got in the fridge and parked for
you
to fucking Ark of the covenant.
How do you survive the,
come on man.
There's a lot of shit going on in that.
I could accept that the fucking news
goes to be apocalyptic.
All of it.
It's supposed to be replacing the dark.
Yeah.
The way it looked the other way from the
nuke.
That's all he needed to do.
Kidney Cancer.
He's got a fucking cool hat.
But those,
those narratives and this,
this life version is all data that's
entered into the human consciousness.
And the more we expose ourselves to it,
when kids are watching eight hours of
fucking television and uh,
people were like constantly and gross in
their phones and all this like two
dimensional data and video and all these
different things on youtube,
the more that stuff gets into your mind,
into your life,
the less you're experiencing the actual
life.
It's almost like a preparation for us
being a part of this hive mind.
Like these are the steps you take when
you create this sort of new type of
being.
I mean,
it's integrated.
You're,
you're talking about the matrix that
we're,
we're slowly morphing into this thing.
And that's why,
you know,
people have to understand that what
happens there isn't real yet.
So like,
you know,
sorta jumping all the way back to that,
Leslie,
don't think it,
when people say mean things to you,
I'm sure if you would look at your
twitter right now,
somebody is probably saying something
mean they will now how they're going to
be really pissed.
You're a bully.
You told them to do it.
You see you,
you've sick.
Don't worry.
There's a lot of mine are you already?
So they'll,
they'll turn it on me door.
We're all fine.
But uh,
but point is that,
that those words,
it goes to that words are not acting
thing like it.
So what someone said something mean to
you,
you got to get over it.
So,
for example,
part of my,
uh,
this is gonna sound sort of Corny,
but part of my success in the last year
is directly related to you because your
name,
because my show is my,
for real,
my show was taken off when I was on here
last time.
And by you giving it a little bump here
and then you've been,
you've been real good to me on social
media.
You helped amplify what I do.
And in the process of that,
I now all my social media,
when I scroll in a weird way,
it's become sort of meaningless.
It's become all noise because if 95% of
its good,
which it usually is low,
then it's like,
oh there's another nice one.
It's nice and it is nice,
you know,
I'm not demeaning and people giving you
compliments just a nice things or I like
what you're doing or retweeting what I'm
doing or whatever.
That's all nice.
And then the bad ones come in and then,
you know,
for whatever reason I focus on the bad
ones more.
But then I just let it all becomes noise
and I'm just like,
you know what?
I just have to do what I do and then let
the rest of it be I,
you know what I mean?
We probably at this point can't respond
to everybody anymore.
Oh No,
I can't.
No,
it's it.
But that's the thing.
It's not fun anymore.
Like part of the,
the price to pay for a little success
here is that the part that used to be
fun when I would play around with people
more on there and spend more time
interacting.
It's like,
it's become such like a cal vacate of
craziness that I,
I just don't have the time where I
didn't have the mental bandwidth more
than anything else.
I have a lot going on and it's like,
so that's been a little bit of a
sacrifice along the way.
But yeah,
but that's just comes with the program.
Especially when you're thinking about
the numbers of people that you're
reaching.
Nobody ever had to do that.
Like madmen magic.
Johnny Carson had a twitter account and
he was trying to interact with all the
fans where he got email carson tonight,
show.com and he's like,
did not know that there's,
look at all those fucking email.
How am I gonna respond to these people?
If you don't,
they get mad at you.
They were,
but this one good thing that's going on
is people don't expect you to do that
when you reach a certain number of fans.
Like I get way more,
um,
messages from people that say,
Hey,
I love the podcast or a great job in the
UFC,
or something like that.
That those kind of messages I get way
more often than someone actually trying
to get me to respond to things I would
like to do if I had,
I had that kind of time,
but no one has that kind of time.
Right.
That's what I'm saying.
There's just a certain amount and that
goes to combining public person and
private person.
Like there's a certain amount of
bandwidth that your brain has that all
of us have to do what,
whatever it is we do.
I could,
we,
the two of us could sit here for 24
hours in a row and just respond to
things and blah,
blah blah.
And it's like your brain also has to be
able to breathe well.
Your spirit has to be able to breathe,
you have to live life.
And I think if you have anything to
offer,
and this one of the things that I'm
finding,
it's kind of important to me and I've
tried to,
I've tried to engineer this in my own
life in a way,
is that I've got to have as much life
experiences or more than I do work
because like just working.
Like if I just did podcasts every day,
I would have things to say because
there's always something going on in the
world.
But I think I wouldn't be doing my own
perspective,
a service I think to do my perspective
of serve it,
to,
to be honest about it.
I need to experience things.
I needed to live life.
I needed to,
uh,
you know,
travel to places.
Yeah.
I needed to do things that are difficult
and I need to get involved in a lot of
activities.
I like to do different things because I
think first of all,
because I enjoy them first and foremost.
And I think embracing that I enjoy them
benefits me and a great way to,
yeah.
Because when I do things that I enjoy
it,
I get happy.
When I get happy,
I work better,
you know?
And I think if,
if I didn't do that and if I didn't like
actively seek out,
it would just,
it's really easy for a lot of people.
A lot of people find this,
they get caught up in work so much that
that's all they focus on.
And then,
then I think you stop being the person
who got to that position in the first
place.
The person who got to that position in
the first place got there because people
liked what you talked about,
what you thought
about.
And then the only way that even gets
more enhanced is by experiencing things.
And by the way,
you don't have to go to,
uh,
across the world to do that.
Even,
I was telling you before we started
that.
So I just,
I bought a house.
We're,
we're doing the home studio thing.
My fans are funding it.
It's like my dreams literally are
becoming reality.
It's as you know,
like Dez validating as anything that has
happened in my entire life.
Congratulations.
Yes.
That's awesome.
It's like,
it's beautiful.
Yeah,
it's very cool too man.
It's awesome.
Um,
and yesterday I'm trying to hook up some
speakers in the house and I have some
old ass stereo that I've had forever and
I'm trying to hook this shit up and it
was driving me crazy,
but I actually halfway through after
like three hours of fucking pulling
things out of the wall and you know,
the old wire is the little metal ones
that you've got to turn and jamming them
into speakers and negative a twist and
the black thing.
And I'm jamming.
I mean that's literally what I'm doing
yesterday and I'm frustrated as fuck.
And then about halfway through I was
like,
this is actually great.
My attention was so focused,
turning those things,
getting that thing in there,
pulling one out.
Wait a minute,
I had to run across the other and make
the speaker work and this one I have to
run outside and it's like,
that was actually great.
It was a moment completely where I set
all my shit aside and I realized I was
like,
wow,
for the last hour I was fucking in this
shitty ass Yamaha Stereo thing,
you know?
And it was actually pretty great,
right?
Yeah.
There really is.
So you don't have to go across the world
to do it.
Just doing something that there was
meaning in me doing it.
I didn't want to hire someone to do it.
You know,
like I want to figure this thing out.
And I did.
I think there's definitely something to
that.
But I went to the Vatican this summer
and I think it was more fun than you
install on your stereo and I got to
learn more about people and looking at,
you know,
St Peter's basilica than I ever would've
done screwing together some fucking
wires and sticking them into some box
that makes noise.
I Bet I can beat you on that because
many years ago,
I believe around 97,
I think it might have been the same trip
that I ended up in Egypt.
I went to Amsterdam.
I like basically shrooms for like eight
days and then we want it.
So my buddy and I,
we wanted to take that,
we wanted to take shrooms to,
uh,
to Rome to trip at the Sistine Chapel.
So listen to this,
we get on the train,
you know,
it's like the overnight train,
I don't know,
probably 12 hours to go from Amsterdam
to Rome.
We got boarded,
the train got boarded by like,
uh,
I dunno,
like blush or police or something.
Yeah,
something.
So we were like,
what are we gonna do?
What do we do?
So we ate the evidence.
So we literally ate the shrooms on the
trains.
I don't remember like enough for one
person each,
like,
not,
not like a crazy amount,
but we're on an overnight train in like
one of those little cruise ships where
you're sleeping with two people above
you.
So we're both on the bottom in a tiny
little room with,
with four Italians tripping balls for
hours and hours and hours.
We get to,
we get to room and we went right to the
Sistine Chapel,
which you have to walk through like a
lot of other chapels kind of to get to.
And he said,
but so I wasn't fully tripping but I had
just enough,
just enough in the Sistine Chapel beat
that.
Now you can't
pretty good.
Well you only thing where you could do
that through four countries cause I
tripped through uh,
the Netherlands.
I tripped through bolt,
Belgium,
uh,
something in Italy.
There's,
there's another one in there.
What else would be in there?
I Dunno.
I mean it all sounds Florence,
did you go to Florence?
I went to Florence,
but that's in Italy.
Yeah.
You said something else in Italy.
So he was,
he just,
it was Belgium.
Netherlands is where I started with
things other than Italy.
Is that what you meant?
I don't know what I said.
I don't know,
but good time.
That's the point.
Like we,
you,
we visualizing just,
you know,
when you have just enough of the
visuals,
like just,
it's like a little moving,
you know,
just a little something.
I was stone cold sober inside St Peter's
Basilica and I freaked out.
I was just thinking about the sheer
effort involved in making something so
insanely huge and how many hundreds of
years it took to build it.
We had a great guide.
He was really smart.
He was a professor and uh,
he spoke fluent English and fluent
Italian and he was a local professor who
did this on the side.
And when someone was like really
enthusiastic about the history of it,
he like lit up like a Christmas tree.
So me and this guy had some awesome
conversations and you know,
you,
he stuck with us for like our like five
or six hours.
Then we went to dinner with him
afterwards and um,
you know,
he was just so,
he sold love the artwork and the culture
and the history of it.
And it was like,
it was so infectious when he was talking
about it.
Well,
that's the thing.
You don't have to be religious per se.
I'm not a believer.
Doesn't matter.
Right?
I believe in things that I,
that can be proven.
If someone could prove something to me
then,
then I would believe it.
If you told me that Lebron James dunked
from half court,
well I'd need to see video.
You know,
like I would just,
Oh,
he did well,
hot damn,
you know,
so why wouldn't I apply that same logic
to the biggest questions of the
universe?
But even not being a believer,
you can acknowledge that the work that
these people had to do,
that maybe they felt some divine spirit,
they felt something in themselves that I
can't explain or whatever.
That there's an incredible power to
that.
I mean,
go to Jerusalem.
You can look at the,
the Western Wall is literally,
you know,
the holiest site in Judaism is adjacent
with the Temple Mount.
The Dome of the Rock is right on top of
that.
The third holy site and Islam.
And if you walk five minutes the other
way,
the Church of the Holy Sepulchre where
Jesus was crucified is right there.
I mean,
so whether you believe in this stuff or
not,
it the fact the facts on the ground
exist and you have to acknowledge that
some people find meaning and value in
that.
And we could,
we could argue whether that would have
been a destructive force throughout time
or I think a lot of ways religion is
like bill cosby.
It's both.
It's helped people and it's hurt a lot.
I mean,
religion is,
or been responsible for some horrible
trustees and not just one religion,
like many,
many religions,
but like many,
many groups of power,
many groups that have influencing great
influence over people.
A lot of times they look out for
themselves,
they protect themselves ruthlessly,
especially when they have massive
amounts of power.
That doesn't make any sense in the
world.
Like when you look at any sort of,
uh,
any side of a coup or any sort of a
usurping of power,
like it's someone who has massive
amounts of power and someone else wants
that massive amounts of power and they
conquer him and takeover and it's always
like this spectacular,
chaotic event.
And that's what human beings sort of,
that's what they do.
You know,
they,
they established positions of power than
the abused them and they're almost
begging for some better,
smarter person to come along and take it
from there.
I think about that sometimes even when
I'd be like walking where I used to live
in west Hollywood where it's like
pretty,
uh,
you know,
it's next to beverly hills,
it's a nice area and that all these
people are sort of walking,
you know,
there's nice shops there and everyone
kind of looks good.
So it's sort of where he's at.
But when they go to the gym,
they tan,
they get surgery,
they're,
they're like,
they're all working on themselves all
day doing their own thing and it's,
and you're right,
it's almost like they're just,
they're so blind to the fact that there
is something else happening.
There is a real power play happening in
the world where there are forces that
want to change things,
either for what may be better for you
or,
or worst for you or whatever.
And most people just ignore it because
it's a lot easier to get lost in twitter
or watch the Kardashians or country
clubs,
the kids of the world.
That's what we are.
We're just spoiled country club kids.
The world that don't realize the
consequences of flying drones in the
Yemen and bombing wedding parties,
you know,
there's like the,
the consequence that's attached to those
people.
It would be so significant it was
happening on this patch of dirt,
but since it's happening over there,
we don't think of it as a big a deal.
Could you imagine what would happen if
someone from another country had flown a
drone over the United States and
accidentally bombed some sort of a
wedding party in Phoenix?
Right.
Could you fucking imagine,
imagine if a one rocket flew over
Mexicans,
Mexico's border to a hotel,
Passover,
a La Jolla.
We bomb Canada.
I mean like that.
Like think about that.
Like it's so crazy when you think,
you know,
and I get it.
As I said before,
I'm not against every state secret.
I understand that some shit has,
there are rules that are beyond what the
average time of day.
They're only that way because there's no
transparency in these other countries
too.
Yeah.
Once all these countries develop this
new level of transparency where you
can't hide shit,
you can't lie.
You're going to do one or two things.
You're going to say,
look,
I'm Gaviscon,
I'm running this motherfucker and you're
going to put in the whole thing.
I mean,
what Putin is doing right now is old
school dictators kills his rivals
publicly.
He has sat,
has Sasa natives,
right?
Did you see the fucking assassination
attempt on him?
No.
You haven't seen it?
I don't think so.
On on Putin?
Yeah.
No.
Yeah,
some wise that it made a suicide attack
on his car,
but his driver was in the car and not
him.
This guy drove high speed head on right
into Putin's car.
When we try this,
how the hell did I miss two weeks ago?
No Shit.
Yeah,
two weeks ago.
Check out this.
That takes a lot at seafood.
Watch this,
watch this,
watch this car.
See the guy in the middle is doing that
so he could hit Putin's caught,
Bam.
That's
it.
He knew where the car was and he drove
in the median and then turn towards
Putin's car.
We tried to tell him one more time real
quick,
now that I can see it right now I see
the front part to watch the median.
What's the middle strip?
That guy is,
they're planning this.
Then he sees the car and turns right
into a holy shit.
Holy Shit is right.
It killed the driver.
I think it killed both guys.
See if we kill both guys,
but Putin was not in that car,
but that's his,
um,
his favorite driver.
Fucking bananas.
So I mean that's,
that's game of thrones.
That's right.
That's to the point.
This is very modern game of thrones
happening.
Yeah.
And,
but all these other people,
these are the people that are protected
by the dark lords that run the kingdom
and that this is just the modern version
of shit that's been going on since the
beginning of time.
So then that said,
does that give you any empathy for what
Clinton has to do to get there?
So that's what I'm saying.
I don't have,
not necessarily empathy,
but a vague understanding of how
ignorant I am about how the world works.
And that's a,
it's a weird place to sit,
I suppose.
And you know,
here's the defense of Clinton,
the major Clinton dot bill because,
you know,
not a defense of whatever he may or may
not have done,
uh,
physically to all those people that are
accusing him of things,
but about his,
like the speeches that he does and all
the money that he's trying to acquire.
People forget how ruthlessly prosecuted
he was my Kenneth Star while he was in
office.
And how crazy that all that all that
situation was.
Um,
who was leading it?
Newt Gingrich,
who as we said before,
it was having an affair off his wife
that was dying.
Yeah.
And then there was another guy,
the strategist who's the,
uh,
the Republican strategist.
It was Ken Mehlman.
No,
that was after,
that was the George W.
Bush guy.
Rove?
No.
Yeah.
Call Ralf Karl Rove is about part of it
too,
right?
Wasn't he partially involved Clinton
thing?
Maybe he's not.
Maybe I'm confusing cause Karl Rove is
definitely a part of the Jeff Gannon
story.
Um,
I don't,
you know,
I don't know what that could have
possibly been like for them,
but I know that when Bill Clinton got
out of office,
apparently he was deeply in debt because
of his legal fees.
And the whole thing was just like off
the chart.
That was one of the things that Hillary
talked about.
Like she had said that when they left,
when he left the office,
they were dead broke.
Well he obviously found ways to
capitalize on it and did it.
But could you imagine being a guy who's
a former president and is,
how old was he at the time?
Like maybe in his late fifties and
fucking,
not just dead broke but beaten down by
public scandal.
And you are,
you're in debt to the tune of who knows
how many dollars and you've lost all
your money to legal cases cause you're
fighting off impeachment by all these
crazy people that want to prosecute you
for doing shit that pretty much every
president has done since the beginning
of time,
whipped his dick out and people just
start sucking it because they're the
fucking king.
Cause it's crazy to be in that position
in the first place.
Who Cares?
Well people should care because he lied.
If you raped people or whatever,
then that's one thing.
But I'm just going to just the general,
if the president's having affairs,
who gives a fuck?
Is the country working?
Is it this thing basically not going
towards the iceberg then.
Okay.
But here's where it's curious.
He didn't get prosecuted because he lied
because obviously Obama now we don't now
found out that he lied about the emails
from the wikileaks.
He lied to the American people.
It is a small lie.
It is a white lie I guess you could say
cause nobody,
you know,
I mean might not be the worst luck.
Obama's wasn't under oath.
Clinton's was exactly that was going to
get to.
But the difference being that he didn't
raise his hand and put his hand on the
Bible and say,
do you solemnly swear to tell the truth?
Like why you have to,
you have to,
I have to know your really honest,
like now,
like this is the time where you can't
lie anymore.
So we have this crazy rule that if you
do lie during that time,
it's so different than when you lie
about what FBI Administrator Komi or
whatever the fuck his title is.
Yeah.
Comb.
He says about what you did and versus
what you think you did.
Right.
Or whether it's who knows what other
things,
whether it's how many fucking cell phone
she had or Ben Gazi or what are those
lines where you have your team destroy
all your old devices.
But Hammers and I had a team,
we actually did take some,
uh,
old hard drives out to the gun range.
Yeah.
And I,
uh,
I put some 300 win mag rounds into him.
That'll,
that'll show him who's boss cause we
were going to get rid of him anyway.
They were old.
It is old bullshit.
I said it'd be fun to take these to the
range.
Just blow them apart.
Say I said we took them out there and I
was siting in my rifle.
Ooh.
Should see what it does to one.
I'd like to try that.
You would like to try that?
I would do that with you sometime
computers or you have some old laptops.
You know what I did today?
Um,
I got off the apple tip.
I got my apple laptop here,
but I bought a windows laptop just to
see what's going on a bottle.
Yes they do.
They make a Lenovo thinkpad.
Uh,
that's what I got.
I was like think pads.
I had one a long time ago and I'm so
let's see what the newest thinkpads look
like.
I'm like,
I still had that little red.
Yeah,
the little nipple that you play with.
I like that thing.
Yes.
They have the nipple still.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I got a p 50 Lenovo thinkpad p 50.
So anyway,
I get this thing pad and it has windows
seven.
Well,
the newest windows is windows 10.
So I try upgrading to windows 10.
Oh Geez.
Three and a half hours later after to
fucking live chats with people.
They can't figure out how to get it to
work to different people.
I'm talking to um,
with,
uh,
you know,
tech support.
They can't figure out how to get it to
work.
It's still got windows seven on it.
I spent three and a half hours this
morning,
not as therapeutic as my little Yamaha
stretches.
Nothing.
I didn't lose my,
I didn't lose my temper because I
treated it.
I have a laptop.
This one's getting kind of,
it's got a lot of space taken up by porn
and stupid shit and I'm fucking pool
videos and a bunch of dumb stuff on my
phone from my phone rather.
And I was saying,
and why I should probably get like a new
laptop,
like,
why don't I see what windows 10 is like?
So I figure if you buy a new laptop,
oh,
for sure it's going to have windows 10
on it.
No one had fucking windows seven windows
seven an
eight nine I didn't know that they did
anything after 95 I thought it was
windows 95 and then that was it.
I heard windows 10 is good.
I've,
I've heard it reviewed by a tech people,
so I'm,
I'm hoping to see what the fuss is all
about.
But I've been,
I at least,
I think it might be like,
like going,
going to a really shitty job for a while
and then coming back to your regular job
and going,
God is so much better.
Isn't it funny how sometimes like if
we're as connected as you may be,
sometimes some technology just kind of
gets passed you and then you realize you
just like miss something.
So for the last five years I've been
using firefox,
the browser,
firefox,
you're on chrome I guess.
Right?
So I'm using firefox.
Nothing would work.
Like things like videos would freeze,
audio would freeze.
I couldn't open three windows at once,
you know,
like whole bunch of shit.
And then my,
uh,
my director were,
Mira saw me clicking firefox and she
was,
you know,
she's 23 or 24.
And she was laughing hysterically like,
you fucking idiot.
What are you doing?
Why are you doing that?
And then she said,
you got to get on chrome.
And I was like,
no,
that can't be any different than
firefox.
I thought everybody was on firefox,
like for as much as I'm in this thing,
this was,
I don't know,
I got on firefox and I just was there.
Chrome is the shit.
So now I'm on chrome.
And guess what,
you press play,
you know what happens?
Shit plays,
she plays.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm a big believer in the Google and one
of the things that I've been thinking
about is,
uh,
getting off the apple tit and,
using an android phone and a windows
laptop.
So I'm going to try that over the next
few months.
This is the beginning of the end.
I don't think so.
I want to,
I don't think being frustrated be such a
bad thing.
I mean,
I think at the very least I can call
people on good dude.
I don't think I could send you a text
anymore.
Something's going on and send me
pictures.
I can't find him.
That's a great way to get off the grid.
Sorry.
I heard when people say the pictures on
those google phones,
like they go into a folder,
like if someone sends you a picture,
it's attached to your text message.
That picture like automatically goes
into a folder and may not even exist on
the tech stream.
Like I don't get it.
I don't know if that's the case.
You know,
even live like this,
I'm going to find out,
I'm going to find out.
I'm going to find it.
I want to see what's going on.
I'm going to try that.
They have a,
Google has a new phone called the Google
Google Pixel heard about it and it's
very highly received by tech dorks.
The people that really know what the
fuck they're talking about unlike me.
And they uh,
they really liked the camera.
They were like the speed,
the pure google experience,
because nobody fucks with it.
It comes straight from them.
They don't have a third party software
built into it so I'm going to say let's
see what's going on.
Cause I think if you just stay on the
apple tit all the time,
like when people send me a text message
is all green,
I can a little envy like this person is
out there and just rebelling.
They're out there and be wild and
sending text messages.
Now this morning when I was dealing with
the Yamaha show you,
I'm not making this shit up.
See I'm just a real big fan of Google in
general took a picture of a wire and it
came back green and I thought what's
this guy know that?
I don't know.
This guy's got green.
He knows he knows things or he doesn't
or he's poor,
poor guy.
He's going to be unemployed.
It was very sad.
It could be that he's just a crazy,
he doesn't trust apple,
but there is something fucking weird
about that.
Those blue things like,
and then if someone's got another kind
of phone then it's Greens.
Like oh they're an outsider.
It's green.
You didn't even send you a blue one.
Like why?
Why do you have different fucking
collars for different people that have
different phones?
I don't like the word where that's going
well the other ones that feel it's that
1984 commercial that apple did in 1984
when they were fighting windows at the
time they were fighting Microsoft.
But the idea that the bigger my apple
gets and the more we just instinctively
go to it.
And by the way,
I say this with all due irony because I
got the iphone seven the day it came
out.
Awesome.
Um,
but you know,
the more that we all do that you
actually incentivize them to not
innovate because if they know that if,
cause this phone,
really the reality is that this phone
that we're both have right now,
it barely is different than the,
than the six.
Right.
Are you finding it?
But who are you now?
We've been talking for awhile.
A little better,
a little better,
but maybe a little worse.
I like the annoying Shin and I do miss
the phone and the headphone Jack.
Yeah.
Guess what?
Sometimes I want to have a headphone
plugged in while I'm in my car so I can
talk to someone with a thing dangling
from my ear because it's way easier to
hear them that it is through speaker
phone or what if you want to charge your
phone and use headphones.
I don't agree with what they're doing
and I don't agree with what they're
doing with laptops either where they're
getting rid of USB and they have,
now they have some new type of Usb like,
come on man,
this isn't any better.
But the thing is that goes to my point.
If they know that you're going to buy
this shit no matter what,
and they know us,
they knew the day they put this out,
they're going to make x amount of
hundreds of millions of dollars if not
more.
So the more that we all instinctively
just go to them,
the actual less they have.
There's less incentive for them to give
us good innovative shit because why keep
changing it if you just tweak a couple
of things and they don't put that much
into it and we all do it anyway.
I also think that it's probably
important to support competition and to,
you know,
like when,
I think once they reach a point where
the tech people are saying this is the
best phone,
like a lot of the Google,
the people that have a reviewed the
Google Pixel,
they're saying,
I have ditched my iphone for this is the
best phone in the market.
Finally for the first time an android
phone,
I don't know if they're rooting for
android and so they may have a biased
opinion.
My,
my tribe,
like these guys are out of their fucking
mind.
Right.
Well we're gonna find out,
I'm going to find out about windows 10
and I'm going to find out about android.
I want to give them both.
A shot decided that recently I was like,
this is just too instinctive a move for
me to just go to apple.
Like I remember when I was on news
radio,
it's when apple wasn't really even that
good.
It was before m o s 10 osx rather,
which was the big operating system
change where it went to unix based
system opposed to the way it was before.
It was like it would freeze up before it
had no memory protection.
You couldn't really multitask correctly.
It did.
It didn't have what they call preemptive
multitasking.
So like the tech people didn't
appreciate the,
the Mac platform until Osx and then Osx
had this really like responsive user
interface.
It was very cool little animation things
would
happen when you click on things and I
saw that and what,
Whoa,
okay I want to try it,
I'm going to try it.
So I went,
that's when I jumped back over from
windows to Mac again.
And there's so many people that get in
these clans.
It's like we were talking about with
Republicans versus Democrats.
There's a lot of clans.
Like when I was on the set of news
radio,
one of the guys,
this is back when Max sucked,
one of the guys just like,
uh,
you know,
do,
do you hear our sales are up,
our sales are up,
but he's talking about like Max,
I go our sales,
he's like sounds of Matt.
Cause you know,
he knew he was a man.
He'd have where apple t shirts and shit.
He was such a,
Bill Gates was there.
Steve Jobs was the key grip on a news
radio.
He,
you know,
he's a creative guy behind the scenes
guy,
but he was like so excited about apple
sales being up.
And I'm like,
dude,
this is weird.
You're getting weird with me.
You know we've got new,
a new Mac.
Books are coming up.
Okay,
don't you have a computer?
Like what the fuck are we doing?
What are we doing?
We become slaves to these machine.
Yeah.
But then it was like apple was the
underdog.
It's a different experience.
Well that's what I mean.
That 1984 commercial,
their whole point was you all bow down
to Microsoft and we are the upstarts.
Where are the people that are going to
break the system?
Break the Matrix.
I think different.
Think different and now it's like think
the same and Natalie's they think the
same and if you don't think the same,
there's something wrong with you.
You've got a green text.
What the Hell is wrong with you?
Yeah.
But you know,
apple for all the cries of everybody
with trump in the taxes because
everything these days is somehow linked
back to together.
You know apple pays virtually no
corporate taxes.
Exactly.
And what's his name?
The head guy now tim cook basically it
was like,
yeah,
when they rewrite fairer tax laws,
we'll bring our money back here.
Now know some back.
For some reason nobody's upset by that.
We don't see people throwing iphone is
out the window.
The problem is they have a
responsibility as a gigantic corporation
to the people that hold their stock.
Like there's a weird thing that happens
with corporations.
They're public and people own stock in
it.
Like you have a direct obligation,
your stockholders to make a profit.
So it doesn't that prove trump's point
though.
So it does proves his point because it's
like,
all right,
I'm doing what's legal.
Right at the end of the year when
you're,
when you go to pay your taxes,
I'm pretty sure you tell your account in
the same thing that every sensible
person does,
which is do whatever is legal and I want
to pay the least amount of taxes.
I don't,
I still don't see everybody.
Does tax shelters exist?
Yeah.
So I don't,
so again,
he hasn't released his taxes,
so that's shitty.
And he lied.
And by the way,
he's lying when he says the thing about
auditing,
you know,
he's whole thing is,
well I'm under audit so I'm not going to
do it.
But then,
then the next sentence at the last
debate,
he was like,
you know what,
I'm going to write it but I won't do it.
But if hillary releases her emails,
I'll release my taxes.
And it's like,
oh well,
which is it?
You know,
I think it was the Goldman Sachs
speeches,
wasn't it?
No,
he said emails.
He said emails,
so he's lying.
You know,
it's just a way of lying.
I'm under audit,
which there is no technical reason that
you couldn't.
But then he says,
but if she does hers,
you know that thing I'll do,
I'll do it.
Well there's no technical reason,
but that's his argument.
It's like while they're auditing him,
he's not going to do it cause he doesn't
have to write.
You know,
which does make sense.
Like if they are auditing him like why
he wouldn't want to like open it up to
public discourse.
Right.
So that,
so that in itself may be,
but the idea
that,
but if she realizes her emails off,
forget that whole thing with the audit
and I'll go ahead and do it like that.
You think though that that would,
if he did releases taxes while they were
auditing him,
it could positively effect for sure.
Cause it would affect public opinion.
And we know for a fact that public
opinion has had a big impact on things
that may,
you know,
if,
if people didn't,
they didn't get outraged about it.
Maybe the president or whoever's in
charge wouldn't move in a certain
direction.
Right.
Well that's,
but that's the point is that if you want
this,
if you feel that this stuff is broken,
that the tax system is broken and all
these guys that can hide money in,
uh,
you know,
offshore accounts.
If you think all that's broken,
don't be upset at the businessman who
used it.
Now that doesn't mean what he was doing
was ethical or whatever.
Maybe it was,
maybe it wasn't.
That's,
that's a different conversation.
But you have to be upset at the people
who put the laws in place that allow
this to happen.
Any businessman just uses the system as
it exists.
So when all these people are like,
well,
trump makes his ties in Mexico.
Yeah.
He's a smart businessman in that regard.
He uses cheap Mexican labor if you're
upset and that that is the reality than
be upset at the people who set up those
trade deals.
But isn't the issue really not the,
does the stuff in Mexico,
the issue is that he does it in Mexico,
but it only pays people at tiny amount
of money.
If somebody opened up a plant in Mexico
and paid people American wages,
there would be no incentive whatsoever
to go to Mexico.
We should have laws as human beings and
what we're,
what we allow.
And not just in America,
you can't just say,
you go past this line,
there's a rock over there.
Once you pass that rock,
you can pay him 7 cents an hour.
But over here we get 11 bucks.
You fuck right,
right.
So team Merica world police.
Yeah.
So I'm not defending the ethics of his
business practices,
I'm just saying all a bit.
As you said,
they're,
they're beholding to their stock shares
and their holders and all that stuff.
So I'm just saying if he didn't do
anything illegal,
then he just did.
He just played the system.
So you should be angry at the system and
you can say he's immoral or took
advantage in a way that a more less
unscrupulous business person may not
have.
And maybe that's the type of person you
would want to work with and not a Donald
Trump.
But that's why this is really complex.
And we instead,
people look at the ties in Mexico and
they go see he's a hypocrite and it's
like not quite the truth.
Well he is.
He's a,
he's a hypocrite for a minute.
He's a hypocrite.
I mean he was talking about of
corporations go over to Mexico.
It will,
we'll find them to the tune of 35% yeah.
Okay,
but you were already there.
No,
but if you're running for president and
you're making your ties over there,
you should stop.
Like,
cause you're saying there's something
wrong with the company taking their
stuff and moving over there and
profiting from it and taking jobs out of
America.
You do it.
I've already done it,
but I'm doing it right now.
So if you do it,
I'm going to find you.
So that's a at least,
so you're making a distinction there
that in the course of this he could have
said,
I'm not going to do it any more to show
you that I'm going to be moral or
whatever you want to call it,
ethical or whatever.
I will stop.
It isn't the ethical moral way to do it,
to just pay them more.
Yeah,
of course.
But that's unfortunately we live in a
reality that,
you know,
that's what a loss so much it past that
as human beings that live in the United
States,
in the world,
the United States of America,
one of the most fortunate countries,
if not the most fortunate in the world.
We will respect our American privilege
and you know,
not be willing to subjugate people that
live in impoverished countries too.
Like taking advantage of that.
Don't do,
don't take advantage of that.
An unfortunate circumstances like if
you're living in a very poor third world
country and a Nike factory opens up or
whatever,
you can't.
As a,
as a person who is aware that they have
the best like location roll the dice
that's available today.
You're living in America,
you're born here like the fact that
you're going to like make someone in
some other country work for essentially
with slave labor,
like the phone you buy this fucking
iphone having my hand is made in a
factory where they have nets around the
factory because so many people have
tried to kill themselves that they made
it where they catch you in a fucking net
when you jump off the roof because they
were cleaning up bodies off the ground.
And when people defend it,
they defend it in the most bizarre way
they,
the defense is.
Yeah.
But the percentage of people that commit
suicide of those factories is very
similar to the percentage of people that
commit suicide and the culture factory.
No fucking money.
And they live at the factory and the
jumping off the roof.
That's,
you can't defend that.
No.
So then what do you make of our sort of
fake moralizing with this where you,
you are fully acknowledging we both have
this thing,
we both paid a lot of money for it.
We acknowledge,
we have the intellectual knowledge of
what you just said,
that they do some shady things and yet
at the same time all these people that
are doing the exact same thing with us
that have this phone will go buzzard
over the ties.
So we,
we picked we and that goes to this
side's everyone's picking aside so well
they can just go and ask you this guy.
They're going after this guy.
And then there's,
there's validity to what they're saying.
Even though they have a phone that was
built by slaves,
there's still validity in what they're
saying.
And not only that,
I mean we had Shane Smith from vice on
one day and we were talking about the
cult [inaudible] cult Tran,
Colton,
that they had to take out of the ground,
the con in the Congo and how,
you know,
like the,
the,
the way they were getting a lot of the
elements that they use in cell phones,
it's fucking complete slave labor and
child labor.
I mean,
it's scary,
scary stuff when you get down to the
nitty gritty of how things are
manufactured and constructed in order
for us to get them at a reasonable
price,
then it's,
it's,
it's just really spooky that we're
willing to do that.
It's,
yeah,
it's,
it's just a,
we just sinked up there.
That was why,
I mean we,
it's partly,
it's just the unintended consequences of
wanting things,
you know?
It's also the unintended consequences of
having this business model of unlimited
growth.
And that what we're talking about about
trump having a sort of responsibility to
its shareholders,
just like apple having a responsibility
to their shareholders like this,
this thing of unlimited growth places
more allity at the end of the list of,
of motivations for what you're doing.
And there's a thing called diffusion of
responsibility that takes place when you
have a gigantic
group of people,
they call themselves a corporation.
You're just a little piece of that
corporation.
It's not like Dave Rubin's out there
making people work for 13 cents an hour.
No,
it's Microsoft or it's,
you know,
Hitachi or you know,
fill in the blank.
I don't know if those companies do bad
things,
but whatever company it is,
apple,
it's paying people ridiculously low
wages.
I mean,
that is what it is.
You know,
it's,
the corporation becomes this entity that
needs Zeros and ones and you have to
figure out a way to get them and you
can,
you get them by taking these people that
have worked for us for 20 years,
just fucking casting them out.
Can you do that?
Yeah,
but they,
they're good.
They do a good job.
Fuck them.
You cut them off and you make asphalt
face to the right,
work for extra hours a day.
So then you take instead,
think of all the executives and all the
mid level people that they've got up in
Cupertino making absurds amount of
money.
I'm not just talking about the
shareholders who cashed in on talking
about all those silicon valley guys
making an absurd amount of money.
I don't begrudge any of them any of that
money.
But imagine if all of them who could
live incredibly well on 10% of what they
have and funneled some of that money,
did the same people making their shit.
I'm not a socialist.
That's why I'm not even saying this
would be the right thing to do in any
way.
But like they,
those people all walk around with a
pretty clean conscience.
You know,
while they have,
you know,
the fancy,
you know they probably all have teslas
and all that shit and the people that
are literally making the shit,
not just the ones coming up with the,
the ideas in Cupertino cause they always
say you know,
Boto in Cupertino but meanwhile they
don't say made in China within that.
It is interesting how we really
distinguished very clearly the
difference between the person who has
the idea and the person who puts the
idea together with their fingers.
Like that's not nearly as valuable but
without that person putting it together.
Because whatever gets done,
like the manufacturing process does not
just include the people that buy the
machines.
That includes the people that work for
the people that buy the machines.
But the people that buy the machines get
so much more money than the people that
work for them.
And then the people that designed the
plans and give them to the people that
buy the machines,
they get even more money.
They get the most money.
The people who design the idea is most
important and I don't know if that's
because of like the nature of the thing
that like that it's,
it's set up that way because that's,
those are the people.
The people at the very top are the ones
who are going to expand this weird thing
that we're doing.
Expand this technological sort of
progression that just this ongoing wave
of improvement and innovation that we
demand.
We demand new better versions.
We not an iphone,
seven's a piece of shit.
When's the eight come out?
Do the aid's going to have hd reality
built in?
The question really at the end of the
day is are any of us happier or any of
us more functional or any of us more?
Yeah,
like what have we done here?
What have we done is any,
if they were to gauge happiness of the
average person who had the exact same
physical attributes as you that grew up
in the same town you grew up in in 1950
versus right now,
is there any quantifiable difference?
And I would
argue,
I would guess that basically it's no,
that doesn't mean this thing has done
incredible things cause Tahrir Square,
all the revolutions that haven't really
worked out the way they're supposed to,
but it connected people all over the
world and that's pretty awesome.
So it does,
of course it does great stuff.
But like in terms of what are we
actually chasing constantly,
as you said,
there is no end because once it's always
profit.
Well we got an mu,
nu,
NU,
nu.
Cause you're not chasing happiness,
you're not chasing fulfillment.
You're not chasing,
you know,
whatever the,
the end game of the human experiences,
you just chasing something.
I don't think it's for humans.
I think it's for the next thing.
I think we're setting it up for the next
thing or the little workers that are
building the shop for the machine
overlords.
Oh man,
we're the guys with the nats or we're
the guys with the nets.
We just don't think we are.
We're our thirst for technology is
probably connected in some way to this
thing wanting to emerge and that as we
become more and more materialistic and
interested in the latest and greatest,
we feel we fuel this,
this innovation and we're a part of it
whether we like it or know it or not.
That's why like as a human being,
it's very frustrating and confusing when
you're addicted to technology,
when you're caught up in it and locked
away in it.
And for me,
I find that the only way I stay happy as
by being involved in very physical
things like,
and I think that's one of the reasons
why record numbers of people are
depressed today.
I think they're not fulfilling the human
requirements,
their biological human requirements.
For me,
exercise is gigantic.
Meditation is also gigantic,
which I also consider a very physical
thing because it's,
it's a focus.
Concentration internally versus on
whatever bullshit is on my fucking
twitter feed or whatever facebook feed
or dealing with some nonsense about a
job you don't really give a fuck about.
Instead of that,
I'm focusing on things that are
important to me,
like the management of the actual mind
itself.
I think putting yourself in a
competition scenario is putting in
things where you have to perform under
pressure.
That's one of the reasons why people get
so addicted to Jujitsu because then it's
like this high level problem solving
thing that you're doing all the time and
it makes regular life seems so much more
easy to manage and regular dilemmas are
nothing compared to a fucking hundred 90
pound man who's built like a gorilla on
your back trying to choke you sleep.
That reminds me of the gym in West
Hollywood and actually
what I did there,
probing ladies and gentlemen,
but I think regardless,
it's happening.
It's happening to US regardless.
The technology in my mind,
nonsense and talking to you about
switching a windows 10 and a fucking
google phone,
this bullshit stupid.
It's not going to fix anything and I'm
not trying to,
I'm not claiming to not claiming that I
ever possibly could or have the
influence,
but what I'm saying is you as a human
being have an obligation to yourself.
To extract that happy juice out of your
body in a positive way.
And I don't think we're designed to sit
at desks.
I don't think we're designed for
fluorescent lights.
I don't think we're designed for movies
and all those things are great.
All those things are great,
but you got to manage the amount of
exposure you have.
Did that shit.
You have to manage the amount of
exposure.
You have to fictitional narratives.
You have to merit,
you have to manage the kind of exposure
you have to electronic influence.
You have to manage the,
there's just like,
you have to manage the type of people
that are in your life.
You around people that are complaining
all the time.
If you just around people that just wine
and like,
oh my God,
another day,
Hey,
you know,
I'm sure you didn't see the movie,
but uh,
there was a,
this kid's movie about,
um,
inside out and it's about like this
girl's brain.
It's a little kids moving.
So all of my daughters,
but it's a little kid's movie about
like,
this girl has like these characters in
her brain.
One of them's anger and Lewis Black
place anger,
which is fucking awesome.
And uh,
and the other one is sadness and sad.
I was like molly and everything,
sadness touches becomes sadness.
Like everything turns blue.
It's kind of an interesting movie
because it's funny,
it's entertaining,
but it's also,
it's kind of,
there's a lesson to be learned for
children that like you can,
you can marinate in those fucking
thoughts.
You can allow those thoughts to
influence and touch all these different
aspects of your life.
Or you can figure out how to stop them,
like understand what they are.
These are,
these are these thoughts or it's almost
like a living thing,
like a life force and that living think
and grow if you feed it.
But if you don't feed it and you push
this side and you feed the positive
thing,
you can manage that little fucker might
not ever go away because you're not
living in a movie.
But you could definitely manage it way
better than you're doing if you don't
take conscious decisions and what kind
of energy you let into your life.
Yeah.
Well,
we all know people that are addicted to
their own pain or their own trauma,
their own story.
And no matter what you do,
you know you can't.
And they love it.
They love it.
We all have relatives like this or,
or friends and it's like,
you gotta do the work.
It is work.
Life is work.
It is,
it is endless.
It's endless till it's over.
And then you may regret not doing some
of the work.
It's also,
it's your [inaudible].
It's not,
there's no,
it's not like there's no options.
There are options to fit thought
patterns.
And if you just allow these like deeply
ingrained paths to exist in your mind,
where you immediately fall into
complaining and the woe is me.
It never works out for me.
You know,
someone sent me a text the other day
comparing to people.
There was two,
the same thing happened to,
people are at the same event and one
person had this horrific like,
like all my God,
this is terrible.
This is the worst,
is such a waste of my time.
And the other person was,
well,
uh,
it hasn't been good yet,
but there's still time,
exclamation point,
Smiley face.
I'm like,
this is a perfect example.
The difference between two different
people in the exact same experience
having two different patterns that they
allow their brain to go down.
Now what if you find that that guy's on
his zoloft that has an issue?
That's an issue,
right?
And that's what a lot of people do
instead of one.
And again,
this is not to disparage people who have
legitimate mental imbalances where they
need medication.
I have a bunch of friends that have had
that.
But the question with that is like,
is that nature or nurture?
Like what does it become,
what it was causing these negative
thoughts in your mind?
Is it a biological issue that you have
because part of you is not working
correctly,
which is entirely possible?
Or is it you've embraced these negative
thoughts and this negative program by
your family or by people that you hang
around with are bad influences and
you've embraced it to the point where
you're unable to take these positive
thought patterns.
You know,
you almost like have to go to a retreat.
They almost have to like kidnap you and
put you on some island somewhere where
somebody talks to you and he goes,
hey man,
this is,
this is life right now is life.
You don't have to get back to that
email.
You think I know you think you do.
Right.
You know you don't have to get back to
those people that are negative,
that are in your life.
You don't have to like,
this is life.
This right here,
breathe in,
breathe out.
You're alive.
You're also alive and maybe the greatest
fucking time the world has ever known.
I mean come on man.
There's never been,
it's never been easier to get food.
It's never been safer to walk the
streets.
There's never been more cool,
cool people to communicate with.
This is the best fucking time ever.
Like don't go woe is me.
Cause some girls want to suck your Dick
Anymore.
Just do we.
Can you just fucking stop and relax for
a moment?
If you were a 90 year old man living in
Ecuador,
you know that his whole life he had been
forced to be a farmer working for
pennies and eating fucking raw potatoes
and shit,
and someone gave you the opportunity to
come here and beat you.
Now how God damn happy would you be?
You'd be so happy.
Well,
that is you.
That's you right now.
You won the lottery bitch and you're
still complaining and 99.9% of the
people listening have won the lottery in
comparison to all the other people that
they're going to come in contact with.
So in a lot of the other people,
you're,
you're almost making a case though,
for people to,
that the key to happiness in the midst
of this technological monstrosity that
were part of that.
The key really is to disconnect yourself
from it and there that comes with
certain costs too.
I don't think the disconnect,
I think to have discipline.
I think for me,
at least,
my,
my best happiness comes from when I have
discipline and avoiding the technology
or,
or limiting my access to the technology
and consciously choosing to do other
things.
You know,
get involved in other hobbies,
get involved in,
uh,
you know,
like whether it's yoga or archery or you
know,
go run marathons or go,
you know,
get involved in,
to go in or a Jujitsu tournament,
go,
uh,
climb a mountain.
There's things that people do that are
hard to do and you don't just do it to
get to the top of the mountain I think.
Or to,
you know,
finish the cross.
That line that you decided you're going
to run to.
You do it because you,
your,
your body requires it.
Your brain may require it like you as a
being as an entity,
problem solving and puzzle solving is a
part of who you are.
Overcoming adversity is a muscle that's
gotta be exercise.
Yeah.
Cause if it's not,
then once the shit hits the fan,
you fucking fall apart.
And we all know people like that.
They're just went,
one bad thing goes on in their life.
They become blabbering fucking idiots.
Yeah,
that's,
I mean that's why you gotta just push
you,
you like you have no choice in a way.
I guess once you see that,
which seems fairly
obvious to someone if you're awake
enough,
once you see it,
you gotta just push and push and push
and you will fail.
As I've said several times,
like you're going to fail at it and I
fail at it all the time where suddenly
three hours went by and I go,
Oh shit,
I just stared at twitter but three hours
literally just taking my dog for a walk
sometimes that that would just reset it
and then I feel better after that.
Yeah.
And if you don't do that,
it's taking that step,
get yourself to take that step and just
once you're doing something,
it's usually pretty easy to do it.
Like once you're working out,
it's pretty easy to be there once your
start like,
oh,
this is what I'm doing now and I
actually started enjoying it.
It's making yourself take that step.
You know like this is a lot of times for
Yoga class where I'm like I could just
stay here.
I watch TV,
I fucking put my feet up and do nothing.
Man,
I'm feeling kind of sore.
Maybe I should relax.
Like your brain starts playing all these
fucking mind games with you but when you
do go to yoga class and you take that
class in,
90 minutes later you've lost fucking
eight pounds of sweat and you've been
freaking out and almost blacking out.
When you get out of there you feel
better.
I feel better.
I feel way better.
And it gives you also I think momentum
and motivation to continue with the rest
of your life too to keep pushing
forward.
What do you think about um,
the fact that you are your own boss
also?
Cause pretty much I,
you know,
I know you have outside gigs too,
but for the most part,
probably 90% of what you do,
I would guess is,
is you are in charge of the,
the ultimate decisions if not 100%.
Maybe it's,
well not the UFC.
The UFC is my one job that I have,
but right.
And it's still,
it's a job,
but it's the greatest job I've ever had.
That's what he was a super pleasure.
And it's also,
um,
it's an honor and it's also,
there's a massive obligation to respect
and represent the people that are
competing in what I think is one of the
most difficult physical endeavors in all
of sports,
if not the most.
I think it's incredibly difficult to do.
And I feel like I'm in a very privileged
position to represent those people.
But yeah,
I like it that I don't need it.
Yeah.
I love that.
I love,
I like not having a boss man.
Even though my boss is amazing,
you know,
that job was the greatest job of all
time.
I like doing things when I want to do
them too,
but it's not like I'm lazy.
So I pushed myself to do a lot of shit
and I,
you know,
I have goals and accomplish them or
attempt to,
and I have,
you know,
commitments as far as like writing and
performing and producing things.
But um,
yeah,
being your own boss,
man,
if you could pull it off,
it's like the greatest thing ever
because it's not work anymore.
It's like you're working for yourself,
but you're,
you're doing things instead of working
like that,
punching in.
I mean,
I went independent in June,
so it's only,
I'm not even six months out of that.
And not only was it the smartest
business decision I ever made,
which partly was because I saw guys like
you and Corolla and a couple other guys
that will,
I was like,
wait a minute.
They built great brands.
They have their fans and they're doing
it.
Like I,
it was like,
I was like,
oh,
there's actual template for this.
If I,
if I built my audience correctly.
And I just took the risk and said,
you know,
let's see what happens.
And
we know we launched this patrion
campaign,
which is where fans can donate per
month,
whatever they want so that,
you know,
do you do like two bucks to get a
newsletter?
We people that donate 250 and I skyped
with them every month and like a whole
bunch of different things.
I didn't know when I woke up the next
morning after we launched it,
they might've been over my career,
literally might've been over like just
like that because I quit my job.
I had no,
I had no job.
My producer had no job.
My director,
I had no job,
no insurance,
no nothing.
And I woke up and our fans showed up and
they took care of us.
And because of that,
now in the six months since then,
now I bought this House and build in the
studio and we're figuring out all other
ways to to make deals and all that kind
of stuff and it's incorrect.
But I still wake up sometimes.
This is my point was I still wake up
sometimes I'm like,
wait a minute.
So I have to answer to somebody.
Like I have a feeling it's just a
feeling,
you know,
like,
wow,
I can't believe this.
I,
I make the decision here and a way like
that,
that hunger that,
that you know,
that fear that to take that chance and
to do things,
that's like one of the best things you
could ever have in life because it's the
motivator.
If you don't,
if you're not like a woe is me,
I'm always going to be a loser.
If you're a person who really tries to
do something,
risk taking is so God damn critical
because it forces you to action and it
forces you to be inspired and to get
fired up and that's when things really
take place.
It really is like that's,
and that's one of the things that Scott
Adams had said sort of about the
election is that there's such chaos now,
but whatever happens after out of chaos,
something new will happen.
May Not be good immediately.
May Not be bad.
I mean,
we don't know what that will be,
but the chaos,
the chance,
the risk will now allow for something
else to happen.
So all these people who,
you know,
all these pundits who got everything
wrong for the last year,
and oh well it's going to be a rubio,
it's going to be cruise,
blah,
blah.
It's like they'll now tell you
everything else that there is going to
happen for the next year and they're
going to get all that wrong.
But out of chaos,
that happens.
And that's what I realized.
I had a path,
I had a salary and I was doing fine.
And I liked working at Ora and Larry
King's been great to me and it was all
good.
But I just had this feeling of like,
I gotta try this.
I got to try this.
You get a very different position if it
didn't work,
you know?
Yeah.
You don't want to be that guy who just
wishes they took that chance and you're
still working for some company and they
still treat like shit.
I mean,
because that's,
you know,
in that sense,
you're the person making the phones.
You're not the person with the idea and
the person with the idea.
Especially if you're a smart guy like
you are,
it's you do yourself a disservice if you
don't express yourself completely,
fully and without any reserve or any
reservations.
And when you work for someone,
you'll always have a reservation.
You're always worried,
man.
You're always,
you always like biting your tongue or
flavoring your words or you know,
they come into your office and go,
Dave,
you've been really hard on Clinton.
I think it's really important for Mike.
You know the,
the produce a producer is a,
he's got Hashtag I'm with her on his
twitter account and we just wanted you
to just think about doing that,
like criticized her if he choose to,
but be balanced,
be balanced and you're being real like
you're,
you're being silly,
but you're also being real.
That is the real shit that's going on.
Hashtag I'm with her.
Yeah.
You know,
you've got to have a Hashtag Jeanette,
the president of the company is going to
come down and talk to you about a lot of
the things you said.
I don't necessarily disagree,
have been kind of misogynist,
you know,
and,
and maybe just a little bit unsupportive
of women's issues.
And uh,
this company is very progressive and we
really feel strongly that that's the
kind of shit that p that and you don't
get to very progressive.
So you should think exactly like you
have to be Dave Ruben with a mortgage
who's worried about losing his job,
then that's,
that's not good for business.
It's not good for thinking it's not good
for humans.
It's not good for the business of
culture.
And I don't mean business,
but the,
the endeavour,
the Endeavour of culture,
the endeavor of culture requires like
sort of some sort of an open discourse,
you know?
And that includes shit like wikileaks.
Okay.
That's a part of the open discourse when
you tell someone like Chelsea manning
that they can't let anybody know about
this horrific shit that's going on,
that you know,
is illegal.
You've,
you've set up this sort of a system
where you're stopping data from going
through it.
You're stopping people from
communicating and you're going to
ultimately stop people from expressing
their opinions on what was communicated,
which is going to stop progress.
A Russian hacker,
the shit must be,
I'm just stuck pot smoking hippies,
but no hair.
All of us are just fucking people.
Dave Rubin,
and I think that's one of the things
that's going to come out when the dust
settles and we pick a new king or queen,
we're going to figure it out.
Anything's going to happen now that we
been talking to is going to win and
everyone's going to hate her and it's
going to be record record number of
people that are intolerant and say crazy
shit and you know,
and we're going to have to all figure
out a way to get along.
Do you see any situation where we wake
up tomorrow night that trump's
president?
100% yeah.
Yeah,
I do.
I don't think it's going to happen.
I would think.
I think most likely Hillary's going to
win.
But I absolutely could see just some
giant fuck up where the mass media has
been lied to by polls and by public
opinion.
And I don't think necessarily polls are
very accurate anymore because I don't
think people choose to take polls very
often.
Mostly call land lines.
When's the last time you had an exact a
mundo?
I had a joke about that in my last
special,
but like,
like maybe you're dealing with 1%,
like the problem with polls is the
people who answer polls.
Yeah.
That's the problem.
Have you ever been pulled?
Ever?
Never.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
So it's,
it's a weird thing that we're doing here
where we're basing that on Poles.
Exit polls are different.
It's a little bit different,
but that was way off,
um,
during with Al Gore,
right?
I mean they,
the predicted Al Gore to be,
apparently he was like the popular
winter,
right when he won the popular,
why doesn't he run,
Fuck's going on?
And I'm not a huge,
I know,
it's very cool to say like,
I'm not an outdoor guy.
Yeah.
You know,
you know what Al Gore did?
He uh,
he created current television.
Right.
And then that,
you know,
then eventually when he,
it was a failure as a network.
It was purging money.
Right.
And then he had a choice.
He could see you had a couple offers
on the table,
could have sold it to Glenn Beck,
but I guess he doesn't like Glenn's back
politics.
That's fine.
He sold it to Al Jazeera,
which is owned by the government of
Qatar that puts out more fossil fuel,
oil,
garbage,
the same stuff that he rails against all
day long.
And he sold him that.
So he basically did the producers,
he used all his,
all of his connections and money as a
vice president to get a network on the
air because it's incredibly hard to get
into the cable system.
So he used all his leverage to get
there,
created a failure.
And he walked away,
I think with $500 million and it was all
funded Qatar.
And it was in many ways funded by his
humanitarian campaign to alert the world
the dangers of global one.
Yeah.
That was what gave him credibility.
So he,
that's a cosby situation.
It's a card.
And on that note,
we're gonna wrap it up with that.
Dave Rubin.
That was just a three and a half hours.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
I honestly had no idea.
I have no,
when I'm on stage or when I'm doing my
show,
I have no sense of time.
So don't do three and a half hour shows.
Man.
People get pissed.
They look at their wall with the longest
one.
Was it?
Was it sam?
Four hours.
What's your longest one?
Oh,
I don't know man.
I'm five and a half for fight
companions.
No Shit.
Yeah,
we've done some long fucking podcast in
here.
I can't shut the fuck up.
Yeah.
Good job for me.
Listen,
I am now going to publicly,
you've already agreed to do it,
but I'm publicly you gotta you gotta
come on like I'll do it.
I'll do it.
I know you will.
I'll do it a little guilty at the end.
If we've had a nice report here,
there's a been a great conversation and
how to get your podcast,
where can they go to?
youtube.com/rubin report,
Ruben report.com [inaudible] on twitter.
We're on the itunes.
It's a,
it's my branding guy is pretty good.
That's all that report you motherfuckers
respect.
All right.
We'll see you soon.
Bye.
Thanks brother.
Thank you.
That was
good.
Yeah.