I just do a podcast,
say I sound like Joe Rogan,
but I'm not totally same voice
everything.
Hello,
nobody.
I'm live here with Super Yogi.
Bert Kreischer,
newly sober athlete.
Resting heart rate of 47,
47.
That's pretty crazy,
man.
I talked to her.
I called my cardiologist right after I
talked to you guys.
Am I dying?
I literally was like,
Hey,
Joe Rogan said I'm dying.
And he was like,
first of all,
he's like,
I respect to a Rhogam but please don't
listen to about your blood pressure
medicine.
But I read somewhere that blood pressure
medicine and I'm,
uh,
anti anxiety medicine lowers your heart
rate.
Uh,
yes,
those are Beta blockers.
Yeah,
I don't,
I'm not on that.
Okay.
Which by the way,
I spiraled out and then.
And I couldn't get my heart rate up as I
was spiraling.
So I was like,
I was like,
I'm freaking out.
Normally my pulse will be through the
roof.
I call my doctor.
He's like,
no,
you're healthy.
He's like,
this is what we've been shooting for if
you just stopped drinking.
So he's like,
let's just do what you're doing.
He's like,
have a good time with it,
and so,
uh,
but yeah,
my resting heart rate's low.
My,
I've never felt better in my fucking
life to be dead serious with you.
How many days in or you were 12 days in?
Say the twelfth.
I'm one day ahead of that because I quit
the day before I quit the day before
because I was,
because I listened to you guys and all
the fucking armed tier doctors who were
like,
you're going to die.
You need to be medically induced into a
coma.
Well,
you were telling us that you were
drinking six doubles a day by the way.
I,
I talk out of my ass when I'm drunk,
so I don't know how much I was really
drunk because I was dead.
I was definitely terrified.
I was definitely terrified coming into
the homestretch of getting sober because
I was like,
man,
am I,
am I going to die?
Like I literally am.
I talked to Dr drew about it.
I was like,
hey man,
can I like die and stuff?
And he was like,
well,
you can have seizures.
But I,
uh,
I stopped drinking,
I didn't even have withdrawals.
It just felt good the next day.
It's amazing.
It's killed amy winehouse,
you know,
I try,
I've googled all this shit,
but I think amy winehouse was just over
the top.
You've got to be the second you wake up
until the second you pass out drinking.
Um,
and by the way,
there on the Australian tour,
there were hints of that.
Like there was not,
I was flying and performing every night
and I drink on planes.
I hadn't flown sober at that time.
And so there was,
I was,
I've always been very measured with my
boobs,
so I wasn't,
I wasn't going nuts.
Did you feel good when you're doing
that?
Like how did you feel when you drink it
in flying and you felt bad?
I felt,
I actually felt really bad and I think,
and I think we all tweeted this,
but I was like,
I was ready for this fucking month after
that Australian tour.
I was definitely ready.
That's a great way to go into not
drinking is flight Australia.
Do a tour for two weeks and then fly
back.
I was like,
fucking bring it dude.
You know what man?
I don't drink that much,
but I feel way better too.
It's weird.
It's like I would have like maybe a shot
before I go on stage some nights,
but some nights not.
And then you know,
maybe someone go,
you want a beer?
Yeah.
Beer may have one or two and then maybe
I'd have a glass of wine with dinner.
So you know,
on a regular Friday night I might have
four drinks and now nothing for 12 days
and no pot.
I went off the pot too because Ari was
giving me such a hard,
your current queer poet,
you're not or cuts with roderick.
I was like,
alright.
I told Tommy,
I was like,
I'm just going to quit.
Not tell them and then break it at the,
at the end of the month like it.
It's easy.
The pots have been easy,
but the dreams have been different.
It is really interesting how when you
don't smoke pot your dreams like ramp
up.
It makes me think like,
what?
No,
honestly like I just completely
objective,
I mean white death can be good and not
be dreaming like right.
Probably something happening.
I,
I was my first few days of not drinking,
I couldn't get out of lucid dreaming who
I was.
I was having intense lucid dreams where
I was well aware I was asleep,
but I knew that if I could just,
I knew,
but I knew that I was dreaming and I was
like,
don't get out of this.
You're having fun.
And so,
um,
yeah,
but dreaming has been intense by the way
that really my favorite thing is just
sleeping good.
Like waking up at six in the morning and
go and like feel good.
Oh that man.
And by the way,
and I,
I know that you like a fucking Uber Fan
of podcasters.
There's like a lot of people I have been
introduced to through your podcast and
like Brenda shots,
one of my favorite people.
I love that guy.
He's awesome and he gets coffee all the
time.
Now I look at that,
that gives me panic when I see him get
getting coffee for the past year.
I've been like,
dude,
how the fuck is he doing that?
I mean,
when I drink I can't drink coffee
because I start shaking.
I get way too blood sugary.
Like really?
Yeah,
just regular coffee or coffee.
I haven't had like a cup of coffee and
probably like maybe like eight months
now.
What is it about coffee?
Is it,
do you put some in coffee?
No,
it's just coffee.
Just black coffee is so.
Yeah,
because it's my blood sugar's low from
drinking.
I didn't sleep well.
I have a cup of coffee and just.
And then that I would be like,
how does Brendan take naps in the middle
of the day?
Like I could understand that dude.
I enjoy getting up and going to
starbucks and getting a coffee more than
I ever enjoyed going to a bar.
It is.
I get up and I feel like I'm part of the
community.
I like say hi to people.
We landed from that first sober flight I
took Dan.
I know that I'm going to sound like a
child.
When we landed it was me and Brendan.
Brendan Walsh was on my flight and he
and he was like almost randomly,
he random moves that my flight.
I talked to him through text the night
before and I was like,
dude,
I'll see you on the plane.
We got to lax,
and he was like,
yeah,
I'm hitting up sober October with you.
I'm not gonna drink either.
And I was like,
awesome man.
Really?
Yeah,
and I said this and I've never said
this.
I go,
Hey,
do you want to get a cup of coffee?
And he was like,
sure.
We both got coffees at like 10 in the
morning at the airport and I was like,
oh,
I got a whole day ahead of me.
Like I got coffee to me.
Like,
dude,
I had the funniest Sunday I've ever had
that.
When I got home that night I like,
I won't be able to see about a cup of
coffee.
Went right to sleep.
Are you worried
that that this is like right now you're
in this really great place,
right?
You're healthy,
you're feeling good,
you're sleeping good,
but are you.
Are you thinking that this is just a
vacation from your other life or are you
changing your life?
My therapist,
my therapist,
when this started,
he said,
do not do this challenge.
I think it's a really bad idea.
I was like,
really?
He goes,
yeah,
asshole therapist you have.
I've heard this like Christine was mad
at him yesterday that my therapist fuck
is this therapist telling him to because
she's got a good therapist that she
really likes,
but I just don't.
Maybe you therapist doesn't trust you.
No.
He said.
He said to me at one point,
he goes,
uh,
so how you feeling?
I said,
good.
I'm not having any epiphany.
I wish I had an epiphany,
but I don't know,
but epiphany.
I'm just enjoying it.
I'm really having a good time.
I was like,
I don't know if I don't know how I'm
gonna get back into drinking.
And he's like,
that's why you shouldn't have done this.
If you want to quit drinking,
you should've just done it for yourself.
You shouldn't do it out of spite for Tom
Ren Cho spite.
It's a fun little challenge.
Like,
look,
I don't want to do 15 fucking yoga
classes in a month.
I'm loving,
but we're doing yoga.
It's great,
but do you really want to have an
obligation to have to do three a week?
Yeah.
Do you do it?
Dude,
I can only work in those parameters.
I can obviously work to the extremes.
Like when we said no pot,
no booze,
I was like,
I'm cool because I'm not going to smoke
pot if I'm not drinking booze.
I'm a teetotaler.
Like I take things too.
I take things to an extreme because
that's the way I can help
compartmentalize things,
but I think my question was like at the
end of this month with November first
rolls around,
are you going to just go get fucked up?
A will obviously be with Orient New
Orleans in New Orleans.
We're doing the impractical.
I'm going on a cruise November,
first lowery,
big J.
Tony Hinchcliffe,
seretse Khama like we're all going to be
on the cruise of the impractical jokers.
Those impractical jokers guys are
killing it.
Dude.
They did the Greek.
I saw 6,000
people fucking insane mobbed and I would
love to have sat in the front row where
they sat me and shit on their show,
but I can't man,
I would love as a comic to be like,
I'm better than this,
but then they forget up there and they
have such great chemistry and they're
showing like inside clips and it's just
a multimedia event.
Oh.
So it's not like stand up.
It's like a bunch of different stuff
that they do.
Like they show like pranks.
They play on people.
No,
they don't show it.
They show more pictures from their
childhood or like things that are
because they've known each other
forever.
Then when they were younger they tell
stories about them traveling together.
It really,
she's really a great show.
Like imagine if I'm me and Ren Tom did a
show with the store and we talked about
sober October.
Tom and I would have a bunch of stuff
very quickly that we could talk about
our hot yoga classes and red and all her
texts.
Like,
like one of my favorite things ever is
when the eve of sober October Ref
fucking puts.
Oh sorry.
Such a cunt.
He puts out all our texts privately
behind
that we haven't been sharing with you on
instagram and Tommy,
tell me that isn't giving you panic
right now because I don't know what I've
said.
Like we've all been like,
joe is not quitting weed.
And then Ari man had already managed
this coup d'etat against you for pray
for Joe already.
Look,
I look,
I know he gets a lot of shit online and
everyone's fucking with already,
but I will tell you this has been
exponentially fund because of his
involvement because this is right in his
little swing zone.
Yeah.
When,
when you said your.
When you said I'm not,
I'm not quitting,
we'd already then branched off to me and
Tom.
He's like,
gentlemen,
get ready for the assault on Joe and
both Tom and I are like,
I don't think that's a good idea.
Order like know what's happening.
I want you to get your comments ready.
I want them to send in.
We're going to workshop each other's
comments.
I want you to be the first comments on
this video that I post on this thing
saying joe is not taking part of sober
October,
so I'll send you Tom.
I love Tom to death.
He's such a cook.
He his first draft or he's like,
this will not be working.
It's too,
too pleasant to.
Joe.
We're going to report and I will rewrite
this for you.
Well Ari has been.
He,
I think he's handling this the least.
Like he's,
he's struggling like he saying this is
harder for me than any of you.
And I'm like,
I think he's being serious.
I think he likes to marijuana for self
medication.
He does and you know he has said his
life up and I think if anyone looks at
it from the outside in,
he said in his life up for him.
Yeah.
He's got his.
He's got a nice piece of cake.
Yeah.
Great apartment in east village.
He got all his friends.
They all go out every night.
He'll get it.
He's got,
you know,
he's.
And he's one of the funniest guys.
Do you ever go to New York to just call
them up and go,
what's the plan for today?
And he's like,
I dunno,
let's get lost,
let's go find some lobster somewhere.
But he's taken it seriously.
He got mad the other day when I was
fucking with them and I sent that text
saying that,
uh,
I listened to your podcast and it seems
you haven't been doing all the poses,
but a good news is there's still plenty
of days in the month to make up for
this.
The 15 different hot yoga classes.
And he took it seriously fucking
superman that struck panic and me,
if you had told me,
Hey Bert,
those ones don't count but you can start
over.
You still have 15 days.
I would have been like,
fuck off.
Like dude,
I was the only fucking with them.
And then my second I had to a two wing
attack.
That was the first level and the second
level was like,
look,
just go to classes and whatever things
that you didn't do from the other
classes,
you could just redo.
I'm on the honor system.
We don't have to do the whole class,
just stand around like I was totally
fucking with him,
but he took it seriously.
He's also by himself in this.
I feel like he's in New York.
Yeah.
So like we'll text messages are weird,
man.
It's not a good way to fuck with people
because you know,
you look at it as this motherfucker
serious.
Yeah.
He like,
look at it and go,
no,
listen asshole.
We're all professional comedians and
you're the rudest one out of all of us.
He said he hoped you rallied.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I understand the context.
I go,
I hope you Ralphie to like.
And he was,
no,
I hope you Ralphie.
And I was like,
Oh,
you want me to die?
Yeah.
What the fuck he is.
He is the most flame throwing.
Burn the bridge down Kinda Guy.
Awesome.
Yeah,
he's hilarious.
But I think that one of the things that
stinks and I wish this had been part of
the better we should have stayed in.
I wish he had.
You had gotten in that yellow corvette.
Yeah.
And I wish that he had stayed in La this
entire month and been able to be in a
part of it because there is a communal,
like when like today you're like,
Hey podcast at 1:31
to go to yoga at 10:30.
And I was like,
fuck,
I got a meeting at 10,
but I would've loved that.
And like I love Tom will text me and go
like,
and this is the fun little of this gun
competition is like toms.
Like,
Hey,
I can only go to 4:30,
are you going to 1230?
And I'm like,
yeah.
And then Tom will be like,
well no show.
Everyone looked at the distillery that
donut factories to video is hilarious.
Check all the hamburger joints.
He is by the way,
we're having fun fucking with each
other.
But honestly I think Ari's taken
seriously,
like all that.
Pray for Joe Joseph,
we'd addict.
It didn't bother me.
I thought it was funny.
I was laughing.
I reposted a lot of it.
Oh that was,
that was the biggest dude I went on
stage on in DC that first night.
And people were like,
people are like,
we should take a moment of silence.
And I was like,
yeah,
I'll take a moment of silence.
Everyone bowed their head and.
And
for you it was so much fucking fun.
Me.
Wow.
It's been like not smoking weed for 11
days is one of the easiest things I've
ever done in my life.
It's not hard at all.
I just don't smoke pot.
It's not like,
wow,
how do I go on?
I've been having some great sets.
Sets have been fun.
I've done probably in the 12 nights,
I've probably done like nine,
eight,
nine,
eight or nine sets.
There's a most sets I've done.
No,
we'd ever really since I started smoking
pot like 20 years ago.
I've real.
Uh,
I did.
I did spots of the story the other night
and I had great set stone sober and not,
you know,
it's so funny is I,
I have a lot of apologies to issue on
this podcast.
There's a lot of things that I said when
we were drinking that I then did and
went,
oh,
I guess I was a little wrong about that.
Like what?
Like for number one is I don't drink on
stage,
like I didn't realize that there's a
difference between not drinking on stage
and having a drink with you on stage.
There's a little bit of a comfort level
knowing I can kill this drink and I
don't have to deal with this.
Like and that first night,
that Saturday night I went home with no
booze for both shows and on that last
show I was like,
oh,
I could use a cocktail and I definitely
drink on stage.
Like I was like,
I wouldn't mind a cocktail right now.
So you were thinking before that you
didn't drink on stage?
I say I go,
it's the truth is I don't mind before
being sober.
I enjoy it.
But I would say like if you had said so,
do you get drunk on stage?
I'm like,
no,
never.
But I definitely bring drinks on stage
with me and I didn't like it
had a breathalyzer.
Tests have been on stage.
Was driving.
What'd
you get arrested?
Uh,
yeah,
like a bullet point eight.
Yeah,
I definitely would go stage,
uh,
that's number one apology issued a
number two is a treadmill's.
We're not real running.
No,
I told you,
dude,
you got to come do my course.
Do the chorus I do with me.
It's fucking ruthless.
Oh,
running hills.
That's where it's at,
man.
Dude,
let's just say um,
I didn't really like,
I run on the treadmill all the time and
I'm,
oh,
I can easily run under a 10 minute mile
A.
I go on the road and my first set of
models was like 12 minute miles and I
was,
I was in pain and I was like,
Whoa,
this is not the same.
And then I got to a 10 minute mile.
I was like,
that feels like a fucking sprint.
But you know,
you can get.
Do we show you those treadmills that are
like running?
They're really expensive.
Yeah,
I've thought about getting one,
but.
So what I do now is I'm doing some sort
of deal with them.
What are,
who are the sponsors,
go to rogue,
rogue athletics.
They're the guys who made the um,
reverse hyper machine that we have in
the back and I'm,
I'm actually called true form.
Yeah,
pull them,
pull this shit out so we could see what
it looks like.
But this thing is different because it's
at,
you're actually pushing your own body
weight.
There's no machine behind it.
It's just got friction to it and it's
got like a slope and you run up on it.
And it really is like the closest thing
to running.
I still think actual running is better,
but that is a very close second.
According to about 5,000
bucks.
They're really expensive.
Tree form hit me so expensive.
They hit you up.
They go.
I'm saying hey to form.
Hit me up.
Yeah.
Hey,
true form.
We'll fucking do a free app,
but we do a free ad for you right now.
You know,
who can afford that?
That's a lot of money.
Well,
some people can,
you know what I mean?
For sure.
Some people would be,
it'd be willing if you had to have one
piece of equipment in your house,
you know,
and you budgeted it out 5,000
bucks,
it's probably worth it if you could
actually use it and get in great shape
with it.
But I really feel like the best way to
do it is just go outside.
I mean,
I think especially if you can go
somewhere where there's like a dirt
trail and like a lake to look at,
it makes it more interesting,
but it's been,
it's been one of the cool things about
not drinking and getting out and doing
roadwork is uh,
my wife calls it source energy of like
getting out there and going like,
oh,
it's fucking beautiful.
Life is really beautiful.
Yeah.
I go to the park that were Joe.
Joe used to live right by this park.
I used to go there all the time.
It's ego.
He and A.
and I go to this park every morning we
go,
my wife will walk it and I run it and
I'm loving it.
So what I'm doing is I'm doing road work
probably three times a week and then
twice a week I get on the treadmill,
just don't,
I'm terrified of injury and then not
being able to run.
So I don't.
And I'm trying to run five days a week.
What are you worried about?
Like planner or something planned you
had that for awhile?
Plantar fasciitis kit is terrifying.
Dot Shin splints.
My you get it in the middle of your
foot.
Like where are you getting that?
Uh,
like if this is your foot,
like right towards the heel.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And then sometimes it'll happen inside
the heel and you'll feel it.
Like when your heel touches the ground,
it feels like glass.
When you first started doing yoga,
are you noticing,
we're noticing rather that your foot was
like a unstable and that like it hurt,
it hurts your feet to try to balance on
one foot and do the poses.
Uh,
I did not notice that per se.
I did notice that what I noticed in the
one thing that is I've done it is the
reason I will continue doing hot yoga or
yoga in general maybe,
but probably hot yoga.
So I like the sweat is um,
my feet are stronger.
Yeah.
Like we're a lot stronger.
Like I,
I was going to say to Bobby Kelly,
I was going to text him and go him and
you should start going to hot yoga.
He has the same problem with plantar
fasciitis that I do and go.
It really has strengthened my feet and
when I run now I have no pain in my
feet.
Yeah.
It makes a big difference.
Is Bobby still heavy?
Oh yeah.
He's not,
he's going on a diet.
I was,
I was going to say to score.
We should fast shame him and get him
healthy.
Yeah.
I'm not that close to them.
I can't fuck with them.
I can fuck with you guys.
You gotta to know who you could fuck
with and who's going to take it
seriously.
Like I feel like I can't fuck with Aria
anymore.
Like he takes it seriously.
He just needs to get over the hump of
hot yoga.
He needs a,
he needs to get high.
It needs a little weed in a hug.
He might need a little weed.
We love you are.
I love you.
Are you just fucking with you?
But he took it to heart.
I think like when all the uh,
res,
uh,
Welcher Shit when people were getting
mad at him and attacking him online.
When people find a little sore spot or a
little area where they can attack you,
they go after.
They don't understand like how many
people were going after you guys?
When you.
Were you doing Thomas Fat Burns fat?
Like you guys were going after each
other for a joke,
but people were jumping in for serious?
Yeah.
People say really hateful things.
There's a website that some guy has.
I guess he believes it's a comedy
website,
but it just is really nasty things about
me.
And then he's like,
just websites were savages,
savagery only.
And I'm like,
Hey man,
I'm a professional comedian.
I know the funniest people in the world.
Those aren't really like great jokes.
Like they're really like birth children
will die alone.
Like,
like,
oh cool man,
thanks on.
That was the one thing was like,
I dunno,
but also you gotta realize that these,
these people,
a lot of these people that are throwing
in there molotov cocktails in the party,
they don't like.
They just want to get a response.
They just want you to hurt you so that
you can respond.
Like that's the one thing that I will
say like ours has been pretty invisible
on my instagram comments.
Like he's going right back at people.
Fuck you.
I'm not a welter.
And I.
part of Me Goes,
oh,
you don't even read them.
I don't read the comments anymore.
Everything that with Tom and Bert is fat
thing.
I stopped reading comments altogether
because I was like,
oh,
they don't.
I make my kids.
I go,
don't touch my comments.
You guys all worked out some sort of a
deal,
right?
Like Ari is going to pay for something.
He's already.
That's the other part is like Ari had.
I don't know why he bounced out of Asia.
I think he wanted to go on the trip with
us,
but he'd already planned this trip to
Asia.
She was like,
I'll take care of you when we get back,
and so I think we're to the superbowl in
February or going to the NFC
championship in January and he's going
to pay for it or is nothing but fluid
money.
So He's,
he's got no dependence and we've all
known that and part of me like I,
I kind of enjoyed the.
I kind of enjoyed the Welsh moniker.
Yeah.
But he didn't,
but I didn't enjoy being called fucking
the GFC with Tom posted when Ralph,
he died.
No one's seen it.
No.
Can you pull up his fucking instagram by
the way?
I didn't enjoy this figure.
Look.
What does it say?
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
So has had to hear about the passing of
Ralphie May.
His heart was bigger than his stomach.
Honestly.
I've always been intrigued by comments
were kind of Larry's offstage.
What does total sweetheart?
Every time I saw him,
a big hug Ralphie,
and it's a picture of fucking me.
Wow.
And you're smelling something with beer
in your underwear.
And drinking fireball.
We're Jack Daniels and affiliate.
Preston and Steve,
are you on a radio show?
You're on.
The other guys are great.
Yeah,
they are on the other side is what are
those shorts?
They are Shyness d,
a bathing suit.
It's a gene bathing suit.
Jesus and MTI Chomolungma.
Ding Dong was on the pot on the show
with you.
He was on the show too.
And he was.
He like,
he's a really cool isn't.
It?
Was really cool.
Really interesting.
That guy knocked it out of the park
once.
I would argue twice.
I wouldn't tell you a couple of times.
Uh,
the fucking signs with Mel Gibson.
Oh,
I thought that one socked swinging for
the fences.
One wasn't bad.
Uh,
which one is the one who plants come to
kill,
you know,
split.
And that was,
that was that good.
But this is sequel to that unbreakable.
Oh,
you know what I'm like,
don't say,
I'll say twice.
I liked that elevator one.
The devil was in the elevator.
You see that one either.
It was pretty good.
Yeah.
But the first one,
six cents,
that was fucking great to me.
And a black guy sat in the lobby,
just have random black guy,
a random black guy who's sitting behind
me and we both realized that he was dead
at the same time and we lost our shit
and then walked out to the lobby
together and started.
I didn't know this guy.
I said,
this is the coolest thing about a movie.
Me and this guy had nothing in common
where he's got covered,
he's dreads,
tattoos and me and him sat in the lobby
and broke down the movie.
I didn't know him,
but we were just sharing our
realizations together.
I was like,
wait,
hold on one second.
Hold on.
So what?
And like both.
And I was,
oh,
it was one of my favorite experiences
after a movie.
It's like when total strangers get
together and they're like,
shut up,
hold on.
Wait,
what happened?
Oh,
it was great.
Yeah.
Those movies where people don't know
they're dead or weird,
like beetle juice.
Remember that?
Oh yeah,
I remember they died in the river.
The car fell in the river.
I don't like movies like beetle juice or
like a or like Charlie and the chocolate
factory.
There were the new one.
I don't like that.
I can't watch anything where there's a
little bit of fantasy fantasy type
thing.
Does that make sense?
No,
I couldn't.
I could not watch Charlie and the
chocolate factory when I was a kid.
Oh,
the old one?
Yeah.
I never saw the new ones.
I wouldn't watch it.
The new one was a thing.
It was just called Willy Wonka.
Right.
Was anyone called the Johnny Depp One?
He tied like this.
The way around.
That came from a book called Charlie and
chocolate factory.
The first movie was Willy Wonka and then
the remake was the one with Johnny Depp
is Charlie and the chocolate factory?
Yeah.
What?
What don't you like about those?
I don't know that like a alison
wonderland.
Anything about like.
I don't know if it's like a bad trip
type fantasy.
They freak me out.
Man.
Did you see the new alice in wonderland
with Johnny Depp and he played the mad
hatter.
I won't watch it.
It's great.
I enjoy the shit out of it.
It's really fun.
Yeah,
it's fun.
You just freak out.
Yeah.
Like there was a movie that really
freaked me out.
I think it was called clown about this
dad who,
uh,
gets his kid a clown for his birthday in
the cloud.
Didn't show up,
so he goes down to the basement and he
finds a clown outfit and he puts it on
and he's the clown for the kid.
And then that night he can't get the
nose off and it meshes into his body.
I couldn't.
Oh,
do this movie is pretty good.
That's a good movie.
Fucked me.
I couldn't watch it.
I started watching it and I was like,
no,
I can't tell me a trailer.
Young Jamie.
Oh my God.
He freaking out.
Yeah.
This,
I don't like clowns,
but see the green inferno he made about
the cannibals and South America,
I think.
No,
it was fucking good.
It's on Netflix I think.
Or is it a horror movie?
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
People are dying as gruesome.
He's really good.
He made that a hostile movie.
He's also in,
in his pastor.
He was bad ass niggas.
The bear Jew,
you know what I keep hearing is fucking
amazing.
Is the new blade runner movie,
but it's not doing good in the box
office.
Apparently they had to sign
nondisclosures when they went to review
it where they couldn't reveal anything
about the movie.
Alright,
give me a.
give me some volume here.
We'll put the trailer here.
Oh,
everything's gonna be fine.
Whoa.
Skin of a demon.
Hello?
Wow
Dude.
You can.
The sound is very loud.
Distorted downstairs.
I want to see my number one birthday.
Whoa.
Uh,
fuck that dude.
I'm watching that tonight.
Are you kidding me?
He makes.
He's got some really good movies that
have come out over the last couple of
years.
What?
What else?
What is he famous for?
I believe hostile is the first one.
He made that motherfucker.
I'm not watching this
moving then clown too.
There was a part two.
He came back to watch the trailer for
clown too.
Made this looks like a joke.
Can ask.
Oh,
is it?
I don't know.
Look pretty fucking violent.
Get deep in there.
See what happens.
So ha ha ha.
I have the outfit on,
maybe not same people.
Same people.
This is the 2017 version.
Just time for us to binge.
This is what we're going to do in the
new studio.
Bert,
we're going to watch some fucked up
movies and do like fight companions for
fucked up movies.
Funny movies.
Oh,
it's not real.
Oh son of a bitch fan me.
Fuck
man.
I can't.
I'm scary movies.
I get rugged,
legit,
scared.
Like I get to the point where I go,
I don't know why I'm jumping out of an
airplane.
I go,
I don't know why I'm doing this.
I don't.
I don't know if I enjoyed this.
Like I,
I saw the when I remember seeing the
ring in the movie theater and I was
screaming so bad that people were
laughing.
Why do you get scared?
I don't know.
Did you see the new it movie?
No,
I would never.
I saw the original.
I was like,
I was.
Stephen King is probably pretty good.
Thriller and the clown showed up,
but I couldn't stop watching it.
The original homes on TV,
wasn't it?
Yeah,
it was a mini series or something.
Yeah.
That bothered you that much.
I don't like clowns.
Clown makeup.
I'll never happened.
Really?
I did once I got mauled by a bowl
because the only time I've ever put
clown makeup on.
Oh,
go to Eddie Bravo's instagram page
and check out this new bull fighting
thing.
They're doing their new doing this new
bull fighting thing where they don't
actually fight the bowls.
These are acrobats and they stand in
front of the bowl.
The bowl charges them and they flip over
the fucking bull dude.
People are taking shit to a totally next
level.
Watch this.
Oh,
shut up.
Yeah.
Nonviolent bullfighting.
So they don't kill the bull and like
this is probably,
first of all,
it's way more interesting and I don't
feel bad watching it.
I mean I'm going to feel bad if this guy
eventually gets a horn through his
asshole,
which is probably going to happen,
but I'm not rooting for the bowl.
Like I'm kind of rooting for the bull
when I see matadors not even kind of.
I think bullfighting is completely
retarded.
I think if you want to shoot a bull and
kill it and eat it,
I get that,
but you should do it humanely and you
should,
you know,
you should do it where you're,
you're,
you know,
you're doing,
you shoot the ball in the head or
wherever you're going to shoot it in the
heart and get it over with.
But they stabbed those things with these
long spears and they poisoned them.
They do a lot of shit.
But this is to me,
way more dangerous.
Way more brave.
Way More interesting to watch,
I would say.
Which addresses a major concern amongst
animal rights activists.
What does the Bulls aren't getting hurt?
But I don't.
This is nonviolent bullfighting.
Oh,
I think we're just watching a loop.
That's what it is.
So it says a Ole.
Well,
this is the guide DPK,
DP Four K dot m.
I follow him on instagram and he's a
radical anti,
uh,
like,
anti factory farming,
animal rights activists.
Guy Or girl.
I don't know if it's a guy or a girl.
Honestly,
I'm just sexist.
But uh,
his page or this person's page,
her page,
whatever,
is just filled with a animal rights
stuff.
It's always animal rights stuff.
We went to a bullfight in Madrid or
Barcelona.
Me and my buddy,
we told him we were 22.
We didn't know what it was.
We were like,
yeah,
we got to go to a bullfight.
Right man.
We were.
Both of us were like,
this is really upsetting.
We were kids.
That's when you'd be like,
Oh fuck yeah.
But both of us were like,
oh,
they killed them.
Like it really is up really a sad with
this guy put up the.
I found out about this guy,
this animal rights guy.
And I followed his page because he put
up a,
a picture of a friend of my friend Adam
Green trees in Hawaii,
Hawaii,
Australia,
because in Australia they hunt feral
cats.
And this guy was holding up a cat like a
house cat.
They shot and killed.
And the reason why they do that is
because feral house cats in Australia
are an invasive species and they are
devastating the local ecology.
They destroy ground nesting birds.
They kill everything and there's a large
population of them.
They actually have a bounty on feral
cats in Australia.
See they've,
they made some terrible
mistakes with conservation in Australia
and one of the mistakes they've done
like over and over again is introducing
invasive species to the continent.
See Australia,
didn't the predators in Australia are.
They used to have the Tasmanian tiger.
They have dingoes and they have
crocodiles which are just the fucking
monsters.
They ruthless.
They have like serious saltwater
crocodiles and then of course sharks on
the outside.
But um,
then they introduced a bunch of animals
to both Australia and New Zealand to
hunt.
They introduced a fallow deer and a
stags and a lot of different things.
Tags and mostly in New Zealand,
but in pigs,
wild pigs and these fucking things went
everywhere.
They're all over the place.
They also introduced a bunch of
different like rabbits and things along
those lines.
And when they did that,
I don't know about rabbits,
forget what it was,
but they brought in cats and foxes to
deal with some of the other species.
But then the cats and the foxes don't
just kill the species.
They want them to kill.
They fucking kill all these other things
that had no idea what a cat was like.
There was no feral cats there.
And so now they have a real problem with
them where they just,
they,
they have,
they run the risk.
I know this guy who's an animal rights
activist,
his thought is he seeing this monster
shooting someone's pet,
but it's most likely not someone's pet.
It's most likely a feral cat.
There's thousands of them,
hundreds of thousands of them in
Australia.
And they're a giant issue.
They,
they,
they hire people to kill them because
they're devastating all these animals
that had no idea what a cat was.
So it's a much more complex issue than a
lot of these animal rights activists
understand.
And I was thrown off because,
uh,
Adam Green tree,
my buddy gave me a bowhunting magazine
from Australia when I was there visiting
him and I was going through it on the
plane and there's pictures of guys
holding up cats and they shot.
And I was like,
what in the fuck is wrong with you
Australians?
But when it's explained to you by
someone who lives there,
it's not like we hate house cats.
These are not house cats.
This is like going out and shooting,
you know,
a bobcat that's been killing all the
local grouse,
you know,
like if you introduced a cat into the
area that wasn't supposed to be there
and it was devastating all the other
animals.
So you have one of two options.
Either you just let everything go
extinct and don't handle it,
or you try to clean up the mess that
your ancestors sort of started before
you were like nutria.
Yeah.
Nutri is a good example.
It's a very good example.
Those fucking things is giant rat
things.
By the way.
I,
I have to,
I have to take two seconds talking about
Adam Green Tree.
He's like my new favorite obsession.
He's awesome.
He,
uh,
you tweeted out,
you got to watch my buddy on this hunt.
When we went,
I was in Australia and I was like,
all my time zones.
We're all fucked up.
And I was not sleeping and I got
obsessed with that hunt.
He did.
Started in Colorado,
ended up in Montana.
Yeah.
I got obsessed with it and it was so
much fun to watch.
And then when he got off the hunt I was
like,
well fuck,
I guess I'll just wait for the next
month.
We'll explain what the thing is.
He was so low he will backpacking
and he was covering and oh by the way,
I speak big.
I'm probably wrong.
Views covering like 15 miles a day on
easily easy easily.
And not just a flat walk up mountains
because you gotta you gotta glass.
These things I'm about to.
I feel like I know I'm a hunter from
watching this video.
Every day he would post on his insta
stories and,
and he was looking,
he find elk and he was hunting elk and
he would find elk,
but it wasn't the one he wanted.
And like he'd see this,
how can I.
he's like six point six,
six point.
Yeah.
And he's like six point,
but it's not the right one.
It was.
They were young.
You didn't want to shoot a young animal,
do you want her to shoot an old mature
animal,
and then at one point there was a bear
tracking him and I'm like,
yeah,
not just tracking him,
charging him,
and he was getting.
He was doing an instagram story of these
bears charging him and in one of the
instagram pictures it's him holding up a
gun and you see the bear in the
background standing at a time legs.
When I posted that his likes are his
followers went from the beginning.
When you started this quest,
it was at 75,000
followers.
By the end of this trip he had doubled
to over 150.
What is he at now?
Adam.green
tree.
He just renewed his vowels with his
beautiful wife,
Kim Australia.
I feel like I know the guy like you have
never met him.
Oh,
I got to introduce to them.
He's going to be here.
Yeah,
he's gonna.
Be here soon.
Um,
what does he got now?
Yeah,
162.
Is that what it says?
Yeah.
When we started,
when he started this trip,
rather look at those pictures of a
grizzly bear footprints in the ground
right next to his footprint.
Fucking,
hey,
look how big those goddamn things are.
And if you're interested in these,
uh,
instagram stories right now,
my friend remy warren just posted
another crazy instagram story about
their time on a fog neck island in
Alaska where they got attacked by a
giant Kodiak bear.
They got attacked by a 1000 pound bear.
One of the guys wound up riding the bear
on its back.
They bear charged them.
Everybody's scattered.
One of the guys hit the bear in the face
with trekking poles.
One guy got knocked up into the air,
wound up on the bears back as the bear
was running down the hill for like two
or three steps.
He was literally riding this bear's
back.
Who's this guy?
Remy,
what Ramey warrant.
He's another friend of mine who's a one
of the like.
There's like,
there's a call with him right now,
full of the best bowhunters in the
world.
And I'm privileged to know,
but Adam is most certainly one of them.
So it was remy,
my favorite,
my all time favorites are always gonna
be Cameron and Cameron Hanes is
starting,
that's remy,
like he's got some pictures and videos
of the hunt that they went on in a fog
neck,
but he had 'em,
they'd killed an elk and that's the elk
down there,
the one with one antler and uh,
he had broken off one of his antlers a
fighting and they were cutting this
antelope elk up and packing it out.
And then they set it down and they were
just sitting down eating lunch
and uh,
they didn't have their guns on them.
They didn't,
they just were just unprepared and with
no warning this 1000 pound bear charged
them just ran right at them into the
camp.
Just decided that he wanted that elk and
it was just fucking chaos.
And everybody scattered and thank.
Thankfully everyone was okay,
but they got as close to death as
possible.
I was talking to me about on the phone
yesterday was telling me that literally
inches away from his face,
he was seeing gnashing teeth like inches
away.
Dude,
what the fuck man?
What's even like?
I mean that's like I can't,
I can't wrap my head around just by
following out of.
I couldn't wrap my head around what he
was doing.
The idea that he like flew to Montana
because he didn't like the hunt in
Colorado.
We flew to Montana.
He drove or drove to Montana and then he
left the car and then just went.
He got lost.
Well he's,
he,
he knows where he's
going because he has,
he uses gps and he knows how to follow.
There's a thing called onyx maps.
You could download the maps to your
phone and then you can,
you can stretch your phone out.
And he was using a solar pad.
Silence followed all his gear.
Girls Went Kevin.
Then when I came in Sunday,
this is so silly that this is like how
life works.
And by the way,
I think anyone who's a podcast fatal
get.
This is unfollowing Adam.
I'm watching the stories and he's shown
all this pack stuff.
He's got a.
me and the girls were getting ready to
go to a to Rei and I went,
oh,
I'm gonna.
Get some of his shit.
Like some of this stuff,
because I know he's,
I know that he's only rocking the best
stuff and the girls were getting ready
to go.
I'm going to be home that next week.
I'm by myself.
So I go and I start looking at things
and then I'm watching this stories.
Leanne's watching me and he's like,
he does some video of the sun shining
and he goes,
look Kim,
it's cameron hanes is smile and I,
I get the joke and I started laughing
and lenses.
Who the fuck are you watching and who
the fuck's cameron?
Hey.
And I'm like,
other friends of mine,
I don't even know these dudes,
but I go there but you know,
but I follow them.
They know them.
So I'm giggling.
Well,
you could be friends with them.
I just have to introduce,
you know,
I'd,
I'd last one night with Adam who doesn't
drink,
doesn't do drugs.
Great.
I'd be in his camp going.
First of all,
we're not bringing any whiskey out of
here.
Adam,
we're going to sit here sober and bear's
going to tell you sober right now.
I go,
that was one of the things he was
saying.
He's like,
no drug,
no drink.
This is what I do.
Well,
he,
his father had a real problem and so he
is averse to it completely.
I have some friends that have
experienced alcoholism,
like abusive alcoholism from their
parents and they have the same feeling.
They just don't want to have anything to
do with it.
It's they see how it just wrecks people
in ruins people and I'll tell you man,
I don't feel that way because I've
enjoyed drinking and I've never really
had a terrible thing happened to me
because of drinking,
but being sober over these last 12 days
or whatever the fuck it's been,
and being in comedy clubs every night
and seeing sloppy drunks like I've seen
three or four like ridge,
like the other night at the store,
some fucking unbelievably drunk guy
wanting to have a conversation.
Me from like two inches away.
You know,
that sloppy drunk,
close talk type thing and I'm like,
who the fuck?
Who does this?
Sober?
Zero people like this is one of the
worst things about alcohol.
It's like people don't understand
boundaries or how they come off or what
they sound like and there's bad things
to.
You're a great drunk by the way,
you know,
you're,
you're like one of my favorite drunks
because you're so used to it.
You manage it well.
You're like a black belt and being
drunk.
So it's like with all the problems that
you've had with your health,
with drinking too much,
you read.
I mean,
you come off like pretty easy.
You're a fun guy to be around when
you're drinking.
It's not,
you don't have a problem in that sense
because like we all know like people
that drink and then just go,
they go dark and they get mean,
you know,
and they get angry.
We've seen that.
Not that,
uh,
that was,
that.
I never have had that.
I think that's also part of the problem
is that I'm a good drunk and everyone
enjoys me and I,
I'm a nice guy.
I'm a sweet guy and I think that's the
reason.
Even my wife's like,
I don't think you have a problem.
I don't think I have a problem.
But like the woman's with me a lot.
Yeah.
I mean she wouldn't be the one to know,
but she's like,
but healthwise has changed my health.
I mean I'm six miles in,
under an hour the other day.
That's great.
That's fast for me.
That's very good.
And it's like.
And so health wise,
I feel amazing.
Yeah.
That's 18 miles in three hours.
Well I couldn't keep that pace and
imagine if you did.
Yeah.
That's like,
that's really fucking good at it.
In 29 minute and 20 miles of a marathon.
Twenty six.
That's almost a marathon in four hours.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
I'm doing a half marathon.
I signed up for a half marathon.
This is gonna sound silly,
but just to keep myself on the rails.
Like I don't,
I don't want to lose the fitness.
I like food.
I like feeling good.
I like to think
Straw was my question initially.
It just feels like you.
This is a sprint,
this is not a change in your lifestyle.
Like it feel like what I'm worried about
is it's like you're just going to like,
this is great.
I feel great.
I've never felt better and now whew,
off the rails there will be a week of
that planning,
but it was almost like you're planning
to go off the rails.
Like this is just like I'm going to keep
it together for a month and then.
No,
I,
I talked to Tom and push about this a
lot,
but like I,
I don't want to stop partying but I
don't want partying to be.
I don't want.
I think it got out of control in the
sense that like I was,
it was like I get on stage and have a
cocktail.
I mean I drank a soda one time on stage
and they lost her fucking mind because I
can't a guild it because they just
assumed it's whiskey.
Right,
right,
right.
I think I'd like to find a middle ground
of like,
of like where I can go and have a good
time.
I want to quit drinking on planes.
That's number one.
That's my thing.
I'm focused on this month,
no booze on planes and then I wouldn't
mind ski,
like working out hard.
Like I think I always say I work out,
but like legit working out is not what
been doing.
Yeah.
Like
when you do a 90 minute hot yoga class,
you realize what suffering really is.
Ten minutes into our first class,
Tom,
tom looked over to me and he goes,
well,
you can't do this.
I'm like,
I'm looking at him.
what?
He goes,
10 minute gifts going 10 minutes.
Then you go 15 minutes an hour.
He goes,
I'm done,
I'm done.
I can't do 30 more minutes.
And,
and then when we go,
you know,
when you get on your back and you put
your arms out and tom just reached over
and grabs my hand and holds it tight
like a lover.
And he's like,
get me the fuck out of here.
And it's gotten easier.
And like things that we couldn't do.
Now we can do and we've only been at
like six classes but we're getting
better at it.
No,
we're enjoying it more.
And like everyone knows us because we're
the two big fucking bears in there.
And uh,
but Tom got in trouble for drinking
water one time.
Didn't drink water during the poses and
you can't do that.
You have to wait until both poses are
done.
Who set one?
Set Two.
He got so fucking pissed.
He went to go drink one of the like Tom,
no water and he was like and looked
around to me like,
are you fucking kidding me?
He's,
he's a guy teaching the class for us
guys are the ones that tell you to
water.
The girls are like,
if you'd like to drink water,
please do it.
When we're done with the pose,
is that you like your.
Everyone's working together.
This is the idea that [inaudible] does
is that you're all working together and
that if you interrupt the work to drink
water,
you're sending a bad message like you're
not in the community,
you know,
because there's something about those
classes.
It's like I'm,
I've done yoga by myself.
You know,
I have an APP on my phone and it'll time
out all the poses and stuff like that.
I can,
I can do it,
but I do a lot of working out by myself.
I do a lot of lifting and running and
everything.
I do by myself,
I know how to motivate myself,
but it's so much better to do it in a
class.
It holds you accountable,
it holds you accountable and it's slick.
There's no bullshit you.
This is going to be your fucking to hold
this pose for 30 seconds,
period.
This is 30 seconds,
you know,
and you do it as much as you can and
your fucking feet are shaking and to.
My favorite one is my favorite one is
this one.
You go down here and sit here.
Yeah.
I love that fucking post.
That's my love that I just because I was
a catcher so it's like it goes right
back to my strength was that one works.
I love that fucking pose.
I go deep when she goes down,
I go deep.
Not In the plain one where you come on.
Good one.
Tom.
Tom and I had been talking about doing a
calendar,
a yoga or yoga poses calendar.
Twelve months.
Me and Tom and different poses together.
You could sell the shit out of that
thing.
It's like great idea Jamie.
You would take the for photography.
A couple couples poses down by the
beach.
We're talking about Jamie,
we want to do a Vikrum hot,
sweaty,
uh,
maybe both of us in speedos.
Oh yeah.
And,
and,
and hold our favorite poses
poses.
I'd wear those in a heartbeat to the
second we went in the first cost.
We went in.
Tom Goes,
uh,
he sees a guy in the speedo and he goes,
how are you not wearing a speedo because
like,
this is your whole thing.
And I was like,
I don't know.
My favorite Tommy Bond story in Yoga
instructor starts telling a story,
you know,
like in between poses.
He's telling a story in the first 30
minutes of class about his son and him
in New York and his son walking and his
son being out of breath and whatnot.
And then continues on with the poses.
Last 30 minutes of class,
we are fucking panting.
We're on our stomachs face to the left,
hands down by your side.
And I hear it in a silent class a year.
Tom Go,
hey man.
Hey,
what happened?
And he's just talking loud as shit.
Scared the fuck out of me because what
happened with you and your son in New
York?
They got goes.
Excuse me,
guys goes,
you never finished your story,
man.
I've been waiting for this end of the
story and you just kept dragging.
Like he keeps talking and I am in
shaking next to him going,
shut the fuck up were fucking yoga.
Does the guy finished?
And that was it.
And Tom Goes,
oh,
he is so fucking funny.
Did you see the video we did with the
girl?
Oh,
did you see the girl?
The video we did with the girl,
Laura Ackerman.
She seemed so good.
She was so cool.
Shit.
The instructors that would know she was
just a person in class.
The look on her face
face when?
When we go to the other machine,
you come coming the tank.
You haven't seen it.
I thought she called you.
No,
no,
no.
You're the machine here.
Play the video and watch the look on my
face when I go.
We're doing with our friend Ari Shapiro.
Do you know her fear?
And she said,
no,
no.
Play the video.
Jamie.
This is the look on my me and Tom's face
when she says she knows already.
We fucking lose our shit.
Hot Yoga class number two.
Laura.
Laura,
how did we do?
We shocked you when you said we were
doing no alcohol?
No weed this month.
Huh?
You got to pray for Joe?
Yeah.
Oh,
let's bow our heads and pray for God.
You Ready?
One,
two,
three.
Now I'm a stage Joe.
Our thoughts and prayers are with you
this week in Vegas.
We know you'll be using the cannabis.
Yeah.
Joe's also donating 100 percent show to
the Las Vegas.
You guys shout out to Joe Rogan on that.
Good job.
Good job,
Joe and Ari.
Ari Shapiro says you do,
but you know,
very severe.
Alright,
we'll see you next.
Hilarious.
And he said that to the instructor.
Oh,
he is,
dude.
He is so fucking.
There's a.
If you like to stand
up,
you would love being his friend because
he's so dry.
Yeah.
As he does in that class or he's not
trying to be funny as being tossed to do
that in class too.
Just talking in the middle of class.
Oh God,
they do tell some terrible stories
though,
because they have you held hostage.
Yeah,
because you're in the middle of Yoga,
you know?
Oh,
I said one time the lady goes,
uh,
Bert,
it's the one where you pull your foot up
and you're supposed to kick your foot
out.
She goes,
burt grabbed the bottom of your foot.
I go,
I can't.
I'm fat.
And then she goes,
there's people fatter than you in this
class going because we know that fucker.
He,
by the way,
I have to say this,
I will always shit on Tom's.
Wait,
he's actually looking really good,
I think is hot yoga is really clicking
with them.
Oh yeah.
You can get much deeper into poses and
can.
I have a hard time getting into deep
poses,
but he really has changed his life.
We weighed the exact same joe.
Yeah,
but he's probably more muscular than,
you know,
a lot more skin.
Something about them that seems more
fit.
Being real.
You're down to 19 or something crazy.
What were you at?
The weight loss challenge was to
probably to 19 to 22.
Isn't that crazy?
You're lighter now and you're not
dehydrating yourself.
I took total measurements in my body
because I'm curious to see at the end of
the month everyone said,
I looked like I'm deflated.
You look thin,
my face looks healthier and so I took
measures on my stomach,
my arms,
my legs,
and just to see like,
like what the shift was.
I was 2:24.
The day West I stopped drinking.
What your face looks different like your
eyes,
like you used to have the.
I've been drinking bags,
you know that a lot of people get six
slash one slash 2:24
chest,
47.
And Are you talking about your Dick?
Yeah.
So you're doing that at the beginning
and then when you get to the end you're
going to check yourself again.
Now what are you eating?
You eating healthy or eating?
Just whatever you want.
Well,
I'm eating healthy for like two thirds
of the day.
Oh,
okay.
Like,
like I'm eating really healthy and I'm
doing this.
I saw this on a podcast you did with
some girl about not intermittent fasting
and fasting for 13,
12 hours.
Yeah.
That's called intermittent fasting and
doing that I'm doing intermittent
fasting,
but by the way,
14 is what I think they recommend.
Really.
Your last meal is at 5:00
PM or just eat at 10:00
PM and then don't eat until noon.
I have my last meal.
Is that mid at 8:00
PM last night I.
Last thing I put my mouth was at apm.
I do seven and nine.
I have dinner at seven and then I don't
eat until nine in the morning and when I
eat in the morning I drink butter
coffee.
Like before I work out I just have
coffee with grass fed butter and mct
oil.
That's what I've been doing that.
And that's your first.
Once you have that structure saying
yeah.
Yeah.
But I,
I go 14 hours every day without eating.
I've been eating a lot of,
I shouldn't say every day,
five,
six days a week.
I go,
I try to do 12 hours every day and then
the first thing I do is I drink a two
huge things of water and then that shit
immediately,
as soon as I have those.
Yeah.
And uh,
and then,
and then I'll eat.
I try to eat healthy in the morning.
I'll eat healthy in the afternoon after
hot yoga.
Man,
I fucking,
I,
I cannot say no to a candy bar.
Like I don't know if it's my,
if my blood sugar's off probably.
Yeah.
But I'm like,
I come home and I'm like,
I need fucking something sweet.
I'll eat a really healthy dinner.
Yeah,
that's probably exactly what it is.
You know,
your body is craving glucose.
It must be.
I had a score.
Bars.
I eat it so quick.
Yesterday have so many calories.
I don't know how many calories you burn
and 15,
they say that's it.
Seven or 15.
That sounds about right.
Well it depends on the effort.
You know,
I'm like if you do it 100 percent,
like I can coast through a class or I
can do everything at 100 percent.
And I've done both.
And the difference in the way I feel at
the end is significantly different.
I did one class that was a mix up.
It wasn't bikram,
it was hot yoga,
and it was a,
it was a little like,
a little different in that we did all 26
poses,
but we also did flow in between them.
Yeah,
that was really tough.
I thought that's the kind of you went
to.
I was like,
I'm never going to Joe's one because it
was like downward dog,
Cobra Warrior one,
Warrior one,
Warrior two on Wednesdays.
Do you really?
Yeah,
that's my Wednesday.
That's a hard fucking class.
Our class.
Yeah.
And then they add humidity to it.
Oh really?
I don't know.
They said just,
I said I walked in those very
competencies with my wife's best friend
and I was like,
uh,
they're like,
have you ever done hot yoga?
And I said,
yeah,
I do back home.
And they're like,
we're a little different.
I was like,
no,
I get it.
It's,
it'll be.
But it's the same poses,
right?
It's like,
no,
there's some flow in between and we add
humidity.
So stand by the door,
like make sure you're masked by the
door.
So they must have like a humidifier in
the room or something.
And I guess that's why I was by the door
and it was so much hotter in there that
it was burning my eyes and mouth and
they would open the door.
And then when they opened the door I was
like,
thank God.
Well we got a sauna that we're putting
in the new studio.
It's actually in already.
So uh,
can't wait to see this new siblings.
Oh Dude.
It's the play house.
We're going to have the best play house
ever.
Oh,
so exciting.
It's happening.
We were setting set to move on Monday.
You're going to move on Monday.
That Monday.
Shit,
we got to do a podcast.
Maybe you telling me.
And already again,
one more time when we're back partying,
going to get already high first.
You have them down,
bring them back to baseline.
I tie them back to happy hour.
I will tell you,
I miss it.
I've never had a real,
uh,
one of marijuana like I'll smoke it,
but I've never been a guy that like gets
high on my own.
Ms Dot Marijuana.
Marijuana is a great thing,
but it's also a great thing to just be
alive and be yourself and take a month
off of everything.
I,
I'm enjoying this.
I'm enjoying this 12 months.
I have zero cravings.
You know,
one thing that I miss,
I wish there was nonalcoholic wine that
tasted the same because I really do
enjoy wine.
I like wine with a nice meal.
Like,
you know,
I've worked hard and when I'm done
working I like to go to a restaurant and
have a nice meal or sit at home,
maybe cooked for myself.
Have An.
Was that you detoxing?
They call it the crocodile shakes.
I'm having a like a steak and some wind
does have one of the great pleasures.
That's the only thing I'm missing.
I've only wanted booze one day this
whole run and that was at the rams game.
Cold beer on a hot day at nice cold
beer.
Oh,
it was a beautiful day and I was with
two buddies and and their kid and I was
like.
And they were like,
hey,
we're going to go to the,
the corona little bar area to get a
drink.
I was like,
okay,
and I hung out and I was like,
Oh,
I definitely want a cold beer and a hot
dog and some peanuts and then just,
Oh,
and then that trade off you do with your
friends.
Hey,
you're going to go out and get beers.
Grabbed me,
grabbed me one and then they come back.
You gotta Oh.
And,
but in the honesty,
I gotta be honest with you.
I,
I really enjoyed,
uh,
being the designated driver.
I've never done that.
So like I was like,
I'll drive everybody.
I'm responsible.
It was really cool to show up and see my
kids and be like that stone sober,
you know what I like?
I like a cold beer when you're fishing.
Oh,
come on like a Medallia or something,
you know,
like a Modelo,
amber.
Nice fucking freezing cold.
We have reached into the cooler and the
ice is fallen off the bottle and you
cracked that fucker and,
or Heineken.
Good cold.
Heineken sounds old Sam Adams.
Sounds amazing right now.
Cold Sam Adams.
Lager.
Stella tastes so good.
I want to be on the on,
on the water,
like fishing with a cold Sam Adams.
Oh,
what would it be?
The drink.
What would be the drink of.
You're sitting on the beach on a beach
bar in like St Martin's in the son's
getting ready to set in some of those.
Can I get you a drink?
What would be your drink right then?
Margarita.
Margarita,
Bro.
It's cold.
It's got the ice.
It's got the salt around the rim and I'm
going to float around.
And Tyla tequilas always meaning your
party and you drink it to kill your
partying.
Oh,
I can't wait.
I can't wait till I get started again.
I was going to be with Red Halloween
night at 11:00
or he's like you started at eastern
standard time that 11:00.
New Orleans.
We get to have our first drink,
so it's.
I cannot fucking wait.
You guys are going to be in Halloween.
You're going to be in New Orleans.
Halloween.
We're going to French quarter.
Your Kid's gonna tweak on that.
That you're not going to be with your
kids on Halloween a.
They were a little upset because they
weren't worth of dominic's or hey,
you want to make money or what?
You guys have a job.
No.
Well Daddy has to work.
Get over it.
It's just a day fucks.
Yeah.
They were a little upset about
Halloween,
but have we find in New Orleans we go
out that night.
I was,
I ran.
I've been talking about it,
but I was like,
we'll go to a nice dinner.
We'll go out to the French quarter a
little later.
See everyone hang out,
be sober and then come 11:00
PM
Coco.
Now when are you going to,
uh,
you're going to do Halloween with your
kids at all or you just can't write it
off?
Okay.
How long are you gone for?
Come back to.
I think ren are going to a saints game
on the sixth and then me,
sal,
Vulcano and neighbor.
Got To.
You're doing the joy theater?
Yeah.
The evening of the sixth.
Oh,
okay.
So then you're at home.
I'm on the seventh.
Why don't you dress up like a clown when
you get home?
Fuck that.
My daughter Ella loves dressing as a
clown and it freaks me the fuck out.
She buys different wigs on Amazon and
that has upset and just throws them on
and puts makeup on her face.
Are you going to wake up?
She's going to be at the foot of the
bed.
That would freak me out.
The worst is someone dresses a fucking
clown in my room.
Oh Dude,
I don't like that shit.
What is it about clowns and freak people
out?
You don't know who is really under that
makeup.
There's like a weird thing,
right?
And also the kind of choices that you
have to make in your life where you wind
up being a grown person,
being a clown.
Like what did you fuck up?
Like what?
What demons are you hiding?
What mistakes have you made?
John Wayne gacy really fucked up being a
clown.
He did because he was a guy that was
like the one.
We were like,
oh,
there's something sinister underneath
there.
Maybe that's where it started.
Maybe that's where it all started with
people it had to write.
Didn't have fucker killed like 30
something kids and bring them all in his
backyard.
Did you ever see what the.
They did a movie on him.
Do you ever see what he would do?
He would.
Oh God.
What?
What did he call himself?
He had a name for his clown.
Wasn't pennywise.
Pennywise is from it.
I was about to say pennywise.
He would take,
he would take trick handcuffs and he'd
go to bring a guy,
a kid,
do his house and say,
here,
put these on me.
And then he put them on and then he'd go
behind his back and he doesn't do it.
And you go,
Huh?
I got out and the kid be like,
wait,
how did you do that?
And be like,
here,
I'll show you.
Turn around and then you get real
handcuffs in handcuffs the kid and then
fucking killed him.
So he wanted the element of fear and
terror.
Not just killing the kid.
He wanted the freak the kid out.
You wanted to trick them.
Mother fuckers
the head of that shit.
I'm all,
I am so caught.
I got offered a threesome my last night
of drinking in DC
across Texas to do with being a baby.
You hear me out,
hear me out.
These two girls were like,
let's go to strip.
But my cool,
they're dating and we get there and not
my,
my spidey sense just shows up and
they're like,
you're in an open relationship.
Right?
And I was like,
I was like,
no,
not at all.
And they're like,
oh,
we'll get you a drink.
And Martin Pardon me is like,
oh,
they're fucking roofing me.
Like they're gonna rob me like they
don't want to fuck me.
Why?
Who wants to fuck me?
They're going to me get me a hotel room
and then fucking take my watch off,
take my ring,
take,
go through my wallet,
take my cash out.
They didn't obviously didn't.
Um,
I'm a little oversensitive about shit
like that,
but I,
they got me a drink.
I've talked to back up to the bar and
go,
hey,
make me a new drink.
And they were like,
what?
I go out,
I didn't see this one coming to me or
make me a new drink.
I'll pay for both.
I don't give you shit.
Made me a new drink and then I said the
lady,
I was like,
Hey,
don't let anyone bring me a drink,
but you just,
you brings me a drink.
She was like,
okay dude,
you're a paranoid.
I'm very paranoid about that shit.
Have you,
have you ever been referred a lot?
A lot.
How many times you've been roofing for
times when?
Just a party and I was the party animal
in college.
People.
People would just drop it in your drink
for the first time it happened to me.
It was a bar.
I think it used to be called the first
eye.
They tore down the first,
but it was a place right next door to
the first over,
uh,
on that side of campus and happened to
me and my beer was fixing up and I was
like,
that's odd.
I killed it.
Next thing you know,
I ended up in my roommate's dog bed the
next day and I'm like,
what happened?
And they're like,
yeah,
you got fucking,
you got slipped something because you
were out of it.
You were talking to the dog and that was
the first time and then it just is how
it got slipped acid one time by a guy at
a party.
He's like,
anything you could party.
And I was like,
yeah,
definitely.
And he's like,
alright.
And then next thing you know he's like,
hey man,
enjoy the trip.
And I was like,
oh,
why would you do that?
So how did he give it to you?
Put it my drink and then kept drinking
and uh,
I ended up in a hotel room in the mirror
and I'm looking at my eye and in my I
can see my reflection of me and my eye
and my buddy Mike Osborne and I
shouldn't say his name.
Well I'm sorry,
said he had drank some of my same drink
group,
sharing the becomes a big 32 ounce cup
and I'm staring at my eye and my eye and
I'm like I don't,
I don't feel right.
I really don't feel right.
And I look at Osborne and he's Mike and
he's sitting in the bathtub and he's
like,
these aren't my feet.
And I was like,
I was like,
I think we got slipped something man.
And he's like,
he's like,
you fucked with that one guy,
there's this Lambda Chi.
I said,
yeah.
And he goes,
yeah,
he was putting acid and your drink.
He put us in your drink,
did I drink off your fucking drink?
And I was like,
ah,
but it's happened.
I haven't one time in Phoenix.
It was about to happen.
I thought it was going to happen.
This kid was really adamant about me
doing a shot with him and I said to him,
I was like,
Yo man,
you're not Ruffian me army are you?
Kid looked at me,
dead serious.
He goes,
hey man,
no offense.
What am I doing with his body?
I go,
what?
And he goes,
how am I getting you out of here?
You see a wheelbarrow like,
oh yeah,
good call.
Well he didn't have to carry you out to
and roof you and leave you there.
But I think that left in the dog bed,
that's the part of the part of it,
of it terrifies me of like,
you know,
I don't get,
I don't smoke joints,
people give me,
I don't,
I don't really do coke,
but people get me coke a lot.
Like I don't do any weapons.
Drugs that they'd given them.
I'm like,
I'm,
I appreciate the offer,
but I'm going to pay.
I don't smoke weed when people anymore.
I um,
had a guy in Cleveland that,
uh,
wanted to,
he,
he looked like a cop,
like completely like their cop.
And he was asking me where to get DMT.
And I was like,
what?
And was like a,
a fit looking guy with a crew cut who
was real sketchy.
I'm like,
what?
And he goes,
uh,
yeah man,
we're going to get some DMT.
I go,
what are you talking about?
And I'm like,
looking at him.
It was like,
come on man,
you know,
I'm not going.
I don't know.
Why don't you tell me what you know.
I go,
what are you talking about,
man?
What are you a cop?
I think he looked at me and next thing
you know he's gone.
It was real sketchy and I was like,
these,
I can't be getting high with people.
I don't know.
You know,
you don't know people you never know.
You like you're running into someone and
they put anything in your joint.
Like who knows,
could be angel dust.
And I know a guy that happened to,
he got slipped.
Angel.
Dustin is weed.
Fuck that.
Yeah.
I had a comic.
I've had comics.
I'm the Goto.
When comics get in trouble on the road,
I always get the phone call going,
hey man,
I'm,
I need to run something by you.
I'm freaked out.
Something happened to me.
This ever happened to you.
And I had a comment.
Call me when I was in DC.
He was like a am I got slipped something
last night.
And uh,
I don't like.
I'm,
I'm still a little sketchy,
but I want to just run it by you.
I know that this stuff's happened to
you.
And I talked to him.
We talked for about an hour and he was
getting.
Then he was like,
alright,
I gotta go to the show.
I appreciate it,
man.
I feel like a lot better knowing that
I'm not the only one that's happened
too.
But yeah,
I mean you,
you're,
you know,
people can do it right
there.
You never know someone's motivations.
I mean you get.
It's nice to believe that almost
everybody you meet is great and most
people,
y'all look,
you could live your life and never made
one single sick fuck wants to roofie
you.
You can be really lucky or you could run
into one.
The first night you decided to take
drinks from people.
That's happened to a lot of people,
especially women.
I know so many women who have been
drugged.
Oh,
so many girls.
I've dated girls who are friends with
people I've dated,
girls who are dating,
friends of mine,
got drugged at a bar.
It's so fucking common.
Every girl,
when she gets a drink from the bar has
to literally keep her eye on the drink.
The whole,
she gets it from the bartender or some.
If somebody gives it to her,
boy,
you're already taking a chance.
You've already lost the chain of
custody,
right?
Some guy grabs it from the bartender who
knows what he did before he gives it to
you and there's a bunch of twisted
fucking men out there,
man.
Really?
There's fucked up people everywhere,
but there is a lot of fucked up men.
I think we've been talking about this a
lot.
This bill cosby thing that I think that
that was a part of what men did back
then.
Oh,
it was super common.
Yeah.
We'll uh,
uh,
hugh hefner,
he used to call him panty droppers and
that,
this,
this is like,
noted that he like,
oh,
there was nothing wrong with giving a
girl a quileute.
It's a panty dropper.
Some girl wrote a book and said that
when she first met half,
he offered her food.
Yeah.
But see,
here's one thing.
Do you want to play loot?
Yes,
I do.
You give someone a quaalude and they
take it and then they're fucked up.
Is another thing to give someone
acquainted when they don't know what
they're taking that.
Yes.
And I think he did that a lot and I that
was,
they used to call it slipping someone to
Mickey.
Yeah,
Bill Cosby.
And that's a different animal.
And there's another thing giving someone
something because you want to fuck them
and they don't want to fuck you.
Let go.
You don't want to fuck me.
Hey,
you want to call a loot?
And then now you're gonna fuck me.
Because you know,
it's just,
it's just something really fucked up
about wanting that.
Oh I,
I say to,
I kind of say out loud with all this
sexual harassment,
all the dirt that's going around and go,
how did I dodge?
How did I like how like is it because I
got married younger like,
but I just never was into that.
So you're not a producer who's holding
employment over someone's head and
trying to get them to suck your deck.
There is a big difference between having
unsavory male behavior that would be
difficult to defend because you're
trying to get laid versus what you're
seeing it.
When people were furious about,
rightly so is predatory behavior by a
person who's in power affecting
someone's employment and career.
Right.
And I was talking with Whitney Cummings
about this and you know,
because Whitney obviously she's a female
prominent actress,
comedian,
she's been,
she knows and yeah,
and she knows a lot of these people and
she was saying what you're not hearing
is how many women sucked his dick and
got a big part,
sucked his dick and made it into a
movie.
Got like five.
Like it was a negotiating tactic.
Like he,
he was just,
that's how he dated.
I mean that's how he got laid.
It's like straight up predatory shit.
And then her friend had a really good
point.
She was like,
what's fucked up about it is not that he
did it.
She goes,
obviously that's fucked up,
but what's also fucked up is that that
was the culture.
That's what those guys did before there
was the internet before.
Like there was any accountability at
all,
like in the seventies and the sixties.
Like that is what all of those guys did
and that's what they did like in a lot
of those starlets that that's how you
got to pay to play and that's what they
did.
They had to fuck these guys.
Like that's literally how it all went
down.
It's crazy.
I always thought that.
I always thought that whenever I got
something like Elliot Gould and I did a
pilot together and he left his number in
my,
in my dressing room,
he was like,
we should go to dinner one night.
And I was like,
ah,
I'm gonna.
Have to fuck him.
And I kept.
No,
I kept dodging him.
I kept dodging him and he'd call and be
like,
bird,
it's elliot.
I still would like to take you to a
seafood dinner.
And I was like,
okay.
So then we went to seafood dinner down
in Venice and it was just dinner.
It was really nice and we talked about
this guy.
He's a really sweet guy.
Even at the end of the night I was like,
you're not gonna.
Try to kiss me or anything.
Birds,
not really into bears.
He was such a sweet guy and then,
and then randomly I saw him like five
years later or maybe more than that,
maybe eight years later,
and I had Georgia and Eila and I was
with Leanna and I was with my dad and we
were walking from a Baja fresh by the
screen actors guild.
We were walking out of Baja fresh and
Elliot saw me and he was like,
Bert,
it's early.
It was like,
hey,
Elliot.
And My,
My,
my wife's dad,
like,
you know,
Elliot Gold knows,
like he gave me.
He,
he,
uh,
we were in this pilot together and he
was playing a blind guy and we were
doing pickups.
We just couldn't get the line right.
The line was at,
the girl came in,
uh,
Liz Vassey came in.
She was the bride.
We were at the bout to get married and
she sees us all drinking.
I'm the best man.
And she's like,
Hey,
wait,
can I have a beer?
And then I'm supposed to go.
Of course,
that's all I had to say,
of course,
but I wasn't getting the.
Of course right.
They wanted the course to really
navigate that,
that me and her were cool,
like they wanted to make sure that we
were cool.
So I mean the whole networks,
their CBS is all there.
It's like 1130 at night.
We've shot the pilot,
we just need this pickup.
I did it like 12 times and then elliot
is a blind guy behind me and he leans
into mind.
He was bird,
how would you say it?
And I said,
what do you mean?
He go,
say it the way you'd say it.
Then just stands back up.
So she comes in,
she goes,
uh,
hey,
can I have a beer?
I go as a duck's ass watertight.
Get over here and everyone laughs,
gets a big laugh.
And then the director comes up,
goes right into my face.
He goes,
hey,
you're fucking me in the fucking ass
right now.
Do you understand me?
You are fucking me in the fucking ass.
You will never work again.
And he walks away.
Elliott state of mind when it goes,
sorry,
never work again.
Fucking the guy.
Poor guy was losing his mind,
but still the,
the,
the.
So that's Kinda,
I mean it's not the same thing as the
sexual harassment,
but as there's this thing of the power
over you,
the power to like literally hold your
career hostage,
you will never work again.
Like that is the,
that's always the big threat.
That black.
I mean,
how many people have you heard were
blackballed,
right?
You always hear that.
You always see like Brett Butler was
blackballed member just to be grace
under fire.
She used to be on that show.
Then you end.
By the way,
let's just talk about the side stories
you'd hear about Brett Butler that they
share when you were young and you'd go
into a meeting.
You don't want to turn into Brett
Butler.
Stay sitting on locking yourself up in a
tree,
throwing oranges at everybody.
You're like,
what?
I can't talk about it.
And then you're like,
what the fuck?
Kind of crazy person that's propeller.
I met Brett Butler doing good morning
America one time.
She was the sweetest person in the
world.
She went through some shit.
Apparently.
She's been pretty open about it,
you know,
and she did Charlie Sheen's newer show,
the newer show and in the newer show,
like she was kind of like,
that was part of the premise,
like she was a bartender.
He was kind of alluding to the fact that
she'd made some gigantic mistakes and it
was kind of like a play to her to who
she actually was,
but she was on that show,
grace under fire and Chuck Lorre,
the same guy that did two and a half men
with Charlie Sheen was the guy running
it and she didn't really drink in his
face and said something horrible and
nasty.
I don't know what she said.
I don't want to misquote,
but it was something along the lines of,
you know,
wonder why your life left you if you
write like this.
Something along those.
What really.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like people.
Look,
I've seen people lose their fucking mind
when they go from being no one to like
in a short amount of time being the
star.
It's grace under fire with Brett Butler.
It's Roseanna.
Roseanne talked about it when she was on
the podcast,
she was saying,
I lost my fucking mind.
I went crazy.
She's like,
and she's,
you know,
Roseanne's the best by the way.
You never meet her A.
Yeah,
she's fucking awesome.
I love that lady.
I love her.
But she was talking about it.
She's like,
I went crazy.
She goes,
you know,
all of a sudden I went from being this
housewife,
you know,
having no money to being the star of
this giant Sitcom.
That was like at the time when she was
on Roseanne.
What was it like for channels?
Uh,
and that was a legit show show.
John Goodman's or fucking husband at
fucking show his giant.
She was the queen of the world.
They're redoing the.
I know the executive producer buddies
was producing it.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
He was like,
he's like,
dude,
it's so much fucking fun.
I'm sure.
I was like,
really?
He's like,
yeah,
he's talked about the writing staff is
like Norm Mcdonald,
Morgan Murphy,
just killer or killers,
killers.
But you know,
but Roseanne is in a position that you
and I will never be in because it's not
even possible to be in that position
anymore because there's so many more
stars now because there's so many more
venues are so many more channels.
Like you were just talking about.
We're talking about impractical jokers.
Think about those guys were giant right
now.
Right?
Those guys are on true TV.
W,
what the fuck is true tv?
Who knows?
Even watching that.
Right?
It doesn't matter.
They made it through a true TV.
Right?
Sebastian is a giant star.
From what?
From fucking showtime.
Who the hell saw that coming?
Right?
The only cents.
Gallagher Gallagher was the last guy to
get giant through showtime and now it's
Avastin.
Right?
Hen Comics in the country making money.
Sebastian.
Thank you.
Think about all the different
possibilities.
All the different youtube stars,
all the different cable shows,
all of the different.
You know,
there's so many netflix show,
so many standup specials.
It's a different world.
Now the star,
she was one of maybe 20 stars.
You know what I'm saying?
Now there's 20,000.
It's a different world.
It is enough,
but I,
but I think the Hubris is still rides
with it.
I know,
I know I'm guilty of it at times,
but you can get carried away and also
the pressure of a show rides on your
back too.
That's another thing to take into
consideration.
You have all these other people that are
around you and they all have their own
little thing.
Then they're fucking with you and it
erodes your own concentration and your
own vision and sometimes like,
hey,
it's my fucking show.
It's the Bert Kreischer experience.
Everybody's shocked off.
Fuck up.
Give me a drink.
You know?
I mean,
that's how it all starts.
I mean that's,
that's probably
what happened with Charlie Sheen.
You know,
it's probably what happens with a lot of
these people.
They just get,
they get whacked out.
And I think also there's a,
there's a thing that happens too when
you do a bad show.
It's a particular type of off the rails
when you know you're doing an
unsatisfying bad show.
And I think that was one of the things
that was happening to Charlie Sheen News
on two and a half men because that was a
bad show and he was a great actor.
Platoon treat.
I mean go back and look at his,
his,
his catalog of films that he was in
amazing movies.
Charlie Sheen was legit and then all of
a sudden he's delivering these lucky
punchlines to a canned laff machine and
he's just doing blow and he's got HIV
and he's just fucking.
Who knows what he's doing.
What,
how do you even get HIV?
I mean he might be the.
If,
if he got it through straight sex,
he might be the only guy ever.
That's what they say.
Yeah.
Like literally who else?
You know,
they say Tommy Morrison,
everybody.
I've heard some things.
I mean I think,
who knows,
who knows what people are doing,
who knows?
But it ain't a whole lot of guys.
It's a tiny little handful.
I used to have a bit about it really.
You know,
they say sam,
they say aids aids is a communicable
disease.
Heterosexuals.
He goes,
it's dance,
it's fucking dance.
Yeah.
That was his,
one of his bits.
It got them really,
really criticized.
But then people were like,
wait a minute,
is he right?
Uh,
I had some people from the CDC come to
my show in Atlanta one time and we were
joking around and I said something about
what was it,
like,
why,
like tell me about diseases,
tell me like I'm trying.
I was trying to think of a bit like
trying to like pick their brains for
something.
And the guy goes,
I'll tell you one joke.
We have said,
what's that?
And he goes,
you know what we call a straight guy
with AIDS.
I said,
what?
And he was a liar.
Wow.
Well,
it could be an intravenous drug user.
Yeah.
I mean you could have two uncles die
from HIV,
but I think it was drugs.
Well there's that.
And there's also the medication they
give the people that was apparently a
giant issue in the eighties and the
nineties was that act that they were
giving him act apparently used to be,
um,
a chemotherapy medication.
And we were just killing people quicker
than cancer was.
So they stopped giving it to cancer
patients and there was a lot of like
real confusing when aids first came
about,
there was a lot like her member.
There was some local story,
some story in Boston about some
scientists was trying to say that aids
was a derivative of the herpes virus.
Yeah,
they,
they didn't know what the fuck it was
when it first burst on the scene.
And by the way,
dude,
everybody thought they had it,
you know,
I'm older than you,
but I got my first blood test for HIV in
1993 and I was shitting my pants.
I was thinking about every
one night stand on the road.
Every freaky girl,
like let's do shots.
Next thing you know,
your raw dog and some dirty hotel room
and like,
oh my God,
am I going to die?
You know,
you start thinking.
I was so scared.
So scared.
And then when it came back clean,
I was like,
I'm only going to wear condoms from here
on out
to good clean bill of health when you.
I got mine in [inaudible] 95.
My first AIDS tests.
Oh,
that's so nice.
it was terrifying.
And I,
by the way,
I'd only been with two checks ever,
but one of the girls had slept around
with a lot of guys.
My bitch gave me the clap.
Digi.
Yeah.
Only been with two checks and I got to
clap.
That's hilarious.
The crabs?
No,
it went straight to the clap.
The doctorate.
I went into the doctor,
he just got back from Russia.
She slept with my best friend was one of
the guys.
She had slept with a few.
I get the clap,
it's burning.
I go into the doctor and I'm like,
uh,
I remember like a burning sensation,
but I'm trying to get in front of this.
I'm like,
you know,
I did a hike in Switzerland and I drank
out of a trough so it's probably through
that.
And he was like,
uh,
no.
Did you fuck a cow?
He's the.
He goes,
you got the clap.
But we've been fucking around by the way
now.
Like I was 22 at the time.
Now I realized this guy was probably
just 27,
you know,
he wasn't,
wasn't grown up just a kid,
and he goes,
have you been fucking around?
I said,
I just got back from Europe.
I hadn't had sex with anybody.
He's like,
oh,
your girlfriend's cheating on you.
I was like,
no,
I don't think so.
Isn't it funny to them it's like so
obvious and objective,
you know?
It's like,
come on,
man,
your girlfriends,
it happens all the time.
No,
no,
not magdalen.
She's a rose.
She's beautiful.
She's the impossible.
He goes,
well,
let me ask you a question.
When you go to a bar,
Do you and your Dick Split up so we can
cover more territory?
I was like,
excuse me?
He goes,
when you go to a bar,
when you go to young's,
do you and your dick takeoff in
different territories to cover more,
more surface area and then meet up at
the end of the night going,
this is who we fucked.
I go,
no,
and he goes,
then your girlfriend's cheating on you.
Still Horman get rid of her.
She's a hoarder.
I remember being like,
I thought he was a grown up.
Now I know he's just a kid.
He's just a kid.
He's like,
yeah,
and I was like,
that's impossible.
Gives us,
man,
I can give you the test,
I can give you the test if you want or I
can just give you the medication,
you can get rid of it.
And I was like,
uh,
given the test,
it's,
I'm telling you if she's not.
And then he did that time.
Have you ever had the test where they
put the q tip of your Dick?
You've never had that?
No,
it is not rough.
One of the most painful things I've ever
felt in my entire fucking life puts the
QTIP.
How far down Downey swabs it?
He swapped how deep?
A halfway I guess.
So two inches.
Well,
I mean halfway for me it was like
probably nine.
I didn't get it.
He probably probably about an inch.
He goes in and swabs it and as soon as
he,
he told me,
he goes,
grab onto the side of the table,
it's going to hurt.
And as soon as he did it,
I was like,
she's a whore,
she's a whore.
I had a girlfriend and went away.
She went to spring break,
came back with rug burn on her back
or lower back.
I was like,
wow.
She just gave me some cockamamie story
about she was drinking and she rubbed up
against a nail.
She was drinking and leaning up against
the fence.
Like you rubbed up against a nail over
your lower.
Yeah,
back what?
He will bear.
Just a drunk.
You'd have to beat a scratch up your
lower back on a nail.
Like it was the dumbest excuse ever.
And I was like,
okay.
Oh I that same girl.
We went to New Orleans to Mardi gras
houses with my buddies.
My Buddy Mark Osborne.
I was with my.
All my buddies.
It was the first time I ever did coke
were all partying and having a great
time.
And they're like,
Bro,
you got make up some chicks.
I go,
no man,
I got a girlfriend I'm not going to.
And they're like,
you know how many beads I go,
I don't give a fuck.
I'm not going to cheat on her and then
we run into her and she was covered in
fucking be
no,
and my buddies are like,
how do you think she got those?
I was like,
we took notes to just give them the
girls.
Oh,
sadness.
Thank God for those road to get out of
your system to get those like you.
I'm so much more grateful for my wife
because she's not that type of person.
I'm glad I had those books.
Good to lower your expectations too,
because imagine if you married your high
school sweetheart.
You met when you were 16.
You fell in love.
She broke your virginity,
you broke hers,
and then one day when you're 35 you come
home and she's getting gorilla.
Fuck her personal trainer who looks like
Emmett Smith.
He's just stuffing her in the corner of
a couch and just fucking hammering it.
You walk in the house,
it smells like Pussy,
like what?
It smelled like pussy and ass holes in
here.
Like what the fuck is going on?
And you hear and she's like
making a noise.
You've never heard.
You walk in the room right when he's
just interface.
Imagine the heartbreak,
see now,
like having gone,
you know what happened to me,
there's a girl that I was dating,
we've heard like kind of.
I don't think we were like,
we weren't like boyfriend and
girlfriend,
but we were definitely having sex at
fooling around and I think I was 17 at
the time and she was 16 and she,
I,
I used to have a paper route or I'd get
up in the morning and deliver papers and
I would deliver papers every day,
365 days a year.
So I was up at 4:00
in the morning on Sunday.
Sunday was the big day.
So Saturday night people are out
drinking.
They're still out.
I'm getting up in the morning and I'm
leaving.
Right.
So it,
it avoided a lot of nonsense in my life.
Like as far as partying when I was
younger,
I've barely party when I was in high
school,
barely jealous because I was fighting,
I was fighting and I was getting up in
the morning and delivering newspapers.
So those two things just knocked out all
the booze I gives a few moment,
like one or two times at parties,
a handful of times maybe I drank and
smoked a joint or something,
Sony.
But most of the time squeaky clean,
just worried about,
you know,
being hung over and getting my ass
kicked and training and stuff like that.
So yeah,
it was a fucked childhood but we've
worked out.
But anyway,
I get up at 4:00
in the morning and go deliver
newspapers.
I go outside.
This girl that I was dating is making
out with one of my friends in the front
seat of a car.
They're both fucked up right in front of
my house because the guy was my friend
who was also friends with my sister and
my sister was friends with the girl and
so the two of them were small town
Newton,
upper falls.
We lived in a small town just outside of
Boston and they're making out right in
front of my house.
So I'm,
I'm like,
I'm awake sober.
I'm looking at them.
They're probably drunk during the car,
grabbing tits and Dicks and shit like
that and I just slammed my hand on the
hood and what,
and they both looked at me and then I
got in the car and drove off.
Oh,
he shut up.
Yeah,
but it was good.
It was good.
I was like,
good.
Okay.
Because I wasn't sure like are we
dating?
We boys,
boyfriend and girlfriend.
Like I went up to your girlfriend,
are we going to do the answer to be
boyfriend,
girlfriend?
Who was that kind of thing?
Like are we dating or just fooling
around who definitely having sex,
but it was like I just not,
I just stopped having this one
girlfriend that I had.
I didn't know if I wanted a girlfriend
anymore.
I was like,
a lot of weird shit when you're 17,
but it's good to just see that early.
Like,
Oh yeah,
this is good.
Like it's good to just be Dev.
Like when I was 18 girl that I was
dating,
she moved away.
She moved to the other side of the state
and I went to visit her and I drove all
the way to visit her and when I got
there she didn't want to have sex with
me.
I was like,
what?
Like she was very manipulative.
Like she,
she was a very,
it was obviously she's 17.
She people are weird when they're that
age.
Right.
But she was just clearly knowing that I
wanted it and just deciding not to and
just was,
but now I've.
That was a super valuable lesson of
being like a needy Weirdo,
you know,
because when you're 18 you're so needy
and just you can be annoying and if one
person wants something too much it turns
the other person off.
You know?
It's like,
it becomes this weird little thing that
you do.
Dude.
Not to segue into a very creepy area,
but like Eric saying that saying that
I've been going through this a little
bit.
My oldest daughter is starting to grow
up and she doesn't need us as much as.
I mean,
it goes from being like this little girl
that just everything,
dad,
let's go on a bike ride,
let's go.
Let's go and catch in the front yard
until like,
Hey George,
let's go on a bike ride.
She's like,
I'm busy.
How old now?
13.
And that's when it happens.
Hormones,
man.
And it's been,
it's been.
I think I naturally tend to that needy
guy like of going like,
and I said to my wife,
I said,
I'm not handling this properly because I
want to.
I get angry.
I go,
come on.
Like I called her the other day.
I go after the,
after the rams game I go,
hey,
we're going over to the hay slips.
And she was like,
um,
she was like 13.
And she goes,
ah,
this is the first I'm hearing of this.
I'm like,
well,
what you mean though?
You're my fucking kid.
I will meet you there.
She goes,
dad,
it's a school night.
It's an early night.
We should probably.
And I go,
no,
no.
Like she just wants her distance.
She wants to be home like reading a book
or she wants her own personal
sovereignty.
She wants to be able to control her own
life.
Right?
Yeah.
But I was like,
there's got to be a dad's book out there
of like how you deal with your child not
wanting to be around you.
Like she asked me to can.
I used to do this thing where I dropped
them off and then I just yell,
I love you.
Until they couldn't hear me anymore.
Like until they were far away.
Like I just go,
I love you and I love you.
I love you.
And like other kids be staring at him.
She said to me the other day,
she goes,
hey,
why do you do that?
I was like,
I don't know.
You don't like it.
She goes,
I,
there's kids that don't know me that
don't know that it's a joke and like
it'd be better if you didn't do that.
No.
I was like,
okay,
I've been doing this since she was a
little girl and I was just like,
alright,
yeah,
yeah.
I can see how that was creepy and I was
like,
fuck man.
Like I don't like,
you can't do that when they're 30 dad,
dad,
my kids are gonna wake up.
Yeah,
your dad loves you.
But there is this needy dude in me that
I do feel like it's part of a breakup.
You know,
when you go into a breakup and you love
someone they don't like,
I just need my space.
Oh yeah.
And you'd be like,
but hold on,
wait,
does this mean we don't go to the movies
anymore or something?
And you start panicking.
Oh yeah.
I started having that with my daughter
and I said to my wife,
I go,
just,
you know,
like I'm not processing her
independence.
Well,
like,
like I just part of me wants her to need
me,
you know,
of course.
And she doesn't know that she needs me.
She wants and totally healthy for her to
establish yourself as your own person
and do own stuff.
But man,
I,
I all I can see is this just going to
get harder?
Well,
there's one thing to take into
consideration that you really can't fix
and that's you're on the road a lot.
Yeah.
You know,
when kids are not around you all the
time and then when you're there you're
really overbearing.
It's like,
Hey,
I'm used to my own space and now you're
fucking with me and you're yelling,
I love you at school and stop,
stop.
You're ruining my thing.
I'm working on my thing and you're
stepping in and fucking it up.
Yeah.
And it's like,
uh,
you know,
I don't like,
think about,
I don't think about the product I put
out.
I don't think that there's videos of me
and speedos or,
you know,
I don't think of that stuff,
but I'm sure that there's kids in our
school that have googled me and he said
something or like,
I can't imagine what kind of footprint I
leave behind that she's got to sweep up
and go.
And I never thought about that shit
before,
but now I'm starting to realize it and
I'm like,
oh.
Like I said,
in the end of the day,
Georgia goes,
I want to watch.
I'm own watch parts of the Caribbean
five,
the last one,
the six,
whatever,
and I was like,
I don't want to watch that and we start
fighting about it and I just want us to
be together as a family stone sober
obviously,
and I have a moment of fucking honestly.
I go,
hey,
I feel like I fucked things up.
So I was on the road for seven years.
Okay.
I feel like I should've never done
travel channel.
I will always feel that way.
I will always feel that regret,
but these are the moments that I need in
my life where we can all be a family and
if you guys don't want to have,
because I was gone for so long,
I get it.
But understand that if someone could
just give an inch so that we can just
hang out and watch this movie,
it would mean a lot to me.
Okay.
I'm going to store,
I'm going to get fish.
I'll be back in.
Georgia just pops up and she goes,
I'll go to the store with you.
And I was like.
I was like,
oh.
And then I was like,
well no,
I want to go to the store.
So we go to the store together and we
didn't handle it though.
That's what I mean.
Look,
you can't fix the past,
right?
Kevin can acknowledge that maybe it
wasn't ideal and that's a great thing,
man,
to have that kind of honesty because
that's a great lesson to your kid that
you know,
like if you have made mistakes,
don't pretend you haven't,
don't gloss over it.
Just talk about it.
Like talk about your feelings.
Honestly.
I mean I think a lot of us were
frustrated by the way we were raised in
that regard that your parents never
anybody ever saying they did anything
wrong,
ever,
ever know.
It was never.
My Dad never once said,
I'm sorry they didn't say that,
didn't nobody said that back then kids
shut the fuck up and go outside.
Yeah,
that's what you heard.
Like nobody taught you anything.
You just,
you know,
it's just like what you did.
Parents went to school,
our parents went to work rather.
And you went to school and then when you
got home from school there was nobody
there.
You had a key.
You let yourself in the house and you
fucking figured it out.
Stupid doubts.
I mean there's none of that too.
Daddy.
How to make one meal.
And that's what you ate all the time.
So that's what you made yourself.
Mine was a frog in a hole where you put
the hole in the bread and put an egg in
the middle of the bread and then you
flip it.
You ever had that?
No.
He ever had that.
Jamie.
You don't call it that though.
What do you call it?
A I have something or other.
I forget.
Yeah,
it's really great.
It's the only thing I knew how to make
you just take a cup and you cut the
center out of bread and then you crack
an egg and you do an egg inside that
center and you let it grill and then you
flip it over.
Those.
The only thing I knew how to make.
I must have eaten the hundreds of those,
Huh?
Yeah.
We used to have to cook like one night a
week.
We'd have to cook.
Really?
The whole family knows in highschool.
Yeah,
it's.
I learned how to cook.
Can I tell you,
and I don't know if there's a sponsor,
your podcast,
but can I tell you one of the things
that keeps my family together is fucking
blue apron.
I swear to God.
Yeah.
They're a sponsor.
The fact that the fact that they come in
and my kids will eat something different
and we cook a meal for four and my
daughters will be like,
what is it tonight?
What's the Blue Apron?
And we have dinner at least twice a
week.
We get two meals from them a week,
at least twice a week.
We do a blue apron.
Well,
the good
thing about it is how easy it is and
there's no waste because everything is
pre portioned and the step by step
photographic instructions makes it super
easy.
It's a great,
great service.
It really is.
They started selling wine,
sort of southern wine out this fucking
this month.
That's just this month he started
signing for me.
They just started sending me one.
It's nice,
isn't it?
I really do.
Like I was.
I was.
I did six months sober when I first
started dating a leanne.
Yeah.
You told me that we just wanted to be
sober.
I wanted to be sober in the first night
I drank was in Venice,
Italy.
Venice,
Italy were there,
restaurant,
tiny restaurant.
We were walking to the restaurant and
start snowing.
It snowed two days after,
uh,
after New Year's Eve starts snowing and
I'm like,
oh,
this is fucking great.
So we go to dinner and now it's dumping.
You see it out.
The window is dumping and Leanne's like,
let's just get lost tonight.
And I'm like,
Oh yeah.
And I go,
I need,
I want to drink,
I want a cocktail,
I want a glass of wine.
I want to enjoy this.
And I said to her,
I go,
I really want a glass of wine.
She goes,
have one who gives a fuck,
have one.
So I have a glass of wine,
have a couple glasses of wine and we go
out and we get lost in the streets of
Venice and we're just hopping in Barda
bar,
having a glass of wine and then walking
around one of the best nights of my
fucking life.
And I was like,
thank you.
Alcohol.
Well isn't it different though in Italy?
Italy's really nice in that regard.
Like this.
There's just a more relaxed atmosphere
like at restaurants,
places that you go,
it's like a different feel,
you know,
there's,
we,
we are making a mistake with the way we
live our lives,
you know,
I think that the pressure that to
succeed,
the hustle and bustle that people have
is not counterbalanced in this country
by relaxation and enjoyment and like
family time and like a nice long meal
and appreciating the rest.
We don't appreciate the rest.
We appreciate a person who sleeps three
hours a night and fucking just hustling
all day long.
Constantly hustling,
hustling.
There's something to hard work and
hustle.
But man,
I think it should be counterbalanced and
I always feel that when I go to Italy,
I mean we've gone to Italy,
uh,
my family two summers in a row and every
time we go there it's just delicious
food and relaxation and you're at the
beach and sitting at the water and just
having a couple of drinks and kicking
back.
And it's like my whole being just,
just feel likes all the bullshit just
goes away.
Like I don't pay attention to the
fucking news.
I don't pay attention to shit.
I tell my manager,
my agent,
you can't get ahold of me.
I'm gone.
I'm gone for seven,
eight days,
whatever it is,
just leave me alone.
Whatever it is,
put the fire out and I'm just going to
be eating pasta and just go to these
churches.
Check out these beautiful places.
We went to the colosseum one year,
the next year we went to some beautiful
church in Ravello and you'd just see all
these amazing places where you're just
seeing places that are a thousand plus
years old and fluid that's just fucking
incredible.
You're eating sardines that are fresh
right out of the water and pasta with
Squid and oh,
and the wine and it's just.
And you're just not thinking about
anything but just laughing and relaxing
and I think that's.
Look,
I'm a as Gogo go as anybody,
but I'm learning as I get older that you
got to also have.
You got to balance that out and you
can't.
Like,
you can't have that other shit on
reserve while you're.
While you're relaxing,
you can't be checking your phone,
checking your twitter and checking your
email constantly.
We've got a slide that bitch aside.
You've got to leave it in the room and
the safe.
You got to do something.
You gotta you gotta just not pay
attention.
You got to just somehow or another
figure out a way to let go and it's
taken me a while to learn how to do
that.
Man.
I was always like,
if you're not moving forward,
you're falling behind.
You know,
that's,
that's always been my thought process.
I have this fucked up.
I'm like aggressive,
competitive thought process.
Do more than the next guy.
That's how you get ahead.
But that's not always the case,
especially in our business,
which is so dependent upon creativity
and the mind.
And I think your mind like you want to,
you want your mind to be in a good
place.
You know,
I think like if you're in it,
my mind is always in the best place when
I have good relationships with my
friends,
my family,
that's where my mind is in the best
place.
That's the most important shit that
cultivate that as the most important
thing.
But a lot of times we think the most
important thing is like financial
success.
The most important thing is this or
that.
These things get that in order,
you know,
uh,
we're gonna get a new house so we're
going to get a new thing or this and
that.
But that's how bullshit like those
things aren't bad to,
to have or to as a goal.
But clearly your base has got to be.
I mean,
I hate to sound Corny,
but it's got to be things matters of the
heart.
It's got to be friends and loved ones
and family.
It's got to be your children and your
wife.
And your mom and your,
your the people that you care about like
yet those people like have good times
with those people like happiness,
like that.
You have to have that.
If you do not have that,
all that other stuff is bullshit.
If you don't have friends that love you
and you love them and you like
legitimately happy to see them and you
have laughed together and fun together,
then all the money in the world won't
mean anything to you.
It will be zero.
You will have a zero happiness register.
You will register zero pleasure for many
financial success if you know you and
your best friends hate each other.
You know what I mean?
It's just you can't have that.
That's not,
that's not what light,
you know,
and a lot of selfish people lose track
of that.
They don't understand how important the
tribe is,
how important community is.
I didn't,
I didn't at all.
I didn't understand that at all up until
this month.
This month.
Yeah,
I was,
man.
I have been at a full fucking pace,
at a full clip this entire year.
Starting from when we did that weight
loss challenge too,
when you guys that,
that Australian tour,
I've been at a full fucking pace and I
had this out.
A couple of realizations.
One of them was if I don't talk to Joey
Diaz in like a month,
then I'm working too hard.
Like.
Because Joey is someone that.
Yeah and I.
and Joe is Joe.
I think Christina Christina said the
same thing to me when I did their
podcast.
So if you're working too much,
I'm working every fucking week.
I feel like I'm very blessed to be in
this situation that people want to see
me do comedy,
so I'm like fuck,
I'm in there every week and joey was
like,
dog,
I do two weeks a month.
That's it.
If I can't spend time with my family and
do my blog and podcast and who gives a
fuck?
Who hears I'm fuck.
Just fucking lights up.
Yeah.
And I was like,
yeah,
I'm working too hard.
I'm working way too hard.
Yeah.
That's my schedule.
My schedule is two weeks a month.
I've been saying that forever.
That's all I want to do.
Two weekends a month.
You know,
people say,
Oh,
you're going on tour.
When do you leave?
Like when do I leave?
I leave Thursday.
I'm back on Monday.
Like when you're talking about I don't
go for very long.
I usually leave Friday morning and I'm
back on Sunday.
Like I'm not.
This is not,
I'm not touring.
I'm not going to go somewhere for 30
days.
Fuck
that.
I can't do that.
Oh,
I'm doing that.
I am doing that coming up.
But are you going to do.
I'm doing two tours this year.
One's like a legit one.
The first ones I think starting in June,
it's the call in sick to work tour and I
think I'm going to do it with two other
comics.
We had a tour bus and we're going to do
some venues.
Did you organize it already?
Uh,
I'm on the process.
We're in the process world.
Why?
If you've already decided that two weeks
a month is better?
Um,
because,
because I don't do what you guys do.
So you and Tom tour very differently
than I do because you guys are doing
theaters so you can add shows and it's,
it's a big deal and you're getting a lot
more bang for your buck.
I think when you do a theater.
I'm still doing clubs.
I think the money's probably in the
money's d.
you're getting a higher percentage but
you gotta be there fucking Wednesday
night,
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday,
Sunday,
fly home Monday and those just add up
into like fucking because you have to do
that.
You don't have to do that.
I don't know.
I never did that.
I know.
But you stopped doing Wednesdays in the
nineties?
No,
Wednesday.
I fly in Wednesday to do press on
Thursday.
Stop doing that.
But I feel grateful for those places
that had me in when I wasn't selling
tickets and so I know what you're
saying.
DC wide sold out a month ahead of time,
but I go can elliot's my buddy he's been
supporting my whole career.
I will be there for Thursday morning
pressed with him.
That's very nice of you.
But it's bad for your health.
Very bad for your health,
what you call in call in when you're on
the road,
but what I'd like to do is like,
I would like to do,
go ahead and get some of my friends,
get on a tour bus and not kill myself
with the travel and do you know,
like straight out 14 dates or 10 dates,
do the tour,
make some money and then go and be at
the store and.
Right.
And because that's what you guys do.
And I,
I never do the straight tours.
You have the straight tour.
I don't think they're healthy.
I don't like them.
They wear you out,
you're always tired.
You wake up in the morning like fuck,
you've got to get to the gym,
get to the gym,
get something to eat.
How many more hours before the show?
Two hours.
I'm gonna try to take a nap and you
always wind up being worn out.
And that's the thing that I don't feel
happy.
Like I feel happy when I'm home more,
you know,
like uh,
it just,
I don't like I can't go 30 days.
I can't do 30 days.
It was most I can do is I only,
this is because of the travel channel,
but I can do two weeks in two weeks and
at the end of two weeks I'm like,
get me the fuck home.
A few years ago I switched just Fridays
and Saturdays,
it was actually quite a while ago,
maybe maybe going on a eight or nine
years ago,
but it was one of the best things I ever
did because,
uh,
I don't like,
I would think about like doing Thursday
and Sunday and I'm like,
oh.
Then you just feel like it's just taken
up too much time.
I would rather do Friday and Saturday on
the road and then come back home and if
I want to do a set Sunday,
I'll do a fucking set at the store or
the Improv or something like that.
Just driving a town,
have a good time.
I get home.
I just think there's a balance that you
have to have.
Like we've all seen those guys that are
older and really burnt out,
you know,
and they,
they just don't have any energy left for
it anymore.
And they feel like it's a burden instead
of a pleasure.
Like when I go on the road now it's a
pleasure,
you know,
like I've taken most of them this month
off.
I did,
um,
the sixth at the Mirage in Vegas.
I'm doing all the rest of the shows I do
in Hollywood.
I'm doing a shitload of shows.
I did two last night.
I did Largo and then I did the store the
night before I did the Improv,
then I did two sets at the store.
So I'm doing a lot of comedy,
but I'm home,
you know,
and I'm doing this.
Being home has been really enjoyable.
I go to,
I go to Chicago in a week and I'm,
I'm,
I'm excited because I'm going to be
flying.
So I'm excited for that.
I'm excited to do a week sober and see
like do some hot yoga and Chicago
online.
Like I'm excited for Chicago.
But then.
But then I go like,
uh,
like in November it starts up hard
again.
And I'm like,
like,
I can't cancel because I've already
committed to these days.
I canceled Austin and everyone lost her
shit.
How'd you cancel it?
Why'd you cancel?
So we were doing this month and I didn't
show up in my calendar and then it did
one day I was like,
ah,
no I can't,
you can't get it because of the sober
Mike.
I canceled because I was coming off of
Australia DC and then I would have
gotten six days off then gone right back
on the road.
And I'm like,
no man,
this is about getting healthy and being
like getting my mind back about me.
And so by the way,
if you got,
if you need to refund your money,
just call the box office at Austin,
they'll refund your money.
Ham.
Dude,
it was serious.
That's a serious choice,
right?
Yeah,
I will.
I,
I'm,
I mean I talked to Tom Almost everyday
and I talked to him about a lot about
this business and uh,
like I'm at the place where they're
adding to Sunday shows,
an extra Friday show and extra Saturday
show,
another Thursday show and he's always
used theaters.
She doing all that.
If you have all those shows.
I'm doing a theater to theater tours
next year.
Next year.
Yeah.
I didn't like the money offer.
Oh,
I see.
I the money offered for me.
Do you have a good manager?
Will Talk.
Um,
yeah,
the uh,
I love.
I just left a meeting with her.
Yeah,
she's great.
But the problem,
I didn't like the theater tour offers
this year and it was mean.
I'll be very candid.
It was a,
the money was just shit.
Right?
And I was like,
well this is the one year I can make
money.
I can make,
I can make x amount of dollars,
uh,
at a,
at a club by doing,
by getting 90 percent of the door and do
an
sales sell $30.
So you get a,
you can get some real money.
Yeah.
Or I can do theaters and it's about
prestige.
For me it would be about,
oh,
I do theaters as opposed to 10.
Never met Jack Shit to me.
But it does for some comics.
I think it's stupid.
It's ridiculous.
I literally had an agent tell me,
now that you've,
you're doing theater so you can't go
back to clubs.
It's like years ago when I first started
particularly like,
what are you talking about?
Stupid.
I have to do clubs like I do the
laughing skull in Atlanta.
By the way.
Ian Edwards there this weekend.
Go see Ian Edwards,
one of the best comics life.
It's only like 90 seats.
Less than that.
I think it's 88 does it?
I know that because I stopped doing.
I couldn't make my money.
I did that two years ago or maybe year
and a half ago.
I do everything.
I do little places.
I do the comedy works in Denver still.
Oh yeah,
I do those.
I think you got to do those.
I think you got to do the little spots,
man.
House constantly.
I did wise guys in Utah.
I know you did that.
I remember that.
I remember at the time I was there when
they put those tickets on sale and I
think Keith came in and was sold out
already.
I was like,
what?
He's like your buddy Joe Rogan just sold
out already already walked away.
I was like,
wow.
I think it's like working out.
I think you have to have weight lifting,
but you also have to have yoga,
you have to have running,
but you also should do something else.
Like I think you got to have a balanced
approach to stand up and one of the
things is like intimate rooms,
like being right in front of people you
know,
and then also not sometimes being in a
big ass place.
Like I'm doing the Belko theater in
Denver.
That's like 6,000
people.
That's the kind of place that you,
you know,
you have the big show.
It's like you're,
it's not intimate,
but you,
you're,
you're act gets honed and all these
other places too.
This razor sharp edge.
And then you go to that place just
fucking send it home.
And the,
the roars of like 6,000
people.
It's crazy.
It's nice to go into a big theater and
go like,
uh,
I'm doing the Wilbur.
I think in January I think I'm doing two
shows and I think what I love about that
is you go in and for me,
I can do the hour I'm working on the
hour I have.
They're all our this new and then when
they yelled a machine,
I go,
it's a theater.
It's called an encore.
Of course I'll do it.
Thank you for coming to my show.
Oh,
what about flying dildos?
Alright guys.
There's nothing after me.
You won't fly in those.
Here we go.
I always say,
hey listen,
I get.
If you have babysitters and you need to
go home,
please leave.
You're not gonna offend me.
I did my show,
but these are for people,
the hardcore fans and so I've come a
point in time.
We got to stop doing that story though.
Why Theater Online?
Because like do you think that at a
certain point in time,
Bill cosby should have stopped doing
that?
Noah's Ark joke.
I never saw it.
Really?
Okay.
Awesome.
I'll put it backwards.
How about Ron White?
Okay.
The.
Yeah,
never did her salad.
I doesn't do it.
Yeah.
Can I tell you something?
But I really want to see them do it.
Like if I go no,
but I want to see Ron White town to see
ron white's new shit.
I do too.
But if you said Ron White's going to do
an hour of new material,
and by the way at the end is an encore,
he does tater salad,
I'd be like,
oh sweet.
Somebody yelled out.
One of my shows recently,
Bruce,
and I'm like,
I can't do it anymore,
man.
I don't even know how to do that bit.
I literally don't know how to do that
bit.
I'd have to think about it.
I have to go over it when I'm done,
I'm done.
I have to put that shit aside and move
on.
But I think that story,
that story for me,
and by the way,
I would love to not do the story.
I would love like stopped doing it.
Now.
Hold on though.
That story for me is such a defining
like it's the way a lot of people found
me.
And for a lot of people it's my
nickname.
It's everything about me.
It's when I go in stages,
the first thing they're all yelling is
they're all yelling the machine,
but they just love you.
Dude.
That's a.
that's a great story.
But if you have other great stories that
love those too.
I,
I do an hour plus of new material every
show.
But man,
he just loved doing that.
I do not.
Okay.
Then don't do it.
Uh,
I don't know.
That's why I'm looking forward to this
theater door.
The Wilbur is great.
I'm doing my Netflix special there.
Are you serious?
Yeah,
I'm going to do it there in April.
First Time I did the wilbur coming in
for somebody at the.
Wilbur was a year ago,
right after the weight loss challenge.
Numbers were super slow.
Did the weight loss challenge sold out
the next day?
Crazy.
So I go.
So I go to the Wilbur and I'm like,
this is fucking to me,
he's a big fucking room.
I'd never performed a room that big by
myself,
like sold it myself.
Right.
So I was like,
I want to see what it looks like from
the top.
Like I want to see like what that.
So I go up,
climb up the top of the stairs,
get it to the top.
I go stick my head out and I forget I'm
the person.
Everyone came to see like I like and I
call is a fucking nightmare of everyone.
Like,
Holy Shit,
what the fuck you doing up here?
And then everyone leaves while you were
at the show.
I was at the show,
the fucking opening eczema stage and I
just had never done that.
Like I'd always been the guy that was
the feature act.
Uh,
so I could go in and go,
oh,
this is beautiful.
I've never been the guy.
Right.
And I fucking caused a shit show on the
third floor.
Yeah,
you can't do that.
I didn't know that.
Yeah,
there's 900 people there,
man.
Can't do that.
That's a great club too,
because it's a three,
300 seat comedy clubs essentially.
Yeah.
It's three levels and it's like three,
300 seat levels.
So it's like intimate comedy clubs,
but there's three of them and they're
just stacked on top of each other.
So you just get roars,
but they're also right there.
It's not a,
it's like one of the most intimate 900
seat venues you'll ever work at.
It was,
I was one of the best shows of my entire
life.
I like where I just was like right
there.
Bam,
son.
Fucking love that place.
The Wilbur,
I walked in that door on the left.
I walked right in that door and walked
up like a fucking idiot.
There's a bar right up in between those
two doors.
Yeah.
And I just,
I was doing that place in the late
eighties.
Really?
Yeah.
There was,
um,
the Wilbur theater has two rooms,
so it has this room and it has another
room that's downstairs.
And that room used to be called duck
soup,
which is named
after the Marx brothers movie.
It's a hilarious movie.
I have never seen it.
It's fucking hilarious.
I have not.
I need to see it.
It's all a,
it's all.
Oh,
it was the type of comedy.
I don't know what it's called,
but it's like a slapstick.
No,
it's not even a slap tickets like a hey,
how about a cigar?
And the guy was like,
uh,
I don't have one.
He's like,
no,
go grab me one down the street.
Huh?
Like,
it's kind of like a,
it's,
it's f I fucking thought the movies
period style comedy.
Like you get a sense of like the way
that people thought.
Yeah.
It's like a,
it's like kitschy.
Almost like a,
like a misleading words.
Like,
like almost like airplane,
like a,
we've got to get this woman to the
hospital hospital.
What is it?
Oh,
it's a building with a lot of windows,
but that's not bored right now.
Like those kind of like that kind of
comedy.
Yeah.
Like Abbott and Costello.
Who's on first?
What's on second?
Yes.
Yeah.
Anyway,
I'm duck soup was a,
uh,
an experiment that the owners of the
comedy connection did.
This was back when they really thought
that comedy,
like clean comedy was the future and
they,
so they decided to create an upscale
comedy club,
a very upscale comedy club and serve
really good food and have like super
squeaky clean acts,
perform their only.
It was a disaster.
It didn't last because it was like,
everybody's like,
what the fuck?
Like guys like Steve Sweeney and guys
like Lindy Clark who like,
you know,
they had a lot of dirty jokes,
they couldn't do the dirty jokes.
They're like,
they were trying to like somehow or
another like pure,
it was a disaster is one of the owners
of the comedy club had this fucking
wacky idea in his.
Had that clean comedy.
Was the future really classy,
clean comedy.
He wanted to just squeaky clean comedy.
I mean squeaky clean,
no sex jokes,
no nothing.
It was death.
So they bought this,
uh,
they set this place up,
they spent a shitload of money on
construction.
They put this thing together and it was
gone within a year.
Really?
Yeah.
And then it became an Improv.
Then budd Friedman took it over as an
Improv and I think they were in business
with him for awhile.
I think bill bloomin' right.
Might've had something to do with it.
Um,
and then then it went under and then,
uh,
the comedy connection open and Faneuil
Hall.
So they had a comedy connection down the
street.
That was a great club at one point in
time,
dude,
they had a the comedy connection in on
Washington Street,
which was like 150 seats and then they
had nick's comedy stop,
which is down the street,
which is maybe 300 seats and then they
had nick's comedy stop at one point,
had three rooms.
They had the upstairs room,
they had a downstairs smaller room and
then they had this disco that's now a
gay bar that's at the bottom and that
was something they took over.
So they had three shows going
consecutively,
so they'd have like Steve Sweeney would
go on there and then he would go down to
the small room and then you'd go over to
the big room and he would do three shows
like that.
So he would do six sets or a nine sets.
So like,
wow.
Yeah,
I probably six probably two shows,
but six sets of two shows,
you know,
to,
to like an eight and a 10,
but an eight and a 10 in all the rooms.
Yeah.
Oh,
so you do six sets a night and then some
of the guys would go over to the
connection,
do a set,
go over to Nixon,
and then duck soup opened.
And so like duck soup was the greedy.
That was that they got greedy and that
went under.
And when that went under bill bloomin',
right.
Who was the genius behind?
He still owns it.
Yeah,
he's,
he's a financial wizard.
He was like,
what the fuck are you guys doing?
Listen,
let me buy you out right here.
Let me take care of this.
And so bill took over the comedy
connection at Faneuil Hall and that,
that became a big success.
And then they go,
you know,
he just sat and listened.
I could fill this fucking place up.
This is like 400 seats.
Why don't I just buy the Wilbur?
So he bought the wilbur and now that's
like 900 seats now.
So that's,
that's the common connection now.
And he just brings in big acts.
But the,
the problem is that Boston last,
it's like local thing.
They lost like the local scene.
A lot of the older big time headliners,
they got older and older and people sort
of forgot.
And then the open mic night scene once
patrice left and once burr left,
um,
the,
like the guys coming up,
there's not as strong.
I think there is now laugh.
Boston has got a good scene.
Last time I was there,
they were pretty excited about the
scene.
They're saying this a lot of up and
coming guys coming and Gals,
excuse me,
and binary nonbinary people and they've
developed like,
you know,
a good group of local people that are
really doing the right thing,
trying to,
trying to really get good at comedy.
But Shit,
there was stitches,
there was a catch,
a rising star and Cambridge.
There was um,
a play it again.
Sam's had a show.
It was fucking crazy.
Like for a small town.
I mean,
Boston's not small,
but it's not a huge city like Chicago or
New York.
And for this relatively small city,
you had a fuck load of comedy and really
good comedy.
That's what I love about the stores that
you could hit three stages in one night.
I do it all the time of Trifecta.
Yeah,
I've done.
I've done that like three or four times
this year.
Yeah.
I'm due to their regularly.
I love Jeremiah's new state new material
show.
Yeah,
that's,
that's where I wrote that joke.
The Helen Keller and frank joke.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Some guy just said it on stage.
I saw.
I used to think they're the same person
and like I was staying in the back of
your like,
that better be a fucking pit.
And I was like,
Nah,
I'm just an idiot.
And then I open up flying builders with
that and I was like,
that still aI.
love that show.
Yeah,
it's a fun way.
An exercise.
I just did it Tuesday,
I,
by the way.
And I just started getting the vibe,
like it took me a long time to
understand the.
Or like the Olr for me was a little bit
of an uphill battle.
The main rooms always been.
It's like,
so it was a great,
just a great performed,
but like I think I was looking at tor as
like a,
as like more of like less of a club and
more of like a workshop and I was like,
no,
you just got.
This is where you have to be able to
selling guns.
You've got to be able to,
to change subjects,
moving the jet to really read a crowd
and take their energy and move with it.
Like,
you know,
this sounds silly that I say this,
but like in a rich vos kind of way,
he's someone that could navigate the our
seamlessly,
you know,
because you can read an audience and
take the energy and push it.
What's a very intimate room to like a
lot of those guys from New York,
they used to be an on top of people
because New York clubs are very small,
which is really weird,
right?
Because New York is so big,
but the space is small.
Like you have a lot of small spaces like
you ever do the stand or a stand up New
York,
stand up.
New York is a perfect example.
Like you could barely move on stage for
caroline's.
Caroline's is like a fucking table.
This table,
this table is bigger than the stage at
Caroline's and when you're,
you're there,
you're on top of the people and they're
sitting right in front of you.
It's,
it's,
it's odd,
you know?
Yeah.
You get used to like,
where are you from sir?
That's why a lot of New York comics talk
to the crowd and they also do like
fairly short chunks.
Right?
The bits are smaller and that's also
because they're sets are like seven
minutes long.
Yeah.
I remember coming out here with Bobby
Kelly when probably it was with Bobby
Kelly the first night I did a spot out
here and I got on stage and I was like,
I remember in my head going where the
Puerto Rican.
I was like,
wait,
what am I going to talk about?
And I remember bobby getting up and
going,
both of us were sitting in the back.
He's like,
I don't like this fucking clever shit.
He's fucking joke.
Clever Shit.
Be fucking funny.
And both of us were like,
yeah,
how can they be funny?
Like,
yeah,
but with the westerns were like used to.
I used to make the analogy working out,
doing standup in New York was like
working out in the prison yard.
You had a,
you had a broomstick and cinder blocks
and you just wanted to get big enough so
you couldn't get raped in the shower and
then working out in la was like almost
like being at a gold's gym.
You were sculpted,
you look good but you couldn't defend
yourself in a real room.
And so like I looked at it that way and
then I was like,
Oh,
if you do the road you can do a little
bit of both and you can really have fun.
I think the road is where I really
learned how to do stand up.
Like for like doing an hour that were.
That was what I was like,
Oh,
you need to be able to like,
well you also have to do an hour.
That translates in Kansas City.
You could do it in Florida,
make strangers laugh.
Use Case said that.
He goes,
someone said,
why don't you do?
Ucb Goes,
oh,
because they are.
They're already gonna laugh.
Anyway.
I want the art form is making strangers
laugh.
Yeah.
And you're like,
yeah,
you gotta make people that.
Well,
that's why a lot of people do like to do
drop ins.
They don't want people coming to see
them.
They like to do a set where people don't
have any idea that they're going to be
there.
There's a,
there's definitely a,
there's a thought process to that.
I did Largo last night,
which was,
what was that like?
They laugh at your setups.
The setups.
They,
they're fucking dying laughing at the
setups.
It's,
it's so odd.
Say so polite.
It's a beautiful space.
The room's amazing.
It's a great setup.
Yeah.
I mean,
it was weird.
The nerdist meltdown one time and uh,
and I just told a story like just the
story that I was working on and it
murdered so hard and I was like,
this is a really legit comedy club fan.
They love comedy.
Yeah.
Any little nuance to a joke,
they're like,
they appreciate it.
They're like,
man,
that was well played.
I saw that movie in high school to all
rooms though.
The problem with those rooms is that if
you just work those rooms and then you
try to do a satiny or your Foxville,
like if you try to go on after Joey Diaz
in the Olr and all you do is all rooms
and by the way Adam,
that sick fuck,
he will throw you on after Joey Diaz if
he thinks you do a lot of rooms.
You know like.
I don't want to mention any names,
but I've seen people just incinerate up
there.
You know,
because you're used to this like really
polite,
set up punchline sort of crowd.
The comedy store.
You get a lot of this,
you gotta have people that are like,
come on is the best club in the world.
Huh?
Come on.
You know,
you see people that are drunk.
You get a surprising number of hecklers.
The,
the back hallway is always fucking
talkative.
Like you have to shut up.
That's a terrible design.
Like they'd been trying to figure out a
work around,
maybe you could figure it out,
I don't know what the fuck to do,
but that back hallway always has people
and they're talking and then even if
they're not talking to people off to the
side of the parking lot that leaks to
the back of the room.
Like you'll see people that are in the
back of the store and the are.
You see them turning around all the
time.
Like what the fuck?
It's so loud there.
I was on stage one time and clearly
almost agent I go clearly someone very
famous just walked into the hallway
because I get to hear everyone like,
Oh hey,
what's up?
Yeah.
And then it was loud and immediately I
just go,
I'm whoever I am planning on bringing up
next is not going up and I get that
light and I look over.
I go,
who's next?
I'm dying to know.
And they go eight to Louis and went,
okay.
That's what I thought.
Yeah.
You could tell telling somebody it's
just a bad setup in that regard.
You know,
the or is a bad setup in the sense of
that hallway,
but it's a great setup in sense of the
size of the space and the intimacy of
it.
The main rooms.
Perfect.
Main rooms.
That you've got the great hangout in the
back.
Can't hear you.
Can't hear shit.
Yeah.
Me and Santinello and bill burl
Kristalina last night.
We're fucking howling.
Just making each other laugh.
Just talking shit and just having a good
time talking about nick cannon.
Standup special.
Oops,
sorry.
But it was just so much dig.
Doe.
Yes.
Um,
we're having such a good time just
talking,
just shooting the Shit,
talking about,
you know,
clubs on the road and doing.
It's just,
it's like,
you know,
you get a chance to talk shop,
get silly dude
back there.
Look,
there's touchstones in your life where
you go.
These conversations were meaningful.
Yeah.
I remember a night I was just started up
doing birth conquer again and you and
Bert were sitting,
you were standing and he was sitting in
that corner seat where the door opens
over to hit you.
And both you.
I remember you.
I don't know what happened.
You go,
how much money is enough money and I
went what?
And you're like,
and you guys looked at each other and
you're like,
I mean,
how much money?
Like how much money do you need?
Like you're doing all the travel channel
again at bars like,
eh,
nothing,
nothing.
Your show socks.
Like I just do stand up for both of you.
Sat there and you were like,
you're good.
Stand up man.
I don't know you're doing on this TV
show.
Just get back to stand up.
And I was like,
only at the comedy store.
You get that conversation and only with
your friends.
I remember hearing that going,
get what the fuck.
You're like,
dude,
you monetize your podcast,
you do the road and you could hang out
here.
And we all like,
what is this your show?
Are you really happy?
So important to have friends that will
tell you that too because sometimes you
don't think you can do it.
You feel like,
oh,
I have to stay under contract.
I have to have to keep working.
But I knew you were on the road for
fucking weeks at a time.
Like,
Bert,
you don't want to do this.
You're a funny guy and you're not really
working.
I stand up that much.
Let's be honest.
You'd go on the road,
you wouldn't do standup for weeks at a
time.
I'd try to put in a date like jamming
the data in between touring but are
doing travel channel.
But the truth was I'd be away from my
family,
be a mess.
And not only that,
it's not enough like a date doesn't do
shit.
It's just like you go,
wow,
I was rusty.
That's all you gotta do you know you
need to be,
you know,
stand up comedies like running,
you take a month off running,
you're going to be out of shape,
you know,
you gotTa,
you gotta be fucking constantly going at
it.
It's,
it's,
it's a beautiful grind.
Yeah.
I'm so glad you decided to bail on that
shit too.
So the best thing to watch is on.
No one's my fitbit and I ran four miles.
Yeah.
But I keep it.
I keep it just to track my try to get to
18,000
steps,
but you don't want the other watches as
well.
It was a gift.
This has sentimental value.
It's not even the time isn't even.
Right.
Oh really?
It's like a bracelet.
The bracelet.
My destiny a girl,
but yeah.
You've got a bracelet on.
Yeah.
Guys wearing bracelets disturbed me.
What are you doing?
There was a period where I was wearing a
few bracelets.
Drives me nuts guys with three bracelets
on one wrist.
Like,
Hey,
you stop.
Especially like Italian guys,
like three gold bracelets and the pinky
ring.
But you're not in the jewelry guy.
Uh,
no,
no.
I've been a jewelry guy.
Thought it was your jewelry guy.
What kind of joy do you ever have a
pinky ring?
A?
Yeah.
You ever have a diamond ring?
A.
No.
I bought a diamond ring.
I've had a plethora of bracelets before
though.
Yeah,
I don't.
I barely wash my car.
Oh seriously?
I wash my corvette.
That's the only one I wash that in my
porsche.
I washed,
but the corvette is just.
It's barely a car.
The corvette is like an art piece.
The funny thing about you is how,
how annexter ordinary you believe you
are like,
well,
I'll tell you that when we tell him,
and I did the first hot yoga,
we did the hot yoga,
we got done and we were really fucking
floored and the first thing we said was
already not doing it right.
There's no way he could do these in
date.
And the second thing Tom said was,
you know,
at this point in Jos day,
it's only like 10 in the morning and he
hasn't done kettlebells run or a podcast
or sets yet.
I was like,
I'm going home and eating candy bar.
I'm going to pat.
But like that's the one thing that's
been pushing me through this month is I
go,
all right,
I'm going to go and run now.
I'm going to,
I'm going to try to do more in a day
than I normally do.
And,
and I think that is only achievable.
I've only people a real true balance
of like being sober and healthy and not
just getting off the fucking rails all
the time.
Yeah.
Because if you do
go off the rails all the time,
your body's just not capable of working
hard and if you're it just steps right.
It's like you can't just start running
six miles a day and doing kettle bells.
Then taking a 90 minute yoga class,
you're not going to have the energy.
Your body's not that.
You're not conditioned to do it,
but you can work out.
You could work up to those things.
Like you could start off with just a
light half mile run.
You could start out with,
do your best in a 90 minute yoga class.
You know,
you could start out doing all these
different things and then over time you
build up conditioning and strength and
health.
And you know,
I'm 50 years old,
dude,
I've never been in better shape of my
life,
never been more healthy.
I work out all the time.
I feel great.
I mean,
they're really do.
And I just always want to tell people
that like you,
you can't.
Obviously,
a lot of people have way more time
requirements and I do in terms of like
your day job and stuff like that.
But the more effort you put into keeping
your body healthy,
the better you're going to feel.
You're just gonna have more energy.
I feel good all the time,
you know,
and I feel better this week or this
month is 12 days in.
I really do.
I do too.
I love it.
I don't know.
I,
I think the first drink's going to be
hard for me to take because I feel I
feel like I'll be letting myself down
because I get,
like I said,
I get teetotaller and I get guarantee
that first drink I probably do a shot
with red and then I'm like,
I don't think I'm gonna go to bed.
Does Dari do shots?
He's like a drink.
Have a glass of whiskey with ice or
something like that.
I saw him do shots in Calgary here.
Oh yeah.
And then we lost him.
He didn't use to drink.
I know when I first met him,
he didn't drink at all.
He would smoke weed but he didn't drink
and then he became a drink.
And when you moved to New York it was
that really?
Yeah.
I never remember seeing him drink ever.
I remember when he lived here,
we'd go to the store,
do something,
like a podcast or something and he get
high,
but he just,
he didn't have.
He would eat candy.
That was his thing,
was like,
ah,
I can't imagine candy now.
My,
I fucking love candy.
Yeah.
Well after a workout,
it's nothing wrong with it.
Some people actually like candy,
like a lot of lifters,
a lot of people lift.
They like to eat candy after they work
out.
Really?
Yeah.
Replenish those sugars.
Supply the muscles.
It's controversial,
you know,
some people don't agree with that.
Some people do.
It's um,
you know,
it's dependent upon what kind of Diet
you have normally.
No,
I try to stay away from bread and pasta.
That's to.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Big One.
Do that.
You'll be healthier,
you know.
Uh,
my friend Cameron Hanes is running the
Moab tomorrow.
He starts the Moab to 40,
which is a 238 mile race and he's been
running a marathon a day for months in
preparation for this.
And tomorrow he begins a 238 mile race.
You could track it at www dot moab,
two hundred.com,
m o a,
b,
two hundred.com.
And uh,
you're gonna be able to track its
performance and where he's at.
And it'll take shit probably.
And also a UAE outdoor.
There'll be posting live video at UAA
outdoor use,
outdoor,
a under armour outdoor.
I think that's you.
A outdoor.
The instagram page,
right?
Click on that real quick.
Yeah.
And there it is.
It shows all his stuff.
He's out there representing underarmor
running his fucking animal.
It's funny it says,
when I first started off running,
I struggled with a five k now doing 200
mile races.
It's not that I was born with this
amazing talent.
Your body gets used to what you ask of
it.
If you don't ask much of it,
it isn't going to give you much.
it isn't going to give you instead of
twice for some reason.
If you ask a lot of it,
it will give you a lot.
Somebody should tell them that they
needed that sentence.
He can edit that,
edit that shit.
Jesus Christ,
under armour.
Get your shit together.
He's a fascinating guy,
man.
He's a,
you know,
whatever the podcast thing has done is
introduced me to people like him and not
in green tree who are just,
I find fascinating.
Yeah.
And uh,
and some fan made me a table.
I picked it up today.
I put it on my instagram and that he
just put like all the,
I guess all the stuff I dig and he,
one of the things he put on the side was
a no one cares work harder.
Yeah.
And I was like,
this cams t shirt.
Yeah,
that's his.
One of his sayings.
And that's real.
You know,
I posted something on instagram today
that there's levels to this shit.
You know,
what we were talking about,
like I'm,
I'm very self critical,
like super hyper self critical.
But one of the reasons why I'm hyper
self critical is I know people who are
just real savages who really are doing
extraordinary things and people who are
self congratulatory for no reason drive
me fucking insane.
Why are you laughing?
Congrats.
Oh,
it's like half joking.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
But I.
But I have a very low threshold for a
reward.
It's to drink.
But like,
and I had,
I think I have like a,
like I think that's why I'm doing that
half marathon because I was like I need
to start.
I want to start testing myself.
I want to start saying to myself,
let's break two hours and a half
marathon.
Let's see if we can do that.
But you're right,
there is.
I think I do that with physical stuff
because I was an athlete growing up and
I just go,
I can,
I can always jump back in.
But when it comes to stand up,
man,
I am beyond fucking critical.
I look at some of these people that put
out hours and I go like,
like,
I'm not going to name names,
but man,
there's some people that people have
said like,
I saw someone who,
I won't say names,
but they closed their specialist street
jokes and I was like,
Nah,
you can't make,
hey,
you don't have friends.
I don't know.
Yeah,
yeah.
This will stay my friend.
I would have told you don't do that
shit.
She wouldn't listen,
but here's the thing man.
A lot of people that get caught up in
that other stuff is one of the things we
were talking about,
like you doing the travel channel.
Imagine if you're doing movies all the
time,
you do one,
two,
three movies,
year movies.
You know how that grind is 16 hours a
day on set.
You don't have time to hit the clubs.
You don't have time to grind.
You're not going over your material.
You're going over your lines.
You're taking naps because you're
fucking tired all the time because
especially if you're not an athlete,
you're not someone who's like really fit
and healthy and eating really good
foods.
Your body is worn the fuck out by the
time those three,
four months of filming or done and then
you have to do press junkets and you
have to do that and then someone,
Netflix,
Hbo comes along and offers you all this
cash to do a special.
Can you do it?
Yeah.
You're not going to say no and by the
way,
your agents,
your managers,
unless they're fucking top of the food
chain,
they don't know shit about what it takes
to do standup because they don't do it.
You have to have a really good manager
who goes,
listen,
we really need to manage the time that
in the energy and the focus you put on
your act because you only get one shot
at doing this act.
You know,
and I fucked that up before and I think
a lot of us have before we've all done
sets where we weren't really prepared.
We weren't really.
And you don't know what,
what it takes until you do it wrong,
and then you feel the sting of
mediocrity and then you realize like,
oh,
there's no substitute for running 200
miles.
You have to fucking run everyday.
There's no substitute.
There's no substitute for stand up.
You have to fucking grind.
Do you have to grind?
You've got to watch your sets.
You've got to go through and say,
where's the lazy writing?
You've got to punch up the good writing.
That last hour special I did.
I think the one that really helped break
me to sell tickets and whatnot was was
me looking at it from the travel channel
perspective of Lazy.
Just get the work done,
get it up.
I just get the last.
I don't give a fuck.
And then going and started hanging out
with clubs and going,
Oh,
I'm,
there's a lot of laziness in this act
and going,
I need to.
I need to really be honest with myself
and go,
this is,
this is hacky.
Like this is.
I'm not doing the work in the special.
I think that applies to everybody that
does everything.
It's not just to our creative endeavor
of standup comedy,
but if you are whatever you're doing,
if you're a fucking engineer,
if you're a chef,
whatever it is,
whatever you're doing,
where you focus on and it gets good.
If you focus more on it,
it'll get great.
I mean it's,
it's just you have to figure out what's
missing in it.
Where's the weak spots,
where's the holes,
what could be done better?
Approach it from a different angle.
You know,
one of the things that I'll do and I've
been.
This is a thing that I've been doing a
lot over the last two years.
I'll take a bit that I know is killing.
It's doing well.
I'll take that bit.
I know it's done.
So now I look at the same subject with
open eyes,
like completely fresh eyes and then I
try to rewrite it.
I try to rewrite the bit.
I've tried to write the bit almost as if
I don't even know how the other big
goals and I write a new version of it
and sometimes when I write a new version
of it,
I'll have a whole new take that I can
add to the first version and the only
way you do that as if you're not
complacent.
The only way you're willing to do that
as if you fucking hate yourself and you
want to just grind it out all the time.
Yeah.
Either or this hour I'm working on now.
Um,
I,
I feel like,
uh,
I feel like I've forgotten too
meticulous with it.
Like I've gotten to the point where I
go,
every job needs to have closure because
I'm doing more.
I'm really doing more stories.
I'm not like doing more like premise
joe.
I'm doing legit like story.
That's what you like to do,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
you know what I have to credit already
on,
this is a,
I didn't realize I was doing,
I was doing like material,
you know,
like,
hey,
if you ever put a vegetable in your
chick's house,
make sure to use a carrot and cucumber,
cucumber,
you know,
like those kinds of like,
fun boy party stuff,
a mediocre man comedy at best.
And I think it was the first one there
was like,
dude,
your stories are really good.
And we started talking about when he was
doing started doing this not happening.
We started talking about stories and I
was like,
yeah,
I got really into it.
And was like,
yeah,
I'm much better at stories than trying
to do what everyone else is doing,
if I can do my shit and just be me that
like I felt like I was.
People were stealing material from me.
So I do a premise and I was like,
it's,
it's common ground.
Like get pulled over by a cop or you
know,
those.
It's like,
who's stealing material from you?
Well,
you know,
I'm not getting into this.
So,
uh,
but you get into stuff and you're like,
and then I was like,
oh,
these,
these stories about me,
like the machines story taught me so
fucking much.
Like I remember I've said this a million
times too.
I'll say it a million times more.
I did this podcast and you were like,
that's your store.
That's your closer.
You need to fucking figure that out.
And I went to Columbus,
Ohio that first time I was at that next
weekend,
there was a kid in the front rows,
I can tell the machine.
Right?
And I was like,
no,
it's not.
And he's like,
Rogan said,
you should tell it.
Bert.
Bert,
we understand it won't be good.
That's okay.
I remember being like,
oh these are the fans I get like,
okay.
But I learned so much at a telling that
story about how to write stories and how
to do stories.
And I think,
you know,
when people come see my show,
they want to have a good time and they
don't want to hear my view on fucking
feminism.
They don't even.
Last year view on feminism is really
funny.
Yeah.
Unless it's funny even you feel.
Yeah,
but like,
like if you feel like saying so many
comics right now are so like a lot of
liberal comics are like,
agenda first,
comedy second.
And I'm like,
no,
I'm not that guy.
I'm not going to push that agenda on
you.
I'm just going to make sure you have a
good time to tell you.
By the time I got fucked up,
I pissed on the table.
I'd fucking frogger.
Train
what ever your agenda is.
It happens to be hilarious.
Like it's got to be organic.
Right.
And that's,
you know,
I mean I don't think you should put
yourself in any sort of a box.
Yeah,
I,
I feel like I feel like if it,
if I like it,
I'll do it.
Yeah.
But then I this bit about cat calling
that I thought it was so fucking good,
but I was like,
I was like,
well,
what are you doing to it?
If you like it,
don't worry about it,
man.
You can't box yourself.
Like you remember won a Tony
Hinchcliffe.
Ex-Girlfriend's was like,
I think Tony should be all dark.
What I think,
I think you should just stick to all
dark and I have a,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Why would he do that?
How about just be funny all the time.
And then I had to talk to him about.
He was like,
oh,
she hates my bit about squirting.
Like she didn't.
The fact that he was doing
sexual jokes,
she was trying to like give him some
really shit advice.
Like he should be all dark.
She's been moody and dark.
The fuck.
It's like when you say
in a green room and then you and your
toe,
you don't know one of the comics.
Then he gets up and leaves another
common goes,
Oh,
just so you know his dad's gay and
you're like,
why wouldn't you tell me that in the
middle of it?
He was like,
I wouldn't see where you took it.
When you go places,
do you get like a crowd in the green
room?
Like weird guys show up?
Like yeah,
that's not good.
Yeah.
And they always want to like reach into
the fucking cooler and grab beers and
talk too much.
Oh yeah.
Oh Dude.
Nine slash computation problems.
So I just would just leave myself a
green room.
I've had that a number of times.
That's the worst man when you show up on
the road and like the green room becomes
like a hangout.
Hey,
this is my buddy.
He's a big fan and this is his
girlfriend.
They're going to.
Okay,
let me ask you a question.
How do you write your jokes?
Just happened so much
material.
You know,
it's funny,
I've been thinking about doing standup
for a while because a lot of people
weren't telling me I'm really funny and
uh,
you know,
I mean,
I watched you and I go,
hey,
maybe I can do it.
I get the thing I get the most is uh,
people in the meet and greet line going,
ah,
I've got to tell you my machine story.
I'm in.
There's a hundred 50 people behind you,
sir.
Oh,
I get these long ones.
I,
these ids lesbians,
we wouldn't stop playing with my Dick.
Nice.
I didn't mind that we're doing the
picture.
As long as they're lesbians,
you're barely counts.
Good girls like,
uh,
I haven't felt a dick in a while and was
doing a picture.
I used to be a.
She used to be a non lesbian.
Yeah,
she used to be a breeder.
What happened?
Why don't you go to the dark side?
Did you ask her a job?
She got me hard.
He wouldn't have stopped doing.
She definitely did.
Dirty girl,
terrible girl.
I love that.
When you find someone who's like,
who pose power,
sexuality,
like there was a girl one time.
It's like,
Hey,
can I,
uh,
like people always go,
hey,
can I go?
Can I pinch your nipple?
And the pictures,
my shirts off.
I go,
Oh yeah,
yeah,
whatever.
This one girl goes,
hey,
coupled with the nipple.
And I was like,
yeah,
she did some sex stuff to my nipple that
I literally knocked my wind out of me.
I went home and then I was like,
Hey,
can you tell me how you did it?
So I can tell that to my wife.
Like,
that was fucking amazing.
You're slammed my nipple in a bank
vault.
I don't feel shit useless.
They don't work.
Don't work.
Goddamn things.
Delegate elbow,
that's what it's like.
It's like Balsa simpler.
Very similar to an elbow.
I Dunno,
man.
Ball sack.
I couldn't like.
You could pinch my ball sack with
buyers.
I wouldn't feel it.
Yeah.
The skin's not very sensitive,
but it is.
When they go like this,
right?
When they tickle my go right up in me,
they suck up.
Oh yeah.
Really liked like a witchy.
Roommaster.
Like if someone gets what they would do,
they would suck their balls up into
their bodies so you can kick them in the
knots and it doesn't even hurt.
Really know,
Oh,
did
those fucking idiots.
But there are a bunch of guys that get
kicked in the balls and they somehow or
another can endure it.
Oh,
we did a.
We had a,
we had a bid on a TV show where there
was a strap.
You put diversity.
This now it looks like a seatbelt,
but it goes around and conquer it.
Goes knows for some spike show.
It goes around your feet and then it
rides your inseam.
So it looks like a seatbelt,
but it's.
It's an inch shorter than your inseam.
So theoretically when you kick it,
your foot,
the foot strap stops the foot before
history balls.
Okay.
So does that make sense?
Yes.
So imagine if you had really,
really strong inseams and you couldn't
get to the balls because the ncm didn't
move because you're strapped on your
feet.
So we get a punter and a professional
punter and the whole gag is.
If I get it,
I'll get kicked in the balls.
But I got this.
This is what I got the strap on a fine,
right?
Right.
So I'm like,
alright,
I got kicked in the balls so I'm
standing like this.
But as he goes to kick,
I squat down and I then loosen the
tension and then I got kicked in the
balls by a pro uponor oh my.
I went down and you could lose a ball
from that man very easily.
I know a couple.
Well guys have lost a ball.
A couple.
Yeah.
They get kicked in the nuts and sparring
and they lose a nut.
I thought I lost it.
Not once in a tournament.
My Ball swole up like a fucking golf
ball.
It was more of a golf ball,
I guess it was.
It was big and bread and it turned
purple later.
Oh,
it was awful.
Yeah.
I really thought like,
because I had in the old days the cups
that you would have where like they were
cops that would sit in jockstraps and
when you would throw a kick like a lot
of times the ball would like poke out
from underneath the cup.
So when you get kicked in the nuts,
that cup was slamming into your balls.
It's not good.
Now.
They have really good compression shorts
and the balls get received is a thing
called diamond mma cups.
They looked like they suck straight to
your body and the outside soft and they
cover all your junk and it doesn't go
anywhere.
You could literally get kicked in the
balls these things on and be okay.
Then they had these steel tie cups which
are the most ideal,
most uncomfortable,
but the most ideal because they,
they tie up through your asshole like a
g string,
like fucking crank up back there time
and I thought,
but it's a steel cup.
Really.
Everything is just fucking shoved in
there,
man.
I remember when I was a kid and they
just pulled a cup out of the out of the
bag and it by itself and go throw it in
your underwear.
Oh yeah.
They do that and you'd have to raw dog
the cup in your underwear.
Just sand all of your Dick.
But designed balls are on the outside.
Right.
And everybody knows it.
Everybody knows how bad they hurt.
Like this is not the thing that hurts
other than your eyeballs.
Things that hurts like your balls.
Everything ball hurts.
Right.
Then your ipod,
was he ever been posting the Iheart?
Horrible,
right?
Fuck yeah.
That's.
That's your balls man.
I said to someone one time,
we were about to do this,
a snowball fight for professional stobo
fight.
So they make them with snow pack them
and they're basically ice rocks and it's
called Yukigassen in Alaska and so we're
about to do it.
And I.
The night before I had said to someone,
I don't like you can hit me on the deck.
It was.
I'd rather be hitting the dick then in
the balls.
And they're like,
and there's this girl,
and she was like,
you're telling me you have no feeling in
your neck?
I go,
no,
I feel in my Dick.
But like if you punch me in the deck,
like just deck,
if you holding my dig my hand a punch,
me I wouldn't hurt as bad as if you held
my balls,
my hand punched me.
So the next day we're doing.
This year he is somewhat of a snowball
right when it starts and it hits me on
the head of the day.
Dick.
And I thought it exploded in my pants.
I thought when I and my hands were cold
so I couldn't feel.
I was like,
when I touch this dick,
it will be in pieces like a trick cigar
and it hurt.
I've never felt a pain.
And then she came up as I'm riding,
she goes,
I thought I could punch you in the Dick
and it wouldn't hurt.
And I was like,
well what about animals?
Like animals all have their balls in the
outside world.
They've never figured it out.
Like I think chimps probably figured it
out.
I bet they when they fight other chimps,
they attack the balls because I know
they do that with people.
When chimps attack people,
they rip your Dick off and then bite
your fingers off,
right,
your fingers off and rip your Dick off.
They pull your eyes out.
It's one of the things they do.
They know what to attack.
They're not trying to kill you.
They're trying to.
Maine.
You try to take away what you need and
want.
Bruce was little animals
I did a podcast with and the other day
and I go and I just,
I love the way his brain works and the
first things out of his mouth.
Have you ever seen a hairless chimp?
As I know,
and he pulls it up and I'm like,
he's like the woman was bathing with
that thing.
Bathing.
Like sleeping with him.
Yeah,
having sex with it.
Most likely.
Oh,
hi too.
She,
yeah.
She would just give the chimp xanax.
Yeah.
She gave him a xanax and red wine.
The one that tore that lady's face off
in Connecticut.
She was giving him xanax and red wine.
Yeah.
Look at the muscles on that thing.
Blocking.
Not only that,
the problem is we look at that and go,
oh yeah,
that's like a bodybuilder.
No,
no,
no.
That's a chimpanzee.
Like those muscles are like courted
steel.
They might be the same size as a
bodybuilders muscles,
but the density of those muscles is off
the fucking charts.
Look at those arms.
Oh Dude,
believe me,
I've spent years of my life staring at
naked chimps,
but that's the chimp would mange.
That's what that is there some sort of a
disease,
whereas hair falls off where you really
see their anatomy.
Yeah.
It's a stunning difference between them
and us.
I mean,
there's a lot of similarities,
but what's really,
really interesting is that that is an
intelligent animal.
I mean,
it's an intelligent animal that now uses
tools,
so much so that anthropologists are now
thinking that,
or biologists rather.
What would it be?
What would it be that studies chimps
don't know.
Definitely as anyway,
whoever the fuck studies chimps,
they have A.
I think they've universally concluded
that chimpanzees have entered the stone
age,
so they are using tools without being
taught so by other chimps.
Um,
they're using tools
independently and they're using tools
constantly and they using all kinds of
different tools and so they think that
what's going to happen is eventually
they're going to figure out a lot of
other stuff and it could take hundreds
of thousands of years,
but chimpanzees,
literally,
chimpanzees,
monkeys have entered the stone age.
I mean,
this is from the BBC.
They're using rocks and tools and
they're cutting things and breaking
things open with tools.
And C would say it's not the
worksmanship,
uh,
that makes them special.
If anything,
a casual observer might struggle to even
identify them as ancient tools.
It's not their antiquity that's
exceptional either.
They're only about the same age as the
Egyptian periods.
What makes these tools noteworthy is at
the t,
the hands that held them weren't human.
These stone tools were wielded by
chimpanzees.
Competence and macaques.
How do you say that?
Macaques.
Hightails monkeys,
but I thought that's a bird.
Anyway,
monkeys,
I'm the sites where they have been
unearthed or the basis of the brand new
field of science,
primate archaeology.
So what they're saying now is,
if you think about human beings,
right?
That one point in the history of human
beings,
uh,
we were far more primitive than we are
now,
right?
If you go back and if you're one of
those people believing the illusion,
if you go all the way back,
you know,
we were some sort of,
um,
Australia pithy,
right?
It's like some sort of a chimpanzee like
humanoid thing and that we got more and
more intelligent for whatever reasons.
And over the period of 2 million years,
the human brain size doubled and they
think that hunting may played a part of
that cooking food might've played a part
in that,
have a bunch of factors,
played a part in that,
but they think that if chimpanzees keep
going the way they're going,
now that who knows what the fuck a chimp
looks like in a million years.
I mean,
it's entirely possible that they could
grow to be a new type of
superintelligent primary.
Wow.
Yeah.
I mean,
look,
it was us,
right?
If you believe evolution,
obviously I do,
but if you believe scientists the most
studied in the field believe that human
beings in this forum,
we've existed in this forum for
somewhere in the neighborhood of half a
million years plus,
right?
I don't know if that's the right number,
but it's some.
I think it varies back and forth,
but who knows how many hundreds of
thousands of years before that we looked
exactly like these motherfuckers.
I mean,
we've been around relatively recently.
I mean if you look at the history of the
human race versus the history of the
world,
the world is like four and a half
billion years old.
The humans haven't even been around a
million years.
I don't think that's crazy.
So it's four and a half thousand
dollars,
million years old for the,
for the earth.
Humans less than a million.
So we're fucking.
We're recent.
Recent people are recent things that
have figured out how to radically change
our environment with tools.
So now these things have figured out how
to start using tools on a regular basis.
So this is what happened with us
millions of years ago or whatever it
was,
and this is what's happening with them.
And this is fairly recent.
We have now recovered buried stone tools
from activity areas of the stone tool of
all the stone tool using primates.
Ooh,
it's going to be weird,
man.
I still can't understand how they can
teach them sign language and talked to
them crazy,
but had it like crazy.
Yeah.
Um,
he,
you know,
humans have a very weird relationship
with primates to it's we,
you know,
we,
we expect them to be pets.
You know,
that's what this crazy lady in
Connecticut where a friend got her face
ripped off.
That's what they thought.
And the people,
the guy that got his balls ripped off,
his face ripped off and the chimps
towards feed off.
You remember that guy?
That guy had a pet chimp and that chimp
got too old and when they get old
they're incredibly strong and super
aggressive and that they don't
understand the consequences of biting
someone's finger off.
They just decide I'm going to bite your
finger off,
whatever.
Give me that finger.
And that's what the chimpanzee is mean.
They're wired to survive in the jungle,
you know,
it is an insanely harsh environment.
It's a little baby champion.
You look at that hand,
it's a little baby and they're wired to
survive in an incredibly harsh
environment.
And that includes like fits violence and
retribution violence.
They're fucking ruthless man.
You know,
they,
they gang up on other chimps and they
plot out war,
like they go after tribes of other
chimps and kill them and target them and
they somehow or another figure out a way
to communicate how to ambush other
chimps.
There's a lot of video on it too.
It's,
it's fucking ruthless,
man.
It's really hard shit to watch.
I,
uh,
I made a gorilla laugh one time.
I was at the,
I think it's called monkey kingdom in
Miami.
And they have this depressed gorilla
because,
uh,
this,
this circus had them before and they
took out his canines.
Oh Jesus.
Because they wanted to,
they wanted to use him.
So they removed this.
Yeah.
They didn't want anything.
People.
Yeah.
So they took the canines,
but apparently canines in the gorilla
kingdom are a sign of a.
that's how you can become a.
like if you don't have canines,
then you were just shunned.
You'll never get a partner.
And so they could never get this one
gorilla partner.
I forgot to you.
Google dental implants.
Uh,
I don't know.
They can do that.
The hockey players handle.
No know.
No they didn't.
It doesn't seem like they could do that.
Get him some nice videos.
Let's give them a fucking operation.
Human teeth and throw a little gas bomb
in his cage.
He doesn't know what the fuck's going on
them up.
So they're like A.
Yeah.
Was with the dogs.
He's really depressed.
And uh,
I think it's called monkey kingdom is.
What is the name of the place in Miami?
They go,
he's really depressed.
He's just a depressed a gorilla.
I Bet I can make them laugh and they're
like,
you definitely aren't going to make a
primate laugh.
And I swear to you,
I swear,
and this did not get included on my
show.
I swear to God.
I started doing an impression of a
gorilla.
I just started going and then slamming
my chest and then I went number one like
this,
and he went,
Huh,
shut up.
I literally lost my mind.
I was like,
I just.
And they're like,
I can't believe you made them laugh.
And I was like that.
And then travel channels I go to.
Let's see why that's pertinent to the
show.
I was like,
I just made a fucking like real
depressed one.
Yeah.
How,
what?
Oh,
oh,
how frustrating was at.
Oh,
you have no fucking idea.
I had a show.
I have a,
I have a clip.
This is the frustrating part is I,
I,
we did the last season of birth to
conquer and I did the whole thing.
I,
everything that we shot,
it was my thumbprint because we were in
between presidents and it was,
it was.
I'm very proud of that product and we
showed it to them and they're like,
it's not all brand.
And so they buried it,
but in the process,
I mean it's a,
it was too blue.
It was too rough.
It wasn't about like,
there was no intro reads,
I wouldn't do like,
my name's Bert Kreischer and I'm outside
Cedar Point,
the home of thrill rides in the middle
of Ohio,
like whatever it is.
Did you do instead?
I would be like A.
I would say stuff like I'm neat.
New Jersey is like a fat ass,
like a,
like not everyone likes it,
but if you're into it,
you get it.
Does that make sense?
And they were really fun reads and it
was so irreverent that if you saw them,
there's no,
you're not turning off the show.
You're like,
what the fuck?
Like I registered it.
Yeah.
So uh,
one of the,
I said to them at the very beginning,
I said,
hey listen,
can you just,
there's some clips we have in there.
It'll definitely go viral.
Can you just air them to promote the
series?
And they're like,
no,
we've got this,
we know what we're doing.
And so they didn't do it.
So one of the most,
one of them was this thing,
Tara dactyl.
It was a ride in Colorado.
That's fucking amazing.
If you go to their web,
if you go to travel channels,
facebook page and see how many views
it's got,
I think it'll blow you away.
By the way,
they never heard it when the show about
to air.
They aired it later on accident and it's
the most viewed thing networks ever had
ever in its history of being alive when
the editor by accident,
by when they one girl edited by
accident,
didn't know a.
we're trying to part ways with burt put
it up and it's got swing.
Yeah.
How many?
Two hundred and 40.
2 million?
Yeah.
Two hundred $42.
Million views.
Got One point 3 million shares.
Two hundred and 42 million views.
Yeah.
Well let me see that.
Oh my God.
I told them,
I said is insane.
I've never been seen something with
$242,
million views.
I said,
hey,
got some viral videos.
And they were like,
no,
we know better than you,
dude.
Eight hundred and 34,000
likes.
They know better than you fucking idiot.
Look at,
look at the fucking screen.
Picture me falling
off a cliff on a chair.
Let me see this.
Play it out a little bit
thing to your thing.
So this is all the free for 100 miles an
hour into the canyon on the terror door.
How do you free fall?
How's it work?
What do I hold onto when you're in this
chair?
It's strung out to a full pro tips.
Advice.
Let's print out what is.
I don't understand what's keeping you
alive.
It's a string.
A cable
struggle across the canyon.
Oh my God.
That is tied to a string in the middle.
You See Colorado?
Fuck Dude.
By the way,
there is one that is 10 times funnier
than this.
They took me into a spook house and it
is the spook house.
Please don't say it involves black
people.
No,
it did not blame people.
It's in.
It's in A.
I wonder if I W I tried to post it
online because he used to let me post
all the content and then once we parted,
once they realized they were ready to
part ways with me.
So it was their idea or your idea.
They asked me what I wanted to do,
the president at the time,
it took me out to lunch,
said,
so what do you want to do?
And I'd said to my therapist,
I was like,
I think I don't want to ride roller
coasters.
I'm done riding roller coasters.
I'll do something that is my idea,
like I'll do something if you want to do
something,
we could do something,
but I don't want to just be a host for
hire.
I want to have a focusing on standup,
a focus on my podcast.
I want to do stuff that means something
to me.
Like last year,
this is a last step for a full year ago,
a year ago on roughly probably today.
I'm like,
yeah,
like it was October.
It was before we had done the weight
loss challenge.
I was the fattest I'd ever been.
I'd wrapper to conquer.
It was about to start airing.
So yeah,
I think it was October.
My special hadn't narrowed my specials
there in November and she said,
what are you want to do?
And I said,
I don't want to ride roller coasters
anymore.
And she's like,
okay.
And so then the fired Bert?
Yeah,
pretty much.
Wow.
But my therapist is like,
don't go in and just ask for a job.
Say what you want and don't,
don't do anything other than that.
What did you say you wanted to do?
Like what was the idea that you wanted
to do a show that I'm,
I think I'm doing,
I'm going to be doing.
You got to do another show I'm doing,
I'm going to do a show with my buddy
tony.
The guy was telling you about this
running Roseanne.
Uh,
but it's,
I can't tell it because it's a premise
is pretty high concept.
We'll talk afterwards but we're doing
that and then I'm doing scripted,
which is what I wanted to do.
Right.
But in.
But I had already shot this product and
there was this one thing at a spook
house where it's like spooky house.
It's a haunted house.
It's in Colorado.
What?
You know,
the place I'm talking about one pulled
up here in Ohio,
but that's not from opera to conquer.
That's from birth to conquer.
How old do I look at it?
It's got to Joe Rogan shirt on if you,
I swear to God,
if you watch the full video of this,
it is the funniest thing you've ever
seen.
I gave it to them and they just clipped
it up and tried to make a.
and I was like,
don't air the fucking whole video
because it's me going 25 but not the
whole video is about 25 minutes or eight
minutes,
but it's me doing like an hour tour to
this spook house and I am losing my
shit.
Why wouldn't there?
Uh,
because what they bombed out at you at
this point?
Yeah.
You were leaving.
I think they just don't.
They don't like them wearing a
different.
You look,
they don't like to wear my shirt.
They're like,
what?
Why can't you just wear a black shirt?
Fuck off.
Fuck off travel.
Ciao.
Thank you for wearing that though.
That's awesome.
It's just me getting scared for you are
so much bigger.
I know.
Different human.
That's so crazy.
Like do you see yourself there and go,
oh my God,
I'm unhealthy.
It makes me uncomfortable.
If you go to the very end,
I'm sweating profusely,
but like this is,
I get scared and I just pushed my system
on the.
Oh well I don't even look like myself.
Yeah.
You are.
How many more pounds are you there to?
Sixty to 60 2:50.
So you're 40 plus pounds have.
Yeah.
Wow.
Just drinking like crazy.
It is amazing how you've done this,
you know,
from January to today you've essentially
changed who you are,
who are,
you know,
you have.
I didn't think.
I think I probably wouldn't have done it
without all of us being a part.
Like it's been fun.
Yeah.
You know?
I felt it
guilty that you guys went through all
that shit and I didn't do anything.
That's one of the reasons why I was
willing to pay for like that's where
things get fucked up.
Like my intention to pay for your trip
to the basketball game was a good
intention,
but it,
it put our in a weird place because I
kind of stepped in for him.
Then when,
oh Joe,
for our or as a wheelchair.
Maybe if I didn't do that,
you guys would have sorted it out
quicker.
Didn't,
didn't mean to do that.
You know when you said that,
you're like,
no,
don't worry our.
He's done it.
He's,
we've been friends a long time.
I got this.
I had it on my pocket.
So when you said it,
it was very like you didn't sound like
you were.
I didn't feel like you're throwing you
under the bus at all.
I didn't feel like it,
but I think he felt like a little bit.
But I also think there's blood in the
water and when there's blood in the
water,
those fucking online paranas they just
find a week.
Yes.
Spot.
And if you show that weakness.
Oh,
milk for a cat.
That's why you were telling them about
the comments.
Don't,
don't fucking respond to those comments.
You know,
don't,
don't do that.
He did.
He look love him to death,
but he posted something Shitty,
really shitty.
One time he knows it and anyone that
knows it knows it and if they don't know
it,
they'll never know it.
I don't give a fuck,
but I watched the comments roll in after
that and he didn't realize what he had
posted and I washed it and it was
realized he didn't realize it's a long
story and I'm going to get into,
okay,
so I love already and I don't want to
end up to deal with it.
But like he didn't realize what he had
posted.
He thought he was posting something fun
and he.
It was super serious.
And then dude,
I watched these people rolling with
comments,
man,
Tom and I've said a number of times did
write down names.
Don't ever forget the guys that are
really horrible human beings on here,
like don't ever forget there are some
fucking lunatics online like legit
fucking lunatics.
Oh,
of course.
Like when,
when,
when you said you weren't going to smoke
weed and we put the prey for Joe thing
to this guy wrote to me,
he goes,
don't ever forget you are nothing
without Joe Rogan.
That is our medicine.
We need this medicine and if you're
going to deprive us of our medicine.
I was like,
who the fuck do you think you're like,
I was rob us of our medicine people just
because a lot of broken people out
there,
man,
and whoever you are,
if you're.
That guy looked mad.
I didn't take my medicine for 12 days.
I'm good.
Just relax.
I mean,
but some people.
Here's the thing,
right?
I used to do a joke about this,
that I did have a medical marijuana card
before it was illegal.
It was illegal only medically,
but if you didn't get a medical
marijuana card,
if you went to a doctor and they said,
no,
you should go to a fucking hospital
because it's probably something really
wrong with you because they were giving
them away like candy,
like anybody can get a medical marijuana
card,
and someone was said to me like,
well you are throwing it in the face of
the people that actually need marijuana
for like glaucoma or ptsd or whatever.
Like what you're doing is skirting the
system.
I might.
Yeah.
So what?
I'm still getting weed legally.
I'm not hurting anybody by getting weed
legally stupid.
Just like promoting the fact that weeds
awesome,
and then also there's the thing with
like it's fun for just calming you down
and giving you a perspective in life.
I think weed has made me and I think
there's probably a lot of other factors
as well.
I don't want to say it's all weed.
The weed is made me a nicer person
because it's made me more sensitive and
I think that if there's one thing that
we could all use more in this,
like everybody gets carried away and
everybody's a work in progress and
people all say things that they probably
shouldn't have or just,
you know,
you're acting impulsively or you know,
just you'd go with the thought that's in
your head and you say what's on your
mind.
It doesn't come out right.
Yeah.
We've all done that.
Right?
But marijuana for me highlights all
those things and know almost ruthlessly
introspective way that makes me a nicer
person.
It makes me think about things,
especially when I'm in the tank,
man,
when I get in the tank,
when I smoke weed,
I just think about every thing.
It's like a God damn.
I should do that.
I should do that time.
New Studio.
I should do that.
Tank new studio has a tank.
I got to do the tag before I quit before
October is up.
Okay.
I want to try it for them.
I want to try it sober and then went in
November.
I want to try it.
Hi.
One time.
Well,
it'll be installed in the third week of
October.
Really?
Yeah.
The tanks coming soon.
So as soon as this one from your home.
No,
no,
no.
It's a new one.
They took the one out of my house.
Crashed.
By the way folks,
if you're in California,
you the float lab is the greatest float
place in the world and this guy is like
a lot of people credit me for.
I'm making a isolation tanks more
popular.
I'm very happy that that's the case,
but my tank increased dramatically when
I hooked up with crash because I had a
friend who was working on my tank and he
was fixing it and I had an older tank.
It wasn't the best tank,
but it was good and I had great
experiences in it,
but he told me about this guy in Venice
that ran this place called the float lab
and I said,
well,
what's the difference?
He's like,
his stuff is just like super engineered.
It's like the best stuff,
like you don't have any of the issues
with like the bladders at the bottom
that hold the hold,
the water in breaking because he doesn't
use waterbed bladders instead.
He uses those things to use for ponds
like Koi ponds,
like a very thick,
thick plastic.
Everything.
He has air pumped in it so you get fresh
oxygen inside the tank.
He just like that he uses to waterbed
heaters and they work together
simultaneously.
His like,
he has a really excellent digital
calibration system for the temperature,
like he takes it to the next level with
everything.
He's got an ozone filtration system that
kills all the bacteria.
It kills everything.
He uses two gigantic Jacuzzi filters
that everything gets run through these
like tiny micron.
I forget what the number is.
Filters where like they filter
everything out of that water and for me
it's like it's only me in the water,
but for public one it's critically
important that you know,
you know,
that you're not gonna catch some weird
skin disease or something when you get
inside these tanks.
So this guy,
um,
I got in touch with him,
uh,
got a tank from him.
He installed them in my basement and
then,
you know,
I'm just,
I can't shut the fuck up about things I
love and that's part of my problem was
I'm repetitive as fuck,
but it's what makes me good at things.
I get obsessive and that mindset,
I'm just like constantly droning on
about the same things constantly and
sometimes that becomes a problem with
podcasts,
but crash that guy,
he's,
he's the motherfucker behind tanks.
If it wasn't for him,
the tanks that we have,
even not the non crash tanks,
non float lab tanks,
all the other tanks in the world they
are.
That is the gold standard.
His tanks are the gold standard in all
the other tanks since then have.
They've elevated in quality
substantially because of his
contribution.
When I first started using the tank,
which was like early two thousands,
like 2000,
I think I got one in 2003 and I think
our first time,
first time I got in one was like 2000
2001 and I had one in my basement in
2003.
From that time the fucking whole
business has gone like this.
Now they're everywhere.
Giant tanks.
There's one in Omaha.
I was in Omaha and this guy was at my
show.
He goes,
man,
I work at a float lab where I worked at
a tank place.
He's like,
we should go with.
I was like,
let's go now.
He was like,
let me call the owner and this is,
I got to say this to this owner and Oma.
Tony's like,
ah,
we can't go drunk.
And was like,
why?
He's like,
I think he thinks you're going to pee in
it,
but yeah,
I want to do it.
Well you will,
you'll do it.
I'll have you,
uh,
in like right after it's installed.
But uh,
so we're getting a new one put in
because that's the thing about crash.
He's crazy.
He's constantly like innovating.
He's like constantly,
like even if it tanks perfect,
he's like,
no,
no.
That's the old one,
the old version.
We got to get rid of that.
We got to take it out.
We got an upgrade,
upgrade everything.
Like he's.
He's just nuts with that shit.
Wow.
Yeah.
He's a mastermind.
He's like a real mad scientist genius
character when it comes to tanks.
Oh,
that's.
I think I,
I could fucking.
Yeah.
I got to get a tank.
You love it.
I tried to get into tm.
TM,
transcendental meditation,
transcendental meditation.
I missed the fucking class.
Well,
the thing about tanks is you could do
all the meditation and tanks,
but you have way more,
um,
disconnection from your body.
And I think that's important.
It disconnects your mind and your
thoughts and your ideas from your
physical frame.
Like that's what people are trying to do
when they meditate.
Like you're trying to sit down in a
comfortable spot and just concentrate on
your thoughts and you absolutely can
achieve these amazing states of mind in
that way.
But I feel like those states are
elevated substantially from the tank and
everyone I know that disagrees is never
done.
The tank.
People that have done the tank.
Oh yeah.
People that know that meditate and do
the tank as well go,
oh my God,
this is a game changer.
It's,
it's just a completely different
environment.
And the people,
the people that resist that have talked
to a few people that meditate and
they're like,
do you meditate?
I'm like,
yes,
I do.
I meditate in my tank.
And they're like,
wow,
that's not the same thing.
Like,
listen,
you fucking hippie know what you're
talking about.
I've meditated regular to.
I just try it.
Have you tried it?
No,
I have it.
They shut the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up.
Because it's a.
it's a complete naturally occurring
psychedelic state.
So anybody who's sober,
anybody doesn't want to fuck with drugs.
I always tell them,
get in that God damn tank and you'll
have a drug experience without any drugs
or you don't have to worry about losing
your mind.
You have to worry about addiction.
You have to worry about overdosing or
getting something to give you the wrong
shit.
You can get in that tank and
legitimately have a psychedelic
experience.
Uh,
yeah.
I got to try it.
Do well.
The big thing,
this is gonna sound.
Once again,
this is going to sound.
A lot of my realizations this month are
going to sound very,
very childish and pedestrian.
But like one of my really hard things
was going to sleep like I didn't.
We call them unassisted,
sleeps in our house so we can go to
sleep without drugs or alcohol.
And I had seven this year total.
I pulled down fucking 13 in a row.
And so now the idea of sleep doesn't
panic me the way it used to.
Like last night I did a podcast,
these,
uh,
young ladies and then I just,
I just like,
it was like,
I'm going to bed now and I got in bed
and I just closed my eyes.
That's crazy dude.
You're healthy.
Like I was like,
I was like,
I'm going to bed now.
I'm proud of you.
I really am.
This is what you've done is considering
your lifestyle.
And how long you've been doing it that
way.
It's amazing.
And I know that you,
you rise to the challenge of a
competition that sort of motivated you
to do that.
Not a lot of people would have done it,
man.
A lot of people would have quit by now.
A lot of people would have found some
excuses or figured out some way like,
ah,
it was my friend's
birthday.
I had to do a shot with them.
You know,
like,
this is all sorts of weird tricks that
your mind will play on you to get you to
quit,
you know,
in,
in a bunch of different ways.
But I'm proud of you.
You've literally changed your health.
You turn your health around in a very
short period of time.
I appreciate it.
Thank you joe.
I got.
I got a lot of those people because a
lot of people were doing it with us.
Yeah,
no,
we'll noonan is quit smoking,
which is a big fucking deal.
Hard one.
Apparently really big.
He quit smoking,
but it's fun to hear the guys who do did
fall off.
God,
I was with the until football on
Saturday.
I'm sorry brother.
And you're like,
you're like,
yeah,
I know.
I know the feeling.
I know what it is too,
but you just have to make a rule,
you know,
and just try again.
You know,
it doesn't have to be sober October.
You can do it in November,
but there's a beautiful thing in having
like a set schedule tomorrow begin.
So bratty.
I have to do it.
I'm going to do it for 30 days and if
you can do it,
the people prayed for me and now I'm off
of marijuana going right back though.
Can't wait.
I kind of wish.
I think all of us kind of wish we were
all together for that first night.
I know I'm kind of bummed out that you
guys are going to be New Orleans,
but we'll,
we'll,
we'll come back for another podcast,
will get Super Jew to get on a plane and
come over here and we'll have some fun
together and by then he'll have already
started smoking pot again,
so we'll probably be more happy,
Ari.
Oh yeah.
We'll be at the new studio too,
but yeah,
we'll do that.
Well,
all three of us get together and have.
We should do.
I don't know if he's willing to do yoga
after this challenge.
I think this challenge,
but for um,
you know,
do you think you will.
I love that he calls it a chore to set
my alarm because I had a george today.
Did you listen to his podcast when he's
talking about it?
I did.
I'm a goddamn professional comedian.
I'm a Jewish entertainer in New York
City.
He liked to drink and do drugs because
this mock anger is so awesome.
If I was howling laughing,
driving the girl's house,
I got there.
I go,
have you been living in North podcast?
He's like,
we don't realize the latest one was 35
minutes ago.
It's 35 minutes of gold for me.
You know,
sort of everyone's list.
You should listen.
I think it's meant for us.
Well,
I'm glad he decided to go with it.
It's awesome stuff.
He was the one that said no weed.
He was the one he,
he texted me personally.
Goes personally,
I don't think you have a problem,
I love you and if you're going to do no
booze,
I'm going to take away the thing I care
about and that's weed and then he and
then he texted that to me,
him and Tom,
and then I made that video of me running
thing and in it and I was like no weed,
and I said to Tom and Tom was like,
I don't know if joe knows about no weed
yet.
And then you were like,
hey guys,
I'm not doing no weed.
And then always like,
oh,
I bullied him into a corner and see if I
can get them to do it.
That's hilarious.
It wasn't affecting me at all.
The bullying.
I thought it was hilarious.
I thought it was too,
but I was willing to do it because I was
like,
all right,
well two things.
I thought one,
the optics,
it doesn't look good if I'm telling you
guys to quit the booze and then when it
comes to the weed,
I'm like,
no,
that wasn't a part of the deal,
but I'm like,
I want people to
know that it's not hard to quit weed.
It's really easy and yeah,
I know I'm only quoting it for a month,
but I'm telling you it's fucking easy.
Like it has literally changed nothing
about my life.
Like I've,
I can do all the same things.
I think marijuana,
like anything can be abused,
but I also think it's a valuable tool
and I think as long as you use it as a
tool and I think one of the things about
this experience,
I think I'm going to use it more
judiciously.
I'm going to,
uh,
I'm gonna use it less.
I think
I'm going to be that way with alcohol.
I want to enjoy it.
I want to,
I want it to be part of the party as
opposed to it'd be the thing.
Yeah.
Like I wanted to like accept like,
like a,
like a very accurate statement is going
out to the patio and the store.
Sometimes you do see something that I
was just part of my night was like,
do my set,
go to the patio and the store as opposed
to like Burger.
I always think Berger uses booze
properly.
He's like a get done a set and he's
like,
you want to go have a whiskey?
You go back to that backbone,
you have a whiskey with them and you're
talking about something for 30 minutes.
Not overkill.
It's like,
all right,
I just made the drive home.
Interesting.
I'm going,
yeah.
He's a disciplined guy.
You know,
he's a,
he's an interesting guy in that regard.
He works really hard.
He's very disciplined,
but he's also very smart and
understanding the trappings,
you know,
where things can go wrong.
You know,
he's a wise man is.
There's a lot of them out there,
man.
You know,
you just got to find him and cultivated
and we're very lucky.
Very fucking lucky.
I will say,
me personally,
I'm very lucky to have the group of
friends I have because I go,
I look back,
I remember you telling me a long time
ago over a shot of whiskey.
You don't have to have a shitty friends.
A lot of people like you just just let
them be your friend,
but you had a few people in your life
that were monsters.
I was not good at figuring that.
I remember you were like here a really
good that we at the ice house,
you were really good guy and everyone's
trying to be your friend.
Just let it happen.
So protected.
Well you had that one monster in your
life and you know,
once you got rid of him,
your everything
kind of went smoother and you also
realize like,
oh,
like other comedians actually want you
to succeed.
They're not trying to hold you down.
They're not trying to shit on you and
like literally remove parts of you
there.
They want you to be happy.
They want to enhance the.
And then also you realize that there's
beauty in that community of like seeing
people succeed and being happy for them
and they're happy for you and you're
happy for each other and everybody can
get together and laugh.
Yeah.
I mean God has called me the other night
and the fights on and he goes,
dog fuck spots.
I was watching a fight.
I want to see mighty mighty mouse.
I saw that.
The video of you guys all together and
Joey high as fuck.
You know,
you've got to contact how you probably
broke the rules by hanging out with
Joey.
I definitely thought about that.
He's like to join us at a time.
Have you seen that video of him?
Joey Diaz,
like talking about like his State of the
Union address.
His is talking
about making North Korea glow in the
dark.
Find it.
I think it's on.
It's on fucking Americans.
He's wearing a green shirt and I was
crying literally.
Tears are rolling down my face when I
was watching.
I think it's on the mat flavors.
World instagram account.
I know you can find it.
Show me.
Show me what you got.
Says October,
let me see what it looks like.
Uh,
um,
yeah,
that's it.
He takes the glasses off.
See if you just play this will.
We'll go out with this.
Bear Chrysler.
I'm proud of you man.
I really am.
We're going to leave.
We're going to leave you guys with the
great and powerful Joey Diaz.
Tough stuff because it's all over.
We had a rough couple of months.
Katrina's cousin Maria,
the other one for the Rico Houston.
Fucking slow and listen,
it's been tough up to now.
The earthquake in Mexico,
you know the White House level?
The fuck is going on,
but it don't matter.
They want to shoot.
It's time to fuck this.
Shoot.
Ducks stuck.
They want to get down and dirty.
Don't forget who the fuck we are.
You understand me with the baddest
motherfuckers out there,
you send the message to that fucking
North Korea.
He's going to be sniffing my deck and
stuck in my ass.
Harder focus.
Korean Americans got put the gun control
that sell them was done for them in the
last three days.
Put the fucking whining.
Stop with the.
I don't give a fuck.
Where were your back?
Keep your eyes open and get the fuck on
snap.
Chatham fucking twitter.
Stay black.
Oh,
he is so fuck.
He's the best ever,
man.
That's the funniest guy ever lived.