The joe rogan experience.
Oh,
that was another thing
they found recently.
Man,
I wanted to talk about this.
They found evidence that a mass amount
of people were killed in London in the 15
hundreds by a volcano.
This is 1258 there was a
colossal volcano in 1258 wow.
This is amazing,
man.
So this is a new discovery
that such a massive global,
national,
natural disaster has been identified
in a small area of east London.
That's incredible,
man.
That is amazing shit.
Yeah,
we don't know too much.
You know when they,
when they really talk about history,
like what we really know about the past,
man,
we don't really know that much.
We don't know.
We just make a fucking assumptions
and every other week we come up
with a new fucking assumption.
It's amazing how much we're fine,
but that fucking tape a
Mars either that looks,
can't keep them.
Me Too.
I don't give a fuck.
You got to go to bars now,
now $14 billion when all this shit we
got going on is fucking country bars for
what?
Who gives a fuck?
My boss.
I'm sitting there going,
this a [inaudible] gazing.
It's fucking table.
They made this in Burbank.
Well this is what I think.
I think first of all,
yeah,
they did go and it's awesome.
And when you,
you spend money on scientific
innovation for space travel,
you're dealing with the cream of the
crop of people that are trying to figure
out how to manipulate space and matter
and transport things and how to,
you know,
you're dealing with the most,
the the most knowledgeable
scientists on earth.
$2 strived and Joey,
come on.
I mean I'm serious and silly.
Every,
let me tell you this.
Everything that they do when they
got to go with the fucking price,
I ex what it has to do fucking age.
We've got diseases,
we got fat kids running around and
March.
Definitely we should pay attention to
that are saying we should go and explore
the universe.
Oh Bernie,
a little by little will
fucking die in here dog.
This country is fucking dying.
We got time.
I don't give a fuck what goes on in Mars.
I don't give a fuck what goes
on ugly and loved it either.
In 1529 I'm from the Church of
what's happening now I'm buck.
If you care about that shit,
you got too much fucking
time on your hands.
What's that got to do?
We've got kids.
We got houses.
Shut the fuck down.
You got billions of
dollars to go to model.
Give a fuck about eyes.
Why don't you get this
excited about the wars?
Because that costs a thousand times.
Don't get excited about and all that
shit because it doesn't have to.
What the fuck?
Not that they'd been fighting for 10
years and I'm still paying $5 for fucking
gas guy that I didn't do.
The money we're spending
on the war is a billion,
billion,
billions and billions of dollars.
Every fucking year I'm going to Mars,
Afghanistan,
Mars,
things,
a positive thing.
The Mars thing,
they're going to get
innovation out of this project.
I need them in,
in everything else.
It's going to eventually lead to
who knows what kind of space travel.
Eventually we're going to have
to do with us.
That's what the problem say is we can't
buy shit that got not in the pocket door
that this is why I care about it,
because it's cool as fuck.
When that thing lands on Mars and starts
taking pictures and sending it through
the sky and I see a room full of people
who've worked on nothing but this for
years jumping up and down here,
it's fucking awesome and I pick
up an envelope at the thing.
All right,
you're going to jump up and down to
somebody landed and mark kick a bunch of
fucking gigs that they were white with
blue shirts on and shit jumping up and
that's there.
That's what NASA is.
Matthew understanding put together,
and I appreciate travel.
You know,
10 years ago we hung out for years and
you would talk about the moon landing was
fake.
Now all of a sudden you're
happy about bucking wise guy.
Come on,
give me a fucking break.
What are they all connected system
that goes out of her day?
It's waste of thought.
We've got bigger things to fry.
Gas is $5 a tech.
We got this note,
Rob,
some guy who's a fucking
commy cocks up a wall.
Fuck from Idaho,
Utah.
What the fuck is from against Obama?
Go into,
that's going on.
Good days.
His wife,
cause she's making fat.
Kids get fucking skinny.
That's it.
I mean what the fuck?
What the fuck?
We don't even have a president.
We know we don't have somebody to both
for the next four years and we're worried
about fucking Mars.
Joe Rogan rarely about fuck what happened
in England and 1529 we need to fucking
know what's going to happen
at the next three years.
You know what dog?
You're right.
I'm about to have a baby and I'm fucking
scared because what is he going to have
in 40 years?
What we're going to have,
we're going to be getting
fucked in the ass by Arabs,
but a bunch of white people.
We went to go see if the
Arabs are jumping up and down,
dare fucking gone.
Wait Til we get those wipe.
If they get excited like
that about landing in Mars,
wait til they sniffed
this Arab asshole has,
they're sucking my dick.
Cause my learning has,
does my daughter to have to learn Spanish
or does she have to learn fucking Arab
in the next 20 fucking years?
That's what I'm worried about,
dog.
There's my kid have to go to school
with 80 fucking foreigners or does she?
That's what I worry about.
So fuck march bro.
I want to hear about fucking Mars and
a bunch of fucking waspy fucked with
Glasser's jumping up and
down cause we landed on Mars.
There's a fucking mortgage
is upside down his country.
Fucking pile of the students.
Are you going to stop doing stand up?
No,
I'm not going to stop doing.
So why would they stop
pulling with rover on Mars?
But what's mine's got Joey's.
That's what they do.
That's what they know.
Level arts eggs,
they're already in
their art is creating something that can
fly through fucking space for a year.
That's great land on your fucking time.
And I think they pay me.
These mother fuckers are using
my money to go to fucking Mars.
They take half of your bucket check for
taking half of my bucket check to go to
Mars.
Motherfucker.
You get angry when you,
they take that money and they go to war.
I don't even think about it,
but war is something that more
than we need war more fun.
What?
How much money do we make
by going tomorrow when we
were to put a burger king on
why we think we need more,
what are we going to put on?
How are we going to pick up an envelope
is they're in a fucking Juliet's happy
right now,
but what's going on in God
cast is sponsored by ear
doctors all across America
and the conspiracy copters and hired
Julie to make people blow their ear drums
out.
That pissed
so many things going on in this regard.
Schools at closing,
fucking people see moral cities,
a clone,
human Bester and we gotta go to
fucking what bars to give a fuck.
Listen,
Joey,
I said I support your
hubris on us and listen bro,
I don't mind.
We've got to send pre Puerto Ricans.
I would establish a ride.
That's what needs to be done.
I'm going to blow up a fucking building
or three black guys establish a wrap.
That's what it needs to be done.
Wore his money to fucking bottom line.
The square root of war guy is Didas
and we've all known that Adidas,
that's the square root of money.
I don't see any DDAS and us going to
Mars except taking a bunch of rich people
and charge them to take them to,
there's a quilt.
Let me explain to you.
Got To every fucking drone is flying
in Pakistan and taken out al Qaeda.
If you believe in that shit bills every,
I agreed by scientists and that's
beautiful and I'm with you.
If you want to argue
about keeping people safe,
the best way to keep people safe.
Look,
I'm not a,
I'm not saying that I advocate drones
because fuck load of civilians have died
from the use of drone attack,
but they eventually get that shit
wired to the point where they can kill
everybody they want to kill.
That's where it's the scientists that
are involved in making that shit at the
same scientists that are
involved in making all sorts of,
I love in spacecraft
Aircrafts and loving that.
Then making the technology.
Man,
you want to kill somebody?
You make up.
I want to see the bullet
that don't need a gun for it.
I just got to go like
business and a hitching.
Your head blows up.
I appreciate the scientist,
but not right now.
Billions of dollars to go to Mars.
We're only that Joey.
That is a fraction of
what our military budget.
It's a title attached
fighting for our freedom.
What does Mars has to do with us?
It's a Martian going
to come back to Vegas,
so that's a crazy thing to say.
You are sending them it die.
One though.
The military is fighting for our freedom.
Is that why we're in countries that have
absolutely nothing to do with and he's,
that's why and we invaded down.
It's,
come on man.
That's crazy side.
So that's fucking flag brother.
We're good.
We're bad.
We got to kill some much.
You got to break a fucking few omelets
stuff to fucking make an album.
You got to break some
eggs to make a few amens.
Whatever they're doing,
it's a lot better than fucking,
they're selling drugs.
The CIU sells coke at
least that make them money,
Mars and got another,
here's the big thing,
Joe.
And every time,
every time they send something to like
Mars or the urge do these missions,
they are also doing hundreds of
experiments and these experiments are
experiments that we can't do,
you know,
down on earth where in a lot of these
experiments lead to other things that do
help us out,
like cures for cancer
and fucking time travel.
Well,
let's get the cool listen,
judge,
to be a dollar fit's going to be,
it's going to come a point in time if we
follow the path that we're on now where
we might not be living on
this fucking planet anymore,
we're human beings might
pollute this motherfucker.
The point where we're going to want to
escape and what they're going to do,
is it going to send shit to Mars,
to terraform just like they did in the
movie aliens and they're going to put a
fucking fake atmosphere on Mars and that's
going to bear a little escape colony.
Yeah.
Can I ask you the question?
Well,
what's he got to do with us?
I'm going to be dead.
I don't care.
He'll be fine.
I don't even know what else to do it.
I'm alive right now.
And when something lands on Mars,
I get geeked out.
Yeah.
I want to just see that shit.
I get names out.
Looking at the photos.
I'm like that,
that land.
Has it ever been seen before?
Is it like,
is there have been people that
have walked on looks like fuck it,
Arizona as well?
You know,
it does look like Arizona,
but there is,
there's a real theory that's a fascinating
theory that Mars used to inhabit life
and then it used to had an atmosphere,
but it was hit by an asteroid.
And uh,
that's one of the reasons why they want
to keep sending things there and get to
task.
Because if it was above a planet
that supported life like ours,
but then it was hit by an asteroid,
we realized that we've,
we've had mass extinctions on this planet,
at least two of them that
were caused by asteroids,
you know,
hundreds of millions of years ago
and then 65 million years ago.
And they know that there's been
some just doozies that have landed,
but it's possible that one could
land that just kills the whole thing.
That's a wrap.
Let me ask you something,
Bro.
What's that dot.
To do are,
okay.
Can you sell an asteroid?
Could you bring an asteroid to a check
cashing senate dogs and you want me to
get my fucking money fucking as to
what was going to vote for this year.
I mean,
I don't want,
could you fill in a right in Doug?
Stan hope.
Yeah,
that's what I was thinking it.
Doug Stanhope.
Yeah,
I can do any of you see what's going on
in this country and we could get a lot
of people to down on this country.
Joe Rogan,
intelligent guy.
I'm a fucking Momo and I know
that those both of them a bumps.
You're an intelligent guy.
You just looking at my face and told
me you are not confident about anybody
who's running for president.
This country.
You and another fucking
million people feel that way.
Sorry about that chocolate bar.
Fucking me up.
You know?
It's all right man.
I know what you're doing.
Just having fun.
No,
no,
no.
Fuck No.