The joe rogan experience.
How does Larry David handle it?
He's not bad.
Yeah.
I'm a big fan of,
oh,
thank you.
You know?
But yeah,
I've seen them go through,
because it was,
I saw him become famous,
you know,
he was on Fridays.
He created Seinfeld,
but that still wasn't the fame that he
has now.
So I saw him through curb your
enthusiasm become truly iconic.
So he's had trouble figuring out how to,
people want to take a picture of people,
you know?
Well,
how do I do it?
And it's always changing.
He's never an asshole.
It's truly one of the greatest comedy
shows of all time.
Well,
thank you.
Oh,
100% and I have to say the new season
we're about to film in October,
the storyline may be my favorite,
and it's really subtle and fun.
It's like one of those things like,
oh,
I,
it's like,
I think people watching it will feel
that they're living a fantasy and after
the first one airs,
I'm happy to come back and talk about
it.
You know what I mean?
Because that premise of where we're
going is delightful.
I love how hbo gives him sort of carte
blanche.
They're like,
you know,
take a couple of years off,
do whatever the fuck you want.
Like,
you know,
take some pretty great,
well for Larry,
it's not about the money.
Of course,
it's about can I do another good show?
And that makes us different than most
shows in history.
Yeah.
And uh,
he,
um,
he only wants to do good work and enjoy
himself.
Otherwise there's no reason.
And uh,
an HBO is smart that way.
They're genius.
I mean,
look,
you think about the show soprano's
fucking game of thrones and now they
know how to let a show.
I'll be a show.
They,
from what I understand,
they give a lot of notes on their
pilots,
but once you become a series,
they kind of leave you alone.
That's amazing.
You know?
Whereas when you're doing a network show
or from other pay sources,
I've heard that the notes never stopped.
Well,
when I was on the radio is the easiest
thing to ruin with notes.
Drama can survive notes.
Comedy cannot because it's like the,
uh,
you know,
doing comedies.
Like,
you know,
the,
the dominoes and if you take one of
those and just move it a little to the
left to the right,
you're screwing up the whole thing.
Dude,
Tom Cruise is fucking legit.
John Travolta has done some silly
nonsense,
but he's also,
he's also done pulp fucking fashion.
He did carry when he was like really
good after the Saturday night live face
off dude.
He's a very fit and active,
a terrible movie face off.
Oh Wow.
That's a great one.
When they cut the face off and put it
on,
the other person dies.
Naked impose structure magically
changes.
And Nick Cage looks like John Travolta,
Tom [inaudible] technologies.
But you're not terrorist.
It was no way Bro.
Okay.
What did it happen if Brian put on you?
I would think
you were,
there's a monster here.
First of all,
you head's way bigger.
So your skin a bit like some 60 year old
lady from Bel Air,
60 year old ladies where their mouth
looks like it's so big a key your head,
cause they've been pulling,
they're pulling the skin back to their
mouth was like the joker.
They lose that in their face as you get
older.
You remember you used to make fun of me
for taking an acting class and I stayed
in.
That didn't last for eight years longer
than I needed to because I love a train
wreck.
And these two guys did a seed.
Jeffrey tambor was teaching and these
two guys did a scene from faceoff and
the curtain comes up and,
and one guy is hanging from a chain and
the other guy's torturing him and it's
like,
and then he goes,
he goes,
yeah,
and it's all,
and he's hitting him and it's crazy.
And at the end of the scenes like scene,
everybody's like,
and Jeffrey Tambor,
it just takes a sip of his coffee and he
goes,
what was that scene?
And the guy goes,
face off,
face off.
What is the,
it's a movie.
It's an action movie.
John Travolta in an occasion.
Tell me about
that scene as band forever.
That was it.
Okay.
Cook a man
is desperate for acceptance,
approval,
and affection from women.
Oh no,
it's different.
This desperation has led to the
compromise of his beliefs and values.
The desecration of his dignity and self
worth and its inability to stand up for
himself.
There's four Chan,
right?
This
and what he deserves it.
Human being example,
loyalty,
fidelity and honesty in a romantic
relationship.
Okay.
Look at it.
Look at the example.
The game.
Hold on a second.
I know John's always wanted a
girlfriend,
but since him and Mary started dating,
he's become a cock.
She spends all of his money and flirts
openly without openly with other men.
I can tell it bothers him,
but he's so afraid of losing her that he
doesn't say
anything that's a cook.
It sounds like a male feminist also.
Can't believe you went there?
I don't.
Um,
yeah.
The male feminist thing,
I've,
I've known a few that were real creeps
that were fake creeps.
You know,
they're like on the side.
They,
the,
they,
what they're doing was there,
there
posturing as an alternative to these men
who don't want monogamous relationships
or would break the woman's heart or not
willing to compromise and bend to the
will of the woman and that they put
these women on a platform and worship
these women.
And I am the alternative and I'm the
powerful alternative,
and these men are assholes,
and then they try to shit on those men
and take those.
But all it does is make those appear
even more attractive to these women.
Secretly,
these men,
these feminists men,
and these women have these weird
relationships where it doesn't work and
they're never sexual,
or if they are a sexual,
the women aren't really sexually
attracted to him,
so they withhold sex and it just,
it gets super weird.
Obviously,
I just generalize a lot about giant
group of people's relationships,
but what I've seen,
it's just,
it's,
they don't run fast.
They can't pick things up.
They're not attractive.
So they tried it.
A little weasels to trying to find
another way in.
Yeah.
I mean,
I think men who,
not all men who call themselves
feminists are male feminists.
So in that,
I think men who ascribed to women being
equal at,
that's a good thing.
Yeah.
I think a lot of guys will say,
yeah,
I'm feminist because they think that's
the right thing to do.
That's the socially acceptable thing and
right.
That's the way we should be.
But then the ones who run around and
say,
you know,
really,
really push it and make that their
identity and really sell themselves as
male feminists.
Those are the guys I have an issue with
because like you said,
they're sneaky.
Yeah.
They and they know what they're doing.
They're not being honest.
Okay,
well you could almost always tell you
you see them.
Yeah.
They're,
they're a type,
you know,
they're just,
they're an unattractive type.
They're not attractive to women.
And they'd try to figure out a way like,
how am I going to do this?
What's it going to be the way you've got
to figure out a way to stand out.
This is the way I'm going to just what,
what are these women want to hear?
They want to hear that.
I'm going to say that.
Yeah.
Egalitarians great.
You know,
someone who believes in equality is
great,
but as soon as you istat like your
proclaiming yourself to be more
interested in the opposite gender and
more supportive of them,
then males,
and even though you are a male,
hmm.
That should be a red flag.
That's a giant red flag.
You should be into humans.
I like people.
I like people I like,
I'm gay,
I'm straight.
I like people.
I like when they're nice.
You're nice to me.
I'm nice to you.
That's what I like.
I don't want you to get discriminated
against in any way,
shape or form.
Yeah.
But I don't want to pretend that one
group is better than other groups
groups.
They,
if he'd had no makeup on,
no money in King Lewin who Sacha Baron
Cohen is.
Do you know what I mean?
The crazy thing is these people must
have had to sign releases.
Yeah.
And I did hidden camera shit,
so I know how that works.
Yeah,
I've done that too.
How did they get those two ways?
There's money,
which is always the best way.
And you make them sign before.
That's,
that's it.
There's,
there's two ways to get the,
the way.
Yeah.
You'd make them sign,
you know,
we're going to be featuring you on the,
say we did this bit,
Ian Edwards and I did this bit for
comedy central for the show that never
went.
Um,
I don't know if I've ever told you this,
but we,
this bit was so fun to do.
We made a thing called Melanin Mayo
Mayonnaise,
mayonnaise that she,
that made you darker
real shit.
And we put food coloring in mail.
But we,
it as new Brown Mayo,
it's a new generation of Mayo.
And so we got people in this test group.
We know that real people in a real test
group that go and take tests all the
time and they emanate sample shit.
We put them in a room,
we made them eat the sandwiches,
just fucking mail was male.
They eat the sandwiches.
All these white people eat the
sandwiches.
And then when they're done,
we sent in this black dude owl and she
shows them a video.
And it was a pre taped video basically
of white people confessionals who have
turned.
We've,
you know,
we photoshop them to have turned more
brown to turn start to turn black.
And we're like in three to five weeks,
you start to see results.
You start to see cultural results,
mental results you're getting,
you're getting more black by culture,
you're getting smarter.
Black,
you're getting cooler black and your
neighborhood to your friends.
Like their faces.
Their faces were perf.
If we didn't have any volume you to
laughed.
Everyone's like,
wait a minute.
No one said we be black.
We'd be turning black.
I mean,
they lost their fucking minds.
People got so scared.
It was amazing.
Uh,
that bit was incredible.
They,
MTV never,
I mean,
comedy central,
never air to any of that come in central
probably hasn't a fucking vault they
throw away.
Oh my God.
That was one of our favorite bits that
we,
that made us laugh so fucking hard.
Their faces.
There was one woman though,
one woman,
to her credit,
she goes,
she,
you know,
people are freaking out in the room.
People started yelling at him and
they're like,
this is,
I'm going to fucking show you.
I'm gonna and he's black and he's white,
but I'm going to fucking sue your ass if
I'm black.
It's like the funny to watch him go.
It's not as bad as you're making it out
to be.
I mean,
I was,
I was born black and I'm liking it a
lot.
And one woman goes,
you know,
it's disturbing because it's shocking
just to spring this on me,
but I don't,
I'm,
I'm not scared I could take on being
black.
I'll just,
let's,
we'll see what happens.
I mean,
she was like,
turn credits.
She goes,
we'll just,
I'll just live with,
we'll just figure this out,
I guess.
I mean,
it was insane that they bought into it,
but also that that's how we did it.
We fucking made him sign beforehand and
then you pay them out and when it's
over,
we broke them off more money.
So they wouldn't say no because they
still have the legal right to be like,
I'm pulling that up.
You pull it or I'm suing you.
So once it was over,
did they understand that it was for
comedy central after,
after everything was said and done,
and then do they laugh?
A few did not laugh.
You laughed.
A few people were not good.
But that was one of my favorite bits.
Melon and Mayo and man,
did it work like a charm?
People were like,
this man needs is delicious.
It was fucking Hellman's or whatever
with a little brown dye in it.
It's unconventional,
but I really like
because it's so stupid.
[inaudible].