Five four,
three,
two
day Ruben lays gentlemen,
how are you buddy?
What's up bro?
Dude,
I haven't seen you a while.
The last time we saw each other,
it was just now,
but before that was right before the
election.
The day before the world changed.
Squirrely tourette's.
Squirly.
Doesn't that literally,
it seems like a lifetime ago.
Not even a lifetime ago.
It's like a different life for me.
I think it's a different life for you.
Think about how much has changed for
both of us in that time,
but it seems like another planet,
like an alternate universe of the day
before the election.
It is in a lot of ways,
right?
I mean people are,
the world's going,
well,
people are,
the world's trying to find its footing.
Yes.
You know,
it's a lot of craziness.
I hate to tell you jail.
Oh,
but you are a little piece of the
finding of the footing because people
are finding the footing.
You know,
I'm on tour repeaters in right now.
I just got in this morning from Atlanta
and it's like there is,
without being hyperbolic,
there is some kind of awakening
happening right now.
People are kinda getting their shit
together.
They're kind of sorting out things there
through long form conversations like
we're all having and all these people
that we're now connected with.
There's something happening where people
are going.
There's another way to make sense and
let me figure out what that is.
It doesn't mean we have all the answers
and I can sure as hell no I don't and I
don't think you think you do either,
but we're at least giving them a little
room to figure it out and it's pretty
cool.
Well,
the thing about Peterson that's been
fascinating is how many people
misrepresent what he says to try to
frame him him in a way that makes him
evil and mix their position seem more
ethical or more moral or better or more
intellectual.
There's so many articles being written
about him almost on a daily basis.
It is misrepresent what he's saying.
It's epic bullshit.
I mean weird.
That's all it is.
These guys want clicks.
That's all they want.
I mean,
I've,
we've done about 20 shows in the last
six weeks or so,
bounced around from Nashville and
Houston and Atlanta and Chicago and
everywhere else,
the crowds have been incredible.
It's,
it's probably split,
you know,
first off they always go,
well,
it's angry white men.
That's the main thing.
It's all angry white men.
Now,
first off,
let's say it was all angry white men
there,
that in and of itself doesn't mean it's
bad.
Let's say there was like a really
disaffected group of angry white men
that really felt like by their
masculinity had been compromised or they
couldn't get jobs or they didn't feel
good about their lives.
Like if there was someone talking to
them that was helping them,
that would actually be good.
But let's just put that aside,
right.
Cause they don't mean it in a positive
way.
So they say it's all angry white.
But now I can tell you it's about 60,
40 male to female,
roughly.
Um,
at Jordan shows Jordan shows.
Yeah.
And it's,
do you think that's like dates that
reluctantly go along with men?
Like right.
There are some,
I mean there will be guys that you will,
he's actually,
usually girls will come up to me after
and they'll go,
you know,
he's a big fan of you guys are,
he loves Jordan are he loves you or Blah
Blah Blah,
and I'm just here.
But then they all have a great time.
I mean I'm telling you,
this thing has been insane.
Love
Fest.
I know you saw the video that Jordan
posted last night.
It was his birthday last night.
We were at,
where the hell was I?
Atlanta,
the Tabernacle in Atlanta,
you know,
almost 3000 people singing happy
birthday to him.
We brought out this freaking stuffed
lobster and a and a piece of meat cause
he's on this crazy meat diet now and
it's like,
it's an endless love fest.
Every street.
We walked down,
people high five and us saying hi.
We did a little meet and greet impromptu
thing at the Lincoln memorial and about
a hundred people showed up just out of
nowhere.
And it's like these people are just
trying to figure shit out.
They're not white supremacists.
They're not all right.
They don't hate women.
It is literally nothing that they say
because they want clicks.
And the way they get clicks,
I mean,
you know,
the way they get clicks because they
saved the absolute reverse from the
truth.
It's not that they lie a little bit like
a little lie.
I think nobody would even pick up on it.
We don't think that's what they do.
I think they're just misrepresenting.
I don't think they're,
they're saying the APPS,
the opposite of the truth.
They're just,
they just look there.
They're finding these little categories
like homophobia,
transphobia.
I'm not a homophobe,
he's on tour with a gay guy.
He's not a transplant.
There are trans people that show up
there.
And I,
and I discussed it with him every
freaking night.
I asked,
you know,
we do.
So I basically do like 15 minutes of
stand up,
up top.
He does an hour and a half and then we
do a q and a together.
Um,
and we bring out all of these things and
every night to clear it up and sometimes
I'll have people bro bust out their
phones and I'll be like,
why don't you guys record this tonight?
Let's get it out on twitter where he
takes down the alt right because he
hates the identity politics of the right
as much as the identity politics of the
left.
I mean,
I think,
I think the reason we all focus on the
thing of the left is because it has
encompassed culture in media and
politics and what you're allowed to say
and,
and uh,
universities and all of that.
So it makes more sense to focus on that.
The little sliver of it that's on the
right.
Yeah.
It's Shitty.
It's horrible.
You should not look at your skin color
as some great thing that makes you
better or,
but it's sort of right thing,
is racism always a right thing?
Like,
oh,
not at all racists,
right?
No.
I think the left is far more racist than
the right at this moment.
Yeah.
Why do you think that?
Because identity politics is based in
racism.
You happen to be white.
I know nothing about you by the color of
your skin.
I know about Joe Rogan because I watched
the show,
I listened to the show.
We've done this several times and we can
for the hours that we're going to sit
here now we can dive as deep into any
issue and that's the only way that I can
sensibly judge you.
But the idea that you will look at
people that you would look at a black
person,
a black person will be sitting there or
a Muslim person will be sitting there
are transports and sitting there and
you'd go,
I have even an inkling of what you think
because of that immutable characteristic
that is actual racism that is
prejudging,
right?
Judging first before you know somebody.
So I have a much bigger issue with that
because that has infected everything in
American society right now.
The identity politics of the right,
that this should be a white ethno state
or something like that.
But it's that of course it's nonsense.
That's not really the identity politics
of the right.
Well,
I don't think the left is necessarily
that way either.
I mean,
I think the identity politics,
there's a real issue,
right,
with people that only identify with
other women,
women that only identify with women and
don't care about men.
There's a real issue with people that
are a only American.
They don't care about the rest of the
world.
This is like,
there's all these weird groups,
but I think we run into problems when we
start saying,
oh,
it's the left.
It's doing this as the right that's
doing this.
I think it's just tribal.
It's just this weird thing that human
beings tend to gravitate towards.
Crow tribes for sure.
And look,
we can we,
can I talk about things usually from a
little more of a political lens then I
think you do.
So yes,
of course.
Ultimately it is tribalism.
However you want to parse that
tribalism,
right?
So yes,
the law,
and I say this all the time,
but the left right thing doesn't make
that much sense anymore.
You're either basically,
you're basically for freedom.
You're for the individual to live
freely,
however they see fit or you believe that
the government should engineer things
and that there should be central
planning so that people,
I think that's always shitty thinking.
I think that people that say that the
government should engineer things,
they're just looking for a solution and
then they think the government should
handle it.
So yeah,
I think we should pay more taxes or is
that going to go,
it's going to go to the government and
what is it you're agreeing with me?
Yeah,
and a lot of,
oh okay.
I thought you said no,
no me.
Your thinking.
I mean their shift,
they're having shitty thinking.
It's like this idea that the
government's going to fix it.
The government is filled with people
like we don't have our own individual
solutions so we don't have a solution as
human.
Just as human beings,
objective human beings looking at
problems.
Why would we ever think that elected
officials,
these,
these people that are for the most part
full of shit,
like they're just trying to say whatever
they can say that's going to appease
both the special interest groups and the
lobbyists and the people that are
helping them get into place and people
are going to vote for them and you know,
and then just sort of like skirt around
all the other issues that are
controversial to the point where they
can get into office named three
politicians that you really like.
I don't know any of them.
I mean,
I know.
All right.
Then Gary Johnson who is like,
who I like him too and I've heard it
before,
but he was the worst possible
libertarian candidate,
you know,
who's the best libertarian candidate?
I mean ran.
Paul should be,
if he really had the balls to be what he
is going to learn how to stuff it
takedown.
Yeah,
right.
He's got a lot right guys coming at you
again,
you got to figure out a way to sprawl.
You could do,
you could do two hours with him and he'd
be a lot better and a lot of ways,
but he should be the guy but he doesn't
have the balls to do it because he wants
to maintain being a Republican senator
in Kentucky and he's not going to do it
if he has to leave the party.
But if,
but I've seen a major shift I think in
Republicans or at least conservatives or
generally people on the right,
whatever you want to call that thing.
There is a massive libertarian streak
that is alive in them right now,
which is why most of the people that I
liked these days that I get along with
that I think are fair and decent and
honest are pretty much libertarian.
Define Libertarian,
libertarian,
so libertarian or classical liberal.
This is what I get more than anything
else.
Cause I say I'm a classical liberal,
which basically means you believe in the
individual.
The sovereignty of the individual is the
simple most important thing.
It is your life.
It is your duty to do what you see fit.
The government is supposed to do pretty
much nothing other than protect your
life.
So it's supposed to have an army and
police and stuff like that and then
really just laissez faire economics and
that.
And then the difference between
classical liberal and Libertarian is how
far do you want to go with the
government.
So I think there is some utility for the
state,
but the more I do this,
the more I have these conversations and
I talked to ann caps and real
libertarians and all that.
I find that hard to defend the state at
almost any level at this point.
But I do think that because I don't want
to live in Mad Max fury road just yet,
although we may be heading there,
I still will defend the state at some
level.
But I would say everything should be
local.
We have an incredible experiment here
with 50 states.
If your state taxes too high,
move,
go somewhere else.
If your state doesn't have good
education,
you can go somewhere else.
If you don't like the weather somewhere.
But the second we make everything
federal,
and this is what,
it's not just the left.
This is what people who were using lazy
thinking that you referred to,
they think we should just have one law
that we should all live exactly the
same.
No matter where we are geographically,
no matter what our religion or what.
However we set our set of uses,
that is a nightmare.
That is a nightmare for a totalitarian
state because if,
if the federal government,
if one government controls everything,
guess what?
If you don't like it,
you got to leave the country.
You know,
go to Mexico,
go to Canada,
you probably won't like it.
They're really referring to like in
terms of like you want subtle laws.
Well because you want states' rights you
should care about is state,
right?
So for example,
we live in California.
We are taxed out the fucking Wazoo.
I bought a house last year.
It's my first time at 41 years old that
I owned property in America.
I made it.
I own property.
I don't have to tell you about my
property taxes.
They're insane.
They're very high.
They're absurdly,
absurdly high.
That's the price you pay for living in a
spot where everybody wants to live.
No,
but that's it.
That's the beauty,
right?
So like there's a trade off there.
Now I could move to Texas and the
property taxes would be way low and
maybe because they don't tax as much the
schools are and as good or a series of
other things,
but that's the beauty of the foot vote.
You can go.
This is an experiment,
this thing in American who's against
that?
Anyone that wants to keep giving more
power to the federal government,
which is pretty much everybody these
days.
Pretty much everybody in mainstream.
Certainly all of the Democrats,
all of you know the,
the,
the mainstream set of Democrats and the
Bernie and the progressive crew.
They would love for the federal
government to control everything and
that is an absolute nightmare.
It's an absolute no control.
Everything like how so?
Like they want to control all economics,
department of Education,
a configure out,
all the environmental regulations,
all of those things.
I would kick back everything to the
states,
let the states decide.
And if you don't like it,
get going.
I mean,
that's,
that's a beautiful thing.
If you,
if you really care about marijuana and
you live in Alabama right now and it's
not legal,
guess what?
Go to Colorado,
go to California.
I mean that,
that's,
that's how you'll influence things
because you can move your family,
your value,
whatever you bring to your community in
your life.
I mean,
think about it right now.
If California just kept taxing higher
and higher and kept screwing up a lot of
this,
a ton that's going wrong in the state,
eventually Joe Rogan might be like,
you know,
I just built this freaking kick ass new
studio here.
I'm now paying,
I don't know,
hundreds of thousands of dollars in
taxes and all this stuff.
You might want to try it somewhere else
where they're going to tax you less.
But that's the beauty of the thing.
You don't have to leave the country.
So the,
the federal government should pretty
much do nothing.
It should make sure we're not warring
with each other that the states aren't
warring that's about,
and then protect the borders.
Beyond that.
It doesn't have to do a lot.
Leave it to the states.
Let look if you had a problem here,
you know you're a sewage leak right
outside,
you want the federal government to deal
with that or do you want the local
municipality to deal with that?
You want everything to be as local as
possible because that's how you'll
influence things.
And that's how you as an individual will
be empowered.
And that's all I have.
No,
I mean,
hearing what you're saying,
but I'm just not hearing this,
this clamoring for the government to
take care of everything.
I mean,
you hear,
you heard a little bit from Bernie,
you know,
but I just think again,
a lot of that is like,
it's not doing it now.
So the idea is that the solution would
be if the government takes over and we
take more rich people's taxes,
you know,
and he will spout off about income
inequality and take that money and
redistribute it.
And then somehow or another that's going
to fix everything.
But it's not,
you're just going to make government
bigger.
You're going to have more jobs,
you're gonna have more jobs in
government,
red tape,
more bureaucrats,
more bullshit.
So you're agreeing with,
yeah.
Yeah,
for the most part.
I mean that's the thing.
It's like they look,
you want to give free college education,
everyone first off,
it's not free.
I mean that it's just,
this is just stupid lazy thinking to say
it is free.
It's not free.
You got to pay the janitor and you got
to pray the professors and everyone
else,
well they mean free for students.
And the,
the idea of being that our taxes instead
of going towards the military,
they would go towards education.
Sure.
So they should at least be honest and
say that because a certain amount of
people just hear free and you just think
it's free but it's not free.
You obviously have to pay for it.
But also we're moving into an economy
where robots are taking over automa
automation is taking over,
go to,
you know what I think Mcdonald's said
within five years it's all going to be
ipads.
Go to half the Mcdonald's and you know,
a fast food places in airports.
Now it's all ipad.
So if you're,
the more you're going to the government,
which doesn't do anything right or well
or efficiently,
the more they say,
okay,
private business,
you're going to have to spend more on
employees.
Well then all these businesses are just
going to figure out ways which they
should do.
I mean that's ingenuity,
right?
They will figure out ways to save costs,
save expenses,
and then less people will be hired and
then at the same time we're going to be
subsidized and all of these people to go
to college.
We're often in college,
they're learning nothing and gender
studies and,
and all of these other crazy classes and
we're just going to have this set of
people who have no real skills
and we're going to set up businesses
that will never want to hire them
because the government is going to tell
them how much to pay.
I mean,
you have employees here,
you don't,
you pay them what you think is fair and
if they don't want to do it,
they don't have to.
But imagine if the government came in
and was like,
Joe,
you're going to have to pay your guys
this amount.
It's ridiculous.
Well think how many people would love to
work for you for free.
I'm sure you get emails every day as I
do.
I don't want to,
I don't stalker.
Yeah.
I don't want people to work for me for
free.
But like the interns,
I don't like the idea of it silly.
But you're a small business owner.
I mean that's the fact.
And you should be able to do whatever
with your business and your property
that you want.
It's as simple as that.
I'm,
I think we get real,
there's a lot of cliche terms and one of
them is like that people who go to
college or studying gender studies or
lesbian dance theory,
but how much of that is really
happening?
And then the man,
it's very small.
It does exist in some weird states.
Like I'm sure you're aware of that lady
who was the professor from Fresno State
who,
uh,
got in trouble recently.
So many of them.
Which one was his?
Some big lady was talking a bunch of
shit.
It's just there and she said she could
never get fired.
They didn't fire that lane.
Yeah,
there's a lot of them.
I mean there's a lot of really wacky
professors out there that do have
tenure.
Yeah.
That woman was tweeting out some bananas
stuff and she has tenure and she's not
going to go anywhere.
There's universities all over the
country.
They're constantly teaching kids.
I mean,
for the most part,
these are there.
It's a small percentage.
It's a small percentage,
but they have way over influence on the
amount of people.
They have scared the majority into
silence.
I mean,
I don't know how often you're doing
colleges these days,
but I don't do it.
I'm doing them all the time and what I
find,
so I did this thing at University of New
Hampshire.
We posted,
saw it,
so look,
they first off,
what they did was they were supposed to
be about 300 people there.
So they,
at first,
because of the protestors,
the school said we can't secure a room.
So thinking what are they protesting you
about?
Well,
I was split technically I was supposed
to be there that day with candace owens
and Charlie Kirk from turning point and
we were going to talk about cultural
appropriation and you know,
some of the hot hot button stuff.
So I don't even know that they all were
there to protest me specifically.
But anyway,
that day was the day that can,
and Charlie ended up on TMZ with Kanye,
so they bailed on me and just left the
left me for the wolves.
They were on Tmz with Kanya.
We've been just a couple of weeks ago.
They,
Kanye showed up at the TMC offices with
them.
So they just showed up with him and they
blew off there.
Yeah,
they're all good appearance.
it's all right.
When was it was me.
It was me and university of New
Hampshire or Kanye and TMZ.
Yeah.
But they had a schedule like they're
supposed to be there and they just
decided not to run again.
So the people like paid to have you
come.
Yeah.
Right.
And they were supposed to be paid to go
to come to think of it.
I didn't get more money for this.
That is ridiculous.
The whole thing's ridiculous that they
would just blow that off.
It's like,
that's a Gig.
You don't blow off a gig because Kanye
wants to go on the gossip show.
Yeah.
But now you're fucking stupid.
Or what?
Now you're talking to me like as a
comic.
Good.
It's like,
yeah,
we wouldn't do that.
It's just a different,
you don't blow off a Gig.
Yeah.
It's just a different,
but come to see you don't just decide,
oh,
this gig is better for me right now.
Yeah.
I'm just curious.
With Kanye on TV,
Hi Harvey Harvey that they spent time
with Harvey Levin instead of me.
Well,
he seems like a nice enough guy.
Yeah.
This business is a little shady.
But the whole thing behind it is you
don't,
you don't cancel a gig because he got
another Gig that you think is better for
you last minute.
Like that's terrible.
What's that phrase,
man?
The show must go on.
Yeah,
it's supposed to go on.
for sure.
So I saw you getting,
uh,
was that the lady that the coins,
the jar,
they brought noise makers.
They were slamming on shit.
They were screaming things where it's so
ridiculous.
Like you would let them talk and they
didn't have any to say.
I mean the best part of this.
So first off,
300 people supposed to be there.
They say we can't secure a room on
campus.
So think about what a defeat that is.
So this is where you might say,
okay,
it's a minority of students,
but think how they affect the majority.
That meant that the University of New
Hampshire,
it's a pretty solid school in the live
free or state live free or die state.
Right.
They could not secure because I'm
showing up a room on their campus.
So that's already a massive loss.
When you,
when you say could not secure you mean
safety wise,
he said they could not secure it.
Safety wise.
There were too many threats,
whatever the hell that means.
Twitter chat or other non,
so candice and the other guy are gone.
So it's just you?
Yeah,
the,
the Gay Libertarian Guy.
And they're like,
too dangerous.
Too dangerous,
too crazy.
Like what is he going to say?
We're going to,
we're going to have to silence him.
Yeah.
Well I flipped the script on their
heads.
I mean,
that's what it comes down to.
Like they don't know what the fuck to
make of me because I don't play their
game,
but I'm just doing what I think is
right.
I don't think I'm a freaking rocket
scientist.
I don't think I'm some massive
intellectual.
I think I'm someone that can communicate
these ideas pretty well.
And uh,
and hopefully we'll talk about it.
But I'm back in,
stand up now like I'm doing,
I'm just doing what I think is right on
this planet while I'm here.
That's it.
And so when you do these speeches,
what do you do when you go to these
colleges?
So,
so I get up there,
so they move it from this,
from the university 300 seat room.
They move it to a hockey rink of 7,500
seats.
So think how absurd this absurd,
this is 300 people and they're in a,
how many people are in the audience?
300 people.
Oh God.
So apparently they didn't apparently
like another hundred supporters of mine
showed up,
but they didn't even let them in.
And even though they were roughly 7,000,
100 empty seats,
why wouldn't they let him in?
I Dunno.
Cause at that point security starts,
everything just gets whacked.
I mean this happens at every college
thing.
Like nobody knows who's in charge
anymore,
you know,
it's just like this big cluster fuck.
So anyway,
so they put up a step and repeat with
the turning point symbol behind me and
I'm doing my thing.
But there's a freaking Sam bony back
there.
I'm like,
what the hell am I doing?
Like this is ridiculous.
And turning point is that conservative
think tank things.
They're the largest conservative,
uh,
college.
A nonprofit.
So why do they have that behind you?
Well,
cause he was sponsored by them.
Charlie.
Charlie runs turning points.
Okay.
Yeah.
But he didn't even have the fucking show
up.
It was either that that then goes,
they were,
I sit literally,
I stand there and literally in front of,
you know,
6,000 seats.
Seriously.
Why?
Yeah.
I mean,
that's for,
for them to figure out why they did
that.
But Anyway,
7,000 empty seats.
I do my thing.
I talked for about a half hour and I
knew they were a certain,
you know,
250 of those kids were there to listen
and agree or disagree.
I mean,
think about it.
These,
this is the conservative group.
They're bringing a gay married guy who's
pro pod,
who's pro euthanasia,
who's against the death penalty for
reforming the prison system.
Uh,
I'm pro choice.
Like I could go on and on about the
liberal crowd that you and I don't get
anymore.
And they're,
they're,
they're applauding.
What do they,
what are they mad at you for?
Well,
so it's not those guys,
man.
It's,
they're mad.
They,
if they don't know,
they just want you to bow forever.
They don't come to listen.
They want to silence.
That's it.
They just want to silence you about like
what is it that they oppose that you're
saying Joe,
I w I literally,
every time I they would scream or they'd
start robotically,
you know,
they set timers and then they
robotically chant.
We're not the problem or just some other
nonsense.
We're not,
we are not the problem we are.
I'd go,
I'd look at them right in the eye and be
like,
I'm standing right in front of you.
Do you have a question for me?
Is there something that I said that
upset you?
Any of that?
And they can't respond.
They,
I mean they just can't respond because
they're not there to exchange ideas.
They believe they are oppressed and they
boo.
I mean,
look,
I always go up there,
what do I say at every college thing I
go,
think about it.
Do you think you have it worse than,
than your grandparents?
I want everyone in this room to think
about your grandparents right now and
99.9% of people in America right now
have it better than their grandparents
had it.
I'm sure you have it better than your
grandparents had.
I have better than my grandparents had
it.
All of these kids,
they're at University of New Hampshire
studying whatever the hell they want to
study.
They have it better than their
grandparents.
But that the power of thinking that
you're oppressed,
the power of thinking that the world is
warped against you is it's a drug.
It is truly a drug.
And one of the things on that,
so it turns out,
did you see the exchange I got in with
the Trans Woman?
Yes.
So it turns,
so this trans woman is telling me to go
fuck myself and whatever she's saying
and screaming along with everybody we'll
ship set about.
Well cause I mentioned the Jordan
Peterson Pronoun thing and I said,
look,
I want trans people to be treated
equally under the law.
I want trans people to be respected.
I hope you find,
I literally said to her looking right at
her,
I hope,
I hope you find someone that loves you
and your life.
I mean all,
I want you to be as equal and happy as
anybody else on this planet.
That is what I want for you.
She's still telling me to go fuck
myself.
It turns out,
I didn't know this till weeks later.
I found this out about a week ago.
She's a professor of gender studies at
University of New Hampshire.
So she's literally trying,
you have a professor that is part of the
protesters and she's live tweeting the
thing about,
all right,
Dave Ruben.
I mean,
so that's where,
when,
when people think it's this little
thing,
it's,
yeah,
it's this little thing that's,
that's metastasizing and spreading like
a cancer.
And I truly believe that identity
politics,
that this thing,
I think is
the biggest threat to the west and to
freedom that exists.
Did you communicate with her at all?
I communicated her from with my mic and
then was there,
did she exchange say what?
She has a problem.
So she kept yelling at me and people can
have a video of this.
Oh yeah,
it's there.
I don't know where it's probably maybe
an hour in herself.
Um,
I saw it and I just was like,
oh poor,
what's he dealing with?
I got a lot of pity for that,
which was good.
It was like,
you know what,
I was shaking the jar coins.
I was like,
Oh,
you know,
it was really funny is that I realized
that there's one,
so there's one moment and I never lost
my cool cause it's like it's a bunch of
kids yelling
and as long as they're not going to take
a Samurai sword out and stab me or
anything,
then it,
then it's fine.
But there was one moment where they just
kept going and going.
So I sarcastically said it.
I was like,
guys shut the fuck up.
And it got a big laugh and then I
repeated it a couple times,
but then I realized that when the school
newspaper wrote about it,
they said,
and then Dave Ruben told them to shut
the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up is very different than
shut the fuck up.
So that was my one,
my one lesson in there,
it seems like is the answer.
She didn't want anything from me.
She wanted me to be thrown out for doing
that because if you are doing that,
you're,
you're disrupting a performance.
I mean,
I'm sure you would have a q and a with
those people.
Right.
He'd be happy to do that.
Do it.
And if they're a half hour,
I opened it up for q and a so let's do
the rest of the last hour.
But you didn't even get a chance to get
to that with her.
Right.
She was already yelling at know and then
I think I even said to her,
I know I did it.
Several people.
I'm pretty sure she was too.
Do you have a question for me?
And I think her last thing was your,
I hate you or something.
Something to that effect.
I mean this is a professor should be,
she should be disqualified for teaching.
She's an a logical thinker.
This is not what you want raising your
children.
Yeah.
But essentially that's what they are.
They're still children.
You got this fucking dummy who can't
focus enough to have a coherent argument
that they're yelling out in the middle
of your performance.
And by the way,
for the record,
the uh,
authorities or the police or the campus
safety,
whatever it was,
did at one point try to have some people
sit down and be quiet.
And I was like guys don't worry about
it.
Cause it's like yeah,
I guess we could escalate it to that
point.
I didn't even want this video to be
released when they videotape this.
I did not want it to be released cause I
don't want to add fuel to the fire.
I'm trying to fix some of these products
as part of the problem.
Right.
Is that this becomes something that they
know that they can get a video of if
they go to your next performance and
interrupt you.
Yeah.
But you know what?
I don't think they want one person over
to their side.
I don't think one screaming lunatic who,
who did not come to respect me even
though I was there to respect them.
I don't think they want anybody.
I think I actually want a lot of people
to my side.
And I think,
I mean I know it cause I've received
tons of emails about it.
I know what you're saying,
but I don't think it's about winning to
your side.
I think it's about other lunatics that
realize that there's an opportunity to
get attention if they go to your show
and yell things out.
Yeah,
well that's why we ended up putting the
video up because a couple of them would
put up these little clips,
very selectively edited that made it
seem like I was doing things that I
wasn't like I was silencing them or just
some other nonsense.
So then finally I was like,
all right,
if this is the way the Internet is and
it just is,
then we'll just put up the whole thing
on edited.
Even though I had 10 minutes before,
I said,
guys,
don't even record this.
I said,
don't even record this,
because because Charlie and candice
hadn't showed up and I was like,
it's ridiculous.
I got 7,000 empty seats behind me.
But then once people start playing that
game,
you can either just be the bitch,
which I refuse to be,
or you can fight back.
Yeah.
It's a weird place to be because you
know what they're doing and they're
essentially just trying to rile you up.
And if they're not willing to have a
real dialogue with you,
they're just yelling,
fuck Dave Rubin.
That really should disqualify you from
being a teacher.
I mean that's,
that's the worst way to communicate.
You're demonstrating that you're
thinking sucks and that you want to
teach about gender studies,
but yet you know,
you,
you're interrupting a comp and you're
trying to claim transphobia or whatever
the fuck he's,
she is trying to claim she,
it's a she right?
She,
she's a trans woman,
but she was a man not as a woman.
Yeah.
By the way,
I treated her with complete respect.
Like that's the thing,
they,
they truly,
they want you,
they want to put their foot on your neck
and have you stay there forever.
And that's why every time now that
somebody's mainstream writes something
about you,
half the time they're calling you a
conservative cause they don't know what
the fuck to do with this guy who's
talking about drugs and all the crazy
shit you're talking about.
All the time,
but also you're woke enough to actually
identify there is a problem here with
what's happening in the mainstream.
So they can't categorize us in any
sensible way.
So in a weird way,
especially because me and you also,
because of the nature of what we do,
we sit from people that are a little
scary.
You know what I mean?
Like you've had Jones on,
I've had molyneux on I,
you know,
I had certain a bit John at the,
at the beginning,
and I'm sure you've had plenty of other
controversial people and it's like,
so they,
there's an odd way that they want to
look at the two of us more than other
people because we,
by the nature of our jobs,
by the nature of how we exist,
that's a threat.
If you want to control the way everybody
thinks.
Hmm.
Yeah.
You're not supposed to give people a
platform.
That's what I keep hearing.
Yeah.
So,
so what's your policy on that?
Because that seemed to be the,
after this idw intellectual dark web
article came out,
that was the big thing that people kept
hitting me on.
It's like you don't want any
gatekeeping.
You'll talk to anybody and first off,
I won't talk to anybody,
but I'm a general believer that you let
ideas out there,
but what is wrong with talking to people
and it's always been what people have
done their,
they've always been interviews with
controversial people.
Guess what happens when you stop talking
to people?
Yeah,
not good.
Yeah.
That's when shit goes down.
But there's a lot of people that don't
want us talking to people.
I mean I look,
a lot of people were pissed you,
you smoke pot with Jones,
right?
You smoke.
Not with Alex.
I watched it.
It's bananas.
I watched all the games and it's like,
look,
that guy has done some seriously twisted
crazy shit.
There is no doubt about it.
The Sandy Hook
stuff,
and I didn't know about the sandy hook
stuff by the way,
before we did the podcast,
I knew that he believes a bunch of
stupid conspiracies that are genuinely
just dismissed,
but I didn't know that he was saying
that those kids never died or that it
was going to change the equation for
you.
Yeah,
it would have been mad at him and I
would have talked about it right away.
I would've been like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
This kids are dead.
Like there's a guy that was,
uh,
it was a terrible story about a guy who
was a conspiracy theorist before sandy
hook.
Then his kid died at Sandy Hook and a
bunch of people were threatening him and
calling him a crisis actor and saying
his kid never died.
And then he realized how insane it
really is.
People are looking for conspiracies
everywhere,
man.
I keep hearing them now about Anthony
Bordain that bordain was going to expose
some child pedophile ring and that's why
they suicided him.
It's fucking stupid,
man.
Without going down and fully on that
road.
There is one odd thing about the bordain
thing,
which is just a few weeks ago,
didn't he tweet some odd thing about
having the,
the,
he's met the Hillary Clinton like
machine or something and it's wrong.
And he was talking about,
no,
I'll tell you exactly what he was
talking about.
The same people that Harvey Weinstein
used would that were,
um,
Israeli,
what does it black cue or some shit.
See what you find the tweet because
[inaudible] he was basically saying
that,
uh,
Donald Trump's people use the same
people that Harvey Weinstein used
Israeli intelligence group too.
You know,
there was something that Harvey had done
to his victims where he was trying to
silence them by scaring them with these,
uh,
these,
you know,
Israeli mercenary type folks don't go
down that conspiracy.
That's not what he was doing with me.
He was just saying,
God is just standing there like he's
got,
he had some crazy thing with his
girlfriend.
We was like fully invested in her battle
with Harvey Weinstein,
you know,
so that's what he tweeted about.
But it was,
it's like they would kill him for that.
Like that's so fucking stupid.
Yeah.
Well what about Ronan Farrow?
What about all the people that wrote the
story?
What about all the people that are
accusing him of rape like this?
The guy's going broke.
Two d people don't understand that
Harvey Weinstein's businesses going
bankrupt.
He's fucked.
He's going to jail.
It's,
the walls are caving in.
He doesn't even have his business
anymore.
I ran a mercenary to go kill a chef.
I mean,
this is fucking stupid.
This is stupid thinking and you know,
look,
it's not,
it's not that it's impossible for
someone who will want to hire someone to
kill someone.
But I don't think that's what happened.
I think he killed himself.
And I think it's a terrible,
terrible tragedy.
And I think it's really disrespectful to
have all these dumb speculative ideas
because there's sport in conspiracies.
It's a sport.
It's a game.
There's a hobby that people have.
And looking to fucking,
I'm looking for the truth bro.
I'm looking at fucking close the gaps.
This is what it is,
man.
It's the Illuminati.
The second you think you got it right
here.
Um,
okay.
Here it is.
Hold on.
Scroll up.
I am in no way Hillary Quinn.
I've been on the receiving end of her
operatives wrath and it ain't fun.
Right?
And that's from about a month ago.
Those operatives,
Oh,
here we go.
Now you're going to fill some gaps for
me.
Her operatives wrath.
Okay.
Know,
but he was,
the thing is Hillary Clinton was before
the track,
before the scandal happened,
there's a lot of photos of Hillary
Clinton hanging out with Weinstein.
Yeah.
Oprah hanging out with them out.
Everybody cuddle and Meryl Streep,
Meryl Streep,
cuddling up with them.
Like the whole thing is there's people
that are complicit for sure in one way
or another.
So after everything you just said and
knowing that Joanne's plays that game a
little bit,
would you have him on again?
If I had them on again,
that would be the first thing I would
talk about.
You know,
I'm,
I've been friends with Alex since 1998
I've known him for a long time.
I don't think he's a bad guy,
but I think he's very wrong about a lot
of things.
He's very misguided about a lot of
things and I think he loves
conspiracies.
There is a bunch of people in this
country that love to make,
they will have to connect the dots and
find conspiracies in fucking everything.
Everything that there is.
And sometimes the right and Alex has
been right.
Definitely.
He's been right about a bunch of things.
He was right about the World Trade
Organization particular about when they
were using agent provocateur tours to
disrupt protests and make them violent
protests by smashing windows.
And he documented all of it and all
these people were um,
none of them were arrested.
They were all,
they all went to one safe house and then
negotiated with the police.
Then they were released,
they all had military,
um,
military issue footwear.
Like he's got all these,
the,
these documents from people that worked
inside either police or law enforcement
that say that there is a standard
practice and this is existed for a long
time and when you have peaceful protest
and you can't do anything about it,
the best way to do something about it is
to take that peaceful protest and turn
it non peaceful.
Yeah.
The way you do that,
he have these guys wear masks,
they go in,
they pretend they're one of the
protesters.
They start smashing windows,
flipping over cars and then you move the
cops and then they shut the protest
down.
So you essentially shut the peaceful
protesters down by introducing non
peaceful people and you,
these are military operatives,
these are people that are working for
the government or working for whoever
the fuck decides to pull the trigger on
this and this is real.
This has happened.
There's a lot of people saying that's
happening with the Tommy Robinson
protests in the UK right now.
See,
I don't know enough about that story
other than the fact that a bunch of
people were mad at me on twitter.
I'm not talking about talking about,
I was like,
I don't even know what that is.
I'm going to back away.
And then I saw it was something about he
was,
he was filming outside of a trial of
Muslim pedophiles.
Is that what these grooming gangs?
Yeah,
grooming gangs.
Yeah.
Tell me the whole story.
So I don't want to do this as if I'm the
freaking lawyer of the whole thing,
but in effect he was filming outside of
the trial for these,
this group of men that are raping,
they're to be like
12 and 13 year old girls.
Basically they're on trial.
He had already been on probation or
something for something else.
And you're not allowed to fill them
outside the courthouse.
So technically I suppose he is in jail
now for the right reasons,
but there's a lot of people that think
he's not going to survive being in jail.
And I look,
I had the guy on my show.
Have you ever,
have you ever talked to him?
No,
I didn't know anything about him until
this,
this thing happened.
I mean he has no,
I know.
It's a lot.
It's all the time,
man.
No,
I know you shit to do.
I have kids.
I don't know.
You have to do occasionally just pick
one and you're like,
this one dude.
There's a lot of them.
I just don't know.
I don't know what's going on.
Like people who will,
how come you're not calm and going?
And it was like,
I don't even know about it.
You fuck.
I know.
I love it.
I love that.
When you sit out something on twitter
for six hours and people started
screaming at you like that proves or you
say anything about it.
Yeah.
Oh,
you talk all day long about this and
that,
but then this comes up and you don't
hear a word like I didn't even hear
about some just now.
Well,
all right,
let's not dive too deep in that so
quick,
but quick on Jones though.
So I'm not actually in case you think I
am.
I'm not giving you shit for doing it.
I'm just curious.
I'm just curious because I think part of
the article that that Barry Weiss wrote
in the times about us,
she was talking about that and there's a
line in there where she said,
you know,
if you talk to these people,
meaning Jones in Cernovich and Molyneux,
that you're either cynical or stupid and
in effect that was,
that was a shot at me and you,
it wasn't a shot at anybody else because
they don't have to talk to other people.
You know what I mean?
Like I love Eric and Bret Weinstein.
What she said,
yeah,
we can probably find the line.
But it was that you'd have to,
I think it was,
you'd have to be cynical or stupid.
I would argue that,
I mean,
are you against that?
Because I don't think you have to be,
they're cynical or stupid.
You just have to be a person talking to
someone.
Just because you're talking to someone
doesn't mean you agree with them.
Yeah.
Idea of giving someone a platform.
Like I'm going to have Ted nugent on the
podcast.
Right.
You obviously endorse everything he's
ever since.
That's what you're saying.
Right?
If you haven't gone,
that's,
that's the only way to look at it again.
That's it.
How come you can't just talk to the guy
and find out like,
like candace owens,
I don't agree with everything can to so
and so's.
Yeah.
And this is nothing wrong with having a
conversation like that.
In fact,
it's illuminating.
What do you got here?
Let's find that holding up the line.
This is from the Times piece.
Um,
it says,
it seems to me that if you're willing to
sit across from an Alex Jones or Mike
Cernovich and take them seriously,
there's a high probability that you're
either cynical or stupid.
Now,
if there's a reason for shorting the
idw,
it's the inability of certain members to
see this as a fatal error.
So that's,
that's Rogan and Ruben.
That's,
that's what that's saying.
Yeah,
I get it.
I'm just definitely things you can
criticize about me,
but,
um,
I have the list,
right?
But here's the thing.
If you're saying I'm taking him
seriously,
I got Alex High and drunk and he started
talking about interdimensional,
chogm molesters.
Like if anything,
it showed people who he really is.
Like,
I've known that guy forever.
I've partied with that dude.
I've had them coming to my comedy shows.
We've gotten fucked up and ran around
the town and went to bars together back
before everybody knew who he was too.
We could go places.
He's a fun guy.
I don't believe everything he believes.
I think he's silly
and a lot of ways,
but I like a lot of people that I don't
agree with.
I don't have to agree with them.
I didn't know about his Sandy Hook
denial.
If I did,
it would have been the first thing I
pressed him on when I talked to him.
I wanted to do it with my crazy friend
Eddie Bravo cause he believes every
fucking conspiracy theory and I wanted
to get him with Alex together and it was
the cluster fuck that I hoped it would
be it.
It was a good thing about it is it
showed people who Alex really is.
It showed a side of him that you just
don't get from his info wars show.
You get to see him hi and laughing and
drunk and pounded whiskey and fucking
around and people are like,
oh I could see why you like that guy.
I can see why he's fun.
We had a good time together.
That doesn't mean I endorse his opinions
on things.
And the idea that this is only red or
white,
that it is one or zero.
It's binary.
That's ridiculous.
I just didn't,
those two choices of adjectives I just
thought were slightly like you could say
defending our position,
I think.
I think she's doing a smart thing
because she's a writer for the New York
Times.
I do have a lot of ridiculous people on
and you have had ridiculous people on
too.
So what she's saying makes sense if you
take them seriously.
But she left that caveat.
If you take them seriously.
I do not take Alex Jones his opinion on
interdimensional child molesters.
Seriously,
I don't his opinion,
I don't want to smoke pot once a year
just to test to see what George Soros
has done with the marijuana.
George Soros is giving the marijuana
fucking dosage recommendations.
Like that's pretty sure.
Roseanne told me that too.
Well,
she thinks that that's another thing.
I don't know what to do with her now.
She thinks she apologized for that,
but she said George Soros was a Nazi or
something.
He was captured by the Nazis.
I mean he was like,
okay,
well anyway,
this,
this gate piracies this gate keeping
thing.
I just think it's,
it's interesting because if we're going
to do what we do well at whatever level
we do it,
it's like we're going to have to talk to
people that people don't like.
And listen,
look,
Larry King,
and this is the one thing I always say,
it's like Larry King in the,
in his heyday,
think of the Prime Larry King,
right?
So 1991,
CNN prime time,
he could have,
you know,
uh,
the Oj Simpson lawyers on,
on Monday,
he could have the cast show Seinfeld on
Tuesday.
He could have a magician on Wednesday.
He could have Lucille ball if she was
still alive on Thursday.
And then,
you know,
George,
the secretary of state or something.
So no one thought he endorsed all of
those ideas or I was friends with all
those people.
But I think somehow now,
because,
because this feels like your home.
Mine is actually in my home the way we
are.
We're different,
we're friendlier.
We're not sitting here with note cards
and with I fbs and it doesn't feel all
produced and planned and all that.
Even though I think we both do a hell of
a fucking professional show that I think
we're both really proud of.
Um,
I think because of that,
they think,
ah,
now you're seeing the real them or
something like that.
Like it's a,
it's something that I'm looking for Shit
to complain about.
Listen,
I might be the easiest,
right?
One of the reasons why I decided to do a
podcast in the
first place cause I wanted to be able to
do whatever I wanted.
I wanted to be able to talk to my
friends,
have a good time fuck around.
Along the line it became something
different.
And along the line it became not just
talking to my friends,
it became talking to people that are
famous are interesting people or
professors or writers or whoever it is.
And I'm going to do whatever the fuck I
want and that's why I'm doing this.
I'm going to do whatever the fuck I want
if I want to talk to.
And if you don't like who I'm talking
to,
it's super simple.
You just don't listen to that episode
and go load rogen.
You're all right now.
All you have is alt right people.
You think you're balanced up cause you
have abby Martin on once a year.
Like I just think I talked to people,
you know I,
I talked to a lot of people.
There's,
I like talking to people.
I like talking to people I agree with
and I can usually talk to people.
I disagree with them.
I get something out of that too.
Yeah.
How,
how aware are you of the thing that you
just said there that like you did
exactly what you set out to do.
I don't know that you fully set out to
do it this way,
but you did it like this thing that you
have created is so it,
it is so what you wanted to do,
whether you fully got it or not,
but like you created it,
it's awesome.
Like I'm,
I'm doing it at a,
I think a lower level than you are,
but I'm very aware of that.
That like I somehow I hated what the
system was offering and I was like,
I gotta do something that feels right
for me and from a different place.
Did it?
Yeah.
Cause I didn't come at it from a place
like I need a Gig.
I came at it from a place like,
oh that'd be fun.
Yeah.
Fuck around.
All the other side of things.
I mean,
I was already a professional stand up.
I was already the commentator for the
UFC.
So this wasn't like when I came,
I mean I did it for years for zero money
for years because I just did it for fun.
Like literally for fun dude,
once a week have fun,
sit down and have some comics over wood,
smoke some pot,
talk,
some shit,
have a couple of laughs.
And then next thing you know I've got
Graham Hancock on and you know,
next thing you know I've got bordain on
and I've got,
you know,
this professor and this author and the,
and then it got weirder and weirder.
But it just,
to me it's just what's interesting.
Talk to people and I've never looked at
it like,
mmm.
Like,
like there's anything I have to do.
I've never looked at it like that.
I've,
I've just always like,
well this would be cool.
Oh that guy sounds cool.
Let me get him.
This guy might be interesting.
Oh,
I like to talk to that dude.
I want to find out about sleep.
I want to find out about exercise and
want to find out about dying.
I want to find out about like,
well how the fuck this finance is really
where I want to talk to Peter Shift.
Tell me how this works.
How do you,
what do you do well,
how do you,
how are you making your money?
Like what it,
what the fuck is going on in Puerto
Rico?
I this,
this,
I love talking to people,
man.
I,
it's a fascinating thing to just to pick
the brain uninterrupted with no
distractions,
to sit down and talk to someone for
hours at a time.
You learned a lot about yourself.
You learn.
Conversely,
I'm much better,
much better at talking to people and
being sensitive and open minded and
being considerate and listening.
And that's a big thing.
Like listening and communicating people,
not just waiting
for my time to talk,
but communicating with people.
It's like,
I feel like conversation is a lost art
with a lot of folks and I've gotten way,
way better at it over the whatever many
years,
nine years,
nine years of doing this show.
Yeah,
I'm with,
yeah,
I mean I hear you all.
I mean,
I said at the beginning,
but I just am doing what I think is
right.
Yeah,
it's fun tactic.
That's why when I see like the barrage
of hate that I'll get online for this or
that or just,
you know,
it's the same thing.
It's just these people that just
endless.
You want to hate on everything and all
that.
It's too much noise.
Oh,
it's like if you're spending all day
long hating on me,
like if anything what I'm doing and he's
the real problem here.
You know what I mean?
Like let's say I'm wrong on everything I
say.
Everything I said for the first 10
minutes about politics is wrong and we
should have strong federal government
and identity politics like even if that
is,
that's how it,
it really is.
Am I really the biggest problem here
that people are all day long devoting
twitter accounts,
people that make accounts all day wrong.
Fuck Dave room and Dave Rubin socks,
Bro.
I was like,
what are you doing?
Is that going on all the time?
People get laid anymore.
I should know that that's happening.
That's the part of the problem is
you're,
you're sort of indulging it,
but paying attention to it.
There's just too many people paying way
less attention.
Yeah.
That's good.
You can't pay attention at all,
dude.
I was in a sensory deprivation tank just
two,
three days ago.
Thanks to you.
I've been doing it more.
I was just in one of these infrared
saunas.
I'm doing it,
you know,
I'm doing all my August off the grid.
I did it last August.
Just literally nothing.
I locked my phone in a safe,
really locked my phone in a safe for 30
days.
Do you call it the TV?
No,
nothing off the grid.
August we had some Ruben Ruben esque
something or other yellow dog.
It's something like that,
but I'm going to do it for now on.
I'm doing that every August.
Really?
Yeah.
I am completely shutting down.
Uh,
I'm working on this book that I started
last August and then,
and then of course the year gets so
crazy,
but I have to pick it up again in
August.
I've been writing it now while I'm on
the road.
What's the book about?
I mean,
I don't want to go too far in it,
but it in effect,
it's when I did that prager u video
about why I left the left.
That's sort of the genesis of it,
of sort of giving people a little bit of
a roadmap.
What does the prager u video,
I'm not aware of it.
So you're,
you're familiar with pay for you,
right?
Well Dennis Prager,
super conservative fellow.
Yeah.
So he does,
he has this online university where they
do these five minute cartoon videos on
different ideas and they'll do on
economics and foreign policy and race
and religion,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
And so I did one,
it was a bout a year and a half ago,
February of last year called,
well,
I had actually never said the phrase why
I left the left,
but I just talked about my frustrations
with the left and why I believe in
freedom and in liberty they titled It,
why I left the left and it's chilly.
The first,
the first half hour when it dropped,
I was pissed because I was like,
man,
did they just like blow my gig?
Like I really felt at that time,
I feel a little differently now that I
was trying to fix the left from within
or at least have conversations as
someone that was one of these people.
Like that's why I was focusing on the
left.
The all these liberals were,
were my people.
This is the thing that I grew up in.
I always believed in.
So the fact that they did that first
half hour,
I was like,
fuck,
like did I just get booted out?
And then quickly I realized that video
went,
went so viral,
it's their number one viewed video on
youtube that I was like,
you know what,
I have to just kind of embrace this.
And,
and again,
it goes back to the labels thing.
It doesn't really matter whether you
left the three,
whether you're a libertarian or
classical liberal of the rest of it.
Um,
but anyway,
that's the genesis of the book of like
just how do you escape this sort of
monolithic totalitarian thinking and how
do you just be whoever you are and how
does that,
how does being an individual basically
lead you to being happy?
Because I think that's actually the only
way that you can be happy.
I think that that's it.
You have,
you know,
it's the most cliche thing ever.
It's what Peterson's telling these
people every night,
the thousands and thousands and
thousands of people are showing up every
night and he talks about the individual,
he talks about stand up straight,
you know,
clean your room.
Like these things all sound silly at
some level and the more that I'm with
the guy,
it's like he's giving these people
saying that has just been so lost.
Like so.
Absolutely lost.
People think you can just be pathetic.
Blame the system.
Everything else.
It's somebody else's fault.
You should be given shit.
All of this stuff.
And it's like ethic about every movie,
any movie,
whatever your 10 favorite movies are.
Is it about a guy who just was like,
oh,
the world sucks and what the fuck am I
going to do on somebody?
It's somebody else's fault.
No,
every great movie,
whatever.
You guys got a problem and guess what he
does solves the problem and that's what
you're supposed to do.
And this is an adventure.
This,
this life.
But when you mean the individual like
being an individual is the only way to
be happy.
What do you mean by that?
That,
well,
first off that we should only be judged
as individuals.
That's it.
So remove all the immutable
characteristics.
I'm gay,
big dam.
What?
But you got any specific questions for
me on that big dam?
Whoop.
I was that big dam.
Right?
But like you know,
like that,
just saying that means nothing other
than you can figure out who I sleep
with.
Right,
right.
Okay.
That's it.
All we can do is judge people as
individuals and you have to just figure
out what is right for you.
So for all the people that I disagree
with that are sort of like big
government lefties and blah blah,
and I get why that unique,
maybe need a little more of that.
If you live in a big city where you
might need more noise regulations than
if you lived in the freaking,
if you live in the middle of Idaho on a
farm or whatever,
it's like if that's the life that you
want to live,
then fight for that.
But what we're doing now is this
collective is craziness,
is causing people to be unable to think
clearly.
So like Huffington post yesterday wrote
a thing about how you have to choose
between being for gay people are I said
I think it was for queer people or for
chick filet.
Now I happened to be the peers because
of Jack.
Cause Jack got in trouble or he's tweet
about chick filet and it was like you
have a tweet about chick filet.
He,
yeah,
cause he tweeted that he,
he showed like a digital receipt that he
bought chick filet and then solar.
That O'brian was like,
you tweeted that on gay pride month and
it's like endless.
But why would he tweet of a chick filet
receipt?
Who the hell knows?
The guy likes chicken fillet.
Who Cares?
We're not allowed to like it.
Yeah,
you better not like chick fil a chick
fil A.
I took a picture yesterday,
there was a chick filet next door to,
uh,
to the theater we were at.
I took a picture of chick ballet there
and I tweeted out the thing and it's
like,
I like chicken sandwiches.
Every time I've gone into a chick fil a
that people are going to find me one
fast food restaurant.
Is that so that,
so that's what he did.
Oh,
it's the cash app.
That's one of our sponsors.
You're 10% boosted.
Chick-Filet was applied.
You were charged 28 43 chick-filet ah,
he dared and leave 10% on gay pride.
He wrote boost and then he tagged
chick-filet.
Hmm.
And Soledad O'brien showed who's I
showed him who his loss.
But that's what I'm saying,
that that sort of this endless guilting
and,
and you know you do this,
so your eval it,
it's ruining the fabric of society.
It really is.
Eat Chicken.
If you like chicken,
don't eat it if you don't like it.
But that's what individualism is about.
If you want to make the choice,
if you think that whatever chick-filet
is doing to gay people,
whatever they're secretly doing,
it gave live.
You think that's so evil.
Even though,
by the way,
during the pulse nightclub shooting at
the gay club in Florida,
when 51 people were killed,
they gave free food to everybody.
But if you think they hate gay people
that much,
then don't shop there.
But you don't have to harangue everybody
else into doing everything that you want
them to do.
That's actually the reverse of freedom,
you know,
live and let live that.
That's why I believe I could see people,
if they're saying that chick filet is a
homophobic institution that that you
shouldn't endorse.
Chick-Filet is particularly if you're a
gay man,
but what does that mean?
I go into chip Jay,
not that I know of.
Okay,
so it's not that that seemed weird.
I don't like to,
I don't know either.
But he clearly is an influencer and I
think that the cash app,
if I had to gas,
because they sponsored this podcast,
they're very active in sponsoring
podcasts.
They probably have some sort of an
endorsement deal with him,
which is why he did that.
So it was a financial thing for the cash
app,
if I want to guess.
All right,
so we don't know about that
specifically,
but if they were paying him to do it,
I mean that's for him.
That's again,
that's for him as an individual to
decide,
I am going to say pride month is this
month,
this month,
this is the gay as month there is dam
and I'm here with you.
Hello.
This is the gay as they come into all of
June.
All right.
Yeah,
June.
It's very gay.
But that's what I'm saying like how many
people were upset,
how many pieces but,
but it goes exactly to where we started
with this whole thing.
There is this loud group of people and
most of them have some sort of odd
influencing media.
They're all of these blue check,
buzzfeed,
4,000 twitter follower people then
retweet all of the articles of the
people like them at Salon in box and
buzzfeed and then in that,
and they make it seem like we're all
hysterical,
crazy people.
And I simply don't believe that,
believe that most
people,
I would say the vast majority of people
probably,
I mean I think it's something crazy like
80% of people I think are good,
decent people who just want people to
live.
They want,
you can fuck who you want to fuck.
You can smoke what you want to smoke.
You can't do it on my property.
You can't take what's mine.
You can't force me to bake a cake or do
any of those things.
But you can allow people to live as they
see fit.
I think that's what most people are and
that's why there's such a push back.
That's the answer to the Peterson.
Peterson said,
I'm not going to use pronouns that the
government forces me to use.
That's all.
That's what put him on the,
that it's all sold.
I mean there's so many of them.
They got so silly with that,
that it,
it,
it made sense that someone was pushing
back to 78 different gender pronouns.
And you're obviously dealing with people
that are being silly.
This is not like there's,
it's not just people being silly.
You remember when ms came along,
there was miss and there was messages
and when was that?
What year was that?
I was a kid.
I remember being super confused.
I'm like,
dammit,
a new thing.
You know,
what's the matter?
He's the CEO of that company too.
Who Is Jack?
Yeah.
Of Cash App.
Oh,
he's the
advertising has company.
Oh,
well that makes total sense.
Makes total sense.
Yeah.
Okay.
Oh,
there you go.
Um,
I just think that,
well that's a tricky one.
That's,
that's different.
Well look,
he's a guy promoting something on one of
the things that he owns and he,
but he's doing it on gay pride month.
Who Cares?
I mean,
really like it just so,
so what is it that they,
so I guess at one point they were
against gay marriage and maybe they
still are now.
Who knows what every cut.
Think of all of us not to late CEO.
Isn't the CEO dead?
I think the CEO that was like super,
I think it is the,
the original guy in his honor.
His wishes though and keep it close on
Sunday still.
You know what?
Every time I do,
but it's fuck,
cause I want a chicken sandwich on
Sunday.
Yeah.
So somebody should be opening that.
Somebody should be opening the Sunday
chicken sandwich.
Not In pro gay,
not in June.
Solidarity to my gay brothers and
sisters.
It's all so stupid.
Eat a sandwich if you want a sandwich.
Don't,
every time I've gotten into chick ballet
when you've got it play,
are they nicer?
Not just when been there.
Literally twice.
And are they nice?
I don't remember.
They're nobody.
They're friendly.
They don't look yelled at me for things.
Okay.
Yeah.
I don't know ma'am.
I just don't think that,
uh,
I don't think there's that much outrage.
I think there's a business in outrage
though,
and there's certainly a business in a
lot of people that write these articles.
And the Jordan Peterson thing has been
very illuminating to me because I've
watched them misrepresent his positions
on so many different things and call him
so many horrible names,
transphobic,
racist,
all right.
All these different things and,
and do so with,
you know,
with no justification or
rationalization.
Like you look at the actual article and
they don't,
they don't post to what he actually
said.
It's like that woman in the,
uh,
the munk debates.
What was it called?
Oh yeah.
The monk debate.
Yeah.
Um,
whoever that woman was
Goldberg,
I think whatever.
Amen.
It was her and Eric a dyson.
Yeah.
When she said,
you know,
that he doesn't want her to,
where he doesn't think she should be
able to wear makeup at work.
And he's like,
I never said that.
Well,
you can google it.
we can.
We can google it.
We can find out.
You made me Google something that you
were wrong about.
That's,
that's upsetting to me.
I don't want you to do that.
You know,
that bothers me more than anything.
That is dishonest.
It's a hundred percent dishonest.
She knew.
He did not say that if they were,
he was having an intellectual exercise
with an interviewer and it's,
I think one of the things that's gotten
him into trouble is his openness to
discuss things with question mark.
Just bad.
I don't question marks.
I don't know.
I don't know if we can work together.
We've only been doing it for 40 years.
I don't know.
Why do women wear makeup in the
workplace?
Why do women wear short skirts and high
heels?
Why do they,
I don't think he's saying you can't do
that or you shouldn't be able to do
that.
He's saying why?
He's saying that there's obvious
realities and when you turn on CNN,
why is it that Jake Tapper,
Anderson Cooper,
Wolf Blitzer and the rest of the men are
all in suits.
They dress exactly the same.
Andersons are a little more tailored,
but everybody just say,
what are the women all wear every single
woman dresses.
They all wear dresses with cutoff
sleeves.
That right there all sprayed 10 they all
have gorgeous hair,
lipstick,
blah,
blah.
Why is it Wolf Blitzer walking in there
with the,
which we're going to have to cut off.
I would look like Netflix special.
I have a whole bit about it.
About women on Fox News versus men on
Fox who's watching it with the sound off
smoking pot.
Some sort of a wild life show.
It's something very strange.
It's a weird cultural dance that we're
doing,
right?
So the idea that Jordan's talking about
this,
that men and women dressed differently,
women put on lipstick to look tracted
why do you work out Joe Rogan?
Uh,
cause I don't tell people I don't want
to buy now be angry.
So number one,
so you don't kill people.
But number two,
you want to look good.
You want to feel good,
you want to be in a body that you want
to look good for your wife and blah,
blah,
blah.
And you want to live long like the,
to deny these realities all the time and
to think that that's because of your
toxic masculinity and all of this
nonsense.
I agree that it is a loud minority,
but what I,
what I think maybe where we're having a
little difference is that I think this
thing has spread in a way.
It is so easy to believe this nonsense,
this abject drivel that it is.
It is infecting young people at an
alarming rate.
But by the way,
there's a lot of hopeful signs on this
cause now they're doing all these
studies that the generation right after
millennials.
So the kids that are like,
you know like 15 now that they're
actually more conservative now because
they see all this as absolute hysteria.
So I think there is,
we are getting like a little bit of a
rubber band effect on this thing and I
think things are shifting into normalcy
and that's why people are listening to
your show and listening to Sam's podcast
and everything else.
I think there's an issue with people
commenting on things that other people
were saying and just sort of jumping in
and not having the other person there to
discuss these subjects
with it.
Particularly like why do women wear
makeup at work?
Why do women dress the way they dress?
I think if you sat,
if you were sitting down with Jordan
talking about it,
he's willing to engage in these subjects
with a very,
very broad canvas.
I mean,
he's willing to look at all the various
aspects of them because as a legitimate
intellectual,
that's what he's doing.
It's an intellectual exercise in
discussion of cultural norms.
Like why do women wear the shoes where
you can see their toes in the,
in the workplace.
Whereas if a guy showed up with flip
flops on,
you're like,
Mike,
the fuck we're at work here.
Get outta here with this bullshit
outfit.
Yeah,
go put on some goddamn dress shoes were
in the office.
You know,
it is strange that women were very
little close in comparison to the way
men do on these shows.
And I don't think there's anything wrong
with the discussion.
The problem is framing it as if he's
saying you shouldn't be able to,
he's,
if,
if someone got on TV and said you
shouldn't be able to wear makeup at
work,
you shouldn't be able to dress like
that,
that would be a problem.
So think about what these guys are doing
in effect.
So,
right,
so you're saying that Jordan's taking
basically a,
a decent but potentially confusing
position,
but it's,
but it's basically a right decision of
let's have a conversation.
So when they write all these hippies and
why do they do it?
Because they can't get any,
you know,
they just did release this study about
journalists and they're basically all
paid like 45 grand a year and they're
alcoholics,
you know,
just broadly speaking.
And they just want all these clicks.
They want their jobs and they realize
that these websites that are faking as
journalists,
uh,
faking as places of journalism that
they're just trying to hold onto their
jobs as long as they can.
But if you're one of these people,
what's a great way to keep your job?
Oh,
there's a guy out here who sold over a
million copies of his book who's on tour
selling out beacon theater and blah,
blah,
blah all over the world.
I'm going to write a hit piece on him
because guess what?
That's going to drive a hell of a lot
more traffic than writing something,
something honest.
So that's part of the game.
And you know,
he,
I've discussed this many times,
including onstage with him.
Why does he keep retweeting the
articles?
His belief is while I'm still here,
I'm still here.
I have exposed them and I'm still here
and if anything,
I'm bigger because of it.
And now one of them was a guy who was
his friend.
Yeah,
I know he's pissed about that one.
That was a weird one because the guy's
argument was shit.
It was like I was,
he was like,
why?
I think Jordan Peterson is dangerous.
Like dangerous.
You didn't explain dude,
why.
The problem with that is I don't give
you many chances like that if you write
something like that,
it doesn't make any sense.
Now I'm going to discredit your
opinions.
I'm not going to think about,
I'm not going to go,
Ooh,
let me listen to this intelligent
person's perspective.
I'm going to go,
oh,
this is that silly fuck that dumb idea
about Jordan Peterson.
And I feel like it was just,
it was a some sort of a rationalization
for him.
Getting attention to virtue,
signal over what Peterson is saying.
If it didn't,
he didn't have any real points.
It didn't make any sense.
I don't think I actually read that,
that full one,
but I know that I tried to go back over
it and see if I'm,
if it made any sense to me and nothing.
You got nothing that he just didn't
represent.
His opinions are accurately.
That's the problem.
When people don't represent the opinions
accurately set up a straw man and then
attack the straw man and then have this
click baity title.
I'm like,
Oh,
you just need a hug.
You need attention or is that what it
is?
You're not getting the attention.
They need a hug.
I mean,
that's what they need.
I'm telling you,
man,
th this tour,
it has been a freaking love fest.
Every night when I go up there and I'm
warming up the crowd and I'm doing silly
lobster jokes and you know,
some of his other buzz words,
and I'll talk about,
make a couple of jokes about Kathy
Newman or like some other silly things.
So we trying to say is like,
I do like a role on though is like five
different lines of like a whole bunch of
other stuff.
But like when I,
I'll go up there and I,
I usually make some reference to the
intellectual dark web.
And if I say your name or I say Shapiro
or Sam or whatever,
people go crazy.
And what's,
what I'm realizing about it is all of
these people think about all the people,
however many hundreds of thousands of
people are watching this or listening to
this right now.
And then how many millions will you know
in the next two weeks or whatever.
Most of them are doing it alone,
right?
They're watching on their phone or
they're listening on their IPAD,
whatever it is,
or you're maybe watching with your
boyfriend or girlfriend.
But most people,
it's a pretty solitary experience in
the,
in the world of what we do now imagine.
And it's like when you do stand up now,
3000 people piled into this place and
you can look around and go,
Whoa,
there's some other people like me and
they're not bad people.
And actually what I've found is that
these people look good,
they dress right.
Like I'm not to make it all about
material stuff,
but like they look like people who are
trying to get their shit together.
And I think I said it to you right
before we sat down,
but me at this moment,
I truly feel like,
like the best that I've ever been,
I really do.
And it's partly because of that because
you cannot be around that constantly.
I'm not saying everything he says is
right and I'm still not with them on
some of the religious stuff.
And I have Sam,
I'm doing my show when I leave here to
go with Sam Harris and there they,
you know,
they are really at logger heads on some
of the,
the training need.
I'm a moderator,
I swear to God.
And Sam has said this too.
I swear to God,
if I was there with the two of them,
I could worked it out when that whole
truth thing that they bounded back and
forth for an hour on the meaning of
truth.
I wish I was there and we talked about
doing some live event together.
We never got around it because Sam's
doing a lot of live events as well.
So they're doing it with their having
Bret Weinstein,
uh,
moderate it.
But I would have been thrilled if it
was,
look,
I love bread and there's nothing about
prep or would be nice like so either it
could have been one of us or or
whatever.
It's completely fine.
And I think they just wanted like a more
sciency focused person and he's a great
biologist powerhouses.
Like if there's any,
like they're doing Jujitsu on each
other.
This is any like openings and trying to
choke each other.
It's kind of,
but that's how we find out if ideas are
valid,
you know,
you'll,
you'll let guys like them discuss them.
They just,
it was very unfortunate that at least
their first part.
First one.
Yeah.
The second one I think was much better,
but the first one was just a cluster
fest.
I called Sam up afterwards.
I was like,
this is crazy.
This is a non conversation you guys.
He's like,
yeah,
I just
got stuck.
Yeah,
but think how cool that is that two of
them are.
The two of them are some of our leading
public intellectuals in the country,
in the world,
probably [inaudible].
They're debating over the nature of
truth and millions of people care.
That's a little different than what's
going on on CNN on any given day.
Oh,
for sure.
Well,
there's a real problem with mainstream
news and first of all,
there's a problem in that it's a ratings
driven thing.
It's like everything they're doing,
they're trying to get ratings.
Anytime there's a big story in the news,
it's just like,
what is it?
What are people going to pay attention
to?
That's what we're going to put on.
There's no consideration.
Like,
is this interesting to us?
Is this what we want to discuss?
It's,
it's a news program,
but it's not a news program because it's
also in an entertainment program and
then they have commercials every 15
minutes.
Did you say that Jim Acosta thing?
What he did during the,
during the Korea thing like that is
crazy.
That's crazy that a journalist would
insert himself into that sort of a
situation and interrupt and yell things
out and people don't have a problem with
that.
We are,
we are truly watching the implosion of
the media and that's why I meant before,
it's like if they would just lie a
little bit,
well just lie a little bit on the
margins as they probably always have
done.
I don't think we'd be in this position
because people wouldn't be able to so
clearly see how messed up the whole
thing is.
But because they've become so hysterical
writing articles that are completely the
reverse of the truth,
because they're actually acting like
petulant children all the time and
because they,
half the time it's like they pretend
they're nonpartisan,
but if you just look at any of these
journalists,
twitter feeds,
it's like pretty obvious what you all
are.
All of you in the mainstream media,
they've created an opening so that now
if people want some sense of truth,
you turn into Joe Rogan and you're
turning to all of these other shows.
I think it's very difficult to get
employment if you're not on one side of
the fence or the other side of the fence
and you're a journalist.
It's not,
it's,
it's not a simple world like the world
of podcasting where you truly can be
independent.
Yeah,
and I mean I think,
I think in a lot of ways it's like
Hollywood.
I mean I've always described Hollywood
is one of the main problems with it.
As you get a bunch of people that come
here seeking attention,
right?
That's the reason why they are here in
the first place.
They want fame,
they want exorbitant amounts of
attention.
And then on top of that,
you are entered into this system where
you have to be chosen for each part.
It's not like you can,
like you have a sprint and the the guy
who's the fastest is the one who wins.
Yeah,
it does not like that.
It's someone's who smelled.
Dave,
why don't you read these lines like,
hmm,
I might like you dave.
How do you feel about Hillary Clinton?
Because I'm pro Clinton.
I mean,
we want Clinton to win.
Don't we want Clinton to win Dave?
And you're like,
oh my God.
Yeah,
you'll drop your standards are like,
I'm,
I'm a huge supporter of Clinton.
I think she's amazing.
And I've seen this because you're,
you're,
it's this weird environment where you
want these people to like you.
So you are terrified of saying anything
even remotely controversial that doesn't
stick to the script of this left wing
discourse.
So there's all these people that are
just,
just faking it.
They're bullshitting you if they didn't
mind,
not even have real opinions,
but they've adopted this predetermined
pattern of opinions that they think that
is going to help them get through the
door with these producers and these
studio executives.
And that's Hollywood.
And then when someone breaks free and
you know,
the,
occasionally someone becomes right wing,
you know,
whoever the fuck they are with,
it's chuck woolery or Dennis Miller,
or they'll like,
look at that fucking crazy man probe
from the pack.
You know,
look at what's,
what's his name,
the fucking actor guy.
The older guy,
Jon Voight,
not Jon voight,
the other one.
A very good actor.
Gary sinise got a bigger deck,
supposedly got in trouble with Dave
crosses a wife.
He said like Dave Cross's wife said that
he tried to hit on her when she was 16.
James Woods.
Yeah.
He's,
he's really dealt himself.
He's got a giant deck.
Yeah,
that's what I hear.
Uh,
yeah,
he's dealt himself in.
He's all in.
He's all in and he's like sort of like
resigned himself to never work again.
Yeah.
I mean it means,
but he's probably like 75 years old or
whatever he is.
He's probably,
I don't give a fuck anymore.
Yeah.
I mean I'm pretty sure he's got fuck you
money like probably,
yeah,
it's definitely saying fuck you.
So if he doesn't have the money that he
might want to send their data.
Yeah,
exactly.
But doesn't that prove though why doing
this was the right thing to do?
Because I'm very aware right now.
It's like I got a lot of good shit going
on.
I'm getting offers and all sorts of
different things and I'm like,
I,
I'm my own boss.
I'm not going to fire me.
I'm not going to accidentally tweet
something one day and then go with that.
I'm going to fire day Ruben.
Like,
you know,
like my,
my fans fund most of what we do and it's
like I need to grow.
Like we definitely need to grow because
there's,
we're just,
my guys are just doing too much.
But I'm also very aware that the more we
start growing that,
all the problems that you just laid out,
we'll start becoming more and more real.
So I like being as slim and trim as
possible,
at least for now because I don't want to
be down the road where we've had,
we got too many people.
There's too many just different
competing interests and business
interests and political interests and
everything else.
So it's like,
that's why,
I mean you're what you're doing here,
it's freaking,
it's amazing man.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
it's nice to be able to do it for sure.
It's nice to be able to just have
opinions on things and,
and,
and also just know that you're a nice
person and that you're not trying to,
like,
I'm not trying to do any evil.
Like I'm in a,
I'm,
I like,
I look at like who I am.
Like I'm a nice guy.
Like,
okay,
all right,
well what are my opinions of,
why can't I talk to this guy?
Why can I have,
what can I have discussions in these
subjects?
You know,
like there's a lot of people that feel
like if you're not in a certain group,
you shouldn't have discussions on
certain things.
If you're a straight man,
you shouldn't talk about gay rights.
If you're a man,
you shouldn't talk about women's issues.
You shouldn't talk about me too.
Unless you're 100% supportive.
You shouldn't discuss the subtle nuance
of human interaction.
Well,
it didn't.
Martin Luther King,
he wanted us to be judged by those
things.
Right.
And he said,
if you're only this color,
you can talk about that.
I'm pretty sure that's what he said.
Yeah,
that's where we're at.
But also,
you know,
there was an article right after that
idw thing came out in the times that was
calling you a conservative.
And I think,
I,
I think I emailed it to you,
man.
It was the twitter thing.
The renegade conservative,
that's what it was.
Pro Gay rights.
Pro Women's rights.
Pro choice pro marijuana,
pro universal health care pro universal
basic income.
Like what else do I have to do?
Like what other things am I,
oh,
pro second amendment.
He must be right one.
Yeah.
Well,
Joe,
you're off.
You can't just have you,
what do you think?
You can have a series of thoughts that
don't all lock in with what you have to
be in a pattern that you have to be in
the pattern.
I'm not just don't understand why
someone's willing to be dishonest like
that.
Like a cursory examination of people's
thoughts and positions on things would
lead someone to realize I'm definitely
not a right wing person,
but,
but the thing is that they own the
narrative for so long and that they can
still get away with it.
Yes,
yes.
And what's happening is now it's
shifting and that's what I mean by I
think we're starting to win.
And I don't mean it when like we're
going to destroy these people.
I mean,
I think the narrative has started to
shift a little bit where the enthusiasm
behind the conversations that we're all
having,
whoever it is in this thing,
the enthusiasm is so great and there is
no counter enthusiasts.
Like where are all the versions of us on
the other side of this?
I'm a bright,
no,
I don't even mean on the right,
like the people that really are selling
identity politics had a really great way
at a comedy level who have a huge
podcast and like where is the,
where is that intellectual set of
people?
Where's the Sam Harris of the other side
of this or the that have real
followings.
They don't exist and that's partly why
the hysteria has been ramped up.
They can't believe that out of nowhere,
just because of our,
all of our just wherewithal and desire
to do what we think is right or what
makes us happy or whatever the hell you
want to call it.
They can't believe we all freaking
created something.
Well,
the queer shout that we're all in a
group,
I'm weirded out that we're in a super
boy band.
We're in a boy band or I guess Christina
Hoff Summers.
Isn't that band too?
Who else is in that band?
Is Heather in it?
Yeah,
it has it in hang a sheet in there.
I mean it looks,
we don't have to Brett,
but you didn't get the car yet and then
get the card.
The clubhouse is under your studio.
Man.
Shapiro with joking around about it,
but like we're like the super friends,
like what is this?
This is the weirdest avengers ever.
It's a weird group of humans.
I mean me and Ben,
we disagree on a lot of shit,
but we're super friendly to each other.
Like when I do his show or he does my,
I really enjoy that guy like him.
You do freaking Shapiro show before my
show what?
Sorry.
What?
The guys had a shelf for three weeks.
People were mad at me with the way I
dressed.
See that.
They're like,
everybody else is wearing a nice shirt
at a time.
Like,
listen man,
I told the guy I was on my way to the
comedy store.
You want to take a photo of me?
I'll be there.
You're not in the bush.
In the brush.
Yeah.
I should be in a bush.
I everybody down sucking it up my ass.
I'm wearing a fucking chucks or converse
and a some sort of a flannel shirt that
I bought that jacket Alaska.
I've just,
that's how it was where I just,
what I was wearing at the comedy store.
I said,
all right man,
that's what I'm wearing.
No greenery around.
The comedy store could go up to sunset,
but either way I just don't,
I don't give a fuck.
That's what I looked like.
That's who I am.
I'm not interested in portraying an
image.
Just it is what it is.
You know?
It's like this,
this intellectual dark web like it's
fucking Eric.
He's crazy and he's,
he gets mad when I call him crazy.
He loves it.
He's trying to get me to,
are you on the whatsapp?
Oh,
I'm on the one hand.
The little fucking check group.
No,
I haven't jumped in yet.
I've been busy.
I don't have the time.
Just two or three messages a day for
different group text conversations with
comedians were talking shit about things
and talking around.
I don't have time for this.
I'm busy,
man.
All right,
well then you can't come to the club
trying to make a yoga class.
I don't know.
Fucking time.
Yeah.
Who the hell goes like are we a group
that we do,
we have a meeting and shall act cards
and like we have in common.
I think we have a respect for our
audience and intellectual curiosity.
Curiosity for sure.
Yeah.
And I think that's where,
that's where a guy like me and Shapiro,
although we have very different opinions
on many different things,
you know,
I think we both are intellectually
curious.
Yeah.
So think about it.
I've had been on many times,
I consider him a friend.
We've,
we've broke bread together,
although he's kosher,
which makes it fucking pain.
What do you have to eat?
Has such a smart guy.
Follow that blue,
do well.
I eat whatever the hell it to him about
whatever I want.
But he usually brings something or you
know,
has to watch.
You did a kosher restaurant.
I did eat at a kosher restaurant with
him once,
but then it was all these orthodox Jews
there and then they treat him like
Jesus.
And I was like,
dude,
I'm not a photographer.
You know what I mean?
I have to take all these pictures of
him.
And they're like,
who's that guy?
I was like,
I'm not doing that again,
but it's funny,
but you know,
I've had Shapiro and look,
he's not inherently for gay marriage,
right?
I've had my studio is in my house where
I knew what his thoughts on gay
marriage.
Well,
now he takes the Libertarian position
at,
which is the government shouldn't be
involved,
but I don't know.
But I see a lot of conservatives doing
that where they should have all,
like,
this is where Rand Paul Lynn mentioned
before,
he should have been years ago screaming
that he's for gay marriage because if
you're truly a libertarian,
the government doesn't delaminate the
smoke was sleep with the libertarians.
She could have taken a really awesome,
powerful,
principled position and said,
this isn't about religion.
It's not about,
it's about freedom.
It's one of the things that a shove in
the face of people that were Hillary
Clinton supporters and my,
do you know that she didn't support gay
marriage?
She'll 2013 you know,
goddamn crazy.
It is.
I supported it when I was 13 this
fucking grown up old lady with
grandchildren.
Yeah.
Is Talent people that she's not for gay
marriage until it became convenient
politically and she just wanted to
separate herself as being at least the
semi conservative option compared to
Barack Obama.
Look,
Barack Obama was not for gay marriage at
the beginning.
He got pinned into it.
Biden made that stupid
comment on meet the press where he was
basically like,
everyone's forward and then Obama had to
come out for it.
But think about it.
If,
if all of this stuff that we're talking
about keeps winning,
if it all keeps winning,
what will happen in 50 years,
they will literally look back at video
of Barack Obama campaigning the first
time around saying that he's for
traditional marriage and they will call
Barack Obama a homophobe and they will
eventually want them.
They will want the Barack Obama library
that's being built now in Chicago.
They will want that being taken down
because that will be the,
that will be the statues of our day.
So that that's why I don't know where
you're at on the monument stuff,
but I would not take any of them down.
You can put up a counselor plaque or
something right next to it to say Robert
E.
Lee did this or that,
but the idea that they're removing the
shit I think is absolutely terrible.
You can't erase history.
No,
I agree with you.
I think they should.
This is a problem with having them in
town squares and celebrating them,
but there's also a problem that they
were all,
most of them,
the ones that you're there,
they're talking about in the south.
They were resurrected during the civil
rights movement to sort of counteract
the civil rights movement.
So like these,
these are really,
this is not like a celebration of these
people back in the day when they were a
viable,
this is during the civil rights
movement.
They erected these fairly cheap and they
put them up quickly and they did it in
response to black people wanting more
rights and you know,
they would still,
I would still face,
yeah,
I get it.
I would still be not for taking them
down.
You put up something next to it,
you put it,
you see what I would you want to come?
I'm for taking it down and replacing
them with something else and putting
them somewhere else.
Like if you want to have a civil war
museum.
So that would be the compromise where
you could get me,
I'm not saying you should melt them,
but it's,
there's something too,
there's something to the argument that
they're racist statues and especially if
you understand the motivation behind
creating them in the first place.
Yeah.
The problem though is that,
you know,
I mean,
I know you know this,
it never ends where it's supposed to
end,
wanted to go after George Washington and
trump said they did.
Trump said that and people were riddick
ridiculing him.
And then almost immediately afterwards,
someone wanted to take down a statue of
George Wallace.
I was in old town Alexandria where
George Washington's Church was,
and it's actually the same church that
Robert E.
Lee went to.
So they had a plaque for both of them.
And because they took down the Robert E.
Lee One,
they also took down the George
Washington one at the church that George
Washington went to.
I mean,
if you follow that logic,
and this is what you have to do when
you're,
when you're doing these sort of
historical trackings,
they will come for everything.
So think about it.
Thomas Jefferson's my favorite founder,
Thomas Jefferson.
You can go to his house in Monte Cello
and they do,
if you go on the tour,
it's incredible.
They are incredibly honest about his
relationship to slavery,
that he owned slaves his whole life.
He was having an affair with at least
one slave and most likely had children
with that slave.
At the same time he was writing the laws
that freed the slaves.
So without this man,
these things don't move forward.
So we all live with these odd in
consistencies.
George Washington,
who gave up power after the,
after the revolution,
like he did the most incredible thing.
You know,
he a power as the commander
of the army after the revolution,
the most incredible thing that a leader
of a country could do.
He owned slaves his entire life when he
died and this,
they do this at his house in,
um,
it's out.
It's outside DC.
I'm blanking on it for a second.
I'll get in a second.
But you can go on the tour there.
And he had his slaves his entire life.
When he died,
his half of the slaves got freed.
But Martha Washington's half didn't,
Martha kept a slot that kept this bitch.
Yeah.
So it's like all of these things,
it's like so surely had half the slaves
were kind of inherited them I think from
her parents or something like that.
Like it's all,
it's deeply twisted and warped.
And of course it was.
Now of course we can objectively look at
it and go,
slavery was wrong and you shouldn't of
course.
But they all were doing things in their
time that you'd,
the world doesn't magically become what
you want it to be just because you exist
and think something.
And the more that we start thinking
that,
the more we'll eventually come after
Obama for running against gay marriage
the first time and,
and all of these things.
There is something that we think you
love meat,
right?
You love elk and all this other stuff.
Guess what?
One day,
if this craziness keeps going,
they will look back when you're
grandfather and there'll be like date
meet because we're at that point we'll
be eating,
you know,
artificially produced whatever.
And they'll,
they'll literally watch videos of you
chomping on,
you know,
some ribs and go see what a savage he
was.
So that's why you have to just be aware
of what your time is.
Your time in this world.
Yeah.
They're doing it right now.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Um,
did you ever see the video of Obama
talking about illegal immigration?
It's incredible.
It's really amazing.
It's when he was a senator and running
for president the first time.
And he is more like,
he's stricter than,
than trump.
Yes.
I mean it's a fascinating thing because
no one brings that up and no one called
him braced.
But I guess we're dealing with a long
time ago,
you know,
I mean,
there's a couple of things.
He was,
it was a 2011 it was doing that.
He was a senator,
so it was probably around 2010,
2011,
something like that.
I mean,
look,
there's a lot of things there,
right?
He,
I mean,
he's black number one.
So it's like they're not going to call
him racist.
It doesn't,
it creates a thing where they can't
compute.
What does that actually mean?
He was saying the things that people
wanted to hear.
He also wanted it to be elected.
He wanted to be elected.
So they elevated him to a point that he
was God play that he was pulseless
listened to this 2005,
2005.
Yeah,
it says early.
Oh,
so he's on the need to better secure the
border and a punish employers who chose
to hire illegal immigrants.
Uh,
you know,
we are a generous and welcoming people
here in the United States,
but those who enter the country
illegally and those who employ them
disrespect the rule of law.
Uh,
and they are showing disregard for those
who are following the law.
We simply cannot allow people to pour
into the United States undetected,
undocumented,
unchecked and circumventing the line of
people who are waiting
patiently,
diligently,
and lawfully,
uh,
to become immigrants in this country.
So that's why we need to start by giving
agencies charged with border security,
new technology,
new facilities,
and more people to stop the process and
deport illegal immigrants.
Having said that,
securing the borders alone does not
solve immigration management.
We're going to have to better manage
legal immigration in order to end
illegal immigration.
Uh,
senators,
mccain and Kennedy point us in the right
direction on that point right now we've
got millions of illegal immigrants who
live and work here without knowing their
identity or background.
That's part of the reason that we need a
guest worker program to replace the
flood of illegals with a regulated
stream of legals who enter the United
States after checks and with access to
labor rights.
Part of the reason that illegal
immigration is so damaging is that it
ends up creating a pool of workers with
depressed wages and no rights.
And that's not something that we find
acceptable.
It's crazy dude.
American employers also need to take
responsibility.
Yeah,
I mean I just scribbled down like I was
doing homework in seventh grade and
think about what he said there.
We have to secure the border,
secure the border trunk,
secure the border,
punish you if you hire,
if you hire illegal workers,
if you,
if you enter illegally,
you're showing disregard for our laws.
You,
we cannot allow illegals to pour in.
Uh,
we can't let them go ahead of lawful
people who are trying to enter the
country.
We need better border security,
more pr,
more process and deportations.
Uh,
we have to better manage legal
immigration.
And then he talked about the millions
that are here now,
which in effect is a pathway to
citizenship,
which by the way,
trump is basically four at some level.
So it's like,
so what are we really talking about?
Every time we scream that everybody is
racist?
It did.
He just make a wild what,
sorry.
I assume he's talking about Latino
people.
So as Barack Obama racist against Latino
Well this was when he was a senator
Ellis.
Like he was elected in 2008 and so he
was probably gearing up to run when he
was in 2005 the things that he was
saying,
he was letting people know who he is and
that he's out there and starting the
ball rolling.
You know this a different time to 2005
was just a different world and it seems
like it shouldn't be because it was only
13 years ago,
but God damn is it different?
So what does that say then?
What,
what does that actually say about the
way things have changed or the cult of
personality around trump or just sort of
the general derangement of the media
that they can't view these things.
It's not just a media.
I think it's also people's access to
communication.
The fact that anyone can voice their
opinion,
whether it's on facebook or youtube or
what have you,
you know,
it's,
it's a different world.
Twitter,
you can just,
you can just tweet instantaneously.
This is fucking bullshit.
You know,
people should be able to whatever they
want or whatever,
you know,
whatever you want to say.
And then a bunch of people can agree or
disagree or retweeted or do you know or
or or screen grab it because they think
that it's damaging to you and they put
a,
can't believe you support this piece of
shit and think about it.
You can wake up on any given morning,
find someone you've never heard of who
said something you slightly disagree
with and you can help get them fired.
That's a lot of,
there's a lot of people want to do that
too,
which is really interesting that people
want to get people fired for opinions.
Does that doesn't make a lot of sense to
me,
but really if we were to do a deep dive
on that,
it's like,
well what did we just hear that is
different than what trump is trying to
do right now?
Does trump you sloppy language?
Yes.
Does trump lie?
Yes,
but they all lie.
Obama,
if you like your doctor,
you can keep your doctor lie Siri or red
line the lie.
Those are pretty big lies that he did
not as trump lie about everything
constantly.
Yes,
but what he has a way of doing is
getting these odd big picture things
correct.
And then it causes this.
So like almost anything.
So like they'll say you okay.
You know,
just in the last couple of days with
North Korea that trump said,
um,
I've been traveling a lot.
So like getting the exact quote,
it'll be tough,
but it'll be something like,
um,
you know,
trump said to the North Korean dictator
that they are,
that they're good friends now or
something like that.
Like he's already giving him respect.
Well,
it's like if Obama,
Obama,
when Obama ran,
he said he would sit down with aqua,
Diana died and he would sit down with
the leaders in North Korea and the rest
of those things.
Now trump is doing it.
So it's like,
do you want him to sit down with them
and tell him to go fuck himself at the
same time?
Like I'm not even saying this things
good or bad.
I have no freaking clue.
Nobody has a clue.
But everyone has every opinion on
everything.
Well,
people want them to fail too,
which is fascinating to me because you
see the Bill Maher side?
No.
So Bill Maher on Bill Maher on Friday.
He said that he's hoping for a recession
because that's how we'll get rid of
trump.
Now.
We talked a little bit about bill before
this thing,
but like,
oh my God,
he's been a huge influence of mine.
I like him.
I used to want to be on the show.
I've kind of moved past that at this
point,
but think about it,
you know,
Bill is probably worth a hundred million
bucks or something.
I have no idea,
but like he can afford living through a
recession,
but when people talk about the liberal
elite that they hate,
it's that type of person.
It's this person on the coast who's
like,
yeah,
have a recession so we can get rid of
trump.
I hope he does amazingly well.
I agree.
I hope trump does amazing the well in
terms of country when I hope he evolves
his ideas as a human being.
I hope he does.
Mushrooms
grows to love people.
Why would you hope for failure?
Especially failure for the whole country
and sending people into a recession,
which is undoubtedly going to cause
suicides and turmoil and crisis,
and people are going to go into panic
thinking and panic voting,
which is not what you want.
I mean,
literally that's what started Hitler.
I mean that,
that,
that's what started Nazi Germany,
right?
They were in the middle of a horrible
recession and this guy came along that
proposed a solution.
You're not going to get a better version
of the future by people living in fear
and poverty and sadness.
Like
I as
I didn't vote for trump,
but he's the president I want him to do
great.
I don't agree with him on a lot of shit.
He lies about a lot of shit.
Yeah.
Still want them to do great.
You know why?
Because he is the guy that's running the
country visa running the country.
I want the country to do well no matter
who's running it like that.
My,
my thought was like this,
this is almost what it's like.
It's like,
I don't like this doctor,
so when he fixes my knee,
I hope you box it up.
Right.
That's it.
It's really almost what it's like.
It's like he's the God damn president.
Okay.
If you want him to be in peach,
because he's done some fucking horrible
crime,
which I still,
I've gone over all this Russian stuff.
I still am not convinced that he did
anything horrible.
I don't see,
it seems like the Democrats did more
horrible things.
Definitely aiming caught on something.
They definitely did something.
And just what they did to Bernie Sanders
alone should be a devastating blow to
the credibility of the DNC.
It really should.
Yeah.
And the fact that it's not,
it's just,
it's just blind allegiance and that he
could say,
I hope for a recession.
Maybe he said that without thinking,
you know,
maybe it was just a flipping remark or,
I'm pretty sure it was a,
it was a package line.
Never hope for a recession,
no matter what.
I would hope the guy does fantastic.
Even if he's hated across the board.
I hope he does an amazing job.
And I hope the economy sores and I hope
people have more jobs,
more.
I hope there's a method to his madness.
I really do.
Why would anybody hope differently?
I don't understand.
Well,
I agree with that and basically,
and again,
I voted for Gary Johnson.
Look,
if I had my choice,
I'm pretty sure you know me well enough.
Like I would much rather have like a
really bright intellectual person who
I'd rather have randon I,
yeah,
I'd much rather have rand Paul.
I'd rather have a libertarian who
basically is kicking everything back to
the states.
But you know what?
Trump is cutting a ton of regulation and
doing a lot of states rights stuff.
The economy's doing really well.
Do you have any sense that we're going
to get into something tractable war in
the Middle East to nation build?
I don't think under his watch there may
be some level of some peace now in the
North Korean Peninsula.
So it's like thing,
man,
I don't think anybody else would have
done what he did with North Korea.
So talked to a bunch of shit to that
guy.
I'm going to call him fat short.
And you know,
like it was very funny.
Like what he does is kind of funny and
then he gets to have a meeting with the
guy and the guy agrees to a meeting with
it.
I think they're baffled by him.
They don't know what to do with him.
North Korea and South Korea,
when the presidents of the two countries
met at the DMZ and shook hands like that
was an historic moment.
Like maybe they can get past all this
fucking bullshit that's been going on
forever.
And if part of that was helped in some
way by trump being crazy,
like maybe it's good to have someone
that fucks things up a little bit and
mixes it up.
It doesn't mean he's a perfect person.
It doesn't mean he's not a liar,
right wing conservative neocon Joe
Rogan,
but Nigga about it.
So they'd be like,
what does he do?
So he brings in John Bolton,
who's thought of as a neo-con,
like a warmonger Neil Kahn,
and then he has madison as the secretary
of defense.
Warmonger neo-con maybe what he was
doing is that he was scaring people from
the get go.
And I'm going to bring
in all these people who are really
scary,
who don't talk about peace that often,
who don't,
who talk about exercising our power and
all of that stuff so that Kim Jong Un is
going to go,
hmm maybe this time they are actually
being,
they might actually depose me cause I
don't.
Yeah,
he's looking at the trump is like this
guy's fucking crazy.
And by the way,
this is where I would say my,
my side in this,
the libertarian side is pretty weak on
this cause a guy like ran Paul.
What he would say is,
you know,
we should be cutting all military and
never doing anything about law,
in which case you can make a strong
argument that you're constantly
emboldening your enemies all the time
because if they know you never want to
do anything,
then it's not a great argument to get
bad actors to stop doing things.
But I think that's a great place to have
a,
a good conversation.
And Rand Paul is supported a lot of this
stuff trump has done at the same time.
Yeah.
Um,
I'm gonna just,
I just don't understand the logic behind
wanting a recession when I can
understand the logic around wanting
someone else to take over in two years
or three years when the new elections
take place.
But,
but don't you think things are basically
going pretty well right now?
Like if you remove the twitter hysteria,
like remove just like hysteria,
stuff like this.
He said,
she said like in terms of what's
happening in the country right now,
black and Latino unemployment all time
low economies chugging along,
um,
like the basic things that matter for a
society are working.
That's pretty good,
right?
It's now really good.
I don't know enough about this,
but what I've understood what I've,
what's been explained to me is that a
lot of this is the momentum of what
Obama did when he was in office and that
the economy,
he's riding the work of Obama,
there's riding the wave of the previous
administration's policies.
So I've,
I've,
yeah,
I've had a economists on my show argued
kind of both sides of this thing.
Most don't agree with that,
but I've had probably more libertarian
leaning economist in general.
Well because they're all about cutting
regulation all the time and trump has
been very good at that.
I think it's something like,
at one point it was like for every 63
um,
or for every one regulation he passed,
he cuts something like 63 regulations.
So if you're a libertarian economic
economist or someone on the right
economically you want the government out
of all of that stuff.
So they're very happy at the,
at the economic level right now.
But all right.
But let's even say that's completely
true what you just said there,
that this is all just because of Obama
stuff.
Well,
it's working.
Like we've got a guy that maybe has just
picked up the ball and he's the lucky
guy and maybe he's going to get it to
the next thing.
But what I'm actually more enthused by
is that I think after all this craziness
that we're in right now,
I actually think people are so starved
for sanity and like a reset to decency.
I actually think things are going to get
much better.
I think again,
this is where I think the conversations
that we're all having or are affecting
things in a big way and I think that
even politically it's going to start
bubbling up.
I when I was in DC the other day,
I was at a small dinner with a pretty
influential senator who probably doesn't
want me to say his name is not going to
say it but I'll tell it to you later.
But on the river somebody,
it was somebody big and he got it.
He,
he really got it like he knew about us
like this whole thing and that's what
I'm saying like I'm not sitting here
like,
oh my God,
it's so amazing what we're doing.
But there something,
there is something happening and I think
it will reach the political level too,
that people will not want the hysteria
anymore and that eventually trump will,
because of his own craziness,
become unnecessary.
You won't always need the icebreaker.
We needed the icebreaker to get all this
shit out.
Now it's all out.
Everyone's reevaluating everything and
then out of that is going to grow.
I mean,
look,
maybe it grows something horrible,
right?
Like maybe the Hitler comes.
I don't think,
I obviously hope it doesn't happen,
but what I think is that something
decent is going to come that that's
just,
that's just her.
Something decent is going to come on.
I think there is,
there's a lot of decent that's coming
right now,
but I think there's some people that are
always going to resist that.
Oh,
of course.
People that are just ideologically
driven and they can't be shaken from
the,
they can't be shook from that position.
They just,
they're hard left or they're hard ride
or whatever they are.
They have this rigid idea in their head
of what reality is and anything that's
contrary to that,
they're going to oppose.
And I think Jordan has been one of my
favorite lightning rods for observation
for watching this because all the
disingenuous articles about him
deceptive,
talking about his positions and an
extremely inaccurate ways and labeling
him as some sort of a prejudice,
terrible person.
What those have done is solidified this
idea that there is a campaign of people
that just are completely ideologically
driven and they don't mind being
deceptive.
And that strengthens the puzzle.
It helps people like us that just talk
about stuff and don't mind talking about
being incorrect or ignorant or not
worried.
We're not worried about our stance.
We just,
we're,
we're going about most conversations
from a place of objectivity if it as
much as we possibly can.
Most people are subjective at least to a
certain extent,
as much objectivity as we can,
as much honesty as we can.
And just talking about things.
And this is,
um,
this is something that's not happening
in these little click baity articles or
in people that interrupt your shows and
shake fucking jars and Nicole's or
whatever they're doing.
It's like there's that,
all that stuff's strengthens this
position that we're in,
that we're in this weird time of
intellectual dishonesty and turmoil.
And I think a lot of it is because
there's a lot of people that were just
extremely upset that trump got into
office and anything that seems to
represent that position or that side
must be opposed violence.
Yeah.
So I think underneath everything you're
saying,
the right there,
you're very hopeful right now.
I actually sense that you're really
hopeful.
And I am too.
And it's like,
how could we ever do this if we weren't
right?
Like I,
I would say that I'm a,
if I had to like sort of widdle it down
what I am at,
at the core,
I basically,
I'm a world weary optimist.
I'm an optimist by nature.
But I believe that the world,
the world is rough and tumble and all
the things that Jordan would say about
existence,
I believe.
But I'm still an optimist.
Despite that and what you just said,
right there basically is showing that
the trump thing was necessary because
imagine if hillary was president right
now in the same machine and bullshit and
nonsense and media and all of that stuff
kept churning along.
Think how much worse it would be for
these conversations right now we would
so beyond the wrongs,
you know the wrong side of things so to
speak,
and the forces that don't want us to do
anything good and have conversations
would have been so emboldened.
Trump just came and took a freaking bat
to the whole thing.
Now,
as I discussed with Eric Weinstein,
it's like trump was the bull in the
China shop.
I think most of us would have preferred
a panther wait,
like we kind of wanted something to walk
through,
knock a few things off.
Trump just blew up the whole thing.
You don't the phrases bull in a China
shop,
not a panther in a China shop.
That's right.
So that's what you get.
But after this,
for every reason you just said there is
going to be a return to sanity.
It.
It goes one of two ways,
but I,
I just am a firm believer that it will
go that way,
that there is enough of us out there now
trying to reset things and because I
don't think people are evil.
I don't think people want to be talked
down to.
I don't think people are dumb and even
the people who are dumb,
I don't think they want to be dumb and
because of all of that,
I think this was the necessary thing to
happen right now.
I'm with you that I think,
I hope that he continues to do basically
good things and that if that means that
he gets in for another four years and
continues to do good things then so be
it.
But yes,
would I prefer that it's sort of more of
a small government calm person who could
tell you how many branches of government
there are and like all of that shit and
all of the stuff from that flag that's
right behind you.
Yeah.
I've got a freaking declaration of
independence in our control room and a
constitution and a big American flag.
Like,
would I rather someone who knew what the
federalist papers are and all of those
things be in the Oval Office?
Yes.
You don't get everything you want in
life,
so you just kind of work with what comes
and I think we can,
we have a little room to work right now.
I think
also as more people open themselves up
to the ideas that Jordan is espousing or
you are,
I am or more people are genuinely
objective about these ideas and start
discussing them.
The more frantic the people on the
radical left in the the,
what would they call the regressive
left,
the more ridiculous they're going to get
and the more obvious it's going to get
that they're out of control.
It's just what happens.
People Start Ranting and screaming
louder because the,
their initial meshes doesn't work.
It's not like they're going to go back
and revamp the message and make it more
logical.
There's no logical message there,
but think about that.
So when that's exactly what they're
doing with trump too.
You keep screaming trump's Hitler,
right?
He keeps screaming,
trump's Hitler,
Hitler,
Hitler.
Now,
Hitler killed millions and millions of
people in many more millions were killed
because of Hitler that he didn't
directly kill.
Now,
if you keep doing that with trump,
and then someone plays that Barack Obama
clip and you go,
wait,
whoa,
Whoa,
you're calling trump Hitler.
Here's Obama saying something that
actually sounds possibly even more
extreme.
If you believe this is an extreme
position to take.
So now is,
is Obama Hiller.
And what they're doing is they're
creating a situation where they're going
to cause a rebound so that people will
be like,
oh,
these guys aren't all nuts.
But if they,
if they destroy all of our ability to
have this conversation,
then when the real Hitler comes in,
we won't even be able to recognize it
because they will have cried wolf to the
point that someone's going to come in
and they're gonna have a big smile.
It won't be a trump win when Hitler,
the Hitler type,
and I hate using Hitler as the,
as the metaphor,
cause it's so overplayed.
But like when the Hitler type comes,
it ain't come in as the angry guy like
trump is.
It's going to come with a smile on its
face,
right?
That's that socialist tee shirt like you
know,
socialism,
Smiley face.
That's how it will come because it will
be masked in identity politics.
It will be masked in all of this
nonsense that will rip us apart.
That will literally have us killing each
other on the streets.
What do you think would cause a,
what scenario do you foresee?
There could be possibly if the extreme,
the ideas of what I consider the fringe
left,
which are pretty much mainstream
Democrat ideas already.
If the Democrats keep going more towards
the Bernie,
Elizabeth Warren,
Keith Ellison,
real hard left progressive stuff.
It is rooted in identity politics,
which I,
you know we've done already but like it
is rooted in something that separates
us.
It is rooted that you should that even
today.
Did you see this,
that Harvard,
I just tweeted out when I was on the way
here,
Harvard released this statement of
defending the fact that they are okay
with basically having quotas that work
against Asian students because they want
to have more other minorities basically
meaning black or Hispanic minorities.
So think about it.
Why would you discriminate if you are
hiring right now,
let's say you're hiring today,
right?
You're hiring for your studio,
you can hire,
you can hire the most qualified person.
Are you going to try to figure out every
little identity thing to figure out who
you should hire?
Diversity,
Bro,
I'm all about diversity.
Exactly.
You'd hire,
it's racist against Asians.
Just haven't been very vocal about it
cause they,
they tend to just put their fucking nose
to the grindstone and keep ticking out
so they have to use that against them.
Now that works so that that's the new
thing.
You will not be a,
if you're Asian and you,
and why did they,
why did Asian Americans are Indian
Americans are a great example that they
have succeeded at every level that we
measure success.
I think the highest socioeconomic
average salary over a hundred grand and
no education,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
If you now say,
well wait a minute,
these people played by the rules,
they came here as it most,
you know,
like,
like all of our ancestors virtually came
here pretty much with nothing.
People on small businesses busted their
ass,
worked in coal mines,
it's said wherever you had to do it,
if you do all of those things and then
you focus on education and on family and
all of those things.
And now the system is going to say,
well it worked for a while,
but we're going to have to put you at
the bottom of the thing now.
And you guess what?
You're not going to get into Harvard
because you're Asian.
That is racism.
So I've been calling this out for at
least two years that the next move by
this identity politics,
this evil oppression Olympics machine is
that they will come after Asian people
and it's starting to happen now.
So I see all these minorities,
by the way.
So candace,
who,
I watched the show and I know you guys
definitely have disagreements on stuff
as do I do when it comes not only to
politics but tactics sometimes and
stuff,
but I really do like her.
Um,
you know,
look,
she's causing a massive rift in the
black community and you can see it in
the numbers.
Black male support for trump or for
trump?
Doubled it was at 11% it's 22 no one.
Well,
it's Kanye.
Kanye was the wrecking machine,
but I actually think,
I think in the grand scheme of things
can't,
candace is much bigger.
I really believe that in terms of,
because I think she could be a direct
line to all of the political parts of
this if she decides to go that route
because I think she could,
I think she could run for Senate or,
yeah.
Yeah.
I,
I can't,
I'm not high today.
Not,
I'm only smoking maybe once a week on
Sundays and now and now I'm on tour so
I'm not really at all,
but let us park up at joint and have you
reconsidered what you just said?
You can smoke a joint and maybe I'll
reconsider.
Said you watched the podcast I did with
her.
Yeah.
I watch,
I don't know.
Maybe at least at least an hour and a
half of it or so.
Yeah.
Why?
What?
I don't know why you saying it that way
because I don't think she should run for
Senate.
No,
no.
I'm not saying she's a,
a young girl with some interesting ideas
and she's got a lot of passion.
I know.
I didn't say,
I didn't say you think she should.
I even say I think she's here.
I think she could have a bigger effect.
Even then Kanye,
when it comes to just everything going
on politically,
I'm going to ask you again,
this girl,
she wants it.
She wants it,
man.
Sure she does,
but when you share affecting people in a
big way,
I think maybe in a bigger way than then
perhaps either one of us don't
understand,
but my butt forgetting candace
specifically.
My point.
My point was nice person.
Yeah.
My point was though that I think all
minority groups are reevaluating what's
going on here.
If you're in the black community,
clearly there is at the moment a
reevaluation of do we have to be
democratic?
If you're,
that is an issue.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a racist issue.
Yes.
Because people assume that if you're
black,
you must be a democrat.
If you're not,
you're some sort of an uncle Tom.
It's kind of fucked up.
Yeah.
Talk to my friends,
Larry Elder,
I had thomas soul on the show or my
buddy David Webb,
or,
or many of,
there are many black conservatives.
Sure you are allowed to think however
you want it despite your skin color.
Right?
So I think the black community,
Ben Carson,
I mean I think the black community
starting to split,
I think the gay community starting to
split because the left has sort of had
this odd embracement of Islam,
which is bad for gays.
So I think the gays are starting to
split.
I think that,
uh,
Latinos are even starting to split a
little bit differently because I think
for all the people that came here
legally,
they're actually not as thrilled with
illegal immigration as the media may
imply that they are.
So I think there's just massive shifts
happening all over the place.
And the way we look at voting where
every election,
you know,
what's his name?
John King goes on CNN and shows you the
map and he goes,
well,
the white working class people here
voted this way and the black inner
city people.
But I think all of that is about to
explode and they won't know what to do
because they haven't been listening.
But I think some others have them.
Listen,
there's real room in this country for a
third party.
I mean,
I think for sure someone could take a
position that's outside those two boxes.
Yeah.
And and make some real valid points and
have a little bit of ideas from each
side.
But the real concern,
this country seems to be throwing your
vote away,
right?
That's the thing that people were always
worried about.
Well,
if you go that way,
you're throwing your vote away and
you're essentially giving it to the
person that is on the other side.
I used to kind of buy into that,
right?
Cause realistically within,
but this is why I was so disappointed in
Gary Johnson.
Every half the country hated hillary,
half the country hated trump at at the
highest levels that you could hate a
candidate.
Right.
So if there was ever a time for just a
decent guy,
right?
Like Gary Johnson's,
just a decent guy.
If he was here,
like he'd probably want to spark up and
you know,
and a nice guy,
he's just a nice guy.
But he was such an ineffective,
confused memory problem.
Couldn't lay out his basic principles
simply,
you know,
he wanted as a libertarian,
he wanted the baker to bake the cake.
That that's a crazy position to hold as
a libertarian.
Makes no,
it's completely against.
What would be your,
uh,
line of thinking as a libertarian,
you would never want the government to
force someone to do a specific task.
Talking about the gay couple that wanted
a wedding cake made.
Yeah.
What's your position on that,
by the way?
Um,
well there's two issues.
One issue is that this,
they apparently went to places they
thought would deny them so that they can
make a story out of it.
Yeah.
It wasn't as simple as a loving couple
went to someplace they wanted to get a
cake made and the people said no.
And they're like,
what the fuck?
Now they wanted a story and this,
so they sought out places that they
thought were going to deny them and then
they made a giant national event out of
it.
I don't think people should discriminate
to the point where they're not going to
make someone a cake.
I mean,
I think there's the government.
Do you think the government should,
government shouldn't step in?
No.
Yeah,
I think you should let people know
publicly these,
these are people that they discriminate
against gay people.
And so if you want your dollars to
represent your opinions and your
feelings on things,
maybe you shouldn't buy a cake from
these folks that don't want to make a
cake for gay people.
But the idea of the government's going
to step in.
It seems crazy to me.
But then as soon as I say that,
I go,
okay,
well what if they wouldn't make a cake
for black people?
Should the government step in then?
So,
okay,
so there's a couple of things,
right?
So there's a couple of things there.
So first off it,
it was about the specifics of the cake.
I know this guy had a lot of people are
going to get into the nitty gritty of
every legal part of this thing.
But it was about a specific,
it wasn't that he wasn't going to sell
them a cake that was on the shelf.
Right.
Didn't want to make,
he didn't want to make them a cake for
this wedding.
Now that's asking him to do something
that's artistic or that's not,
what was the variables like that.
You want men.
So I apparently am the conversation
actually never got to that point cause
he denied them before that because he
knew what it was going to be.
So it never got to like,
oh,
are you when you're going to draw us
together or whatever.
But he knew it was going to be a gay
wedding.
So let just said no,
I'm not making a cake for a gay wedding
right now.
Look.
But they could have bought a cake that
was there.
So like it was an interracial wedding.
Would you have a more of an issue with
that?
So,
so here's the deal.
So it's,
look,
we have the civil rights act of 1964.
You have to serve people based on race
and,
uh,
all of the minority statuses that there
are.
I'm not for re litigating that,
but uh,
but there are,
there is a libertarian argument that
basically would say we don't need those
laws anymore because the,
the civil rights act was in response to
Jim Crow laws were states in the south
had discriminatory laws.
So we had the federal government come in
and clean that up for everybody.
So you have to serve everyone equally.
You can't deny a black couple to come
into your restaurant or [inaudible] can
you walk?
Can you deny a gay person then?
Nope,
because,
but it was a specific thing.
It was a specific,
so let look put it,
put it this way.
If you had a,
if there was a Jewish artist who took
commissions,
uh,
for paintings,
would you force that person to bake to
paint Neo Nazi signs?
Of course not.
You would never have the government come
in and say that they are forced to paint
something that's against their
conscience.
So I would say that your original
position is the right one,
which is,
it kind of sucks,
right?
It kind of sounds like,
I wish in my heart of hearts I'm gay
again.
Like I wish that every Baker would treat
everyone equally and every person would
treat everyone equally.
They're not allowed.
He wasn't allowed to deny them something
that was in the store already because
you can't deny based on those protected
categories.
So he wouldn't have by the Civil Rights
Act,
he wouldn't have been allowed to deny a
interracial couple of cake that existed
there already.
But could he have cody have denied them
one that he would have had to draw a
black woman and a white woman if he was
a real racist.
I think the answer is that he could have
denied them that and that would have
been very shitty and he would be a
racist and a really awful person.
But if the answer is that the government
should then come in and tell this man
what to do,
I would not be for that.
I see what you're saying.
Um,
I just,
that's just the cleanest way to deal
with this related to freedom.
It's kind of shitty.
Like freedom is messy.
It's definitely shitty.
It's Shitty.
And,
but the government can't protect you
from shitty.
Yeah,
no,
I mean obviously that's why the KKK is
still exists.
Yeah.
And what's the alternative?
I mean,
what's the alternative?
We would all love the KKK to go away.
We would all love there to be,
not all of us,
but most sane people don't want racism
to exist.
But should we not let people meet?
Should we be bugging people?
Should we force people to do something
they don't want to do?
I mean,
I just don't,
I just fundamentally do not believe in
that.
I don't want people to be racist.
I don't want people to be homophobic or
transphobic.
But the idea that the government can use
its authority to make people do all of
these things I just think is absolutely
crazy.
So whether they decided to intentionally
inflame this or not by finding people
that,
that weren't going to do it.
If you really,
if you're listening to this right now
and you're getting married,
you know you're getting gay,
married,
um,
or untraditional,
he married as they call it,
you're doing that and you live in
Alabama and there's only one baker there
and he doesn't want to bake a cake.
It sucks.
It does suck.
But what you might want to do is what I
said about an hour ago,
which is maybe leave that town like
maybe take your skills,
whatever,
whatever worth you bring to a community
and move to a bigger town where there
probably is some of their do it or order
a cake online.
I mean the technological part that you
just mentioned that you can now tweet
about stuff and go,
don't go,
don't go.
Like we have power as people.
And the idea that we outsource all the
decision making to the government is
extremely dangerous.
I mean,
every,
every horror in human history is a
government doing things basically,
you know,
as long as governments have pretty much
existed,
it's not bands of Nice individual people
that disagree on some stuff murdering.
Yeah.
I mean,
I understand your position and I'm with
you to a certain extent.
Uh,
I wish there was a clean answer.
There's no clean answer,
but freedom is not clean.
That's the,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean even the freedom to be a piece of
shit.
Yeah.
And to be racist and to be sexist or
homophobic or whatever it is.
And you know,
we,
we have to define what that is and the
first place,
right?
Like who by whose definition is
something homophobic or by WHO's deaf?
And I mean,
is it homophobic or is it religious
freedom?
Like if,
if,
you know,
if someone is deeply religious and their
religion discriminates against gay
people,
are they discriminatory or are they
religious?
You have to give me an example of what
they were actually doing.
Like you're allowed to hate gay people.
You,
you are,
I hope that you do not,
and I actually think this is somewhere
where the conservatives have moved.
I really do think they have moved.
There's virtually no mainstream
conservative that's screaming about gay
marriage anymore.
Even Mike Huckabee who sort of
irrelevant or like that,
that the Christian conservative side of
that,
they pretty much have ted Cruz,
what does he say about gay marriage
anymore?
But that's again why rand Paul should
have led or the the real,
the true conservatives that believe in
limited government should have led the
charge on this.
So this is where the progressive's did
do something right years ago because
they were fighting for real equality
because real equality means you should
be able to marry whoever you want.
They weren't going for extra rights for
anyone.
Now they're going for extra rights
because we all have equality.
Doesn't mean we all have equal
everything,
but we have to have equality under the
law.
That's all the government can provide
you.
And then once you have that,
some of us are going to be born into
more money,
right?
Like your kids are going to have more
money then you did right.
Fact should they be punished for that?
A lot of people would say yes,
he was a lot of,
we do think that,
yeah.
I mean,
look,
I don't believe you should be able to
give your kids money when you die.
We'll do
the estate tax.
I'm mostly,
I hope that I'll be able to make enough
money in my life that that will be a
problem,
but it will be a problem for you for
sure.
Short of you go bust on everything
you're doing,
which I'm assuming is not going to
happen.
Do you think at the end of your life
that you've paid taxes your whole life,
you've paid payroll taxes because you
have employees,
you've done all of these things,
you've done everything right as a
citizen,
do you think at the end of the day the
government should be able to come in and
take something like 55% of your money at
that?
No.
That's creepy.
It's creepy that they're able to do
that.
To take money from taxed money.
Yeah,
so the money's already been taxed for
your whole life.
Yeah.
You earned that money and then they're
going to tax it on top of that,
but that's a mainstream democratic
talking points.
It's one of those things where they're
dealing with the redistribution of
wealth that that conversation,
the redistribution of wealth is super
slippery because like who's going to
redistribute it and to who and like when
do you decide that someone has too much
money or what?
You know,
what's the standard,
what's the metric and what what,
what occupation are we going to,
we are we only going to go after the
bankers and we're going to go after
artists as well.
Like what if someone's a successful
artist and we're going to take all their
money are we're going to remove
incentive for success?
There's a certain line that you're going
to cross where you shouldn't be more
successful because they're going to tax
you harder if we're going to keep people
in some,
some,
some sort of an artificially constructed
glass ceiling to avoid being taxed like
it's a real weird,
I hate to tell you,
but everything you just said there is
completely against what Democrats
basically are for.
They are for the estate tax.
I mean the bold why,
what's the argument?
The argument is you died and now in the
greater good,
which is,
which is a phrase that sounds really
good but it's,
but it's your,
your face pretty much summed it up.
It never leads to good.
Well we can,
okay let's just give more money to this
thing that wastes money on everything at
that has no accountability.
This giant money churning monster.
Yeah.
That's the real issue,
right,
is that this thing doesn't have
accountability and that it does waste a
shitload of money.
Think about this.
If the government was slim and trim and
effective and you know,
we were all tax right and it was
transparent and effective and
functional,
there would be no reason to be a
libertarian.
I'd be sitting here going,
I'm for government.
You know what I mean?
Like if it really operated in a slim
way,
but what the government doesn't do
anything good.
Name one problem you could possibly have
in your life,
Joe Rogan that you'd be like,
get me,
get the government to solve this.
Did they do the post office?
Well,
no.
What?
Like what do they do?
Well they do.
The Post Office is pretty good actually,
but guess what?
If the post office closes tomorrow,
it will be all right.
You'd still get mail,
Amazon pick note.
When Amazon was,
say us through ups,
it would cost a lot more.
He wouldn't though.
Competition would start kicking in and
between ups and Fedex and Amazon and
drones and Blah,
blah,
blah and DHL,
they'd all start.
I would probably drop prices because
right now we've just got this artificial
thing that sits there that then allows
them to price according to that,
but if you drop that,
why is the government in that business
anymore?
I have three chickens.
I've really done the Joe Rogan lifestyle
here over the last couple of years,
but I have three chickens right now.
We had,
I'm going to give you a good ups story.
We ordered them.
They were born August on a Monday
in a cleveland.
They hatch that day.
They threw him in a box with a little
hole you sps,
and they showed up at my door in La on a
Tuesday.
The USBS has been doing that for about a
hundred.
The only way you can do it,
by the way,
you can't order chickens through any
other methods suggests usbs.
Yeah,
so actually I was given the usbs credit
there cause my chickens all arrived
live.
Yeah,
they send the checks.
you're,
you're buying these live checks.
That's the way you get them to the US
Postal Service.
I'm pretty sure though that if the u sps
stopped,
it didn't exist anywhere.
You'd still get chickens delivered and
Amazon and could probably do it even
more effectively.
That's my point.
It's like I'm not saying these things
have to be eliminated tomorrow.
I'm not even really calling for them to
be eliminated.
But just generally what problem would
you,
everything you were building here right
now,
right?
Do you want the government to tell you
how to do all these things and all the
regulations that you got to have your
electric thing this far from this and
like all have regulations like that for
construction are important though.
You don't have to make sure that people
don't do stupid shit,
but a power lines near a water line.
There's a lot of,
but I would put most of that on the
builder's though.
They want to build things that are good.
Now I get hauled.
That's not true.
Listen,
people don't know.
People are going to build all the time
like you have to have regulations when
it comes to construction methods where
people are going to get fucked,
they cut regulate.
They cut corners when there aren't
regulations anyway.
They do.
They would cut a lot more if there
weren't regulated.
I'm not totally third world countries
and look at construction methods.
They're fucking dangerous.
That's why schools collapse on kids and
foreign countries sometimes like,
well,
I'm not complete.
I'm not telling you that I'm against all
regulation period.
That's where,
but that's where I said intellectually,
I like that argument because you could
make us,
I think you can make a very sound
argument that competition would force
people to do better work.
Like if you're a plumber,
you have a vested interest in doing the
best plumbing job you can so that people
were rate you on Yelp so that you will
get more work.
You don't have a vested interest in
cutting corners.
Now you might write,
you're going to push it as much as you
can to save as much time and energy and
money as you can,
but once you go over that edge,
yeah,
you don't want to be known as the guy
that the,
you tighten something too much that you
flooded the house or when you're
building a house.
Thinking logically though,
when when people fuck things up and
short things and do things terrible,
they're not thinking logically,
but I don't think it's the government.
I don't think it's the government that
they're like,
the government gave me this regulation
so that's why I'm going to do it.
Right.
Well,
you know,
didn't have any regulations.
That would be no incentive whatsoever to
do it.
Right.
No.
There would be an incentive knew there
were no inspectors,
no one was going to check their stuff
and make sure that their stuff was up to
code.
Listen,
man,
I was in no instruction my whole life.
My Dad was an architect.
I've been in construction since I was a
little kid.
You fucking need regulations.
These guys,
a lot of people that are in construction
there,
they'll do whatever the fuck they can to
make money and it's not good for the
people that have the house because they
might have that house for five,
10 years before that problem manifests
itself.
The people who are establishing these
codes are licensed builders or people
that have been involved in construction
for a long fucking time and they know
what's safe and what's safe.
That's why
those codes exist.
It exists to protect the consumers.
You can't just protect the consumers
through the marketplace because so I'm
not calling all the time for these
problems to become a real issue and
these problems could potentially damage
everybody in the neighborhood.
It's not just going to affect the person
on this one lot like of a fire starts,
it burns all the houses in the
neighborhood or if a flood happens and
it floods everyone downhill,
it's,
it's a real problem.
Like you have to be real careful with
construction.
I get it and you know,
my dad wasn't in construction so I'm not
privy to like all of that,
the little stuff.
But I genuinely believe that as a
general level people have a vested
interest in,
especially now because of phones and
apps and yelp and all of them doing good
work because that's how you will get
more work.
You are,
you're never going to remove the people
who will do shotty,
shitty malicious shit,
but you can keep them at bay with
regulation.
I think this is where I'd say you can
hate it.
Some regulation,
educated,
regulate regulation,
people who actually understand what's
going on and you know,
make sure that someone doesn't do
something stupid with a power line or
someone do something stupid with the,
the way they constructed main beams
where the,
they're just subject to collapse.
I that's important because most people
buying a house,
I don't know what the fuck they're
looking for.
Most people getting a house built,
they have no idea about construction
methods and they need someone to inspect
things and make sure that it's up to
code.
That's why code exists.
It's very important.
Yeah,
I saw,
I'm not,
I'm not totally with you on that.
Like I do think Mo,
I think most of it,
probably 90% of it would be who has the
most vested interest to build a good
house.
It's the builder because he wants more
work.
He doesn't want the house to collapse
because then he'll be added.
I'm telling you,
man,
I got you.
I got you though.
I get it.
Then he's got not just cops.
There's a specific thing.
It's a dangerous thing too,
because it's where you sleep.
It's where your kids sleep.
It's,
it's,
you know,
you just,
I think there's a lot of idealistic
notions about deregulation and I think
there's,
there's some consumer protection has to
be put in place because people don't
have the time to spend all this time
researching construction methods and
making sure everything's done correctly
and be there and make sure that the
joists are a certain width and they have
a certain amount of support.
Like all that stuff has to be done by
people who understand code,
assuming that the government regulators
understand code correctly and aren't
just on the take or just try,
you know,
just basically just taking money and
signing off on things.
I mean,
house Spec things,
man.
If you ever had a construction project
done.
Yeah,
well I got my house last year and we had
to go through all the inspections and
had several guys come back and we didn't
build it.
Now there's a big difference between
insurance inspector and a code
inspector.
Code inspectors are very different when
you're having a house built.
And I've had construction projects where
I had to explain to people and go
through it with,
with builders.
They're there making sure that the house
is in fucking fall on you,
that the power lines,
you know,
are,
are done correctly,
that all the electricity done
correctly,
the pipes,
uh,
late incorrectly,
your septic system,
where your sewage system has done
correctly.
Do you think that could be privatized
then?
See,
cause again,
I'm not,
I'm just,
I just think it's an regulations.
How would it,
how would you could have the company no
incentive.
Well No,
you could have companies that would,
that their job would be to make sure to
inspect.
Yeah.
And you wouldn't have,
they wouldn't have the thread of law to,
to enforce these things.
Like if someone is,
if someone is building something and
they're not up to code,
they lose their license and they can't
build.
If you privatized it,
what's the incentive for them to follow
the guidelines?
Yeah.
So this is,
this is where I'm not telling you that
I'm calling for all this.
I just think intellectually it's just an
interesting space to,
to argue something.
Cause I think that there's more the more
that you can give to people to freely do
what they think is right.
I think generally they will.
Like again,
I get it.
There's going to be some real shitty
construction people out there you don't
think you should have on to talk about
this.
And I think people have looped you in
before is you're on Brooke from uh,
from mine ran institute.
He's,
cause he's no only sweet began with no,
no.
All right.
So I'll be happy if they have,
I'm pay attention.
Okay.
So I'll,
I'll be happy to do it.
He's a really interesting guy whose
mother was thinking a little bit on
this.
Those iron brand people are fucking
harsh.
They like ideas,
man.
Those are,
they're not the most fun people on the
there on the planet.
But I generally,
I generally liked them because they just
want their kind of live and let live.
That's really it.
Like that's like the crux of it pretty
much.
Is that really the crux of it or I mean,
yeah,
people think that there's like sort of a
cruelty aspect to it.
I ran philosophy,
well they believe in,
in rational self interest,
which if you say self,
it makes people think you're evil.
But,
but we all basically operate in rational
self interest all the time.
Right.
But espousing it with us,
the thing,
it's like proclaiming it is a thing that
people go,
oh,
you're,
you're essentially setting up the idea
of the Gordon Gekko idea.
Greed is good.
I kind of buy into that idea.
Do you buy into greed is good.
Yeah.
Basically not greed to destroy the
world.
But if you do you joe,
do what is good for you.
And by extension greed,
well that's [inaudible] ambition.
Well,
all right.
Exactly.
That's my point,
right?
Where it gets conflated,
isn't it?
Right.
So with,
so without wiggling it to the definition
of greed versus ambition,
it's like you do what's good for you,
but,
but it doesn't mean you're just running
this like rampaging program to destroy
the world in the name of Joe Rogan.
You're doing what's good for you because
you actually like your audience and you
want them to learn you.
You want to have money so that your
family can live in a house that you can
afford,
that you can send your kids to good
schools and all of those things.
That's all rational self interest.
If at the same time you were running a
nuclear power plant and you are Mr.
Burns and you were dumping in the river,
well no,
that's actually no longer rational self
interest because now you're polluting
the very environment that you live in.
So rational,
I mean the key takes care of that.
Who regulates that?
So they,
so generally comes in.
So those guys,
I don't want to speak for a little,
gets you in trouble if you,
in your opinion,
if you're,
you're this deregulation
guy who goes after you when you dump
shit into the river.
So I'm not saying there should be no
regulation.
I just was saying that I like this.
Generally I like this line of thinking
there has to be some regulation.
I agree you can't.
But what I would say is,
you know,
that's where the regulation comes in and
the environment.
Yeah.
That,
I would say there has to be some,
but I've had some interesting people on
conservatives who are dealing with doing
uh,
environmental stuff from a conservative
perspective that there's ways to make
money actually in green stuff,
in green products and in Al Gore.
Yeah.
Well,
look,
yeah,
he's been,
I don't know that he's creating anything
other than movies,
but he's making me make a lot of money,
a lot of money in green corporations.
Right.
So that,
but that's him doing it privately,
right?
Yeah.
But what is like,
what's the solution if someone pollutes,
if you're not going to have regulation,
what is the solution?
If someone does something that's
illegal?
Well,
if you're not going to have regulation,
he wouldn't be illegal.
But your question is,
well,
it's illegal dump,
dump things into the river,
right?
I mean,
it's just illegal.
That's not a matter of regulation.
I mean,
polluting,
we'll willful poisoning of rivers.
I'm sure he's actually terrorism.
It would be a bunch of like,
so what those guys would argue is what I
said before,
which is that ultimately,
especially now because of technology,
like in the old days,
so like every time someone cuts
regulation,
I've heard Bill Maher say this a lot,
they're going to start a polluting the
river immediately.
That implies that these businessmen,
whatever their,
you know,
where they're,
whatever they are,
whatever industry that they're in,
that they're immediately going to be
like,
Huh,
the regulations gone start polluting the
water.
We live in a time now where everyone's
walking around with an iphone where
maybe 50 years ago you could've got away
with a lot of bad shit,
right?
Coal miners that we're breathing,
all kinds of horrible shit that nobody
was ever going to find out about where
now everybody is walking around with
snapchat and instagram and blah,
blah blah.
So a lot of this stuff would be exposed
more so that all of the things that
we've been talking about for the last
couple of hours about,
about people getting involved,
a lot of the things I think would start
self regulating.
But again,
and then I won't say it again.
I'm not for just deregulating
everything.
I just think there's probably better
ways to do it than just having the
government come in and say,
this is what you gotta do and now figure
it out because the government isn't that
good at most things.
Yeah,
I know what you're saying there.
But,
uh,
I do think that obviously there has to
be laws in place,
uh,
specifically laws in place that protect
people from someone doing something and
it's going to damage all the other
people in the community.
Yeah.
Well,
by the way,
that,
so you can do that from the government
supposed to protect your life and your
property.
I mean,
that's a very simple libertarian thing,
you know what I mean?
Like,
so that there's a good argument there
for why you could have some level of
regulation.
Right.
But I don't think it's just like
specifically in terms of like someone
polluting rivers.
I don't think it's good enough to snap
chat about it.
I think people should be locked up and
go to jail if they find out that
someone's dumping toxic waste into the
river because it's too expensive to
process it and get it removed and put in
some place where it's,
it's,
you know,
safe.
That's a crime.
Yeah.
Well I'm all for finding those people
and having the company's fire them and
all those things.
As far as putting them in jail,
I don't know that I'm glad come up.
Yeah.
I don't know that I'm getting them off
the streets.
Take the money,
give it to Bernie's kids.
I'm not a fan of putting more people in
jail generally.
But
yeah.
No,
I'm not either.
You know,
I think that's one of the more
interesting things that happened in this
administration is when Kim Kardashian
got that lady incredible generated or
whatever,
he did got a release to get her sentence
commuted.
That's Kinda crazy.
Like she showed up and she presented
this case about some woman who's,
uh,
been in jail for,
she's essentially jail for life for
nonviolent drug offense.
Right?
Yeah.
And how many other people are like her
for non violent drug?
A pen this long,
doing something with your own body.
Yeah,
well that's where we're full and total
agreement.
I just think that this idea that the
pharmaceutical companies can sell drugs,
but people can't sell drugs that they
can,
they're responsible for the UN
untenable.
The unimaginable number of people that
have died from opiate withdrawal or
opiate,
um,
overdoses.
Fentanyl.
I mean,
fentanyl.
Just last year we lost Tom Petty.
We lost prince.
Um,
couple of other people too.
I can't remember.
There's some other famous people that
died from fentanyl.
Um,
uh,
Patton,
Oswald's wife,
she was another fentanyl.
This,
it's like,
it's a horrible,
horrible,
horrible drug and no one's clamoring for
these people to go to jail
scratching drugs all day long.
You go watch cable news all day long.
What are they selling all day long?
Prescription drugs with a zillion side
effects that are seemingly far worse,
including thoughts of suicide and
depression and blah,
blah,
blah.
Then the original thing they're trying
to treat.
So look when specifically opiates.
Yeah,
it's of the day,
the real deadly ones.
And then you think about how many people
that are in jail right now for
marijuana,
how many people that are in jail for
cocaine,
how many in jail people are in jail for
psychedelics?
MTMA mean it's,
there's no comparison in terms of the
amount of damage done per capita.
I,
I completely agree.
Look when when the thing happened with
Roseanne and then she blamed ambient or
she at least said she was on Ambien,
you know the Ambien,
the parent company,
whatever it was,
they tweeted out something like there
are a lot of side effects but it doesn't
make you racist.
But knowing how Glib and ridiculous that
was.
Yes.
No one is saying that ambien makes you
racist,
but ambien does have a litany of,
I don't know,
50 side effects it,
you know,
sleepwalking saying crazy things,
eating,
you know,
literally just being unable to control
what you're doing while you're on ambien
being in this Zombie like state.
So is it possible that even though she
has also said that she didn't realize
that Valerie Jarret was black,
which I actually kind of do believe.
I don't know.
I sent it to me.
Yeah.
I don't know her.
I know,
I know.
I mean,
I know her a little bit.
So
she didn't think she was black.
I believe her.
I believe her 100% but look,
she said dumb shit in the,
the Susan Rice
thing was much more egregious to one
where she said that a Susan right rice
was a man.
Eight balls.
Yeah,
no.
Yeah.
So I'm not defending what rue events at
all I'm saying is that Ambien,
the maker sends out this Glib tweet,
like we don't make people racists,
but guess what?
You have people doing all kinds of crazy
shit that they can,
having conversations,
people have driven their cars and the
wrong side of the highway.
People who have done all kinds of crazy
shit on there.
Right.
So is it possible that made her impaired
enough to have a stupid thought and then
100% yeah,
it's 100% there's definitely side
effects.
The,
whether or not they're responsible for
those side effects is where it gets into
the realm of personal responsibility.
Like,
if you take ambien and you do something,
are you responsible for it?
No.
Yes.
What are we going to say?
If you drink and you go commit a violent
crime,
are you responsible for,
we all agree,
yes.
So it gets real strange.
You know,
it gets real strange.
I mean that,
that's one of the weird things when it
comes to gender and responsibility
because there's been so many issues of
men and women,
particular,
it's almost always men and women.
You never hear about these from gay
couples,
but men and women or I haven't heard
about it,
at least men and women,
uh,
getting drunk and having sex and then
the man gets accused of sexual assault.
And this has gotten so weird that a guy,
um,
preemptively guy and a girl got had sex
and the guy,
um,
called the police and wanted her charge
was sexual assault because he was drunk.
And he did it as a preemptive measure
because he was worried that she was
going to come after him.
And so the university took action
against the girl and I'm like,
Jesus Christ.
And we play in little stupid games.
And pretending that girls rape guys when
they're drunk or that it's really
devastating for the guy.
Like what the fuck are we doing?
We are going to criminalize everything.
We're going to criminalize every,
I think of all of the stupid things
you've done in your life,
whether on drugs or not or whether we
when you were in college or not
involved.
Now add social media to that.
Add the the amount of pictures that
people send to each other and everything
else.
If we don't stop this attic control
monster,
we are all just going to destroy each
other.
But there's a gray area because we know
that some people do take advantage of
people that are drunk.
Like if someone was,
if someone was like porn drunk drinks
down someone's face and they were sober
and they were doing it with the
intention of raping them once they were
intoxicated and they couldn't consent
anymore,
that's one thing.
But if two people are getting together
and drinking and then having sex and
then the woman has regret in the morning
when she sobers up.
So she decides that it was rape because
she and he were both drunk.
That's preposterous.
But we don't have this ability to
rationally process each and individual.
Each individual case.
By the way,
here's something that trump did that was
really good.
He got rid of those ridiculous title
nine laws that Obama in stated where
they were basically having these clown
courts in colleges that you could go to
them and instead of having due process,
which is perhaps the most important
piece of,
of a functioning western free society
where you are innocent until proven
guilty.
They were suspending male students just
by accusations and then it was leaking.
I had Laura Kipnis
on who's a professor that they were,
she was fighting against title nine so
then they brought up title nine charges
against her.
I mean there's,
and there's many,
many other stories on this.
That's something that Obama brought in
that trump actually got rid of that
evil.
What's her name?
[inaudible] Betsy devoss got rid of.
So it's like we've,
we've just gotten to the point where
we've politicized everything.
We've politicized our own capacity to be
free and make decisions for ourselves.
If you get drunk and are fooling around
with somebody,
some of that's on you,
you might regret it.
And the next one,
we,
every,
every single one of us listening to this
has had sex with someone or done drugs
with someone or something.
Woke up the next morning and be like,
fuck,
I shouldn't have done that Jamie.
Jamie's clean.
Um,
except here's my thing.
I was thinking about driving.
If you drive in,
you're drunk.
No one says you're exonerated because
you're drunk,
right?
No,
man,
you are drunk and fucked up and you did
something drunk.
You're responsible for your actions.
But if you have sex drunk,
all of a sudden for some strange reason,
you're not responsible for your actions.
That's preposterous.
It doesn't,
they don't match up.
It's not,
it doesn't make any sense.
Yeah.
But again,
this is where the,
the identity politics of all this ruins
everything.
Because you're not saying that anyone
that gets drunk,
you're saying if a girl really,
although that one example that you gave
is true.
That's like a curriculum.
It's a complete throw away.
Ridiculous.
Shows you how fucking stupid the
university is that they let that fly.
They should've smacked him.
Send it back to class.
Smack him in the face.
Yeah,
Sun right back to class.
Congratulations Buddy.
He's got laid.
Yeah,
good for you.
You were drunk and the girl took
advantage of your penis.
Did you orgasm?
You did.
Shut the fuck up.
Get out of here.
What are you doing?
It's,
it's ridiculous.
Across the board.
It's a far more ridiculous though.
When a guy is accusing,
and let's just be honest about this,
it's far more ridiculous when a guy is
accusing a girl of rape in those
circumstances,
and I don't want to hear all your
progressive nonsense screaming and
yelling and no,
it's not.
We're all equal.
Fuck you.
It's not the same of a guy does that to
a girl.
If a guy purposely gets a girl drunk and
does it because he knows that she
wouldn't consent any other way.
And then gets her department.
She's like,
oh,
and she's barely conscious and fucks
her.
In my opinion.
That's rape.
Yeah,
and my opinion that that person,
but if a couple gets together and they
have a few drinks,
they're laughing,
they're flirting,
and they make out and then they go back
to her place or his place and they have
sex.
It's not rape.
We know it's not rape.
All right,
so let's split the difference on that
one.
So now it's a,
it's a sorority party.
In College,
the girls decide they're going to drop
Ruthie's in a couple of the guys' things
late at night.
Girls are just,
you know,
let's just,
I don't know what the girls look like.
Right?
Okay.
So girls look good,
right?
So,
right.
So a bunch of hot chicks now there,
they drug these guys.
I mean,
I'm sure this has happened.
This is definitely never heard of it.
If you're sure it's happened.
It's got to have happened.
They roofie to guy.
I'm sure a guy has been,
I'm pretty sure I got roof by a girl in
college.
Now I'm married to a dude.
So who knows what's going on.
Me,
she fucked her brain up.
She,
she seriously,
it was some high level
Ruthie Shit.
I was like,
we went all night and then I was like,
you know what,
I've had just about enough of this,
enough of this gal stuff.
You really got roofie by girl.
I was roofied once in college.
I like just like a keg party.
What'd you like?
Who did it?
I don't know who did it.
I don't have much of a recollection of
it other than I remember I had like half
a beer.
I could not really think.
And I remember I couldn't stand.
Did you realize something was wrong and
try to get it out of there.
I knew something was wrong,
but your mind doesn't operate correctly.
And I remember I was Kinda,
I remember my friends were there,
but we were all like stoners at the
time.
So I don't even know that.
I was like thinking clearly like
something you don't realize fully.
You don't,
you know something's not right,
but you're like,
at least what happened to me was I just
couldn't like put all the pieces
together.
You get tested,
do you find out what it was now?
I mean I remember,
I remember at one point just sitting on
a couch in the corner.
I remember a very bright lamp light
above me out.
I have no recollection of how I got home
or like any of that.
But it also makes 20 years roofing all
like why,
why wouldn't you think it's,
how do you say it,
hip and all something.
How do you say that?
Let's just say Ruthie,
Ruthie.
What makes you think it was that and not
like,
oh I don't know.
Maybe,
well cause I didn't trip.
I mean I wasn't,
you know,
I've tripped,
I've done that stuff.
What does that other stuff that people
give or ge or something like that?
Yeah.
Like I don't think I was in like a k
hole or I've never done that.
I don't think I was in that kind of
state.
I was just in this,
like my body kind of couldn't move,
you know,
little aura kind of stuff.
Bright light and like I kind of couldn't
think straight that that's the way I
would describe it.
But I've,
I mean,
I've done mushrooms,
I've done most things that are out here.
I wasn't hallucinating in any way,
so,
but,
but just playing that went out for a
second.
If a girl did that to a guy,
managed to get him hard,
fuck them.
Right.
I think you think it's the same thing.
You walk it off,
walk it off policy.
Those are my four words.
Suck it up,
suck it up,
get off.
You got you got laid.
Yeah.
It's not good.
It's definitely not good for anybody to
take advantage of someone's body and
particularly give them a drug and where
they can't Dev no control and then raped
them.
Yeah.
It's the same thing.
If a girl does it to a guy,
it is the same thing.
She roof,
he's the guy and has sex.
And especially what if the guy has a
girlfriend and he doesn't want to have
sex with her or you know,
fill in the blank.
He's not attracted to her or he's gay
and you do that to him and he's repulsed
by it.
Yeah,
it's right.
Yeah.
But you know,
now we're in the realm of Bill Cosby,
right?
The bill cosby situation is fucking
break,
right?
Yeah.
100%.
No doubt.
It's a big difference between that and a
couple that gets together and has a
couple of drinks.
Have you heard it from a gay
perspective,
like two gay guys getting drunk and
having sex and one of the guy's accusing
the other one of sexual assault because
he was drunk?
Well,
I've definitely heard of the first part,
two gay guys getting drunk and
hepatitis.
I've heard any of the events that's
happened a lot.
Uh,
the rape one,
I haven't heard it that I've heard so
many stories about a woman in this one
story about a man claiming that he was
sexually assaulted because they were
drunk.
I've never heard it about two gay guys.
I actually do know one of a guy,
um,
that was given something,
that gift that was given something.
Yeah,
but not two guys not willingly got drunk
and then,
no,
not that.
I definitely have people been given.
Sure can attack 100% that that's
probably just a guy thing.
Fucking dark thing.
Man,
that's a dark thing that people are
willing to do that that caused me,
thinks,
shook me to my fucking core.
The idea that this guy who was America's
sweetheart,
America's dad was possibly the greatest
series,
not the Russians or the greatest,
but one of the worst serial rapists of
all time,
if not the worst.
Did we we,
the first time I came on,
we talked about cosby.
He's the reason I got into comedy at
four years old,
I think it was 1981 or 1982 maybe I was
five.
I saw a bill cosby himself on HBO.
I remember sitting in the,
in my family room buckled over and
laughing to the point,
you know,
when you just your whole body,
you cannot pain in my stomach.
And I remember thinking,
I want to be funny.
And now my comedy hero is basically the
biggest serial rapist of all time.
What the fuck,
man?
I used to have cosby records hanging up
in my house even to three years ago,
and eventually as the story started
leaking out,
I have one of his great records and I,
at first I was like,
I'm just going to leave it up.
Like it doesn't change my feelings about
him as a comic.
And then I remember people would be
coming into my house,
oh,
you got gotta be over there.
You should do you just take it and then
put bars over it.
That's what I should do.
I bet you that leave it up there,
but bars over it.
Yeah.
I might do this just so fucked.
Like how could he,
how could he be that guy?
How could he be the guy who is so funny
and everybody loves them and also be the
guy that that drugs people and rape
some.
It's like what a dark,
dark,
dark secret.
I mean,
I think Jordan would have a lot to say
on this stuff that we,
these inconsistencies that we live with
that often drive us and that,
you know,
why did we find out that that,
these people preaching about morals or
all the time are the same people that
are doing all this weird shit or that
we've all done things that we're not
proud of or whatever it is.
And it's like that's part of being a
human.
It's just part.
Yeah.
You're talking about the evil,
I mean,
someone who's doing this into his
fucking sixties he was doing this,
but he gets,
it becomes an addiction.
Like anything else like you or your
mind,
I'm sure,
I'm sure people do studies on this about
what happens to the actual brain
chemistry when you're doing these things
that I would guess it has something to
do with the dopamine levels that are
released at the same time when,
when you know somebody's snorting coke
and doing whatever they're doing,
you know,
whatever it is,
I don't know what it is,
but it's just so stunning to me.
Yeah.
I mean,
there's a,
and again this is,
it goes back to laws or there's a need
to protect people,
but there's also a need to go,
hey,
college boy who got drunk and had sex
with a girl who was also drunk.
He didn't get raped.
Fuck off.
It's,
it's really disrespectful to people that
actually had been raped,
you know?
And I get,
it's kind of funny that he's turning the
tables and he's doing it to her.
I think there was a story,
part of the store was something about,
she had done it to one of his friends.
She had said that to one of his friends.
So he's preemptively doing it because he
thought that she was gonna come after
him now.
Well,
part of it is that it's gross,
that it's all public,
right?
Like everything has become so public.
And I think that that's part of the
problem all the time.
Like who banged who in college?
The idea that that now is like this
thing that gets written about and people
get interviewed on all of these things.
Like,
again,
all of that is kind of dangerous and
that's why I try all the time.
And I think what you usually do is you
usually talk about ideas not people
cause it's the underlying philosophical
ideas that matter.
Not the specifics of this kid.
I mean you didn't pull up the picture of
the kid and mentioned the girl's name
and hers are twitter and all that,
but that it's the underlying
philosophical issues of why are we doing
this?
Why are we exposing everybody?
Why are we attacking and destroying
everybody and all of that.
That,
that's much more interesting to me.
Then just the specifics of the people or
you know,
all the people that I'm so sick of all
these blue check writers and buzzfeed
people.
Like I never called them out
specifically like that guy.
I hate that guy.
Cause like he,
that guys,
nobody during the business of writing.
Right.
You know,
I think a lot of it is,
I mean we can decide that these people
are enemy,
but like we're in some ways photos on
the battlefield.
You know,
I just,
in a very perverse way,
and I don't,
I just think it's just like their job is
to write about things and when we're
involved in a story,
they find an angle and they go after it.
Just like I do with jokes.
Like when I,
if I crack a joke about somebody else,
I do a bit about someone else hate them.
Like I had this whole bit about,
um,
Bruce Jenner and the Kardashians.
What led bruce to become a woman because
I hated him.
It's cause it was,
I thought it was funny.
Yeah.
I thought is there's an angle there.
It's a story.
It's a big thing that's on people's
minds.
And so it became a target for me the
same way it is when a lot of these folks
write articles and you know,
a lot of them are in their twenties and
you know,
they're idealistic or they're young and
evolving their thoughts and maybe they
wouldn't write that article five years
from now or 10 years from now,
whatever.
And we don't think we have to take that
into consideration as well.
These people are embarking on a career
in journalism and you know,
for a lot of them shitting on Jordan
Peterson gets them social brownie
points.
Yeah.
You know what,
you want to shift topics for sure.
Can we do a little mid shift there?
Sure.
We can do a little mid ship.
So I was talking to Jordan about
something that I think is kind of
interesting that I haven't talked about
publicly before and I thought if I'm
going to come on Joe Rogan,
let me see if I can bust out something
kind of personal.
So you know,
Jordan was having all these autoimmune
problems and that's kind of what led him
to,
uh,
to doing this crazy diet where he in
effect is on the carnivore diet.
Yeah.
Like it's like meat.
That's it feel doing that.
Great.
He looks so much better.
Even even then,
probably last time he was here,
maybe what,
four or five months ago,
he,
his skin looks good.
He looks,
he's got some color back in his face.
You know,
he's definitely lost some weight,
slimmed down a little bit,
but,
but in a good way.
His energy,
his back.
Um,
he just,
his hair looks better.
Like he just looks better.
Like I don't know all the science behind
the carnivore diet of whether you can do
it forever and not eat vegetables and
truly survive.
I don't know where you're getting the
rest of the nutrition that you need and
the rest of the vitamins and all that.
But,
but when I've gone out to dinner with
him over these things,
guy gets a freaking the biggest steak
you can imagine at every place.
Chops it up,
eats meat.
That's it.
Um,
so anyway,
so we were talking the other day in the
green room before the show that it's
interesting that he had this health
problem as his success was growing and
it's like you don't really think about
that in life because we all like to
think like as we're growing and getting
better and doing what we're supposed to
do,
that our health is kind of in line with
that.
So,
I've actually never talked about this
before,
but about two and a half years ago,
right when my show was really taking
off,
I think probably about the first time
we,
we did our first sit down,
so not the one last year but two in
about two and half years ago as I was
for also first getting hate online at
the same time I started losing tons of
chunks of hair,
tons.
Like I'd be in the shower.
Yeah.
And tons of hair would be everywhere
after I showered hair in my towels and
everything and lost like huge patches
back of my head,
up top,
like all over the place.
So I had a al or I have,
I guess I technically still have it,
alopecia areata where it's an autoimmune
thing.
They don't know why your white blood
cells start attacking your hair
follicles.
Um,
so I went about two years ago and again,
this is just as I'm like starting to
really succeed.
Like I'm really just like breaking
through for the first time.
And uh,
I went on this like crazy experimental
drug.
So usually when you have this,
they just shoot cortisone into your
cortico corticosteroids into your head
and they hope that that basically
reverses it or stops or whatever reduces
the inflammation that's causing us
something like that.
And,
but my case was so severe that I went
to,
I found this doctor who's doing this
really experimental thing,
we're in effect,
they're putting something like poison
ivy on your head so that your white
blood cells will attack that instead of
attacking your hair follicles.
And the hope is if you do just the
slight amount that's necessary that you
won't have like crazy reactions and
you'll be,
and your hair eventually grow back.
Anyway.
I did it for about a year and first off
when I was on camera,
I mean there were points where like I
was like,
oh my God,
like I don't,
I can't be on academy more.
I was doing like,
not spray hair but like powdered shit
and like grew out my hair to like hide
so that we'll later I can show you.
Like I still actually do have some spots
here.
Um,
but anyway I went under this
experimental stuff and literally for two
years,
virtually my entire body was broken out
like red,
itchy,
Gross,
disgusting.
My head was like,
like terrific years.
Yeah,
for like a year bad and then and then a
year not as bad but like Ge,
like oozing my head like as if you had
poison ivy.
I was literally basically putting poison
ivy on my head and like I was sensitive
to heat and light and like it was,
it was a truly misery.
I had like a real,
oh I gained weight because of it.
Cause it likes screws up.
You're like my,
my neck actually look thicker.
Like I look at videos where I did not
look good for a year.
Like I look kind of bloated because my
body was basically having like an
allergic reaction at all times.
I was putting something on my head to
cause my body to have an allergic
reaction like it for whatever reason I
was just very sensitive to it.
But anyway,
I bring this all up.
Hey Cause I've never talked about it and
I thought it would might just be
something to like throw out there.
But B,
what I've discussed with Jordan is just
this interesting idea of sort of as
you're succeeding and as you're doing
what you're supposed to be doing,
that life just throws you weird things.
And I'm,
I'm pretty much over it now.
I'll show you later.
Like I definitely have some stuff still
that,
um,
now I'm just taking the injections and
we'll see what happens.
Um,
but don't you think it's stress related?
Yeah,
so I'd really Jordan doing the float
tanks.
Now I'm doing the Saunas.
I get massages every couple of weeks
now.
Um,
I'm definitely trying.
That's why I did the month off.
Jordan was not famous his whole life
now.
And then in his fifties became famous.
That is not,
it's a not a normal state that people
are accustomed to.
Even a clinical psychologist and a
professor and a professor.
And you know,
there's,
I mean,
how many stories do we have to read
about people who go famous and lose
their fucking marbles?
Yeah.
It's not an easy road.
It's not,
it's not easy to handle.
People ask him about that.
So when we do the q and a at the end
there's an APP that people submit
questions and then I just kind of
moderate it.
So I picked some funny ones and then I
picked some serious ones.
But a lot of the questions are asked him
directly about that,
about what it,
what pressure do you feel now that
you're famous,
what is,
what if you screw up,
what if a lot,
you know they also ask them what lot,
which I think is a great question and,
and I don't want to paraphrase his
answer because I won't do it justice,
but they ask him,
you know,
you talk about religion and archetypes
and all that,
are you a profit?
They will ask him now,
not because they're saying he's a
prophet,
but like if you believe in all of this
stuff,
if you believe that product you factor
in,
right.
And he,
he goes out of his way to say he doesn't
believe that.
And he's not trying to make anyone drink
koolaid.
He's trying to help have them live the
best life for themself,
not in life that he's laying out for
them.
Um,
but,
but watching him go through all this,
it's just been,
it's been truly fascinating.
Like it really,
it's like,
and then I think I said it before,
but it like the whole thing is like this
love fest.
It's not what they want it to be.
It's not the people that are writing all
of these pieces and who often,
I invite a lot of the writers sometimes
that right things.
I'll be like,
you want to come to the show tonight at
any of them are welcome to come as my
guests.
They can sit right up front.
I'll do the exact same thing,
Jordan.
We'll do the exact,
so you know what's good about those
people.
What's good about is the same thing that
I try to do with all my material.
I look at it and I learned this from
Doug.
Stan hope,
Doug Stan hope actually said it to me
and I realized I kind of do it,
but from him saying it,
I did it more.
He said,
you should write your bits as if you're
a defense attorney,
like you're defending your bit like
right.
Your bit like as if
you,
and so I,
I think that one of the things about
having haters out there or critics out
there is that they're examining your
material,
finding holes in it.
And I think if you go over all of your
material and all of your ideas from the
perspective of someone is watching,
I'm right now trying to find fault in
everything that you do.
You will find it.
Just be undeniable.
Find,
find those holes,
patch him up.
And you know,
there's going to be disagreements.
It's not like you're always going to be
able to state your point and it's going
to be,
uh,
undeniable to someone who completely
disagrees,
you know,
ideologically with your stance on
whatever the fuck it is.
But no,
as long as you,
it's undeniable to you,
uh,
you've,
you've rationally made your case.
You've objectively stated the facts.
You've,
you've,
this is your position and this is why.
And you could back it up.
There's too much sloppy work going on
where people think they can and you see
this a lot,
there's a lot on the progressive left or
the regressive left or what do you want
to call it,
where they just expect that other people
are just going to agree with their
stance on things.
So they,
they,
they have this sort of
will,
this very rigid ideology that they're,
they're trying to put out.
They often think that they're morally
right.
Yeah.
So then you don't have to do the leg
work of the arguments.
It's a lot harder to take a position
that says you should be who you are and
you have to fit that into society rather
than saying,
this is what the moral imperative is.
This is why we need those laws.
And if you deviate from that,
you're the bad guy.
So unfortunately they've just embraced
that,
I think too much.
So it's like,
it's like one of those things like when
I go to these colleges and I'm usually
invited by libertarians and it's like
the returns want low taxes and limited
government and live how you want to
live.
Right.
That.
That's the basics of it.
But they'll often say,
you know,
I talk about low taxes in a college
class and people say I'm racist.
And it's like,
well,
how does race get into that?
But what they will say is that what
they'll say is,
well,
wait a minute.
If you want low taxes,
that means you don't want money going to
people who need it more.
And often it is people of color who need
it more.
So you inherently are racist.
You have to think on how to make the
counter argument to that.
The,
I think there's a very valid counter
argument that I buy into,
but you have to think it's very easy to
just take somebody who thinks the
reverse of you and go,
you're racist.
You're race such such a lazy way to
approach an idea.
Yeah.
It's so lazy.
The only thing I,
I've a problem with what Jordan has been
saying lately is this idea of enforced
monogamy being the solution to insoles,
these involuntary celibates that's not
going to help.
So what do you think the,
I become men.
Well,
what do you think his definition of
enforcement argument is?
Just to be clear with the horse,
monogamy were people,
you know,
the,
the culture encourages and supports the
idea of monogamy.
Yeah.
In effect,
he's talking about Matt,
he's just talking about marriage and
that,
but that's not going to clear that way
to people that no one wants to fuck.
It's just not going to,
the idea is that there's a bunch of men
out there that are taking all the viable
females
because no one's getting married and
they're just,
there's no room for these insoles.
No.
They are not attractive to women,
whether they're not physically
attractive.
He told me Harvey Weinstein was
physically attractive.
That's fucking disgusting pig.
Forget about what he did to those women
are the rapes or the sexual assaults.
He had a gorgeous wife.
His wife is gorgeous.
That was a voluntary relationship.
Okay,
so how did that happen?
It happened through success.
It happened through success and
confidence and whatever the fuck else
he's got intellect.
I don't know what his mind's like.
These,
these insoles,
they have to become men.
Okay.
And there's a word.
It's all about that.
I mean his whole message is right.
I just don't think that enforced
monogamy has any factor whatsoever in
this.
So he,
I think he would say this,
but I'm not as lawyer,
but I think he used the phrase all he
meant was marriage.
That generally societies that more
people are married and let's just say
married.
So I think going to help.
I think perhaps if he was being
interviewed again by,
by her,
he would use a different phrase.
Even if they,
even if he says marriage,
marriage is not going to help in cells.
These guys that are involuntary
celibate,
they have to become attractive so they
have to become men.
Well the rest of his messages about
that,
but they have to do difficult things.
Yeah.
That's what they have to do.
They have to,
they have to deal shit,
confidence,
get your shit together.
And martial arts I think is one of the
best ways to do that.
I've seen so many men that were like
sick,
insecure and Dorky and w they become
fucking nerd assassins through martial
arts.
And it did.
I think it's a great way to build
confidence and I think there's an
extreme lack of adversity,
like physical adversity and a lot of
people's lives.
And overcoming physical adversity is
what leads to a lot of confidence in
men.
And I just think that there's a lot of
men that are just have no idea whether
they can or can't do anything difficult.
And they have massive insecurity because
of it.
I think he would agree with every word.
I think he went to everywhere that you
just said there.
Yeah.
I just think that marriage is not fixing
it.
You know,
culturally enforced monogamy's not going
to fix it.
They have to become men and women was to
have a reason to want to have sex with
you.
Yeah.
So I think he would agree with that.
I think he would say that once you
accomplish that,
that that's when you will find more
women and that the next step,
the next natural progression in life is
that you will find someone that you want
to be partnered with and that that then
has the best value for our society.
But I don't want to completely state his
case.
Hmm.
It's an interesting case,
but he completely,
I mean,
look,
why is it that for the little bit that
these articles get right about him?
It's that he's helping men.
He is,
yes.
He's also helping women.
But yes,
he is helping men.
Men need their shit together.
They need framework for sure.
I mean,
people need this,
this thing about discipline and you
know,
uh,
you are,
you,
are you aware of,
you know,
you're aware of Jocko Jocko willink.
Yeah.
That discipline equals freedom.
It's like one of the best catch phrases.
It's so,
it's empowering.
It's so empowering.
Get your shit together and then you,
the time that have for
recreation,
you'll appreciate it so much more.
You don't appreciate rest when you're
fucking off all day.
You're appreciate rest.
When you've worked hard,
that's when it means something to you.
When you've accomplished goals,
that's when this celebration is,
is something that you,
you get a good feeling from it.
Do you have a part in your life that you
feel like is lacking in that department?
In what department and just like getting
your shit together,
like not slacking on.
I'm pretty good at that.
Yeah.
That's what I do.
I mean,
I do a lot of shit.
They're the only way I could ever do as
many different things as I do is if I
just get after it.
Yeah.
I get after it pretty fucking good.
And I'm not,
I'm not an insecure in that.
I mean,
whether it's through martial arts or any
kind of exercise or work,
I just,
I take pride in getting things done.
I take pride in working,
you know,
especially working towards things that
are important to me,
whether it's working on my set,
working on my stand up,
whether it's working on a podcast,
whether it's working on my martial arts
or my fitness or yoga or whatever.
I get after it.
Man,
did you got to?
Yeah,
and for me,
it's not a matter of whether or not it's
an option.
It's like brushing my teeth.
I don't decide one day,
oh,
I don't want to brush my teeth today.
I just fucking brush my teeth.
And when there's days where I'm doing
fasted cardio,
when that alarm goes off,
it's not a matter of whether or not a
shut the alarm off.
That's not an option.
You Get up,
you put your fucking shoes on,
you get the dog and you go running
because that's what you do.
And if you just decide that's what you
do,
then you get things done and then a
month later you're like,
oh shit,
we did this all month and then six
months later it's like,
oh I did this half a year.
And then if you're doing Jujitsu,
you're like,
oh shit,
look I got a blue belt.
Oh Shit.
Now I'm a purple belt.
And that's how you become a black belt.
You just,
you know,
and I got my,
the good type of progressive cause it
gets progressively easier too.
I told you I'm doing that.
It doesn't though.
It doesn't get easy.
You don't think so?
Cause it can hard every time that alarm
goes off like fuck.
But you for you now then,
right when you started,
I don't know man.
You know the reward of it,
you know that that reward is some
enforcement.
There's some enforcement in the success
that I've had in,
in completing these tasks,
but every fucking time I go to yoga
class,
I'm like,
oh Jesus,
90 minutes in 104 degree temperature
with these all these women that are
going to humiliate me.
They can definitely do things that you
can't do.
Well.
This is their tough man.
There's a lot of these older ladies that
are fucking tough.
Yeah.
You know,
they just gut it out.
I was just one lady that goes there.
She's like 60 years old.
She doesn't even bring water and this
lady's in there for 90 fucking minutes,
sweat it out.
She's there every time I go,
I'm like,
she's not bringing water.
You sure?
She's 60 she could be like 20 and just
dehydrated.
Oh,
she's gray hair and tough as shit.
She drinks water before and she drinks
it after.
But when she's in that class,
he's just tough.
It's just,
you know,
they're there.
It's never easy to do.
You know?
It gets a little bit easier when you get
better at it.
But then you just try harder and it
makes it more difficult.
If you're always giving a hundred
percent effort,
it's always going to be hard.
You know,
you,
you take some pride in the fact that now
I can go two miles through the hills and
you know,
and reach the point of exhaustion where
before it was one or whatever,
whatever your little little progress
markers are,
you get some satisfaction that,
but it's always difficult to get going.
The the,
the hardest step is the first step is
not the 30th step or the hundredth step.
It's the fucking first one.
It's getting on the trail,
getting going.
It's the hardest thing.
The hardest weight to lift is the first
one.
Cause once you get going like okay,
I'm a half hour into my workout,
I'm writing things down.
I'm supposed to be doing now I got,
you know,
20 Chin ups,
then burpees and then all these days you
have to do it.
You just have to do it.
And so many people have a hard time
doing it.
If read in moving,
if you would have ever thought when you
started standup that you'd be sort of
like,
cause you're kind of like a lifestyle
guru in a in a way.
You know what I mean?
Like every time I've done the sensory
deprivation stuff,
ride the float stuff,
every time I've gone into the place when
I just talked to the girl,
when she's like setting it up or
something,
I'll be like,
oh Joe Rogan got me into this.
And they're always like,
oh Joe Rogan,
he got everybody into this.
Like you literally like created float
places.
All,
I went to one in Nashville,
like the woman was like,
oh Joe Rogan.
I love Joe Rogan,
but like that and the mma stuff and all
that.
Like what a bizarre adventure.
You know what I mean?
Like you probably would have never
thought
now that the only reason why it happened
because I had no intention of doing it.
It's like I didn't have to pull them
zero and time,
never written a book on lifestyle or
just fucking what to do.
I just say what I do and I do it by
example.
Like obviously I do all these things.
I mean that Jim's not there for looks.
Yeah,
I fucking do all these things.
So this is,
I think this is,
this is just a natural thing that's
happened,
but the float things,
the most bizarre one because I can't
believe I'm the one to tell everybody
but this doesn't he man.
But how the fuck doesn't everybody
already know they do now.
More people know now,
but how the fuck didn't they know when I
first got my tank in 2002 and um,
I had been talking about it for a couple
of years before because I had done one
where,
you know,
you go to a place and you rent it for an
hour.
That's how we regular people do it.
I get it.
You've got to get it.
I need one man fucking need.
When I tell you how often do you turn
it?
As much as I can.
I mean it's right there.
It's nice you're doing this more like
once a week or oh,
more than that for sure.
And I like to come in here,
you know,
different,
I'll come in here sometimes even after
the comedy store,
you know,
coming near Weird Times.
I'll come in here during the day.
But the whole idea is that this is
something that somehow or another was
created in the 60s by John Lilly and
nobody talked about it.
It was like kind of a suit,
Weirdo,
popular thing with hippies for awhile
and then it fucking went away.
But they were barely around.
And then I started talking about it and
now they're everywhere all over the
planet.
And that is the strangest thing to me.
It's one of the strangest things about
my entire career is that the float tank
business has sort of started up because
of me.
Yeah.
And that they're everywhere in the world
now.
There's hundreds of them everywhere in
every country and they didn't exist
before.
You know,
and that somehow or another,
you could directly connect them.
A lot of them.
To me that's very strange.
What does that say about ideas?
I mean,
what does that say about saying what you
think and explaining what your life is
to people?
That's what they want.
I mean,
I think when I,
when I'm with Jordan,
the thing I realized more than anything
else is he's giving them a little room
to be who they are.
He's taken some of the bullets,
you know,
the hit pieces and all that stuff that
we've talked about.
He takes a little bit of that to take
these positions that are not wrong,
but her just politically incorrect or
somewhat intraocular are controversial.
And by taking those positions,
he gives other people just a little bit
of a force field to think a little bit.
So,
so for you in this,
it's like you started doing something
that gave you a little peace of mind,
a little something that made you feel
good and feel healthy and clean and
mentally sound and all that.
And then you started talking about it
and then holy shit,
somebody in Nebraska was like,
I'm going to try that.
And the next thing you know,
she opened a clinic for it and is doing
it.
You know what I mean?
And then that that spurs and so if
that's the beauty of saying what you
think,
well it also works the same reason why
this podcast works like this pot.
I've never promoted this podcast.
I just did it.
And through word of mouth it got bigger
and bigger.
Yeah.
The thing about float tanks is I'm
telling you how amazing it is.
You try it and it doesn't suck.
You know what I mean?
It's not like if you don't enjoy that,
I don't know.
Yeah.
It's not like all these people went and
tried it out.
Like he fucking lied to me.
God dammit.
No,
they went to,
oh my God,
it's so relaxing.
It's amazing.
I got it.
Fresh perspective and my body feels
loose and relaxed.
This is crazy.
It's like there's a real positive
benefit.
I'm telling the truth.
How quick can you snap into the zone
that you want to get into and you're in
there.
Cause that's when I was just did it a
couple of days ago.
I've done it a couple times now and I've
usually been,
it takes me about 20 minutes to kind of
clear the clutter.
But you know,
sometimes it's more,
sometimes it's less.
This last time just cause I think we've
been traveling so much.
I've been planes every day and
everything else.
It wasn't till the law.
That's what it happens.
Like the last five minutes I finally got
to that place where I was kind of
disconnected.
But do you have a trick for that when
you get in there?
I've done it so many times that my body
knows what it's doing.
Yeah.
I lay in a tank and my body is like,
oh here we go.
Oh yeah,
just sink in.
But I've done it.
I don't know how many times I've had a
tank since 2002 so you're more tank
tank,
tank time,
you know,
and then I've been in there on mushrooms
and weed and you know,
we'd edibles especially that's the weird
one.
This marijuana edibles or the one on
some of the most underrated psychedelics
in terms of like introspective thinking,
self examination.
It's like,
it's one of those things that just
forces you to really go over every
single aspect of your subconscious
you're trying to hide from.
You got gotta.
You got a good strain of Endeca that's
not going to completely destroy me.
Like my weed situation at this point and
I used be a big pothead.
My weed
thing is like end of the night puff for
my vape pen,
like watch the same simpsons episode
that I loved in 1989 like that's good
enough for me.
Like I don't need,
like I know a lot of my comic friends,
like they want to smoke a sativa and
write,
and I'm like,
I've opened up enough doors in my brain.
If anything,
I'd tightened a couple of hinges,
you know what I mean?
I don't need to go the other way again.
Like for me it's much more about
relaxation.
Well there's a lot of great sativas or
indicas rather.
All you have to do is just go to any
store and then just take a little hit
and then we'll try it out.
Just the whole thing is just don't go
too deep.
Like people try three,
four or five hits and then never smoked
pot before and then they were in a k
hole in the corner crying and screaming.
And you know,
it's like Jesus,
what?
Your body doesn't know.
What the fuck to do with all that.
Thc like this,
watch this,
watch this.
I,
that's it.
You're good.
Blow it out.
Relax.
Give it an hour.
Find out what the fuck the effect is.
Don't just keep hitting it.
You know,
I've seen people that don't smoke.
Poggle I'll try
and then an hour later I'm like,
are you going to die?
You think you're going to die?
Like you,
you look,
you're freaked out man.
Yeah.
Um,
so I back in the day,
like college and a little bit after
college,
I did mushrooms,
I don't know,
maybe 20 times in my life,
something,
something around there.
And then I haven't done it in about 15
years.
And then about six months ago,
so mushrooms appeared,
it doesn't matter how they were in my
house.
And I was like,
all right,
here's what we're going to do.
My,
my,
uh,
that's friends over and David was there
and we were like,
all right,
we're all just going to take one cap.
We're not going to like have a full
fucking pussies.
It's been a while,
man.
Come on.
So I was like,
you know,
we're just going to take one cat.
Okay.
See what did I do?
So we'll take a cap.
And we had smoked a little and we had
drank.
It was after dinner and we were just all
hanging out.
It was a couple of us and we were like,
all right,
we're going to go play some video games.
So we're playing,
uh,
like nba jam kind of thing,
you know?
And we're playing and plan,
plan,
plan.
And I'm going,
guys,
my controller's not working.
My controller is not working.
I can't control this.
Nothing's,
we're working.
David looks at me,
he's like,
you're not holding a controller.
I was playing on my leg.
I was actually,
I had the controller on my life.
Yeah.
I had no control over.
I was actually,
I thought it would.
So I'm telling you one cap,
you mocked me,
but one cap can do the trick.
That's the story with a,
you need to go to a doctor and find out
what's wrong with your brain.
One caption this.
Hmm.
Wow.
Worlds for more interesting than I
thought it was.
Video Games.
Rogan,
playstation four I jumped connected.
I have jumped right into like
playstation four you know,
video games are good when you're with a
little bit.
I would recommend once you get into the
two or three caps,
you put the fucking video games down.
Just lay down and think about your life.
Yeah,
I but I for video games,
like again,
I just want to have enough time.
So like I like old school,
eight bit run one way.
I want to run Wah Wah.
I want to run back.
Yeah.
I want that.
I want to run that way.
I don't even want to run backwards and I
definitely don't want to run this way.
I just want to run that way.
So Mary Oh metroid that kind of thing.
I tell you that new silly shit.
Yeah.
Like I want to blow some stuff up for a
few minutes.
I can,
you know,
I don't have to murder a family and rape
people into steel crown or,
I mean I,
you know,
I've raped a couple of prostitutes and
you know all that.
It's fun when you're doing it.
Someone's going to take those fucking
sound bytes.
There we go.
I see you subconsciously.
You give it to him.
You know,
I just gave it to little people.
Who are they?
Who are,
who are you?
Are they?
They all need a hug.
Everybody needs a hug.
I think do,
I'm less combative with every year,
less defiant and combative with every
year with this stuff.
I'm more shrugging than ever.
I'm like,
just try to be a nice person.
Tried and tried to be nice.
Try to be nice to each other.
Do you do your best at whatever you're
doing,
keep moving.
And when things pop up and people write,
things just go,
okay,
well what am I gonna do you think that
could be a connection though to
eventually killing the drive to want to
keep doing things,
like to want to keep being funny,
to want to keep getting out there?
No.
My drive is for the people that enjoy my
work.
My drop when I'm,
when I'm doing standup,
my drive is because I know there's a
bunch of people that are getting
babysitters and they,
they're there.
They bought tickets in advance and then
like next Friday,
Joe's coming to town and I'm,
I'm working hard for that.
I don't want them to have a bad
experience.
I want to do the best fucking show I can
do.
I'm dead serious about that.
That's very important to me.
I understand it's a massive
responsibility and I'm doing the Chicago
theater like I did last weekend.
Two shows,
3,700 people show.
That's a lot of fucking people.
I don't want anybody to be disappointed.
I want to do my best job the best I can
do and that's where my drive is.
My drive is to,
I'm dissecting material,
I'm rewriting it,
I'm practicing.
I'm going.
I went up three times last night.
I'll probably go up.
I'm going up at least two times tonight.
I'm doing the Improv and I'm doing the
comedy store.
I do that all the time,
man.
I do that all the time.
And my drive is to,
there's a great reward in making people
laugh and there's a great reward in,
in d we made an exchange,
you know,
uh,
they came to see me,
I made them laugh.
Everybody's happy.
Look,
we had a deal.
That's the deal.
And I've worked,
it's not an easy deal.
It's like you got to work hard to fill
your end of the bargain.
But if you do work hard and you do work
at it and you do examine it,
you do put in the hours on stage and you
do go over the rewrites and listen to
the recordings and do your best.
It's rewarding.
Yeah.
The reward is that I,
I,
I can say that those people have a good
time.
Like when I put a video up on Instagram,
a bunch of people cheering after the
show,
my feeling,
what am I,
this is like,
we shared this time.
You guys had a good time.
I had a good time.
I'm super happy.
There's nothing like thank you.
Yeah.
Cause I told you I'm,
I'm just getting back in.
So I just booked my last couple of
hours.
So on the nights off that I'm with
Peterson.
So we sold out the DCM prep.
So that champion perhaps holdout Irvine
Improv here or by an Improv.
Yeah.
Urban apro and yeah,
I feel that now cause it's weird because
you don't know me from comedy.
So it's like
I did it.
I lived all those New York City years as
a comic,
never hit into,
I was a good comic,
but I never hit into to TV in that way.
And that's why I started doing all these
other things that led me to this.
But it's like they can put my name up
and now it sells out.
And I was,
it wasn't before.
Right.
So now it's like,
I feel this extra pressure of like,
wow,
these people,
like they're really coming from me.
It is extra pressure,
but it's reward to it too.
It's been awesome.
I mean it's like I'm getting back to
this thing that people don't know me
from and it's like I'm good.
I,
I sent you,
uh,
the hour.
I haven't sent it to anybody.
I'm not putting up publicly,
but I wanted you to see it because even
if you could only watch a minute,
because I wanted you to know that I'm a
real comic,
you know what I mean?
Like,
because otherwise it's like we can all
sit here and be like,
yeah,
I'm kind of blah,
blah,
blah.
Um,
but it's,
it's incredibly powerful.
Like when you're in that room with those
people and you make it real for that.
And I know my style,
like I'm never going to be the best joke
writer on the planet.
It's not where my passions lie,
but I like being in that room with these
people doing what we did here and,
and getting everybody playing and being
in the moment.
And I get people kind of yelling at each
other and screaming and announcing their
political differences and like all this
crazy shit.
And I don't know anyone that's doing it
the way that I'm doing it.
And it's not like I'm doing a set the
way Seinfeld with layout,
you know,
every word,
for the hour.
Um,
well not a,
but I love it.
Again.
It doesn't matter.
The beautiful thing about comedy is any
way you want it.
You do it your way,
your way.
Dave,
we just did three hours.
Shit,
man.
Now I got Sam Harris.
I've got to run home.
I came here from the airport already.
It's already three 20 that's crazy.
I got Harris at four I got to get the
hell Outta here.
Well,
thank you,
man.
It's always a pleasure.
Wait,
hold on.
Now I'm getting you official.
You went to Shapiro before me.
This is what I listen to.
Just it happened and it was free that
day.
We'll do your show.
All right.
I've so many other things to say to you.
Gentleman,
Dave Rubin backs brother.
Thank you.
[inaudible].