Okay,
Ladies and gentlemen,
is the ces wrap up with young Jamie.
Hey.
So uh,
you decided to go to the consumer
electronic show,
this big gigantic expo that they have in
Vegas every year.
It's like the show for new computer,
gadget tree,
everything and like anything you'd see
at like a fry's or best buy from all the
way down to anything that'd be in a car.
Anything in a kitchen or anything in the
bedroom?
Anything.
Consumer electronics basically.
So the show is essentially everything
that's coming out,
all the stuff that's on its way out of
things that have just been announced I
think.
And then I think most of the stuff
that's supposed to be coming out for
sale this year.
Okay.
So some of it is,
we were just about to get into it,
but we were like,
God you got to say it for the podcast.
You were saying that some of it you
think they're kind of bullshitting.
I saw a lot of things that I just like,
they might not be ready or their
prototypes and just like at a car show
too.
There are some things are just showing
you,
this is what we can do right now.
This isn't even what's going to be
available.
This is what we can do.
Maybe if there's a lot of interests will
make it.
For instance,
there was this really cool laptop that
has three screens on it now,
so if the gaming laptop that you can get
some sort of crazy,
but they were just prototypes to and two
of them just got stolen last night or
two days ago.
So they're trying to get at them,
take them back.
So they stole prototypes.
I don't know how that could have even
happened.
Oh,
gross.
How gross to think that some nerds are
thieves,
right?
Wouldn't you like to think that like
whoever,
you know,
whoever you have to be to be an
innovator in technology and electronics,
you would have to be some super fucking
smart guy.
You would think you'd just leave every
room open with people like that.
Wouldn't you like to think that?
I would like.
Yeah,
for sure you'd like to.
But that's accounting world.
I kind of threw them,
but I mean that's fucking crazy.
You know what,
dude,
I'm balls deep into house of cards right
now.
First season apparent.
I didn't know.
There's so many seasons.
It started in 2012.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's three,
three seasons.
I think that's it.
I think so.
Yeah.
So did they take a long time to make a
season?
Yeah,
for sure.
I mean I think they completed it and
then they shot the whole thing then read
it again.
So there's a little bit.
That's good.
God Damn show dude.
A spoiler alert.
She anything,
don't you?
Dare you send.
How many episodes are there?
You think it's probably 11 or 12 and
each one.
So God damn.
It's a good show that Kevin Spacey's
motherfucker.
Woo.
Yeah.
Good ups and
telling me that thing is just the
dumbest shit ever is discussing a show.
Um,
you know,
like today in this day and age,
it's not like you could talk about loss
because it was just on the air,
you know,
when we were watching last,
that's how recent this dvr thing and
this streaming thing has gone.
When we were watching last.
That wasn't a long ago
man.
And everybody waited until it came on
the next week and you could dvr it,
but you didn't.
He didn't.
Bend Watch
wasn't there even that,
uh,
they even did things that we had where
they would show like three episodes and
then take a four week break and then to
show two more and then take another
break.
You remember how that would work.
And then I think the writer's strike
happened in the middle of it too.
So there was a longer gap too.
I think I came into last.
Well I think I got the DVD of like the
second,
the like when the second season was out
of the first season.
I think that's how I got into it.
I kind of trying to remember now.
I really enjoyed it up until the end,
but I'll never forget this one moment.
There was this one moment where they
were all standard around this pond and
it was like some pond that like brings
you back to life or some shit like that.
And they were like,
I don't remember what the scene was,
but it was something insane.
And they're sitting there with their
arms crossed,
waiting for their turn to talk.
Like the scene was so flat and fake.
I was like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
You guys are in front of a magical lake
right now.
You're not freaking out like this is.
This is how you respond.
And you just standing there with your
arms crossed,
just do another merger,
Glueck,
whatever the fuck it was.
I was like,
I can't do this anymore.
I can't do it anymore.
Plus they killed Charlie
once they killed Charlie.
I was that Bonita that day as such.
I was really.
That's probably the best episode of the
whole show.
The whole.
They tied everything together at that
really good,
great show.
That was up until the end.
The end.
Those are keys dot.
Okay.
We're good.
Did you just happens with the show?
It's right.
It's like relationship sometimes.
Just a guy.
Okay.
It was great.
They're getting
enough,
enough fucking zombies enough this
enough ogres
enough that that's Kinda how I am with
game of thrones.
No offense to those dare you well enough
for the dragons and shut your mouth.
That's the one I have in last,
any enthusiasm for,
but I got to tell you,
westworld was so good.
I got sucked in so quick and I in the
possibilities are so fascinating because
they're their timeline jumping and it's
just,
it's really interesting to me.
It was kind of.
They didn't,
they weren't up for many golden gloves
on that,
but hbo didn't win anything and I only
remember seeing one or two westworld
people even up for anything.
It's kind of shitty.
Maybe they missed the nomination date.
I don't know.
How could she not nominate?
That show's awesome.
Fuck.
That shows good.
That's crazy.
Well,
it just shows you if that is the case,
maybe it's just there's a lot of other
shows that are even more awesome.
The we're just not aware of yet.
This seems like the Golden Age for TV
shows.
It really does.
Yeah.
The show.
That one I hadn't heard.
It's called the night manager.
That one,
like a Hugh Laurie who used to be house.
He won an award for that and the other
Guy Tom Hiddleston when another word.
Somebody was just telling me about that.
Someone's short six,
seven episodes.
I think it's a Netflix thing,
right?
I don't.
It might be on Netflix now,
but I think it was on something else to
originally.
This is an amazing time for television.
Think about all the great shows.
I haven't seen the OAA yet,
but I keep hearing that.
It's amazing for.
That's good too.
It's supposed to be A.
I don't want to even want to say what
it's supposed to be.
You're like,
you're not even supposed to know too
much about it before you watch it.
That's the best way to do this.
For sure.
A good way to go.
Like stranger things.
I didn't know shit about stranger things
until I jumped in.
I didn't know a goddamn thing.
I still haven't got play on it yet.
Fuck yeah,
that's good.
That's good.
Don't let.
Don't let red band steer you wrong.
It's some things to see you just see a
tweet some time to just what's in your
head.
I don't know what it is about the day
you see it or the timing was like,
fuck that show.
So He's like,
I've never seen it.
I don't care how it would have been
awesome if you hit play,
but somebody says just it's the first
thing you heard about it and now you're
fucked.
Yeah.
And then you're like,
well,
sometimes you watch it and you're
surprised.
I don't even know how often that happens
when you're surprised on some.
You see,
it's so hard to tell because people's
tastes vary so much.
It's almost like they're watching
something different than you
who you are like as a person,
your life experiences and what that show
means to you when you're watching it.
It's so different for all of us.
Like for each one of us is different.
That's what's weird about televisions.
What's weird about books and music and
comedy and pretty much everything.
It's,
there's not one universal awesome thing.
There's some shit that like everybody
goes,
God down.
It's good no matter what [inaudible]
like,
like Michael Jackson and his prime.
You know,
I remember there was this radio station
in Boston.
Uh,
it was,
um,
I think,
uh,
pretty sure it was wbcn.
It was either wbcn or Wcio Z.
Those are like the two rock stations.
Coc was a little harder.
If you're a nosy person,
you were like a little bit more into
like Metallica a little harder.
Yeah.
And bcn.
I'm pretty sure it's bcn.
They played a Michael Jackson song and
Dez back when Djs could just play music,
you know,
was a different world.
They could just play whatever they
wanted to.
They could just like as if you were a DJ
right now and you had a bunch of records
and you had an internet radio station.
If they let you do it,
I don't think you can,
but if they did let you do it,
you just play those records.
I'm play whatever the fuck you want.
That doesn't exist anymore.
It doesn't exist.
So this dude,
I wish I could remember who it was,
just started playing this Michael
Jackson Song.
He goes,
I don't care why you like this is great
music.
You don't remember the song?
Sure was Billie Jean.
Okay.
I'm sure it was billy Jean because that
wasn't that all off a thriller was
Billie Jean on thriller to.
It's hard,
I think for people today because there's
so many superstars,
there's so many different venues.
I mean there's people that are
superstars just from the Internet.
Yeah,
it was on thriller.
Yeah.
It's hard for people.
I think today I think there's a much,
much larger number of celebrities and
have super celebrities,
you know,
of beyond ses and Jay z and Kanye
West's.
There's so many of those now that it,
it kind of,
um,
we,
we don't,
I don't think we can appreciate today
what it was like when Michael Jackson
was in his heyday because there was
like,
he,
there was one,
it was one guy,
it was one guy that just boom,
there was no one like Michael Jackson,
one guy who had so much impact on the
culture.
People were wearing those stupid jackets
everywhere and dancing that way.
I mean,
Corey Feldman,
Corey Feldman and Corey Haim,
the two of them would go out and they
were buddies with Michael Jackson,
so they would dress like him.
Me,
it was a serious trend,
man.
People wanted a.
There was that trend and there was the
other one with the hat.
Smooth criminal,
there was a little bit of that,
that people were one glove.
Was that a fuck?
Yeah,
they did.
it's hard.
It's,
I think it's hard for us to appreciate
how crazy that was with no internet,
just television stations and radio
stations
and much less people on the planet
that's even weirder.
So what do we have like 100 million more
people than when I was a kid.
What was the,
what was the,
uh,
find out what the population was in 1980
in the United States because that would
have been when I was like 13
because I was in high school in
[inaudible] 81 to 226 point $5 million.
Two hundred million more people here
now.
$100.
Million more people here than when I was
a kid.
That's fucking bananas.
Wow.
That's an insane number
mean.
That's really hard to imagine.
It's really hard to imagine you stop and
think about what that means for another
30 or 40 years.
If it's going to go up another 100
million,
where are we going to put all these
fucking people?
I mean they say that it peaks off
though,
um,
when cities and start doing better
because then they start having less
children because they,
um,
there economic situation turns up and
then a lot of women get careers and
they're more reluctant to give up those
careers to have children and they have
less children when they do have
children.
And so they think that if you look at
the trends towards urbanization,
there could potentially be a time in the
future where we worried about a decline
in population,
like a natural decline.
But it sounds like horse shit to me.
I've heard that too.
I feel like Porsche,
I feel like I've heard it,
that it's happening now that it's not
that we've almost not peaked,
but it's,
it's on a decline in some places for
sure.
I think I've read.
I think people are just moving out of
those spots and coming here.
It's crazy.
It's obvious there's more people now
than ever.
It's a trend.
It's 100 million trend in the last,
whatever it was.
Thirty plus years.
I wish I was trying to pull it up right
now.
I just saw an article yesterday maybe
about how many houses are needed in Los
Angeles to keep up with the housing
required in 100,000 houses a year.
Yeah.
They have to build a 100,000 houses a
year.
Yeah,
and that's like,
that's silly.
Oh my God,
that's insane.
Because there's no room.
I did this thing before my showtime
special in 2005 where I was comparing
like mountains and lakes and rivers to
what you see when you see a city,
how it looks like a growth and then it's
like a lot of other gross,
like even if you burn it,
like you got to burn it all off.
Otherwise it just comes back and it gets
bigger and stronger and if you could
look at it as something.
If you were outside of
our understandings and our knowledge of
what cities are and people and languages
and communities and cultures and if you
could look past all that,
you'd look at these things that are
growing on this planet.
He'd look at this concrete weird fucking
growth and when you break it out,
if that's a real number.
If we need 100,000 houses a year,
I saw this picture,
this was on reddit yesterday or the
other day,
and this is a 60 square foot flat.
It says in Hong Kong,
I believe.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
It's.
It's basically people that I look.
I don't know how many.
This is two people living in here.
It looks like,
at least to.
This is like a closet
and every time the closet,
everything is in there.
The tiny little refrigerator.
Tiny little sink.
This is crazy.
Yeah.
Just sleeping on bunk beds.
It's just this is not good for people.
Yeah.
Why?
Why would people choose to do.
Like if you,
if you weren't a person and you were
looking at this,
you'd be like,
why don't they spread out?
Why don't they spread out?
What are they doing in themselves?
Do they like it like this?
Does they have to be there?
A
family keeps them there.
Then the city or like from keeping for
moving to Hong Kong,
so we can only speculate,
but I think
the population in Hong Kong,
it's fucking bananas.
It's true,
right?
There's just too many fucking people
I.
Yeah.
I don't know,
man.
It just weirds me out.
When you,
when you look at people like a
mathematical thing,
don't just look at him like,
hey,
that's my friend Jamie.
You know,
hey,
that's this guy.
And I know that guy.
Oh,
that guy is cool.
Instead of that,
it's just looking at like math.
Let's just look at the sheer volume.
Then watch it as it multiplies and
continues to multiply in.
That one multiplies and keeps going and
going and then the people move here and
multiply and it's all multiplication.
You're like,
we'll,
we're not planning this out or oh,
we're just stack it up.
Fucking houses weighted mean it's going
to get to a point where there's nothing
else but houses,
if we keep going,
I don't understand why people think that
that's totally sustainable by the way.
That's coming from someone with three
kids.
So I should probably shut the fuck up.
Did you,
uh,
have you,
have you gotten further into Black
Mirror yet?
No,
just two episodes.
I just did two.
I will go,
I will watch more,
but I really enjoyed the memory one.
That was the one that you kept telling
me,
you saying?
Yep,
Yep.
Well they had an awesome take on it too,
that the um,
I don't want to spoiler alert anybody,
but they,
um,
they were able to record their memories
and that's what we've been talking about
that for years that I think,
you know,
I think a lot of people have been
talking about that because it's pretty
obvious transition between being able to
record memories with your phone,
which is essentially that's what a felon
does.
You know,
when you're taking photos and videos and
stuff from your phone,
you recording memories and how long
before it's somewhere where you could
play it on your brain.
I could see it in your head and you
know,
we,
we've,
we think that
I would,
I would love to see
if there is a way that they can even
take photos that way because I know they
can transfer images.
They can transfer like an image into
someone's mind now.
Like in like very like simple,
like a triangle and you see a triangle.
Isn't that in that the latest
sorta.
I mean it's still a.
okay.
I know you're talking about.
Yeah,
and there was one where they were able
to transmit a word through the Internet.
Right?
That was more like a one and zero thing.
It was like on or off,
like are you feeling and not kind of
thing.
That's what it was.
I thought it was an actual word or
gotten into what a word is spelled that
they might have spelled out the word.
I don't think it was a spelled out
thing.
I wish I could remember the explanation
they gave for it,
but I think it was like what that word
represents,
you know,
like.
So the intent of that word
and like so the person on the other
side,
like I knew the word,
like know or knew the word not or
whatever the word was
says they were able to send the words
Ola and chow from Indian France subjects
solve messages of flashes of light in
the peripheral vision.
The results described as remarkable step
in human communication.
Who that is fucking crazy.
They're sending messages through the
Internet.
They were able to send the words,
scroll up a little bit back where they
were.
They were able to send the words Olan
Chow from a location in India to
location and France transmitted signals
directly.
Wow.
Like this is nuts.
It's just hard to imagine
how far that could go.
You know they can do that.
Now.
What I've been thinking,
this sounds like total bananas,
but I've really been thinking a lot
about it lately is that you don't have
the internet kind of allows everybody to
communicate together.
You,
you can have your twitter account and
your facebook and all that jazz.
I feel like what's gonna happen with
this kind of technology and this sort of
hive mind technology.
It's if they can transmit signals from
one person to another person through the
brain with with this technology.
This is real similar to like when they
first started putting things on message
boards and the Internet and bulletin
boards and like someone would put it up
and then you'd have to check it and that
was the only method of communication.
Like my friend Andrew's talked to me
about that a lot.
He was on in the really early days of
the Internet and those se bulletin
boards were really primitive and this is
one of the first things that people had
devised to communicate with online,
but now here we are 20 years later and
it's fucking,
you're streaming live on instagram and
you're doing facebook live and you know,
people are taking pictures
instantaneously uploading them and
they're gonna they're gonna be able to
some way somewhere,
another allow us to interface with our
brain's the same way we interfaced using
these phones and using computers.
I was just a way,
if that happens,
would,
uh,
I mean,
I don't know how this work.
This obviously was a two way
communication.
They're both wanting it to happen.
In this scenario you're bringing up
like,
what if a,
you sent me a message I didn't want,
I will or I didn't want to have right
then I didn't want.
Right now I'm busy,
I'm doing something else.
Or You just blasting me with this
message.
Like,
hey,
wake up,
wake up.
I'm going to come to sleep.
Or who knows what's going on,
or I'm getting 10 messages from all
over.
I'm getting spam messages from outside
too because they're going to be a way to
turn it off.
Well,
I mean we're probably going to be able
to opt out of it,
but how many people are going to opt out
of it?
Like,
and even if you do,
maybe you could turn it off airplane
mode,
you know,
and like you do what your phone
at night if you're watching a TV show or
something.
I think that if you're,
if you're really gonna keep going with
this and it seems like they're gonna.
I mean if they're doing things like
this,
it's not going to stop right there.
It's not going well.
We did it.
That's awesome.
Let's just leave it there.
No,
there they have these new batteries.
Have you seen these new fucking
batteries that uh,
they're powering with nuclear waste?
No.
Yeah,
the last for like 5,000 years.
I did see that Tesla's factory got
turned on and they started making
batteries.
Oh really?
Yeah.
There was something about batteries
being made with nuclear waste.
Um,
diamond battery made from nuclear ladies
can last more than 5,000 years.
Oh yeah.
Put that in a cell phone and put it
right next to your Dick.
That shouldn't hurt him at all because
radioactive sources in case safely
within the diamond,
the hardest known substance it would be
safe to use.
Say the researchers.
Fuck those guys.
They're going to open up a port to hell.
Those guys from halflife.
Fuck you man.
Fuck you.
You're going to put what?
And you know the chicks are going to
want God damn nuclear diamond.
You know those really super fucking high
maintenance checks.
They're all gonna want nuclear diamonds,
like a regular diamonds.
Not going to be good enough.
That's going to be the next top level
shit is a diamond with nuclear waste
inside of it.
You see this a cremation diamonds.
People are being cremated and turned
into diamonds.
Yeah.
Wonderful.
So what that those two things possibly
related.
It's cremations.
Weird ways and you were probably fucked
can over nature by being cremated.
We really are.
We're probably fucking over nature also
with a formaldehyde.
You know,
I mean there's some,
that's probably one of the disconnects
that we have with nature,
like we don't absorb into it anymore.
We don't,
we don't,
we don't just bury our dead and then let
the body do its natural decomposing
process and then become a part of the
natural ecosystem.
Now we've completely removed ourselves
from it.
We take the body,
we drain all the shit out of it.
We fill it up with chemicals we spray.
Painted is weird man.
Have you seen a body like that's about
to be buried?
Not for awhile,
but yeah,
my grandpa freaked me out
cause I was like,
wow,
he's not there.
Like,
this is weird.
It didn't,
it wasn't.
There was nothing good about it.
It was nothing good about being there
like that.
It was,
I don't want to use the words grotesque,
but there is something severely damaged
about the idea behind it.
It was like,
oh my God.
I felt like I was watching some crazy
ritualistic shit.
You know,
that was like reenacted from the
primitive days of early man.
I mean,
looking down at this spray painted shell
of a human,
it's just,
it's bizarre man.
Uh,
you could tell that's not.
He's not really there.
What is this?
These are different funerals.
What does it say?
Puerto Rican gangster.
Puerto Rico gangster.
Propped up playing dominoes at his
funeral.
Oh God.
As Superhero.
Oh my God.
This guy's in a car.
Jesus Christ.
This is crazy.
I've seen.
I've had like different disguises.
Here's a boxer.
Oh my God.
He's a boxer.
So they put him in his
warm up suit and they put them in a
corner of a ring.
Jesus Christ.
This is crazy.
He's got sunglasses on.
I want you have sunglasses and you read
about the fight and
want to see a crazy fucking picture.
That Guy Joseph Smith Jr who just
knocked out Bernard Hopkins first day on
the job since he won the world title and
he's got a photo of themselves,
a Gi Joe Smith Jr.
He's got to.
He's got two instagrams where I saw it.
Maybe cHabad it up.
Yeah,
there it is.
Look at that.
Joe smith's first day on the job.
Since he one.
I mean,
this guy just knocked out bernard
hopkins and he has a construction worker
job.
it's crazy.
It's insane.
that's insane.
Hey dude,
quit that job.
As I say,
do you think at this point he needs to
do that?
I don't know how much you got paid,
you know,
he might just be a and have another
fight lined up or.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think everyone would just assume that
if someone's world champion that they're
rIch,
but it's not really the case.
You have to be a famous world champion.
the real,
the money.
I Mean the money's in promotion.
The money is in,
you know,
a guy like oscar de la hoya in his
prime.
He was a,
like a teen idol and also an amazing
boxer or olympiC gold medalist that
kinda guy sold tickets.
Floyd mayweather sells tickets.
Mandy pack out sells tickets
now.
Joe smith jr.
His next fight will probably make a lot
of money.
You know,
this was an opportunity for him and he
capitalized on it and he knocked out one
of the greatest of all time,
but it was
just weird to see them working.
You know,
that fight was fucked though.
I know what rounded that happened in
like the fourth or the fifth,
I don't remember.
But uh,
he had,
he had been getting to bernard hopkins
and it looked like one of those classic
fights where the old veteran just as
lost a step,
You know,
he was getting to bernard hopkins,
he tagged when some big shots and then
when he got him in the corner and just
unloaded those shots on him and then
bernard fell back on his head.
I was Like,
god,
this is just so fucked up.
It's just such a fucked up way to end an
amazing career.
Dan is just what that sport does,
does what that sport does.
There's no getting around that.
If you're a 51 year old band and you're
trying to fight one of the best young
lions in the game.
Especially,
he's not on pds or anything.
He's not on any.
I don't.
I mean,
I don't think he is.
He might be.
I doubt it.
He seems like Just a super disciplined
guy and his body sort of reflectS that.
He doesn't quite have the same body that
he had when he was younger,
but he still looked very fit.
Like when he was younger,
he was a savage.
I mean when he beat like felix trinidad,
nobody gave him a chance.
Everybody thought he was done.
They thought he was old.
I feel extremely.
That was going to fuck him up.
And he went on to fight for like 13 more
years.
Yeah,
man,
he fucked up.
Kelly pavlock,
they thought he was old.
Then he went to fight kelly pavlick and
everybody's like,
oh,
this is going to be a bad fight for
bernard hopkins.
You know,
he's,
you know,
I think he was 39 or something like
that.
I forget how old he was.
I remember.
That.
Might've been a little younger than
that.
Anyway,
he fucked up.
Kelly pavlik.
No,
he was in his forties.
Find out how old bernard hopkins was
when he fought kelly pavlik after
pavlock had already become the champ.
Right?
Yeah.
I want to say he pavlock had beaten
jermaine taylor.
Right.
And I think man,
hopkins might've been 40 years old at
the time,
cause it's just,
you stop and think about boxers.
In the paSt there was a few guys like
archie moore,
George Foreman,
he was 43 and 26.
That's crazy.
And almost 10 years later he's trying to
still do that with these murderous white
men because kelly pavlock was a
murderous white dude to murderous
puncher.
And then thIs,
uh,
Joe Smith juniors at ferocious puncher
or he's just a killer.
Bernard hopkins,
like you got a one thing you gotta give
the guy is amazing as his career has
been.
Even at the very last fight,
he takes the toughest fight he can find
or one of the toughest ones.
Just a real young dangerous kid.
But it just,
even though like we've seen it happen
with sugar ray leonard,
we saw it.
I mean,
remember when sugar ray leonard got beat
up by hector camacho.
I just in long.
And hector camacho just beat the shit
out of him.
And it's like,
wow,
this is weird to watch.
And he had billy blanks in his corner.
Billy blanks,
teaching them tibo
dead.
He had billy blanks.
Billy blanks is a karate champion too.
He was a yoke dude,
and you know,
knows a lot aBout fitness,
but apparently triggered something
fucked up with his calf,
like you pulled a muscle in his calf.
Then he had to get a cortisone shot
before the fight.
He had like a little bit of a limp.
I remember would Hector camacho fucked
him up?
But the really scary one was Terry
Norris when Terry Norris beat up sugar
ray leonard.
Do you remember that?
Terry norris jr
does.
Terry norris.
He put a beating on a lot of dudes.
He was a scary kid
when he was at his best terry noises
like lightning.
Yeah.
This is when Terry Norris was,
you know,
world class and he was just a step
faster than sugar ray.
And you could see he's getting into him.
Terry norris,
he had been knocked out a few times
himself to man.
He got gotten the war is one of the
exciting things about norris was that he
would,
he would get hit,
he would get in front of guys and he
would,
you know,
really take some risks and one of the
reasons why he was so fun to watch,
but yeah,
this is just,
I don't even remember exactly how this
fight ends,
but I'm pretty sure terry stopped him.
Oh,
this is just round seven.
I thought it was a highlight or.
Oh no.
Oh yeah.
They got knocked down.
Yeah.
See when you see shit like that,
like,
whoa.
See him,
get up staggered.
We've seen this so many times.
It shouldn't.
It shouldn't be weird at all.
Oh,
what a good time for the internet to
freeze.
It shouldn't be a confusing to us,
but it's just some.
It's this story that repeats itself over
and over and over again.
It doesn't seem like anybody ever learns
their lesson.
There's a few guys that get out on top,
lIke if I really do hope,
floyd mayweather says fuck you to
everybody.
It just takes all that money.
I really do hope he does that.
I would love to see a guy get through
the whole thing without ever getting
fucked up once,
like I mean if you think about what he's
done,
made stupid amounts of money and got
through the whole thing,
might have gotten her three or four
times and it's whole career.
Might have gotten tagged,
never got beat up,
never got knocked out.
Just get tagged a few times over the
course of how many fights.
I mean,
that's beautiful.
Someone can do
that.
That's like retiring as a bmx rider with
no broken bones.
Is that possible to do?
I don't think that.
No.
Yeah.
See what,
what he's done.
If floyd mayweather retires,
he's done the thing that nobody ever
does.
He went out on top undefeated with all
the money after having fought all
challengers mean he might've fought pack
y'all late,
but you can't deny that he fought all
challengers.
Hooky as fuck.
I mean the 50 things seems to be an
issue or not an issue.
Forty to 50.
You know,
whether or not he wants to break the
record.
I mean how much of that as his ego.
That's gonna last for.
I mean,
he's still pretty young,
right?
Yeah.
I mean he's,
I think he's 36 if I had a gas,
but he's in really good shape.
I mean he takes care of himself really
well.
He's notoriously disciplined about
workouts and he'll even go out at night,
go to a nightclub,
drink water,
and then work out at 2:00 in the morning
because he has his own gym and his own
thing and he and he works hard.
You don't get that good on just talent.
You know,
you get that good on talent and
discipline and hard fucking work.
There's just no way around it.
And smart.
You've got to be smart too.
You got to be sneaky.
You got to be clever.
Do you see,
uh,
who is training right now for a fight?
Yeah.
He's a trained soldier.
Boy,
soldier boy is really going to fight
chris brown.
Is that real?
I don't.
I mean,
it doesn't seem like it,
but it's been talked about for a few
days now.
Apparently it's going to be on paper
view.
Um,
and fighting over a girl.
Don't.
I'm going to tell you right now,
chris brown is gonna fuck him up.
Probably.
Yeah.
That's an angry dude that.
See,
that dude is on the left with the red.
That's a real angry dude.
The other dude,
I just do not think he is angry,
but knows,
man,
I've never seen either of them
personally know
one of them.
Maybe soulja boy's been hide some sick
boxing skills and just pretending this
whole time,
I doubt it.
See,
I feel like chris brown is probably
punched a lot more people,
you know,
don't you think?
I don't know.
All,
you know,
wife beating girl beating jokes aside.
He's definitely seems like a dude who is
much more likely to punch people.
Um,
maybe,
maybe more likely to,
but I couldn't really see neither either
of them getting in like a street fight
or anything.
They've been pretty famous for most of
their life and pretending to hm.
Interesting.
Since they're in their teens,
um,
two guys,
shit happens.
So I mean they might have thrown some
darn down once or twice.
Oh
boy.
Here's another thing.
Here's another reason why I say chris
brown.
Chris brown is a real fucking dancer
here.
See that guy move?
Oh yeah,
yeah.
He could do some crazy shit.
He's really good In basketball.
Basketball.
Listen,
this is going to be a bloodbath.
I might be wrong.
What'd you buy it?
Yeah,
I'll fucking buy it.
You know.
And if a soldier boy fucks him up,
I'll,
I'll apologize.
Have a.
I was trying to think about this.
Hasn't there been other things?
I mean,
I know you were supposedly supposed to
fight wesley snipes,
but like wasn't there other things like
this ever happen?
The whole celebrity boxing show.
I remember That happened a couple times.
Yeah.
Danny bonaduce fought screech.
Um,
he fucked up a couple of people.
I remember when I was younger,
there were supposed to be a big event
where shaquille o'neal was supposed to
go one on one on pay per view with this
other big player named chemo chemo one
box.
Not box.
They were going to come play basketball
one on one for a million dollars,
but it never ended up happening.
I don't know wHy.
Oh,
it went away,
but I was just kinD of wondering in my
head like I feel like this is how I've
heard things like this coming up and
have like,
or at least been announced,
but that just kind of fizzle out.
Who knows,
man,
I mean,
people have done crazy shit.
This just seems like a really,
really nutty one and they're fighting
over a girl.
I just.
Have you seen any evidence of soldier
boy's athleticism?
He,
somebody put up a video of him working
out.
There's a compilation of him working
It's,
but it's hard to tell if he's just being
silly,
you know?
I was like,
he's a,
he's shadow boxing and he's riding an
elliptical machine.
He seems like a really young guy.
How old is he?
Man?
In his twenties still too.
He's in his twenties.
Yeah.
Well there's,
there's a bunch of this complication
here is so
whoever they do,
that was it.
He was like,
oh man.
He goes,
you're working out with your socks on.
This is not the same compilation,
but it was pretty funny.
He's like,
only real savages.
Workout with their socks off.
I don't know,
man,
it's just,
you know,
why do they want to do this?
There's two,
I don't know,
they need a hug it out.
When you were talking about that black
mirror episode,
I forgot.
That's the one that you saw.
Uh,
one of the things I actually got on and
was seeing shown at this seat.
Yes.
Event was that I showed it to the other
night that gopro gimbal I got.
It's called the a karma grip,
lets you hold onto it.
I'll see it if you want,
but this is some of the video I shot
with it.
And so the idea is that it balances
itself.
Put the camera,
the camera's on you.
So like you just kind of hold it and it
keeps itself stem stable.
So like as you can jiggle it around a
little bit and it stays pretty simple.
And this was me walking around.
I have it at two to a double speed here.
But this was connected to my shoulder
basically.
And I was walking.
So you taped it to shoulder?
Uh,
I had a velcro strap
like this.
I had a brown my backpack.
And so I was just kind of like walking
around the event and here's one of the,
here's one of the cool things I did see
at the event too was a projector that's
projecting on,
um,
it's,
it's the stabilization actually
stay up,
but this,
uh,
this projector right here is projecting
onto a curtain,
which I kind of ran past it pretty fast.
I wasn't really shooting my video for
that purpose,
but
let's take a shower curtain with like a
pattern on it.
Yeah.
But it's showing a solid image on that.
Exactly.
It's showing a hockey game and you're
not seeing the ripples,
so you don't need a flat screen for this
projector.
You can project it on anything.
And I got three exactly.
Or ideally you would want something a
little smoother than that.
But yeah,
you could still have a flat image on
that.
So,
uh,
that was pretty neat.
But some of this video is pretty cool on
the stabilization.
And then I went over to the samsung
booth and they have what they're kind of
showing here.
Is this stuff flat flat hanging tv.
Which different.
Only way it's different from the things
now as like when you hang a tv up on a
wall,
it's kind of hanging off about four to
six inches.
This is literally flat.
Don't know if you can see right there.
Yeah,
it looks like I couldn't get very close
paper.
Yeah,
but you can't really.
I don't know if you could slide anything
in there.
It says it's a no gap wall mount and
then there's really no cords hanging off
of there either.
It's one cord.
No htmi.
I don't even know if power was coming
off of it either.
It then one optical cord.
So it's like using light optical cables.
Use light waves.
So the one chord is powering it and
providing the data.
See it says invisible connection right
there on top.
It's showing some of the data.
Well,
it kind of makes sense.
What would they can do now with these
power?
I should say
set a power.
It hasn't,
but it does.
Do all the four k data does the htmi in
every place has all of that.
But with these new iphones,
with that,
uh,
what is that connection connecting
lightning connector,
that connector,
you use it for sound like.
Well,
your earplugs.
Yep.
Your era earbuds,
you use it for,
um,
an external microphone.
You can use it for the charges if you
could split it off so it charges it at
the same time.
You're also listening to music so both
things can go through at the same time.
Um,
another interesting thing that was being
shown is some transparent,
uh,
lcd screens.
So I'm trying to say this one a little
bit.
This one right here in the middle,
discuss trying to show you.
This screen right here is actually a
full lcd screen pointing at the corner,
but there's an art display shown over
top of it,
like an eight ink art display.
So when you're not using it,
when you're not using the tv,
it looks like a piece of art hanging on
your wall with the rest of the art.
Wow.
Oh,
so it's a screensaver,
basically a screensaver.
That's insane.
And there were a couple other companies
showing some seethrough lcd screens that
great idea white.
These are all,
still haven't come to market yet,
but this is some of the stuff that
they're showing.
It's so beautiful too.
That's beautiful artwork and if you can
do it with that kind of resolution.
I'm here.
I was just,
I looked at some three d,
so the curved,
curved,
uh,
monitors.
This is like the most curved monitor
ever.
I'm still not super sold on these.
I don't really understand why everyone
or why they're selling them so hard.
I don't really have an interest in
buying when I've tried a few times to
look at it,
but
it's very gimmicky.
It seems to me like,
um,
remember when those three d tvs were
coming out and everyone was trying to
convince everybody you need to get it.
Three d tvs coming and I've watched it
for like a couple of minutes with the
glasses on.
I was like,
this is not going to work.
This is not here yet.
Know it's just two goofy that's gone.
Pretty much gone.
I think that's the same with these
things.
I think people are,
you're going to use them for awhile then
you're going to go with.
But this is,
why is it,
why am I doing this?
Why am I curving the fucking
screen?
It seems like it's only for one viewer
too.
Cause if your curve and it's for the
other people,
then they can't.
It's fucks it up for everybody else.
It makes it to one person.
But I would say the majority of people's
use of computers is probably one person.
Right,
right.
Yeah,
for sure.
At least one person at a time.
So in this video you can also see kind
of how crowded this whole event was to.
Is.
This is a.
I walked 25 miles,
I think my,
my fitbit tracked 25 miles in two days.
Wow.
And that was the only six to seven hours
per time that tired after that.
Yeah.
Dude,
you had a workout for sure.
And I was carrying around a backpack,
a pounds of gear in it.
But here's an interesting new laptop
coming out.
You can't really get a good view on it.
I kind of picked it up.
It's literally,
I think it weighs less than a pound or
right around a pound.
And it felt like a,
like a kid's toy.
That's how the plasticky it did,
I don't want to say it felt cheap,
but it felt like a toy.
It felt like you could just throw it
like a frisbee.
But it was a full laptop made by
samsung.
Uh,
and had an lcd screen.
I had a full keyboard,
I had a mouse pad and they had a little,
uh,
I think it was a scale next to each
thing that just proved to you how much
it weighed.
But are you that much of a pussy that
you can carry around a one pound laptop?
Get it?
Yes and no,
but I mean the safe.
If you want to take one hunting and you
need to,
you all your ounces like oh yeah,
well
definitely shouldn't take a laptop or
anything.
But if you did,
yeah,
you would definitely want to do that.
Yeah.
Guys cut their toothbrushes in half.
There's a lot of like drastic weight
reduction when it comes to those things.
But I just feel like for laptops it's
not that hard to carry one around and
you know,
you put it on your back and to me like
features and a hard drive and
speed and that's the most important
shit.
Like yeah,
it's not that hard to carry a pound or
two pounds or whatever the fuck it is.
Three pounds.
It's not that hard.
They haven't gotten that back crazy.
I guess they are getting all lighter.
Yeah.
Means that doesn't weigh that much.
Those retina displays are very light and
it's beautiful.
You know?
And then they have the heirs and those
are featherlite.
You don't need anything lighter than a
goddamn mac book.
Air sure that.
Nothing.
There's got to be a reason.
There's got to be a small market.
It also probably is way cheaper than a
macbook air.
I would have to say.
Well you remember when people want it
smaller and smaller phones,
we bias fullness that big.
I saw a phone once that like it was so
small that like there was a dial for.
I'm trying to remember how the fucking
numbers were pressed.
There was some novel way of like they
barely could fit a number pad like to
dial phone numbers,
so they had some weird dial thing to it.
Trying to remember just reminded me,
I might be making this up.
Iphone prototype.
It showed an iphone prototype.
I don't know how it came out today or
not today,
but this week someone made a or showed
video of how one of the ways in Iceland
was supposed to originally work and it
was using that scroll wheel that used to
be on an eye on the old ipods.
Do remember that?
Yeah,
so someone kind of hacked it together.
I think on a current iphone to show you
how this worked,
this operating system worked,
but it seemed like the aap obviously
worst way ever to be controlling a phone
because even I think you would had to
input numbers that way by scrolling two,
three,
four seems so bad.
It was that really considered.
I mean it's work.
It's a working prototype,
so I'd have to say someone at least
thought it might've been a good idea.
Well,
it has to be that they went through a
bunch of different ideas before they
came up with the.
Yeah,
I mean I heard they're going through 10
different phones right now just to try
to figure out what the next iphone
they're going to go with this or 10
different testing models.
So do you think that they've hit that
point of critical mass where it's like
unless something really huge comes along
like a hologram projectors or something
really bananas,
you've got everything now you've got
amazing cameras,
you've got massive hard drive space,
you've got so much you've got.
You have all these apps that you can
use.
You've got all this usability,
like what are you gonna do that's gonna
make people want like a next generation
and next generation and next generation.
Like there has to be some sort of a leap
because it seems like for all the
technology we have today,
people are almost like over computered
and an over phoned.
Right?
Definitely for sure.
I mean,
I was trying to walk when I was walking
around that event,
I was looking for like either the big
crowds to see what everyone was like
stuck around looking at because this
event was so huge to,
to stop and spend five minutes at a,
at a particular,
I don't know,
a pod or product
or even just let someone talk to you to
take your time for that five minutes is
insane because there's just so much to
look at.
Um,
but at the same time,
well I kind of lost what I was doing
there,
but um,
I just kind of looked over at this thing
I wanted to show you,
which was distinct called vertifi,
which is this three d virtual reality
program who,
um,
they showed this guy over here doing a
demo for it.
I didn't want to wait in line.
I really didn't want to wait in any
lines there because there was so many
people and I didn't feel very good to
stand somewhere for 30 minutes.
Sweat
young.
Jamie got the same stomach flu that I
had.
But uh,
what this shows right here is this.
I think I'm pretty sure that this thing
on top of yours to camera that records
the event.
Hmm.
Then what they were showing,
this guy was getting a demo of it,
which I wasn't seeing on this screen,
but they did show and you can kind of
see.
I'm pinching his hand up there on top
on this video.
They show you watching,
uh,
with a vr headset,
let's say a concert.
And then you can decide to grab the lead
singer and move them into your living
room.
So the performance this now he's not,
I don't know,
it was real weird how it showed it and I
don't have it on this actual video.
I went back and watched another
and so he's wearing some fairly small
goggles.
It was not,
not a lot to what he's wearing.
Yeah.
That's one of the,
uh,
one.
There's about four or five big things
going on there.
There's vr headsets,
different new multiple companies sharing
vr headsets.
Was this augmented or was it virtual
reality?
Because I believe it was the virtual
reality,
but he reached up and grabbed someone,
pinched it and brought it in yet.
But it would have to be a little
augmented because you were seeing it in
your living room.
You'd have to also see the living room.
Yeah.
If you go back to the video,
you being there,
like see,
like when you see his actual goggles
itself,
like watch ice pass by a little bit on
the can see it.
See that's the lead singer.
Moved onto the couch.
Just bringing the artists to our home.
How bizarre.
Which would I.
I kind of like pulled into the comedy
world.
You could bring the comedian into your
living room and just have performed
performing your front and your living
room instead of at the comedy.
That venue that they were at,
which would be interesting.
Yeah.
How odd.
Uh,
drones was a big a big thing.
There are tons of drones now,
right?
Tiny ones.
There's this selfie drone which didn't
seem like it worked very well.
It kept flying up and flying down
different sides.
I'm not quite sure how you're supposed
to do
controlled.
Go.
Go through this for a couple more
seconds to see that guy's a goggles
because I think he gets see through
them.
See,
look how he's looking.
Yeah.
Okay.
See how you see his eyes.
I mean that's what it seems like to me.
I have that microsoft surface.
Oh sure.
And there's a behind it too as a
wireless vr headset.
So they were,
like I said too,
there were a lot of headsets and there
are lots of things and let's.
Let me just throw out a number and say I
did five tech demos out of those five,
two or three didn't work or that didn't
go well or that didn't work perfectly at
all.
So thAt's where I've kind of like,
I don't know that a lot of this stuff
wasn't maybe not ready or maybe it was
supposed to be shown that way.
And you're.
This is like,
this is our only demo product we have
for you guys to see where it's supposed
to work all the time.
It usually does,
but we've done so many demos today.
It kind of froze up a little bit.
That could have been happening to a
little bit,
but there is a lot of things going on
here where they're just trying to show
you some.
Show you an idea and hope someone with a
lot of money walks by and I was like,
ah,
that looks like a good idea here.
Some one kid
go make it.
That kind of thing.
Like some 19 thirties carnival barker
and know it works out for that.
does that happen?
Are there lIke guys who troll around
this place and look for a.
I saw products.
I just walked by.
Oh,
the intel booth and randomly saw a guy
will walk up to one of their workers and
say like,
I have some patents on baseball,
wifi technology,
who do I talk?
That kind of thing.
So that's all.
there's tons of different meetings.
Things sorting are happening by the way,
in case anybody misinterprets what I'm
saying.
Troll around.
I don't mean like a fuck with people on
the internet troll.
I mean like fishing troll.
when you drag a line behind you go look
for things to catch.
Do you think that um,
this,
this was like the big thing in this ces
though as far as emerging technologies
with all this virtual reality stuff
every year it is a.
Apparently it's focused on something
different.
Like this year there wasn't very much
cell phone,
anything really and used in the past
years,
like there's been big announcements of
cell phones from different companies.
I think I only even solid maybe one and
it was this company called highway,
I believe it's how you say it because
they had a,
they paired with this a really well
known camera company called leica and
have a 20 megapixel camera.
They make binoculars and stuff too.
Um,
but I tested that out to see how good it
was and I wasn't sure if I was holding
the actual correct model,
which was the one that had all the best
features in it because I had a couple of
different models out there.
So much going on there.
It was really hard to get a grasp of
what you were doing.
That's really interesting.
You bring this up.
It's making me think like when you get
to a certain level of this virtual
reality stuff,
you're gonna want to look through like
the best lens available.
You know,
you're gonna want one of those high end
binocular companies to come along and
craft something.
Yeah.
I'm trying to remember right now.
I want to say it's gopro.
I'll have to google it for.
I kind of say something off,
but do you know,
have you heard of the company called
hasselblad?
Yes,
I believe,
yeah.
Go camera company that they were the
people that uh,
had the cameras that they put on the
moon.
Yeah,
I think it's dji,
dji mobile.
Allegedly they were on the moon.
Yeah.
So dji is a arguably the best drone
maker right now.
They're biggest company.
It's a company come out of China.
They make a,
the phantom,
which was,
uh,
the biggest consumer drone and right now
they just put out the thing called the
maverick,
which is.
So they acquired hassle bad.
Apparently they had a minor stake in the
company and they just took a major
stake.
So they just took over the stockholding
what's the correct pronunciation?
It's hassle bland.
I believe so,
yeah.
So dgi is this,
they made this thing called the
maverick,
which I got to hold up the event.
I didn't get the buy one.
They're not there on backorder still
right now.
They've been there for a little while
folded up because each of these legs
folds together.
It's a a little bit smaller,
a little bit bigger than this than my
iphone seven s a little bit thicker.
You can see that sticker,
but the actual size you can hold it and
it's about same size as the palm of your
hand.
HolY shit.
And it shoots four k video.
It goes up to,
I want to say for about four miles away
from you.
Yeah,
so you'd obvIously you're going to lose
sight of it and it goes to I think 20,
30,
40 miles an hour or something like that.
Something crazy and this is a bite sized
god.
Does it avoid avoid things or obstacle
avoidance?
That's what these cameras on the front
floor.
There's some on the back or the bottom
too,
so they have another versIon which is
the phantom four.
A pro I believe,
which is a bigger version than this.
They have an inspired,
which is the way bigger version and then
they have like the full film,
like a film company would use,
which has got like eight big crazy props
on it and whatnot.
Do you remember when they filmed that
movie?
The twilight zone and they didn't have
drones back then.
They had a helicopter and actual real
helicopter behind them doing a stunt.
which
do you remember that there was a
horrible accident?
Um,
man,
it was a horrible accident where the
actor in this little girl were killed.
Oh wait.
The helicopter came crashing down on
them that you said that there was two
people.
I think I did hear about it.
Don't even show me this dude.
I don't even want to watch that shit.
We can try.
I didn't see it.
Something.
Something about
seeing people die for a movie too.
It's like particularly gruesome.
It's like why?
How did you think that you could just
fly that helicopter right next to
people?
Hm.
Well,
with all this drone stuff,
I'm able to kind of asked you this
question because I don't know if it's an
actual trend I see happening or if it's
just something they're forcing or what,
but there's just seems to be a lot of,
uh,
camera equipment being made available
for the individual to use to make really
high end stuff.
And I don't know if it's the trend that
people were just going to start making
all this content.
Are they gonna just start shooting
everything they're doing?
Are they just making it as technology
and allowing that to happen for us?
Well,
it seems like there's only so much you
can do with it.
I feel like what would they have to do
though is have the best shit.
So thing if someone has four k you have
to have four k,
you know,
someone has um,
virtual capability,
you could upload it digitally.
It's like fitness trackers were really
big there.
I still,
I,
I don't remember who it was that came in
here.
I think it was the first time burke came
in with one.
I sort of tried to ask him,
I was like [inaudible].
I had one too for a couple of weeks,
but it took it back because it got
recalled,
but I was like,
what are you doing with that?
The one I had at the time got recalled,
it was for what?
It was causing a rash on people because
the battery connector wasn't.
Oh,
right.
I don't know.
They fixed it apparently now,
but I haven't bought another one since
then because I found out that the fitbit
app on my iphone works just about the
same and there's also the built in apple
iphone apps now to that do the health
stuff,
but what w,
what is everyone doing with all that
data or are they doing anything with it?
Mostly at all besides really,
really,
really into fitness.
People like personal trainers.
Well,
I think there's some technologies that
even though they keep getting better and
better,
they're kind of ignored after awhile.
like here's one of the most bizarre
ones.
His voice sound quality.
Nobody gives a fuck about when anybody's
voice sounds like on a phone.
It's like it almost never gets
discussed.
Like,
isn't that one of the most important
things about a phone?
You should be able to listen to someone
on a phone and it should sound like
they're talking to you and she'd be
like,
right here.
Like,
what's up jamie?
Oh hey,
what's up dude?
It never sounds that good.
Yeah,
ever.
but they have the ability to make it
sound that good.
Well why haven't they made it sound that
good?
People barely fucking use their phone as
a phone anymore.
The phone part is totally stagnant.
Like the signal gets a little bit
better.
You can catch a signal somewhere else,
but it still sounds just as shitty as it
ever did.
It doesn't sound perfect.
Clarity doesn't sound like you talking
to me in the same room you telling me
they can't do that.
Of course they can do that.
If they could get you to listen better
now with a better sound now than then
the rotary phones,
the 19 sixties,
they could improve on the sound quality,
but there's no demand for it because
people hardly talk on the phone anymore.
So iT becomes one of those things where
it just hits a certain point,
nobody gives a fuck about it.
And then the market goes where people
give a fuck that people give a fuck
about cameras.
You got to get a juicy camera.
I want a 15,
18,
whatever a megapixel is.
It sounds awesome.
Get me one of those.
Oh,
it's gigapixel they have gigapixels I
need to get your pixel.
You know,
how many people are just just buyIng the
latest shit me included because it's the
latest shit cuz it sounds awesome,
you know,
because you want that one.
Oh,
the asce has the uh,
image stabilization that I'll never use.
There's so much of that shit out there,
but it seems so compelling.
you know,
like if apple had an iphone eight,
you and me would be in line like a
couple of years.
Like I still keep talking to.
Sometimes I
think about this for the seven s I have.
It's like it's either I have it,
I like it,
that the camera's on is really good,
but it's so big.
I kind of dislike it.
How dare you?
I liked the,
I liked the smaller phone,
I like to success.
Well the six or the seven,
you know,
you can get a regular size one,
two,
but the stats on the phone or are,
are down.
It's not as,
it's not as good as a phone as the
seven.
S is really seven s plus or we're a
Yeah.
Um,
as far as the hard drive in as far as
battery life.
Right.
It's got dual cameras.
The other ones don't have the battery
on.
This is actually really good.
I'm very good.
I'm super surprised at how good the
battery is on his phone.
Especially if you don'T keep wifi and
bluetooth on all the time.
You can last two days almost,
which is way surprising because the
screen's way bigger,
but I don't.
I could sit when the next one comes out
and a couple of them.
What a couple of months they're going to
announce it probably in march or may and
there'll be out by the fall like,
or do we need it again?
And then the answer is like why?
Because we're shooting it has four k
video on it and say,
yeah,
I one has four k video,
but I've barely done anything with the
four k video and the four k video I do
have where like or with this go pro,
I just got the new gopro five you have
to
convert all the footage so that you can
actually edit it,
which is like a big gigantic step that
have tO convert it for you.
Edit it.
Yeah,
you can do a little bit of editing and
their program,
but to take it into final cut or to do
what I did just to show you more than 30
seconds at a time I had to spend
whatever,
12 minutes per eight minute video
converting all of it.
That's only because tHat's my.
The capabilities of my computer.
If I had a faster one,
maybe it'd been faster,
but they're slower computers too and
it's just like,
what's the need of the four k video?
Then I couldn't even show the four k
video out because I can't broadcast
how big of these files we're talking
about.
Huge.
For a nine minute video,
it was like 40 gig.
Oh my god,
that's a fucking giant hard drive.
Back in the day,
I think my first hard drive was four
gigs.
Forty gig for one file.
That's crazy.
For what I mean,
that's just so I could have two hours of
gopro footage of me walking around ces
to whittle that down and it's like,
what is the normal person going to do
with all that?
If they went to shoot their kids,
it's like they're going to have to have
so many hard drives are going to become
digital orders for sure.
YeaH.
Yeah.
You're talking about actual physical
space now.
Now,
what is the benefit of that over like a
more standard hd format other than the
fact that just looks a little bit
better.
I mean,
and really it is just a little bit like
you're.
You're really struggling between hd and
this four k.
It's like I.
It's better.
It's a smidge smidge better.
There was some eight k tvs at ces.
K?
Yeah,
those motherfuckers.
Several cameras that shoot ne k now.
Right.
When you thought you were safe with four
k now,
what's going to be 80 gigs for the same
video for at least fuck that.
That's crazy.
Well,
and that's the.
That's kind of where we're getting.
It's like there's no the distribution of
this content.
Now b is b becomes the next step and the
next hurdle you have to get past.
I was looking around a lot at three 60
cameras because I just got that three 60
camera and did the test footage with the
way and that we did last week in the.
I didn't personally just like how the
footage looked.
There was.
I got a,
there was a smudge on the screen which
transferred over and it doesn't look
very good and it wasn't at eye level and
I was shoot,
I believe I was shooting that in four k.
It just looks a little grainy and messy
and so I was looking around that whole
event to just try to find.
Because there were multiple,
three 60 cameras and multiple.
There was four k streaming,
three 60 cameras and you need to.
They all have their own proprietary
software to run it off of a,
but I did find one really good one which
does three d,
360 video,
which was really,
really cool.
But I'm also wondering too if I saw
something,
one really good edited video they made
to show it off or if I was actually
seeing this is basically exactly what
the camera does.
Straight like pretty much straight off
of it because it was really cool.
It's called the views camera and eye
contact
you're getting.
That's when you're getting into really
bizarre stuff right when you're talking
about like eight k video and they need
to talk to you about 360 degree three d
because it seems like if we're going to
enter intO a real virtual realm anytime
in the near future,
all this ramping up of the specs or you
know going from four k to eight k and
then you know 32 k's just around the
corner.
They're just going to keep getting
better at this shit.
And when you're talking about something
through like a high end glass,
like a really high end,
like a binocular type class and then
having insanely high definition video
and then having this exponential jump in
this virtual technology where they
figured out a way to really lock you
into something that is not,
it's not invasive to the point where
it's not liKe fucking with your
experience by you feeling it on your
head.
It's very light,
you know,
because sometimes you putting those
bulky headsets and the goggles,
you know,
it's over your eyes like that's going to
shrink up to,
that's going to shrink up to almost
nothing.
And with um,
with all these big jumps that they're
making,
how far away are we from some fully
immersive avatar world
gotta be getting close.
It's going to be bananas.
Do you know what's going to be like an
avatar world that you could go go for a
journey in?
I mean imagine if movies,
if what they become.
Because you know,
think about how these serial shows like
sopranos and then ultimately,
you know,
game oF and a lot of these other great
shows,
they,
they catch you and they rope you in and
they bring you into a world and then you
follow that world episode after episode
and you get sucked into it,
right?
It's very different than a regular
movie.
What did they start doing?
These cereal?
I mean,
I think of like game of thrones is a
serial movie,
right?
There's a hundred parts to this movie,
but it's a big giant ass movie.
I mean,
it's,
it's so much better than a regular
television show in terms of like it's
special effects and the grandness of it
all.
If they can figure out how to film
something like that,
but let you participate in it.
I mean,
uh,
let you strap on to some three d
treadmill type thing and move around in
this fucking weird world and follow
these people on their journeys.
Be right there when the orc slaughter
the people,
like the blood splatter in front of you
and you're watching theM get chopped up
and then you're going to go over the
mountain to where the castle is.
You have to actually walk over the
mountain,
but as you walk over the mountain,
horses ride beside you.
You get to see them.
I mean,
we're real close to something like that.
I feel like that's only a few years
away.
Avatar world coming out soon.
Like in disney at disney disney world.
What are they going to do?
How's that going to work?
They've been showing some things like
this is,
I think this is just a imagineering,
whoa idea,
but just like you're gonna be able to
take a boat ride through the middle of
the navi forest.
Oh,
okay.
Well that looks like it's a small world.
Yeah,
it's going to be a little bit of a step,
but they're going to have some vr stuff.
You're gonna be able to float through
and go on the uh,
whoa.
Here's how they look and disney world
right now.
Oh wow.
So they're,
they're building it right now.
You're obviously not going to have to
walk on that.
When is this going to take place?
I think it opens this later this year.
Disneyland does not next year,
but what you're saying,
what else?
They just took the extension of that and
just instead of like making the avatar
movie,
they just went,
look,
avatar is avatar world and if you want
to come live it out,
you've got to come to disney world and
pay 50 bucks.
100 bucks or $150 bucks,
300 bucks.
Something crazy to do it.
Now you're talking.
That would be,
this is what you do.
You construct that world and then once
you're in that world,
then you put on the vr goggles and it
turns everything into fluorescent neon
greens and blues and like the avatar
world.
You could see everything and then you
actually watched the movie play out in
there.
That would be a nerd gas.
I feel like they're way closer to
something like that.
Then we are everyone being able to do
with this app.
Well,
the thing about that though is it's
going to require so much resources and
land and money and it's Just,
I feel like a three d treadmill and uh,
you know,
where you can't,
you don't phySically go anywhere,
you're not going to be able to go up
hills and you're not gonna,
you're not gonna feel a sensation of
walking,
climbing things.
That's the only difference,
but you'll be able to be like right in
front of it,
but it won't feel like grass.
You know what I mean?
Like if they could figure out a way to
do a virtual world where somehow or
another you could change the textiles on
the ground or changed the way it feels,
the tactile sensation of what you're
stepping on.
If you can make it feel like water.
If you can make it feel like grass or
dirt.
If they could start doing shit like
that,
that doesn't seem outside.
The realm of possibility Just seems like
something way too smart for a dummy like
me to figure out.
So there's one technology at cds,
there's a couple things there I didn't
get a chance to even see.
WHat does it say wants to let you feel
fabric through your touch screen?
Whoa.
Yeah.
I hand invis
I find it there.
There are a lot of places I think I was
trying to find that I couldn't hear
and actually just find,
you know,
dudes are going to use that for just
gonna rub girls' panties and porn films
and it's going to be the only
application for it.
Oh,
it's right there.
Touch it.
The idea of it sounds pretty interesting
though.
Yeah,
I mean you can,
you can have a like a,
a bump to it.
So is it working on an ipad or something
with a.
It uses a little bit of like the haptic
feedback that is already built into some
of these things,
but it uses it differently.
So that was what it was kind of cool
about.
Um,
the htc vibe is that haptic feedback
because when you're doing the bow and
arrow thing,
it really does kind of feel like you're
drawing the arrow back,
gives you a little bit of vibration as
if the arrow is pulling across the arrow
restaurants rubbing on it.
It's really cool.
So they just made some announcements to,
they didn't,
they're not going to make a new vibe
yet,
but uh,
they showed a new head set attachment
that makes the vibe put on your head a
little bit more comfortably and this
showed what they're calling the tracker,
which is essentially the end of the
controller which can be attached to.
They said anything.
So it depends what a developer makes it
work with,
but one of the things they showed as it
were on the end of a gun told us to like
play different gun games.
They put on the end of a baseball bat
and a baseball bat.
Then you could,
you could see the bat and the vive game
that you were playing or the baseball
simulation you were playing,
but they could pull in real major league
baseball pitches,
actual data because they have them all
from the last,
I don't know,
five to 10 years.
Any pitch from any picture you want to
see.
You can have now come at you and you can
go ahead and try to hit it.
Oh my god.
Probably then put you theoretically at
any park you want or wherever the hell
you want to be swinging baseball bats.
How many dudes are going to be blown
their shoulders apart?
Well,
swinging in the air with this thing,
hopefully you're not bashing your house
up to,
but like that idea can be expounded on.
Now would you,
uh,
I would think that if you were going to
do something like that,
you would want to do it with a bat
that's like the same weight as a real
bat.
You'd probably want the x.
They had an actual wooden baseball bat.
They just screwed the thing on the
bottom.
Oh,
that's great.
Yeah.
So you could do it with that.
You could probably have a sword.
You could probably have a.
Oh shit.
Yeah.
If you had a sword,
do you know,
kind of a fucking awesome workout you
would get.
My arms were so tired at dunkin's place
just for playing his archery thing and
I'm not even pulling anything back.
I'm just holding my arm up.
Like there's no,
there's no actual resistance pulling the
bow back,
but just holding your arms straight in
front of you and doing this over and
over again.
my arms were killing me,
man.
I was like,
this is amazing.
Like this actually has some physical
benefit to it.
And the boxing game,
the boxing game has real benefit to it.
Like the boxing game,
I think you could,
you could learn how a person moves and
how it feels like to spar with them.
You see punches come at,
you can learn how to slip punches,
you can learn how to counter with
things.
You don't feel hitting anything.
That's the only thing that's missing and
you don't feel them hitting you.
But at least when they hit you,
you see like spark.
So,
uh,
one of the try to find that a little bit
really.
It's not worth me pumped the video.
But uh,
there was a haptic feedback,
a essentially a backpack slash chest
thing you put on for vr that would give
you some sort of shocks or you'd feel
something.
I don't know how hard it would feel
should jolt the shit out of you.
There was another,
there's a company that in the video I
watched showing the data trackers that
they were adding onto different,
uh,
devices.
They put it on a fire hose and they also
put a jacket on you that had heaters in
it.
So your boy putting out a fire and
that's given you feedback of the hose.
It's also getting warmer and you're
getting hot.
So like there's different.
I don't,
that's not really a game as more of it
as a simulation or it is a training
training tool for an actual fire
company.
Well,
it's also to let you know like what's
the potential for like a doom game from
for 24.
Yeah.
Maybe not even.
Maybe two years from now.
Hopefully we'll see what happens at e
three this year with what these
companies are going to announce with the
new xbox is supposedly supposedly going
to have a vr.
If someone comes up with a haptic
feedback suit that's able to get hot and
cold and vibrate and jolt and even give
you a little bit of pain.
Yeah,
you need something,
you need a little bit of pain,
a little fucker,
you know,
where you're really feeling it.
Remember that was that,
uh,
I don't know which James Bond movie it
was where they were holding on to the.
There's some sort of like stick they're
holding onto and like the loser,
it just gets more painful and like
trying.
It's like a man man versus man contest,
but there's a bunch of,
like at a cocktail party.
I don't remember that one.
I'm,
I avoided a lot of those James Bond
movies.
Eddie bravo said something to me a long
time ago and it fucked me up.
We were talking about,
um,
it wasn't a conspiracy thing.
We were talking about,
uh,
like action movies and he's like,
the problem with this action movies is
you always know who's going to live.
The guys always going to live like he
never.
Oh yeah.
He's going to hang by fucking thread.
Yep.
He's gonna make it.
He's gonna live,
you know he's going to live.
I'm like,
you motherfucker.
Like I knew that.
Of course I knew that you go to see the
terminator or you go to see a predator.
You don't think that arnold
schwarzenegger is going to get killed by
the alien at the end.
No.
You think that's actually really bad for
us,
isn't it?
It's really bad to have the the good guy
when and all of them.
That's why I think like no country for
old men is probably important.
So important to know that sometimes the
guy who you think's gonna live gets shot
in the last couple of minutes of the
movie and the other guy just wanders off
spoiler,
and that's the end of the movie and
you're like,
what the fuck kind of movie is this?
Well,
that's a movie that's more like a real
live story.
Arnold can't beat that alien.
You know it.
I know it.
That thing's gonna.
Fuck him up.
Why are we pretending this is stupid?
It's not a world where I can imagine
that predator losing to arnold
schwartzenegger I can't see,
aren't ongoing at the donald.
The other day,
no I didn't,
but I can't believe that donald wanted
arnold.
He's the god damn president sir.
Down of course.
Well he see he compared it to his first
season,
you know,
and then all the 15 seasons he did
afterwards,
they fired him from that show for
talking about mexicans.
Did you know that?
That's when they fired him.
They fired him from that show and he's
still the executive producer.
So he's talking shit about a show that
he's still the executive producer of.
How is he allowed to be a producer?
He gets his fucking friends.
I don't know all the rules about that,
but I thought there were rules about
that.
He's probably going to step down now
that he's president.
I don't know.
He said he was going to do a step down
from a bunch of shit.
Now that he's president,
it'll dude,
it's going to be weird.
Fucking for sure.
It's going to be weird and he's going to
be weird during the weirdest era ever.
It's next friday,
right?
Yup.
Twentieth.
Soon as he gets into place.
You think's going to happen that day.
So paint the white house black house,
you know,
open up right in front.
It's going to be like a river of lava.
Does that the actual end of the world
day?
Yeah.
The mayans were only off by four or five
years.
They were off by a little.
What did they think?
December 20.
First 2012.
So they were off.
They were off a little four years.
In a month.
Yeah.
Not that bad.
They might sit a little bit.
They did it thousands years ago,
man.
Few fucking guessing thousands of years
ago.
Me and I wonder if there really is like
a cycle where a civilizations just,
they,
they get to a point where all the monkey
shit that led them to scratch and scrape
and dominate and procreate and get to a
point where they have a city and finally
get a little bit of safety.
All of that just bites it in the ass
because all those,
even though you've gotten past the
monkey existence,
all those monkey dna,
human reward systems,
they're all still in place and they
still make you want to chase the same
shit that people chased thousands of
years ago.
Conquest and domination and control the
food supply and now that I'm president,
I'll have all the gold
that need for competition.
That's going to be one of the things
that I think technology is probably
going to neutralize first.
I think that when You get,
when you get a hive mind type scenario,
which is a hive mind or a virtual
virtual worlds scenario where it's
literally preferable to this world,
like why would you want to hang around
and just go to west hills and get lunch
at some shitty place and wait in this
thing and then go to the movie.
Why would you even want to do that?
When you get all your food through an
ivy and you're going to live in the
avatar world for a couple of weeks,
lot of people would do it.
Dude.
Damn food would probably be the only
problem,
like food and taking a shit.
There's not a black mirror episode.
You just started saying it had another
time.
It's happened from time to time.
Like you just start going down a concept
and it's like that's a black mirror
episode.
Original fuck.
Yeah.
what can I say?
It was just an idea that you can go live
in another,
in another place that's going to happen
that amount of time.
What's the name of that episode?
I want to watch it.
San junipero I think is that one gonna
happen man.
It's just a matter of time and when it
does happen,
it might be a complete mental
experience.
Like you might get out of this and you
might be like those poor guys who come
back after a space walks,
you know those guys at are up there.
LIke I'm a hatfield commander hatfield.
I had him on the podcast and he was
describing after being.
I think he was up for six months.
I think so yeah.
It was a long fucking time and when he
came back down like his body's brittle
takes like a year for your bone density
to come back.
Like you're,
you're a mess.
You can't stand.
He's throwing up all over the place,
your whole body.
So baffled because you've been up in
space for six months.
Like those guys make a tremendous
sacrifice so that we can understand like
what happens to people's bodies and zero
gravity,
like all these people that are signing
up to go to mars and want to go on all
these journeys and space like settle the
fuck down.
Okay.
We might be able to go to better spots
and we just stay right here.
We need to put a,
a,
a roof on this thing.
We got rocks flying in.
Need to put a god damn roof on the
planet.
Build that first big ass thick roof with
lcd screens.
So at the bottom of it,
It just shows nothing but beautiful
skies.
Everywhere you go,
it's going to be like
the truman show
and there's gonna be a big scoop that
catches all the rain.
The rain is going to fall on the
outside,
it's going to get funneled through,
but we need like a four foot wall now.
It wouldn't even matter.
The the,
the kind of asteroids that killed the
dinosaurs.
I think they said something crazy like
it was five miles deep into the earth
within the first half.
A second.
Yeah.
I might've made those numbers up,
but it's in that range where it's so
preposterous.
I rememBer hearing this guy speak about
it and talking about just the.
The impact that the earth rang for a
million years.
Bob
rang from the impact for a million years
out.
What the fuck is that like so we can't
really have a.
We need something better than a roof.
That's what I'm trying to say.
Work on that first and you got damn
virtual reality.
Then think about going to mars.
I was listening to richard dawkins talk
to sam harris today on this podcast.
Very interesting,
but one of the things that we're talking
about is people going to mars and if
they did colonize mars,
the genes on mars would not be in
contact with the jeans back here on
earth and would human beings go off in
different directions and then on top of
that genetic manipulation once genetic
manipulation gets perfected and they
start really fucking with people's dna
and really changing what people look
like and what,
how they can perform and how their
Brains work was going to be like in
comparison,
like the guys that are doing tHat on
earth versus the people that are doing
it on mars.
Yeah,
that's weird.
I ended.
The atmosphere is obviously different in
general because of the way it's really
grow and just be different.
He can't breathe it.
You have to somehow or another they're
going to have to terraform,
create an atmosphere or um,
they're gonna have to put some kind of a
like domes up and live inside the domes,
which is terrifying.
What is that kai?
I feel like,
was it an interstellar where they made.
We didn't like,
we call it,
we didn't colonize planets,
but we've made life floating terraform
cylinders and we lived on those.
Is that what that was?
I didn't watch that whole movie.
I got to most mostly did that movie and
I fell asleep on a plane.
So you didn't see the end and seeing
that movie at the chinese theater was
where I saw it done in hollywood when he
goes and they go into the black hole and
I remember even reading,
that's where Christopher Nolan was t
test watching that movie.
It was so loud.
So big.
It made that such an awesome experience.
Chinese theaters I'd love.
I love to see it makes bad movies.
Good.
Yeah.
I saw pulp fiction.
There was like,
holy shit.
That was when pulp fiction first came
out and this was like 90 or something.
Yeah,
man,
I didn't see that movie,
but that matt damon movie the martian
was all about terraforming and trying to
survive on mars.
Did you watch the arrival yet?
I must have watched that.
No,
no,
I haven't seen.
It hurts really good though.
it looks really good,
but that kind of came and went,
huh?
I mean kind of events that just how it
goes now.
There's too fast.
Things are too good.
Too much that people want to watch them
at home now.
Yeah.
That too.
They're going to start allowing that to
happen I think are charged with more.
Yeah.
Charging 50 bucks.
Nobody's figured out how to get through
the uh,
well maybe they have get through the
apple tv and downloaded.
Have they like to steal from that?
I don't think so.
You don't like to steal from that?
So just ask.
I'm assuming you mean steal from them?
Yeah.
I don't think so.
I don't know.
I don't think anybody's been able to do
that.
Maybe they have,
but like when you're streaming,
like you're streaming,
I guess if you were streaming to a
computer,
that might be a way to do it.
A screen capture and some sort of way.
Maybe.
Maybe not.
I don't know because they have it built
into the.
Well,
I guess it's streaming a lot of the htmi
cable is now,
uh,
if you're,
when you have your xbox or your,
another system hooked up to something
that you're trying to do game capturing
onto like Broadcast on twitch or
something.
If you bring up a video or like your tv
turns on it goes black because it knows
that that signal is bad.
It's not supposed to be broadcast.
It's not tHe game signal at the tv
signal and you'll probably people's
trying to show tv online,
it knows that you're trying to or
whatever.
They put the dispute that stop in there.
Right.
Exactly.
Be removed.
Right.
Or maybe maybe.
But I feel like there's gotta be a way
to take apple.
Like when you're using your computer,
you can use a regular computer and watch
things on itunes,
correct?
Yes.
Right.
So if you were using a regular computer
and you were streaming a movie,
like there's gotta be a way that you
would be able to screen capture that
with your computer.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
But just open up a program.
You mean record?
Just record it.
Yeah.
And then would have just some big ass
file that would be like the hobbit or
whatever the hell you were screened
there.
There's probably a way they can put in
some sort of digital rights management
thing that it will put brian record to
that or it'll put of big watermark on if
you try to do that or maybe not.
And then someone will hack away to
against it and that that's like a battle
probably going onto the battle that will
go on forever,
right?
Yeah.
I'll just make a new file format and
then
videos will be in that file format for
the next five years until it gets
hacked.
Keep playing cat and mouse games.
I think it's really interesting when we
were looking at that video or the
article rather about the people that
we're transmitting ola and chow back and
forth through the internet.
And then think about this kind of stuff
that you're talking about,
like really high level digital
management.
He putting out four k are you streaming
movies and people are trying to steal it
and you know,
think about all the bit torrents and all
the different files that are available
online when it comes to all these movies
and hollywood studios.
Pen spend millions of dollars to make
and then boom,
a screeners online like moments before
it's released and like this constant
battle of technologies.
It's just,
it's really crazy because we could just
sit here and like just show up at this
ces.
We don't have to participate at all.
Show up every year.
What you got now?
One year.
What do you got now?
Can you,
can you read my mind yet?
Nope,
not yet.
I'll see you in a year.
What about now?
Will we can't read your mind but we can
send you images.
Okay.
We'll see you in a year.
Can you read my mind yet?
he just keep going back.
Like you don't have to do any work.
Like no one gets mad at us.
It's not like the people in the village
that had to go get the water.
Like you drink water every day.
You fuck,
you never go and get water and they
never asked you to get water.
You just got to give them money and
they'll just keep doing it.
You just show up every week and they
never go,
what do I have here?
What do you have for me?
If you want to see my mind reading
machine,
I got money.
Not good enough.
NoBody ever says that it now like you
don't have to.
You literally don't have to participate
in it to enjoy the benefits of it.
It's a rare thing.
Yeah.
I was trying to think of a,
like at the end of the car companies
outside was showing some stuff,
but it was super.
It was like a call to the statue,
but it was supposed to be an actual
model of a car.
They called the car statue because it
doesn't have a drive train in it.
There were people sitting in it.
It was supposed to look like whatever a
future thing was.
But the girl that kept,
uh,
she was telling you what was going on
and explaining things to you.
She kept calling.
She kept referring to the car as a
statue.
I thought that was weird because I think
I've tried to show it to you before.
We were lIke,
does that.
Is that real?
Is that legal ease?
Yeah,
that doesn't work then that when you
call something a statue,
you could say that it's a prototype,
like this is what we hope it looks like
in the future,
but based on what like do you know what
the imaGes.
Do you have a.
Can you pull it up?
I was trying to remember who it was.
I want to say is it seems like if you
just call it a statue,
you could just totally bullshit people.
It doesn't have to have any basis in
real engineering or anything.
You can just say it's a statue and he
could just have like a design concepts
to it.
Was it a concept as far as like a crazy
technological
vehicle with that?
I think that's what they were trying to
show off the tech
inside.
Yeah.
Have you seen like what new cars are
doing now where all their dashboards are
all lcds.
That's
what I was trying to get.
That's what they were trying to show.
I think a little bit was like this is
what the new dashboard and everything's
going to look like.
Go ahead and sit in there.
It's crazy.
Whenever one of the bmw,
I think it was an eight,
they had it inside the event.
There was long line for this,
so 100 percent wasn't waiting,
but you put on the,
I think it was the microsoft surface
with it,
so I don't know why you would have this
on while you're driving,
but maybe in the future we'll be doing
that and you're getting all sorts of
extra information.
Um,
at least my,
this is still just a prototype,
so I don't know.
You weren't driving down the street so I
don't know what they're showing you.
They're just blasting stuff in your face
on what it might look like.
Wow.
I don't know what you would be wanting
to see though also.
Well,
it just seems like whatever,
you know,
whatever possibilities they have now,
it's you,
you,
you just try to extrapolate.
You try to add up the steps between now
and fIve to 10 years from now.
It's going to be really weird.
Did you see the darpa,
one of the darpa announcements that
we're talking about?
All the different.
Well,
it wasn't an announcement.
There were,
it was an interview they did with one of
the guys.
I tweeted it so you could find it on my
twitter timeline,
but they're essentially saying the new,
uh,
inventions over the next,
12 months,
we're just going to blow people's minds.
So apparently they're working on some
really heavy duty stuff when it comes to
neural implants.
Things along those lines,
I think he was mentioning
is darpa's biotech chief says 2017 will
blow our minds.
Air quotes
the pentagon,
pentagon is research and development
division.
The creative force behind the internet.
And gps retooled itself three years ago
to create a new office dedicated to
unraveling biology's engineering
secrets.
The new biological technologies office
has a mission to harness the power of
biological systems and design new
defense technology.
They're gonna make terminators right
over the past year with a budget of
about $296 million dollars.
It has been exploring challenges
including memory improvement,
human machine symbiosis and speeding up
disease detection and response.
Fuck dude.
Listen to what that says.
Human machine symbiosis there making up
fucking terminator.
They're gunna make a terminator 100
percent.
If someone comes along and one of the
first pieces of artificial intelligence
is a soldier of machine soldier that
makes no mistakes,
feels no emotion,
does everything.
It's told consent back data in four k in
real time and you watch a screen through
its eyes and tell what to do and it's
invincible.
What?
Of course they're going to build that.
Why would we just send those to mars?
We would probably,
but people want to go to mars because
they want to be the first.
You know here we're doing yoga and
maurice were all amazing.
Like I saw a couple of those,
a unit,
they're not brand new but like a robot
assistance essentially where it's like a
a laptop or an ipad screen that's
attached to a droid or a little robot
and there's someone on there talking to
answer your questions or whatever and
they can control it.
Moving arounD the room.
Have you ever seen those?
No,
I've walked.
I kind of just walked by and I thought
it was funny because there was three of
them people were talking to and there's
just one guy no one was talking to and
he just looked bored.
Like moving around like someone talking
about someone talk to me.
What was the most impressive thing for
you at the event?
Man?
Honestly,
that I'd have to.
It was weird.
I probably just because I was looking
for,
but that camera,
that three d stereoscopic camera,
three 60 camera,
but again,
I'm not sure if what I was seeing was
the rendered video because that's
specifically what I kept asking to see
when I would walk up to one of these
guys.
I didn't want to.
I don't,
I don't want to be pitched.
I just want to see what your rendered
video looks like.
What does the output.
MosT of what I was seeing wasn't great
or didn't look better than what's
currently on the market except for that.
And then a couple of didn't even do
audio or you couldn't mix audio into it.
And for our purpose,
which is I was looking for it to help
here in the future.
I was trying to knock that out.
Um,
there were a couple of car things.
Mostly just the bmw 7:50,
the coolest one.
They were showing those off there.
They're also doing test drives with like
[inaudible] and I think some of the self
driving cars maybe
I think the sevenfifty drives itself to.
I think that's the big one that does,
but I believe it makes you put your hand
on the wheel,
but it'll drive,
which is even freakier like imagines
driving for you.
But the idea is like if it fucks up,
but what am I doing then why does my
hands here?
I didn't see it.
right.
I didn't take it on a test drive myself,
but they had one sitting out that you
could like get in and just kinda like
sit in and whatnot with all the extra
screens everywhere.
But the backseat,
which probably is,
I don't,
I probably just didn't know this.
It's basically like a first class luxury
seat like that.
You could lift your feet up,
stick on the back of the seat.
There was a place for them to have
massage or.
yeah,
it was insane.
Yeah.
They give you a back rub or massage.
I don't know if it's a new hot
technology right now or if some
companies are very smart knowing people
are walking around this event tired and
need a massage,
but the lines for massage chairs at ces
were insane.
Well,
think about this jamie.
You run all the time.
Yeah,
I mean how many miles a week do you run?
Oh no,
I haven't been doing it very often,
but at my height probably 30,
but maybe 10,
10 a week now what's going on with you
now?
I just kinda weight training instead of
running.
Oh,
again,
yoked,
young.
Jamie getting swole.
My point is you're a very fit guy and
you exercise on a regular basis,
so for you to walk 25 miles,
if that's a strain for you,
imagine what it is for a bunch of these
fatties.
No fence,
no need to fat.
Shame.
You know what,
you are no big deal.
You know,
I mean it's,
it's got to be really fucking hard.
If you are really poorly fed,
you know you're eating a bunch of shitty
food and you're out of shape and you're
overweight and you're walking around
ces,
geeked out of your mind on caffeine.
Yeah,
it's probably a good start for the new
year.
So you just keep that going.
Walk 10 miles a day.
Every day you'll.
That way it'll peel off you find a hill
unless you live in Iowa or you know,
some flat spot.
Find a fucking hill.
Walk up hills.
It's hardest thing.
Just got one right in front of my house.
It's amazing.
Two hundred yards up hill to take a
backpack.
Throw some fucking sandbags in the
Walk up the hill and then get off the
trail,
like get off the trail and just walk up
the hill hill like walk up the grass and
the dirt.
So it slides and you have to correct
yourself.
It's one of the best workouts you can
do.
I,
I was in pretty fucking good shape the
first time.
Everyone hiking with steve rinella when
we went hunting and just following him
walking up hills.
Did we die?
It's the second time it's happened.
It's the video still recording,
but the stream is just Putting.
So if,
Do you think it'S um,
the machine or is it the connection with
youtube we don't know.
Did you find,
speaking of which,
did you find any new a streaming
solutions because right now for people
don't know.
We're using a tricaster setup and it's
okay.
It's really good for tHe most part,
but it has fucked us in the ass at least
three or four times.
Pretty hard
there.
There wasn't a lot of stuff because it's
again that was the consumer show so
there's not.
Consumers aren't really out here
streaming for four or five different
devices at once and all that.
But I did find a couple of things that
were close that I don't know.
There were upgrades of stuff we used to
use
couple of years ago.
Well If you think about how many
episodes we have,
what are we on?
Like 880 episodes.
Ninety six.
Okay.
There you go.
Outside.
Plus a little slight tension.
Eight 96.
So think about that.
Eight hundred 96 episodes and it's shit
out.
How many times a day
knocked down to that?
$400.
So on here and just brush it out four or
five times.
That's not good.
One.
One percent.
That's not good.
Yeah,
It was not very good.
It shouldn't at all.
That's way.
That's way too often.
I mean maybe we're fucked up.
Maybe we did something wrong.
Maybe a.
I don't know.
Maybe our machine just got a weird bug
to it.
YeaH,
I dunno.
I mean I reset it multiple times and I
have problems.
I do the protocol of update.
Do you think it's just because it's long
term.
You were doing these for hours and hours
at a time and heats up.
We do stressed the hell out of it.
Yeah.
If you think about like what we do and
company.
You know what my frIend justin I know
was doing the action report.
Same thing,
right?
Yeah.
He was streaming for six hours at a
time.
I can,
yeah.
I think every time I think that I find
another comparison.
It's like,
well,
they'll do just about as long justin.
I don't remember having any problems
with his system.
Maybe we got a wHack system dude.
It could have been when we went to
lemans happened with cars from time to
time.
That could have just been some component
in here that was bad that we've gotten
around working with that now.
It's just
not gonna work anymore.
Cars are another interesting thing.
Along the same lines when we were
talking about earlier about technology
is that it's reaching this point where
like is way too much car for like what
you need.
Like they're putting out these cars.
Right?
Right.
Out of gm,
like they have this new camaro.
Have you seen the camaro zl one?
It is.
It's insane.
I think it has fought.
I don't know how many horsepower it has.
Final,
how many horsepower?
It has.
Fifty six,
58.
jesus christ
and it's got a corvette z o six engine
in it with a supercharger.
Wow.
It's an unbelievable car.
Like this is a zero to 60 sub four
seconds.
Zero to 60 car,
massive,
uh,
all that.
See that stuff in the front.
That's all designed to keep the body
down.
All those aerodynamic little flares and
stuff does design for downforce so that
this thing can go fucking screaming up
to like 200 miles an hour.
It's crazy.
You can just buy that in a store where
you could go to the chevy dealership and
buy one of the most competent sports
cars ever created.
Like that car.
You remember those ferrari's from a few
years ago?
Like a three 60 mo,
dana,
or uh,
you know the one after that?
Four or five slash eight.
Those beautiful ferrari dad fucking car.
We'll burry one of those things.
I mean,
into the dirt.
Good.
Suck my dick.
Kiss my ass.
America.
Fuck yeah.
Screaming the entire time I'm off.
And it's $65,000.
$70,000.
Yeah.
That car is american muscle at its
finest plus technology because you know,
real american muscles kind of loose and
crazy real man.
Like if you get like,
if you bought a real 19,
69 mustang,
mach one,
I mean there are a gorgeous car.
I mean it is a stunning piece of art,
but if you had a drive it today,
you would,
uh,
you would be terrified.
You'd be thinking the entire time.
like,
oh my god,
I'm driving a death machine.
Like they're so bad in comparison to a
brand new mustang.
Like if you bought a brand new mustang
gt,
which I think you can get for $35,000 I
think.
I tHink a new mustang gts,
like between 35 and $39,000.
And they are way fast or handle way
better than anything.
Top of the line from the 19 seventies.
Yeah.
How much does this across to under 35.
That's crazy.
It's stunning car.
That car is foreign and 20 horsepower.
Four 30 4:35 crazy.
That's a beast of a car for 35 grand.
Sixteen miles a gallon.
Twenty five and a highway.
You see what they've done by continuing
ramp up to specs,
ramp up the litter regular car that you
buy from a dealership is equivalent to
like one of the best cars ever just 10
years ago or 20 years ago.
So the,
the technology is so ahead of its time
that you go back to 97 and you look at
the cars that were like the top of the
food chain back in [inaudible] 97.
Like they didn't even compare.
There's just nothing like these things
and they're going to keep doing it.
The only thing that,
like you,
there was some cars from 97 that have
some attributes that people like,
like um,
those old land cruisers.
If you bought a land cruiser from toyota
in [inaudible] 97,
you essentially got an off road vehicle.
They had two solid axle,
solid front axle,
solid rear axle.
you could take those things and just
drive up the side of a fucking mountain
in it with the right tires.
They were crazy beefy,
like right out of the bat.
And so people to this day,
they take those cars and they jack them
up and put bigger tires and wheels on
them and they put corvette engines in
them just because the configuration is
so durable,
like they don't really make too many.
I mean there's only a few companies that
will make like a real car that you could
actually take right now,
just go dry like a jeep.
Jeeps are perfect example.
You can take a jeep kind of like right
off the factory floor and drive to most
places that most cars can't get to or at
least drive to places that most cars
can't get it too.
But when you want to get further and
further into it,
they started doing all these crazy
modifications to these things and make
them so that they could literally just
drive through the woods.
What do you Look up their fellow?
Uh,
I just remembered this bad ass supercar
that I saw at ces.
It was three d printed.
Oh jesus.
It's called the divergent,
I think the company that makes,
it's called divergent three d.
And this is called the blade.
Oh,
do you sit in the middle,
like a total bad ass?
Oh,
that needs to happen.
I think the whole entire thing is three
d printing shop.
we're down to the tires.
That is just such a.
That's like the alien from John
Carpenter movie.
Not John Carpenter,
ridley scott,
ridley scott's alien.
It's like if he drove a car like it was
on his planet,
look at that thing one seat.
Someone would probably sit behind you
to.
I was trying to find the spec to see.
I don't know how weird.
I wasn't sure to either.
They'll fit like was it a car that can
drive if it's a or if they're just also
add concept of showing like look,
we can put these pieces out in three d
printing because I saw a three d metal
company,
so a company I was printing stuff and
metal
it looks like at work.
So
these cars today,
man,
it's,
it's really interesting because they're
backed into this weird corner where how
much better can they keep getting and
how long before they're all automated
because it seems like just a matter of
time.
It seems like just a few years from now,
they're all gonna be automated.
That's what everyone.
That's what a lot of the companies were
showing off their automation.
LIke mercedes,
I think nissan,
toyota and video.
The video game card company was showing
off a.
I don't know exactly the,
their software I think.
Are there hardware that was being put
into cars to show you how things are
being read?
like this is a car,
this is a light,
this is a person.
Just like how it's being recognized and
whatnot.
I mean it's going to go.
Mercedes was showing it and I think bmw
gotten to a car wreck,
but I don't think it was their
autonomous car.
That car.
And then Fair day we're looking at the
camaro.
Zl one folks who are just listening or.
Yes,
there's images of it online.
You can go look at it.
Had the fair dave.
So what's a fair day?
Because didn't,
um,
fisker have a new car too.
They came back,
right?
The fisker karma.
But I don't know if they were showing
this at the event.
So this is an electronic car with
electronic car.
That was being shown off there.
They had a little issue with like their
reverse while they were doing their
demos,
so like again,
one of the problems that doesn't always
that nothing goes perfect.
I think they tried to announce this last
year and they had some bigger issues so
they ever seen an ad where the president
of the company stands right in front of
the volvo and it hits,
it,
hits him,
sends him flying.
It's like,
wait,
this has technology to avoid contact
with humans and it just fucking runs him
over.
He went flying.
That guy probably broke his hip on that.
It's happened a few times where they've
tried to do things.
People will stand in front of it trying
to show her husband was working for this
company.
Here's the car though.
Woo.
So they're gonna.
I don't know if they're going to do.
Oh it up on the screen in the background
like this is going to be like a big
competitor to.
Or tesla car.
Like a tesla.
Yeah,
I think they're going to be on the
market this year if not already.
I think you can preorder him now.
Not very good looking,
kinda super sexy looking aT the problem.
Very sexy.
Look,
that's problem.
Oh,
I like how they have the gangster doors
though.
They have suicide doors in the back.
Yeah.
A lot of them were doing suicide doors.
The volkswagen had a suicide door.
The doors went up.
We got to.
The door shuts itself to.
How about you save fucking battery power
and let me shut the door.
What does that?
Everybody wants to be like a spaceman
door shut.
She shutting.
Shutting dave.
How's it could shut the door.
That doesn't look good.
You guys had all this time to design
this thing.
He spent all this money and you made a
fucking alexis mom car.
Well that happened.
I wanted to sort of ask you that.
I think that was one question.
So like,
you know when they do a car show the
show,
let's say that they're going to do one
this year,
they'll show a car for 20 slash 20 and
it's going to look super high concept.
by the time it comes out it won't look
that way
sometimes.
Sometimes you're too well they,
they,
they smoothed out edges and make things
cheaper to build and there's a lot of
cars that start out in concept form and
then when they get ultimately delivered,
they're disappointing,
you know,
come out with a bunch of different
things that they add to them that just
turned out to be too expensive.
Is that what it is?
They're just try as the same kind of
idea.
They're just trying something or
Thailand.
The car company to like toyota,
like say if someone comes up with a new.
Toyota has thE most expensive car they
sell the land cruiser,
that big four wheel drive suv,
that's their most expensive car.
It's pretty expensive.
It's like,
I think you get one,
they're all loaded.
You only get them one way and they're
like 90 something like $90,000.
So if you're building something that's
going to get more upscale than that,
then it becomes a bit of an issue.
RighT.
Doesn't that make sense?
I accidentally,
I was looking for toyota supercars as
this came up in the toyota.
Supra might be coming out again.
Yeah,
no,
that's the question.
Like will it look like this when it
comes out?
You're right.
That's a perfect example.
That's a concept car.
I think it would probably look a lot
like that because that looks awesome.
I mean if they wanted to make some
money,
but like then all those angles and all
that stuff.
Is it more expensive?
Is it less expensive?
What know?
What do we do about that wing?
Has it deploys it mechanical?
How much does that cost?
You know,
what kind of brakes are we using?
Which kind of it it really.
It gets into this weird area when it
comes to these cars,
but they also have to be stunning in
terms of their ability because cars
today are off the charts.
WhaT you could buy from a subaru wrx.
Just one of those little subarus that
has an insane little car,
you know,
and I don't think those are very
expensive either.
I think that's in like mustang gt range,
right?
Where it's like in the thirties,
32 to 35.
I did.
I'm pretty sure take that to 1970 and
you will destroy any car on the road.
There's nothing comes close to it.
You would think you were from another
fucking planet.
If he took that on a race car race car
track,
you'd be blowing people away.
They'd be like,
what in the fuck is it?
Just particular car companies are a lot
of the newer cars getting harder to fix
to where they have to be fixed at a
death by the dealer.
They all have to be fixed by the dealer.
Everything is computer program now.
They hAve minds,
you know the computer programmer or the
program rather than running the car runs
a traction control system.
The lane change system of accident
avoidance system.
Some of them hit the brakes for you.
Some of them alarms go off when you get
close,
so they've got sensors,
they got cameras,
so getting your car fixed at a local by
a local guy somewhere and it's not
happening anymore.
Yeah,
that's going to be phased out.
It's going to be all dealerships.
It's going to be like getting your
computer fixed.
I mean,
it's really going to be like a super
high tech computer with rubber and metal
and all this jazz that connects it to
the ground.
That mk
market marquez,
brownlee.
Mark,
I don't know how you say his name
actually,
but mkbhd on youtube.
He got up at.
I don't want to do it.
Been here.
Yeah.
Mark has got a full lemon,
but his.
He had a tesla issues.
We just got a new tesla and his drive
train was locking up fixed and then he
got it back and it got locked up again.
Wrong dude to fuck a shitty car.
He should have tested that one first.
That will cost you some money,
right?
Yeah.
That kind of gives really good reviews
to his,
um,
his online reviews of technology or one
of my favorites him,
but him and louis from unbox therapy or
my.
There are two of mY favorites.
Yeah man.
The,
those things are not perfect,
but nothing electronic is,
is,
you know,
what are you going to do?
Somebody fucks up.
Somebody put it together wrong or some
issues in the wiring.
Who knows?
Part of why I'm not always super
convinced when someone goes full like
this is going to be,
this is how it's going to be in the
future.
It's because we still,
even today with all of this,
the coolest shit we have,
there are still major,
major problems that haven't been fixed
and I don't,
I don't see full fixes for them.
Like which ones do you think tesla?
It's like if they're going to be fix
that,
they'll fix it 100 percent.
Just stop and thinK about how clunky
computers were just a few years ago.
You know,
just when 1995 windows,
95 came along.
Think about how clunky the oPerating
system was.
The blue screen of death,
you know,
I mean computers were crap,
but it still happens all the time.
Right?
But not nearly as much as it did.
Then think about how many computers
operate,
how many things all throughout your life
and how rarely they crash.
If they crashed one percent of the time,
like the,
you know,
the tricaster,
we get pissed,
which we're spoiled little babies.
Back then when you had windows 95,
you had a backup things every 20 minutes
he can fucking kid crashed at any
moment.
You're sticking in floppy drives and
backing up files and stuff.
True.
It's better.
It's better now.
It's going to be better soon and with
whatever the issues that they have with
a tesla cars or maybe it's just one
tesla.
Just somebody fucked up.
Maybe somebody just put a wire in that
had a scratch and who knows what the
fuck?
No,
it was.
I don't know anything.
I don't know.
I still feel like,
I dunno.
Maybe it's a senate senate scenic view
of it.
I've had.
Let me tell you this though.
I've had two of those.
Lexis,
those big toyota land cruiser trucks,
the lexus f,
f five,
7:55,
7:50.
No,
five slash 76.
Five 70.
That's what it is.
The big ass truck.
They fucking never break like nothing
goes wrong with them ever.
I mean ever.
Nothing goes wrong.
They just every morning start it,
drive it.
Oh,
it needs an oil.
Bring it to the place.
They put the oil and they check
everything.
EveryThing's great.
See ya.
Bye.
no problems.
I'll try by range rovers as a brand new
range rover.
It's got one headlight on fucking smoke
coming out of the hood.
Like what happened?
Like what?
What is the difference between a car
that's like a super reliable car company
like toyota and a car company.
You know,
like,
like if you get a maserati,
you get a maserati because it's
beautiful.
You don't get a maserati because you
plan on driving to the fucking moon and
he needed to stay together.
It's not going to.
It's just not.
It sounds awesome.
He started up blah blah blah blah blah
blah.
But if you get that car,
you get in it because it's sexy.
You're not getting it because it.
It's well designed.
OKay.
Yeah.
I guess I didn't know how I want
everything to be awesome.
No,
I think I just.
It should have already happened
sometimes.
Like those kids in that lego movie,
everything is awesome.
I didn't see it too.
It's a cute movie.
I saw it with my kids.
My kids love the lego movies,
but I enjoyed it.
Like I genuinely enjoyed it.
The lego movie was good.
I just saw a commercial for the newer
one.
I think it's got a batman not on all the
warning look for.
Okay,
okay.
They're really well written.
They're fun.
I mean,
you gotta you can't be waiting for
things to be deep,
deep.
Jamie.
Really,
really tired of it.
I'm a less deep every year for real.
Like I something that ron white said
when he was on the podcast,
key blind and stay drunk.
Like I'm paraphrasing,
stay drug.
You keep lying.
I mean in some ways the best way to
handle things just not go deep.
The deeper you go.
Like I feel like we're clinging to
simplicity with the last of our
fingernails.
That's what I think and I think just
sitting on your fucking back porch,
smoking a cigar,
drinking a glass of lemonade.
I think that's a thing of the past and
just a few decades I think we're going
to enter into some super bizarre world
that's like darpa is talking about
symbiosis.
Human computer symbiosis,
mean people complain.
Now the kids don't go outside their sit,
sitting at home everyday playing x box.
Just imagine what it's going to be like
when we get to these really intense
augmented and virtual reality spaces.
Are you scared?
No,
I just stopped caring.
I think of that stuff about kids all the
time.
I don't have one side.
I can't,
uh,
I don't,
I don't see the day to day their
interactions and how they're different
to mine,
but I just compare because my generation
or where I'm,
I just turned 34,
But I just,
I feel like I've just missed out on so
many things.
The year after I left high school,
they all get a guy like tablet pcs for
everyone.
It's like literally the year after I
left.
And like you were tHe last.
Yeah,
it's good talking about you.
Maybe
one day if you have kids.
Yeah.
My dad grew up,
they didn't even have the tablet pcs in
the class the year after he got out.
That's when they came in.
Whoa.
But it wouldn't,
I don't know how things would've been
different had we had them because
whatever we know,
we always had a of people would look
back,
like
if I could go back to high school now
with everything I know,
dominate and kill everything.
No,
You do it and you wouldn't be nervous.
That's why you would dominate.
True.
Yeah.
But if some kid decided to kick your ass
and still kick your ass,
that would be disturbing.
But I didn't even mean it.
Like on the whole,
on the whole thing like that.
I'm just going on specifically,
uh,
like a technology,
a run.
Like if you had,
if I just took all my computer knowledge
I have now and had an ipad when I was in
high school and we could communicate
with everyone throughout the whole high
school all day anytime we wanted to.
Whereas like we had to write and we were
writing notes.
I still have,
I found a note from a girl in high
school like not too long ago in a box.
It's like,
it's a literal note.
Dear jamie.
Yeah.
Dumb shit.
Oh,
I missed your touch.
Stupid questions of like what's so check
here
like that they might write notes still
today.
That might still be a thing.
it probably is.
I don't want to be that,
but like the purpose of it isn't there
anymore.
Yeah,
it's way more text messages to notes.
Yeah.
So this is.
And then a facetiming people.
We couldn't.
That wasn't even a possibility.
We had to literally falling into call.
Like if I,
if,
if I was in school with your kids,
it'd be calling your house,
be like,
hey is so and so home.
Can I talk to them?
They'd go get them and then we get to
talk for 20 or 30 minutes maybe.
Yeah.
When was the fIrst year we're skype came
out and people started skyping probably
within the last 10 years.
There was an ease.
There was light video communication back
then,
but it was terrible.
Well if that's one of the things that
apple has nailed,
having facetime and its operating system
so you just automatic it automatically
works,
you know,
you don't have to download anything,
you have to go get skype.
like if you have an android phone,
do you have to download skype or does it
come with your phone?
I
don't know,
but I think that they have a thing to.
They have an androId thing to that just
like it.
But what's fucked up is it doesn't
communicate with the apple thing.
right?
Like you have to get in like everybody's
got to come to.
Well there's new apps too.
I mean you can do it through,
you could do it through facebook now if
there's a new one that's blowing up
right now called house party,
which you can have like eight people on
and everyone can be having a video chat.
Yeah.
So,
buT that's an app that you have to
download.
Like should be just like a phone call
should be like phone to phone.
It should be phone to phone,
coMmunication with android to apple.
It seems silly to me that they go
proprietary on that.
Apple's got a bunch of really sneaky
ways to keep you around.
Man.
That I message is one of them.
Facetime is another.
Um,
uh,
what is it when they,
airdrops airdrops another one for
images?
No compression sends it through
bluetooth,
so amazing for videos and pictures and
stuff.
I don't want to say it's a problem isn't
the right word,
but that they are like the only record
label basically write or record
distribution play state control of it.
That's kinda crazy to.
It is well interesting too that
a lot of musicians complain about that.
They're like,
apple is the biggest music company in
the world now.
So strain of every transaction.
Do they really are?
I'm pretty sure.
Well they when
they definitely want everyone to answer,
there's an answer and it's like,
well now you're not necessarily happy
with the answer,
but yeah,
you got one.
It's A very weird company in that regard
because it's also like the loyalest
apple loyalists are so extreme,
like people who worship at the cult of
mac and apple,
like I had a conversation with.
The dude was sincerely bummed out that I
started using a windows computer.
It's like so sad.
He was really sad.
It's like,
come on dude,
it's fucking computer.
Just a computer.
Just relax.
You know?
I do.
I type words.
I'd say boards and I look at porn
and I read dig.
I read a few things.
It's not a lot of processing power going
on here.
I'm not making videos,
it's not in it and I,
I just don't understand why everybody
would get so attached to a company,
you know,
so brand loyal,
fingered real prep blend,
brand loyalties.
Real weird.
This chevy country.
Have you listened quietly?
You'll hear for rust and
so many dorks like that.
Like they have calvin and hobbes like
he's standing on the chevy logo,
pissing on the ford logo.
Magic put nine on your car.
Mind you being that fucking stupid.
If you're listening to this and you have
that on your car,
don't change.
Stay yourself man.
It's all right.
Change if you want to,
but don't worry about me.
What else did you see there?
Anything else worth discussing?
How many,
how long were you there for?
One day.
I got there friday,
friday and saturday.
And when did you feel the stomach flu
coming on wednesday night.
Oh dude.
FucK man.
Power through.
I was also kinda like wonder.
I could have just been one of those 24
hour thing are.
I was like,
I feel like shit now.
I feel great tomorrow,
so I just went ahead and went.
What was your stomach rumbling?
The whole.
Not the whole thing.
I just flew in a coffin.
Just felt weak and worn down kind of
thing.
Yeah,
man,
that makes you aPpreciate feeling
healthy,
doesn't it?
Like when you.
Are you feeling a little shitty right
now,
right?
Yeah,
for sure.
It's not 100 percent,
but you know that feeling where you're
like,
man,
when I get healthy,
I'm drinking fucking vegetable juice
every day.
I'm not fucking around anymore.
I'm limitiNg myself to one glass of
wine.
No sugar,
no this,
no that.
I'm going to take my probiotics.
I'm doing yoga.
Twice a week he started thinking of all
the different ways you can keep yourself
healthy and being in vegas isn't the
best place to think about that too.
Like the worst.
it's the worst for your soul to your
soul's tugged at the gambling.
I wonder what they'll do there is
because smoking is smoking weed path,
right?
So how do you think they might handle
that they're in the Future?
Well,
they're going to have to handle the
extreme paranoia.
A bunch of stoners going
in there like,
dude,
I don't want to lose all my money.
They're going to go into those casinos
and they're gonna.
Well,
I think if I was running a casino,
I would try to figure out a way to
capitalize on the stoners.
The Big money that they make apparently
is those fucking huge disco places like
haka song where they get those dj's to
come in.
YeaH.
Somebody was telling us who the fuck was
telling us about this,
how much they get paid.
Is it russell?
Because russell,
it might've been russell the other night
because,
you know,
russell hates those electronic dj's
because he's into like old school hip
hop dj and he is a dj.
Um,
but when you,
when you hear how much money people pay
to get into those things,
like some dudes are paying like 500
bucks each to get into those things.
More than that.
How much more than that?
I feel like a table.
Oh,
if you want to table it,
that's something that needs to get it by
the bottle for a couple of days and then
paper had to get in and girls get in for
free,
but guys definitely don't.
Well they were saying at a certain point
in time,
even girls were had to pay 150 bucKs if
you go late probably.
Yeah.
That's crazy money.
I mean that is just swarming money and
then there's all the alcohol money on
toP of that.
Those are probably the biggest
generators of income other than crazy
gambling guys that just come in and blow
their whole.
Their whole wad
a $100 to buy a ticket right now for
this weekend if you it.
That's pretty ahead though.
But yeah that's ahead of time.
Yeah,
a hundred bucks.
Alright.
But they have open container laws.
You're allowed to walk around all over
vegas drinking.
You can buy it anywhere you want.
You can walk around and drink right in
front of a cop.
Well here's an interesting thing too.
It's sort of an unspoken thing,
but those hock hassan places,
all those places,
there's booze flowing for sure,
but there's also pills,
a lot of those people in the mtma.
How many of those people,
what percentage?
Like if you could light people up at the
little thought light bulb popped up on
their head.
When you look down on the dance floor
and all the different people that are on
mtma,
what is it?
Like 30 percent?
If you had to guess,
man,
30 percent is being very reasonable to
go with at least 50,
but I feel like that's even low.
Yeah.
And it literally might be like 60
percent of the people on ecstasy.
It's like,
do you.
Do you roll?
Are you rolling?
No,
I don't roll.
Wow.
Crazy.
Why are you here?
And
so
if you a casino,
okay.
And you know that all these people were
on ecstasy and you start counting all
the pills start counting and we're
missing out on $150,000 a night.
And ecstasy sales.
Okay.
Who's selling the ecstasy?
Who's the guy?
Where's all that coming from?
How's it getting in?
Who's aware of this?
I didn't have know.
Do they have to know or does it all come
from outside?
Maybe it's all completely detached.
Maybe they don't want to know.
Maybe they know that they need the
ecstasy in order to keep the business
running because like,
I don't know.
See,
here's the thing.
These rooms where people just get
together and dance with a guy on a
turntable that's just sort of pressing
play and also electronic music and
lights.
This is a Recent human phenomena.
it's didn't exist 30,
40 years ago.
People would.
It was saturday night fever.
Staying,
staying alive.
I mean,
yeah,
disco balls.
That was like the best light show you
got.
Oh my god.
The light goes off the ball.
It's crazy.
Now they're.
They have laser shows.
The music is insane.
You know it was.
Confetti is getting shot through the
air.
These people have stayed.
Shows the strobes like,
look at this.
Where's this look?
I don't know.
Random vegas partY.
Dude,
this is insane.
I mean,
they're just a visual splendor of it.
All the,
the led or lcd,
well actually led rIght?
Light emitting diode displays.
It's crazy,
I mean it's beautiful to look at and all
these people have glow sticks like that.
When you see glow sticks,
those people were on ecstasy.
Those people are fucked up.
A lot of them,
like a good percentage,
like look at the size of that place.
A concert that do in the summer called
electronic daisy carnival.
Jesus christ.
This is also in the middle of the summer
when it's 150 degrees out there.
Um,
how many people are just dropping dead
sweat and their dicks off.
They just caught him off and throw them
in a hole in the desert.
This whole wall is in big led show.
Wow.
So like,
I don't know if you're not what you're
enJoying on there if you're not on mtma
or.
Yeah,
you would still enjoy it.
We would,
if we were high,
we would enjoy The shit out of that.
you go and smoke a bunch of weed and go
and stand there.
Same people would pay the same price as
they pay,
pay for alcohol.
They'd pay foR those for weed if they
could smoke them and kind of
the problem with smoking in there as
assholes would light people on fire,
you know?
I don't know if they would do to
displace.
RArely would you find me.
You can even In a group full of peace
minded hippies,
you're going to find one or two dick
wads and once a white someone's hair on
fire,
you know,
dropping ashes on their hair or
something like that.
So you can't really do it.
And that kind of environment.
Well,
wHen you're,
when people are closed in together,
like smoking's fucking dangerous.
Not that dangerous.
You know,
you like,
you thinking about burns to your face or
at me,
haven't you been burned by people?
Yeah.
We all have like accidentally there
cherry drops on you and you're like,
what the fuck?
And like your hands on fire.
You don't know why.
It's because some drunk is hovering over
you with their cigarette while they're
talking and it just drops on you.
That happens.
I mean that's a minor thing.
I mean,
anytime you get a giant group of people
together like that though,
you run risks,
if they could give away pot,
see
the problem with selling it,
even if you're selling it as you're
going to be responsible for all these
people having heart attacks,
if you give them edibles,
like give them that goddamn spray that
joey diaz just pumps it his mouth.
like it's nothing.
This stuff is so powerful.
It's so powerful.
Like it's psychedelic.
It's very,
it's very much like acid in a lot of
ways.
When you get a high dose of the,
uh,
the,
the sprays.
And so if you were doing this experience
on that mean if you could keep it
together,
it'd be wonderful.
But a lot of people are going to get
super paranoid and freak out and have
panic attacks.
And so you don't,
you're gonna want to sell them edibles.
It's like it's too strong for most
folks,
especially people that don't regularly
dabble in it.
They won't know how much to take.
It's not like booze.
Like if someone gives you a shot,
you take a shy,
like holy shit.
Like you feel it pretty quick,
right?
Someone gives you a couple shots.
You're like,
oh geez,
I gotta stop.
I've got to settle down.
Or you go crazy,
but you know what a shot does like a
couple of sprays.
This who the fuck knows what's going to
happen?
You don't know.
You're taking a chance.
Hey,
eat this cookie.
Okay.
You don't know you're taking a chance.
A cookie might be like a shot or it
might be like a whole bottle of vodka,
you know?
It might be so much of a hit a,
you're paralyzed and you just want to
lay in a fetal position on the ground.
So anytime you get a giant group of
people like this,
alcohol is like the safest bet.
If you're going to sell it to them.
Everybody has how to deal with alcohol,
where they deal with it poorly or not.
You kind of know the numbers,
you know,
oh,
I had five beers.
Do don't drive.
You're fucked up.
You know?
Oh,
I had one shot while you're a 350
pounds,
you probably barely feel it.
You know what I mean?
Like we all know what the tolerances
are.
It's pretty.
It's pretty universally acknowledged.
I'd love that.
A place like this exists though,
man,
that these kids can get together and
just go fucking bananas because you can
make some life decisions in these kinds
of rooms.
You could decide where you're gonna,
how you're gonna live your life for
real,
because if you work everyday like Joe
Smith on that fucking construction site
and you show up even with your gold wbc
belt and everyday is hammering nails and
picking up wood and thinking of the time
you have off.
Sometimes you can go to a place like
this and you just experienced joy and
laughter and fun and partying,
and you start to think about your job
job,
your real job,
and you start to dread it.
You start to really dread It.
You start to really get sick and you
start to think about all these people
that are putting on these electronic
carnivals.
Why can't I do that?
Or you think about something else you
do.
I got to make a living making furniture.
I love making furniture.
I fucking loved designing it.
I've got to figure out a way to open up
a shop and then maybe something like
this.
She's these,
these moments when you're away from the
grind and you're just in this fantasy
land and you hear it
and everyone's on ecstasy and people are
walking by touching everybody's chest
and everybody's laughing and you just
realize like,
this is A.
This is all temporary.
This whole experience is temporary and
I'm wasting so much of my temporary time
doing bullshit that I don't want to do.
Everybody tells you what law I want you
to take over the faMily plumbing
business.
I don't want to plumb.
I don't want to clean out anybody's
broken shitter.
I want to make those led lights that,
that turned into floatinG mushrooms.
I want to make those.
Somebody has to make that.
That's a job.
I have to figure out how to get that
job.
That would be the shit.
I mean,
all these people that we have to rely on
and we keep the,
you know,
go to ces every year.
All those people that you have to rely
on,
like all those people pretty much had to
take a chance.
All oF them,
pretty much everybody that's doing any
of those things where they're putting
out these new technologies and showing
all this new inventions,
all of them had to be like
disenfranchise or disenchanted with
something and just got to take a chance.
This is what I want to do and then this
is what I'm going to pursue.
What else did you find that?
Anything else?
Because we've got to wrap this up soon.
I think that was honestly,
I didn't see tons of stuff that was
blowing my mind this year.
I saw a couple of cool things.
What was the phone?
Oh,
that phone.
Yeah.
So the interesting thing about it,
I'll try it.
I even had a little bit of my tomato
weiwei.
Weiwei?
Yeah.
What's,
why way?
uh,
is it an android phone?
Oh yeah.
It does run android thing.
This is it right there.
yep.
Why way?
Who makes a weiwei?
that's the company.
The phone was called like a mate mate
nine.
I think it's the model of their phone.
I was asking this guy question about it
because it.
What it does is it has a really good
lens on it or two lenses actually,
and so it's doing this thing called
aperture and I forget what it was
actually calling out,
so I'm hitting this button here and
trying to see what it was going on.
So I was trying to figure out if it's
actually doing lens blur,
which is what a lot of people were
always after when they're taking
pictures they want really good blur,
photo look good.
Which is what that portrait mode and the
new iphone,
it's kind of all about.
So it keeps the foreground in focus in
the background becomes blurry,
like a real camera.
So I was just asking if it was actually
doing it or if it was simulating it
using software and what he say.
I'm pretty sure he was telling me that
it was stimulating using software.
That's why he was hitting that button.
That's what I kept putting my hand in
front of it to kind of see what was
going on.
So the cool thing about the iphone is it
uses hardware doing that,
right?
Yeah,
it's,
it's using the toolkit as far as I know.
And then again it could be doing some
other stuff.
It's not the same as me grabbing my dslr
camera and having a really good lens and
frame the focus point and all that.
It's not the exact same as that.
So when you,
if you did That with a camera,
you'd be able to tell the difference in
the quality of the image.
That's sorta what I was going.
I was like,
I kind of should be able to tell.
I feel like just by looking at it,
if it's real or not,
it didn't look real to me.
It could've just been a trick and I
might not have been.
I might've just been looking at
something I didn't,
I think I was seeing.
But uh,
what are these kids playing here?
What's three d games?
East sports.
So this is the intel booth.
They're doing a little bit of a there.
This is what an ea sports game situation
might look like in the future because
this is going,
there's a tbs is broadcasting a lot of
east sports or some other company's
investing a lot in it.
How come they don't play those games on
ergonomic chairs like these,
these are ergo depot chairs.
He desert,
those are ergonomic sort of like race
car chairs,
but racecar chairs you sit back.
See when you play a game,
you lean forward just like you use a
computer.
Some,
some people do,
most people obviously are leaning for,
but they also have extra pads and um,
so like have your back in certain spots.
But what,
what's going on here as a,
on the screen above them,
this is a,
their gameplay is being rendered above
their head so that you can be viewing
this in three d space.
So if you had a vr headset onto,
you'll be viewing these situations all
differently in the future.
It's kind of just flows like a concept.
I'm pretty sure they were showing.
Do these chairs we use are so good.
I look at other.
Everybody's sitting in other chairs.
I'm like,
you poor bitch.
These ergonomic capisce co chairs.
Um,
do those have haptic feedback or sound
to come out of them that know those
chairs don't really or anything.
I'm still doing that window thing.
Huh?
Where they have the window in the side
of the computer.
We look in that one I was trying to show
here.
It has some e ink display going on,
which you can't.
You could see it moving a little bit.
Oh whoa.
Oh,
that's dope.
So it just looks cool.
Yeah,
it just looks cool.
Yeah.
Well they've by having all these
different companies making pcs,
they opened themselves up to so much
weird innovations.
One real cool thing,
and again this is one of those things,
I'm not sure if this is real or not.
This is called a tiny most camera.
What they're saying this camera does.
It's made specifically for shooting
outdoor astronomy photos.
It's got google,
the google star maps built into it.
And the reason I don't,
I'm not sure on this because I've tried
personally to take photos of stars and
the moon in different things in the sky
at night.
It's a really hard to do and like for
for one,
if you're trying to take a picture of
what they have done here,
which would be like the galaxy where you
can see the different gasses and
whatnot.
You have to leave your aperture open for
a long time,
a couple of seconds and let the light
get in there.
The opposite of that,
if you're trying to take a picture of
the moon and get detailed picture of the
moon,
you got to go really quick because
there's so much light coming off of it.
You have to get this assistance.
Snap second.
You have to have really good lens and
whatnot.
This camera is good for both and it's
about the same size as a point and shoot
camera and it says that they're allowing
you to take all the and I don't know
exactly how because I couldn't take this
outside myself and play with it.
WhAt do they say when you asked them to
describe how it works?
I.
I didn't ask.
I heard this guy giving a description to
somebody else.
They didn't really give a great.
This is all the data and this is how
everything is a,
this is how it actually works.
They have some,
they have a software which said it was
like a patent pending on some noise
reduction filters,
which would be reducing noise on your
photo and sort post after the fact,
which I don't know if that's,
if it's tricking it or if it's just
removing some of the data from your
picture to make it look like a better
picture,
but it was being advertised on lots of
different outlets as this is maybe they
actually got hands on and I didn't and
they got to see that it was proven so
well.
It'd be really interesting if it was
true.
If you could just point a camera up and
take a picture of the galaxy,
that would be the shit,
but you would have to have no light
pollution.
Correct?
I mean it's not.
No way.
I would see through the law.
You'd have to go somewhere,
right?
Oh my god.
What is this thing?
So this is another like vr.
The skies flying around in space.
This is insane.
You were looking at this guy leaning
forward,
he's got his forearms and his hands
connected to this.
These two handles on the front and the
back.
His feet are strapped into this thing,
so he's kind of planking the whole time.
It doesn't look good if there's anything
on his stomach,
is that correct or is there something on
his stomach?
I don't think so.
So I think that's hard to do,
man.
It doesn't look.
It didn't look like the most comfortable
thing.
Yeah.
See he's leaning on his forearms and
he's,
he,
he's steering himself with his own body
weight.
Well that would be a fucking vicious
workout man.
When you're flying.
I don't think he'd be laying on
something really eat unless you were
flying on like a carpet or.
You know what I mean?
Well you still like.
It's like his body is not subject to
gravity,
but his stomach,
his body's being pulled down.
So you'd have to liKe really develop
your.
I've bet a lot of people gonna hurt
their back on that because like you're
going to do it and you're going to strap
yourself into that thing and you're
going to get to a point where you're too
exhausted to keep planking
or what it says up here in the corner
underneath their little banner that says
it's good for exercise your core and
your upper body and all that.
Oh dude,
people are going to be bulletproof.
They keep doing that.
Like if that's going to be one of those
dance,
dance revolution type things where
people start doing it and they get in
shaped because of it because like this
looks really hard to do.
You remember that thing that we had on
the podcast that we reviewed that frog.
You remember the frog,
brent?
I believe shop was telling us about it,
but it's a a weight thing that you do.
Will you move your body forward and
backward?
Yes.
It's like a.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
And you actually move forward and
backward with it.
I think it's called the frog,
but it looks remarkably similar to that
thing.
So imagine if you have a game where you
put virtual reality headsets on and you
do that frog workout thing.
You can't find it.
Give it a try.
I typed in frog and it's just given me
pictures of frogs lifting weights and
stuff.
What about frog?
Weightlifting equipment?
The frog.
The bull frog?
No.
Is that it?
What it is,
folks is you know that the way a frog
looks when it's moving across water,
when it has those kicks with its back
legs and it's four legs and they come
together and then they go apart.
Frog fitness.
There it is.
And this thing is this weird.
It's got wheels in the front and wheels
on the back and you connect your feet to
the base of it and your upper body to
the front of it.
SkuchA heads.
We could see these guys doing this.
You look,
I got a football,
but it's a serious piece of workout.
See here you see this guy moving with
this thing back and forth and back and
forth,
and uh,
I think you can change the resistance in
those cables.
You can make it more difficult to do and
apparently it gets you in sick shape.
I've heard a lot of people talking about
this thing saying it's a tremendous
piece of a strength and conditioning
equipment by open.
Yeah,
it's 1:30.
All right.
We'll bring in hunter mott's.
That'll be a podcast too.
But imagine doing this with like handles
virtual reality and you're doing a game.
I mean these guys are crawling along
with this thing.
Imagine if you're doing this,
but you think you're flying a spaceship
and you're shooting shit.
We need to Just need to get virtual
reality in a bigger Spaces so we can be
moving around and be playing with each
other.
I think that's a big,
big gap.
We need still to,
to be fixed.
Yeah.
Football fields.
Virtual reality on football fields.
We also don't want to be.
We need to not bike.
If we both have on headsets,
I don't want to bump into you.
Yes,
that's big.
I figured that next step to interesting
stuff.
Young Jamie.
All right,
we'll be right back with hunter mott's.