Drive by day Joe Rogan podcast by night
all day.
I always find a way to get my shit
together and dig myself out of
situations and like ultimately rise
above situation.
Beautiful as long as you don't count on
it right now where I'm sick of getting
in my own way and like,
like UFC 200.
Let's talk about that.
I literally what happened,
I did everything that I could to be back
in a position to win that belt back.
I was getting ready to show this
triumphant amazing story of someone who
she's made it through a hit and run
situation,
had almost had everything taken from
them and got it all back.
And then,
um,
and then,
I'm sorry,
I have,
I'm,
I'm thinking about so many things at
once.
What happened?
Um,
so let's just talk about what happened.
You,
you tested
positive
for some
estrogen inhibitors,
Sgl blockers yesterday and blockers that
a lot of people associate with people
who take steroids,
right?
People take steroids,
they want to restart their system or if
you want to testosterone boost,
you take clomid or clomiphene and these
are,
these are standard drugs in the steroid
users world.
Yeah.
This is on new for me.
Um,
basically what did you take?
So I took a,
I took an offbrand cialis pill.
Offbrand it was,
it wasn't extra Cialis,
but it was described to me as being a
cialis.
And so I thought it was a Cialis and I,
I just took it.
So why does a guy like you need cialis?
Have a huge got jail that's too big.
It's too big.
That's a good answer.
Okay.
We don't have the resources to get it
normally.
Uh,
yeah.
You know,
I um,
you were of,
no,
it wasn't even necessarily a party and
I,
I've taken like a melon harassment
before and for people who haven't taken
it and you literally,
you know,
you go from being like that to just,
it puts the twist at the end of the
punch list.
You know what I mean?
It,
it like,
it.
[inaudible]
it's a good time.
You know,
I had to go to be a quote.
It's a good time now.
What was this like?
One of them's gas station.
Rhino
pills?
No,
I had an edit teammate basically tell
me,
hey,
uh,
he was talking about how his
girlfriend's a pharmacist and,
and he,
he's capable of getting all this stuff
and,
and all that type of stuff.
And I was like,
wow,
I don't do,
I don't do drugs or anything like that.
And he's like,
you ever take a Seattle said?
I was like,
yeah.
He's like,
I got to Cialis.
And I was like,
well,
you said you don't do drugs or anything
like that,
but you would done drugs.
Well,
yeah,
but no,
he was talking about all these
painkillers and all this different shit.
Other things on top that he has because
his girlfriend's a pharmacist and I,
and he was getting this off brand stuff
from,
it's like,
I dunno,
people get a lot
of stuff from China.
I mean that's what happened with
Anderson.
Anderson got liquid cialis from China
and it was tainted.
Yeah.
Look,
this happens.
I know for a fact,
and it mean everyone knows for a fact
that happens.
The supplement industry has a giant
issue with the people that mix the
stuff.
Like if you have a VAT and you're mixing
up whatever creatine or something like
that.
And right before,
I mean,
if this is done in some country or some
place,
it doesn't have excellent standards.
It's not scrupulous.
You could be scooping up steroids in the
batch before that and you just throw the
creatine in it and some of it gets
contaminated and they don't clean it.
Yeah,
that's pretty much,
uh,
log.
I'll get to that,
but okay.
So you take this off brand Cialis,
the guys like,
do you ever,
do you ever do less
flaggers and all that stuff?
And I'm like,
yeah,
I've,
you know,
I've had melly hairspray pills before
and he's like,
oh,
I got cialis.
And I'm like,
oh,
this is great.
So I ended up taking one of the cialis
pills and,
um,
and I thought everything was fine and
dandy.
I had no clue.
Um,
what Ha,
you know,
that I,
that I was now having something else to
me that was illegal.
I took at the Seattle Spiel on June the
14th,
June 16th,
um,
you side came over to my house,
six o'clock in the morning.
Hey,
what's up guys?
That coffee going off her and everybody,
water bottles,
Super Nice,
hospitable,
come in,
um,
laughing and joking with them.
I had no clue that that's test was going
to be the test that derail my life.
And um,
you know,
right before UFC 200,
uh,
my manager mouth,
he calls me over to his hotel room and
he's like,
Hey,
I want to talk to you man,
and that what's going on?
And he's like,
Hey,
you're not going to be fighting.
What are you talking about?
It's like,
you know,
you didn't feel,
you didn't pass your drug test and uh,
the level of hurt and just,
and confusion and I literally had an
anxiety attack and I had never had one
of those before.
What does that feel like?
I felt like the whole room just came in
on me.
Like the whole room came down on me and
I was just,
I couldn't breathe.
I remember opening up his hotel window
looking for a balcony so I could just
breathe and realized that I'm like not
trapped.
Um,
there's little,
the window opened that much.
What the fuck?
So you don't jump out hotel in Vegas?
Where was it?
Vegas fucking brick and I'm breathing.
They don't want gamblers or sleeping
back in.
I'm breathing through the thing,
calm myself down.
And um,
and I instantly started thinking about
the weight of the,
I had the weight of the world literally
on my back.
I knew that,
I knew that I wasn't going to be
fighting a few hours before everyone
else knew.
The public knew and I was just,
I could already start hearing
everything.
Even my own coaches,
we're looking at me like just their
hearts were on the floor.
Like I had done so much to get back to
fighting at UFC 200,
like getting my life in order,
getting the people around me in order,
getting my head,
my health,
my mind.
You just being in order to,
to beat DC and,
and like literally right now I've done
so much,
so much of the right things to be back
in a good position.
And right now,
you know,
people look at me as if I still don't
have my shit together.
But the only thing that I did was I took
a pill that I thought was going to give
me a boner and literally it's caused me
a lot of heartache and a lot of
disappointment and a lot of,
and it just threw me
here in any way,
shape or form.
When someone gives you this pill and you
don't know where it came from,
you don't know.
What did you think,
man?
I don't know what's in this.
No,
I didn't.
I didn't think of it because,
um,
I had been dealing with the athletic
commission.
I've been in the UFC for a long time and
I've taken a little gas station,
Dick Pills before,
like,
you know,
and I've never felt the drug test ever.
But then you,
did you ever think that you might've
gotten lucky?
No,
I didn't think I got lucky.
I thought that you felt drug test when
you're doing sketchy shit.
Right.
But didn't you think there might be some
sketchy shit,
some Chinese,
no.
Station Rhino.
Dick pill.
I,
um,
what do you know about the rhinos?
My friend Ryan,
my friend Brian called it,
he was on the,
on the podcast.
He said,
you know,
John Likes to party.
I bet he took one of them.
Did
pills.
Um,
no.
that's funny.
He called it.
Yeah.
Well he,
he was,
he was on,
I haven't,
I've taken him several times before and
with the Nevada State Athletic
Commission,
um,
I always pass my drug test and,
and I know that I would never do
anything to cheat this sport.
I have a lot of pride in my work ethic
and knowing that dude,
I look,
I've been skinny my whole career,
whooping people's ass.
I'm not a knockout artist.
I wouldn't because I'm smart and you
know,
I work hard.
Um,
but with you,
with the nod,
Nevada athletic commission,
I never had an issue.
And then I was suspended when you cited
came.
So I was never really educated on how
serious you shot.
It really was like I um,
I came back into the game and there's
like,
Oh hey,
we got this new company name and each
side of instead of Nevada.
What were you suspended for when you saw
the king?
Oh,
I'm into this sport.
I understand what you're saying.
When we came into your house,
so when you started came into the sport,
I was used to spend it because my hit
and run and so I never had even met
anyone who worked for you that I,
I'd never been sat down.
I know you signed a seminar,
what to do and what not to do and how
serious it is and what could happen if
you do this.
And only thing I knew it was I had to
report where I was at.
Like if I go to La for the weekend,
I got a little sad to know that I'm in
La because they can drug test me at
anytime.
That's the only thing I really knew
about.
You saw the,
I didn't know that doing something that
I had done several times before.
It could ultimately lose me a fight.
So,
um,
the only difference was I had taken like
little gas station pills aren't,
I've taken viagara before.
This was,
this teammate gave me something that was
Seattle is I thought the only thing that
it would do is make me bigger and
stronger for longer.
That's all I thought was going to be
happening.
Right.
I,
and then when I find out that,
that I had just failed the drug test.
Do you know that via Viagara is a
actually illegal in the Olympics?
I didn't know that.
You can't take that stuff.
The Viagra is a performance enhancer
though.
It's a Vasso dilator,
I believe.
I believe that's how they describe it.
And it actually has athletic performance
enhancing pro,
um,
properties to it.
How does it,
how does it help you?
I don't know.
We'd have to look into that,
but I think it,
it's similar to,
in a lot of ways to nitric oxide
supplement.
Like a PR,
like a pre workout.
Get your,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean it does something to open up your
blood cells and get you pumped.
I mean,
it does something not just to your Dick,
but to all of your muscle.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I don't know if I would want it to be
pumped up during a fight.
I don't think it works that way.
I mean,
I don't,
I think it actually can possibly
potentially help endurance.
Well,
yeah,
I know,
but I know that athletes take it for
that reason.
That's why it's banned from the
Olympics.
Yeah.
But,
um,
but yeah,
you know,
I understand that it wasn't your
intention.
It was not my intention.
I had no,
I had no clue that I needed to report
this to your side of it because I
thought,
you know,
literally I was reporting everything
else.
What supplements,
what preworkout what,
you know,
my amino acids,
my protein powder,
like you saw it,
it had all my stuff.
And what happens once you find out?
Did you,
how'd you narrow it down to this pill?
I literally,
I went through my supplements and I,
um,
handed it to,
I hired that private lab in the lawyer
and we started handing it,
giving them everything that I took,
which isn't really a lot of stuff at
all.
You know,
stuff that everyone should take.
Fish oil,
basic,
basic supplements,
protein,
protein powder,
fish oil,
um,
you know,
liver cleanses or whatever.
I'm just grape seed extract,
that kind of stuff.
Yeah.
Just very,
you know,
multivitamins for men,
Beijing.
Very basic stuff.
Okay.
And um,
and then,
and then get nutrition and it's like,
you know,
we,
we've scanned all of our stuff.
We know it's not from that gut nutrition
website though.
It's fucking hilarious.
Got Nutrition website.
The moment we found out about it that
someone said,
John sponsored by Gat Nutrition.
So we've,
oh,
hey,
well let's check that out.
Get nutrition.
There's some fucking dude is,
they have a lot of great,
great products that you want to get big
and strong and then you can definitely
go to them,
you know?
But as soon as we saw that,
we were like,
what in the holy fuck is he taking?
Oh,
no,
I mean,
but people saw you,
you got gigantic,
huge,
completely,
uh,
completely unnatural.
I,
that's what I have great pride in being
a natural athlete.
But,
um,
but uh,
so they got,
they got all the cat stuff,
test it and clear,
right.
Everything was clear.
Um,
this gets to have other things that you
saw don't regulate.
Absolutely.
But the things that they gave me they
were super smart about and I,
all the products I was thinking with
clear and um,
and so my manager was like,
think outside of the box.
Like did you take anything that could
have possibly been?
And I was like,
I don't think so.
Then I was like,
well,
one of my teammates did give me this,
this dick pill.
And he's like,
I need those.
So we got those pills tested and sure
enough,
they and their ingredients,
they listed about five products in their
ingredients and they actually,
uh,
there was actually like seven products
too that weren't listed in the
ingredients.
The two estrogen blockers were never in
their ingredients.
So,
um,
it was a tainted pill.
It was what I'm saying.
Yes.
So,
um,
so the [inaudible] was able to tell,
okay,
this was totally in attention or there's
no engine,
no way in Hell I'm John would take these
estrogen blockers and purpose.
First of all,
it was very small traces.
So it wasn't like I was loaded up with
estrogen blockers.
And why the fuck would they put estrogen
blockers out?
We believe that,
uh,
the factory that created these,
these Dick Pills,
um,
were maybe manufacturing these pills in
a dirty laboratory or whatever.
And there were because of this container
just tainted.
Yes.
Because each pill that we,
that we had tested,
some of them had more estrogen blocker,
some had almost no estrogen blockers,
some had small traces.
Actually none of the pills were
consistent.
So it was obvious that when we started,
we tested several different packages.
So it was obviously that,
that these pills were probably getting
made in the same machine and there was
just traces,
which is to show up in your system.
We found some of these dick pills that
had none,
no estrogen blockers.
They're like,
damn,
why did I get that?
Yeah,
exactly.
So I took one that was just contaminated
enough and literally I got tested two
days later and it was in my system.
So it was,
it was obvious that it was complete
accident and even,
and even if I were to report it,
the Dick Pill to you side,
uh,
they would have read the label and the
label would,
it never said that it was extra blocker
in there and I still would have had a
dirty right.
Entertainment contaminated.
Where does that leave you?
How much time did they suspend you for?
I got suspended for,
for a year from starting from back in
July.
So now I find in July of two subs,
I love you shot up.
I love what they're doing.
I don't agree with things like that.
Because what you took does not enhance
your performance.
No,
it doesn't.
It's especially in such a trace amount.
I feel like in certain circumstances,
like there's been several fighters like
Chad Mendez.
Um,
he has,
uh,
I believe he has eczema.
He was taking an Eczema cream that had
some sort of a,
was it a hormone precursor or a hormone?
Peptide?
I believe some sort of a hormone
peptide.
I think that enhances,
uh,
the,
the use of this
cream.
I don't,
I don't the full,
I'm
obviously not a doctor or a scientist,
but there's something about suspending
someone for something like that.
That seems ridiculous.
Yeah.
Well in my situation,
they,
the,
the evening you start his lawyer,
he showed,
he showed a little bit of remorse.
I can,
I can feel that he felt bad about what
was happening to me cause I think he can
really,
even the arbitrators,
they could tell what had actually
happened,
but their problem was they said Janet
was just negligent.
Like you didn't,
you should have reported this pill.
But that's it seems to me that's silly.
That means that,
but even if I would have reported the
pill,
they would have read the ingredients and
they would've never saw that there was a
trace of,
of something that wasn't advertised.
So
spend someone for something like,
because they,
because they said it,
there was zero tolerance policy.
It was just like I was the first fighter
to ever take them to into arbitration
and,
and they were more upset that I didn't
let them know that I took the pill.
Then what actually happened was like the
rule is you tell us what you take and we
can point you in a different direction.
Right.
But I never told him when I took,
my whole argument was even if I told you
what I took,
right,
it's still was never on the label.
So unless you guys were going to spend
all the money to take it to a private
law or tickets to a laboratory to test
this individual pill,
you get what I'm saying?
I still don't ran into the same
situation.
I think it's great to protect people
from people that cheating.
I don't think it's great to punish
someone for taking something that has a
trace amount of something that does the
absolutely no benefit whatsoever and
clearly and wasn't supposed to be in
that pill and wasn't supposed to be in
that pill and clearly wasn't being taken
to enhance athletic performance.
Right.
That seems silly.
It seems like a mess.
Right?
It seems like a mass that,
I mean,
I,
I understand their zero tolerance
policy.
I don't agree with it in this war,
the Chad Mendez situation,
you know,
there's,
there's weird ones like Yoel Romero,
he tested positive for something.
They found out that it was a,
in one of the protein powders or
something he was taking,
it wasn't supposed to be in there.
It wasn't listed that way and they gave
him an abbreviated sentence.
He should have had no,
no,
no parts whatsoever.
But um,
I mean,
my whole thing,
Joe,
is I'm so grateful.
I'm still optimistic,
man.
I'm always looking for light in every
situation.
Um,
and I think that's the way I deal with
things.
I just,
I'm always trying.
I always believe there's going to be
good at the end of the day.
That's just how I am.
I'm just so grateful where most people
would be so upset with themselves and
all this type of stuff.
I'm really not,
I'm upset about the fans that I let down
who flew out to UFC 200 and things like
that.
But as far as the whole situation,
I'm just glad that that my ne,
my name would no longer be associated
with steroids.
I rather it be bowling or boy or
whatever you want to call me.
You know,
But steroids that that was,
that would have really,
that was really bothering me,
so I'm just glad that it's out.
What actually happened
[inaudible].