Du du,
Du,
Du du Du four,
three two one my brother and the man who
got me into instagram for it wasn't for
you.
I would have abandoned net member.
You're the whining and I still got like
40,000 followers and you got like 4
million.
I don't have that many.
I don't even think I have 2,000,002 men.
Whatever.
Uh,
you got me into it man.
Hey Stacia [inaudible] what does that
mean?
You say that all the time slot.
You is like the Gaelic Irish.
A salute.
Slungshot it's like s l a I n t e with
like one of them crazy marks on it.
Oh,
that's a,
it's so gaelic gaelic is a function,
real wrangled language to read or try
and pronounce some shit.
It'll be like somebody's name will be
gary and it'll be spelled with like six
17 letters.
Say Shit.
Crucifixes rooms,
crucifix with the circle.
I was just,
I think it was among those rooms and
shit.
I don't know dude.
Does anyone speak Gaelic?
Couldn't you go have a conversation with
some oak in Ireland?
People do for sure.
So it was,
you're like,
um,
like kind of fading away thing,
but there you'll find pockets that
definitely do.
It's fucking crazy.
When you stopped thinking about how many
different languages that are,
like if you done much touring in Asia,
um,
it really only Japan.
I haven't hit crew.
I've never been to Korea and never been
like,
um,
China.
Never been in Indonesia or anything
that's not written.
Yeah.
Indonesia,
yes,
Sorta Asia.
I've only been to Japan and only for a
few days.
Can you imagine?
Oh,
it's amazing.
The people are so nice and polite and
it's,
it's fascinating.
Culture works.
One of the reasons I love it so much too
is it's like you go to Europe,
you don't feel foreign necessarily.
You know what I mean?
It's really the forerunner experience.
When you're there you go.
Here I am now out obvious outsider.
I'm tollard most people and I'm
Caucasian,
you know?
And there's a lot of places they're
like,
I tried to go to,
I'd get the low down on a Sushi spot
from somebody that I knew there.
And then you go there and be like,
oh no,
no guys,
you can,
we don't serve them.
We don't serve you all here.
Like still places like that.
You know what I mean?
When you're trying to get the down low
anthony bordain treatment like Anthony
Bourdain,
you might not have no luck,
you know,
show up at that 0.0 crew.
Yeah man.
It just,
um,
they're so different than us in their,
their culture that it's like this crazy
immersion into like an alternative
world.
Like Japanese writing is so different
than American writing to sound.
Their languages is so different than the
sound of English.
Then when you go there you're like,
wow,
this is like,
look,
I'm literally peering into a coexisting
alternative world.
Like what if,
what if there was no different
languages?
It was just language.
Like everybody knew what everybody
spoke,
right.
And your language was the s the sounds
that they make and the way they
interpret things and the way they
interpret things shapes the way they
look at reality.
I sure that's,
I mean it's a weird,
like our culture is in a lot of ways
almost like an operating system.
I think Terence Mckenna described that
way and thinking kind of makes sense.
It is like an operating system.
Yeah.
We learn a basic set of parameters and
rules that we all kind of Obi yeah,
we're all individuals within it,
but like there's,
you know,
hey,
in this society this is what's
acceptable and this is what it isn't and
here's how we peer it.
And when you see something like we were
talking about this book,
dear reader,
Michael Milas who was on and a yesterday
who was just amazing podcast guest,
but it was talking to us about North
Korea.
Like that's a different,
totally different operating system and
that shit is going on right now.
Right now there's like a whole country
that's imprisoned.
Yeah.
What's amazing to me is that that many
people can be subdued to me in that
manner.
Like wears you out,
you read throughout history.
It's like,
you know,
people got sick and tired of some shit
after a while and just bucked up.
Yeah.
Where are they?
What,
what is going on?
There wasn't mastery to these dudes have
that.
It's crazy.
I mean I look at it and there's millions
of people that they're starving and
still accept and this dude's living in
is whatever,
golden palace,
whatever kind of lifestyle.
And nobody's really like trying to
revolutionize started revolution or buck
up and make a cool would be a problem.
Cause I think the old guys around him or
even crazier,
but,
well malice was telling me why he was
saying that the way that society is
structured,
everybody reports on everybody else
about what you did wrong.
Like if you and I were hanging out
together,
we'd be forced to report at the end of
the day,
I would have to report on everything you
did wrong.
Like maybe you didn't cry long enough
when something happened.
Maybe he didn't express enough grief.
Like you'd have to,
there's like rules to the way you
grieve.
People who didn't grieve heart enough
got six years,
six months rather of hard labor for not
grieving hard enough when Kim Jong and
go later.
Yeah.
Whoa.
That's so they tell on each other.
So they have this crazy culture of
television that podcasts was
fascinating.
Man.
That dude is a really,
really interesting guy.
Scary that that's a worlds,
it's happening right now.
It exists and next door it South Korea,
which is driving and pop culture galore.
Yeah,
crazy plastic surgery.
Those girls,
I'll get a,
those are not those all of them,
but a high percentage of girls get their
eyes changed.
They get this crazy surgery that makes
your eyelids,
they shrink your eyelids so they don't
have the Asian look.
Oh,
there's inner,
I tried it for a more of a round.
I think they tried for a mortar of an
anime thing.
Oh,
the big guy.
Have you seen it?
I think I have.
I,
but I don't.
I don't think it was an Asian girl.
I think I saw some,
some girl on Internet who just trying to
look really much talking about Barbie
Lady.
Right.
The party leading.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
There's people that go do,
it's like,
how do you think like that?
How's your brain working?
I mean like you're not looking in the
mirror and seeing the same thing.
I mean this is your,
this is giving you satisfying,
I don't understand.
I think it's just body dysmorphia.
It's the same thing as like a,
a person who's a bodybuilder who just
can't get big enough or a woman who
can't get fake enough breasts.
Like they keep wanting to get bigger and
bigger ones.
You,
you don't see yourself how everybody
else sees you.
So it's almost like a disease.
And I that um,
it's always funny cause I've always
thought it was a pretty fucking awesome
dude.
Yeah.
Well it's called self esteem.
She pulled those pictures up so the
checkout what they do,
see if you could see good ones.
Three reasons why one gin,
plastic surgery for ice,
eyelid surgery shit,
but show some like before and afters
because they kind of a little one,
right?
They're kind of crazy.
Some of them are kind of crazy.
Like they look like a totally different
human.
Like if you went to high school with
her,
you be like,
what?
That seems totally normal right there.
There's been some extreme ones.
See if you could fire her whole face is
different shaped at that point.
The one you just passed.
It was more than just eyes done there,
man.
It's interesting seeing that younger and
younger girls are having that kind of
stuff done too.
Whoa.
Damn,
whoa.
That one was very successful.
That was a good decision.
Yeah,
it was an excellent decision.
But how do we know these are real?
You know?
That's another thing could be getting,
fuck.
Holy Shit.
Look at that one.
This is something I wanted to talk to
you about.
Anything.
How do we know what it's like?
How do you know what the fuck is true
anymore?
It's almost impossible to come because
everybody's mastered the half truth.
Yeah.
You mean that I got a piece of the truth
and then I spin it the way I want to
spend it.
So a certain amount of people are going
to see it that way.
That's what,
that's how they,
they really,
the whole,
I,
I trip on this whole system.
I know I don't give a fuck about trump,
Clinton,
any of that.
All right.
You know,
fuck all of them.
They're all lying crooks as far as I'm
concerned.
Right.
But peep game on how they have blue
states red.
We're like bloods and crips here,
they,
and they're making it more like that
every day.
Like the hatred between this blue and
red.
It's like,
what the fuck is this?
Yeah.
It's like people got along just six
months ago and now at each other's
throats and there used to be a thing
when we were young,
when the new president was elected and
he became president and we all kind of
sat back and said,
okay,
that's our president.
Let's see what,
right.
I'm not saying we're not even gonna get
into dude.
Right.
I'm talking to you as a,
as a just as a principle.
That's that exchange of,
but we all sat back and said,
okay,
let's,
let's give the guy a shot at least.
Right.
And again,
we're not even gonna.
I'm not even interested in getting into
all the individual in question.
Right.
That doesn't exist anymore.
It's like the minute this dude's
precedent,
the next fucking campaign starts and
like,
it's just fucking crazy.
Is it that as crazy as I think it is,
Joe,
or am I just sitting at home?
Everything is crazy dad world of,
of taking care of these babies and going
on tour and I just turn on the TV and it
blows my fucking mind blowing
everybody's mind,
man.
I mean there's a weird line that's
happening now too and like,
this isn't really even a criticism,
but Newsweek had an article that they
tweeted and the article shows how Molina
rejects trump's hand.
I mean this,
this was kind of awesome.
I saw it.
It was kind of locked it away.
It's cool.
It is kind of,
but who knows what's going on.
Maybe she gets public gangs,
anxiety and she hasn't like holding
hands when she walks.
Like he doesn't necessarily have to mean
anything.
The fact that it's a fucking story that
Newsweek tweets out is stir range.
CNN had it on,
I believe.
Uh,
they got a whole article after hand.
Swat.
Let me,
this is nothing.
It's like they touch hands for a second,
back it up again.
I'm no trump supporter here,
but look,
Newsweek,
I'm not,
don't get me wrong.
He does anything wrong with what you're
doing.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with putting this up.
I watched it.
I'm glad you put it up.
You would watch it.
It's not news though.
We are all part of the biggest reality
TV show ever created in the universe
now.
Yeah.
It seems like trump as the host.
Yeah,
I see it as and that's,
and this man is actually living out his
goddamn fantasy right now.
Like we have all given this guy,
and again,
I don't care.
I'm not even gonna say,
Hey,
love whatever.
Fuck them all.
It's fascinating.
But this dude is like king of the
fucking universe in his mind right now.
There's nobody can fucking touch him.
And that's the fucking,
that's why the show is going to get so
hilarious.
It's just going to be great.
Well,
I think he's,
he's not dot stupid.
Like he's aware that there's been a lot
of criticism and he's trying to iron
things out.
But what he's doing is he's taking this
approach that he's made become this real
estate magnate,
this,
you know,
big tycoon,
big businessman,
which is why he was always this
rambunctious sort of flamboyant
personality,
right?
He always put his name in gold letters
on these buildings and we didn't mind
that when he wasn't running the country.
It's just when you run the country and
you start doing the same stuff,
like the criticism that he's getting,
his kind of each,
you can't kind of do the same thing when
you're the president.
You can't like talk to him about it.
I was showing the number one thing,
it's a bigger than yourself thing.
You just nailed it.
In fact,
you have to let go of self to a certain
degree.
You know what I mean?
To be a good one.
And I'm not saying I'm not going to sell
you one guy has been better than the
other.
We all know we have our opinions on that
shit.
You know?
I mean,
and honestly I grew up in an age where
politics and religion,
whether if it was going to be bad news,
you didn't bring it up with people you
like.
Do you know what I mean?
And now it's just the,
the hatred.
I see like even from people I respect
the red and white,
red and blue hen they cripping and blood
now here,
hard man,
hard for their parties.
And it's stupid because none of them
care about you.
None of them want anything from you,
but more of your tax money.
No matter how much they're going to tell
you,
they're going to cut your taxes.
You know what I mean?
They,
if they're going to find a way to
fucking get that money,
they might make it look good to you.
But Hey,
guess what ms,
middle class family and $36,000 a year,
whatever.
We here's two grand.
You don't have to pay in taxes a year,
which just seems a lot when you're in
that level of living.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I blow that on fucking sneakers.
I'm ashamed to say.
You know what I mean?
But the point is they don't give a fuck
cause they just stole it out the back
end of your health care or they just
took it off the top of not rebuilding
all the roads.
This is their game.
They run the game.
And so these motherfuckers come up with
some shit where money comes out of the
politics.
I don't respect any of it.
I would like to think that some of them
have your best interest in mind that
there's just a crazy competitive system
and that we may be,
you know,
maybe it's just like what the system
makes like the system kind of corruption
because of lobbyists,
because of the way it's set up.
It's almost like you can't pull it out
of it.
I totally agree with you that there's
plenty of good ones.
It's just like cops.
I know a lot of cons and they're all
good guys.
When the shit storms pop up,
but when the shit storms pop up,
they don't bug out and say like,
you know what that was wrong and go
against what the group of cops are.
Politicians is saying either one.
I could be either one they side even in
wrong times when they shouldn't.
Where are those voices?
I want to hear him.
Don't you think there's way more?
That's where you get respect.
Yes,
I do.
Politicians.
But,
but my point is there's a code,
I'll use a code and that good cop will
fucking not shit on a backup.
Maybe he will back him,
but he's still,
there's a time when you got to shit on
that thing or person or that act,
that,
and,
and there's this code and politicians
and cops where they don't call out the
bullshit.
Yup.
You know what I mean?
And that's where I lose all the respect
for everything.
It's like,
oh,
and I just sit back,
I'm on some Carlin Shit,
man.
I got a front row seat to the freak
show.
You watch it go down.
You're asking them to do the impossible
job.
You're asking them to be around violence
and lying and danger and they're the
enemy.
You're asked him to be the professional
enemy to professional criminals.
That's what you're asking them to do all
the time.
And so like there's a reason why they
bond together like that because they're,
they're all in the war together and it's
us and them and it's,
we on the outside,
I don't think we understand what the
fuck they go through.
That's why they have this bond with each
other.
It's no doubt you wouldn't want that you
will really would want,
but there comes a time.
You're right.
And there's been a few of them lately
in,
in recent history.
Oh yeah.
Well,
there should have been an overwhelming
coming in condemnation by a group of,
of,
of a smaller group of that group's
actions.
Um,
examples that Eric Gardner case in New
York where they choke that guy who's
just selling cigarettes.
They didn't have to do that.
There was no reason to do that.
That guy didn't even have any cigarettes
on him.
The whole thing was fucked up.
They were saying he wasn't complying.
Why should he comply?
He didn't,
he wasn't doing anything.
You can't,
and you can't tell when you went to the
video,
was he not complying enough to die?
You know what I mean?
Well,
I think the dude had like an asthma
attack or something,
but obviously the vote bark,
they have choke there.
The gas choke though.
It was more like,
honestly,
I mean it was a choke hold,
but it was more like the way he was
applying it was like a restraining thing
more than it was.
I want to see it.
Let me see it again.
Maybe I'm remembering it wrong,
but without a doubt the forearm is under
the neck.
Like if I was in a colony in a fight,
I would say this guy's getting choked.
Right.
Honestly,
did not even go down that road.
But the point of this conversation I
believe was just saying like,
oh,
that overwhelming larger number of good
folks,
whether it's cops,
politicians,
soldiers,
whatever.
Right.
I do believe that exists,
that the majority of them are decent,
good people,
but when the shit hits the fan,
they don't collectively say that's wrong
and that's fucked up.
No.
They all band together and say like,
all right,
we'll try and bury this and hide it or,
or just deny it kind of thing.
And that as a group loses you respect.
When people are seeing you know,
that are interested in justice and
interested in fair and interest in that
seed,
these things happen.
They lose faith.
You and I think there's no faith in
anything right now.
The way I see.
I see the way I see the division in this
country on it,
there's no faith in anything open.
It's just a wave and it's going to come
back.
It will.
I mean that's what I'm,
I'm thinking that we're going to react
to,
I just hope it doesn't come easy.
We really fucked up ways because
sometimes when that wave crashes,
it breaks shit.
You know what I mean?
Well,
it shouldn't.
The problem is it's so easy to think
that we're against each other.
It's so easy to dig your heels in and
argue one side or argue the other or
pick a team and be totally committed to
it.
Whether it's red,
blue or whether it's black,
white people get on these goddamn teams.
We do it.
Men and women.
Did you see it?
It gets real divisive online with people
separating men and men.
Women like criticizing men,
all men in general,
criticizing women,
all women in general.
It's the same shit it exists.
Whether it's Democrat versus Republican,
it's,
it's the same shit.
Vegans versus carnivores.
It's the same shit.
People pick a fucking team and they
fight for it and they think they're
right and they have many,
many good reasons for thinking that
right,
but I think all of us or are way better
off if we're taught about these team
ideas early and recognize when you see
them in yourself and do something like
self governing and avoid those,
avoid those and we'll find common ground
on a lot more shit than we think.
It's pretty much,
we can sum that up but like no,
think for yourself.
Yeah.
It's hard to do,
especially when you're bombarded the way
we are now.
That's another thing about how we
started this conversation is a how do
you know what the fuck is really true?
If you really want to know what the fuck
is true or at least get a good semblance
of it,
you have to look at more than one
fucking thing.
If you read some story on facebook that
outrageous you and fucking makes you so
pissed off,
maybe it was intended to do that.
Maybe you should go look further,
look down the road,
look at a paper you would never look at.
Look at it.
I,
I like to look when I,
when I get interested in the news,
which isn't as much as it used to be
because I have my own things,
which I'm sure we'll get into it.
I tried to be like,
all right,
I see CNN is on at my studio a lot
without the sound because we'll be
making music and whatnot.
And mostly I just read the ticker
because if,
you know,
nowadays news is on the ticker,
opinions are what are coming out the
fucking speakers when the,
when the personalities are talking.
News is just the facts that roll scroll
along down on the bottom and you know,
there's some spin on it and whatnot.
But I try not to listen to the talking
heads cause they,
you know,
Fox has to pro Democrat guys that no
matter what the Democrats do,
they're going to defend it.
And CNN has a couple of trump guys that
no matter what goes on,
it's a game.
They're playing a game.
It's a game.
You know what I mean?
They're,
they're all,
it's all a game.
It's a,
it's a television show.
I was watching it that not too long ago
when CNN came on after a commercial and
the studio was lit up,
red and Korean stars were everywhere and
there was nuclear missile launches like
pictures in the background.
And I was like,
oh my God,
what the fuck is going on?
Did they just launched missiles and the,
and nothing like it had happened.
They were just discussing the
possibility of the future of if they got
a missile that was capable and it's like
this is,
and people are tuned into this shit.
And is that,
like I said,
it's on in the background cause I just,
God forbid that breaking news and you
want to know,
I mean it's reality TV honestly.
And again,
it's what we're talking about people
acting as groups and did above.
It heals groups.
I watch it.
I see too.
It's entertaining to me.
But my,
my,
my deeper self,
brain,
whatever you want to call it,
the whiskey starting to fucking talk to
me right now.
So that has a conscious,
my conscious,
my soul know,
evaluates why I'm being entertained by
it and finds it disturbing a lot.
Like in wants to say like,
hey man,
we should all fucking take a step back
and I love you because you're the love
shit.
I've always have had love in my life.
I've been a very fortunate man.
But like coming in here has grown men.
And when I first started doing your
podcast,
you would always be preaching love.
And you know how many Joe Rogan's a
tough guy,
he kicked the shit out of 90% of the
fucking people around.
He's not interested in it.
He just wants to love life is better if
you just hear about it started me down a
pad dude where I was like,
I've explored almost every religion,
you know what I mean?
There is,
um,
and I,
I don't really practice any,
but I have a philosophy that's taken its
own good parts from all right.
And,
um,
lately I've been reading a lot of
Buddhist stuff.
I'm not a Buddhist at all,
but like this tick not Han guy and a few
other things I've been reading.
But these things are also kind of
started here because connecting with you
in a weird way,
it made me open my mind up to it.
Like,
like there's a lot of things we don't
think alike at all on,
you know what I mean?
But it doesn't,
that's,
that doesn't fucking matter.
I know talking to people that I don't
necessarily exactly,
but I respect it.
That's like one of my fit,
some of my favorite conversations.
That's the best kind you can get that.
And that's the point of what they're
trying to keep from happening in this
world.
Whether it be,
I mean,
just this whole online shit has taken
us.
Yeah,
there's a lot of great things that have
happened from this,
but this social networking shit is
anything but social.
We're working it out.
You know,
he didn't say anything but social.
Well for a lot of people it's just way
too distracting.
A lot of wicked evil,
just venom that like,
you know,
I've learned from either very once in a
while,
every once in a while I'll cater in
their office.
I'll let her do no online like,
hey motherfucker,
you really don't.
You really don't know.
That's,
you know what I mean?
Hey whatever.
You really don't know.
I pee addresses are easy to you know,
and that kind of shit.
And you know what?
Nine Times out of 10 when I do fuck up
that rare occasion,
it's a Joe Rogan Fan.
It's like,
hey man,
take the high road dude.
Chill to ask Joe.
You know what I mean?
I'd be like,
Oh fuck yeah.
Shit.
All right,
you're right and I'll and boom,
that's over.
Yeah,
kind of thing.
You know what I mean?
This show is being
like a real serious not just to show you
me and you having a little friendship
cause I've hung out with you a lot since
it's been three years.
We've got though,
it was where we were trying to figure it
out.
We're like,
why does it not feel like three wheels?
Let me explain.
Three years now since we were,
since I couldn't come in for a while and
I explained this to you on the phone and
when we hung out a couple of times,
my mother was passing from Alzheimer's
and then when she did pass it was like I
was emotionally and capable.
If I would have to,
I couldn't even have said those words.
I would have been a blubbering idiot on
your show and you know,
you know,
whatever.
Some people might've been like,
hey that we'd been great radio.
I mean you were the one that said,
hey,
get your shit together.
Do you know what I mean?
Cause I wanted to come here and hey boy,
I said it like that.
That would be like Joe Case shit
together.
So your mom's dead Bro.
It's us talking.
You know what I mean?
That's how I said it.
I know what you mean.
But it would be more like,
you know,
looks today was I went to,
it was the last four years,
probably started probably last right
before I stopped.
The last time I came on the show,
there was like a big law suit over jump
around that I actually wound up winning.
But like if froze money that I depend on
Brian,
like mailbox money,
we call that those checks,
they just kind of come in and then know
jumping around,
it's been really good to me to jump
around is one of my favorite hip hop's
25th anniversary this year,
the whole first album.
So,
but point being,
so I got out when I first started
hanging out with you because I was such
a fan of that song,
I was like,
I can't believe I know this dude.
I remember you were weirded out when I
lit a joint in the club and then you
were like,
what are you doing?
I was like,
what do you mean what am I doing?
I'm lying to join.
And everlast goes,
he goes,
you want to get high?
I go,
fuck yeah and,
and I go,
where you want to go?
He goes,
go.
That goes,
Yo,
we ain't going nowhere.
But it looks to me like sideways,
like go splash it right in the club.
And I was like,
oh,
this is hilarious.
And that wasn't,
that wasn't that that same night that
you performed on stage and there was a
bunch of musicians and it never worked
together on stage.
Dave Navarro is,
you know,
that was a day Camp Freddy.
They had like a band or they just did a
bunch of covers and I remember being a
fucked up and they weren't calling me a
bunch of like three or four times
before.
I'm on to what is like a fucking drunk
night.
That's us all.
We're barbecue.
God,
I can't see my eyes.
That's exactly the spot we were smoking
a joint in too,
right?
It's exactly where it was bad.
I just never remember you looking at me
sideways and go and go fuck up.
Go hide in the bathroom and smoke a
joint of here.
I took way too good for that bullshit.
Especially in Vegas.
If any place in the world you're going
to be over outlandish tipper,
be there because you'll get away with
murder.
Almost literally the valets,
we'll say like,
all right,
Yo,
the cops are on their way.
You put it,
get the fuck on it.
I'm sure they want to keep them.
Checks come in.
Cops are coming whether you like it or
not.
Imagine being a Carbon Vegas,
Jesus Christ who regardless how many
people they have down there,
robin casinos and shit.
Crazy movie style heads with masks on
and machine guns and shit taking over
casinos.
But um,
oh I was talking about so that I was
like so much money got froze.
So I was having like bust my ass crazy
heart like on the road trying to make up
the difference for awhile.
And then my mother started going way
downhill kind of fast over two years,
you know,
it was like dealing with that is anybody
going through that is is,
you know,
gets,
I mean there's a lot of things that go
on in my life that I'm getting my heart
sent out to those people.
But watching somebody you love just
disappear.
It was tough man.
That was,
that was spective right.
It changes your perspective.
You realize that this is,
this is how it ends.
I had a lot of guilt involved because
with a kid with cf,
I couldn't have my mom in home with a
nurse in any infections that she could.
She was getting lung infections all the
time.
So I had her in a home,
a really beautiful home.
They took a magnificent care of my
mother.
But there was a lot of guilt.
I was,
I was fricking for a while,
like with a lot of darkness that I was
swimming through.
And as that guy,
he's just wasn't good for me to come
through.
And then,
you know,
and then after cheap has,
and like layla has just been like a
learning,
you know,
I'm only just me and my wife now,
it's,
she's seven years old and I think,
I'm not saying we got anything licked or
co,
but like the life we have to live,
we've been able to figure out with her
cystic fibrosis,
cystic fibrosis.
Oh cause there's all,
I mean it's heavy.
There's a lot of shit you got to worry
about infections and any common cold
cause senator to the hot.
It's like so much pressure on a person
to do that.
It's,
it's,
it's my wife and I like,
you know,
I won't fucking make it funny.
We,
we've been very close to the brink a few
times,
but we've finally gotten to a stage
where it was like,
Nah,
none of that's going to break us.
You know what I mean?
We're good and we're good and we're good
in this life and theirs and we accept
where we are and we're going to make
sure this,
this young lady is,
is going to make it as deep and as far
into this life as she can.
You know?
And it's been some medical innovations
too,
right?
I haven't,
they're working on some stuff,
man.
There's a,
there's a couple of drugs that aren't
quite for her yet because this drug has,
in the,
on the DNA level of the chain,
there's,
there's mutations.
Layla has two different mutations.
One's called the a D Delta f five five
Oh eight I believe it is.
You've got me hiring a little drunk
care,
but like,
no,
no.
People know.
People who know know it's easy to find
out what she has the most common.
That's the most common one.
Like the Delta five Oh eight,
and then she has this other,
a weird kind of off shoot one.
There's one for some people have a w.
Dot.
What they call a double delta.
There's a drug right now that's really
working well for the people with the
Double Delta.
They're starting to experiment it on,
on it for people with the single now
does she have to be on a special diet
like uh,
uh,
the only diet we did,
we just need her to,
she needs to do,
they have a problem gaining waves.
Cystic fibrosis,
they um,
uh,
they don't process fats properly.
They have to take enzymes with
everything they eat.
So gaining weights,
a real serious issue.
Um,
Laila actually has a g tube,
a feeding tube that she gets sick,
shake protein shakes a day,
pumped into her stomach.
Oh Wow.
She again,
if you're,
my daughter very rarely is down about
this.
She'll have her moments,
don't get me wrong,
where it's like frustration and anger
overheard it,
but it's,
this is life.
She's never known anything else.
So it's like at the same time,
like we post a lot about it.
We've made a decision.
Layla has her own page,
people are free to try and follow it.
If my wife will approve you,
if you can get by the security
clearance.
Her thing is layla l a I l a beauty oh
nine.
She wanted her own page because we
start,
I've never posted anything without
asking her.
Right.
Even when she was like barely able to
understand,
I tried to be like,
can I post this picture?
A lot of people will see it and she'll
say,
okay daddy.
And now she's,
you know,
she's sharp.
And uh,
about a year or so ago she was like,
I want my own instagram page.
I want to share my life,
like cystic fibrosis with people.
And so she's doing that and we,
this is may actually assisting fibrosis
awareness month.
So we've been posting and she happened
to be in the hospital the last 10 days.
She's home right now.
Recovering.
Um,
Chelsea pneumonia.
Do an article on a cystic fibrosis
treatment.
And what was that?
It was a while ago.
I don't know,
but my wife and I are,
I did it involve CBDS?
I don't remember because I read a send
me things and we're investigating some
stuff on that level right now because
there are a lot of good things going
along with this because it's one of
them.
It's one of the best anti inflammatories
there are with no side effects and all
kinds of stuff.
We're not using it all my daughter yet,
but we're investigating like what kind
of uses there are you,
I forget.
I might have to go back through my
emails or whatnot and so I remember you
did send me something.
I don't remember if it was cbds or stem
cells or some shit,
but I just saw lapsed and now there are
a lot of levels they're working on,
on the stem cell level there.
There's a lot of things going on where
it's like if they can create correct
things on a cellular level,
at some point it's going to be,
yeah,
there's never going to be a cure.
It's a genetic disease,
so you can't say cure in that sense.
You know what I mean?
Like the way it works is my w two p the
two people that are,
that fathered a child have to each have
the gene.
All right.
So me and my wife are known as what,
what are known as carriers,
which we never knew cause we've searched
our whole history after we found out.
Nobody in my family's ever,
ever had this.
Nobody in her family ever,
But we're known as what's carriers.
So when we got together and we had a
child,
there's a one in four chance that child
is going to have cystic fibrosis,
there's a two and four chance that
they're going to be a carrier.
Oh Wow.
There's a one in four chance they have
no nothing at all,
which is our other daughter Sadie.
So we kind of represent the whole
spectrum.
Yeah.
Like our family,
you know,
and Layla,
her mom,
me and Sadie.
Um,
which is another reason I go,
I'm not having six kids cause I love
being a dad,
but it's like two cystic fibrosis
children in the same household is even,
and a lot of people do it.
It's hard because they pass infections
and it's very,
as it [inaudible].
I can't even imagine how the people with
multiple,
two or three kids with cystic fibrosis
pull it off.
I hats off because I know what his
language,
just one that's kind of the,
um,
of not just t must be changing you as a
person.
Like think about like how much more
compassionate this has made you and how
much more appreciative of Hell I've had
to also accept and learn how to deal
with a lot of anger.
Yeah.
A lot of anger.
Like,
um,
uh,
I,
I consider myself a pretty spiritual
person.
Like I said,
I've explored a lot of religions.
Um,
I find religions confining,
you know,
I mean,
I believe in a greater power,
greater high,
whatever,
something bigger than us.
I kind of believe in that,
you know,
whether you want to call it God or just
are connected collective energy,
you what I mean,
whatever it might be.
Somewhere in between their lives,
something greater than us.
Um,
I felt for another reason,
the last three years is,
is um,
what's the captain's name?
And,
uh,
in forrest gump,
Captain Ed is,
or no captain,
oh,
Captain Dan,
Lieutenant Dan,
I for the last couple of years,
I'm Lieutenant Dan on the top of that
fucking sailboat.
Like,
fuck you,
that this is what you're going to do to
this little kid,
you know?
I mean,
watching my child suffer,
you know what I mean?
And there's greater,
there's huge injustices and world.
And,
and let me tell you another thing,
having to take my daughter to children's
hospitals all the time,
I see people that have it worse.
Do you know what I mean?
Angela,
do you not know?
I'm a huge fan.
I don't know him personally,
but I'm a huge fan.
He's a great dude.
But one of the things he said to me,
I'll never forget,
he was talking about the secret.
Do you remember when the secret was this
big movie,
the book traction and people are going
to manifest their own destiny and they
were going to make it happen.
And everything in your life you created
in your mind.
And he was like,
fuck you.
You're telling a young sick kid that she
made that herself.
She made that he,
she made herself have leukemia.
She made herself have cancer.
You're telling me that fuck you.
Fuck you.
And when he said that,
I was like,
wow,
I never thought about it that way.
But he's totally right.
That's exactly what it is.
Like you can't,
that's ridiculous.
You're dealing with a bunch of people
that have become successful and told you
why.
Cause I saw it happening.
What about the people that saw it happen
and it didn't happen?
This is bullshit or a far greater number
by that.
It's a part of life.
It's not the whole key to manufacturing
a life.
It's an excellent like being a positive
person,
being healthy,
having a good vision and focus.
All those things are like contributing
factors.
But kids that are sick or the monkey
wrench in any idea that we've created
our own reality,
I don't buy,
you can't make a baby responsible for
cancer.
That's crazy.
You also can't make a god responsible
for like,
uh,
God has a plan.
You know,
sometimes there's not a fucking plan.
Sometimes there's a glitch in the
goddamn matrix and you just gotta deal
with it.
You know,
you got to handle it.
And the more important thing for me,
that second most important thing in my
life other than keeping layla is
healthiest possible,
is making sure she knows that you know,
she can still achieve and all she can.
She's at an age now where like she
kinda,
and I,
you know,
I'm not trying to have her hate me in 10
years if she ever hears this,
like we're giving up her business,
but like she's in a stage right now
where she's very resentful of Xi ix.
She expresses it well,
she'll say,
I hate this.
I hate that I have this.
I just want to be normal.
I just want to have a normal life.
And it fucking rips your heart out man.
But you can't,
you have to say,
hey,
you are normal.
This is your life.
Your life is normal.
It's like Carla,
I'm a big Carlene guy.
You know what?
I know you're studied student of it,
but it's like he had his routine where
it's like about being home made or all
natural.
He's like,
everything's fucking all natural,
right?
Ain't no matter what you do with it.
It's all fucking natural.
And that's Kinda how I tried to approach
it.
Whether it's like you are normal,
this is your normal life.
You know,
you're not in any better or worse or you
know what I mean?
You have to,
there's,
there's fights.
People fight that you don't even see
Layla.
You know what I mean?
That you don't understand.
Yours is obvious.
Yours is here,
right here in front of you to fight.
Some people are going to fight demons.
They'll never meet.
Yeah.
This is a phrase on that.
Uh,
what is it?
Comparison is the enemy of happiness.
Thank you.
I'm fucking going to use that Joe.
That's a,
I'm going to look it up and I'm going to
find out.
Find out whose quote that was.
Comparison is the enemy of happiness.
I really liked that.
That's a,
that's a very useful,
the inspiration sentence.
You should get inspiration from other
people,
but comparison is not really healthy.
Who was it as Theodore Roosevelt said,
comparison is the thief of joy.
Oh,
there you go.
Perfect.
That's so somebody probably me.
I probably fucked it up,
but that's even better.
God Damn Theodore Roosevelt.
You've had mother fucker.
He was a bad ass motherfucker.
Motherfucker writing without charging up
the hill and San Juan and all that shit,
man.
Right?
Comparisons.
Theodore.
The other one was,
well,
this is the guy that made the,
he,
he set aside,
um,
the national parks system.
He set aside like Theodore Roosevelt was
the reason why we have the grandkids,
which our current guys trying to
dismantle,
not the Grand Canyon.
I know.
Cam was happy about that shit.
No,
everybody's upset about it.
It's,
um,
well,
shout out to duke.
He's in Alberta Right now.
I know.
I see him giving you a hard time.
I Cam and you,
he's so nice.
He's a nice guy.
Nice.
And people threatened him.
He just put,
Hey,
look,
this guy's threatened me.
We what?
I threatened you.
I went and threaten you and kill you.
Well,
the whole,
but I wouldn't eat you.
That's why I won't kill you.
It's a lot of people in other countries,
man.
A lot of people that get mad about is
hunting pictures.
They're from some other country.
They're all,
a lot of them are from South America,
like a Yam.
You're going to be,
oh God.
When the electricity all goes out,
they're going to become an ia man.
They're going to be coming to you.
There'll be happy as fuck,
and I need a recommendation on the
beginner bow.
I'll,
I can hook you up.
Oh,
there we go.
We've got Joseph.
Oh Man.
Now Dude,
I'll get a hoyt to send you one.
You really want to learn.
Yeah,
that'd be the Shit I do.
All right,
well next time I'm hanging out with John
Dudley,
I'll have him come and coach you and
we'll make a little video.
Let me know.
Maybe I can attend me.
I can jump in.
I want him to coach you and teach you
how to shoot.
That's amazing.
That would be perfect.
We'll do it.
We'll make that happen.
Yeah,
so that's three years kind of a lot.
Condensed Reader's digest version is I,
I mostly wasn't in prepared to be here
and hang out and have fun.
I would have been like the,
I would have been the like episode that
everybody's like,
oh,
you gotta hear this heart wrenching
fucking,
oh my God.
Well,
it's heart wrenching now man.
But I'm glad she's doing better now,
but it's heart wrenching.
But,
but um,
I can stay in here like a man and be
like,
look,
here's,
I've been through it.
You know,
you didn't want to see me.
And it's like you didn't,
it's like you don't want to see me
cowering in the foxhole now the battle's
over.
It's like,
yeah,
I cowered in the Fox hole for a little
while,
but then we got out and we won the
battle or you know what I mean?
That's,
that's where I want it to be before I
came and I didn't have any,
and I know I didn't need anything to
promote,
but all of a sudden it's like I did this
free project and I was like,
I really just put it out in my fans have
found it,
but the response has been so good behind
it.
It's like,
I want to get this out there a little
further.
So it gave me an excuse to be like,
I think it's time for me to be on the
podcast yet and if you want to buy a CD,
they still have no we don't.
You don't.
You could maybe at our shows.
All right.
Cause if we bring them there and we've
charged basically what they cost us to
make them and ship them wherever we got
to take them and try reading that shit.
Yeah,
you don't.
You can't read it.
That's the luck.
It's fucking gangster calligraphy.
Shout out,
shout out to big sleep whenever he's one
of the finest out to big sleeps.
You win.
Yeah.
There you go.
Shout out to big sleeves for the
calligraphy.
That's gangster stuff.
Read it.
You weren't built to read it.
That's all it means.
I get it.
Now that you've explained it,
I can read it and it's just a picture
like old school,
old English calligraphy and then mixed
with gangster letters.
Yeah.
And you can see I struggle with the R
and because it comes back up like it
comes down and then it bang,
Bang.
That's his artistic.
That's art man.
I understand.
Let me,
let me explain his mind.
Made up a letter,
let me know and seems to me like a made
up letter.
That's some Gaelic Shit.
Old School data end is actually pretty
old school.
English,
old English.
Do you know what that is?
Jamie does.
Ellery can end to you at the end.
It looks cool.
That looks like an end.
You.
Where do you see the end?
The end here.
Wait a minute.
That's not the Ar,
but where's the fucking are?
Oh my God.
This is ridiculous.
That's the are that is to add.
Oh,
okay.
All right.
Let's see.
Here is the art without the arm down.
Listen to it all.
It's beautiful.
Don't get me wrong.
First of all,
if you can't read it,
that's why it's art.
All right.
Oh,
okay.
And it's gangster shit.
Every gangster,
if you go to Pico Union,
those guys will read that shit like it
ain't,
it's going to be,
oh yeah,
that's his war porn.
Oh,
that's fun.
Hilarious.
But the point is,
all right,
I was struggling to make my next singer
songwriter ish hip hop kind of.
I was kind of revisiting the Whitey Ford
formula a little bit and expanding on
it,
but I got kind of stuck halfway through
because I was just,
after all of this stuff that I went
through,
I thought it would be smart to judge.
I kind of,
another thing about cystic fibrosis,
it's really isolating because you get
really protective of your child and
other people who were sick.
I mean,
I remember at first I used to come and
be like,
everybody's going to be all right at the
studio,
right?
Nobody's sick.
I mean,
you know,
I trust you now.
I know.
It's like if you were sick,
you'd tell me.
Um,
but you still,
I understand what you live that life and
you get tired of asking your friends
every five seconds.
And so the invitations to hang out
become a little less,
it's not an intentional thing.
It's this slow kind of isolation of
yourself.
My friends didn't do it to me.
I did it to myself.
And I'm coming out of that now.
Like I'm hanging out with a lot of my
old friends and seeing things,
which is great.
But,
so like I was stuck in a studio,
it was just me and like an engineer kid
who,
I had a guy that worked for me for many
years who moved up north and then I,
I had this new guy who's good at his
job,
but it was like I w I there was no,
but you're Kinda your own boss.
Right?
So how do you decide when you're going
to go into the studio?
How do you decide when you're going to
write just,
well,
because I don't know how you think about
life because we don't live by the
paycheck rules.
You know what I mean?
We,
so I'm thinking six months out,
I know I'm good for Pri right now.
I could sit on my ass for a year before
cash ran out,
let alone other stuff.
So,
but I'm always thinking six months.
All right.
Like if I creating something now that's
going to generate like you're writing
your next stuff for whatever your next
special is going to be,
you know,
what do you get at one of those two of
those a year?
Like a solid hour?
I mean,
am I,
when I boil it down after two years,
it's like a real good hour and 10
minutes.
I'm sorry.
So that's what I'm saying.
So you're thinking on kind of that time
level.
You're like,
I'm working this out to get to this
point.
That's what my schedule is.
Now.
You know,
anybody who files my career,
whether it was house of pain or everlast
psych,
I've never been this like some cats are
like clockwork with their product.
They a year,
every year,
every year and a half,
there's an album,
bang,
boom,
bride.
Me,
I've had two year intervals,
three year intervals,
four year intervals.
One know never a one year in it will
never,
I'm never that guy.
I have to be inspired.
I have to,
but I know if I'm not creating something
and sometime the show money,
which is what I live off from now,
basically we,
besides the mailbox stuff,
um,
gets smaller as long.
As long as you're,
if you can always just make,
you don't even have to have a hit at my
stage of career.
You know what I mean?
I don't need hits.
I just need new material where it's like
I got something to promote that gives a
promoter.
You and I do a lot of work in Europe.
I do more work in Europe than I do here.
Yeah.
Way More.
I'm about to wait six weeks in Europe.
Wow.
I got,
I leave literally day after tomorrow.
Um,
whew.
That's a lot for us.
I go to Napa,
actually,
I got a festival in Napa and then I
could come home for a day and then I go
to Europe for six weeks.
Nap is a trump and I made,
if I do well in pockets in the United
States,
and there's a lot of places like the
south,
I think I would do great,
but I've never gone as like,
promoters don't call.
I don't know what it is.
I don't chase it.
Here's the,
you know what?
I'm,
I hope I'm not all over this.
I've never chased this.
I've never ran it down.
I've,
I'm where I am because I just looked at
the signs on the road and said,
oh,
go that way.
And I go there.
I'm not the guy who thinks I'm the worst
social media.
I got 40,000 fucking instagram
followers.
You know,
I've sold millions and millions of
records.
I don't,
I don't try.
I don't want it.
I don't know what it is.
I I get extreme amounts of joy.
I think we talked about this on the
first podcast.
I already did that.
My music is more famous than my face
like that.
I think it,
cause I did say like,
I like to go to Ralph's and get it to
all of bar and just fucking get olives
and nobody knows who the fuck I am and
jump around.
It's actually playing in the supermarket
or something.
You know,
it's fucking hilarious to me that Steve
Miller was like one of the greatest rock
stars of all time because nobody knows
what the fuck he looks like.
Take the money and run diseases.
So I'm happy with Joe.
Bobby sue.
Fuck is that guy look like cause I'm a
smoker.
It was that much older boy and I'm a
midnight toker.
Yeah,
the joker.
Um,
jungle love.
I was another great jam.
Damn.
He had some great jams.
So I'm sitting in the studio by myself,
stuck.
Um,
uh,
a friend of mine asked me to do a
feature on his rap record,
which I really wasn't,
you know,
I mean,
it wasn't,
I don't do a lot of that anymore.
How long had it been since you had done
it?
Well,
I made the first La Coka Nostra album.
I was,
it was,
I was part of the whole album.
That was a few years back.
That was oh eight.
Oh wait,
oh wait.
And I've done it.
A wrap here are wrapped there for
friends for a long time to go between
that and war porn.
You new project war porn.
When did you guys start that?
What happened?
I'm,
I'm getting to it is,
is this cat asked me,
uh,
to Alim shout them out.
Just do Raju.
Um,
plenty of shops on this show,
Jamie.
Like,
like the fight or from a street fighter,
you know what I mean?
Right.
He has an album out.
Um,
and I did a song on there and it came
out of May.
That was so like in love with what I did
like after all these years,
like wow,
I busted a fucking really dope rhyme on
that thing that him and I was like,
Yo,
we should do a little mix tape thing
just to help promote this,
whatever,
whatever.
Something happened.
He just couldn't be involved.
And then I immediately thought of my
friend and,
and,
and partner now,
uh,
this guy's sick jacken from a group
called psycho Rome Latin,
excellent names,
sick Jagat and cycle where he was going
to be,
he's going to come next time he,
I called him today and I was like,
Yo,
I totally space if you want to come do
this.
Very is the ball guy right there.
Uh,
and then divine did all the beats and he
rhymes on the project.
But the way it came back,
it was like when Dude couldn't do a
divine already,
he was making the beads.
I Call Sick Jack.
I was like,
Yo,
I got this project.
He came,
heard all the beats and we literally
made this record in like a week and um,
a divine styler,
a short background.
I would not be in this business.
I would not be making music if it wasn't
for that man.
Um,
he's the first guy that ever told me I
could rap.
I used to want to be a graffiti artist.
He was an amazing graffiti arts and I
was just following him around is like a
16 year old trying to learn like styles
and shit.
And I would bus wraps because they were
making music to like make fun of Shit
like your mom or this or that.
And they would always be like,
Yo,
you can rap.
You should like make a tape when you
just was adr.
Yeah.
Does it get you high?
No,
not really.
I mean not,
not in the sense that,
I mean maybe a collect after a while you
might feel a little different,
but like you were mass and shit.
I'll do they wear a mask.
Well now they were rude ones.
We used to just tie Bandanas and Oh,
okay.
And cause I would imagine if you're
standing there like some of those I
passed.
If you were like in a room like this and
tried to paint that whole wall
ventilation,
you'd probably would.
But this is mostly outdoor on the wall,
on the bus on in La,
the the,
the scene was like down.
We had a yard.
Every crew,
you'd have a yard somewhere,
like in an industrial area between
buildings where there's like a brick
wall in two buildings and you'd just
bombed it would be called your yard.
You know what I mean?
This cruise yard or that crew yard,
the other crews,
yards and you'd like bomb over there
pieces.
That's not good.
Right.
It's like it's,
it's a game almost.
Except this little snake.
Yes.
If they caught you for sure.
Kick your ass and steal your pain.
Oh No.
You Know David Show is,
you know David,
I love David Chaum.
David's got these crazy fucking videos
he's putting up on instagram now.
Three m thrown paint all over the place.
Floor fumes.
He's high on paint films.
He's going crazy.
He's like some industrial building.
Just,
I love that dude.
Taking a trailer,
like running it around like he's so far
out there,
there's no map.
No one's got a fucking map.
David Choe land.
I mean he's got a cart and he's just
pouring paint on the ground.
Savage.
He's also super smart.
He's a great dude.
This is on purpose.
This is,
there's purpose to what he does,
man.
I believe that.
No,
David,
he's a sweet,
sweet guy.
Like I really like him as a person.
I don't know if he still does it.
I did his podcast,
I think I kicked his podcast because he
heard me on yours and he was like,
comment,
please bring your guitar and you know,
he doesn't now bank something.
I take very serious pride in the fact
I'm the first guy to ever do music on
this thing.
I don't,
and I think it's honey,
honey,
the only guy,
other people that have really done
music.
Gary brought us,
Gary Clark Jr brought his guitar band.
Dude,
I love that guys the best.
He's such a nice guy too,
man.
Oh Man.
It's such a sweet music man.
I'm really a big fan of that dude.
I'm a big fan of him as a person and as
a musician and I went to see a honey
honey played in downtown La.
They had like this midnight show on a
Wednesday night and I'm Gary Clark
joined
them on stage and Gary Clark Jr and
honey honey.
God Damn.
It was good.
And I was like,
you know,
10 feet away and there was a hundred
people in the room and it was Gary Clark
Jr just Jammin with honey honey.
And it was,
he's one of the baddest motherfuckers on
the guitar ever.
He is a beautiful sound,
like he's got such a distinct,
oh,
here it is.
Jamie's got it a,
I put it on my instagram.
I think I remember this.
You hear this?
No,
it's him.
Is there a
flare or am I not seeing him or,
well the bass player is the dude in
front of us that's been,
he's just been and everything.
Mentors.
He played another guitar.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
That's like,
it's hard.
It's not a big pick up a bass.
Oh well somebody is putting down some
nice low end.
He must've had that Gary queued.
Somebody has an acute.
Isn't that it sounded good.
That's all I was making the point of.
Yeah,
man.
God Damn,
I don't have a bass player.
My keyboard player,
Brian who comes through here,
he's got the meanest fucking left hand
on the keys.
Like he plays all his keys with the
right and the base is left.
Oh Wow.
That's amazing.
We're a trio now.
Like me and my,
when I do my band stuff,
it's just me and two other got drummer
in him.
That's amazing.
And we sounded like six guys.
It's crazy.
Gary Clark has got his own sound.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Like you hear his sound like Stevie Ray
Vaughan is a perfect example of that.
Like I hear some Stevie Ray Vaughan and
I'll hear like one or two bars and I'd
go,
that's Stevie Ray Vaughan.
He's got that sound.
You know this is like a certainly
gibbons slide.
Yeah.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
The minute played on a album of mine on
a couple of songs.
I love Warren,
the ghost of Whitey Ford.
And he came in with this little crate
amp head,
which crate is not a fancy company.
It's like a cheaper,
not cheaper,
I won't call it him,
but like it wasn't like super hot.
It was like some regular fucking head
and this one pedal and live sound.
I was like,
how the fuck did you get?
And it's just something that some guys
have a magic man.
Some guys have a magic about the sound.
Me,
I play acoustic.
That's what I'm best at.
I know how to make that sound good.
There's,
I have electric guitars but I could
never get my,
I could have that same fucking guitar is
Gary Clark Jr right there and the same
equipment and set it the same way and it
probably won't sound the same.
Yeah.
So in the neighborhood,
but I'm saying there's something,
there's some people that just got to
inherit and magic about feel on an
instrument.
You know what I mean?
It's crazy amazing about someone who can
play an instrument like that is that
they're making some sound,
that it syncs up with our brains so
well.
It syncs up with our hearing so well
that it just gives you pleasure,
you know?
And by the way,
folks that's with an iphone,
can microphone and camera.
I mean that is a terrible recording
device as far as like getting good audio
quality.
So when you're there,
I really fucking good.
There's more computing power in here.
Then there was it then when they
supposedly send people to the moon,
you know what I mean?
To the moon.
Alice supposedly.
Do you think they sent people on the
moon?
You know what?
That's one of them things.
How do you know the fucking truth?
But I'll tell you one fucking thing for
sure.
The earth is not flat.
Fuck you.
See,
that's where it gets tricky,
right?
How do we know these scientists could
all be like,
Ooh,
look at the mood that's Brown,
but wouldn't be interesting if so,
what is the only one that wasn't?
And that was,
that was why everybody was trying to,
Hey,
I'm just trying to see both sides.
Just asking questions.
I'm cool with the,
Hey,
it makes her fun arguments.
But the moon landing is my favorite day
next to big full moon landings.
My favorite aspect to me,
let me say that there's a lot of things
I've seen you on TV.
Either suspect,
Hey,
I saw a movie maybe 15 years ago called
wag the dog.
That fucked everything up for me.
Like when I see the news,
I wa I see wag the dog all day long.
Those a great movie.
Yeah.
And then do you remember when the CIA,
um,
it came out to the CIA had pad a half of
million dollars to make the fucking isis
videos.
What was it?
How much?
How much was it?
Was it a half a million dollars?
$500,000 to make may?
It might've been more than that.
I am.
I like way selling it short.
Was it like $500 million?
No,
I think it was a half.
How much was it?
I think it was half a million to make
videos,
but still like to make homemade looking
very,
it was like half a million dollars.
That's a lot of money.
I think it was more than that.
540 maybe it was five 540 million.
Half a billion.
Okay,
thank you.
Yeah,
when I said 500,000 I was like,
no,
that sounds cheap.
Half a billion.
Yeah,
and so what they stop to think about how
many x men movies you can make for a
half a billion.
I mean what kind of a ship return on
your investment and ferb fake out kind
of videos.
Know what that is?
Know what that is right there.
That's two motherfuckers.
The guy who owns that from is the buddy
is somebody you know.
That's,
that's the thing I was talking about
earlier where they figure out how to get
the fucking money.
Anyways,
that's it.
That's it.
That's the kind of shit I'm talking
about.
Well that is about a clear,
as an example,
as you can get where it's 540 players
back when,
remember what it was at 20 years ago
when they came with the whole thing
where like a Pentagon was paying like
thousand dollars a hammer.
You're like your toilet seats were like
seven grand and you know,
it was like,
I'm over that $540 million is a crazy
number two.
That's like,
wait,
Whoa,
what the fuck?
Jesus fully,
we talked a lot of money man or pores
war porn.
So like I said,
divine was,
he's,
he was,
he's
my mentor.
He's like back in the day before,
it used to be if somebody,
like if you were the son of somebody
that was like your mentor,
like now it's kind of almost like they
treat it like an inch.
So if I was device,
I'm the son of divine styler in this
game.
That's how I look at it.
I learned style from him.
I learned how to rap from him.
He encouraged me to do it at first and
then I went on my own journey.
So coming back to do this project with
him was fun.
It was,
this was strictly just in my mind,
an art project like literally we're
going to give this away.
We're going to,
we're just going to make a few cds and
make some fun art to surround it and you
know it.
We'll call it a day and then it came out
amazing and I'm not selling myself
short.
That shit is fucking banging hip hop and
it's free and you can get it at war porn
industry's dot com and click on the mix
tape and download it.
It's free.
Well,
I've been enjoying the videos,
man.
It looks like he's having a video.
I'm going to play a good time to,
it's the been the most fun I've had in
forever.
It's the point of like what?
Like I said,
I was,
I was stuck in this Rut and then these
guys came into my studio and brought it
alive again and I realize it's communal.
Yeah.
What I do,
even even when I'm trying to just
express my own thought and idea,
you got it's communal.
You need some people around you that are
going to,
you need a,
I'm sure guys like Joey Diaz or this for
you.
Oh yeah.
When you have an idea for a routine or a
Jew joke,
it'd be like,
what do you think?
Should I pursue that?
There's a guy that you'll turn to and
he'll be like,
fuck yeah,
that's the move.
Or fuck no,
don't do that.
It's better when there's a lot of,
yeah,
you feed off each other,
you don't have fun and you,
you also like,
it's very important to be happy for
other people like Ge,
like seeing other people.
Kick ass should make you feel better
like and being around bad motherfucker.
Shit like this in the studio when the
three of us are,
the official name of the group is war
porn industry's war.
Porn is the first record.
Why War Porn?
What does that mean?
Because it's fucking cause.
Exactly.
What does it mean because,
exactly because everything's war porn.
Turn on your TV.
It's war point.
I'm reading this script.
I'm even more confused.
This script.
No,
it's the same thing.
We just separated it and made an ark
out.
It's too confusing.
Oh well good.
The logo is bad ass though.
I'm an old band.
She was demand.
Let's shut down his right heel goes
dope.
But that,
that is just going to reaffirm ideas of
devil worship and pornography.
He people are your monsters.
You're what's wrong.
I intend to scare you about dope and
manly and images you can get.
There's a skull where the pussy should
be.
There's thei had legs.
It's a death's head.
Moth is the overall concept and this
fishnet stockings involved with guns.
That's the spine of the wings.
Trust and neat and he's a fucking bad
ass.
Dope as fuck and guns were that.
I would consider getting that tattoo
that somewhere like I'm like,
I might have,
it might be my my back piece.
It might be,
that's a good back piece.
That's a strong back piece.
No bullshit,
but straighten out the words.
I'm just kidding.
Keep it as is.
It's your lingo.
Imagine going to the Japanese people and
go,
hey man,
your language is a fucking too weird a
English.
Can you use English?
Use Ours.
But on her.
So we got a few videos.
What you got up right now?
You got anything close to up?
Which one is this one or we got three
videos.
So one let's crank.
This one is the first one was called
world's end.
Do we want to go in chronological order
or we should if it's a piece sort of.
Here we go.
Shout out to John.
I sad marshal von [inaudible]
shot the videos.
Shout out to Grandpa from the great
beyond.
I hope you looking down,
having a good time up there.
We drove in with Jesus.
This is shot at the uh,
there's a,
there's an abandoned missile silo
apparently at the top of the Soto in the
valley.
Really?
Yeah.
Yeah,
you're fine.
Put the needle of plates and rock final
fingers.
You get the plates in far cry.
No whiskey bread scattered or fresh.
So rough.
Why?
No is saw nine or we should get on your
idol.
Six cycle homicidal but titles,
Glib spray on the random who the target
is 10 and the way he had to stay on the,
that sounded pulling away from me.
What I'm missing.
Jack is one of the most slept on
underrated MCS ever.
Mccool weaponry,
green smoke.
My remedy.
Passive aggressively choke my enemy,
my cavalry bucket list.
Religion Wall on industry from my native
fascinate with extreme big and street.
Happy Weight home.
A pleats summer time again as she check
or I'm at call,
triple hexagon one that will be on the
devil's Word is Paul or three depths,
so under water,
the dad role,
bioengineering,
stem cell counting for late with the
ball rolling
in the building.
Baby is that old man rap.
I like it.
God.
Hamill Marsalis sonic rock for Berlin
almost on cotton metal.
Matte glass surfaces with the birds,
with straws for the burner.
His boss for the job cost both in the
urban grip torn from the flame of the
Chin to you.
Now is this profile of the new world is
broken.
Meet Reem Americana boss is war porn the
from the ass of the bottom of why this
toby in the Fallopian Tube Maya for
Zirconia,
nickelodeon made the whole porn thing
and that could go draw a blown off the
hinges to him.
Brings up remotely from the podium
priests,
several priests and felt the holy moly.
Not In love with the hell.
The full,
the lowliest fabricated modified while
I'm sitting,
come with me to the,
to the mayor.
We've had a blast,
man.
We're going to make many more records
in the rap game now dog for a minute.
It's cool to hear and you wrap again for
a site is fun.
I really enjoyed your transition until
like more acoustic stuff.
I'm still doing that too,
but yeah,
this is,
this is fun.
Like this is unadulterated for me.
Like you were talking about you need
cats to push.
You are golden.
The studio is like when Sig Jack comes
off the mic from saint averse,
he wants me to look at him and be like,
fuck you gotta go,
Oh fuck dude.
Your lyrics or no lyrics so sharp it,
both of those dudes that are,
that are on either side of me in this
are retarded when it man you,
if you really sit back and analyze
divine styler like speaks in tongues,
man,
I don't know.
That dude's on some super scientific and
sick Jack is on some street level hood
shit.
But the way he puts it together is so
crazy.
It's almost like we a representation of
like almost like physical,
like a mental and spiritual.
Like mine is more mental like you guys
like see no evil,
hear no malls cobbled together and when
we get together the shoot,
all three of us will tell you it's,
it's the energy that we create with each
other.
Yeah.
We don't find it anywhere else.
We,
we've,
we're,
we're addicted to this right now.
That's why I'm telling you it's going to
be way more.
We're really working on the next one.
So I think that can't be overlooked man.
Because I think that there's a,
you get a lot of the people that you're
around all the time and I think you're a
different person when you're around
different people.
Absolutely.
Sure.
I'm sure you experienced that,
right?
Absolutely.
And I think that being around a bunch of
bad motherfuckers on a regular basis,
like you are in war porn,
like everything is probably like
everybody sharpened.
Everybody's not,
everybody is also aware of the full body
of work.
All real hip hop
fans.
So you aware of like nozzles,
Best Shit and Jay z's best shit in the
bar gets so high and so sharp,
the edge gets sharp.
So like that riff right there,
that's,
that's like one of my all time favorites
that I've heard in the last couple of
years.
Right.
That's great.
You should feel like,
like in,
in my opinion,
you know,
and I come from a certain era,
I'll give that to people.
You know,
there's a new era of kids and I don't
shit on them or hate them.
They have this whole thing hating on
these kids call it mumble rap and I
don't,
I don't really got a problem with it.
You know what I mean?
My only problem was is like,
Hey,
there are certain cats that are kind of
disrespecting the past and it's like,
hey,
be you,
be new,
be different.
That's cool.
Be What you want to be,
but don't fucking shit on cats.
Like biggie.
And I'm not even gonna call out names
and all was right,
but anybody who's listening to me and is
really hip to the game knows there's
these youngsters that are kind of almost
trying to,
they're almost trying to make noise by
disrespecting and it's like,
listen,
the path that was walked before you is
the only reason you could fucking wear
that fucking cheesy fucking shit
jewelry.
You get and fucking act so ignorant.
You know what I mean?
And go to the met ball and gallon on is
when you ain't nobody,
and next year you're not going to be
anybody at the met,
the met gala.
You know what I mean?
You're just,
this year's fucking like not a novelty.
I don't know.
Your Business does the music game in
general,
the older dudes had been around.
There's a lot of youngsters that are
like,
don't know the history and I don't say
you need to know biggie's every album,
but don't fucking come on shit.
You can't show,
come on shit on POC,
but it come out and act like they didn't
exist or you don't know anything about
them.
That's unfortunate.
And when they're few and far between,
but they've made big headlines and
that's why this,
there seems to be this disrespectful
hate for the young,
right.
I don't got that because listen,
I always said like I just don't ever
want to sound like that old fucking
bitter dude.
I'll tell you I don't like that.
I'm not a fan of that song or that guy,
but get go do what you,
I might be old,
maybe I don't get what you're doing.
You know what I mean?
As I've gotten older I give less of a
fuck about what other people enjoy and
when I was younger I had to,
for some reason I felt like I had to
argue with I enjoy versus what you enjoy
and that doesn't make any sense to me
anymore.
It's like we're all so fucking
different.
The idea like you meet people and
personalities vary so much.
They,
in other words,
I'm going to like to see that shit
crazy.
Qualify
what I was just talking about actually,
cause really what I was talking about
wasn't young people.
If you want to be,
if I want to be perfectly clear,
what I was talking about was people my
age that I hear throwing a lot of hate
and a lot of just like just like,
oh that ain't rap or that ain't hip hop
rain.
Maybe not to you,
but you really just sound old and
bitter.
You know what I mean?
Let them kids get there.
I made the record I wanted to make,
I didn't try to make a record that
designer or future or any of these cats
that are doing it now would make cause
that would look stupid.
I would look like a thirsty idiot.
Right.
Cause that's not what I do.
That is what they to to sort shit on.
It is shitting on them and I don't know
them.
I don't know anything.
And honestly I've heard future and I've
heard designer records and they're not
the worst things I've ever heard.
I'm just not a fan.
I've just don't,
that's not my thing.
It's not garbage.
And I don't like when I hear people just
calling shit out for garbage that isn't
garbage.
If it's garbage,
called it garbage,
like Mr Brainwash or something like
that,
that's garbage.
You know what I mean?
You don't even know who I'm talking to.
You and I talked,
I don't know any of these people,
but I do know what you're talking about.
You know?
Here's what beautifying crochet that
was,
that was,
that wasn't even cool,
but it's not at all.
I don't,
I will tell you,
I don't know what the fuck's going on
the rap world,
but what I do now,
not to even talking about rap,
he knows,
you know?
Tell me what you're talking about.
It's an artist.
You just answer like fake fucking street
artists like stole everything he ever
did was anybody.
You see the banks,
the banks,
he won't be the guy that fucking like
faked it till he made it like this.
That's who I'm talking about.
Okay.
He's garbage dude.
Like that's garbage.
That's garbage.
You got to be right to be offended.
Is there somebody,
you know what for you,
it's the equivalent of like Carlos
Mitzia.
Yes.
Mr Brainwash.
Okay.
Exact.
That's a perfectly legitimate,
yeah.
Correlation.
Is that the right word?
Yeah.
Thank you.
I said coalition.
I know what you're saying.
I know,
I'm talking,
well,
how many two glasses deep into whiskey.
Jack Daniels.
Single Barrel Rye,
the real shit.
You owe me a case now.
Jack Daniels,
Lynchburg,
Tennessee,
send that shit to the crib.
All right.
This is where we got this man.
Y'All can't drink it there.
I see the commercial.
Y'All can't drink it.
They're sending an extra case this way
to the Joe Rogan experience.
Isn't it amazing that we were like
interested in stuff that like sits in
barrels that have been fire brewed.
Like they,
they take fire,
they burn the inside of the barrels.
Right?
Isn't that like part of the process of
making this stuff?
A lot of the new shit too is the darker
versions is like,
some people will use the,
actually get the,
the whiskey that's soaked into the wood
and somehow get that out.
And that's where you get these dark
versions of like,
um,
what Jameson caskmates and uh,
other stuff like that.
And then there's a new,
there's a new movement or I don't know
how new it is.
I'm talking out of my ass a little bit
because I've had a few,
but the where they like by old aol like
Guinness or like beer once and then put
whiskey and no reason like yeah,
there's like con like where they kind of
cross chases.
They're crazy.
These kids today.
I just love the fact that that's how you
make this.
Like I'm not,
I'm not selling this,
but like when you talk about like,
like a whiskey taste.
I'm a James Guy but this is nice.
This is nice.
Look,
it's an acquired experience.
Sick Jack Gentleman,
Jack Guy.
He loves the gentleman Jack.
So I'm,
I'm,
I'm hit Koolaid.
Tastes good.
This is an exotic mouth experience.
Okay.
It's like a,
there's something going on.
Have you gone to a tasting like a scotch
tasting or something like that?
Because I'm a grown man who has other
things to do.
Go to Scott stays take to fuck out here.
It all tastes like fucking Turpentine.
Like some of it tastes.
Okay.
Ms. Dot.
Koolaid right.
It's not,
gatorade are only like a couple.
There's a lot of them I don't like,
I don't like to admit it but I like our
cold coke one.
I no one of those coke zero that what it
is.
I call it coke one.
I know it's but sometimes that
is what I want.
That tastes good.
If that could get you drunk.
Oh here's a funny story.
So my wife gives me a present the other
day and it's like this key chain with
this elongated like metal tube looking
thing on it and I open it up and it's
just empty and she's like,
ah.
I just thought,
you know,
if you smoked a joint you could put it
in there and it wouldn't stink up your
car.
And it was a smart idea.
Trust me.
But I'm looking at it and I'm looking at
it and I'm like,
Babe,
um,
I think this is a coke file actually.
I think that's really the intention for
this.
She was like,
you know,
it's funny cause there were smaller ones
too.
I thought that's really small.
I wonder what that could be for now.
It totally makes sense.
So I got this bullet looking thing.
I put joints in it,
but it's like it's a coke vile dude.
You imagine what would have happened if
they made coke legal like a long time
ago?
Like how am I,
how much would,
how much would culture change of coke
was like beer
just,
I mean he could drink yourself to death.
We all know someone who's drank
themselves to death.
I think our obesity problem would
probably be John to be the weight I
wanted to be,
you know,
I might be closer to the weight.
I really truly want to be,
you know,
I have a theory and my theory is that
much like how we,
you take sugar out of things and then
just have like processed sugar and you
eat.
It's terrible for your body because it's
not as numb.
All the natural fibers,
it's very dangerous.
Like you,
like you get fat.
It's not dangerous.
I'm not saying it's like nuclear power,
but my theory is that I bet those coca
leaves are exactly the same way.
I bet if you just chew those coca leaves
like those people do up in the
mountains,
I think it's great for you.
I think it's just like eating fruit is
really good for you right now.
Like if you have a bowl of fresh
blueberries,
that's not just because it had some
sugar in it that's really good for you.
Rich and antioxidants,
rich in vitamins,
strawberries.
Delicious.
Good for you.
Not Bad for you,
good for you.
But like spoons or sugar in arguably not
Right?
I mean not the worst though.
What you're talking about right there is
something process versus something
that's natural.
Yeah,
it's exactly the same thing.
You know what?
I would actually,
if I with all my heart issues,
I got a heart valve.
If you sat two plates on and have played
a coke and you said you had to do one of
these and here's some cocoa leaves,
I'd be like Oh fuck,
I'll chew those.
Cocoa leaves all one and I want to
experience that man.
I want to know what that's like because
they,
things I'm writing about are like pets
that work in those,
cause that's mountainous area.
They liked chewing them all day and work
and do shit.
It's just like coffee to them in a weird
way,
you know?
Maybe a little,
you know,
I don't think it's stronger than coffee
man.
I don't think it is.
I think from everybody that describes
the describe it as
like just a mild stimulant and it makes
you feel good and it also has like,
what did they call flavell chewing on
it.
It's getting yourself so Lima is
dissolving.
You're processing it through a digestive
system instead of just banging it
straight to your brain in a power of
powder form.
You know what I mean?
I think it's Prob,
I mean obviously I'm speaking way out of
line here.
I don't know anything about [inaudible].
Does it take to make a line?
That's another thing you don't know.
It might be 400 coca leaves.
Like how many strawberries does it take
to make a good tablespoon of sugar?
Exactly.
That's a good,
that's a good analogy.
Interesting.
There's whiskeys.
Really Nice.
So feeling good.
God Damn this California marijuana is
also very effective.
Yeah.
Can't complain.
But we sparked up again.
There's,
there's a whole thing right there of,
of this whole new ae.
I've smoked my share fair share of some
dabs and whatnot here,
but like now we're talking about let's,
if we're going to keep it 100% honest,
we've always kind of sat around and
smoked joints and be like,
hey,
we don't really do drugs.
You know what Dabs of you do dabs.
You do drugs.
That's a drug that's weed being
processed into an actual work,
potent,
more compact form form to smoke.
It's drugs.
It's the math of weed dabs,
like phrase tattoos.
They're like,
you went too far fucker,
which is slow down.
Settle down.
Okay.
Don't,
don't turn your nose.
Nose had my fair share of DABS and I
would partake under the right
circumstances.
Boom Bap.
I'll have a little dab,
but what I'm saying is I,
it's too much good movie here.
I'm okay.
I'm fine.
Pens though.
You're smoking pens though as dabs.
I actually don't smoke.
Uh,
too many different ones,
but I have some that organic,
it's still adapt.
No,
it's an oil.
It's oil.
Same fucking team.
Same as her smoking wax.
And he has seen different people who
were interested in soldering irons and
fucking verily I'm more into,
I'm not personally a little bit more
into what they call the solventless like
ice hash and shit like that.
Like a little bit different.
I mean,
Bho scares me a little bit.
Sometimes I'll just like a thing as a
trigger that hits me when someone says
you want to do dabs?
Like oh no,
no,
no.
Cause you're one of those people that
does dabs.
Like I'm not,
I'm not doing no,
no,
no.
You're the dude who calls in sick to the
country club because you're too fucking
high to drive,
right?
No,
no.
We're not doing dabs together man.
Get your shit together.
You don't have to get that high.
Come by the studio there Joe.
Cause you're doing the DAB.
Now if they come by my studio,
it's like I'm going make you do at least
glasses of wine or do you do want to
drink glasses of whiskey where you can
drink glasses of wine and enjoy it?
If you drink glasses of whiskey,
you'll be fucking dead.
Okay.
That's like dabs.
You went too far into the dark land son.
You met the shy,
you know how much weed you smoked,
the orks you're,
you're wrong about that.
Some people,
you're right about it.
You're right about it.
Like the average Joe cat like that
doesn't know much.
What if you know how much we use smoke?
I don't get that fucked up from a dad
because you know I have smoked a lot of
weed for 20 fucking years.
You know what I mean?
But what it will do if you smoke,
what I don't want to do about that shit
from what I understand is why I don't do
a ton of it is because it'll,
you'll stop getting high from actual
weed if you do too much of that be,
that'd be good.
If that's what the best way to be is get
high.
So often that you can be high and not
even feel like your high,
like maybe that's the best place to be.
Hi though.
I want to know that I'm Ha.
No,
no.
It's like letting go.
I don't want to like get,
well now you're talking about being a
junkie.
You're talking about and not know you're
high,
but be high.
That's called getting well,
you're sick plant man.
I smoke taxes,
man.
There's no point to me smoking if I'm
not getting a buzz.
What I'm saying man,
I'm,
what I'm saying is achieve a perpetual
vibration of uh,
let's call called elevation.
Let's could not call it being high to
achieve a perpetual state where it's so
common and normal that you don't even
feel like you're high.
How do we live?
Isn't that how we live?
Pretty close.
Pretty far.
I take days off though.
Do you take days?
Absolutely.
Honestly more than I like since in the
last seven years,
way more than it used to because of my
kids.
I want to give away before my kids,
I was perpetually high.
I was high from the morning.
I woke up to the moment I went to sleep
and I don't even look at that as a bad
thing or like I like smoked weed.
Yeah,
I was perpetually high.
I know a lot of people that are very
productive and very smart who also do
that now and they enjoy it more.
The wife and I,
at the end of a long day,
we'll go out in the backyard and because
we don't smoke anywhere near the kids
cause of cystic fibrosis and other,
but like we will just like that.
And you know what?
Fuck anyone who doesn't like it,
Ma,
I know that are alcoholics and shit.
You know what I mean?
It's illegal now.
He's decompressed from a day of doing
fucking nebulizer treatments and fucking
give a shit.
Yo.
It works for us and it's cool.
But if I wasn't getting as in smoking or
to get even,
I wouldn't even do it anymore.
Like if I didn't get a buzz,
you know what I mean?
It's a happy thing.
I'm not saying get even,
I'm saying state elevators,
but no,
you're elevated the entire time.
No,
just like you know you're breathing in
oxygen,
but do you pay attention to it on a
regular basis?
Well then just like knowing I liked it,
I liked the conscious actual like,
oh,
I'm in a relieve state of pain right
now.
Listen,
you're right.
I'm just,
I'm a essentially army cookies man.
I'm not looking for cookies or anything,
but maybe it's because I live in a
slightly elevated level of stress than
the average person.
By appreciate it.
Know the difference.
I want to feel that cushion.
It's like the pillow on the bed for me.
I want to feel the pillow.
I don't want to just accept it's there.
I don't want to go Buddhists like that
and washing the dishes just to wash
dishes.
Right?
I want to get
high to get the fuck Outta here for
fucking five minutes.
You know what?
I find that it's one of the most
beneficial things about being high as
it.
I've only thinking about a few things,
but I'm thinking about them very
intensely,
simply and very intently.
Instead of thinking about a whole host
of things peripherally where it's almost
like there's too much data coming in
from all these other things that I don't
really care about or need.
Look,
you care about all sorts of things in
your life that you're not going to deal
with right now and take to harbor.
Even a chunk of that in your
consciousness is it robs the rest of
your resources for thinking about other
things.
And that's one of the most apparent
things about pot to me because like when
I,
here's a perfect example,
when I smoked pot and then I play pool,
I am 20% better,
like a legitimate 20% better.
And I really think that it's because I'm
not thinking about,
oh I gotta do this and then I got to
call that guy and then this guy,
I got to respond as to his text.
I got to respond to that person's email.
When I get high,
I just see balls,
I see balls and green cloth.
And either one step further is you're
also not even thinking about it.
I got to beat this fucking guy you're
thinking about and I want to make sure
Shannon douchebag.
No,
no,
but you want to make the shot.
It's more about the shot though.
Like I want to make it a shot.
I want to fucking win this game cause I
want to make the shot.
I want to do you see the angle?
There's a zen to it for sure.
There's a thing that happens with pool
that happens the same way in archery and
then in archery,
like when you hit a target there's an,
it's so foolish.
Like of course it's just a a hay bale
with a target on it with a little paper
target that has a yellow center and you
hit the yellow center.
Whoop de do nothing changed in the
world.
I understand that like rationally as my
Dick was say hard.
If I do that though,
I'd be like,
oh,
but the thing about doing that is that I
don't know why,
but when you do something correctly,
when it all flows in harmony,
just like with pool,
it's the same thing when you have a long
shot and it goes in.
If you've ever been at a bar,
when you watch people play pool and some
dude makes or some woman makes the
craziest shot ever for the win and
everybody goes crazy.
Oh Shit.
Because we know how hard it is to do and
there's something poetic and beautiful
about watching it happen.
It's the that you just described.
Why Gulf makes any sense at all?
I live on a golf course basically.
I like to hit the balls and fucking I
suck.
But what keeps you coming back is you'll
play that 18 whole day and one time.
Do you feel you'll hit the shot that you
meant to hit the way you meant to hit it
and it went where you're meant to go and
you're like I can do that again.
I know I can too.
I don't play Golf Jason.
It's like crack.
You're chasing that first fucking high
forever.
I'm not disrespecting anybody who plays
golf cause I know I would get addicted
but I don't play golf because I know I'd
get it.
Because you would,
your whole personal it would cause you'd
hit that one shot the first day and
you'd be like,
Oh shit,
same reason I don't coke.
Yeah.
It's the same reason I've never done
coke.
The exact same reason.
My friend in high school,
Jimmy Lawless,
good buddy of mine to this day when we
were back in high school,
we went to a party and uh,
people were doing coke and he goes,
Joe,
don't do it.
You'd fucking love it.
It's like Dewey Cox for movie was like,
you don't want this.
I trust your buddy.
I go,
I'm fucking done here.
I'm done with this.
And I've told him,
I've said this before,
but this is a real thing that happened
where it was on two lane road and we
were driving side this car that had the
dome light on.
And I looked over and there was this
chick and I'll never forget her arms.
She had these big arms like shit,
like almost like,
like,
like she had a sleeveless shirt with
like thick arms.
Like it was kind of girl that would
punch him in the face.
Okay.
And she was doing coke in the back seat
and she looked over at me with the Dome
light on and she just goes,
fuck you.
She just says it to me like I'm just
looking at her.
I'm just looking at her.
You're doing coke,
you're on the,
you're on a two lane road.
There's the only two cars in the road.
I'm watching you do coke.
I'm seven feet away from you doing coke
and you're saying fuck you.
Like whoa,
fuck coke.
That's what I was thinking.
Yeah.
We used to call it a,
I had a few experiences with coke in my
life,
but here,
here's the breakdown of cocaine and why
it's evil.
We used to call it amongst a few people
that I actually trusted enough to
partake of it in my life.
We called it the sneaky pouch.
Sneaky.
Because what would happen is like you
get some coke and it'd be like in a
fold,
you know,
like a paper fold.
Everybody would put in for some coke and
every,
you'd go somewhere and every once in a
while,
you know,
be,
Hey,
let me get past some,
go to the bathroom real quick and
whatever.
Right,
right.
When you went to that bathroom,
the nature of coke,
you would take a little piece of that
off of yourself and put it in your own
little dollar bill.
Yes,
you're sneaky Boucher.
Sneaky,
sneaky pouch.
But what it says about,
and everybody did it,
the whole crew,
like nobody made cop to it and nobody
fucking,
it got analogy.
But it's like we all know we took a
little piece for ourself.
You know what I mean?
Off of the cook file and whatever,
whatever sneaky pouch.
It's,
it's,
it's a deceitful,
are you writing this?
Uh,
so it's like kind of just describes the
nature of what that what mind state that
puts you in.
It's like,
well fuck everybody else.
If this goes,
if everybody's sniffs,
who's sniffing,
you know,
it's just like,
that's what that drug creates.
And that's why,
you know,
the,
I think three times in my life I've done
it
well.
Any drug that radically changes your
brain chemistry,
whether it's whiskey or whether it's
coke or eat,
you know,
honestly even pot,
especially pertaining to edibles,
we should watch it very carefully.
What happens when people take it,
you know?
And I think that's one of the things
that I've been guilty of and I know a
lot of other people have been guilty of
it too,
just to totally come clean.
I defend pot so much that I never look
at the potential negative consequences
of people doing pot if they're too young
because I didn't do it when I was down.
I mean did a few times,
maybe like a handful of times before was
30 and then when I was 30 I met Eddie
Bravo.
We started getting blazed all the time
and it just changed the entire west.
Second Pot.
I smoked pot was 14 I'd,
well I definitely smoked it younger than
that.
I smoked when I was eight.
My stepdad gave me someone I was eight
just to a puff cause I was curious.
I was like,
what,
what and what happens when you do it?
He goes,
do you want to try it?
I said,
how much should I breathe in?
He goes on breathing in a lot,
just breathing a little bit.
This is obviously like sketchy memory.
I did it once when I was eight and then
the next time I did it I was probably
like 14 and then I did it probably maybe
again when I was sending him
teen when we cut school and some of the
kids,
a couple of kids that were the cool guys
that I kind of took a liking to me and I
was like,
cool,
like coke is like me.
I'm going to go hang out with these
dudes.
They smoke weed and I remembered I hit
it and very,
and they were telling me like,
have you ever smoked weed or no,
I never spoke with her.
I'm,
nothing might happen to you the first
time.
But I remember vividly hitting this
joint with these dudes and literally
spending probably an hour and 30 minutes
laughing my balls off that.
Nothing.
And I thought it was the greatest thing
ever.
And from then on I was like,
I quit baseball.
No,
it popcorn became an artist.
Well I started drawing and painting on
walls.
I was like,
I was a different person.
That changed my life.
We eat is another thing that's probably
semi responses.
Well from my path I had a very important
moment when I was 16 like I only smoked
weed a handful of times before I was 30
years old,
like less than 12 like legitimately and
a one time when I was 16 it was me and
my girlfriend and my best friend who
went over her house and uh,
I had stole some weed for my Stepdad and
we'd rolled up a joint and we got so
high we were teleporting.
We would like find ourselves in the
kitchen,
astro bleeding type show.
I'll be staring at each other on the
couch and then all of a sudden we'd be
in the backyard.
We were barbecued.
We were were fucking 16 I think my
girlfriend at the time was 15 had josh
was my age,
he was,
he was 16 and we were just time
traveling all over the fucking building.
It was,
we were way too high.
That's how I,
I
described the for the first and only
time I ever smoked dust.
Oh Jesus.
He did that while I hung out with like
when I was one of the neighborhoods I
moved into this.
Is there a fucking gateway drug to dust
and tell me what it is.
It's called Solos.
Cholos.
Did they go right from Diet Pepsi to
dust?
I don't know.
Here's my story is I moved onto this
street called Independence Avenue in,
in the valley.
It's like West valley kind of Desoto
Sherman Way Ish.
And it was heavily Latino neighborhood
and like we moved in and it was cool.
I mean like I lived here,
I came friends with a lot of people,
but like,
um,
I went from like the end of elementary
school into junior high,
right in that era.
So like once we hit the junior high,
it's like a lot of the Mexican kids I
was hanging out with started hanging out
with you a little bit older Mason
candidate kids and a lot of them were
dealing in like kind of gang life over
there.
Um,
uh,
it's just part of the way they get down
and so,
and a lot of them like to fucking do
dips,
which is like a fucking sherm cigarette
dipped into my fucking angel angel dust.
Sounds like healthy choice dude's out.
It's how I wound up with this,
this little tattoo right here.
The first Tattoo I ever had in my life.
This little three dots normally is
supposed to be up here,
but I wasn't in a gang.
Oh,
I'm so,
it's like for some reason I was so
fucked up.
This is what wound up,
I mean this,
this represents what they call them a Mi
Vida loca.
It's like little three dots here.
But it's like that happened because I
smoked dust because these dudes pass me
the showroom.
I didn't really know what I was,
I was like this bang,
and the literally the way you just
described that time traveling and it was
like,
I felt like if I thought of something to
do,
by the time I was finished with the
thought of thinking to do it,
I had already done it.
I'm going to call my mom because my mom
was like fucking nuts.
I fucking never experienced anything
like that.
I was terrified.
I was terrified,
terrified.
I didn't know what the fuck is going on.
It was almost like,
you know what I mean?
It gave me a lot of feelings is if you
remember the first Friday movie when
Chris Tucker reflects on like somebody
snuck him a little piece of dust,
any fucking line.
It's,
I didn't lose my mind naked,
all that shit.
But I feel like I was the butt of a joke
that night.
Like,
like somebody gave me some dust.
It was like,
let's watch fucking the white boy
fucking trip on dust on it.
But it made for a good story on Joe
Rogan.
So now we're either,
I had an ex boxing coach who had his
finger bitten off when he was on dust
and he had his toe removed and a his
second toe replaced his index finger and
he made it curled so that he could keep
throwing right hooks because he did.
So when you'd shake his hand,
you'd shake his hand.
He would get like,
yeah,
you get a tow boat.
So when you shake his hand and get a
little of this,
and he's a big Ole Irish gorilla,
you don't want to say shit cause you'll
beat the fucking,
the dude as a toe or next figures can be
written into a movie that is a savage.
That's like something at a snatch.
I knew a lot of savages when I worked in
Boston,
when I worked in South Boston,
I worked at this place called the Boston
Athletic Club in South Boston.
That you did that to my poem.
I hear you man.
Yeah,
Dude.
I worked at the Boston Athletic Club and
then I worked at,
um,
Nautilus plus in revere.
I met a lot.
Revere Massachusetts is like,
well,
what's that place in Brooklyn that's
like all guineas and what does it,
Bensonhurst and,
right.
Yeah,
that was like the bents and Hersa Boston
was like revere and I uh,
I worked in a gym there,
so I was around a lot of crazy people.
I was around lot of people that,
I was around a few people that that got
indicted for murder.
Like this one dude,
he didn't get indicted.
He got arrested.
I don't know if they ever even tried
them.
Anyway,
long story short,
I don't say,
I don't know how much I can talk about
this guy's life.
Oh,
he was a nice guy,
but I think you might have fucked a few
people up.
Well,
there's nothing weirder to me.
Would not even weird.
I don't know if that's the right word,
but strange and uncomfortable as being
around.
And I'm not talking about like ex
marines are guys who have been in the
war or anything like that I'm talking
about,
but like a civilian person and I've been
around quite a few of these kinds of
people,
whether it be biker gang guys or
whatever.
To that,
you know?
Yeah.
You know,
you know have fucking killed,
you know,
you know that.
You know what I mean?
And you're not feeling threatened by
them.
You don't think they're going to kill
you.
But like you know it's,
there's a d
I used to train a guy who was in yt
bolgers gang.
He was like,
no.
I don't know if he was a Hitman,
but that was like the room or the room
one at least.
But he asked me why I was teaching him.
He asked me if I was going to kill
someone,
what's,
what's the best place to hit him?
And we sat around talking about,
it were,
me and him were talking about this when
I was a black bow and he was a white
belt.
So it was a,
it was like a valid conversation for him
to be having with a 20 year old kid.
And that was like the neck.
I got it.
I would,
I would hit someone in the neck like a,
your next very vulnerable and people get
knocked out very easily if they get hit
in the neck.
Sometimes even more so than the head.
And he was like,
yeah.
And we looked at each other.
I'm like,
okay,
this is what I want you to work on right
now.
We're going to work.
It's like,
that's funny because I had a cousin when
I was young,
like before,
like any of the house,
probably 1918 I was in California
visiting and he was a correctional
officer,
oo in upstate New York.
And he said the thing they were taught
first is cause all they walk around and
there's only like maybe 30 guards at a
time on duty and what 600 to a thousand
prisoners.
Right.
And depending on what the circumstances
are and all they have is a big metal key
ring.
And they're taught,
the first thing you fucking do is punch
a dude right in his fucking throat.
Yeah.
If you feel like you're any kind of
thing.
That's the,
and he told me that like that he was
like,
if I was going to give you any advice
and you felt like you were fucking,
he's like the first thing you do.
And I and he explained it well enough
that I knew and as even as a young man
like you're playing with a person's
life,
punching them in the fucking Adam's
apple or something,
you know what I mean?
With a kill them with like full like he
was like well what's that?
Well you can just put your fist.
If you hit him rake you would be amazed.
You'd be amazed at how much damage
people can take.
I actually,
I'd rather get punched in the Adam's
apple.
Then I would get kicked in the side of
my head like around here cause this is
what shuts you off.
It seems like,
again,
many things can shut you off just with
the caveat.
Like you can get shut off with a kick,
even like to the top of your chest snaps
your head back so much and get shut off.
But there's something about neck kicks
like Bang Dude,
just go.
They just crumpled and sometimes they
crumbled from Chin shots.
But I think it's the same thing.
I think with the Chin shot is doing is
somehow or another pinching the garden
hose that is the spine.
And shutting the system off.
It's also,
if I'm not mistaken,
your,
you know,
your brain sits in that little bit of
fluid and if you have your scope moves
fast enough,
the brain doesn't move as fast and it
touches the,
once a short rain touches the skull,
that's lights out that that absolutely
too.
Also,
I think the same principle like rear
naked chokes and um,
head kick knockouts are not the same in
that a rear naked choke is way safer.
Like if you get choked unconscious,
you're going to be fine.
If you get head kicked unconscious,
Ooh,
you got to take some time off.
Like you could just got fucked up.
But the mechanism behind them is kind of
similar in that it's cutting off the
circuitry,
not like specifically cause the choke is
like stopping the blood.
But the head kick is just jolting.
It's like rebooting your computer head
kick.
I would imagine.
I've never experienced it nor can I
throw one that high.
Uh,
but I would imagine why it might be
worse is because like right,
you can punch and it's the motion of the
head almost.
And the brain not moving that is causing
the knockout.
If you get kicked like this,
it's a shin.
It's everything.
Your head doesn't even get to move so
the brain is actually just cause getting
slammed against the other side of the
fucking skull.
I've made this point really recently and
even yesterday I think people should
have no gloves on when they fight.
I think fighting with gloves is like,
it makes it easier to punch people,
which is more an more unrealistic and
getting kicked in the head is way worse
than getting punched in the head wound.
That argument for Olympic head gear.
That's why it's going away.
It causes more problems than it's
actually worth it at this point.
I also think it's unrealistic in terms
of like the limitations of your body,
like there's limitations of your body
with punching people and that's the your
risks bend like anybody's ever punched
someone or condone tape or just no bra,
no bra.
I that's,
yeah,
it was taped is really what the problem
is that when you take this risk like so
well that I can't really fuck it up.
I'm going to,
I'm going to throw it with abandoned.
Well also it's like no abandon you.
Right.
If you can,
if you can tape.
Here's what we're thinking with Noah
band.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with two people agreeing with a like a
rule set.
Like they agree,
okay we're going to wear gloves and
we're going to wear khaki pants,
like things along those lines.
But like if you could work gloves,
gloves for a striker or the equivalent
of [inaudible] pants for a really good
Jujitsu guard player.
Like if a guy like Eddie Bravo is
allowed to wear Gucci pants and he gets
you wrapped up.
If you'd like some regular dude,
you're going to sleep,
you're going to get fucked up.
You know,
unless you're like some highly even like
coiler Gracie fucks up when he's wearing
the geek pants cause he knows that those
g pants provide insane amounts of
friction and traction.
Clamp a hold of you and he could do some
shit to you that you're just going to be
super uncomfortable with.
In a way,
that's as much of an advantage for him
to be able to wear.
The g pants as it would be for a striker
to wear the gloves,
but only as tracker gets to wear the
gloves,
like the grapplers have to wear shorts.
Like it's really kind of interesting
because having your knuckles taped up
and having your knuckles padded up is a
real advantage for someone who knows how
to hit things because you can,
you can be like much more a relaxed and
liberal with your use of punches.
You don't have to worry about hitting
bones,
but you would never allow that the other
way,
like giving,
like giving the option of a striker to
wear hand pads and then a grappler to
where g pants,
it's really,
it's like we have a very accepted idea
of what civilized.
One of the things is you cover your
knuckles.
It's kind of stupid because you don't
have to cover your elbows,
but people are smashing and slashing
people up with their elbows.
My case against it is that it's not
logical.
It's just historical.
We're just,
we're just going by a tradition and it's
not a logical tradition.
Right.
Still Queens,
mark's barry kind of,
it is up,
but these are,
these are limitations that we inherited
from a single discipline,
so it's also like think back back,
not,
not that long ago,
a 75 round fight isn't,
wasn't unheard of.
Yeah.
They didn't have no cte.
There was no will smith movie.
There was no,
no one knew what the fuck was going on.
There was no real sports with Bryant
Gumbel and nobody had any idea that
getting the hit in the head for that
long would be that bad for you.
Crazy.
Yeah.
It's,
it's kind of fascinating when you think
about it,
but I really do think that the gloves
are,
I think we're doing a huge disservice to
the art of fighting because I think we
have unrealistic expectations based on
the idea that you could just punch
someone with padded knuckles.
I think if we didn't have padded
knuckles,
we'd be much more clever and how we use
our hands,
because you might break your hand in any
shot and it would be easy to choke
people.
So jujitsu be more effective to have
those things are way better for the
athletes and way better for the the
honest interpretation of what fighting
is.
The problem is no one's going to agree
to that because people got up from home,
they're going to look at it and go,
oh,
this is barbaric.
This is horrible.
They don't even have gloves on their
bare knock or the first time a guy
catches a tooth in his fast and it's,
and it's just push open.
They're going to be in your elbow,
which essentially it fixed in your chin
or,
yeah,
me,
but what's the difference between a,
you catching one and your knuckle or
catching one in the end of your foot?
When you kick someone's face sideways,
you can wheel kick them in the head with
your heel,
but you can't punch them with bare
knuckles.
It's stupid.
It's a dumb rule.
It's the whole six to 12 things and
stupid too.
It doesn't work,
but I'll leave that.
I'll leave that and take no gloves any
day.
I really think there should be no
gloves.
I think even for strikers,
I think,
yeah man,
you pad some dudes up.
You,
you fucking give a dude like tyrone's
loves.
Just like protecting your lane.
Blood skin,
but no taping.
What if that w would you,
why urban text?
Your knuckles and skin.
Why?
What are we looking at?
We're looking at the why.
How can you look it up on my elbows,
devil's advocate on that.
We're looking at exchange of bodily
fluids.
If I punch you in the teeth,
you know what I mean?
Silly.
You're getting that from everything.
You getting that from arms choke.
People really like people getting bitten
when they've been choke.
When you choke like a rick,
like you watched Damien Maia versus rick
story and he's going like right over his
face and you don't think he's getting a
little bit of bite.
You get bites and your arms.
You don't even,
they're not even trying to bite you.
They're trying to breathe and you're
crushing your bar.
Rarely do you see his arm come away,
bleeding or something.
I'm saying there's the rare occasion of
like though but but a far less rare
would be if there was no gloves and
you're punching a guy and a
modification,
you're going to catch them teeth.
You going to be a lot more cutting of
the hands too.
I'm just playing devil's advocate.
Devil's advocate.
Here is a solution.
Double Mouth Guard in enforce the rule
of a devil mouth guard,
which means that there's a space and a
metal version too like an old school
like no,
no,
no.
It goes lower teeth and the upper teeth
and then you have a space in the middle.
Bernard Hopkins always used to fight
with one of those and it covers your
lower teeth and your upper teeth and
there's a space in the middle and you
breathe through that and you breathe
through your nose and you get used to
doing that and the lower mouth guard.
The problem with having only an upper
mouth guard is most people do that,
but only in upper mouth guard will work
for the most part.
But there is,
if you're bare knuckle,
there's,
there's a real argument for using an
upper and a lower because you're dealing
with different situations.
Joe.
Well,
even then you would just have it fitted
to your face.
Just devil advocate.
I understand what you're saying.
What I'm saying is
shut up either,
but know our dough.
Bernard Hopkins,
my favorite fighter of all time.
Personally.
I know.
Hey,
whenever my favorite,
he's my favorite boss.
I'll tell you why.
He's my favorite.
I'll tell you why is my fear,
first of all,
I saw his last fight.
I was there in the forum and it was,
it was a bummer to me.
You're better than that and I'm,
your fucking career will be forever
because here's what I knew.
Bernard Hopkins was the fucking man.
All right.
He was,
I be real.
I've always been surrounded by Latin
guys.
Alright.
That's just all the dudes I know are
Mexican,
Cuban and these kind of guys,
you know,
be real is one of my best friends on
earth.
Um,
sick jacket,
that's another,
you know,
these are all of that and dues.
These are all Spanish guys,
Mexicans and whatnot.
So anytime a fight like that would come
up,
you know,
they're all taken de Felix Trinidad or
the whoever it was.
Of course when he was fighting Felix
Trinidad,
we were all watching at [inaudible]
house when his mother fucker took the
Puerto Rican flag.
He was in Puerto Rico Talking Shit on
Felix Trinidad at the time.
The fucking all mighty fucking son of
all Puerto Rico,
the Puerto Rican flag,
which if you know about Puerto Rican
guys and I know plenty of Puerto Rican
guys,
you put that flag on anything.
They've got so much pride.
They'll,
they,
they'll buy it,
they'll wear it there.
Is it a flag?
Is Everything.
They get crazy.
He took this flag in Puerto Rico.
Dude on the ground is stepped on it.
Jesus.
Why go back you?
I'm sure it's on youtube where he'd
steps on the Puerto Rican for the end
point in a room and I literally told my
friends if he gets off that island,
nobody on our speaking his ass.
I was like,
cause they should be trying to fucking
kill him right now if know anything
about
Puerto Rican people,
what me and when he got the fight came
that day.
I bet everybody and be,
be real used to throw like barbecues
every fight like it would be,
that's where we be.
That was,
that was our routine.
We got it.
And then it was always anytime it was
like a black guy versus like a Spanish,
Spanish guy.
It could be any kind of Spanish guy.
I would always like bet against the
house and more times than not I won.
But like Yo,
he stomps on the God damn flag and got
out of that island.
We threw it,
he took it away from fields to on the
ground and then he beat his ass.
I feel like he killed him and the ninth
round and my car.
I feel like he killed him right there
while he definitely landed a sack of
working with,
owed him right there.
Cause it's like if you didn't get
stabbed before you got off the island of
Puerto Rico,
that's a win.
He put a lot of pressure on himself
though.
That's how,
that's why I always knew I was like the
is my man.
I'm just,
but just for the ball factor of that,
that's a big ball factor.
I mean if you would have pulled that in
New York,
I would said you were fucking crazy in
Puerto Rico.
Jesus man,
that took huge nuts that we took the
dude who was in jail for most of his
life and was living off commissary
donations.
It was a brilliant performance too in
that fight.
He kicked ass Yo Bernard until the last,
he'd beat the shit out of fields.
Five,
six fights of his,
he'd beat the shit out of everybody.
Well,
you got to realize he's like 51 which is
incredible when this fight,
I want to say he was 34 35 well,
he was old when I did 36 spent so much
time in jail.
Oh my God.
What a beautiful counter punch,
but you know what this show is always
about him.
Is he live like a monk?
Yeah.
It was always in training.
He never fucking partied.
Never any smoke?
No.
Just us foods is the big thing he was
saying.
He eats very healthy and clean.
He was one of the early advocates of the
raw diet kind of thing.
I know he also was a brilliant boxer and
I just loved executional.
Came out with the mask duty.
You got to realize this guy got passed.
He got past 12 rounds and Sergey Kovalev
without getting knocked out and he got
rocked and dinged several times in that
fight.
He fought cove 11 is prime cove left,
who my opinion is top three or four
pound for pound in the world.
I mean it's arguable at least number one
right now or a fight.
Dude,
he wanted that first four could have,
I feel like he'd get [inaudible]
opinion.
I thought he was my humble opinion.
I agree with you.
I would have to like go over it with a
real legitimate boxing judge and like,
I don't,
I mean I know what I think about boxing
towns.
Crawford fight where he put it on that
Cuban or whatever he is,
put the fucking crowd he's,
and he's in the argument for number one
pound for pound in the world is,
I feel like it's changing.
Tito got beat,
right.
Controversial fight,
but closer yet to handle those
decisions,
see the fight.
But I heard it was controversial.
Some people disagreed with it,
but my ma,
what I feel is that like terrence
Crawford and Loma Chanko or the guys who
put it on people to the point where he,
they just run away from it.
Just set the fight and run away from it.
But they just set the big fight.
The fucking triple.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
What's
your thing?
What's you think it's a very important
fight?
It's a very important fight because like
you look at how good can l looked
against Julio,
Cesar Chavez Jr [inaudible] come on.
Let's be real respect to pop's.
Respect to pops all the way that got
cheetos.
Junior was never,
ever,
ever anywhere.
He shouldn't have been in there.
The only thing he got to read,
only reason he got in his,
cause his name was Chavez Jr man.
Honestly,
you're 100% correct other than the few
good.
He's had some good performances.
Sergio Martinez and once he got busted
for that we shit.
It seemed like after that it was
downhill.
The kid just didn't care anymore.
You know what?
I equate it to this personally.
I don't know the guy,
I'm not assuming my take on it is he
just got tired of fucking trying to be
the fucking his dad.
What a hundred and something and how
many losses?
Just the cop.
That was one of the greatest of all
time,
if not this right here.
This floyd mayweather,
like 40 and something.
Oh,
didn't dude go like 70 something and Oh,
why does that,
no,
he didn't.
He didn't.
He didn't and my trip man.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The then my phone for facebook.
Fake News.
What was the,
uh,
what was Google,
what was Julio set up since I shot
record before he lost,
there's two amateur fights or something.
Before the Loma Chanko was only had one
amateur loss.
He's got one professional laws,
one batch,
a lot check in boxing because I've
become such a UFC fan.
I'm like,
I'm some cats.
I have friends like my buddy vinny pass
from,
from any paths.
He fucking hates him.
It made fucking hates it.
This task please Joe.
Joe,
I'm there that day when vinny comes
invitation,
any paths.
What do you do it in July,
July 8th.
July 8th?
No,
that it,
I don't think I'll be back,
but if he wants to go call.
No,
no,
no.
I want to be there.
But if you change that opinion out cause
he's a boxing,
but he is,
I told him the Natto,
he loves the [inaudible].
I know he is.
I know what he looks.
Disrespects the MMA game to a certain
degree where I'm like,
okay,
what's your little like comments,
dude?
You know,
he's real fighting.
in the streets.
Floyd Mayweather,
we'd get his fucking ass busted by
Connie [inaudible] wouldn't even be
close,
but it was more destruction.
It would be connor mcgregor,
grading floyd mayweather's face into the
pavement like parmesan cheese.
That's what it would be in real life.
It was just rip his legs out.
That's it.
Floyd didn't tag him with a knockout
punch from the first few seconds of the
fight.
Connor would be way away from him
kicking his legs out.
Hands out.
I read this article.
I don't know.
She probably saw about like,
what if it was like a,
what if article?
What if connor took the flight with
mayweather and just came out,
picked him up,
slammed him on the fucking ground and
dismantle them and like rip design.
It's just to do it.
He could do it and he really could do it
if you wanted to take them down and just
lost all their money and everything,
but I still kicked his ass.
He's,
that's nothing.
MMA destroys fucking,
he would go to jail or something would
happen because it would be,
here's a problem.
There'd be betting,
right?
It'd be all these people bet against it.
What do you do there?
Because Floyd winds by disqualification.
You knew you were going to do this and
you didn't go into this with good faith
class action lawsuit against conor
Mcgregor.
Wow.
You're taking a what if article way too
far.
That would be funny.
It's what I do with everything.
It's my problem.
No,
I love it.
I go deep too deep on this thing,
man.
It's going to be an interesting fight.
If they fight,
I think she fight with no gloves.
See what the fuck is really going on.
Hey,
one other,
that's my thing since I'm really,
I'm really glad joe started me drinking
whiskey before the podcast.
Two in the afternoon.
I ain't mad at you.
Come on.
Don't,
don't act like you didn't say,
let's drink some whiskey.
Everlast to say no,
Then you have made the full pot.
But what I want to say real quick,
it's because I've been drinking and I
haven't been there in awhile either.
My good friend Jason Ellis,
just one,
his king of the cage match won by
submission,
right?
Yes.
He won outright by submission.
Congratulations.
[inaudible] you fucking worked hard for
that and that that inspires me.
That kind of shit inspires me when I see
Jason Dude and I'm like,
fuck,
I'm making a lot of excuses for shit.
He did real strength and conditioning
with like no train deal.
First of all,
he beat up a couple of MMA guys.
I mean rape or what it was gay Rutenbar,
whatever.
He beat that.
I was there when you beat him up,
man.
Watch me beat him up.
All right.
That's actually fights.
Whatever you want to say about all the
weight cuts he missed on the ultimate
fighter said that guy's a professional
fighter.
Jayson beat the shit out of him and
knocked him out.
All right.
When I heard about this fight,
I was texting him like,
you're going to win this fight,
dude.
I know you went,
but Yo,
you fucking won that fight dog.
Real deal.
Love you.
Congrats.
Yeah.
And did everything he had to do like did
the real shit to get in shape that
that's what I'm saying,
he's inspired that that Kinda guy is
inspiring to me.
Remember,
because what he does is he chooses
something and he says,
I'm gonna commit to it.
I was saying,
I think earlier I'm here because I
follow road signs and I just,
I,
I consider myself adept at reading the
signs of life and where I'm po when
there's the forks in the road.
I happen to be good at making the right
choice.
There's certain guys that don't give a
fuck about the fork in the road and
determine their own fucking path and
decide.
You're kind of one of those dudes.
And I admire that.
I mean,
admire what I do.
I know,
I recognize there's a skill and a talent
and a blessing and what I do,
but there's something about being of
decide something and fucking make it so
even though maybe it's not supposed to
be so,
and that is my next chasing life.
Maybe not to it.
If I,
even if I don't achieve it,
to understand it,
how it's possible,
how could I be that guy?
How could it at 20 maybe I have under
understood a little bit differently,
so maybe by the time I'm 70 God willing,
it's an illusion.
This is the illusion.
The illusion is that looking at the
ultimate results
from your perspective and you're saying
how,
how do I tune myself in?
How do I,
how do I get totally connected with what
I really want to do and not be
influenced by the opinions and the ideas
of others?
How do I find my true sweet spot,
right?
The problem is we all look at other
people's destination.
Again,
like that crazy quote,
that comparison is the enemy of joy.
It's really kind of the same thing.
The thief of joy.
Yeah,
the thief of joy,
that the whole key I think to anything
you do,
whether you're a guy who makes furniture
or a woman who paints or whatever the
fuck you do where you were a rapper or a
blues singer,
a standup comedian or an author or
whatever the fuck you do.
The thing,
the thing is,
and this is a cliche expression,
but it's re there's a reason why people
keep expressing and over and over again
get out of your own way.
Half of the reason why you're not tuning
in perfectly good to whatever fucking
vibration is available to you in the
universe as you get in your own fucking
way,
you get in your own way with insecurity
and with ego and with expectation and
with pressure and with all the different
judgments you cast on different forms of
art that you may or may not like,
like you're wasting time.
You're wasting energy.
It's clogging up your gears.
You only have a certain amount.
You got to manage your attention the way
you would manage oxygen if you are in a
space ship.
You got to say,
I can't give away this stuff to
bullshit.
I can't be sitting around wondering if
you know w,
W,
w whatever the fuck it is.
If it's not relevant to your life,
you will be wasting way too much time
thinking about it.
This,
okay,
let me come at you.
Okay.
And this is personal.
This is personal.
Oh
I accept everything you just said as
truth,
but let me throw a personal angle at
you.
Yes sir.
I want to be in much better shape.
Okay.
We can do that.
We can get that.
No,
here,
let me gets to the,
the,
the circumstances.
Every,
I have a life that
okay.
Presents me with a lot of problems that
can
make emotional conflictions yes.
With what I'm trying to achieve in life.
Right.
Legitimate ones.
You know what I mean?
Cause certain,
I won't call myself ever depressed cause
I don't like that word.
I mean I do get depressed but I want to
use the word like,
oh I had depression.
I think a lot of people lean on some
shit and like try to actually milk it
in.
Especially in media.
Do you want to see something right now
before you keep talking to this going to
change your life.
That's going to like lock into exactly
what you're saying and you don't even
know what am I finished saying but yes,
I'm going to show you the way Jamie,
go to my twitter page and pull that
Jocko.
Good.
Watch this.
This is very important,
my friend.
Please is very important and I trusted
you enough to be like all the back end
from the beginning.
I won't picket fence that you
didn't hear the finish my store.
Bring it to the beginning.
We put it up on the screen and we're at
least going to play one more war porn
video cause I promised my guys give it.
Give us some volume.
Listen to this.
One of my direct subordinates,
one of my guys that worked for me,
he would,
he would call me up or pull me aside
with some major problem,
some issue that was going on and he
taped.
So we got this and that and the other
thing.
And I look at him and I'd say,
good.
And finally one day he was telling me
about some issue that he was having some
problem and uh,
he said,
I already know what you're going to say.
I said,
well,
what am I going to say?
You said you're going to say good.
Uh,
he said,
that's what you always say when
something is wrong in going bad.
You always just look at me and say good.
And I said,
well,
yeah,
when things are going bad,
there's going to be some good that's
going to come from it.
Okay?
Didn't get the new high speed gear we
wanted.
Good.
Didn't get promoted.
More time to get back.
Oh,
mission got canceled.
Good.
We can focus on the older one.
Didn't get funded,
didn't get the job you wanted.
Got Injured.
Sprained my ankle,
got tapped out.
Good.
Got Beat.
Unexpected problems.
Good opportunity to figure out a
solution.
That's it.
When things are going bad,
don't get all bummed out.
Don't get startled.
Don't get frustrated.
Can say the word good.
Guess what needs,
need.
You're still alive.
It means you're still bleeding.
And if you're still breathing,
you still got some fight left in.
Get up,
dust off.
Reload,
recalibrate,
reengage.
Yeah,
go out on the attack.
Jocko willink,
changing motherfuckers lives right now.
Live in America.
Coming to you from southern California.
I jocko rhino goosebumps right now.
My kids got pneumonia and her fucking
left.
Learn to a degree that nobody fucking
knows what to do and fucking even the
doctors are perplexed while you write
about that,
what he's talking about.
This is my question.
This is why I was saying I'm not asking,
I'm not asking of,
I'm saying I actually came on the show
today.
A say of if,
if something in this room,
if somebody in the valley area or La
Greater area,
my twitter's,
Oh gee.
Everlast my uh,
everything's the same.
Oh Gee.
Everlast or Erik Schrody on facebook.
Legitimate.
I need a little help.
I need a little help in the sense that I
want to be in better shape,
but I travel so much and then at home is
a stress of like,
I want to go to the gym.
I couldn't go to the fucking gym for the
last 10 days.
It was either me or my wife at the
fucking house and you hear somebody
don't know.
I don't wanna make you feel bad at all.
I want to say it's like that's,
that was beautiful.
Whoever,
who is that guy again?
Jocko willink,
Jocko willink.
That is fucking supremely motivationally
on any level except what I'm trying to
say is like skating your way around this
fucking kind of emotional fucking
dilemma of like it's hard.
Of course I'm here saying it's hard.
I'm actually bringing it up to say no
one's denying failing in certain ways at
at what I'm trying to achieve.
And so like that's what I mean when I
say I'd see Jason and I know again,
I got a little extra,
I got a little extra to deal with.
I got a little,
my backpack has a little more weight
emotionally and mentally.
Okay.
But I'm not making that an excuse.
What I'm saying is is like how do I be
more like that?
How can that,
I want that.
I'm asking.
Well,
what he's given you is talking about
very specific situations given you
opportunities that Rick Carson was,
I got down,
I'm fucked up.
It's when it's this other thing,
this other,
this is a whole different level of like
mental challenge to it.
I'm not saying what he's saying is
wrong.
I'm not saying it doesn't work,
but how do I find that in that?
That's tough.
It's,
it's a sin.
What he's proposing,
the principles that he has the answer
please fucking Holler at no listen man.
The principles that he's proposing when
he's saying that you can apply them to
everything.
Figure out how you can take whatever
situation you're in and improve your
position.
Do 400 curls a day and be as buff as Joe
Rogan.
I can't,
how do I get to,
I'm making fucking,
I don't even,
you're acting like literal with this
literal.
Don't get literal with me.
Alright.
Cause to drinking whiskey or drinking
water,
that's whiskey.
I only got to drive a block.
You got to drive however far
interesting.
Someone's comparing joy.
I'll walk thief,
thief of joy that's crept into our
travel pillows.
Actually just meant to be like a little,
you know,
but um,
I want that.
I,
that I found that very motivating.
But what I'm saying is like,
there's this hurdle I understand of cap
or lieutenant Dan that's got some real
fucking anger issues.
I'm working,
I'm out,
I'm working on him.
I'm,
this is the real,
hey,
the whiskey,
I'm being more honest than I even
thought I would be today.
Okay.
But you're,
I mean,
you don't get on a fucking platform like
Joe Rogan and say,
Hey,
I'm failing at this,
unless you're fucking trying to do
something about it.
You know what I mean?
I want to achieve,
I don't want to be you,
but I'm like,
I see the way I love to watch it.
I,
you know what I'm saying?
But I've been watching your videos about
running,
about running.
I do.
Another thing that has also gotten to me
and me to,
when I
do get to work out,
it's because I hear Joe Rogan tell me,
don't let the inner bitch fucking get
you.
Yeah.
And I can extension.
And that that's been a big motivator for
me as I,
but there's,
it's not an inner bitch to be disturbed
and upset and your life up heaved by
this thing is dad.
Absolutely not.
It's absolutely not.
Do you feel where I'm coming from?
Right?
Think but what he's saying in this
video,
what is applicable and you can argue
whether or not solve,
but I'm asking you on a personal level.
I sit on a personal level and I'm not
trying to argue with you or be
argumentative as I'm saying on a
personal level.
That's the level of it with it.
The level of that that are that that
inspirational message is great,
but I'm struggling.
Of course you are with this part of it.
Like how do I,
I,
if I got my arm broken and snapped by a
guy who tapped me out or,
or life just kicked my ass and I didn't
get the job I or the opportunity,
I wanted an good,
I understand that.
But I am personally struggling with he
as an excuse,
not using this but the truthful
emotional fucking agony of like seeing a
child tow you like and not just tell you
but go through this hospital of the last
two weeks.
These things of like,
how do I be stronger?
How do I,
you and anybody and what I'm saying,
I'm not being argumentative with you
again is saying,
please,
if you've got a book throw,
it's tweeted to me.
If you're the dude who fucking is local
and says,
I know how to help.
Plus I understand I have a heart valve
replacement,
my workout.
Let me tell you why working out gets
weird for me.
I'll start,
I'll do good.
I'll drop 15 pounds,
bang,
boom,
boom.
And then I'll start to push myself and
I'll,
I'll get distrustful of my own heart,
like a pain or a tinge that really might
not be anything will come along and
fucking scare the shit out of me because
there's nothing,
I never was afraid of anything in my
life until I had children.
And the only thing I'm afraid of on this
planet is not being here for my
children,
my life or death.
I do not care.
I've died twice,
literally.
All right,
I don't care about that.
But now there's this fear of like these
children,
these girls,
not even boys.
I honestly even feel I would feel
differently if I had two boys.
Like there'll be all right.
I can instill the manly shit into him
while I'm here.
But my girls,
I'm of the,
my biggest fear in life is not being
here for them.
And I'm good.
I'm healthy.
I,
except for about 25 pounds of weight.
I'm actually,
my blood works,
all that.
My doctors are all very happy with me,
the only complaint they ever have.
And the only complaint I ever have is I
have some back pains.
Sometimes I'm asleep.
Right.
Let me stop [inaudible] go ahead.
Let me stop you with all of his talk
because you have a lot of reasons why
things aren't working physically the way
you would like them to.
Cousin,
I'm definitely,
I would like help.
I understand you are,
but there's too much extra energy spent
on things that aren't helping you like
you and I know you have these time
constraints,
but to focus on them is
counterproductive because you have the
time constraints that time constraints
rob you of your time and then the
focusing on the time constraints and the
agony of those time constraints and the
fucking frustration of having those time
constraints robs you have more time and
more energy.
You just got to accept it.
You've got to be zen about it.
I had a friend and he's on it.
He's a comedian from Boston,
his name is Tony Vee,
and he said something to me once.
It's very important and it applied to
the rest of my life and it was a very
simple statement.
He was driving from Boston to New York
several times a week,
several times for some job he got and
I'm like,
how do you do that?
And he goes,
you know what I found when I get in the
car I just go Zan.
I say,
this is what I'm doing.
I don't,
I don't concern myself with the fact
that will wash the dishes.
that I can't believe I have to do this.
Oh my God,
woe is me.
He goes,
I just do it.
And then I thought about that that day
and then I applied that to my life
because that's the best advice anybody
could ever get it from you.
Anybody who's doing anything they don't
like to do.
Of course you don't like to do it,
but to concentrate on the fact that you
don't like to do it compounds the not
like to do it aspect of it.
It makes it worse.
No,
no.
Actually it was describing is actually a
lot of the stuff I'm reading right now,
which is like the art of mindfulness,
which is again,
when I keep saying wash the dishes,
wash the dishes,
it's,
it's kind of like saying exactly what I
like.
Wash your dishes to wash your dishes,
don't wash your dishes to get to the
next thing because then you're not
living life.
You're not breathing in.
I live in,
in your moment.
So I'm working on that.
But at the same time I'm still saying
like,
ah.
Also,
ah,
you know what I found in the last couple
of years,
especially through like the little
social media that I managed to be
successful,
that,
that people want to know the real deal.
Shit ain't fucking perfect over here.
There's a lot of things about me.
I'd like to be better.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Just because I make good money and I
ain't hungry.
I could eat philemon you own.
And while that every night,
you know me,
I could live really.
I do live really nice.
I'm very fucking grateful for my life,
but there's a lot of fucking dark.
You don't see that.
If you saw,
maybe you wouldn't all this fakery
there's a lot of instagram,
how dare you,
whatever.
And you go bring him up.
But um,
yeah,
that,
you know what that is?
Jamie's been bringing up a little balla
nonstop.
Just the Cherry on top of fucking
fuckery,
you know what I mean?
So what he got called out for,
but he was on a flight,
at least he was like,
you know,
on a plane in first class was even,
wasn't really my business.
At least I fly,
I don't fly first.
I fly business as long as I can lay
down,
as long as the tape,
things like this.
When I fly to Europe I'm cool.
But you know,
and the few times I have flown private,
I instagram that shit.
Hell yeah.
Cause I don't fly private dude.
I know what it really costs.
Right.
It ain't cheap.
When I hollered data like,
hey can I catch it lifted the last
flight and I don't get a response back.
I know it ain't cheap cause that's my
dude.
If it was cheaper,
you'd be like,
yeah,
come on.
That's funny.
I think you have to log you.
Exactly.
Why has ever last going?
I play my song and every event.
How's that?
Is that good enough?
Important.
Every event and I love Dana for that.
Thank you man.
I love that fucking 35 cents I get for
that shit every cause that what'd you
get?
Probably something that anybody,
if it's one time in an arena but
thinking about pays 35 cents.
Well the radio only plays five so I'm
going to just assuming that,
wait a minute.
Every time your song gets played on the
radio,
you get five sentence basically
somewhere in that neighborhood,
somewhere between five and 10 probably.
What a weird deal.
Hey Dude,
it gets played a lot because the checks
I'm sure are fat because you deal with a
lot of countries,
a lot of humans,
7 billion people that 5 cents as the
fuck up.
He does mailbox money.
We call that.
It's a good way to describe them.
Like I said,
you know what I mean?
It's just like,
hey man,
I'm honestly like saying,
Hey,
throw it out there.
There's somebody local,
my diet,
my diet is working on it.
I told you so knows my fucking enemy as
bane of mindless crap hole is it is
cracked.
What?
Coca Cola is my crack.
Don't,
don't ingest poison.
You drink coffee in the morning?
Yes,
I don't.
I hate coffee.
I drank.
That whole story makes you live forever.
What was the article that I retweeted?
I said I want to believe and it said
coffee can make you live longer.
I didn't even read it.
I read that article for like half a
paragraph.
I might've got into paragraph number two
was clicked my email unless play it
another war.
Porn video cause it's fucking dope.
Let's play another war.
Porn video.
Jamie.
Plus I gotta pee bad but I'll be right
back.
You need whiskey,
bladder,
brother days.
This was the second one.
Here we go.
[inaudible] last night,
last night.
All Gas.
No choice in the street with the
scratching.
Perfect timing and your back.
Yes sir.
Had it released some whiskey.
I understand.
I did as well.
Shout out divine styler.
He did all the tracks for the record
shout.
You know what I mean?
I gave him like four already,
but still I think this is the most shout
outs on a podcast.
Well,
I'm going to say shout out Joe Rogan.
How'd you like that?
What up?
You know what I mean?
Shout out to everlast.
Shout out every bravo shout out a tape
flight.
Hottest podcast I ever did in my life.
Get some fucking air conditioning in
that building and take the word no,
no,
not here.
No.
At Eddie's spot a problem.
And there was like 400 water bottles
when they did his shit.
Yeah.
They don't have a mate.
Is that van eyes?
Yeah.
Over there somewhere by the spearmint
rhino down.
People are going to find him.
Yeah,
he's a what's hilarious.
I did it once and there was a dude
playing drum solos next door,
like some dude in the building next door
was playing the drums.
He could hear it through the fucking
walls like,
oh yeah,
okay.
That makes it,
yeah.
It was kind of a rehearsal studio and I
was like,
dude,
does this happen often?
He's like,
sometimes it happens,
you know,
he's got to get a smoke serpent remixes
on,
you know?
Yeah man,
that's my dude.
I liked that guy.
He keeps offering,
introduced me to a dude out there in
corona near where I live to work out to.
Uh,
uh,
he said he got a black belt off there.
Then once,
you know,
I,
I was doing a little Brazilian Jujitsu
with Marcus Vanessa's over at,
uh,
beverly hills one just so I was
literally probably one lesson away from
my blue belt when I just everything
sign.
It kind of went haywire in my life.
Layla was born and all this,
all of this stuff happened and I kinda
moved south.
I didn't live here anymore.
Well,
you're friends with Joey Diaz.
You should go with Joey.
Joey does it in Burbank.
If you can make it up,
you bring it back.
I live in,
I live an hour and a half fucking one.
Find a place near,
you mean I'll find what I want his
privates.
I want,
I'll set up my garage with a little pad
system that cause the,
here's the deal.
I know it doesn't happen often,
but anything like staff or anything like
that is so dangerous for Layla.
That is,
it's really scary.
So like working out in a gym with like
40 guys working out,
there's too scary.
There's too frightening things for me.
Working out in a normal Jujitsu class,
the fucking average novice that doesn't
realize he's fucking stupid and fucking
pulls my left arm out or my right arm
out and I can't play guitar for fucking
six weeks or a month or six months even,
you know?
So I only trained with the teachers.
That's my,
what I just said,
hey,
I'll pay for that.
Whatever little extra of private,
whatever.
You know what I mean?
But obviously brought I,
Eddie doesn't live out that way so,
but he told me,
he was like,
I got a fucking guy out there who's
awesome.
He's a fucking black belt.
He's fucking awesome.
And I just,
I haven't followed up as much as he
hasn't gotten back,
you know what I mean?
So it's not like he's like ignoring me
or anything.
I'm just saying I got to follow through
on that and get that going to,
cause if I lose and I've lost about 15
pounds honestly with all this talk we're
saying and recently,
uh,
it's called the great American worry
diet has been a week in the hospital and
lose 15 pounds,
especially at one that doesn't serve
meat or caffeine,
you know,
so those,
shout out to the seventh they advocates
who don't eat meat or caffeine and the
most stressful situations ever.
Yeah.
But you know,
honestly I won't even say the,
they,
they took such amazing care of my
daughter.
I love every single one of them.
That's awesome.
Now they're non meeting non coffee
drinking assets.
I loved them.
Maybe try that diet.
Let's keep,
keep riding
it.
It's working.
What do you,
what you said about the worry though?
I just get the worry part of the worry
diet is the hard part,
you know,
of course.
That's the whole reason of what I kind
of brought up earlier.
It's like how do you get around that?
How do you get around worrying about
your own kid?
You're going to have to read some books
on strategy,
how to do that.
I'm trying,
but I'm also here.
I'm feeling myself.
I've smoked a little,
I've drank a little,
right?
I trust the Joe Rogan person and his
audience that,
hey,
if there's an interesting idea out
there,
go ahead and shoot it.
I'm sure someone will find me.
There's going to hae and I know I'm
going to get like 400 fucking shitty
ideas,
but if there's one good one out there,
great.
Yeah,
this is going to be dudes who recommend
video games.
Bro.
Fucking solved all my problems,
dude,
bro.
Jump Rope and virtual road a fake bomb,
dude,
ping pong changed my life,
man.
You know what?
You're,
uh,
you're,
you've been given a very difficult test
by whatever,
by life itself.
And the truth of the matter is,
up until that man,
I had an easy ride he had.
Okay,
so don't feel bad for me.
Right?
But if he got a suggestion,
please shoot it my way because I'm,
oh,
I'm at this point in life like I've
understood again,
the communal,
I think beyond the music lesson of it
being communal,
right,
is as a human being,
we are communal people.
Yeah,
and even hails back to the beginning of
what we talked about,
the blues and the reds,
they are trying to separate us because
we're communal and if we all actually
sat down,
even the most fucking worst opinion over
there in the worst pain over there.
If we were only in the room together,
we could find somewhere over here where
we could both at least be the least bit
angry at each other.
I honestly think we should eliminate
political parties.
Thank you.
Think what we should have is just a
bunch of people with money out of
politics,
money pull money here.
Let's hear she.
Interesting idea.
Here's an interesting idea about
England,
right?
England announces their elections.
There are three months from the
announcement of the elections till the
election for you to legally campaign.
Why is that good?
It's better because of what?
Again,
hailing back to what we said earlier,
the day after the presidents elected,
it seems like they're talking about
who's going to run in 2020 already.
Right.
All right,
and,
and this,
hey,
we might be in a particularly weird
circumstance now in America again,
I won't,
I won't even delve into that.
What I want to say is the day after our
president is elected,
we shouldn't be talking about who's
going to be the next fucking president
until that guy fucks up enough to say
who's going to be the next president.
There should be this,
and again,
we are in some extremely absurd and
weird circumstances at the moment,
but under normal circumstances,
I would,
this is my argument would just be we're
Americans.
This guy got elected through the process
we agreed to and even now I'll say that,
but dude's already fucking again.
That's why I don't want to visit that
because that's a whole fucking four
hours on his own.
Honestly,
I don't,
I don't and I just don't want to even go
there,
but give America a fucking chance.
You know what I mean?
Am I making any sense?
You make four whiskeys now brother,
I make Ma,
I mean what your idea is of America
versus what everybody else's idea.
We need to come some sort of
clarification.
My ideas this,
and I don't mean to interrupt you,
my idea is this,
is that you could be the furthest away
from me.
You could be and I could be way over
there,
but if we were in the same room
somewhere,
we in here we'd find a place that we'd
be like,
all right,
I can live with that.
That's the idea.
We need to figure out what these things
are that we're talking about living
with.
Cause I don't think there's very many of
them that were very agreeing,
disagreeing rather on between the left
and the right.
I think there's a lot of bullshit and I
think it's a lot of what we were talking
about earlier,
this tribal boohoo,
those in the sand,
the people who elected this personal
president right now.
Personal.
Yeah.
Personal president is a personal
president.
This is a,
a very few amount of people.
There's really truly very few people
that are his base.
35% let's keep it real.
Let's keep it real.
Let's keep it fucking room.
Yeah,
cause a lot of bailed on him because
they realize what they voted for was not
what they fuck.
They voted in protest almost a lot of
people.
What's his approval rate?
It's pretty low,
right?
It's fucking the lowest in history.
Is it below and again,
I don't care.
What I'm saying is like a lot of people
said,
fuck the whole system and for a second
they bought into the fact that this guy
actually might think the same when this
guy has spent his entire life fucking
over the working class.
Dude.
In fact,
as much as I'm a,
I would have voted the other direction
for whatever you want to say.
And I again,
I don't give a fuck about Hillary
Clinton.
I'm not telling you the fucking world
would have been saved by Hillary
Clinton.
Fuck that shit.
All right.
That was an entitled motherfucking
person who was only given that fucking
position because for some reason the
people,
the,
the elite of that party thought it was
her turn or something.
I don't know.
That was wrong.
That's just as much their fault for
losing as fucking really shouldn't be
talking about politics.
We're way too stupid already there.
I'm drunk.
What I'm saying is this is that dude is
going to give me a tax break if he's
successful and the guys that actually
voted for him,
the union guys and the fucking working
class guys are going to get fucked over
and at the end of the day they'll be
regretting it as much as like some of
the things he spitting at you and saying
to you or appealing,
he's not that fucking die.
Just like,
Fuck Hillary Clinton.
Fuck Donald Trump.
So you can't be mad at me.
Fuck all of them.
Bernie Sanders was probably our most
logical choice,
but I said,
fuck him because I read his tax pan plan
and he would have fucking raped me.
So it's like there's gotta be,
I don't know,
there's gotta be a whole new system
where the money is.
There has to be a flat tax kind of thing
where every fucking person,
firm corporation.
The problem is too many corporations are
considered legally talking way too much
about politics.
You're freaking me the fuck out.
I can't do this anymore.
Jma.
No,
here.
I understand what you're saying.
I'm just saying this is as a person,
everybody is good politics.
It's like explore the fact that they are
separating and dividing.
You could be a white supremacy,
you could be a black fucking
nationalists,
whatever you want to be there.
Fucking playing on that.
They're playing on that.
These,
this is designed facebook,
all that.
These algorithms are fucking designed to
design.
What do you want to see on your page?
Well,
it's,
remember that Eddie,
you want to see this conversation right
now if everybody will just remember
there or no,
I just think it's been fact of the way
they set up programs.
They set up a program to say what's
going to be most like the guy who
invented facebook,
Mark Zuckerberg get his team,
whoever's his team,
once his,
his,
the people who use his product to be the
happiest they can be with it.
Correct.
I'm assuming.
Here's the direction we're going with
this.
Okay,
so if they look at the things you click
on,
right,
and start developing a pattern in an
algorithm and you click on these
extremely right things or you click on
these extremely left things,
sooner or later,
that's all it's going to be on your
page.
Instagram even changed their fucking
algorithm too.
It's not like what was just last posted,
right?
It's what was last posted that's most
popular and what's appealing to you that
you like.
You know what I mean?
That's where I'm going with this is that
these people are,
they don't understand.
You're being catered to your being fed.
You're being fed ideas.
You want to be fed.
You're not being challenged,
and I've always said this about pr,
even personal,
my art,
if there's not somebody,
it goes back to being in a room by
yourself and why I got stagnated.
We're making a record.
If there's not somebody in that room
somehow to challenge your idea,
your idea isn't the best it can be ever.
I understand what you're saying,
but I think that an alternative point of
view would not be that you're getting
fed.
Would that be?
These algorithms recognize your
interests and whether it's golf or South
American fishing or fucking skydiving,
whatever the fuck you're interested in,
and you start searching for that,
it'll give you things that you can start
just what you're searching.
That's what you're liking and it's,
it's,
it's like you're saying the
conversations that you've best had in
your life or almost alternative opinions
and those start getting filtered out of
your feed and then you're seeing only
your own choices if you choose to go,
why don't you just search out things
that are alternative to what you are
because you're Joe Rogan and you think
like that.
We're talking about the guy who works
fucking 40 hours a week who gets on
facebook and sees what comes down is
feed guy that he's no different than you
or me.
He's listening to you.
I'm sure.
I hope he is.
I hope he's listening to you,
but you hear what I'm saying though,
right?
Like it's not a fucking dismissed idea
that there's guys who got their heads
fucking down just trying to get their
pay check for the next week to get the
mortgage paid and they look up for a
long enough time and maybe facebook is
the one thing they look at a week and
then that's where they get their
information from.
Yeah,
but that's not facebook's fault.
Good.
Facebook creates an algorithm that
reinforce what your injuries be aware.
I understand what you're saying,
but you're saying it also in the way of
like almost like these people are
victims of this.
This is just a simple algorithm
themselves,
but it's not even there,
but they don't even,
they're not even aware of that,
that are victims of themselves and they
are.
I would,
I would save if they're creating their
own universe,
the Europe completely creating,
and this thing is allowing that.
All right,
it's Phil.
You can block whatever you want out if
you don't want to see something you can
create.
And what do they call it in the fucking
and cure rate.
Your own universe.
All right.
And let me tell you something about
resistance.
What I find interesting,
like Keith Olbermann resistance sort of,
sort of,
he's sometimes he,
okay.
He can be a propagandist too.
I'm just kidding.
He's a propagandist too.
Like Michael Moore,
everybody.
There's no true center right now.
That's why I keep coming back to like,
how do you know what's truly true?
Right?
And you want to know where I find truth,
where Comedians,
comedians are the new punk rock
comedians,
truthfully are the people who are
challenging the status quo right now,
whether you're talking about the guy on
Hbo who has the last week tonight show
or the daily show kind of news,
more Americans,
and this is a studied fact,
trust,
comedic news as truth.
Then they do fucking Anderson,
fucking vanderbilt,
cooper,
vanderbilt,
vanderbilt middle name.
He's a vanderbilt.
I'm just throwing it out.
You know,
he's uh,
he's not saying I means he comes from a
very fucking privileged family dog,
you know,
and he represents a very leftist Stan.
It's fakery is what I'm saying.
He's a vanderbilt.
Alright,
that's what I'm saying.
It's like saying he's a rock of fucking
feller.
All right?
And if you don't follow me on that,
he rockefeller,
Rockefeller Not Rockafella.
Oh,
alright.
Rockefeller like the fucking evil.
Fuck that just died.
Oh,
he's a bad guy.
Bad Guy.
All right,
1%.
He's a one percenter.
All right.
Trust that.
Trust the people you're watching that
you trust.
Fox News,
CNN,
all this bullshit and hey,
I might get a lot.
I ain't even been look at twitter
letters later,
so fuck all y'all.
You know what I mean?
I don't look at twitter.
I don't care.
So if you hate what I'm saying,
I'm going to say it anyways.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Is for the greater good.
It's like I'm not telling you I'm left.
I'm right.
I'm saying there's a place in the middle
where we're all fucking people and we
all give a fuck about the same shit like
our lives and our children and our
eating and our fucking having a roof
over our head.
And there's no reason that the richest
fucking planet on Earth can't figure
these fucking problems out.
And the only reason there are problems
because they want there to be problems
and for you to fucking be fighting with
each other.
Your blue or your red choose a crip or
you blow.
This is something that they've chosen.
You cripping or you blood and what
you're doing,
you a blood,
you a crip in this political fucking
environment and you a blue state.
Are you a red state?
My man.
What up?
That's what they doing.
That's what they're doing.
And I know we didn't want to go here and
I know I tried to push it off for like
hours,
but I ain't making it personal about a
president or I think I'm saying there's
a system in place that's fucking keeping
us locked down and it's fucked up and
it's money related.
And if we took money out of it,
we could get more of an honest
politician who would actually give a
fuck about your kid and whether there's
fucking power lines going over your
house or whether you got healthcare over
the,
you got this or that.
Until then,
don't expect me to give a fuck about any
of y'all [inaudible] y'all that buy into
this system and ain't ready to change
something and say that something should
be different.
I think everybody thinks I'm no they
don't because they're not doing shit
about it.
They're not doing shit about it.
Joe,
and I'm not trying to be angry with you.
I love you.
You know I love you brother.
Okay,
but not even,
but all bullshit aside.
What are you doing?
There is no bullshit.
There's no bullshit in this,
so he still shouldn't have been put
aside.
What I'm saying is like,
until people want to realize that
there's an answer and the answer is
pulling corporate and fucking it,
if you can't,
there should be a limit on what you
could donate to.
A fucking politician should be like $100
or $1,000.
Let's make it $1,000 of facebook,
like whatever.
There should be some kind of system that
says it's not fucking the coke fucking
brother pumping billions into a dude.
Whether it's through into ms direction
or fucking with it.
Let's keep it fucking real.
Man.
This is this.
We're getting fucked as a people.
Hey,
I do well.
I'm doing myself a disservice by even
saying shit they gonna come get,
you know,
but I think it,
they're going to tax me more if I,
if I keep the chicken,
if I keep preaching the style of life,
I believe I will pay more taxes.
You really think that they come get you
more to come get me.
You're fucking playing me like I'm dumb.
You're doing the,
you're doing the entertainment thing
right now.
I'm being so real right now,
Joe.
Is that I'm saying they will fucking tax
me more.
Yes.
If the government and the way of life,
I think I should pay more yes.
Than the fucking person who makes
$36,000 a year.
But you know what?
If my accountant smart enough,
I don't have to.
That's honesty.
All right.
I can fucking figure out a way not to
pay as much taxes,
but because I have legally,
even legally or illegally,
I'm talking about totally legally.
I'm talking about what your president is
pulling right now that he's never shown
you his taxes.
All right?
He's pulling the,
it's,
you can easily skirt a lot of taxes if
you have a little bit of information,
like a lot of mother fuckers are dumb
enough to buy cars.
All right?
I don't buy cars.
I'll keep it fucking real with you.
I don't buy a fucking car.
I lease a fucking car.
You know why?
Because it's a fucking basically almost
a hundred percent fucking tax write off.
I guarantee you bill baer bought his
car.
Bill Burr owns his house.
Bill,
I love you.
You're one of the funniest guys ever
play games at tiff.
You fucking lease cars.
You can write off the fucking payments
he was in front of you right now.
I'd be like,
fuck you.
I want to own it.
Good.
Good on it.
And then when you want a new,
I like new cars.
So guess what?
I get a new one every fucking two years.
Christ aggressive with this car thing.
No,
but what I'm saying is there's games
that are played that you're not even
tripping on because they sold you on the
opposite angle.
They got rappers telling you that
fucking owning your shit out right?
It's perfect.
So pay $100,000 for that car,
drive it off black,
get a dent in it.
It's we're fucking 40 grand.
Now.
I understand you're very passionate
about this,
but I could see both sides.
I could see that someone would want to
lease something because it'd be a nice
tax write off,
especially if you're incorporated,
which I'm sure you are and I am,
but I'll see someone who says I left
who's got money,
has the games down because I have the
guys who give me the information just a
lot of guys and they say,
well this off.
No you don't have it.
Being Incorporated doesn't involve being
rich.
I understand that.
Yeah,
but the fleet leasing is Nissan Sentra
doesn't and he could actually
incorporate himself and fucking write
off his fucking $300 or even a month
payment.
Like there's ways to get yo,
there's fucking games that are being
played that people don't fucking know
about is my point.
I understand this is a deep game.
It is going in thank games that are
being played that people don't know
about.
I love you.
And I feel like maybe I'm drawing as
you're looking at me like I'm talking to
stupid shit.
Definitely drunk a little bit,
but we're bust drunk.
Drunk.
I'd be trying to fight you joe.
Well,
let's not do that.
We're friends.
Um,
war porn industry is,
when is it?
When are people gonna be able to
download this now?
Right now,
right?
This second war porn industry's dot com
war point.
It will,
you could probably do this show for
another two hours until we both sober
up,
but I've got to get the fuck outta here.
So war porn industry's dot com you can
get it now.
Good Dad gang.
You know about that,
right?
Do okay.
Can I get in that you're in,
it doesn't pay off to have it hooked up
for you.
You're going to be a,
uh,
a fully licensed.
I just want some to slip in my wife when
I get pulled over by the cops.
You're going to be so,
and you're going to be able to start
your own chapter.
Excellent.
All right.
Is it like an AA thing and,
well,
Jad game.
Okay.
It's good dad gang.
That's what it's called.
My man terminology,
who's on the war porn album?
A rapper started it as a movement for
like,
you know,
inner city kind of Shit to get the good
dad thing going and it's good dag and
he's blowing it up and it's doing really
well.
Good.
And I'm going to get you a bunch of
merch.
Alright,
you can go get it all.
So a good dad gang.com I make not a
goddamn thing off it.
That's a shout out to that fucking whole
floor shout outs.
This is insane.
This is a record number of shout outs.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
I hope you've enjoyed the show as much.
Am I playing myself or something joe?
Because you guys got to get over.
Is this just a good podcast?
It was fun.
Okay,
because you need,
and that's two things.
Either we did a good cop podcasts where
it's like,
oh my God,
everybody has played on some this whole,
it's a good time the whole time.
Just understand that whatever I say and
whatever I do is only intended to
express love for love for humanity.
I don't give a fuck if you voted for
Donald Trump.
Hillary Clinton.
All that political shit.
What I was trying to point out with
that,
and I'll end it on this,
is all of us are not involved in the
game that's being played.
We are victims of the game is being
played in a lot of ways and that doesn't
mean we can't change shoe.
There's,
it's easily changed,
but we're told it's not easy.
We are in a hurricane.
Get the fucking money lady texting
illogical brothers can't donate to a
fucking party.
They can affect the fucking election.
This is a hail storm.
Some of these ideas were good.
I hope you enjoy it.
Good.
Some of them were buzzed,
some of them were fucking fun to listen
to and entertaining.
I hope if you take anything out of it,
it's Jocko willink video.
Good.
That's it.
No,
that's what that's going to get part.
It's good part of this good
inspirational thing,
but dude was already on the Internet.
This was brand new.
I'm asking him,
Jules,
buddy,
I love you.
Give you jewels.
I agree with those.
Those jewels are powerful.
One more war porn video.
Before we go,
let's end it on.
I got to leave.
Be Real.
I've got to eat your shit.
Shut you down bro.
Tell people where to go and gain 40 set
on it.
Joe.
Can't do it cause I got to do ads.
Do the ads.
Why can't I can't.
I can't.
Honestly,
I'm late already.
Everlast I love you.
I love you too.
Yet Jamie,
I love you.
Joe Rogan.