Five four,
three,
two,
boom.
Justin trail,
the jungle.
Look,
you got coconut water.
Are you ready to party?
Oh,
absolutely.
You got to have them just in case.
Oh,
I live off of that stuff.
Um,
so first of all,
congratulations on your belt or fight,
man.
He looked outstanding.
Thank you.
Thanks a lot.
Like it's really like clicking man.
It's really coming together.
Finally,
the muscle memories back and uh,
I met a new camp that's great for my
style training with Rafael Lovato Jr uh,
maybe the best American grappler for
Bjj.
Most accomplished,
maybe.
He's fantastic.
So you're in Oklahoma is or where he's
at.
Oklahoma just moved there and then
December I moved there to train and
interesting train alongside him.
And that's also where water four is
headquartered out of Oklahoma City.
How fucking convenient.
Absolutely.
So now I have the best of both worlds.
My two passions right there.
That's it.
May He's,
he's really good ban.
Rafael Lovato has that pressure style to
that Solow Barrow smashing style.
Very Fun to watch that guy.
The only guy I've ever felt
claustrophobic underneath without a
doubt.
He's just,
I can't,
I can't explain it.
You just cannot get away that smash
pass,
that pressure pass out.
He just melts into you and there's no
escape.
It's like he's melting and he's like
glue.
Yeah.
Salo John G,
the whole,
that whole family of that style of
Jujitsu.
So powerful man.
I've gotten to meet both of them now a
train.
It was Salo and then Shawn Gee was there
and,
uh,
our corner.
So it was pretty awesome for a bill to
our flight.
I was Kinda,
I was Kinda bummed out.
Rafael Lovato,
his last fight,
he stopped and with strikes I was like,
God damn it.
I kicked him in the head.
13 seconds.
Yeah,
it was crazy.
I mean,
it's great to see him succeed and do
well,
but I wanted to see his Jujitsu.
Oh yeah,
absolutely.
Just getting the wheel.
But he's,
man,
he's an animal.
Honestly.
He's one of those guys that is so well
rounded.
And you think he's just one dimensional,
uh,
because of everything he's done in
Jujitsu,
but he grew up kickboxing doing.
Yeah.
His Dad's been a lifelong martial
artist,
a senior.
He's an incredible guy and he's been
taking roughly I'll all around the world
since he was a little boy,
having them train mixed martial arts,
not just Jujitsu his whole life.
And he's fighting bell tours as well,
right?
Yeah.
That was his first fight,
so we fought back to back.
He fought right before me.
I fought right after him.
Oh,
that's nice.
Yeah.
Bella towards making some moves,
man.
You know they're,
they're doing mitre owned versus fader
and they're going to Lorens lark and
just signed with them.
Yeah,
Roy Mcdonald's signed with them.
That's a stable,
now they have a legit state,
especially their 170 pound division.
It's super legit.
Daily Mvp,
Lima,
Koresh Golf.
That's a serious division man.
And now fade or very interesting.
What did you think about the fade or
mitre own thing where they had to pull
out like Mitchell and had to pull out
because of his kidney stone and then
they're going to schedule it again.
Apparently Madison Square Gardens.
So June's paper,
paper view first one for Bella tour or
if he was tough man,
it's tough to get people to buy
something they've been getting for free.
Right.
And uh,
but I think,
I think this card there,
they're stacking it pretty heavily
versus vanderbilt,
which that's where Rafael has been going
down into,
I forget to say it,
but cure tb.
Brazil,
yeah.
Down there.
And was sparring with vander before his
fight is a fight apparently.
Yes.
He sent me a meme of something like,
let's train easy.
Um,
and then releasing like,
yeah,
train easy.
But it's that picture of him and a pride
or something or maybe training where
he's jumping in the air and he's just
coming down with a big hammer fist and
gonna land on you with his feet.
That's a light day.
He's kind of known for that.
Just being a barbarian 24,
seven.
Yeah.
But that's why he's so fun to watch.
And I think what you said and just asked
about what did I think between fader and
Matt Mitrione when they had to pull out,
man,
I,
I flashed back right away to,
do you remember whenever Stephan struve
had to pull out of his fight with Mitch
reone backstage and they were,
he was like blacking out or something,
right?
Yeah.
It's a serious pastiche a couple of
times.
And he was having that heart problem as
well.
Uh,
but Mitch Rune was back there all gloved
up,
already taped up,
had his gloves on,
was hitting Mitts,
and then there were some of the behind
the scenes cameras that caught a moment
where I believe it was Dana coming back
there,
tell him the fight was canceled and
Mitroville and just was,
you know,
cussing up a storm.
No Way.
No,
not at all.
No.
But then all of a sudden you saw it
shift where all of a sudden he was
worried about Stephan and he walked down
there,
went backstage or to his locker room and
man,
he just hugged him and Stephan was
sobbing and Matt Mitrione was just like,
you know,
hey,
it's all right bro.
I know if you could fight,
you would have and all the other stuff.
And so I guess he had passed at least
one or two kidney stones,
the fight week,
a couple days before wins.
Um,
and then the day of the fight they just
started coming back out.
I think he had something like 15 or 20
times.
So man,
uh,
I know all the ladies out there you are,
you're a lot tougher than us,
uh,
giving birth.
But I hear this is the equivalent,
you know,
for the men,
it's passed out any stone.
I doubt it.
Yeah.
That's be like more like passing a
marble three your call,
you know,
maybe even a golf ball.
It seems like it's not even close.
Yeah,
it probably hurts.
It sucks.
Yeah,
it does.
But that 15 or 20 of them,
something like that and that would be
brutal instead of just one or two.
They are a side effect of weight cutting
for a lot of people.
Right.
Like I know Aldo had one and a,
I think some other fighters have had
them too and I think it has to do,
there's some sort of connection with
massive dehydration,
which I'm sure Matt doesn't have to
worry about,
you know,
fighting heavyweight.
It doesn't have to cut the weight like
that.
So I wonder what what caused his,
yeah,
I don't know.
But yeah,
exactly.
I mean you're putting some your kidneys
through so much when you're cutting
weight,
especially those extreme weight cuts.
Yeah,
I'm lucky.
I'm a heavy weight,
very fortunate dude.
Fuck all that man.
Yeah.
Like what do you walk around at?
Like what's your,
when you're in shape,
like you're in shape right now.
I weigh two 48 that's a good size man.
Right to 45 don't you think they think
that that to 40 numbers,
like the right number for heavyweights.
They feel like not,
I don't know who they are,
but it was just talking
shit.
Yeah.
They think that,
um,
the,
the conventional wisdom is when you get
into to sixties and above and you know,
like above two 50 that there's,
there's a point of diminishing returns
where you're,
you're carrying around so much mass,
you can't really perform as well.
But a 240 pound guy is so big and so
strong that you can handle a 265 pound
guy,
but you have more endurance and it's
just a better wait.
I totally agree with that.
I mean,
when I was living at the Olympic
training center in wrestling there,
the weight class was to 64.5 or 120
kilos and we always try to stay above it
and then cut for the,
to make weight because wrestling,
I mean being the single sport or
wrestling,
like you need that weight,
it's only six minute match.
Um,
and then the new Greco Roman rules,
I mean you get three breaks in between a
two period round.
Um,
and so you're getting that weight.
You need it to throw the guy around when
it comes to them and May and you're
adding in that Eh,
what is anaerobic and aerobic strength
and cardio and everything else.
You need it all.
And so,
yeah,
my first two fights back,
I was coming in heavier,
um,
in men to drop a little bit.
I felt a lot,
lot better.
My conditioning was,
was on point.
I wasn't rushing.
I'd put in the time,
the effort and everything else and get
my cardio good.
My Diet really Rafael's got an awesome
strength coach.
His name is Lucia is tyree.
Now he's my guy named from green strings
and man,
he just got us on this warrior kind of
lifestyle.
It's not about a program or fight camp
and you getting ready then it's about,
hey,
let's just live this in day in and day
out.
Eat the right food,
real food,
put real nutrition in your body.
Real strength,
kind of like the honest stuff,
you know,
the kettle bells,
everything else.
And I had never done that before.
So,
uh,
this was a real shift in my training
and,
uh,
it paid off.
So he works with your nutrition as well?
Yeah.
And what kind of changes that he made
for that
man?
Uh,
for me,
I think that,
uh,
it's about maturing too.
I mean,
the five years I took off,
um,
and before that I was 19 fighting
professionally until I was 23,
24.
Um,
and I was young and dumb.
I was tilt with addictions and
depression,
other stuff.
And Man,
I would,
I would tighten everything up during
fight camp,
but before a fight coming up,
I'd eat whatever.
Um,
and this has just been,
you know,
having just tons of salads,
um,
eating meat,
veggies,
fruits,
just fueling your body constantly.
Um,
and so that's just been something really
good for me.
I,
I have CELIAC,
so I can't eat the breads,
the grains.
Yeah.
I can't eat wheat,
barley,
rye,
huge guy to have celiacs.
That's interesting.
And what did they find out when you were
really young?
Uh,
no.
I found out,
so I had gone through the opiate
addictions and at six years of that that
I had an ulcer in my stomach.
And so,
uh,
but I noticed that during that time,
anytime I would eat wheat,
wheat bread with breakfast,
that I would get a nauseous.
I would,
uh,
I would
time.
Yeah.
So did you have it before or did you get
it because of the ulcer?
Um,
I think that probably triggered
something.
Um,
the opiate addiction and everything
else.
Then when I went to Congo,
it really got bad and I didn't know what
it was.
And then whenever I got back,
I mean having the malaria three times
didn't gay fever,
blackwater fever,
um,
all sorts of intestinal parasites and
bacteria is,
um,
when I got back here,
I was just wrecked in.
So my doctor did some tests on me and I
was like,
man,
you have,
you weren't just any more gluten
intolerant.
Now you have full blown Celiac and here
at the top of the chart.
So you used to be gluten intolerant?
Yeah.
And then it became celiac top of the
charts.
Now do you think anything has connection
to,
for people who have never heard of you
before,
you live in the Congo for long stretches
of time working with the pygmies and
digging wells and you've caught malaria,
they're on two separate occasions,
but you've got it three times cause it
reoccurred on you.
Right.
Do you think that that might have
compromised your immune system and
contributed to this CELIAC's disease?
Absolutely.
They say about that.
My immune system was just shot and so
that's been,
I mean so the five,
I mean before that,
the drug addictions,
that took a toll on my body.
Then going to the Congo,
having the malaria,
having other things,
it's,
it's wrecked my body and so now over the
last three years,
and that's why I am so thankful for a
guy like Raphael modeling how to live
this lifestyle just day in and day out.
Lucius there to guide us because I
needed that.
I really needed to rebuild my health
from the ground up.
Right.
And to stay consistent with that.
It's like when the fights over maybe
indulge for like one meal but then get
right back on the grind.
And so it's been,
yeah,
really,
really great for me to live it out and
to really,
I dunno,
just felt like I'm finally healthy
again.
That's awesome man.
That's amazing.
You just come back after taking five
years off and essentially not even
working out at all.
And now,
you know,
I mean,
you look good in the first fight,
but man,
your last fight,
you just really look tuned up.
Yeah.
Thank you.
It was awesome.
I appreciate that.
Now when you,
you say that you have celiacs,
so they're,
they're adjusting your diet accordingly.
Like what?
Like I'm really big into like fat based
diets these days.
Are you doing something like that or are
you on a different kind of
carbohydrates?
Like how you,
um,
how are they monitoring it?
I'm definitely getting a lot more,
uh,
a lot more like coconut oils and the
grass fed butters and all of that too,
to have a high fat content with every
single meal,
breakfast,
lunch,
and dinner.
I was still dropping weight.
And so that,
I mean this is kind of all new for me
where it's like me and I'm getting in a
lot of fruits,
veggies,
carbs and mostly fats,
fats and proteins.
Then fruits and vegetables.
And then probably carbs.
Carbs are in fruits and vegetables,
but sort of they plan your meals out for
you.
Do you have like one of those?
I have a meal prep place and a Okc
provision kitchen and it's pretty
awesome because they,
um,
they have their own farm.
Everything's organic,
locally grown.
And so yeah,
I just go in there and they're able to
help me out in Luke,
works with them and Lucius helps me know
what I need to tell them to eat.
And so it's just for me,
man,
I,
I mean,
being a heavyweight,
um,
a lot of times we haven't had to take a,
a diet too strict.
And other times I would during fight
camp,
but I would just do what I thought was
right and what was fueling my body was
feeling and performance for performance.
Yeah.
But now it's just like all around health
and performance.
Like,
I need to perform like a machine,
like a professional athlete.
I need,
I need to fuel my body like that.
And so having this team of people that
are around and I think that's why the
move to Oklahoma City before coming
back,
having the five years off,
then come in and uh,
being a Dallas Fort Worth and trying to
rush back.
Then moving to Colorado,
trying to get the camp there,
train at six or seven different gyms,
you know,
cross train.
Um,
it wasn't really all clicking but now
being in Oklahoma City,
there's water right there.
There's Raphael's team,
which he has a worldclass guys all
around him.
He's got the nutritionist and the right
restaurants and places have in place to
where now I can just focus on training
and then I get to,
in the meantime their break time,
I get to share the story of why I'm back
to fighting.
That's amazing.
Now this a meal prep place,
do you give them like,
Hey,
I would like my food to be,
you know,
75% this 25% that this is the
carbohydrate quantity.
I'm looking forward.
This is the amount of protein.
So how to calories basically.
And I don't know exactly,
um,
I need to have a better like input into
it.
But man,
they've just really said this is what he
needs here in fight camp.
And then I was focused on training and
so it was really good though because I'm
getting,
you know,
a bunch of coconut oil and Avocados and
everything else all throughout the day
to make sure I'm having a high fat
content.
And how many times do you eat in a day?
Three to five,
three big meals.
If,
uh,
if I'm not able,
if I'm just swamped and busy,
but then if I have time to make sure I'm
feeling about him eating five meals.
So are you working out twice a day or
like how you two to three times a day?
Five to six days a week?
Yeah.
Wow.
Damn.
So back in the heat of things.
Yeah,
hundred percent Rafael's a machine
trying to keep up with him,
but feeding off that energy.
Um,
it's been really great.
I mean,
cause it's,
I've been around a lot of guys in the
sport and uh,
I,
I didn't even expect to talk this much
about him,
but it's uh,
it's been really encouraging.
I've been around Kenny Monday,
Kendall Cross,
Cael Sanderson,
all these Olympic gold medalist and it's
been great cause they were,
my coach is pouring into me.
But here's a guy that's the best at his
craft.
That's Worldclass,
that's world champ.
And he's completely obsessed with every
aspect of MMA.
And being able to see that and feed off
of it has been incredibly encouraging
for me.
So him and I both were like,
hey man,
like the stars are aligning.
This is destiny.
You and me both.
We're going to go get those Bella tore
straps,
world champs.
Let's do that first unless do that
quick.
What does he weigh?
Many,
he walks around it probably to 10 to 15
maybe to 20.
And what's he finding a man?
He cuts all the way down to one 85.
So he's the biggest one.
85 were I've ever trained,
was crying and he feels like he's 400
men.
I mean,
Brendan and I were just talking about
this yesterday.
Um,
but being under Shane Carwyn and worst
case scenario where he's having you
mounted,
I mean it just,
Eh,
you hated life,
big Shane on your shore.
Um,
but there's something so,
uh,
demoralizing,
but then at the same time encouraging
because a raphael is doing that and
making you feel claustrophobic,
like a 400 pound gorillas on top of you,
um,
or 600 pound whatever.
And then,
but he's also coaching you,
telling you how you can do that to
somebody else.
And so at the end of it,
you know,
he's,
he's shown you how to do exactly what
he's doing.
So he's a fantastic coach and you don't
always see that from the best athletes.
Um,
sometimes they're incredibly talented
and great at their craft,
but explaining it,
you're like,
okay,
now explain it to me again or show me
how to do it.
Like here I'm showing you like,
just watch,
you know.
But he can,
he can tell you every little detail,
every little inch.
Well,
that's probably has a lot to do with a
solow who barrow lineage too.
You know,
that's very,
very technical school and they're really
involved.
Solid is really involved in the history
of all the,
the different techniques and you know,
where they came from.
And now why did he move to Oklahoma
City?
Why is he down there?
Uh,
I actually,
that's where he's from.
So I think whenever he was like six,
seven,
eight years old,
he moved from Chicago there.
Um,
I watched a documentary on flow
grappling.
That's how I even got Ahold of Rafael is
knew I was moving to Oklahoma City.
I'm like,
who's there to train with a moving there
for water for and fight for the
forgotten.
Um,
and I saw that documentary incredibly
inspirational shows the whole lineage of
whom trained with Sahlu and Shawn g and
how he went to Brazil to train with
them,
live with them.
And they came up to Toledo,
Ohio.
At first.
He went there and they were living in
basically like this little apartment
that was freezing inside and the Toledo
a winters.
And they're having to put their gies
over the heater to try to warm him up
after every training session to get back
in there and do it again.
And that's some of their best training
matches were in the living room on the
mat that they would throw out there
right in front of the couch.
And so it was just cool to see how these
guys,
where they were,
where they came from and what they've
done now.
It's like truly for me,
inspiring cause that's what I want to do
now.
No,
I mean that's the best way to do it,
right.
To just be with the elite of the elite
and that one particular discipline,
at least resilient Jujitsu and you can
get so much out of that.
Especially coming from your background
as a wrestler.
You know,
I was super impressed with your arm
triangle too,
man.
Thanks clamped down on that.
A head and arm choke.
That was nice.
Yeah.
Thanks a lot.
No,
I think it's a great style because I'm
coming in with a wrestling background of
when a couple national championships
there and then to come in with Raphael
once I put a guy down,
now I need to finish them.
And it surprised me Lovato was a
wrestling cause he's actually got some
good stuff that he does,
but now I'm gonna be able to show him
that and he showed me his world and then
we're growing together as boxing.
That's so good,
dude.
That's so good.
It's so interesting too because there's
very few real submission artists today
in the heavyweight division,
you know,
it used to be fade or when he was in his
prime was submission artists.
Of course.
No,
was the premiere submission artists,
Frank Mir,
one of the all time greats for sure.
And in terms of his accomplishments as a
submission artist,
but there's not a whole lot of that
today.
You know,
you see knockouts and stuff,
especially in the UFC,
you don't see a whole lot of
submissions.
Right.
Except for doom,
you know,
if we're doing can still submit people
and won the title off of cane that way.
Yeah.
So,
so I'm,
I'm excited because statistically I
think in my fights,
if I've put it on the ground,
I've already finished it.
But now having that guy with me coaching
through,
um,
I heard them in the fight during the
fight,
I'm doing this,
I'm doing that and he's just telling me
these little adjustments to me right
next to you while you were,
he was across the cage where he's,
he's a good coach and I had the whole
camp to sit there and listen to him
while he was off to the side.
He's yelling at me.
[inaudible] yeah,
Nice.
Trying to do that.
And we used to do that at grudge
training center in Colorado.
We would,
uh,
turn up the music,
we'd blast it,
uh,
during sparring.
And then we have our cornerman the off
to the side and they're hollering and
yelling that we were able to start
trying to pick their voices out with
like a distraction with loud music going
on,
just like in the fight.
So that way if there's a huge crowd all
yelling out different stuff,
you're able to tune into the voices you
need to hear who's idea was that?
Trevor's yeah,
Trevor's Trevor Whitman.
Yeah,
he's smart.
Very smart,
very smart.
Now how are you balancing out your full
time training now that you're moving up
in the rankings and Bella Tor and you
know you are,
you're being more and more successful,
but you're also doing this for a cause
and for people don't know you are doing
this for your pygmy family,
these people that you've sort of become
a part of their world and you've lived
there for many,
many months at a time and you,
you go back and forth to help build
water wells with a water four and your
organization fight for the forgotten and
how are you balancing that out with
being a professional fighter and trying
to compete and perform at your very
best?
Yeah,
that,
that's been a learning process without a
doubt.
But now it's trying to find ways to set
the right boundaries and in a way to
protect my training schedule.
At first I was just saying yes to
basically everything.
Um,
and that made it really tough for my
first two fights back,
uh,
where I felt rushed.
I didn't feel like the muscle memory was
clicking in between every training
session or I'd be late to training
sessions doing the interview or trying
to talk to somebody or trying to tell
people the story or I would have to
leave early to go do it.
Now it's like,
it's been really great to move to
Oklahoma City,
have water for there to protect my
training schedule.
And training comes first because if I
can keep going up in the ranks,
if I can get a world championship under
my belt or a few,
you know,
I'll have a bigger platform to stand on
to tell,
you know,
have the bigger microphone,
bigger platform to be able to continue
to tell this story.
And so yeah,
we have a team about 10,
12 people at water four,
they've all rallied around it.
They're trying to take stuff off my
plate,
um,
and be able to help fill in my schedule,
but making sure I'm getting enough time
to get in the training,
get in the rest and man,
just eight,
nine weeks of that before this last
fight,
it,
it truly paid off.
It felt like there was a whole team
around making sure that going into this
fight everything was exactly the way it
should be.
And that's how I felt too.
I mean,
uh,
I have a little highlight clip with a
fight,
but I mean the,
the crowd was just,
uh,
eh,
it was overwhelming and incredibly good
way where it like felt I could feel the
energy.
I could hear everybody there.
I grown up in Dallas,
fort worth water for and fight for the
forgotten is based and Lovato's is out
of Oklahoma City.
Um,
and everyone met up in the middle on the
border at this big casino called
Windstar and it was just awesome going
in there and having everyone rally
around.
I don't feel like me,
I mean me too,
but rally round fight for the forgotten
what I'm fighting for.
Yeah.
And then the post fight interview.
I mean that's,
that's what I'm living for now.
That's what I'm fighting for,
so I can talk.
And how supportive has belt or been
about all this?
Oh Man.
Incredibly supportive.
It's blown me away.
I mean,
I get to,
I get to talk about it and everything.
So it's been,
it's been awesome.
There's Raphael up at top left big Josh
Copeland to the right.
Um,
and yeah,
I get to put fight for the forgotten all
over my stuff.
No,
I've had that.
But uh,
yeah,
it's been really great.
Yeah.
Added anything to it.
Um,
Dell,
I had the cross in net.
I did add the vikings below it,
but here I had gotten a lateral job
before and then I was able to hit a
belly to back thinks.
Ooh.
I like how you call it Sioux play.
Yeah.
And there's the arms.
Nice.
So now where do they have you in the
rankings?
And I mean,
they're,
they're heavyweight division is in the
deepest in the world,
right?
Who's there?
Heavyweight champion.
Uh,
well,
that,
that was Vitaly Medecav.
But he's been kind of,
you know,
in a struggle with,
yeah.
Been inactive.
Here's the part that I,
I really like.
I don't know if we can turn on,
you were kinda getting your feet
underneath you,
remembering how it went in all seem to
come together tonight.
Is that how it felt?
Yeah,
I definitely,
I got,
I got a lot of room to improve,
a lot of work to do,
but yes,
it felt like the muscle memory was back.
I'm in that camp that is so great for my
style with Rafael Lovato junior and the
team big Josh Copeland.
And you're so blessed,
encouraged,
excited to be here.
The little dance I was doing in here.
Hope they didn't look cocky or arrogant.
That was my dance.
But we do out in the forest.
I just love them to be able to come in
here and fight through.
Most people are lucky enough to have one
tribe.
You have to not only a family Congo,
apparently here they were very much
behind you.
How did it feel to win in front of them
from water for Oklahoma City Eco
Survivor?
I'm just slow.
Uh,
lucky.
So fortunate jumped behind this because
I love to fight.
I love to be here and compete,
but it's even better to fight for people
and so to know that fighting in here,
getting a choke out,
I'm going to go into Congo and knock out
the world's water crisis.
Moving forward.
You said you have a lot of room to grow,
but with performances like that,
people are thinking about you in a wide
open heavyweight division.
What's next for you?
Well,
I'm coming for that balance.
It's going to come and just might take a
little bit of time to get there.
I'm still getting my feet under me.
I had five years,
two months where I did zero training and
so I'm excited to get back in there.
Keep my way up.
I got to earn it.
But I have,
I think more of a reason,
a purpose of passion to be in here.
And so I'm just so thankful for everyone
that's got behind us.
Eco Survivor right here is donating 50%
of their profits of their entire brand
to come to the water wells in the Congo
for water,
for her fight,
for the forgotten.
Thank you guys for getting behind us.
Before you go.
You owe soccer pygmy family.
Would he have to say to them to pick a
hot pin on the Gulama Goo not Kupenda
sign.
Now want him to sign a Santi sign a
Doobie Django?
Man,
I just,
I love him so much.
I was saying I'm in here.
I'm in here because I love you.
That's what I'm in here.
I'm gonna Google the Google.
We are one.
We are not different and so a sequel
meaningi it's been many,
many days.
I can't wait to come back and see you
guys very,
very soon and drill some more.
Well,
so the big pig meat,
that's a crazy platform man.
To be able to do that on tv like that in
front of,
I mean who knows how many millions of
people watch too.
I think that came to the 1.1 or 1.2 is
the headline.
That was a Marlos,
Conan and Julia Bud for that,
uh,
inaugural featherweight,
I believe,
or a world title.
Do you feel like Bella towards getting
more respect now?
Like it's,
uh,
it's becoming more of a,
like for a while it was looked at as
sort of a,
an also ran,
you know,
but I think like now with the lineups
getting stronger and stronger,
it seems like,
uh,
the organization is growing and
notoriety.
Yeah,
I believe so.
And um,
I mean,
I think it's healthy.
It's very important.
I think it's good for everybody.
Yeah,
exactly.
And,
and,
and great for the fighters.
My bosses,
my disagree right.
At the UFC,
but I really think I actually,
I don't think they would.
I think they'd probably agree.
I think it's important.
It's important to have competition.
It's good.
It's good for everybody.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And so,
yeah,
I think Bader just came over.
Yup.
Um,
Phil Davis,
Davis is the,
is the light heavyweight champion now.
Yep,
absolutely.
So you don't really have a heavyweight
champion?
Is that what's going on?
Are they stripped fatale Melnikov of it
because he's fighting over his contract.
Allowed them to fight and fight nights
or efn over in Russia.
I went over there,
Corner Josh against fatale.
Um,
and so he just hasn't come back and he
just has,
I think he's making money in Russia and
fighting there and,
uh,
they're,
they're kind of been in a standoff and
he can come back and fight,
but he's been stripped of his belt.
Um,
and now I think they're,
you know,
Scott's a smart guy,
so it was rich.
Um,
they're putting something together for
the heavyweights and uh,
yeah,
the fade or Matt Mitrione fight,
that's going to be exciting to watch for
a title though,
right?
But is that a three rounder?
Yes.
Three,
three fives.
So when are they gonna try to have a
heavyweight title?
I think it's coming up pretty soon,
so I think probably in the next six
months.
Where,
I mean,
within that next three months now
looking at yourself and your own
development and growth,
how far away do you feel like you are
from that fighting for that?
Me,
I,
I want it now.
I want to take that now,
but,
uh,
I think that realistically being smart,
strategic,
get another couple of wins under my
belt,
some good wins or I get to go in there
and,
and really show to myself,
to Bella torn one,
I need to earn it and to um,
I need to get a couple more real
impressive wins under my belt.
Um,
and yeah,
I think,
I think I know who I am as a fighter and
I can hang with those guys.
It's just I need to to build back cause
it's,
it was a long time off.
Yeah.
It was a long time off and then train
week.
Great guys.
I think in the next two or three fights
I'll really start taking big steps up
and then,
um,
after that,
maybe in the next two,
three years I'll have that belt.
Yeah.
They have,
uh,
their division is interesting.
Now rampage is going to heavyweight too,
right?
Yeah,
I think,
uh,
I think it's a catch weight against King
Mo.
Um,
I think that might be this next Friday
or Saturday.
So yeah,
they're fighting in Chicago.
Yeah.
I've been reading shit.
Talking online.
Yeah.
They keep going back and forth with the
chemo,
keeps trying to fat Shayma a rampage and
he's coming back.
So I love that expression.
It's so silly.
And one of his fighters fat shaming when
they're about to beat the fuck out of
each other.
So these lanterns you've brought me,
first of all,
thank you.
Second of all,
what is the deal with these bad boys?
So this is the first product that they
had developed.
Um,
and it's ECO survivor.
They're also out of Oklahoma City.
So this is the common of,
is donating 50% of their money,
their profits to waterfall.
Absolutely.
And so all the packaging,
this is old packaging,
but know the water.
Four is the company that's building
these wells in the Congo for the pygmies
and is the organization that you work
closely with.
And so they started eco survivor so that
it could be basically an empowerment
mechanism on all the,
all the packaging.
It's going to have a picture of me,
a picture of the wells,
a picture of the pygmies.
Um,
and we're going to tell the story.
And when they go to eco survivor.com,
which I think just launched looks great.
You would almost think it's a nonprofit
website because they're highlighting the
cause so much.
But they were talking about how we make
it sustainable there,
empower them with sustainable business
and they're like,
hey,
we want to,
we want to do that here.
They were already very successful
company,
the parent company's Jesco Products
Company and they make a,
they do licensing things,
lights and all sorts of things for
general electric and a energizer and
Philips.
I mean they have 3000 products on the
market,
so they are incredible.
Um,
yeah,
so there's,
would you drink dirty water?
Neilia a billion people have no choice.
This is a,
this is great man.
Oops.
I just turned it on accidentally.
And so they're,
they're rugged.
They are.
Um,
I mean I,
I've,
I've done impact testing where I'm
jumping up and down on top of these now.
Yeah.
There you go.
Put it down,
stand on it.
You'll be fine.
I mean my,
my heavyweight but gets on top of it and
jumps around and to this incredible,
right.
So,
I mean our team is using this in the
Congo.
There you go.
Look at that balance.
You are what's at the Scorpion?
I don't know what it is.
I don't know.
Pay Attention.
I just do what they tell me to do.
That's amazing man.
That's crazy.
You could stand on this thing.
I've done that with,
I won't name any names of the
competitors,
but whenever I start to stand on the
other ones,
the bulbs crush and break and uh,
yeah.
So this right here though,
it's got karabiners.
Our guys were using this to one 30 in
the morning,
maybe a week ago.
They put it up on the tripods,
um,
and then they're able to just go to
work.
Uh,
so it's really great.
That was the glass made out of,
how's the of the glass supporting me?
That part actually.
So I don't,
I do know this,
that a dome structure,
uh,
is the strongest thing out there.
It's plastic.
Yeah,
it is.
It is a plastic,
which is a super strong plot,
super strong plastic.
It's led light and it's got a 360 degree
Omni directional lighting,
which basically just means it goes all
around and there's no blind spots with
the light for the most part.
And then on it's killer man.
Yeah.
And then so from there we're going to do
flashlights,
headlamps,
a Bluetooth Speakers,
bluetooth speakers that have battery
packs in them than just battery packs.
Then we're doing walkie talkies,
walkie talkies that have battery packs
in them.
No Shit.
Yeah.
And so we're doing it to where I,
the everyday adventure can be part of
it.
Um,
but,
but we're doing it so that way this
stuff's going to last for a team in the
Congo.
And then when people are buying it here,
they know that 50% of their purchase or
the profits from the purchase are going
straight to the cause.
That's awesome,
man.
Yeah man.
I've heard of companies doing,
you know,
I love it when a company gives 1% 2% 5%
10% but I never heard of a company.
I mean they're,
they're,
they're running this better than a lot
of nonprofits are.
Percent of the profits away.
No,
that's insane.
That's incredibly generous.
That's awesome man.
One more time.
The company's called ECO survivor.
And what does their website,
Eco survivor.com and it's Kinda cool
Jamie,
if you can pull that up.
Uh,
even if you scroll down you,
so two days ago was world water day.
Oh yeah.
And right on their makeup,
make a donation,
goes right to our page,
make a purchase.
You can buy the lanterns right now.
We have a lot more coming out soon.
So right now it's just the lanterns
headlamps coming out because I use
those.
Yeah.
Hopefully I'll get you some.
I want to thank you so much.
Um,
and then it shows where her in the next
three years and being built.
Yeah.
Wow,
that's so cool.
And then down a little bit shows the
statistics.
Um,
and it just shows,
I mean,
the average water walk for instance,
is 3.75 miles round trip for a woman to
just go collect.
Oftentimes dirty most of the times,
dirty water and heavy,
heavy,
44 pounds.
It's a 20 liters,
five gallons.
Most people have no idea how hard it is
to carry 40 pounds.
I well think about one of those
kettlebells,
right?
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
and then a lot of times the women,
the women do two at a time and the
children do one.
And so these little can't go to school
cause they and that water walk,
but they are not doing that one time a
day.
They're doing it two and three times a
day because they're,
their household needs more than just
five gallons of water.
And so a lot of times the girls can't be
sent to school or the kids can't read.
They have to pick one of the kids that
can go to school.
So the other ones can go collect water
all day.
I think it's over a billion days each
year,
um,
workdays that are lost just because of
the women that have to go do the water
walks over a billion workdays.
And there you,
you,
and if people have never seen any of the
episodes that Justin was on before,
please watch the last ones a,
if you get a chance,
it'll,
you'll catch up more.
To what you've gone through,
what some of these people have gone
through,
the kind of parasites these people get
from this water and how important it
says for you and how much growth and
progress has been over the past few
years of your efforts down there.
Yeah.
Well thank you so much.
It's,
it's been incredible.
I,
emily was telling me,
uh,
my wife,
coming here that wow,
this was over four years ago when you
were on Joe show the first time and we
hadn't drilled one single well,
that's crazy.
I had just been there.
Um,
Andy Bo had happened,
the one and a half year old boy that had
passed away.
I held his lifeless body and buried them
and just did a,
it ripped me open,
you know,
tore my heart apart like you would
anyone like it would anyone.
But it was just a rude awakening to the
water crisis that,
that there's 800 kids every day die just
because of diarrhea,
just like literally die from diarrhea.
And then 2000,
350,
2000,
350 die of the malnutrition that
diarrhea causes.
So if you're in an area that doesn't
have access to clean water,
there's probably not an abundance of
food around you.
But even the food that you do get,
you're eating it and it goes right
through you because you have diarrhea,
you don't absorb any of the nutrients.
And so that's over 3000 just because of
that.
And then that's not counting a lot of
the sicknesses and everything else,
typhoid,
Nikolai.
And so that's 1.5 million deaths a year
of children under the age of five,
1.5 million.
All of them are preventable.
And so like I truly believe man,
like we have,
we've found something really special at
water four and others,
other organizations that I'm sure are
doing it in different spaces.
But I feel like us,
we are doing it in a way that we put the
tools in the hands of the people that
need it the most.
The people in the community,
I mean our teams,
18 people and we've first year that I
was there.
So in the last five years,
I've lived there for about two years,
back and forth,
one once,
one year at one time.
But then Ida was able to help drill and
train them for the first 13 wells.
The year I was stepping back,
I was nervous,
you know,
I'm not going to be there.
I can't micromanage.
These guys are,
I can't watch him.
Mccain encourage them,
you know,
uh,
I don't want to micromanage anyone,
but I can't be there to do the work.
But then they're able to do 20 wells the
year without me.
The next year.
The last year they did 29 so we're up to
I think 62 wells,
um,
that they've drilled for themselves and
their own community.
And that's,
our guys have 18 but water four has 375
and they drilled 690 water wells last
year alone.
Wow.
And that served.
So those are 375 people in the continent
of Africa that live in 16 African
nations.
And they were able to give 172,000
people clean water for the first time in
their lives.
And so,
um,
man,
we can,
we can knock this water crisis out in
our lifetime if that's what we do,
if we give them the solution.
That's incredible.
That's,
that's amazing progress.
And just a few years,
yeah,
it's been a,
it's blown me away,
but so talk to me about how belt or is
helping and how they're getting behind
this.
Well,
that's what really sold me with,
I mean,
I had offers from most places when I
was,
when I came back and,
uh,
but,
but when I sat down with Scott and,
um,
and I was writing the book,
uh,
with Loretta and went out to eat with
them in Santa Monica and he was just
like,
hey,
like we want to give you a chance to
really tell your story.
Like you need to fight.
You got to prove it.
Like you have to have that,
that hard work and skill and talent
behind you.
You have to be able to perform.
But if you can do that,
we're going to rally around you.
Um,
they want to rally around their fighters
that,
that put in the time,
the effort that they can produce
results.
But,
um,
it was really encouraging to hear that.
And then I was bummed out the first two
fights.
I mean,
I won,
but I didn't win decisively like I
wanted to.
So to get this last fight underneath me
where really performed well,
um,
and,
and was pretty dominant like a,
I think they know that I can fight and
uh,
and I know I can fight.
And so now we can do this in a way that
man,
when I win,
literally wells are being drilled every
single time.
And so eco survivor is helping me drill
several wells after this last one.
That's a chronicle.
Yeah.
Now how do you balance out your training
when you're,
when you're visiting the Congo and
staying there?
Yeah,
so a tough thing is,
so I kind of shared a little bit of our
model and how we give the tools for the
people,
um,
in the community.
So my travel schedule,
it's uh,
it's been a hard pill to swallow,
but I think it's the most strategic
thing where I'm only going to go once a
year now.
Um,
I'm going to go once a year because I
need to be here training.
Um,
that's my,
uh,
at first I thought I was the one that
that made this thing go.
But really it's,
it's,
it's our guys in the field,
they're the engine and I was maybe the
spark plug that,
that,
that kind of started up something and
now I get to go back and be the
encourager or to fuel and back up.
Um,
but they're the ones doing the work and
so I'm only going to go once a year.
I'll probably fight in June or July.
I was talking with Bella tour and then
right after that we're starting up a
soap production facility in Congo with
our guys is going to start another eight
to 10 jobs because we go in and we teach
the wash program.
So we need,
uh,
we need them to start making soap for
themselves because right now the only
thing I've ever seen available is car
washing soap that's packed full of
chemicals from China or India and they
have all the Ross themselves with
carwash.
I did while I was there for the year and
my skin would be raw afterwards cause
there was nothing else available.
I mean I took soap with me,
but when I was there for a full year,
I mean it only lasted for the first
month maybe.
So the rest of the time I was using this
car washing soap,
that man,
it,
it's rough on your body.
And so we are partnering with a company
called Pasha soap there at all the whole
foods and they have a sister company,
uh,
a Mozzie there at target.
And though those guys go around and they
start up,
so production facilities in the
developing nation to give jobs.
So is it possible that that could become
an industry for the people in the Congo
where they can start selling their soul
and then,
you know,
maybe eco survivor could sell it on
their website as well?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Or start up a new,
yeah,
that other company.
Yeah.
Pocho which has been great to us.
They actually,
uh,
kind of cool story that the founder of
[inaudible] was listening to this
podcast whenever he had the dreams to
start it up.
And he was actually being like kind of
a,
I think it was a janitor at night
through the night shift.
And he was listening to this and he had
the dreams to start up Pocho he helped
us get our five o one c three with a
fight for the forgotten holy shit.
So after my first time being on the
show,
he reached out to me and he had just
started up Pasha.
And so he helped me get fight for the
forgotten started up.
His name's Andrew Verbus.
Wow.
Incredible guy.
But the inspiration you got from here to
do something,
make a difference.
Now he's in all the whole foods.
He's about to be in target.
Um,
and he's coming with me this next trip.
We're actually,
he might not come because we don't
really take volunteers now.
We just empower the locals.
But we're going to start up that soap
production facility and it's going to
start eight to 10 new jobs will go into
schools and t because last year our team
spent 301 days teaching the wash
program.
So teaching water and sanitation and
hygiene,
helping them dig latrines,
helping them know the importance of
clean hands.
So we set up,
set up outside the latrines,
a hand washing station,
which is called a tippy tap.
So they have a clean jug of water,
they have a bar soap,
they step on a stick in a rope and it
tilts this jug over and they're able to
wash their hands right there.
But then they only had that car washing
soap.
So now we're going to meet another need,
start up the soap production.
They have the eucalyptus trees there,
the palm oil,
the Avocados.
I mean,
just whatever we need with lemon grass,
um,
whatever we need to make the soap with.
Which that's not my specialty,
but I know all the raw materials are
there.
What does this company,
again,
how do people find out about this
company?
[inaudible]
P,
a,
c h,
a Pacha soap.
And you can go,
I think in any auction.com I think it's
just soap.com/ soap.com but then they're
incredible,
man.
They're in whole foods already in whole
foods.
They just started,
no,
no.
They've been there a few years ago.
A few years now.
Fill your Easter basket.
But yeah,
but you're saying this is all within the
last few years,
right?
Oh yeah.
Within the last few years.
Last four or five years.
It's amazing.
So it's patches,
soap.com yep.
[inaudible] hiring.
Look at that.
There you go.
Yup.
Purchase spread.
Goodness.
Yeah.
Wow.
And so they do a buy one,
give one,
but they do it in the right way because
they're the social entrepreneurship of
like you buy one and then here,
and we give one and a developing nation
sounds really good.
It's got the right heart,
good intentions,
but it can be very dangerous if it's
distributed in the wrong way.
So there buy one give one actually
creates jobs in the developing nation
than they make it.
And then they sell it and they're able
to give it that way to their community
instead of some of the charities.
Um,
you buy something here and you go give
it over there.
And then when they go,
they go with huge amounts and they say
if they're dropping off shoes or clothes
or whatever,
the local people that have a shoe store
go out of business.
Whenever you bring in containers and
containers of,
of shoes and where the guy that's
repairing the shoes,
the cobbler,
you know,
the one that's making,
she was there.
So you can't just go into the community
and give it out.
Actually watched a documentary recently
called Poverty Inc man.
It was powerful showing how,
how charity hurts or how,
there's also a great book out called
when helping hurts and it talks about
hey charities,
awesome in and when it's absolutely
needed,
but it's very dangerous if you use it in
the wrong way,
you can cripple a community.
And so how do we empower the local
communities with a hand massage,
pull the community by,
by giving them something for nothing.
I give him something for nothing either.
Either.
Yeah,
that's first on the surface.
Um,
that they can develop a dependence
mentality of just putting a handout
because they got to get what they can
get whenever people just show up,
blow up and blow out of there.
But the documentary poverty inc goes in
there and shows how in Haiti,
they're local farmers have been put out
of business by government subsidies from
I,
I've been to Haiti and I've seen the
American grown rice that's all just
given out for free or at the markets.
The people that get it for free then go
to the market and they beat all the
local farmers because they got it for
free or they played a paid such a small
price.
They didn't really do all the work,
so they're able to beat all their
competitors,
the local market,
so they get it for free and then they
sell it.
Is that what you're saying?
They can at little shops they can do
that or they just get it and they don't
need it.
I think it cuts off the local farmers
who are trying to sell their own stuff
and they can you,
since they're getting it for free,
they could tell them a much lower price.
Absolutely.
And it shows it.
It dives deep into how,
how it,
how it hurts so much in a way that like,
man,
I think Haiti's you there,
they used to eat rice two to three times
a week.
Now they're eating it three times a day
with breakfast,
lunch and dinner and they're doing it
and it's all the rice that they have
available to them are from the u s or
from China or from India.
And it's because these big farmers with
a lot of power in the government,
they're able to make deals with the
United Nations and other places to be
able to go in and give out their rice
there and they get paid for it from the
government here,
right?
You government pays these farmers,
these,
these prices,
and then they go into a community.
Just give it out.
And now how do I say this in a,
that it's not bad intentions.
No one's trying to her.
I don't think there's these evil people
trying to destroy developing nations.
I don't think that's the case.
But there's a model out there that's
been the traditional model of let's
announce our arrival by throwing,
throwing a parade.
Let's throw a big party.
Let's get a bunch of pictures.
Um,
and let's,
let's leave to the next one because we
have such a big organization are so many
funds or,
or a big quota to hit.
We have,
this is our goal this year.
We have this many tally marks to get.
So we blast in one community and then we
blow out of there into a new one.
We don't develop relationships with them
to build,
empower them,
teach them skills that,
that part,
how do I say it?
Like the answer to poverty isn't
charity.
It's opportunity.
Opportunity is always better than
charity,
if that,
if that makes sense.
A handout or hand up like the given
Manna fish,
feed him for a day or teach man a fish,
feed him for a lifetime.
And so if there's a disaster,
if there's a person with a disability,
if there's a war or famine than charity
is the solution.
But there's gotta be an escape plan.
There's got to be a route out.
Otherwise,
whenever I went to Haiti,
it was a year and a half,
two years after the earthquake and the
tent city,
they had had doubled or tripled in size
because I met a guy there that was
saying I could,
I moved out of my apartment which wasn't
damaged by the earthquake and I get to
go live at tent city,
rent free.
I still have my job and I get three
meals a day,
breakfast,
lunch,
and dinner.
I don't have to prepare them,
I don't have to pay for them.
And so in these places are always going
to be giving to that tent city and it's
actually grown in size.
He was like,
I'm saving up to buy a house.
And so it's like if people think,
oh,
there's just this disaster,
it's like man,
if someone brought in like some
vocational training,
you know,
let's teach these people how to do this
kind of work.
Like I don't think honestly,
most sane people,
um,
out there that are living in poverty
want to be poor for the rest of their
life.
They're sitting there waiting for an
opportunity.
The Dad wants to put food on the table
for the family.
So it was the mom,
she wants to take care of her kids.
And so whenever we can come into a
community and spend time with them,
if that makes sense,
like sit down,
listen to them,
learn from them,
and then we can say,
how can we work together?
How can we brainstorm?
What is your community really need
instead of treating it like there's a
cookie cutter solution or blueprint that
since it worked in this community,
it's going to work in that community.
Or since it worked in this country,
it's going to work in that country.
Like every country has its own culture
and the Congo has over 200 tribes.
That's over 200 different cultures.
And so some are going to receive it.
Well,
some aren't.
Some how do you,
how do you work with them in a way that
isn't just coming in and just giving
them stuff that,
I've seen it,
I've seen a riot happened in Uganda.
It was in ginger,
ginger,
Uganda.
We're a organization came in with
a bunch of canned foods and they did it
in a very poor fashion where,
um,
they just cracked open this container in
a slump and it's one of the roughest
slums and Uganda,
um,
and people just raided it.
And it didn't even give probably a
quarter of the people in the slums,
uh,
a canned item from the u s and so people
start fighting over it and they're
fighting over it and it's a,
and so we got really hurt.
I don't know if they died,
but someone got really hurt there.
We had to get out of there.
And so what I know from that
organization is,
and I'm not going to say the
organization,
but I heard from the other organizations
there that they,
they had been warned like,
you're new at this.
Don't go in there and do this.
Don't crack open this container and do
it that way.
But they had spent like $20,000 getting
the canned goods there,
shipping,
buying a container,
shipping it over there,
going through Kenya,
then uh,
then probably Tanzania or Tanzania,
then Kenya,
then Uganda,
they're had to pay all the fees
everywhere they go to just go give it
away.
That $20,000 could have empowered so
many farmers locally or people that
don't know how to farm to be able to
start farming for themselves,
that then is going to have such a better
return on investment because you're
investing into the people,
into a trade,
into a skill,
into something that they need and it's
going to last.
It's going to continue to produce
results.
I totally makes sense.
And I think what you're saying is so
important that these people have great
intentions,
but that just human nature and that
given the circumstances of which these
people live in where they had no hope
and then all of sudden they have this
one thing and it's one thing as gifts,
right?
Far better to do what you're doing to
provide them with opportunity.
You know,
and I think that's,
I mean the issue that I think a lot of
people are going to have with even
discussing that is the callous
discussions of the welfare mentality.
You know,
the,
the way people look at some communities
and people,
you know,
the,
the term welfare brats or welfare,
you know,
welfare people that are just kind of
like connected to that,
the,
the need for charity.
And I think that mirrors,
um,
the,
the idea of welfare and you know,
when people don't have jobs and don't
have opportunities and just getting
money and getting,
getting addicted to that money,
that problem has existed in America as
well.
Obviously it's a much bigger deal in the
Congo because you're talking about like
basic life necessities,
fresh water.
But I think that's important,
man.
It's important to understand what human
nature,
um,
the mechanisms of human nature and like
what you're talking about here is really
powerful.
There was,
you have thought it out so well and to
give these people this opportunity and
now to give these people at this
opportunity with the soap.
I mean Pacha is doing an awesome job.
I mean that's,
no,
that's an amazing thing.
I think that's so important and I really
hope that more people listen and more
people hear you and more people say,
hey,
you know,
I want to get involved.
Let's,
let's do something else in the Congo.
let's give these people another
opportunity that they can start
businesses down there,
man.
Yeah.
And like really empower themselves and
be able to build homes and just like in
your lifetime you could see some crazy
change.
Yeah.
I
know.
I know that's coming and Congo,
but I think like,
let's not,
let's not set a ceiling or roof on it.
And I'm not,
that's what I'm not saying that's what
you're saying,
but I'm just saying that I truly believe
that the water crisis,
1 billion people not having clean water
in our lifetime,
we have the tools,
the technology and people are learning.
I mean from podcasting,
like people were getting better than
doctorates,
degrees,
you know,
like in information and,
and,
and life experience and learning and
learning to do things the right way and
truly have people's best interests at
heart.
Um,
I think there's going to be a real shift
to where,
I mean,
if I have,
if I have the water to take a piss in,
um,
or to water my lawn with or to give my
dog clean water,
uh,
we're going to be able to give every
person in the world clean water.
Um,
but it's through empowerment and it's
through opportunity and a,
and that's what I love.
I even have a,
since it was world water day,
two days ago,
I have a video at that kind of explains
the problem and a,
it's from a village that,
um,
I'm really close with and him Atilla
Hulu and there's this little girl named
Sicu that was just a,
a beautiful little girl and um,
and if it's okay,
but it shows what they're facing,
what they're drinking.
Yeah,
for sure.
Um,
and man,
it's,
it's powerful.
You got that Jamie.
Hashtag a powerful
yeah.
Who I got my shit,
but my hope for my children is for them
to go to school and back to grow in and
to be good and take care of me when I'm
alive.
Yes.
Okay.
That's the water.
They were drinking cheeses for folks
just listing it's green algae all over
the surface of it.
It looks disgusting.
Yeah.
Everyone is suffering,
but in most cases it's our children.
Hulu,
Mike,
I know that water we drink gives us all
these sigma Sas,
my daughter's name.
Okay.
See I keep double.
She couldn't speak yet.
She was able to grow.
She was a baby.
I suffered so much when she was
suffering.
I brought her to the hospital.
She passed away there.
If get I'm talk doctor,
I said to myself,
I was just carrying my baby when I was,
I need to see burying her.
They said,
how did she disappear?
Where did she go?
She's carrying this water on her head
folks.
His giant Jug when I lost my child was
that I lost all hope for the future.
We're watching a video of her walking
through the Congo carrying this water
jug on top of her head is 45 pound jug.
Fuck man.
Does hard to deal with if someone like
you wasn't being attention to this?
I mean,
do you understand like what about huge
role you're playing here?
Is that,
um,
I mean it's,
it's surreal and uh,
but at the same time,
like I,
yeah,
I think that's why I've completely
wholeheartedly dedicated my life to this
because that was the,
that was the first promise.
I didn't know that we could do anything
with land or water food at first.
Um,
now we have 3000 acres of land drilled.
The 62 wells.
We have three farms up and running.
Um,
they bout to start the soap,
but me and like,
I didn't want to make any promises that
I couldn't keep.
And for the chief to come to us and say,
hey,
everyone else calls us the force people,
but we call ourselves the forgotten.
It wrecked me.
And then he said,
can you help us have a voice because we
don't have one?
I said,
yes,
I knew that from fighting from Ed,
being on the ultimate fighter.
Um,
when did that ever grew or didn't grow?
I had some people,
and just having the platform of being
here,
being from the West,
being from somewhere where people can
have an abundance of resources to make a
difference.
Um,
and even if it's small,
like our small here is so big there.
And so,
uh,
I said yes,
to that and little [inaudible],
who was the third?
A little one that I knew,
uh,
that had passed,
um,
an auto,
the Hulu.
And before that was andiebo after that
was a little Babo,
um,
a little girl named Mo also,
uh,
in Sang Goulay Endcap,
Tula in [inaudible].
And,
uh,
these are all kids that I knew that I
was,
uh,
had become friends with over two years
living there.
And,
um,
and so have any either held them or
buried them are having played,
grown up knowing their families are
seeing some of those kids grow up and
then their lives get cut short.
Um,
it's been like,
man,
like when I fight,
it's an honor for them when I talk about
this problem.
Like I know the,
it's not just I read about it or I just
maybe saw it and it hurt for a little
while.
Like I knew him.
Like those,
those kids,
800 kids a day from diary in 2,350 from
another 1.5 billion a year.
Like I know the names of some of those
kids and had relationships with them and
their families.
And so,
um,
I never would've thought that test that
I would be in a position to try to,
to help or that I even knew about the
problem.
I didn't,
um,
until he hit me upside the head.
But,
uh,
but now that,
that's where my life has gone and that's
what I'm going to dedicate it to.
Wow.
That's powerful shit,
dude.
He'll live in a fucking crazy life.
Yeah,
you really are.
I mean,
you,
you really living a life of purpose.
It's so rare that someone does it,
but it's such a high level and now
you're,
you're in a very strange situation.
Very strange driver's seat in life.
Well,
think,
I mean,
yeah,
it's definitely strange.
But thank you to you man,
for,
uh,
for leave and allowing me to have this
platform before we drilled.
I mean like we were,
we were getting to it.
Um,
but,
but we hadn't actually completed it yet.
It's kind of how Andrew was listening to
the gre while he's being a janitor had
this dream.
I had this dream and you allowed me to
come on and share about it.
And so many like stars have aligned
because of that.
Um,
and,
and there's just been a lot of really
great stuff that,
that knife,
actually,
I have a picture for you.
If maldon up a,
a knife.
It's a made out of a nail.
It's actually,
I use this to open up all my letters and
packages and stuff.
Yeah.
So awesome.
Chiefly Leo made both of those for Ya
and uh,
uh,
I think on that little file it says
knife.
Um,
and I actually had a picture I didn't
get to show you yet,
but this is how he makes the knives.
Um,
but he just finds the nails out in the
forest and uh,
some ladders or different things and he
pulls him out.
Uh,
think people do,
forcing the rain forest,
he gets their nails and make some
something,
uh,
something useful.
Um,
and so that,
that's a picture of the knife.
I think there might be one more picture
of him making the knives.
So what he's doing is he's taking a nail
and he's hammering it flat and he's
taking this big spike nail,
like a construction nail,
like a railroad and not quite a
railroad.
The site,
actually,
the one in his wreck,
a framing nail,
right.
That makes all the one in his right hand
that he hammers it down with uses a
hammer.
It's a railroad spike.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
just really creative.
And this is actually,
if you pull up the other one that says,
oh yeah,
there he is with some of the Kiddos.
This whole Swazi on the right.
Um,
and there's the huts behind them and the
twigs and leaves.
They make those kinds of doorways,
uh,
in there.
And um,
it's just been really cool.
They live on 247 acres.
It's land that they have,
um,
for the first time.
And Oh man.
So I,
that,
that video was powerful because it
showed the problem,
but there's actually one that's with
chief Leo May,
uh,
it's the second video on,
on that list and if I can show that to
you,
I got something for Ya from there.
From Leo mays village,
it's called the Bofi.
Um,
and there's a video,
uh,
that's going to show like kind of the
transformation or the solution kind of
to the problem.
And that just,
that first video just showed the problem
is hard.
Right?
But then there's hope to see what we can
do something about it.
Yeah.
Real transformation changes the present
and the future.
Hey,
so he's walking with,
my name is Leona hunting.
The label born from above you village.
I want to teach my grandson how to hunt.
We are teaching these young boys this
because this is our original way of
life.
One day we'll die,
but these young people will live on.
I love that.
Gorgeous.
People treat pygmies like we aren't
important about Bob.
They think we're stupid,
but when we worked on farms,
we would get 10 or 15 bananas to split
among seven people by Bob tried to start
a small farm.
Someone would take it from me and say,
your father did not own any land.
2013 Leo may spill at your seat land of
their own.
It's about 247 acres.
I was happy to have my own lane,
but we weren't getting water from the
river.
He was bad or people were sick.
One day you should get it,
but sometimes they would get sick and
die without treatment.
I've never heard of anybody getting sick
from the water since we've had the well
here.
It's so good.
It's so sweet.
I love it.
I'm with the big change is that
farm before and after the same place?
All those banana trees
you started with the potatoes didn't
cassava.
Then we planted some banana trees.
Banana trees.
Have you planted that?
I cannot.
It's a lot.
I can't finish county.
What Nissan in his make up the first
time we took bananas to the market,
we bought clothes for the children.
When we saw them wearing clothes and
shoes,
we were so happy.
Today we have a toilet,
we have a place to wash our hands.
We have a place to shower.
So to me that's progress,
right?
Because he made everybody get getting
erection in generation.
Judah,
we've beat this land.
Wow.
And Tans who not just living your whole
life in despair and then all of a sudden
the last few years,
things radically change for the better.
That's powerful,
man.
Wow,
What a crazy thing you're doing justin
wren.
Well,
I,
to be completely honest,
me and like I got to be the spark plug,
but man,
there's a big engine around this.
Oh Hey stan state side water four.
Without a doubt.
All of our supporters couldn't do
without them,
but mostly we couldn't do it without the
people on the ground.
There in the Congo,
18 Congolese people with a heart to
change be the change in their own
country,
to change the country from the inside
out,
countryman,
the countryman,
uh,
not being dependent on others.
I mean they're,
they're starting to secure water
contracts,
uh,
to drill wells and do water projects in
their own country.
So that way they don't have to be
dependent on us.
I mean,
our team in Uganda is over 70% self
sufficient,
self funded inside the country,
our guys in Congo or close to 50%.
Um,
and we're on track to get these teams to
where they're 100% self sufficient to
where we just come in with the training
and the techniques and the tools.
But like they don't need us to fund it
anymore.
So that way we can go off to other
places and do it again.
Replicated.
Wow.
So what is the,
is there a longterm strategy in terms
of,
yeah,
so basically things that work in their
context so that way we give them like
the manual drilling.
Um,
one instance,
I don't know why this Swahili proverb
just popped in my mind,
but they say,
you,
you Americans,
are you westerners?
You guys all have watched us,
but we're the ones that,
who,
who have time.
And so,
uh,
does that make sense?
Like,
you guys don't have watches,
but we have time.
And they see us as always rushing,
rushing,
and trying to get this done and that
done and this done.
And they're like,
hey,
it's good to go out and crush things and
get so many goals and so many
accomplishments under your belt,
but let's make sure we're doing it all
the right way.
So that's what I mean,
honestly,
I've learned from them.
Slow it down so you can do it right,
do it correctly.
Um,
I've even started implement that into my
lifting and in training,
right?
Like slow things down to a slow
controlled and do it correctly instead
of just trying to put up a bunch of
white.
Um,
and so they're,
they,
they slow things down.
Um,
and,
and honestly,
the longterm solution is reason why we
don't take volunteers anymore.
Um,
and I've only taken two people with me
to the Congo.
Uh,
but they were Geo hydrologist or
engineers that needed to come.
Uh,
but the reason is,
is because when you take volunteers
over,
most of them are going to be amateurs or
they're going to be white belts.
If I had to put it into a mma or Bjj
analogy,
um,
and our guys in the field,
they're,
they're becoming black belts where they
are now after years of training,
years of development on this,
since 2011,
um,
I mean,
our guys in Congo,
I've drilled those 62 wells,
but they went to Sierra Leone.
They taught a team in Cameroon from the
ground up.
They went to Uganda,
Kenya,
and Rwanda.
And they're,
these teams are working together and
they're going off after they learn how
to do it,
they're going to other communities in
their own country or they're going to
another country.
It's so cool.
We have this dynamic going on between,
we call it the Varunga initiative.
There's the Virunga mountains that are
on the border of Uganda,
Rwanda and Congo.
Now there's so many,
uh,
rebel groups,
that are there.
Um,
and,
and the w those countries I've been at
war against each other.
Like the people from those nations
pretty much hate each other.
Like they all blame the one another for
you guys are doing this in our country
and your rebel,
you're sending rebels into our country
and where your government soldiers are
actually pretending to be rebels,
but they're working for the government
and they're stealing our golden her
diamonds.
And anyways,
so they,
they don't work together.
But now our well drillers that are from
Rwanda and Uganda and Congo,
they're all working so much together.
We get everything in from Uganda.
Um,
our team goes to co,
uh,
Rwanda from Congo to teach them how to
train,
but that Rwandan team comes over to us
and teaches us business principles.
Um,
and so it's just been so cool to see how
they're working together and how are
guys in Congo or holding Ugandan and
Rwandan flags over their back taking
pictures and the other guys are wearing
Congo flags over their back.
And our team that came from Uganda to
live with me for three months in our
team to help us really get off the
ground and start learning.
They had drilled over 100 wells for
their fellow Ugandans.
They left for three months to come live
with us in Congo there.
First Day there they,
they,
the car flipped,
their taxi driver flipped a,
the car ran over,
a woman killed her.
They don't speak the Congolese Swahili
or French there from an English speaking
nation and Uganda.
And all of a sudden they had the car was
looted,
it was torched.
Um,
and people were chasing them down,
wanting to put tires around them and set
them on fire and burned them and kill
them because they were Ugandan.
They got in an accident.
It's the whole mob justice kind of
mentality that happens.
Like if,
if they send them to the jail or court,
they know that,
you know,
justice probably won't be had if they
have money on them.
And so,
uh,
people just want justice.
Then it's kind of wild over there and,
uh,
and that area of the world.
So these Ugandan guys literally knew
they're risking their lives to come live
with us in Congo just because they're
hated by Congolese.
But then whenever they flipped their
vehicle,
first day,
they're there on the border,
basically still of Uganda.
They're in a town called Nica,
which means snake and they hit a lady,
it killed her.
And that was the taxi driver drive and
he's not part of our team.
But then they all wanted to kill the
Ugandan guys inside of the Congolese
guy.
Um,
and then they still stuck it out.
We're able to regain our $15,000 a well
drilling equipment that was there.
Luckily we had a,
uh,
this is a side topic,
but we had this,
um,
this water filtration system that was
from solar panels and they had these two
big chambers on it.
And in the middle is this timer that you
literally twist and it goes for an hour
and has a green and red light on it and
it ticks tick,
tick,
tick.
Well,
we had it locked up whenever it came
from the states and our Ugandan team
picked it up and they go,
hey the the something called Tsa broke
off the lock and left you a note.
And so they are checking it cause it
looked like these two chambers and a
timer and it looked like it could've
been a bomb in this big Pelican case.
So whenever the Congolese guys loaded
the car,
set it on fire,
they ran away with it and hid behind a
hut.
Um,
well whenever they opened that Pelican
case,
all of a sudden they thought it was a
bomb and they ran away and left all of
our stuff there.
So whenever they found out that these
guys from Uganda already risked their
lives to come here and teach Congolese
how to drill wells for themselves,
they were truly good guys.
It was just an accident.
They got behind us and let us back to
our equipment and said,
be careful though.
Like that bond,
that's why we left it out there.
So they understood that it was a big
misunderstanding.
Yeah,
it was a big misunderstanding that
forgave those people for,
gave them for,
gave our Ugandan well drillers who
weren't even really a part of it.
There was the taxi driver that actually
hit,
did they apologize for,
to stick tires around them and light
them on fire?
Yeah,
absolutely.
And so,
uh,
so anyway,
that's a long story.
It was crazy wild and we thought our
guys are going to die because we were
like six hours away from him and we were
hearing like a Ryan basically happening.
Um,
but it was so cool man,
that,
uh,
that we got all our supplies back and
then afterwards,
um,
I mean we,
we,
we gave,
we helped with the burial process and
the funeral and everything else.
Even though it was the taxi driver,
not us.
We,
we felt so bad that that had happened.
But then to know like,
hey,
now it was just a story that we were
able to,
I mean,
not,
not that loss of life,
but,
but those people now know that we're
here to help them.
Uh,
and we were able to go back in there and
do that for them afterwards.
So it's amazing,
man.
I mean,
I know there's a book that a Loretta
Hunt wrote with you,
right.
But you've lived another life since the
book.
Yeah.
You know,
I mean,
you have another books,
life,
uh,
books,
well,
life's worth of them.
What's the word?
Way To describe it?
Another easily another book.
Right.
Well thanks.
Well,
that's what I love about me and these
short films.
That's all part of the documentary.
Um,
in fact,
maybe,
I mean,
I should probably say that like after I
was on the second or third time here,
we did a kickstarter for the documentary
and we got it fully funded yet the
documentary is not out yet because we're
going back one more time,
uh,
to film a,
they'll probably be July or August right
after my fight.
We'll bust over there and we're trying
to submit it to sundance film festival
this year.
We submit it in September.
Hopefully we get in the festival.
Um,
it will be there in January and then it
will be out in a lot of the gre
supporters that gave to the kickstarter
will be able to do it.
But we really wanted to do the story,
not the story when do the pygmies,
um,
in their family in and everyone's
suffering for the world from the world's
water crisis.
We wanted to do them justice to give
them a voice.
The book was me giving them a voice,
but the documentary,
they're going to have their own voice.
And so it's been so cool.
It's been filmed over three and a half
years now.
I think when it comes out,
there'll be a four full years that
Derek's been able to go back and forth
and go get more of the story and show
not just like them getting water for the
first time,
but then also how we're giving jobs,
how they're getting trained,
how they're starting up workshops,
how we're breaking ground on the soa
production facility where already have
the land.
We started the foundation of the place.
And,
um,
and so how it's the full spectrum of it
to,
to hopefully show how empowerment,
uh,
how much farther that goes.
Now it's a lot tougher.
It takes a lot more time.
You really have to be strategic.
You have to sit and listen and learn and
be humble enough to say like it's a
learning process.
Like when you do something,
whenever you get out of that lane of
truly listening and saying,
I think that's,
that's the quote that our team tries to
live by.
It's a swahili proverb that says if you
want to go fast,
go alone,
but if you want to go far go together.
And so it's like how,
how can every community we go in,
how can we take this as far as we can
not go as fast as we can because if we
want to go fast,
we just leave them out of it.
But if we want to go far,
we'll go together.
And so we do that with our well drilling
team,
but we do that with the communities too
because they all lived like a saying
that that's just ingrained in them.
Wow.
Do you have a long term strategy with
this?
Like do you,
do you see yourself,
like how long do you see yourself
fighting and what do you see yourself
doing after you're done with that?
Um,
I think I'm going to fight for the next
five to seven years.
I,
well,
I mean,
if I can go out on top,
I'd love to do that.
Um,
I don't think I need to carry it too
long,
too far and go out on a bad note of a
string of brutal losses.
Um,
I think,
uh,
I want to get that platform when you get
to the top.
Um,
and then I want to delete and go do
something else and,
uh,
which is this.
But man,
it's been so cool.
Our team and Sierra Leone and our team
and uh,
uh,
Kenya and now we're about to do it in
Rwanda.
We did this like crowdfunding campaign
that we threw up on world water day.
We're doing it through the rest of the
month.
Um,
but we have started water towers.
So basically we drill a well and then we
have a water tower,
which turns into a water kiosk where
people from the community come up to it.
They might pay pay five shillings for
Jerry Cam.
So jerry cans,
five gallons,
they pay 5 cents,
but eventually all the people in the
community,
the one in Rwanda we're doing,
it's going to serve 4,000 people.
It's at a school.
So the kids will have clean water all
throughout the day,
but then people come there and the one
in Kenya is funding a school,
but the one in Rwanda is going to fund
more water wells.
So as these people by clean water,
the only clean water around there,
that community,
the only thing they have to drink,
there's a lake that,
uh,
has the cows and everything else
drinking out of it.
Cow patties are inside the water.
And you can see people collecting water
at the same time that cows are drinking
from it right beside them.
Uh,
people washing clothes in it,
they're washing motorcycles in it.
Um,
and then that's their drinking water.
And so we're putting up this water kiosk
where yeah,
we're going to charge him 5 cents when
they get five gallons of clean water,
but those are going to turn into
multiple water wells throughout the
year.
And so we're trying to do all these
sustainable solutions to where after we
do that in Rwanda,
we're taking that to the Congo,
there'll be close to the soa production
facility in the community development
center.
We're going to have,
which will have land,
water,
food solutions,
um,
even the forestry,
what we felt to replant over 4,000 trees
now in the Congo.
And it's like,
because of deforestation,
so brutal.
So I think it's just sitting back and
saying,
what do you guys need?
Listening and learning that need and
saying,
okay,
where can we fit in?
How can we help in this area?
Who's a specialist?
How can we really make an impact?
I think our lame is definitely water.
I mean from that chiefly Omi village or
the story that you just saw,
but bofi where he made that knife for
Ya.
Um,
you can see that water changes
everything.
And so that's going to be what hubs,
that's our hub,
that's,
that's our lane and that's what all of
the waterfall teams are doing.
But in the Congo,
because of the pygmies are so
vulnerable,
we're trying to find the ways to help
them come up.
And as they come up,
other people are watching and looking
and they're starting to implement the
same kind of things.
So it's pretty cool to see that happen.
And before I forget,
the reason I wanted to show that video
was I got you something.
This is Leo [inaudible] wife.
So you have the,
you have the,
the knife from Leo May,
his wife made you this right here.
And so because from our second jre
episode,
I believe,
uh,
we funded a water well there in Bofi and
so,
uh,
she's really talented.
Um,
I mean it might not look like too much
here,
but uh,
it's cool.
What does that mean?
It's bark cloth.
So it's a tree bark cloth.
And when they take the bark off the
trees,
fine.
But they a,
that used to be what they would make
their clothing out of their clothing.
They would make other materials out of
them.
They can make these little kind of
carrying cases or backpacks kind of out
of it.
Did they treat it with something like
how do they get it so soft?
They pound it down and I haven't seen
the whole process,
but I've seen the bark and where they
pull it off and then they kind of beat
it down and beat it down until it's this
like cloth.
I know that this right here when I've
been doing research,
they have those pygmy,
uh,
boothy pygmy paintings that are made out
of bark cloth at Lake Card,
National Museum of history in New York.
Um,
they have a few of these there and so
it's Kinda cool to see.
I Dunno,
I just was,
uh,
was excited to bring it back to you.
I think I got a picture of said painting
and um,
it's,
it's Mama Leo May and she's,
uh,
she's paying that for Esl.
That's awesome man.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And thank her.
Please.
I will.
That's so cool.
I will,
they just have,
when I go back sometimes they're like,
hey,
well that's you're making it.
Thank your friends.
Yeah.
So that one's not the same one.
I actually didn't think to or I didn't
get picture of it whenever she was
painting this one,
but I got a picture of her doing some
other ones.
That's a Mamma Swazi and uh,
she's pretty great at it as well.
And so they just,
uh,
yeah,
I mean that's a little bowl.
We'll leafs,
um,
this paint that you actually have there
was,
they had some leftover black paint,
but sometimes on that other photo they
just use like cassava or berries and
they beat it up a pound it down and make
this paint out of it.
But it kind of fades over time.
So this one's one where,
yeah,
that's,
that's it right there where they just
pound up the stuff and it's part of
their culture.
It's what they love to do.
They kind of how he saw Leo may a pass
him down,
uh,
you know,
the farming and that video was actually
San g over here from the hand print
that,
yeah,
he got his grandson.
Um,
and this is what the women pass down to
their girls is how to make the spark
cloth and how to,
um,
how to paint.
So
wow.
It's pretty neat.
Their culture,
like they just do everything together.
They rally around each other,
they're happy together.
They sing,
they dance,
but they also suffer together.
If one person,
the community is lost,
even for instance,
it might sound weird in our culture,
but let's say a mother passes away who's
dear?
Like,
she's breastfeeding,
right?
And she passes away,
but the baby survives.
Some other woman in the village will
take the baby up and start taking care
of that little one.
And um,
there is an adoption in the pygmy
culture like you do.
No one,
no one needs to be adopted because the
community rallies around them when
someone's lost,
they all mourn the death together,
but then they rally around that family
and see how they can all help and put
in.
So it's pretty cool.
I love it.
I've,
I've learned a lot from him.
Well,
that's how people used to be,
man.
That's,
that's the original sort of tribal life
of human beings.
They,
they would all raise each other.
Christopher Ryan had this whole,
um,
uh,
take on it in sex at dawn,
you know,
and Mckenna had a take on it as well
where they were talking about these
ancient cultures.
They,
because of these small groups of people,
they were much closer.
They knew everyone in the community.
It was intensely important and that
they,
there's a lot of people that think that
some of the problems that we deal with
today in society are because of this
association that we have with our
neighbors.
And we don't have a real sense of
community.
I mean,
I know like two or three of my neighbors
and I see them once a year and I say,
hi wave,
how's everything man?
Everything cool.
All right,
good seeing Ya.
But that's it.
You know,
there's no real community,
there's no interaction.
There's no,
there's certainly no contribution as far
as like working together together,
food or water or anything like that.
And I would imagine that these people
were,
it just intensely close.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I mean that must've been a big part of
the attraction to you to them.
Like when they took you in and you were
living with them and,
yeah,
absolutely.
I mean,
I think the average my booty pygmy
village is only 85,
250 on our 10 villages that we help and
have the 3000 acres of land.
Um,
it's over 300,
uh,
for rich each village.
Um,
do you know about Dunbar's number?
Dunbar's number is a number that,
I mean it varies,
but the number,
somewhere around one 50 for most people,
there's a number of people that you can
keep close relationships with.
Oh Wow.
They really only have room for 150
people in your head.
You essentially of hard drive space.
Wow.
Yeah.
And that seems to be related to ancient
tribal communities that people sense
that we'd developed that way,
that we develop these,
these small groups of 50 to 150 plus
people.
Yeah.
And then when you get larger than that,
things get weird.
Yeah.
Well,
no,
that's,
that's so true.
Like I,
whenever I went through the six year
battle with oxy and just,
uh,
narcotics or pain pills,
like I,
I,
um,
I don't know.
I would always be able to isolate super
easy.
Right.
Cause as well,
when you're in your home,
you're completely alone.
Um,
and so
it's different when you're in a village
and with the pygmies you saw some of
those huts,
how,
how small they are.
You know,
seriously in several of them,
whenever I'm sleeping,
I have to sleep in the center and I have
to have my feet out the door.
Um,
because it's so small.
Uh,
but it's,
um,
the only go in there when you're going
to sleep or if you're not feeling good
and you need some rest or the sun's
right over your head and in your hot.
Um,
but besides that,
you're cooking your kitchens outside.
Um,
that's where the people is.
That's where you do life is outside of
your home.
Uh,
around the campfire.
We call it campfire university because
that's where we've been taken to school
from the,
from the pygmies.
Uh,
they,
it's where they teach us the most about
life is around the campfire,
learning their culture,
learning about their kids,
learning about the hunts,
learning about how they make this,
make that,
um,
and it's where you get to do life
together.
And so it's something really,
really cool.
Honestly,
I told him they want to know a little
bit about my life and I told him that I
went through drug addiction for six
years and you know,
they don't really struggle with that at
all.
And,
uh,
and then I told him I got really
depressed and I told him,
I really said,
and I told him that I got so sad that I
decided one time to take as many pills
as I could and drink.
Uh,
there's like half a bottle of everclear
or more.
Um,
and snorted a bunch of coke and just
wanted to end it all.
So,
I mean,
I told him that I was suicidal and um,
and I,
I,
I will never forget how they,
how they looked at me almost dumbfounded
in a way of like,
and then,
and then one of the questions the chief
asked me said,
well,
wouldn't hurting you.
You're set.
Wouldn't hurting yourself,
only hurt you.
And,
uh,
so the whole concept of,
I guess what I'm getting to is they had
never heard of anyone killing
themselves.
Like maybe they had heard stories or
something like that,
but they have never known anybody that
actually killed themselves or heard of
it.
It's not something that they or their
community,
their culture,
the pygmies kind of untouched out in the
forest or even not a up in the city.
It's like,
that's just something that they don't
struggle with.
They're,
they're struggling so much day in and
day out with struggles that are so deep
and they see their family and they do
life together.
That I think they just have so much more
of.
W W we were just talking about so much
more of a support system.
People that were rally around them.
When you lose a family member,
everyone rallies around you.
Like whenever I go to the funerals,
it's the,
it's the worst thing in the world.
The sounds like people don't try to
compose themselves.
They don't try to dress the body real
nice and f flowers all around and now,
now losing loss of life is always tough.
Always terrible.
Um,
but there's something we do here in our
culture where we make it,
um,
try to make it as,
as nice or smooth or almost pretty as
possible.
You know,
the person's dressed really nice and has
the flowers and you compose yourself to
come there.
You gather yourself,
you prepare the eulogy,
there's a,
there's a program.
When you step in there,
people get handed something and you know
what's going to happen there.
So you kind of can all compose,
man,
they are just so ugly.
It's so raw.
It's so real.
And it's so like in your face and it
just rips your heart open to where
people are mourning.
I,
I saw Jayla,
um,
whenever Babo I was the one,
me and ben were the ones that told Jayla
while he's the chief.
Um,
about his grandson passing away.
We were there when it happened.
He wasn't around,
he was out collecting or gathering.
Um,
and we met on the same path together and
he saw it in our face that he knew Baba
was sick,
but now he knew that he was gone.
And I remember Jay Lodge is falling on
his back into this,
off the side of the foot path into like
this pile of brush,
like a,
like,
like probably two,
three foot tall where he like sunk into
it and he was just squirming on his
back,
you know,
he's like in his sixties and he's
watched so many of his grandchildren
like pass just because they don't have
clean water and seeing them squirming,
almost wanting to like crawl out of his
skin,
you know?
Um,
and so,
but I don't know.
I don't want to be a bummer.
I,
I'm,
I'm just,
uh,
just express yourself.
It's,
it's,
but then how the whole community,
all hundred and 50,
200,
300 people that were there,
uh,
all mourned together.
Like we shared it.
Like I,
I cried in a way that was like,
you know,
like,
like wiping my tears with everybody
because everyone,
everyone was morning,
everyone was crying.
It wasn't just a few people.
It wasn't just his mom and his dad,
his mom,
macho w it wasn't just j Lajuan,
it was the whole village cried together.
And so,
I don't know,
but for me,
that,
that makes it seem like,
I don't know if this,
I don't want to make too many
connections between our culture because
they're completely different or a lot
different.
But I think here a huge cause of divorce
is the loss of a child.
Um,
but there,
it's almost unites the parents.
Um,
so much so whenever they lose a little
one.
And I don't,
I don't mean to make this comparison,
but it's like,
I think it's because when they mourn,
they truly go to the depths of the
darkest place and they're able to truly
almost get it out,
if that makes sense.
Where when you're at the funeral,
you let yourself go.
You just let go and,
and,
and it's okay.
However ugly or however you handle it,
whatever emotions come,
you just ride that wave,
if that makes sense.
Do you think that because their life is
so difficult,
that life itself becomes more precious
and the loss becomes more powerful or
more intense?
More,
more raw?
Wow.
Yeah.
I needed you to,
to sum that up for sure.
Um,
yes I do.
I think whenever you struggle so much
your,
you become so much more appreciative and
grateful of life of every breath you
take.
Um,
well that's kind of,
yeah,
connected to their lack of understanding
of suicide because our,
you know,
our idea of what a difficult life is,
it's difficult,
but there's food and shelter and this,
you know,
and really the easiest place to live in
the world,
all those things connected.
Whereas with them
just staying alive is such a struggle.
And getting water,
which is so easy for us all,
we,
anybody can walk into any bathroom and
any gas stop,
turn the water on,
water comes out.
I mean,
everybody waters on hard to get in
America.
And even with the droughts,
it's easy to get water.
We water fucking golf courses with
millions of gallons of water every day.
Yeah.
Our understanding of what a struggle is
is so different.
Yeah.
And I think whenever we,
when we've really struggled here,
we can go hide away and we don't have to
deal with it.
Now I have to have conversations about
it.
Um,
we can,
we can almost escape it.
We can escape it with our,
with our toys,
with our technology,
you know,
we can,
we can just bury our face in our phone
or a computer or sit and watch a movie.
And like,
whenever those uncomfortable feelings
come up,
we can try to ignore them or suppress
them,
if that makes sense.
And they're there.
So it's almost,
man,
this is going to be a weird,
strange curve ball or left turn.
But it's almost like a,
I've started floating recently and
whenever I go in there,
um,
into the tank,
it's like you have to,
you're,
you're left alone to your thoughts,
right?
You don't have that technology.
You don't have this.
And so you can deal with stuff and you
can try to focus and let go.
And for me it's been really beneficial.
And so I don't,
I know that sounds weird for me to make
that connection,
but uh,
but whenever you're just left alone with
your own thoughts,
you can go deep.
And I feel like our culture here,
well,
okay,
if we compare,
and I love our culture,
there's,
I'm not saying there's so much wrong
with it,
but uh,
but I feel like they're in
relationships.
You go an inch or two wide and you go a
mile deep in the Congo,
you get to know people and then hear,
a lot of times you go a mile wide,
but you go only,
you only scratched the surface.
You don't go beneath the top soil that
much.
Um,
so you do sometimes with,
with a few people,
um,
there's only few people that we trust
with that,
you know,
but it's almost like they're,
everyone's so open to,
um,
to go in deep with one another.
And because of that,
you get to know each other better.
You get to a truly hurt when they hurt,
you get to laugh.
When they laugh,
you get to cry when they cry.
Um,
and I may not,
I don't have to keep going on about it,
but no,
please to don't apologize.
There's a real,
um,
there's a real argument for the,
the way that we live right now is not a
way that we were designed for.
Meaning that not that it can't be
sustainable,
are manageable and you can't figure out
a way to live a harmonious life in the
modern context,
but that a lot of people think that
we're just,
we would naturally fit right in,
in a tribal environment that it would
feel natural.
And a lot of people experience that when
they go camping for long stretches of
time when they're out in the woods
together.
You know,
for whatever reason,
they just decided to find a place and
live off the land.
I mean,
that's why I think a lot of those shows
like those,
um,
subsistence living shows like,
the,
those homesteading.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's very,
it's a very attractive to people because
I think there's a longing in our,
our DNA eve and where it just,
there's a pole.
There's a pull to that man.
I would love to just grow Kale and raise
chickens and live off the phone.
It's a lot of people that feel like
really,
really attracted to that and I think
it's,
it's something deep in our being that
we're longing for this connection to the
real world and we've done an amazing
thing creating cities.
It's dependence.
It's,
it's almost beyond our comprehension
because we're a part of it.
You know,
we're a part of it.
It's normal.
You get on the subway,
you get your car,
you drive through the city.
It seems normal,
but it's so far removed from every
single aspect of our history.
I mean,
this is so new.
It's so recent.
I think these people are just more in
tune.
I,
it's horrible that they have to deal
with these situations,
like the lack of water and toilets and
the diseases and all the other struggle.
But man,
there's a part of what they're doing and
the way they're living that just seems
like they're more in tune in a natural
way.
Right.
You would think that they would be more
depressed and uh,
but,
but like you heard,
you heard Leo may's laughing that when
they asked him about the bananas and he
just got tickled,
you know,
he couldn't,
couldn't hold himself from just laughing
and saying,
I can't count that much.
Test someone from Beverly Hills and say,
Hey,
this is what we got for a cause.
You can grow bananas now.
They were like,
fuck you.
How do I get Outta here?
Firstclass only you know,
where's my iphone?
Yeah.
It's weird.
It's weird band because essentially this
life is temporary ride for all of us
involved.
No one has ever got out of this thing
alive.
No one,
no one will.
It's not going to be you.
It's not going to be me.
We're not gonna make it.
No one makes it.
No one's ever made it before.
No one's ever going to make it.
So it's essentially like,
what is the quality of your experience
while you're here and how much people,
how many people are you touching?
And by that life,
by that definition,
you've lived one of the richest lives
that a person could ever live.
Thank you.
Do you realize that every time brown yet
feel like a piece of shit?
No,
I don't want anyone to feel that way at
all.
Really.
That,
but then the way you're so selfless in
that regard.
Well,
I,
I just,
okay,
if I just connect it back to that.
I remember little gimpy,
he got about 10,
he's chief of condos,
grandson,
um,
chiefly omaze brother is chief Alondo
and his grandson,
chippy,
uh,
had gotten paid basically 10,
12,
maximum,
probably 14 or 15 peanuts.
He worked all day long.
He's a five or six year old child that
worked from sunup to sundown.
And that's what he got paid was five or
up to 15,
uh,
peanuts.
And so a little handful in his little
hand.
And he came and he sat by me and I just
kind of put my arm around him and said,
how are you doing?
And he just instantly like put his hand
out for me to have in like,
he,
he went like this and he got like half
for him and got half for me and just put
half of his peanuts in my hand.
And like,
you just worked all day long for that,
you know,
like from sunup to sundown.
But they're just so incredibly generous,
you know,
hey,
what's mine is yours and what's yours?
I mean,
like,
it's fun to kind of sit around the fire
sometimes and eat because,
uh,
I mean it's,
it's rude and our culture and everything
else,
but,
uh,
but I just,
I just enjoyed it whenever people would
start eating off my plate and how to eat
off of their plate and it just kind of,
because it's part of it.
Yeah.
Or there's just a kind of a pile in the
middle or big plate,
big thing.
And it's like,
Hey,
this is what we have.
Let's,
uh,
let's share.
Let's,
uh,
let's make sure we share everything
together.
Now,
some eight B,
sorry to interrupt you.
But besides the farming and besides the
clean water,
what other,
what other changes have you witnessed?
Okay,
so [inaudible] um,
which is so cool.
He's like my little buddy yet getting to
watch him grow up and he's going to be
chief one day.
And uh,
so we just got determined that like that
young yeah.
Was his father had passed away and he
would have become the chief.
But uh,
she signed under the chief and who's
not,
it's not an election process or
anything.
Basically there is a,
just among the village,
whenever I think I forget,
I need to ask chief Alondo how he got
kind of voted in or whatever.
But he was just the one that showed the
leadership qualities,
the one that everyone followed.
Uh,
the one that was most respected,
the one that was kind of the most
knowledgeable or caring.
That's a huge thing for them.
Who's going to think about our interest
the most and um,
and then be strong enough to like be
tough whenever it needs to be tough.
And so chief Solano,
he's got incredible leadership skills.
Um,
like just a great guy.
He was one of the first ones that bought
into the vision for us to come in with
the land,
water and food.
A lot of people didn't trust us
thinking,
oh,
they're saying this.
And they have those tools that look like
they're going to drill wells,
but really they might be serving for
gold or diamonds or Colton who knows,
there just maybe using this as a cover.
But he was one that stood up in the
community and I was like,
no,
we believe them.
We're going to work with them.
And so from that he's been able to go
out and tell other communities what's
happened in their village.
And so one of the things that he's able
to go do is say,
how has changed everything to where they
were able to get land to secure that so
we could come in and drill the wells for
them.
Then after that they're able to start
farming and then you saw them going and
selling it at the markets to where they
can buy clothes for their kids.
Well,
it's not just about clothes.
Um,
little gimpy last time I was there
getting ready to leave,
um,
he's always around and I had just been
able to get for the weekend and I was
only being able to stay there for three
days,
this trip in that village,
cause we're going to some other places,
but I always stop and see him.
And so we're leaving and I don't get to
see kind of like my little buddy and I'm
like,
where's,
where's gyp yet?
And like,
Oh,
you'll see them as you go.
And so we got in the truck and we start
driving out and all of a sudden little
gimpy comes out of the schoolhouse and
he's running to us and I got to get out
and give them a hug,
tell him bye.
Um,
but what's so huge is he was the first
my booty pygmy ever in school,
in that region,
that area that they know of.
And so from kind of getting a little bit
more equal rights,
but then also being able to pay for
themselves.
Uh,
you know,
they're supposed to be a government
program where the pygmies can go to
school and go for free,
but they're like the only ones,
they're kind of like the native
Americans of,
of,
of Congo.
Um,
they have basically zero rights,
but that's one that the government has
said,
but normally it's not honored.
And secondly,
um,
they don't go to school if they need to
be spending time hunting or gathering.
Cause you know,
kids going to sit in school while he's
hungry,
he's not to be able to focus.
Right.
So for him to be able to have food to
take to school is a huge thing so that
he can sit there for them to be able to
pay the school fees on their own.
They didn't take that.
They said,
no,
we don't want the government program
saying we can come to school for free.
We're going to pay his school fees.
He's going to be chief one day.
We're investing into him.
And so to,
to know that once,
once there's some educated my booty
pygmies that takes away the last excuse
that I see for the government to not
honor them as true citizens of the
country.
Um,
they have no representation on the
government level.
Zero,
but there's over 200 tribes there.
All of them have representation.
But,
uh,
for years it was because,
or for always it was because they
thought they were half man,
half animal.
Well,
now it's,
um,
it's because they say no one's educated.
No one's ever graduated from primary
school or secondary school and no one's
ever graduated with a high school
degree.
And so until that happens,
no booty pygmy me or they don't have
representation.
So we're hoping that as they get
schooling,
there'll be able to go to the courts and
represent themselves and have more
rights in their community and culture.
I don't know if I've ever told you that,
but I'm a real dark part of the,
the pygmy history,
uh,
or Congolese history and what we,
what people have done to them,
what we have done to them at 1902 to
1906,
uh,
we had,
um,
a booty pygmy from night taree rain
forest,
right where I've lived in state and we
put them in the zoo.
Did I say that?
Maybe we didn't talk it was talked about
it on the podcast,
but yeah,
it's horrific.
Yeah.
It seems Ota Benga and we literally fed
them bananas in the Monkey House at the
Bronx in New York.
So we threw him bananas,
why he lived there with the monkeys and
a Christ in a human being like that.
And so,
uh,
you know,
that was a over a hundred years ago,
but it's almost like in those regions
where they don't have land or wa are
sorry,
they don't have running water and
electricity and a lot of education that
we do here,
some places are kind of stuck in this
pocket that's kind of about a hundred
years back.
Um,
and so some of that mentality still
exist.
So this could be the beginning steps and
just completely changing their culture,
educating.
That's what we were seeing,
having,
having the chief come out and say,
this is the first official ever land in
the booty pygmies own and our
government's history.
This is the first water,
well clean water source ever among them
a booty pygmies that they've ever owned
first time they're ever farming for
themselves and going to the market and
selling it that had local radio station.
Um,
there's only like one,
and it's the reinforce a few hours away,
but they came out to the market to do a
story,
uh,
with chiefly among them because they
were actually selling their produce and
they're like,
what?
The pygmies have always been hunter
gatherers.
Well,
the deforestation has made it basically
impossible for them to completely
sustain themselves off hunting and
gathering.
Animals are scared and skittish and they
run away from the trees that when they
fall sound like thunder going through
the forest.
So it makes it really hard to,
to go hunt,
um,
and be able to feed a whole tribe,
a whole village.
And so,
uh,
yeah,
to be able to say,
these are,
this is the first time they're farming
and selling this,
you know,
it just,
they're getting more and more,
I don't know.
It's like they're,
they're catching up with the people
around them and we want them to do it as
slow pace that they want.
So keep everything culturally sound for
them,
but what they do want to bring into
their culture,
we want to rally behind that.
Wow.
That's powerful dude.
You're,
you're there at the,
the steps of their culture changing.
I mean,
you're,
you're right there.
Well,
it's been,
it's been changing or,
or it's been corrupted so much because
of,
because of outside influences coming in
with the,
the chain saws,
you know,
that are mechanized ones where they can
just start cutting the trees down at
such a crazy rate.
Yeah.
I've seen those monster machines a
terrifying,
absolutely.
Stripped the bark off of it all in one
movement and cut it down.
Isn't that nuts?
Some of those.
It's scary.
Yeah,
I can get,
it's like science fiction movie stuff.
Yeah.
So they have that because there's a lot
of,
it's not as advanced as that,
but um,
they have guys just constantly day in
and day out that it's almost like,
uh,
aunts following each other through the
forest,
but they have bicycles and they throw
these long,
20 foot planks of a Mahogany or I think
it's a,
isn't it ebony that,
that other really heavy,
uh,
hardwood and they're just taking those
out of the forest all day long.
Uh,
just in lines,
there's a line of people going with
empty bicycles and there's a line coming
back out with it full of wood and they
just start legally deforesting putting
it in the,
of these 18 wheelers that normally have
two trailers on the back of them,
or two containers on the back and they
fill them to the top.
And that's where a lot of the bridges
collapse because they're going over,
they're overloaded.
I have a picture of that.
And it was a wild,
wild time where we got behind this,
uh,
this Lori that was ahead of us and we
didn't see it collapse or anything like
that,
but,
uh,
but we knew that they were carrying way
too much weight to cross the bridges
that we had crossed earlier.
And so we knew,
Oh man,
I hope that bridge is still is still up
and running by the time we get back.
Um,
and then it just completely caved in and
crashed.
Wow.
That bridge,
that bridge is ridiculous.
Yeah.
And so that was built and how do they
get across that?
They drove across that they were
driving.
That was,
that was the bridge.
Yeah.
Wooden planks.
And that's what we would drive across
all the time to go out and drill our
wells and stuff.
But the guys legally logging and
carrying way too much weight legally
illegally locked.
Yeah.
I thought you were saying legally,
no,
sorry.
Illegally.
Uh,
and so what kind of reinforcement that
they have in their laws,
like the deforestation laws,
uh,
basically nothing.
I mean,
they say it's illegal,
but,
but everybody does.
It turns a blind eye because they're
getting paid asset bribes.
But there's a lot of money involved in
hardwood.
Oh yeah.
Especially those rare African hardwoods.
And that's where the rubber boom
basically started was Congo by the
Belgiums King Leopold.
The second he wrote a crazy,
or there's a crazy book written about
him.
King Leopold's ghost talks about how
that was the African Holocaust and
basically that Congo had 20 million in
population,
but eight to 10 million people were
killed throughout the Belgians coming
and colonizing the Congo.
Um,
and he,
he paraded around like he was the hero
of Congo and we're bringing
infrastructure and business and they're
getting rich and they're growing and
they're getting water and buildings and
they're advancing so much.
And he would go on these public
campaigns basically talking about all
the good they're doing in the Congo,
but basically a,
you can see these terrible brutal
pictures of basically a father,
I think reaching out to his child's hand
that's on the ground because they took a
machete and cut his kid's hand off and
he's reaching out to grab it and he
doesn't have hands because they had
already cut his hands off too.
And so it's just been,
since,
it's just been brutal.
They're always,
because they had the,
it was the rubber and ivory boom,
and then after that,
now it's the rare hardwoods,
the gold,
the coal tan,
the uranium,
which they used to make cell phones
with.
Yup.
It conducts electricity that really high
rate,
but it stays cool so it doesn't overheat
her blow up on you.
And I think 80% of the world's Coltan
and it comes from the Congo and
basically all of its illegal mining by
rebels and everything else.
Yeah.
That's the dirty secret about people's
phones and a lot of the electronics that
we use.
Yeah.
Yeah man.
It's a,
but it's been,
it's been an incredible journey to be
part of tis.
I couldn't have dreamed this like
wouldn't have,
I wouldn't have thought it up or it
didn't have it on my goals list,
didn't have it on my radar as a kid.
You're so perfect for it.
That's what's so crazy.
It seems like it's kind of changed you
as a human being without and solidified
you.
Yeah.
And a lot of ways I think conviction
that you fight with,
it's not just that of a competitor.
It's like a man with a,
not even just a goal,
like a destiny.
It's a very strange,
you know,
you're,
you're doing something that's bigger
than most people can even comprehend.
And I feel like the weight of that is
pushing you forward.
And this,
uh,
this really incredible way to watch.
I don't know anybody like human,
the only guy I know,
like you,
you're the only guy I know.
Like you,
my friend.
So interesting and so,
so many awesome people that you've been
able to interview and have them pour
into your life and you pour into theirs.
And because of that,
there's so many cool things that are
happening in man.
I mean,
honestly,
I'm just grateful to have your
friendship and have this opportunity to
share cause it's helped out so much.
US be able to do this.
The very grateful,
very grateful as well.
Very grateful as well.
And I also feel like this,
I mean,
I can't even take credit for this thing,
this thing and made itself.
Yeah.
How do you miss,
I don't know,
turn into this,
you know,
I don't know.
I don't know what this thing is.
This thing,
I just have to show up and try not to
fuck it up.
That's what I tried to do.
I try to show up and not fuck it up.
Yeah.
But it's so nice.
Well,
you know what,
uh,
the float tank center that I go to in,
Oklahoma,
it's called Fluid Casey on w my first,
no second time in there.
Uh,
they were like,
oh he didn't check the box of how you
heard of this and a,
it was like friend family,
this or that.
And then Joe Rogan,
because they started up because of you
and like they're talking about,
hey,
you know,
there's probably 20 or 30 in the country
before joe started talking about it on
the podcast and now it's just grown.
So it's hundreds of them.
It's crazy.
I think there's over 300 people said,
do you have a piece of those?
I'm like,
nope.
Yeah,
no good,
good.
Keep going.
I don't want any money.
Yeah.
More power to them.
I think it's an amazing way to change
the way you look at the world and see
yourself and be alone with your
thoughts.
And I just think it's a,
it's one of the best tools for human
development.
Oh,
that's awesome.
I just think it's incredible.
I just,
I was shocked when more people didn't
know about it.
Yeah.
I had one in my house in 2002 wow.
Somewhere around there.
We'll do that.
Yeah.
2003 it's awesome.
You're,
one of the reasons why I got this house
was because it had a basement and I'm
like,
Ooh,
perfect place for a tank.
And I'm like,
that's,
I,
you know,
I'm,
I'm looking at houses all fucked up.
I might,
do,
I have enough room in the backyard to
shoot my bow yes.
To.
Is there a tank room?
You know what I mean?
That's how I look at houses now.
That's cool.
So how do you,
if it's okay,
how do you use,
I floated eight times now and the,
I'd finally done a two hour float,
which was I think a lot more beneficial.
Doing it bit lost the game changer.
Oh man,
that was awesome.
And then,
but Wednesday before my fight on Friday,
March 3rd,
I went in and I had this intention where
Neil from photo casey was like,
hey,
why don't you instead of just rushing in
here from training or rushing in here
from,
uh,
from the office at water for like come
in 30 minutes early,
kind of sit down,
chill,
close your eyes,
like,
you know,
set an intention.
Um,
and then do it.
And I came in and I had watched a
documentary called the flute nation.
Um,
and uh,
it was cool cause it's like an hour,
hour and a half.
And it showed a lot of different things,
but it showed some scientific stuff of
uh,
of sports psychologist and basically
visualization.
And then I've done some more research
and there's this like place in Tulsa
that has some brain doctors,
I mean doctors that are research and
neuroscience and for stuff,
but they're finally doing a clinical
study with people with anxiety and
depression.
It's finally fully funded.
Um,
and the guy was talking about it and was
saying that basically the same exact
results that antianxiety medicine has.
The float tank can do a hundred percent
naturally and that the studies are
coming out to back it up.
And so it's just really cool.
But the tank Wednesday,
I basically visualize the fight exactly
the way it went down on Friday.
I just had this intense tie that was the
best float I've,
I've had were just sitting there
thinking about the fight,
thinking about the fight and saying
everything that I wanted to do.
It's almost like I went to training
before then I got and I was drilling the
moves I wanted to do on the flight.
Then I went into the tank and I,
and I had right before that.
So I was drilling early that morning.
Um,
everything that I wanted to do on the
flight kind of visualizing before I went
into the tank.
Then when I came out I was,
or before I got in the tank,
after training,
I started to watch fight film on him,
see how he's moving and then I went into
the tank and I was able to just think
about what he's going to do,
think about what I'm going to do,
how I'm going to implement it.
And then it's not,
it's like the only thing only difference
was is I got two big throws instead of
one big thorough,
um,
in the vision had one throw and then in
the fight had two big throws but the
ground and pound straight into the arm
triangle.
Exactly what I've been envisioning.
So when you say personal development,
I'm like,
man,
I get it.
Like,
so how do you do it?
What do you,
I mean,
I don't know if that makes sense.
Like I'm wanting to learn how to go deep
with it.
Just let go and use it as a tool of
personal development.
Yeah.
The more often you can get into it,
the more you get relaxed and the more
you can sort of slip into that
comfortable state of not feeling the
water or feeling the air and just being
in your mind,
see nothing,
feel nothing released from your body.
And then I'll either go in there with
ideas like maybe I'll go in there.
I've,
I've gone over Jujitsu in there.
I've gone over different martial arts
techniques in there where you sort of
visualize movement.
Uh,
but a lot of that I use,
I do,
I'll go over material.
Like I've,
I'll have ideas.
Sometimes it fucks up my float where I
have an idea that I can't let,
like I have
to set something up where I have a voice
activated recorder inside the float tank
where I can talk,
but part of me doesn't want to talk
while I'm in there.
I just want to be alone with my thoughts
because I think when you talk it'll take
you out of it.
But there's some,
some ideas that I don't want to escape
me because ideals are slippery,
man.
They,
they,
you know,
you have a great idea.
Like sometimes I'll have a great idea
when I'm in bed and I'm like,
oh,
I'll remember that.
I don't remember it ever.
Like you fucking ever,
I might remember one at a 10 that I
think I'm going to remember.
So I'm probably going to have to figure
out some way to record things while I'm
in the tank.
But for me,
um,
you know,
it depends on what I'm trying to do.
Trying to be balanced,
think about life,
think about my behavior,
think about my,
my interaction with people,
you know,
my is to have as much energy and,
and an appreciation as I should do.
I have as much gratitude as I should.
You know,
I want to,
I just want to optimize my thought
process,
you know?
And then definitely not claiming that I
do or that I always have it right.
I definitely don't.
It's an ongoing process and that's one
of the realities of being a person,
the idea of the perfect person.
It just doesn't exist.
And I think it's a bad,
it's a bad model to strive for and
instead he should strive for doing your
best whenever you can,
as much as you can.
And I think that reviewing your thoughts
and reviewing,
um,
your,
your whole mental process is a very
important part of optimization about
being your best and just taking account
and looking at it from,
I think it's one of the rare moments
where you're actually alone with your
thoughts,
you know,
where there's no influence of the body
that the distractions of the body,
of just even the weight of sitting down
and feeling your butt on the chair,
your,
your elbows on his desk,
all those things are factors and there
they're being calculated by your mind.
And the way,
the analogy that I always use is if you
and I were having this conversation,
but right next to us as a Jackhammer,
it would be super distracting.
But that's just input that Jackhammer is
just,
it's just profound input.
And I think that everything is input.
Social Cues,
looking at people,
sounds,
feeling touch,
gravity,
all those things or input that is going
into the mind that your mind has to
calculate in the absence of any input,
whether it's physical touch,
you feel like you're flying through
space,
you feel it in zero gravity.
You don't feel the water cause it's the
same temperatures or scan,
you're floating in it.
It's total silence,
total darkness and the absence of that
input.
I think your brain becomes super
powered.
I think it becomes supercharged and I
think you get to see things in a much
clearer way.
And I've,
I've,
I've seen myself at fault when I thought
it was innocent.
I've seen myself a happy and fulfilled
when I thought it was longing.
I've,
it's given me a much more balanced
perspective and a better way of
addressing the realities of the
complexities of life.
Hmm.
Yeah.
That's great.
That's awesome.
Powerful tool,
man.
It was weird to me that around 2002 when
I really started talking about it,
that nobody knew what the fuck it was.
I was like,
how is this a weird,
how am I the guy who's talking about
this,
how's the UFC commentator,
the guy who's talking about floating and
we just didn't make any sense to me.
Yeah,
no,
I,
I don't think I,
I mean you had talked about it and I
knew about it,
but it wasn't until I got in the tank
and came out of the tank for the first
time that then I got it.
Yeah.
It was like,
Oh man,
like this is awesome.
And the physical aspects of the way,
the magnesium in your body feel and the,
the looseness of the being in zero
gravity environment,
what feels like zero gravity?
Everything gets loose.
It just relaxes the back,
relaxes the arms and knees,
the,
the neck.
Everything just gets loose in there and
you come out just feeling good.
You want to hug people.
Oh yeah,
I know.
That's exactly how I came out.
I came out and had a smile from ear to
ear and when I came out of it,
they're like,
oh,
you have the post float glow.
And I actually gave the guy a hug if I
didn't even know his name,
but gave him a big hug and it was so
cool,
man.
And it's neat.
Uh,
the,
the float community seems like a like,
like everyone just chill.
Everyone that has a deeper appreciation
for that might be too much,
but it seems like everyone's got a
deeper appreciation for life where they
just,
um,
I dunno.
I think there's something to what you're
saying.
It sounds pretentious,
but you're right,
there is something there.
I know what you're saying.
It's like saying that,
I don't know.
It's,
there's something special about it.
It,
I think a big part of what that
something special is,
is the alleviation of tension.
And I think tension,
you're much like inflammation causes a
lot of diseases and a lot of disorders
that people have pertaining to dye it
and that inflammation causes,
like,
like you were talking about with a,
you're a CELIAC.
Absolutely.
That is a lot of it is based on
inflammation,
right?
Right.
I think tension is,
uh,
in,
in many ways the physical tension is
also a,
another,
a real boundary to comfort.
And that physical tension is alleviated
greatly when you're in that tank.
And I think when you're more
comfortable,
you're more relaxed.
When you're more relaxed,
you're more open.
When you're more open,
you're more loving.
I think all those things sort of
cascade,
you know,
they,
they feed on each other and they help.
And when a tense person that's like
stressful like fuck,
fuck,
you know,
you got Janet,
it's really hard to like be calm and
kind,
you know,
it's like you're so wound up.
I think that thing removes a lot of the
physical aspects of being wound up.
And then on top of that,
the deep meditative effects of being in
that tank,
especially if you go into it like you
did with like a vision or a direction
and a thought to work on.
I think it does wonders for free of
thought process.
I mean I'm still learning about it
because the first couple times I was
just trying to just wipe my mind clean
and it coming this stress
completely stress free,
feeling completely stress free at least
was awesome.
And then going in there with an
intention and with a goal with a fight
just a couple of days away.
I don't,
I don't know that this is what happened,
but in training I had been feeling great
but then it felt like something just
turned on or sort of firing where it
connected.
Like the mental visualization to the
physical of actually going in there and
doing it the exact way that I saw it was
something that just,
I kind of blew my mind.
It was,
it was cool to see that happen.
Um,
because you'd want to see the match or
the fight a hundred times in your head
before we ever go out there and do it.
Um,
I mean not,
not put things in,
it's where if it goes bad or if it
doesn't go exactly the way in the fight
that then you freak out during the
fight.
But you want to have a goal and an
intention and know what you're going to
do in there.
And I think that's probably what connor
did when he was fighting Aldo.
He knew he was going to go in there and
indeed quick and he saw that happening.
And so I'm not saying I don't want put
words in this top.
When he talked about it after the Eddie
Alvarez fight,
he said,
I,
I had a vision of me standing here with
the second belt and acquitted the focus
me other their belt.
He was like really upset,
right.
I visualize this,
I wanted,
and then tyron woodley of all people,
they had to give his belt.
Right.
It was really cool that they did that,
that the tire and allowed that to
happen.
Kudos to him.
But then that,
that,
you know,
the visualization of a goal is very
important to like solidifying this idea
of what that goal is in your mind.
Visualization.
It's been,
um,
there's been studies done on
visualization and as far as athletics
and,
and skill learning and some people
believe it is as important as physical
practice,
which is kind of crazy,
you know?
Yeah,
no,
I can see that.
Um,
I mean Kenny Monday who's been involved
in them and make community quite a lot.
He was my high school wrestling coach.
And,
uh,
he told me,
go home,
write a goal,
put it with somewhere,
you can see it.
So I wrote down,
uh,
he told me to write down state champ,
but I wrote down national champ and I
put it above my bed.
And then over here,
you know,
working with him,
training,
getting some wrestling moves,
I put,
uh,
a step around body lock on the left and
I played a lateral drop on the right.
And so my,
my favorite rest and move on the left
and my second favorite wrestling move on
the right.
And when I won my first national
championship,
it was what the move on the left and one
on one my second,
it was with the move on the right.
And so it was,
I was going to bed thinking about it,
dreaming about it,
Waking Up,
starting my day,
thinking about it,
and uh,
in wanting to really put that in action.
And so I,
I totally get it and I,
I need to be more conscious of it and
dive even deeper into it because I'm
like you,
I agree that,
um,
or at least I can see the point and how
it's valid that the mental focus and
energy and visualizing is pretty much
just as important as actually physically
doing it.
It's huge.
And all of them together are really what
it's all about.
Yeah.
It's none of that.
No,
no,
no aspect.
Yeah,
no aspect can be ignored.
Um,
I got to get out of here soon.
Is there anything else you want to tell
people about or wrap this up?
Man,
we can,
we can get to wrapping it up,
but a real quick,
we have two goals going on right now
where I'm at water four.org.
We're doing a world water day campaign.
Uh,
we threw up a goal to raise a set
audacious goal to do that water tank,
water tower,
water kiosk system.
Uh,
it's going to serve 4,000 people and
then create more water wells.
It's a $50,000 goal,
but we've already raised 35.
Someone yesterday gave 25 grand to it.
Um,
and so we're,
we're,
we got a f,
uh,
about a week left and,
we're hoping to get another 15 because
if that happens,
we're able to really make that
sustainable,
that team there in Rwanda.
Um,
and then,
I mean,
we know for that people go to
waterford.org.
Yeah.
Waterford I'd worry if they go to my
search number four,
number four.org.
And then it's like campaign,
it's,
it's our world water day campaign.
I think I have it up right now on my
social media,
on twitter and on instagram.
It's the,
the link,
uh,
like the website or the link in the bio.
Um,
it's the actual campaign link.
So if you just go to,
at the big pygmy on instagram or
twitter,
um,
you can just click right there and get
right to the campaign and yeah,
and for people that can give one time,
uh,
that's,
that's where you can give one time and
if you want,
we're trying to make us sustainable
here.
And so if we had people that bought in
and,
uh,
did $25 a month over the course of a
year,
your gift,
15 people clean water for the rest of
their lives.
And the reason that is,
is because we train up the locals to go
out and be able to repair the wells and
always be able to serve the community.
And so $25 a month goes a real long way.
Um,
and yeah.
So brother,
I appreciate you so much.
I appreciate you seal maxim is always,
always a pleasure having you in here.
And thank you very much for the gifts.
And please tell your a pygmy family.
Thank you for this.
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna definitely have this frame.
Absolutely,
man.
Justin Wren,
ladies,
gentlemen.
Whoa.
See you guys soon.
Bye.
[inaudible].