[inaudible] take notes while I take
totes up. The marijuana soap. Oh,
you want to choke guts. Smoked duck float.
Vicky. Smells familiar. Y'All don't back.
Lay off the hook.
The layoff.
Good lights and take notes while I take
totes up the marijuana smoke though you
weren't a choke gun. Smoke done float.
Vicky [inaudible] off the racks.
Lay off the hook. The layup
motherfucker. Say Your prayers.
Hail Mary full of grace.
Smack the bitch in the face.
Take a Gucci bag and a north face store
for bank. Chappa if she I know, huh?
Funding with the money. Oh, you got
me. Mistake. I don't want no rape you.
I just want [inaudible]
to call him Mister Macho.
[inaudible] Macho.
I got so much to be done with the stop
list to break off the wake up shaky
smalls and mixed up with led Zeppelin.
Who did this? Let me shop. See,
don't remember
every hit in your and
sucking on the [inaudible].
Fucking bad ass doesn't even
say he did it. That's weird.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the podcast.
Our guest today is the one and only Mr
Al Madrigal,
longtime friend Allan.
I first worked together in San Francisco
at the old old cars, tiny carves,
a hundred seater, didn't even
see it. 150 probably 200 tops.
Tom Sawyer is squeezing
chairs. Really? You legally,
I don't think you'd call kinds
of fire codes. Look violations,
let's say let's say 200 let's say one
50 so we don't get anybody in trouble.
But it was a fucking awesome little
club and then now it's like totally
different now it's like this big
gigantic we did new year's. Yeah,
first New Year's. You
remember that? A lot of gigs
going way back to like what? 2000 maybe
2000 and think something like that. Yeah.
11 years. Cause I haven't been doing,
I met, I met you when I had just been,
you know,
started to do standup comedy a year in,
we worked together at that old cobb's.
You were funny.
Back Down even a little fuck.
And it's funny cause I just
think I just figured it out.
I just feel like my latest
stuff has been clearly a videos.
How many years? 12 years. 12 years.
That's what they say. They say 10 years,
10 takes 10 years for you to become a
real comic. You know, like I buy that,
I buy that totally,
you know,
or maybe put it takes it seven years
to get your law degree and then another
seven years for you to
become a good lawyer. So it's
like that's the same thing.
We stand up practicing as a professional
comedian for x amount of years.
Then you know, becoming really
good at it, finding your own space,
finding who the fuck you are without
influence of other comedians and actually
having your real
personality be you on stage.
I should takes a long ass time really
does. Especially if you're distracted.
If you have other things going
on and it's easy for all.
So you lose your way as a stand
up. And a lot of guys, you know,
just stop trying. And my big
pitfalls have always been TV shows.
Like uh, there've been
great, you know, news radio,
especially like when I was
on Newsradio we learnt,
we worked some serious long hours.
So you're working in,
you're taking away from your stand up,
you're not able to hit the clubs as
much as you'd like. I haven't been on,
I've done six pilots and heaven too,
that made it on the air.
And so I, you know exactly what
you're talking about. This,
you're working every single day and
then I have you, we have families. Yeah.
And you got to spend time with them and
then stand up gets pushed to three when
stand up is usually number one.
Very hard to justify getting on
stage all the time. And for me,
I just straight got lazy because not only
did I, I did stand up on the weekends,
I would do like,
oh dare you go the funniest
I've ringtone to. Oh,
by the way, we're sponsored by the
flesh, by the way. That's a good reason.
That's why was calling Karma fleshlight
calling again. Tell us yo bitch,
we pioneer. Yeah. Yeah. We are
actually sponsored by the flashlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net and click
the link, you get 15% off and uh,
and I endorse it. It's fucking good
product. Have you ever used one buddy?
No feeling no one has had sex with, so
let's play, that's the butthole version.
Yeah. Gray touch that.
It's technology, man.
Put your finger on amazing plastic. Using
realistic, it's very realistic, right?
Sure. This is a good product. There's
nothing better for beating off.
It's a commitment. You gotta.
You know, you got to go out
of your way and say, okay,
I'm going to fuck this tube now within
this and the coconut juice. I feel like,
uh, I learned to grade. Yeah.
C Two o sent us a bunch of
cases of coconut juice, but
I ran out of them. Sorry.
C Two o this is Amy and Brian's.
I had to pay for this shit,
which is really good too.
They're all good. Yeah. Great.
But CQL gave me some free
shit. So props. Um, but the um,
the flush light, if you go, like I said,
if you go to the link on Joe rogan.net,
click it and enter in the code Rogan and
you get 15% off and it's a good product.
Like I said, keep the
push that, where is it?
Put that lid on it and
I got to keep it fresh.
Don't want to get a dust it with
Ken and Shit, man. I got cats.
Yeah. So yeah, the in your
allergic to cats. So you might be,
so that's the thing is I,
it hasn't affected me yet,
but there's a very good chance
that I could completely lose it.
And you have to be rushed to the hospital.
There's no big deal.
The volcano's going to bypass all
that and put it in order for you.
Is it a breathing thing or is he
get swollen or anything? Eyes.
Throat closes the hole. Oh, Shit.
Mouth to mouth resuscitation might
be necessary. In other words,
he's a [inaudible].
That's the thing.
That's what a large part of my
act is become about allergies.
Me like talking to a Cholo,
but I have allergies. Yeah.
Like, no, I do, um,
like a couple of different stories
that I have is a Cholo soccer dad.
Then I'm talking about and a,
and stuff like that.
It's all about me having allergies
in front of black people.
Yeah. Hey, sorry.
Here's a fascinating thing that I
read about the h one n one virus,
that flu virus. They're saying now
that the people that survived it,
the people that got it and survived it,
they have like super immune systems
now and now they don't get any flows.
They don't get any of the flows.
It's like in the,
they think that they may be able to
come up with a universal vaccine for is
based on the h one n one wow. Based
on the people that survived. Yeah.
Pretty fascinating shit man.
I use a motherfucker of a flu.
The thing about this flows is they're
getting better. They're getting stronger,
they evolve just like everything else
evolves and when these assholes take their
fucking medicine,
they don't take it all.
Especially this is especially
true about antibiotics.
People who get sick and they
take antibiotics and they only,
they only take it for like
until they feel better,
like say if you're supposed
to take it for 10 days,
the bacteria that survive is like super
powerful antibiotic resistant bacteria,
so that becomes like this strain.
It's almost impossible to kill.
That's where this mercy shit comes from.
Now the people are dying from
these crazy staph infections.
It's because assholes don't
take their fucking pills.
They take like a percentage of them and
then they quit and I developed this new
fucking super virus because
of that and he's cons.
So you're going to finish all your
medication finishing medication bitches.
You don't,
you're not smarter than the scientists
who shit till a little we're to asking
people to do is use the fleshlight.
Yes. You feed off in that shit.
Here's your medication, take the
all of it, take all that shit.
I'm really bad at that. I admit it.
I get down to the wire too and yeah,
she didn't do that just
as guilty as anybody else.
And part of the manatee for
humanity take that shit.
They should give to ekster just so I
don't take this to treat you like a child.
I'd be Chad at birth control, but
yeah, they said, oh, you'd be pregnant.
How would be totally knocked out for
sure. Portions all day. And Yeah,
you know, they say that a big supply of
pharmaceutical drugs are in the water.
The water supply. There's
not a big supply, but a big
percentage like you know,
this measurable amounts of everything.
Everything from antidepressants
to birth control pills. Yeah.
Cause people flush their shit
flush their stuffed on the toilet.
I mean that's where your
water supplies coming from.
A lot of it's coming from re
constituted poop water. Yeah.
You know in some places, right? Isn't
that where they get their water supply?
They fucking fix up the poop.
Water
doesn't go anywhere. It's never going
to die. It's the same water. Right.
How much can you fool to filter out
where you're leaving in the birth control
pills, but giving me no poop. You're
sure there's no poop in this academy.
Some poop in there. You Fuck?
I'd like some poop free water.
The same water is coming our way
that birth control pills get into.
Unless I'm ignorant about
how birth control pills get
into water and they're not
being
well she is the amount of worth of pills.
You're like a,
anything going into the water
system, is that really, I mean,
large enough to effect it. I mean
I don't, it's a good question,
but I would like 0% of
birth control pills,
a money diet 0.0 [inaudible]
no pregnant water anymore.
At least what, what? Yeah.
Um, I think, you know,
we've gotta be real careful
about that shit man.
You know the idea that water is 96% of
our bodies and that's the one thing that
we love to throw things into. It's a
fucking stupid, you know, we need water.
Obviously humans need water over always
dumping shit in the water cause it's so
easy. We're such constantly owl. Owl does.
I do a lot of things vigilante dumping,
dumping oil and shit.
I see.
I'm guilty because when I see a
dumpster near my house and my God,
I got to put a fucking that
chair in there and I thought,
well there's nothing wrong with that.
That's I think Robin emotional countries
in these companies are actually locking
a Oh, you know, like
1-800-JUNK-YOU get, is that? Yeah.
That's where the come and
they come and get your shit.
They're shipping it to fucking China
where they're paying for cheap landfill.
Some cute,
huge like secret in the night.
Fucking barges full of our shit shows
up in China and landfill all over the
place.
And so I mean no flushing pills down the,
I mean that's at least of our trouble.
It's all these foreign countries that
don't have any luck in laws that are just
allowing you to dump and Barry and Huck
is toxic waste that we're shipping over
there. Do China's crazy. They
develop some new ECO city.
It's fucking fantastical. Have you seen
this thing? No, it's on my Twitter. Brian,
have you seen it? It was,
I posted it. Someone,
someone tweeted it and I retweeted it.
It's pretty fucking amazing man.
This is new city that they have.
That's like some,
it looks like like some
gigantic future space.
Solar powered like um,
like greenhouse of a city.
It's like they have glass domes
over the down buildings. It's China,
Pauly shore running around inside
the Simpsons.
What is the title of the
article so someone can Google
if they want to Google it.
What does it say?
Tagine Eco City in China.
You just type in Eco City in
China. China. I'll find it.
It's an amazing world.
We live in that and just do the j I.
N how fucking cool is that?
You can just type that into a box and it
just gives you the instant information
information instant. Yeah. We
don't even realize how crazy it is.
Why is there college anymore? Yeah.
Right. Just a way to torture you. Yeah.
Who has to go somewhere and
foster commercial on right
now where they're doing
that.
You just see families sitting around a
phone and he'd look over and they see
just to be actors who they don't
know who exactly it is and it says,
his says his name is tell the toe and
these people are just googling and getting
instant information on the
spot when they need it.
And that's totally what we're doing.
And my phone is fantastic. So amazing.
That's when people have their
phones on in comedy shows. I say,
I realize that's a fine, fascinating
device. I mean I have one,
I fucking losing it all the
time and I love it. Yeah,
now's not the time to have it, so
just put it in. That's my first one.
You do wig out on people that film you?
Um, I make, I make them stop a lot.
Some people are just so blatant with it.
They're like sitting right
in the front row and they're,
they're pointing a camera
and filming, like just flip
video camera, just straight.
And uh, I usually point
out, but sometimes people
don't care, you know, just enjoy
the fucking moment. Enjoy the show.
Doesn't have to go on to youtube.
I do laugh factory and you're standing
on the stage and there's two monitors on
the side. You've done that closure.
And I sometimes look in the audience.
People are watching me on
a fucking monitor. Yeah.
Yeah. That's weird. If people do
that, the UFC all the time too,
and they watch the fight to the Monitor.
It's in front of you. Yeah. Wow.
How can I do that?
Sometimes ringside at catch myself
doing that dude replayed side.
The guys are fighting five feet in front
of me and I'm looking at this little 13
inch monitor in front of me. Well,
sometimes you get a better perspective.
That camera still funny that I'm
doing it. Yeah, you're right there.
It's right there and I'm watching a TV.
Yeah.
I like it on the UFC just because
it's like the different camera angles.
Especially when you get on the ground,
you can't see anything on the floor. Yeah,
totally. Yeah, that's, that's where
it's real confusing too. If you don't,
if you're in the stands and
you don't have commentary,
like a lot of times you don't see what
guys are going for. You don't see what,
how a guy slept. Trying to set something
up. You know, you just [inaudible].
My very first one was the uh,
Las Vegas Palms will resoling Fox a fight,
a spike night fights
spike fight, fight. Spike
couldn't get it out. It
was great. Did we get it?
This is the finals of the ultimate fighter
and then they have a Tivo was around
a, he also got, he got a ticket
from you and he's had to close her.
He was just texting us,
constantly saying who's sitting next
to and so on until really? Yeah.
A little girl tweets rampage who was
behind them and you tell him in front of
her in pain. Couldn't believe, you know,
so he was all abuzz location and very fun
and games like a little kid in a candy
store. He said he was just loving life
that was dressed up. He wore a blazer,
the blazer, rainbow socks
down. He's a good dude. Good.
Very Fun and funny guy.
Very smart guy.
And he's been around for a long time and
a hilarious, frustrating when you know,
you see go like that.
It's not getting anywhere and you're like,
how come you know what's going on?
What's happening?
Why isn't it more very famous,
you know, strange world.
We live in this comedy world.
So when I met you,
you'd only been doing it like
what? Two years? Even less
than that. Less than that.
Wow. Dude, I met you in
the day's Sun and um,
you recommended me for the
comedy store. Yeah, I'm sorry.
He was you and Freddy
Soto. And I was like, oh,
this is the best I'm going to go in.
And then we were doing a
Fridays and Saturday nights
there until everything blew
up over there. And then, uh, I, you
know, I've worked with you quite a bit.
It's thought of comedy
store jokes, man. Yeah.
And you used to have the DEA,
you put in the recorder.
What I always appreciated the Jill
bought a digital recorder, not a digital,
a CD burner for the club.
And so I'd go in there with a CD just
constantly on a Friday night and just show
up and hand my CD. I have old three
different things that I bought.
I started out with a dat player,
a dat recorder.
I had digital audio tape installed there.
But the
problem with that is that no one had a
dat player. Yeah. So then I said okay,
we'll get many discs cause
that seems like a good format,
but the problem was many disc died
out. Sure. So then I switched it to CD.
So it's awesome.
So I put three different systems in there,
the CD,
and then you handle all of like those
live moments that you never really get on
a comedy album.
Yeah. All recorded it at the comedy
store. Yeah, that was perfect. Yeah. Well,
you know,
just like it did.
We needed to have it there and
there was a budget issue. Yeah.
There's the comedy store appreciated.
You've,
after you did all these nice
[inaudible] did the real comedy store,
did you know that was more,
my loyalty was in the first place to put
in the kitchen over there. Good guys.
You get food poisoning 20 years too
late. What the fuck? You know, how many,
how much money they lost from not having,
but you know what dude,
it was the comedy store. This
was supposed to be it. The,
the real issue there was that they stopped
nurturing good comedy and they had a
lot of those issues that al and I were
talking about right before the show that
he's dealing with there right
now. If it's, they don't
have the right intentions.
They don't have,
there aren't looking out for comedy there.
They're not even looking
out for the club anymore.
They're just looking
out for short dollars.
They're looking out for what's gonna
work and what's going to get the money
right now.
Yeah, it sounds, it's tough
because I really, I mean on
those Friday and Saturdays,
I remember those.
I honestly won't some of the best nights
you were there for all of them. Yeah.
Some of the best nights, uh, that I've
ever had as a comic, that place packed.
And it's like that old cops you were
talking about when you get that 150 to 200
seater really packed. It's great. Yeah.
That was a fun Gig man.
Because when I was doing fear factor,
I couldn't really travel.
And so I just set up shop at the comedy
store and I set it up so that I paid for
everything. I paid for
the sound system. I did,
I advertised everything in my space.
I never asked for a dime pack the place
every weekend and work totally for free.
Yeah. And um, when, when that
was happening in man, that was,
that was like the most fun time ever
for comedy for us, for me, you know,
so we had some good times in that past,
meet him. I mean, crazy weekends there.
At least 10 times. I bought the
entire audiences shots. That's crazy.
At least about times. Remember
that the whole audience had shots.
Whenever I would kick somebody
out, I would go, look,
I know that we just went through
this douchey moment together,
but we can change this.
We can get out of this feeling.
I know this feels terrible.
We had some drunk assholes yelling things
and they got kicked out and everybody
feels weird. Like, what the fuck man,
you know, and there's a few people going,
they paid to, you know, to stop.
Those are douchebags right? Let's,
we're not douchebags we're
going to change all this shit.
So I would like to buy you guys a
drink, everybody and, and you know,
kind of bring the mood back and
everybody would cheer and we'd all wait.
I would say that's the one
thing that we gotta wait,
we gotta wait and everybody
waited. Man. Every time.
We never had an issue with people drinking
their shots early. The waitresses,
they hustled, they came back and forth.
They had to do like fucking 10 15 trips,
you know, with big trays, full of shots.
But we give shots to everybody
that wanted them. Yeah.
Probably a few alcoholics fell off the
wagon. Probably a few guys who were like,
wow, fuck it man, he's giving me
a shot. I don't want to be a dick.
And next thing blacked out with his pants
down. You know, very a lot
of people's, it's shots for
everybody. But that was the,
that was a shit load of people.
Thousands of dollars every time it was
the shots for everybody and there was 10
people there are dying. That's what shots
for everybody in a big fucking room.
But it was, you know, it worked though.
It totally restored the
vibe because first of all,
everybody knew that I was paying for it.
So you know,
it was going to cost real
money and you know, and it was,
it was just all for the vibe to
fix it cause we can, you know,
all that was the, the whole
attitude about it. And that's,
that should be the attitude of comedy.
You know, it's supposed to be the,
it's about getting into it
and find, finding, you know,
finding what's fucking fun about and
taking everybody with too. What's fun,
you know, and when you,
you have an opportunity to
correct the vibe of the room,
you know, if you can do it like that,
that's really what it's all about right
now. Now, you said you had used to
do a podcast like five years ago,
five years ago when the podcast first
came out and those were really big back in
the day and they kind of died
and it, was there a, yeah,
there was like a poser because, um,
you know, it was four years ago.
I don't even know what she,
you feel your own podcast called?
I did 17 episodes of the lot of
you think it's a lot of them.
I did a TV show in 1994. Only did six
episodes. I can tell you a lot about it.
It was,
um,
it was a, we had sort of many names
for the thing, but it was the, um,
uh, I, we did it with Peter Myriad at
a comedy writer. And so it was just,
and he's half Mexican and I'm
half Mexican and it was too
combining full [inaudible] calls
it two. Yeah, one maximum together.
We are one Mexican done me a good
name for it. Can one Mexican feather.
We one Mexican and we still don't speak
Spanish. You don't speak any of them? No,
not really.
It's horrible because must get mad at you.
Yeah, it's, it's uh, yeah,
like I said, just like the
allergies to put music. It's,
I'm on a weird spot with the
big guy with the Laker Jersey,
don't we guys
fromm also was at the,
in La, the segment you,
when I was working with Joe and San
Francisco, when we first started,
I didn't even know I was Latino comic.
I was just a comic and then you moved
down to la and immediately I got put in
this Hbo Aspen Comedy thing
where it was me, Jeff Garcia,
Freddy Soto.
Willy Birth Center.
Oh, that's fine. You guys together?
Yeah.
And they gave me a tin of red hots.
They brought me a 10 of red hots and
they said, this is for you, says Hbo,
Latino on it, and this guy, Mateo
comes up and goes, my name is Mateo.
Can I interview you in Spanish? You know,
and shit like that. I was like, yeah,
you can fucking try to work out.
I don't know why. I don't know.
I'm not a Latino comic.
I'm just the one comic.
And I went to my friend Becky Pedago,
I was like,
they give you a hat and they
gave me fucking red hots.
[inaudible]
okay, let them know with these
guys. And I looked at her,
I swear to God with these guys
said, I said, I looked at her, I go,
I'm a Mexican comedian,
this word
of God. And I was like, I just learned
it. Oh No, we want to, can I Aaron?
So I did the sets in and that's
weird for me because you know,
just like you sort of get put in that
group and they all sort of make funny.
I did a new years.
They make fun of you would like to,
real Mexican comics were there.
I remember walking up to you don't have
those comedy break dance circles form
where it's just a Commie, uh, like a group
of comic standing in a circle. Right,
right, right. And I do see two TV, the
Latino Comedy Festival on, you know,
TV chauffeurs, CTV as Shitty, you
know, want to be English speaking.
Latinos station I think still exists
and it's really tiny at the time.
So they're doing stand up. And
I sent him a there with, um,
this Guy Rick Cutera's and all these
Mexicans comics and they're talking about
how him and Gabriel lived together
and they don't go on the road.
They go out and they're on the road so
much that no one's ever at their house.
And I looked at him and I go, wow,
it must have a lot of dead plants
and there, and the guy looks at me, he
goes, we don't have any power plants, bro.
What are you talking about? We don't
have any fine or what the fuck? No class.
That's how I feel like
around all these guys.
I got made fun of every night over new
years by a comic that I was supposed to
co headline with. I'll never do another
Latino show again. You've got to be, yeah,
it's a co headline.
Who is this fucking Willy Willy
birth sending me funny funnies. Yeah,
well he didn't think he
was making fun of me,
but we had a conversation about
it and I felt like he was just,
he kept bringing up my name, like Sam
and he actually said this at one point.
He goes, I don't want my kids to grow
up. Like, Oh, you know, like all scared.
Whoa. Like that. And she was, was
talking, you know about me, you know,
and doing the whole,
my name is Al Madrigal and I'm a lot know
like, okay, I fucking get it. I talk about
myself and I'm stepped, self-deprecating.
So we were doing the New Year's count
down and um, he was off on his time.
He started trying to do the
countdown five minutes early.
Everybody has fucking cell phones. They
call them one, you know, they're like, no,
it's not it.
And so he has to wait.
And then he yells to the back of the
room to the manager at the Sac Punch.
He goes, you're trying to
humiliate me, bro up here on stage.
And I grabbed the back, Mike flipped
it around really quick and I go,
what's a matter,
Willie?
Don't like being humiliated on stage
is ever fucking get through you like a,
and he's like, this is bad ass.
He's like a East La Street fighter,
uh, killed people. And then, uh,
he goes, we had a problem
or only but, and I go, look,
Willie. And I made him understand,
I go, I get just as angry as you do,
but I don't have the fighting
ability. Do you understand me? I go,
I'm just as fired up as is.
You've killed guys, you know,
and fucking Nile aided people. And, uh,
I don't have the ability to do that,
but I still feel fucking angry as shit.
So you got angry at him saying that
you are scared to talk shit about,
you're still like to what
Andy comic brings up to get
next comic before them and
starts really fucking referring
to somebody, you know? And, uh, yeah,
it was using me as an
example of what will happen.
What if you were really good friends with
them and they were joking around with
them like,
you know,
like I have friends and they'd go on after
each other and joke around about each
other and it's just like Joey
will go on after Ari and,
and you know, and talk about
art being a Jew, you know,
but how it wasn't real guys know
each other. Real good, real good.
I always make fun of Joey. Yeah.
You know, but it's like, oh no,
I'm just saying it then it's all about
the relationship. I totally get that.
Your relationship, it's more like he's
actually mocking you. He's say yeah,
I think you really,
I don't want my kids to grow up like you
will scared Montreal in 2002 and I've
told them this story and we've
talked about it and I walked out to,
when I use the only other non white,
you know,
like he's the only Latino guy there and
I don't know anybody and I wait until I
go, hey Willie a hey, hi.
Nice to meet Ya. Al Madrigal.
And he looked at me and goes, you don't
even see your own last name, right, bro?
Like,
wow.
It like motherly Gal to really,
could you imagine if you really did
that dual enrolled your tongue and
everything, you'd be committed to
every other word. Exactly. It's like,
do it for that. Yeah. Just roll the name
and not really, when I was in college,
you went to Tijuana.
What? What? Oh, excuse me.
Yeah.
So you've got to commit.
When I do the Wayans and I
have to pronounce Dude's names,
I have to decide whether or not,
I don't want to commit to that Super
Spanish way of saying things, you know?
And there's a lot of Mexicans in the
UFC, right? I mean, sure, yeah. Yeah.
I think it's the correct way to
say it, but it's like, you know,
like Montreal is how we say it, but
they say Montreal, they say Montreal.
So really you should say Montreal.
Like who the fuck are you to say Montreal?
And he out their cities to get pissed
when people say Frisco and shit like that.
And nobody knows. San Franciscan
likes stuck in for it. You
really like touchy. Oh,
San Fran. That's a, that's it used to get
pissed at them calling it Sam phone. No,
no, no. I'm just saying it's a
native to be for a Faggot Ville.
It's what is the most derogatory names?
No,
I'm just saying when you're calling
it the wrong thing and you're a local,
you know, I mean, we're not, no one's
expected to browns saying faggot anymore.
I just haven't used it wasn't
even, I just is an example. Oh,
try not to think that someone else.
Yeah, I totally stopped saying faggot.
Did you hear that? Toronto is
censoring the Mark Knopfler Song,
the dire straits song. Um,
what does that song, um,
the rock star Song, what does
that fucking song? God dammit,
it's dire straits. You don't know. Dire
Straits, of course. Money for nothing.
Nothing to chicks for
free because it's got,
that song has the word Faggot in
it three times. Oh, that's you.
Little Faggot zone. Jet
Airplane. That little side. Good.
He's a middle unit. I forgot about
that. That she was on the radio.
Yeah. Yeah. City of Toronto. They have
decided, well, no, it was in Toronto.
It was in the newspaper in Toronto.
And you know, they've decided,
I guess in Canada to start censoring
that song, at least in Canada. I mean,
I don't know if they do in America. I'm
sure they played on classic rock. Yeah,
it's tricky. It's tricky man.
Because I mean, that is a gay sex,
that's a gay slur and it's on
a major song that's on the TV.
[inaudible] I remember that was willing
to the first music videos. Yeah,
it was on TV. Yeah. Yeah. There
was like three d animation,
Bang it on the, uh, yes,
they did. Yeah, they told us the
popular version. Yeah, absolutely.
On the television version.
On the radio version,
we could look up the MTV video right now.
Let's look up into the idea and
what's not listened to it though,
because it's really not that.
No, no, no, no. You know,
they had some killer songs with,
that wasn't one of them.
That was just so fucking old videos
where they had like neon flashing in the
background and smile and it's like
poorly. Yeah. Dope roller girl.
You ever heard that song roller
girl from dire straights? No,
but it pulled it out from
boogie nights like that shit.
Apparently that bitch is courageous.
She just did the hangover. Yeah.
Yeah. Oh, that's right. She was a hooker.
Yes, but again, that's a good role. Yeah,
I heard she's off the charts crazy.
I love people like that.
It's just like knowing they're out there
dire straits or alerts. It's kind of fun
into the habit. It's got skate away. Dire
Straits. Skate away. That could be it.
Yeah.
Scared away.
All right,
let's see.
Skate away.
She's that girl.
Yeah,
this is it.
This is a song from my child in that
this is a song in front of this.
I mean,
I might've been like fucking 13 or 12
or some shit when this song was out.
They're brilliant musicians,
man.
It's like it's a different kind of
rock and roll was really big too.
It's not like this is some. No,
there were huge. They were huge.
When I was in highschool, dire
straits, we've gigantic that was gone
down the wrong way. Cool
video too. Is that a Walkman?
She has hung around that big giant man.
Please walk,
man.
Same little clues in the campsite.
[inaudible] that take [inaudible].
Yeah, I really feel in this song
or you guys. Yes. I love it.
How dare you record on these. The
skate away from me. She's ugly.
She's living in 1979 dudes and
they didn't make it back then.
They used to dress themselves up with
flowers. Clown makeup looks like,
you know,
she used to have to wait around.
This is a window to another world,
Bro. This is a different era.
That's how crazy this fucking world is
evolving and how quickly I got that big
stupid Walkman she's got on,
you know are giant stupid headsets.
Although stupid headsets,
big ones like we're wearing right
now. They've made a comeback. Yeah.
Because of those beats.
Dr Dre will,
everybody wants to pretend
they're fucking DJ. Yeah.
You know gotta get a real good
sample of this music gum soon.
I need full coverage of my ears.
I'm saying
like Ernie,
I got to hear the whole song.
I'm going to hit a dirty shit in the
background. I'm sure I've got the Bose.
Bose noise canceling. Yeah.
Airplanes. Those are dope.
Yeah. Yeah. The, the beats ones.
I have those lists.
They cancel the noise to spice.
I like a rap battles have moved onto
headphones now cause it's like you got the
Dr Dre ones now and I think 50 cent has
Luda Luda just came out with his old
shit. Why not everybody shared their
own. Have I want my own headphones.
There'll be cool. Yeah. I
think it's an easy company.
Start Alien logo on the headphones.
You can smoke them when you're
done listening. Yeah, right.
We could store a stash like there's an
extra battery area to the show would have
a set of those Joe Rogan headphones.
That would be weird.
That would be step one of the Colt. Step
one. Step two, purple Nike's. Step three,
alien logo tattooed somewhere on
your body. Step four, step five.
If you embraced Twitter owl,
I've heard you on that thing.
Are you addicted to it or you,
you know what? Um, I read
a lot more than I post
someone's alert.
I'm not that much of a [inaudible].
So tell me this problem that you were
having at the comedy store that we're
talking about?
Well, you know, it's, um,
I guess when you stay in one place for
too long already it's with your job or
with anything else,
you just start to realize that the people,
if you start associating with the
same people over and over again,
sometimes you need to get a little
negative. Yeah. In terms of,
there's always been a real
negative vibe there. And uh,
but the state of time is amazing
and we just were talking about,
yeah, that's what talking about
like you had some great times.
They're done working out.
Yeah.
Bear is harder than
working on anywhere else.
I think Blaine compassion, very funny
comedian said, um, if this was a comedy,
clubs were a video game,
then the comedy store will be one on one
of the hardest level Las level, Boston,
Yale, then then you'd go
like laugh factory Improv.
And then when you get down easy would
be like the UCB and all those things.
Cause they're very,
very supportive and like smart
and everyone's paying attention.
And I'm at the comedy store.
I have Russian guy's yelling out at you
constantly. And so, you know what
though, the sad part about the stores,
when it reveals its true side,
when someone goes up who's not good and
kills someone goes up with some really
dumb hacky shit when they
destroy and then you go,
oh you guys aren't cool. You just in
the dark. That's what I was talking.
Just dummies in the dark. It
sort of makes you, makes you
feel bad about yourself when you go up
and you think you had a good set and then
just the worst in the world
goes up fucking two,
three after you and
just murders, you know, that's a symptom.
That's a symptom of what you were talking
about with like to UCB will the UCP is
very well organized. It's, they've
got a very clear ethic. Yeah.
They're trying to put out good art.
They're trying to put out good comments
to support it. You know, it's like,
it's very obvious what they're up to.
And so because of that,
that's the kind of crowd they attract.
The comedy store is just people
are just walking by and you know,
and they've heard the name
and they stumble in and they
don't know any better or
they know who advertising or it could
be, hey, how magical put it on Twitter.
He's going to be the comedy store tonight.
Let's go down and check it out.
But it's like he gets such a hodgepodge.
It is.
It is like a vortex of crazy
people for whatever reason.
Crazy people are drawn to that spot.
Like I don't want to believe in energy.
I don't want to believe anything of that
fucking crystal sucking astrological
bullshit. I don't want to believe in
that. I want to take things on face value,
but if ever there was a fucking,
there was some evidence for a place
having like crazy energy and having like a
weird attraction to it.
That fucking comic store was that man.
I'm the same way. I feel like, uh,
I don't believe in any of that crap,
but if there was ever a
place for that to exist,
you would have to be
something you're just saying.
Yeah. Maybe its affects are over
exaggerated. Like it's not the only,
you can't only have shitty
times at a place like that.
But you know when you find out the
history of that place and you know,
but it was Bugsy Siegel's nightclub
back in that cereal. Vishen days. Yeah.
Dr. Rose. Yeah, they,
yeah, it who said that?
Eliza Sleshinger so they were
doing abortions in the basement.
But we always get into the subject.
But how fucking crazy that places
and how creepy it is. But they,
they killed people there for sure. And
maybe there's like a little shred of that.
It's still in the room.
It's no funny bone. You know, as
you know, corporate leg comedy club,
it's a little bit different than those
animated microphone microphone standing
in the back.
Yeah. Showing you who's coming up
next week. And that's the other thing.
When you get used to being in other clubs,
you get used to like working for the
Improv and you see how fucking organized
they are.
They know when they have posters of guys
that are going to be there next week
and you know, with supporting acts. And
the show times and they have a, you know,
online where you can buy tickets.
It's all on the poster and they're just
like way in advance. You go to the store,
there's a piece of paper that fucking
Tommy's got spilled coffee on, you know,
and it has everybody's name written on it,
you know?
And if you call in and you ask,
well who's up tonight? The light.
Um, um, who's, uh,
where's the fucking list?
Um, it's like nobody, nobody knows what's
going on so you can caulk snail too.
But at one point in time, yeah, he wants
to know if you're sucking cocks too.
Cause what he asked Brian Cox
and I get off stage and he goes,
you still can cook snow to
Joe Rogen fucking went off on me like a
good set and I get off to and Tommy and
he just goes crazy on me just saying I
was gay and now he's using the comedy
store and I was a spy and sucking
dicks and just fucking nuts.
Yeah.
Well what's funny is that
been greeted like that ever.
I know it's bad and what sucked is like,
cool.
What's funny is I got off stage and
I was just feeling so happy and good,
and then when he did that to me and I was
like, oh, why are you doing this to me?
But I guess you'll do dude. He
bows killed you. Yeah. After,
after talking to a lot of comics,
I guess that's just what he does and
he's trying to scare you into thing.
So he's doing it using
intimidation tactics. Yeah. Yeah.
It's so you just swung on him. It's like,
dude does that. You just swung on him.
You put your Dick in his face. I just
pull your dick out. You hold them down,
you pull your dick out and
just rub it all over his face.
Don't you ever fucking do that to me
again? I thought like that constantly.
That's what it makes me sure of danger. I
just got to go in, develop a good mount.
I just got to go and do
my job and get the phone.
I'm tired of fucking like rubbing
your Dick on his face. No. Yeah. Well,
there's a lot of negative energy
in that place. You know the,
what you were talking about before
that you don't want to talk about.
Obviously there's a new comedy thief and
at the comedy store and a guy that got
kicked out of the hall cafe and he's
another one of these guys that's blatantly
on purpose looking to steal
people's material and use it. Yeah.
But I have to be very clear and uh,
I don't even want to get
involved. I know. I hear Ya.
Can I have you got to
bring the guy's name up?
We don't have to bring us down.
That's not the issue.
What I was talking about was how the
club, um, justified it and now they,
they actually told you when you brought
the guy's name up that he's not bad
looking on the eyes. Yeah. That's
actually a Tommy quilt, right? Yeah.
Whoopsies sorry.
Yeah, this is what he said to me. Some of
your comic now and I said, yeah, I try.
And he goes, are you working for Joe
Rogan still? Yeah, I still work for him.
You saw cock now too.
And then I
put together if you can repeat that and
working for jewelry. And Brian said, yeah.
I said, yeah, it's like two Cox,
three, four Cox and then five times.
And then he goes,
you come with me at this criticisms.
You go onstage and you worked for the
phony fuck. And it's just like, what?
Where's this coming from? Just really
took the wrong size in the sole thing.
It's about them making the wrong
choices. Uh, you know, just threw out.
If they gave me a lot of
statements, negative energy, man,
that's why they have to do it.
They're sucked into their own suck.
But then I got my ankle
weights and I want to go.
I can where you don't have to though.
It's not necessary. I, you know, I,
my aunt got a lot better.
As soon as I stopped being there,
I got less angry and I think some of my,
like comedy was being formed
by the energy in that place.
There's a lot of great things about
that place, but it's also, it's dark.
I love hanging out there. I love it just
because of the people. But you know,
other than that, if they all hung out at
fucking waffle house, I'd be there. Brian,
he married. Yeah. Tell
Him we were filming and then hooker came
back and just wanted to start talking
to us about the business and how she
meets guys and how she sets it up. Yeah,
it was pretty crazy, man. Out
of nowhere, this girl just,
she came up to us and she seemed,
you know, like fairly normal. Right.
She didn't seem totally crazy
you. She was just, you know,
having a good time like everybody else
and then she starts talking about being a
hooker. Yeah, it's crazy.
I run into hookers a lot more often
than I thought it would ever run into
hookers.
Just like talk.
They just come up and start talking to
you and they act normal and they don't
say that they're a hooker.
You Think,
oh this girl is talking to me
and they suddenly see slips in a,
and then he little hooker. The world.
The world that you travel in though,
you travel in a very interesting world.
I mean if you looked at your life from
any other part of the world, you know,
you take some guy from Idaho
and say, Hey, I'm going to,
I'm going to hang out with this guy.
What are you going to do today? Well,
I'm going to hang out with this girl.
She's a penthouse pet of the year.
We're going to go to this porn awards
party and then we're going to go to the
improv where there's a naughty show and
a bunch of porn stars are going to go up,
and then I'm gonna hang out with some
standup comedian friends of mine and we're
going to smoke a lot of pot and
let him fuck is this is your life.
I want to go crazy, man. Do you
mind if I tag along? I said, sit,
have gone to college, I guess. Yeah.
Then you'd be out of word. Sure. To do.
Look into your life and
music. How did I end up? Yeah,
but that's why there's so many
hookers in your life as well.
I'm trying to tell Ya,
you're traveling in strange circles.
Definitely hooker material, not there's
anything. We're all being a hooker man.
Buddy of mine was talking to me about
this time massage place that he goes to
and uh, they give you a real time massage
and then they jerk you off. And he,
he talked about it like, like it
was the greatest meal, you know,
like I would talk to you about like a,
a certain steak house that knows exactly
how to fucking cook a good piece of
meat when you cut into that medium,
Maria and the outside,
it's just crispy but the inside is juicy
and delicious and warm and the fucking
blood from the meat just
fires up your synapses.
That's how this guy talked about getting
jerked up by this Thai lady while I was
talking about it. Like it's the
most amazing thing. He goes,
somebody told me to go to this place.
I didn't think, you know, like that.
It was that kind of place cause
it looked like a real place.
And he goes and I go
in there and I'm going,
well obviously I'm not going to pull my
pants down because this is a legit place.
I'm getting a real massage.
Like they giving them a real massage.
They're stretching them out there,
rubbing them down, elbows in muscles,
loosening all the things. He's like, I'm
getting a little bit chipped massage.
There's no way. The same broad
jerk me off. And then at the end,
after like 40 minutes of that, she's
like, so does that feel good to you?
He's like, get the fuck Outta here. This
is a fantasy. She starts rubbing his leg.
Yeah. You know, do you want
anything more? Do anything more.
And the next thing you know, she like
glances over his Dick and he arches his,
his back like towards her hand and she
glances over his dick and then she just
gets that the green light. She gets
a hold of it, pulls out the lotion,
starts rubbing his balls, jerks him
off, Bam. Done. Wow. It's like 40 bucks.
Wow. Sorry. Shit chick turned
to me. I was just, uh, you know,
she's going to ask you if you want to,
you know,
extra parts because there's a lot of
them to Abby charge more, you know, like,
so she knows me, she goes means and he
goes, do you want me to make banana cry?
Whoa, whoa. Hey, what are
you fucking say to me?
I know banana feels bad about himself
just being in here. Banana cried.
She offered, yeah. Opposite Banana
cry. And you said No. Well, you know,
uh, since haven't, uh, yeah,
my daughters would have spoiled me for
a lot of fucking porn to right a little
bit. Yeah. Me a lot. Strip clubs, porn,
all that. It's not the same anymore.
Now it's not. I mean, it used to be,
I used it all the time. I'd be there.
You have babies, you look at them. And I,
I used to look at him as this is a really
hot check. Like, wow, look at that body.
Look at that ass now I go,
why is she dancing? Probably
Cause her dad didn't love.
Yeah. Yeah. And I'm gonna live my day and
I thought I'm going to be a better dad.
Yeah,
I'm trying also.
Yeah, you really think about, and
also the germ factor and shit too.
Like these chicks are rubbing up on
fucking all these dudes. I can't,
when I go to a con, if they tried to put
you in a comedy Kondo, I would start.
I won't allow it because I started
thinking about fucking Mark Curry.
Probably one out on the couch.
Curry.
Why Marcher hanging with Mr [inaudible]
and you look at the lineup and you go,
oh my God, that guy was fucking here. Mark
Crowe would be the least of my worries.
She's a cool dude. Yeah,
no I love my career,
but I'm just using him as an example
of somebody just randomly in,
oh go with Barry diamond.
Hurry diamond. Just
applying tanning cream. He didn't
go out. So use your brother.
What's his dark fucking Mahogany
looking deck? Cause you can never,
never has lotion. So you guys do
use tanning loads. Those Shit, man.
Black Orange is like a giant carrot.
Lupa Lupa orange reds.
Really dirty carrot.
Yeah. There's always that one dude that
could have stayed more comedy porno.
I think.
I know there is some of it,
but I don't know how many people want
to want you to know. Surprise comics,
mixed comedy in Porno together.
This face Thomas Ward who
does a fantastic bill,
cause bill Cosby was a in
a couple of porins right.
Not to be type where he
didn't bang anybody, but you
know he does his background.
Thomas Ward is another one.
Man,
I got that guy introduced that got in
my manager in many, many years ago.
Cause I was like this kid
has got something and he's
like real raw and he's got
a good way of looking at things and
he's fucking just a natural on stage.
But for whatever reason
just doesn't happen. Didn't,
didn't click with him. Yeah.
You know, kind of ways. So God
damn tricky. Yeah. You know,
it's like you pick the wrong wave.
You're, you're not in the right mindset.
You know, you're not, he can never
really get your life in order.
Whatever the fuck it is that
keeps you from getting it right.
There's a lot of guys that we know,
you know Holtzman,
his name comes up all the
time. Yeah. But it's like he
just allowing yourself not
to get distracted and just
staying on point, you know,
holds funds kind of job that he works.
I think he was a mechanic
for aircraft at some point.
And so he's got all these
other life distractions and
you gotta be fucking on it.
If you want to go get something,
you've gotta be on it 100% and I
think these guys are half ass in it.
They got themselves to a position,
a comfort. See that's the happen.
What happens with any sort of fucking
dream is you get yourself to a point and
you're like, oh, you should sacrificing
by like compromising and go, oh,
I don't really need fucking that. I'm
happy with this. And you get just,
Richard reached a point where you settled,
you know,
you don't give a shit anymore. So
you're just like, I'm cool with this.
This is a great life right here.
I can just fucking stop trying.
And I got this and then
what I did, man. Yeah. When I was on
news radio did, I didn't write anything.
And here's one reason,
one of the things that turned it around,
I did sets and when I would do these sets
I would basically do the same fucking
material that I had had for
years and years and years before.
I would just go up on the weekends cause
it was easy because it was something to
do. You know, I hadn't,
I had this TV show so I was doing the TV
show all the time and the weekends I'd
only been in la at year.
I didn't really know that many people.
So my social life was
going to the comedy clubs.
So I would go up and I want you to do
the same act pretty much just over and
over and over again. Nobody knew who I
was. I didn't have any responsibility.
I don't have any fans.
I know responsibility to give them
new shit and I lost my feeling for it.
Like it wasn't really any more to me.
I wasn't,
I wasn't in the comedy mode for real.
It's like,
cause I was just reiterating the same
shit. And a few writers from the TV show,
from news radio came to see me at the
comedy store and I had a really late night
set.
It was really late night in the main room
when you have those late nights at the
main room, the energy just gets sucked
out of the room where there's nothing,
and I went on like next to last and
I ate a dick. I just was, I was,
I felt like wow.
Saying it that what I was saying was
stupid and it just felt empty to me.
I could feel reciting the words. Yeah,
I could feel them feeling bad for me.
I could feel them judging me
and not liking what they see.
I just did not have it. I just wasn't
in the groove. And then I realized,
I'm like slacking, like I'm not really
writing. I'm not really performing.
I'm putting any effort into
it for over a year for, oh,
maybe it might've been two years
for over a year at least I,
I just would go up and do the same
fucking tired shit over and over again.
But that bad set made
me completely refocused.
And then like within a year
I did my first CD cause I,
I just started going crazy.
Then I would go to the stand up.
I would do it every night.
I was doing it every to every night.
I was doing it at the laugh factory and
the Improv and I was just trying to get
in as many sets as I couldn't
write as much new shit as I could.
I just realized that like you
can't just keep doing this anymore
point that goes off and then
you're just trying to, I try to um,
work new stuff in constant.
Yeah, I'm always adding just little
chunks here and there and he,
not even a whole new bit,
but just adding to the old shit that I
have and always growing and evolving.
So that's why I have a hard time
putting out bits too quickly. Like,
if you do something and then you know,
you put it out,
you put out like a DVD and in the next
year you want to do another one like
Louis C K is doing, which is, you know,
really super ambitious. But in my,
like what's in my career,
like the things that I've done,
they've always gotten way,
way,
way better as I kept doing them like
over a long period of time and sort of
completely tweaked them and got
them to the place where, you know,
I have just a the right punch lines
in the right places, the right set up,
the right, you know, think about the
right material to do before you do it,
you know?
Yeah. I got an album then I just
put out and a, I felt exactly
the same way when I locked
it. You're like, Oh shit,
you know that and a couple jokes.
I'm trying just not to do any of that
stuff anymore so it won't feel bad about
it. I'm just put it away. But
um, yeah, once I do it, yeah,
I think that's how you have to do it.
I've,
I've filled Berness Bellbird
does that. What does he do? He,
once he does it on TV or on an album,
it goes bye bye and just starts fresh.
Well that's the Louis CK way too. That's
what Louise doing, you know. And I think,
um, I think you have to do that. You
know, if you really want to keep moving,
there's no way you can just do the same
thing for it to a few bits of people
call them out.
Like when I do a Q and a sometimes in,
especially for about a couple of car.
Yeah. And I'm pretty on it, but um,
you know, it's, um, that's the,
the hardest part about comedies just
to keep that momentum going and keep
finding out new and interesting things
to talk about. Yeah, I know. Now it's,
it's tough, um, to, you know,
just let it go on it, man. No Way.
It's so hard to stay like, grow
attached to some bits to you. Yeah, man,
there's some good ones. Fucking
love my bit about tigers. Fucking,
I used to love doing it.
I still love everything about it.
That's my favorite bit of all time,
but like all of them,
there's got to be, sorry, make
the tough decision. Put it behind.
You were talking about how bill bird,
just um,
every single time he did something
on TV or on an album goes gone.
Just because it starts fresh.
Complete him. That's, that's the,
that's the George Carlin way.
You know,
George Carlin's style of doing comedy
and Louis C K adopted it and bill burrs
pretty much doing it too. You know,
it's the way to do it. Just keep him,
keep pounding out.
Shit.
Just very hard to do when you're
doing other things as well. Yeah.
That's what we were talking about
earlier is you get stuck on a TV show and
you're working a lot and then cranking.
I mean it's hard to get to
sleep and shit too. Yeah.
Would you recommend comedy to people?
Like if you,
like if your child wants it to
be a comic, would you say, Hey,
I would recommend comedy or
would you scare people away?
Was already asked what he
wants to be when he grows up.
I knew you looked at a group
of your legacy. I just want
to tell jokes. He goes,
uh, why wouldn't you recommend one
of the great jobs all the time?
I mean, I get to write, I've written
for a couple of other people, you know,
and just, I have a great time. Just,
you know, doing what I'm doing.
You seem to think that you wouldn't
Brian then what you're saying?
Well, I, I, I don't know if
I would or wouldn't. Um, I,
I do see just being in it how,
how competitive it is and how it really
is hard to get to a certain point of
where you can survive, uh,
like, like higher up then,
then didn't like the normal comic.
Like there's so many really good comics,
but they seem like they all
get to a certain level and
then they kind of balance
off, you know, where, yeah,
they're making money and stuff,
but a lot of them are still kind
of struggling here and there.
But it seems like it's really hard to
get to the next level where you're just
like, you know, you use the base
analogy or any pro football or
anything like that, any sporting thing.
It's like know certain amount
of people get certain distance in the,
you know,
there's levels of professional and
people just climb up that level of
professional.
There's a lot of different things to
think about cause it's not just being a
comedian and being funny.
It's also the marketing of yourself,
which is very alien from the
creative aspect of stand up comedy.
So it's real tricky. Like what gets you
to the next level is a lot of times,
so has nothing to do with your proficiency
as a comedian. Right. You know,
there's a lot of comedians that we know
of that, you know, they're really good,
they're really solid, but for whatever
reason they never enter into the,
oh you're talking about Brian Holtzman is,
yeah.
Your example Zeitgeisty never accepts them
for whatever reason. Nothing. You know,
they, they never figured out
how to get promoted correctly.
And also they sabotaged your own
career. I mean, did you hear? I remember,
I don't even know I have the story right.
But Holtzman jumping into Martin Lawrence
came into the audience and he Holtzman
had people there to see him.
It was a big deal and he was finally
going to get a shot and then Martin
Lawrence is bouncer came in and said
something and yeah, I guess, uh, Holtzman,
he just looks and says fuck it and
just jumps in and they, I guess, uh,
the bouncer just knocks and
ride out and fucking walk.
Claton seven right in front
of all of these people.
Yeah. Again, I think what was was
Martin Lawrence was heckling. Yeah.
And Brian Holtzman was on stage and
Martin Lawrence was heckling and Martin
Lawrence went offstage and was saint
lanes. John, but this is Martin Lawrence.
Can you believe this?
I'm getting heckled by mind lawns and
the bouncer gets up and punches him.
He's so serious. Yeah. Can't
too close to that. Yeah.
He has a stuff like that happens.
All right. It sucks. I was calm.
Lettow would have taken off if he had
been around agents and managers and stuff
too.
That's the other thing about the store.
No one's going there to hang
out because they have to pay.
If you go to the Improv and everybody
gets in free, you know, managers, agents,
they're all hanging out.
There used to be an issue to try
to get people to come in, you know,
like put them on the list to
come see people, you know,
it'd be hard and people couldn't just
couldn't show up. Hey, I'm Mike from IBM.
Can we come in and see the show? They were
like, yeah, sure. 20 bucks each pitch.
When you're saying about the marketing,
I think it's also, it's um, that
book, uh, that Malcolm Gladwell book,
the outliers years. He then
either where it's very good, uh,
but it talks about people not being
able to express themselves. Like, um,
there was a story of a genius just
kid just, I mean went to Iowa state,
but there's,
mom didn't turn in his paperwork.
They were just sort of dumb about speaking
to people and his kid was there and
didn't go talk to anybody.
Clearly they wanted him at the school
and what are going to keep them at the
school.
But all he had to do was know to go and
talk to somebody or like people are just
socially unable
and how he didn't talk to anybody and yeah
he does. You know he's a manager
somewhere or does this kid has the guy,
has the man is the highest
Iq the almost imagined,
well there was some guy that get tested
like for the highest Iq ever in America
and he was a bouncer.
There was a bouncer in long island or
something like that and it was a really
weird back cause he was like really kind
of full of himself a bit and like we
would talk about things,
he would talk about things like really
pompous and you just going to go,
hey back the fuck up. You're a
bouncer dude. Like what did you,
if you are so smart and it's
fucking smug everything,
what are you out there swimming in the
human condition every day as a bouncer,
getting to know the dark side of humanity.
Are you,
what do you fucking Charles Bukowski poet
type character or are you the smartest
man in the world? Cause something, there's
a disconnect there fella. You know,
you're, you're living life like a dummy.
Not, not that bouncers are dummies.
I know a lot of guys that are bouncers.
I came and they guys,
good job that a lot of power had bouncers.
You get power and you do don't do shit.
Yeah,
but I mean,
why would you do that if you're a
fucking super genius and you're like 40,
all right.
You know,
it's not like he's some 20 year old
kid paying for his college education.
Some money on the weekends. No, he's
fucking 40 year old genius character.
Working as a bouncer is services
should be used elsewhere. Totally.
Like if he's that so I can smart, let's
give him more socially. There's the needs.
Social intelligence needs to be factored
into the whole idea of intelligence.
You know,
your Iq design include your ability to
fucking maneuver around human beings.
And then a similar kid with a
big upgrade. Uh, you know, uh,
really wealthy upbringing that
had the same Iq went, you know,
that many times further, you know,
his life and became this great. Yeah,
I had a friend when I was living in New
York who was a pool hustler. Uh, and uh,
he was a a brilliant guy. Um,
not just socially. He's like,
you had a brilliant
mathematical mind as well.
But he was the first guy that I'd ever
met socially that would like look for
traits in someone, look for things
that people are doing, look for ego,
things like he could do
impressions of people,
like really good impressions of him.
They wouldn't sound like the person,
but it would be exactly the type of shit
at that person would say because he's
always analyzing people's personalities
and looking for weaknesses. You know,
I did not know until I met this guy that
people were out there that did that,
that like would look for a weakness and
how in your game look for weakness and
how you talk,
look for weakness and how you behave.
And then they find that little spot
and that's where they start picking.
They start picking on whatever got
you to say that in the first place.
Whatever got you to stand up for yourself,
whatever.
Got you to make an excuse about something
that happened and it was kind of sick
that day. Normally that would never
go down like that. Oh really? Yeah.
Normally you're the best, right? The best
ever. Like he would just find the spot,
find whatever it was and just start
picking his opportunity. Yeah,
they're out there man.
Fuck gathering out there man.
But that's a lot of what comedy is too.
It's finding that little,
that little spot,
the fun,
seeing that little thing that
other people might not have saw
now in San.
Then also getting that out and reflecting
that in a creative way that has not
really been done before too. And you
don't want to fucking go regurgitate.
So another old and tired shit.
I know.
So it's also like there's a couple of
rules in place where not only have you had
that thought and found that opportunity,
but now you've got to put this through
this filtering process to determine
whether or not it's okay to
fucking make it up on stage.
Yeah. And then there's the saying
that the right way and you know,
figuring out the best shot of me of
words. Yeah. There's like a lyric cool
aspect to it at that point to now you're
in putting shit together. Like, um,
you know, I try to do that a lot in
one of act when I'm talking about,
and I actually tell that whole banana
cry story on stage as a bit and leading
into it and I said,
this is the way,
I don't believe that you
didn't get jerked off.
I just want you to know I love you.
But yeah, keep saying what you said.
You don't have to say anything.
Keep going. Oh, sorry.
Go ahead. So, um, the uh,
banana cry lady,
I goes,
this is not the first time I found myself
in an English as a second language,
sexy talk situation. You know,
and so I say shit like that,
so I has to come out like it
can be lyrical at the same time.
You can use alliteration and
fuck around with it from there.
So then you got to put it through all
these steps and then it finally makes it
out. And that's why they're tough
to give up her baby and ARD.
Yeah.
They're like your babies man.
So when she'd get good at them
and get them all tightened,
you know exactly how to hit them and they
have all these fucking punchlines one
after the other bang,
Bang, Bang, Bang. You know,
that was the Boston style of
comedy to Boston. Um, the,
the best guys for whatever reason,
didn't really write new material.
They just had a gang of
stuff driving, stating, yeah.
Like if you understood that like
that you just go out and just,
they're just crushing. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. There's guys like that.
It's harder to do now though,
because of the Internet.
It's just not the same thing.
You know when people and be,
these guys didn't have
cds out so it could,
people couldn't go and replay there bits.
You had to go see it again. You know,
you couldn't play it over and over
again. So it's like, you know,
you know the exact timing
from the punchline comes and
it's not like that people
are still going out though. I
mean, yeah, comedy is still the,
the most fun thing for me to go see.
You know,
if I know that Stan helps
kind of perform or you know,
Lucy case in town or you know,
Nick Depaulo or something,
someone that I really think is really
funny. I love fucking have a great time.
It's still the most fun thing to see.
Who are you saying?
Last night was at the Hollywood Improv,
Stan hope was there.
David Tell Ron White, uh,
Nick Swardson, Doug Benson.
It was just like never ending and it's
also just a fun hang to [inaudible].
That's the difference between
that place in the store.
Like I never realized that
there's managers that were
actually happy to see you
there. Well and thankful. Can we get
you a water? Do you want to drink?
Did you like something? Are
you hungry? Do you want to eat?
They got a menu in their hand. They have
good food there. Great Burgers and shit.
Everyone's friendly. The wait, staff's
friendly. The bar tenders friendly.
There's a bar.
Everybody sits down and has a good
time at the bar and then there's a back
showroom.
Barter Summers are also the Eddies Deva.
Yeah, they're great. Great. Had
been to the south sessionals
down the street sales.
No, I want to go there. Oh, that's a
shit stop by sometimes. Salad Listener.
And do you know if we're in contact?
I don't know. We'll get you in there.
Don't worry. We'll get you in
there. We did it a Sunday night.
It was fucking awesome, man. Just talked
about it on Twitter. Sunday place.
It's a real small place. So let's see.
It's like 70 at the all right now.
But they're also have two more showrooms.
They've got a whole back
area that's gigantic.
They're going to blow out and build this
like huge 300 seat room back there at
300 seats. Right. Well there's two
rooms. I think they're going to split it.
I think he should just
build one huge room.
I don't know why I keep this small room
in the front and then make a big one,
but I guess he's doing like
an Improv room of like uh,
80 and then a bigger room 150 or
something like that. Improv like,
like Improv, like that's shit like
gimme a topic, that kind of Shit.
What kind of like the like you know like
the side room at the improv where he
does his show. You know what I mean? Like
like a workout Improv. I don't know. Hmm.
Yeah. Well hey maybe not.
Maybe, maybe you could do it.
Look the comedy store was three
rooms. Yeah. Forever. You know,
if this guy can actually pull
off three rooms and that spot,
he's got the perfect
attitude. He's like, you know,
sounds like one of those guys that you
hope would come along and open up a
comedy club. A guy who really loves
comedy. He's a really fun guy and he's,
he's willing to take some chances
as business sense as well.
That is exactly what he's doing.
And he bought this place and right now
it's got a front area where there's a bar
and a bunch of seeds and that's what
we performed Sunday where there's a
backyard. This is like old school bakery
and it's been a bakery like forever.
And uh,
apparently he's gonna take over that.
And what was it before
the Big Deanna Cafe?
It's a cafe with a big yellow awning.
It's on Melrose, says Vienna cafe.
Doesn't say sounds comical. He's like
tried to like, you know, like Vianna cafe.
Oh, it doesn't exist anymore,
but come on, we're going to show
phase it in slowly.
He was telling me,
he was telling me a funny Stan hope a
bit earth story last night when he had a
club in New York. Uh, he, everyone
was trying to get into his club,
like all these really good
comics and he wanted Stan hope,
so he called Doug up or something
like that. It was like, hey, you know,
really like you to come to my club in
Doug's like, I don't do clubs. Sorry.
And then it sounds like, well, just, you
know, ask around first before you say no,
because I think you're,
you would like my place,
said Doug calls back and
goes out. Everyone's saying
great things, I'll go there.
And so he'd be kind of came friends with
Stan hope and then he had like a party
to watch, like a boxing
match at his house, like his
apartment. And he, he's like,
Doug, you know, if you want to come over
and watch the boxing game come over.
So Doug invited the whole entire club to
come to sell his house and he just said
they're like 40 people were climbing
over his fence and just fucking drinking
all his beers.
And can you imagine inviting a whole club
to somebody else's [inaudible] Douchey.
Yeah.
Well, Stan hope drunk. Yes, of
course. Is that a real question?
That isn't a real question. And Islam,
that's funny. Yeah. And after that,
he's still in a comedy, right?
Who? To Glutton for punishment.
I know this, um, I'm sure, but a principal
empty Ted Williams, the golden voice.
A homeless man, right? Yeah.
And um, this guy is like junkie.
Yeah. And now they're giving them all
this money going. I fucking got it. Some,
he was on Dr Phil and I guess he's about
to check himself into rehab or he did
checked himself into rehab
because of the doctor Phil show.
But Dr Phil brought up the
whole point of where like, um,
that he used to steal cars and like,
he's like, yeah, the great voice.
It's not like the innocent
cry baby guy that you first,
it's going to be famous. Do you think he's
getting pussy yet? Internet. Pussy. Um,
I hope not. He sort of looks like
Matt. You remember when already locked?
Donald's had that moon man commercial
or it was like a moon face jack that
night. What was that? I
remember it was um, Mac tonight.
Mac Mac tonight. Wow. Met. Pull
that up. I got to look at that now.
Mac tonight was when Mcdonald's had
some moon headed man wearing a suit.
Well, I don't remember that exactly like
that. I know almost Guy Tim Williams.
So he goes on Dr Phil and he tells them
that he stole cars and all kinds of
other shit while he was doing drugs.
Is that what he said?
Yeah.
Well what he first said that he like
doctor Phil brought up the fact that he,
uh, uh, hold on, I'll tell you exactly
what it was. I'm just worried. Is it?
Uh, he is the PM for people that don't
know there was a guy, and this is,
if you haven't heard this story,
there was a guy that was standing on the
side of a road and he had a sign that
said, you know, we'll use my
golden voice for, you know,
God gave me a voice and give me
some, give me a dollar, you know,
whatever the fuck it is.
Right. So this guy, um,
does this impression of like a morning
DJ on a television show or on a radio
show and it's amazing.
It's like a really good radio voice,
like that perfect fake radio voice and
it's, feels, it seems weird coming out of,
uh, out of a homeless guy
and he's got like, you know,
a bunch of shit plan that
he can say like that.
And so this became an internet
thing. It got huge. And then from it,
this guy gets a bunch of different
job offers. So now he's on Dr Felons.
So what happen?
Uh,
well,
Dr Phil sits down with them and discuss
it as in like all the challenges that
he's had in his life.
And he did not,
he first denied the incident
in which Dr Phil, um,
was accused of violent behavior,
public urination, stealing customers,
cars at a tire store in Ohio and all
this other crap. And then later, uh,
in the interview, the guy finally admits
that he did all those things. And then,
um, the next first few lines, but first
he lies, he's still lying. He's still,
he's still doing the lying thing.
And then he admitted it later after Dr
Phil probably owned them or some. Wow.
And then supposedly he will appear again.
I'm Dr Phil,
accompanied by his ex wife
and he has five kids. Wow.
Oh,
the kids got money with this kid is not
what you hope the kids got money and I
guess supposedly that the, the, the wife
and kids, um, are worried that he's,
he's going to relapse and then later
in the interview or whatever, they,
they say that he's going to
go into rehab on Thursday.
So we already realized this today.
Yeah.
Well you've probably got some cash and
you know, straight to the bar. Yeah.
Almost guy in the shower and
straight to the bar. Joe,
do you remember this commercial? You
probably don't remember this commercial,
but this is who, uh, Al says that he
looks like this old, uh, the Shin.
Yeah, I see it, but I don't
remember. I don't remember it.
It's a big campaign
for robots,
like 24, 2007 to, and that can be 2007.
There's no way those
four years ago, bitches. Oh wait, here's
a 1989 I'm talking about this. Yeah,
that's a, that's a freaky one. That
was, that was it. New revamped version.
I don't see what the fuck do
you guys are talking about.
That's a guy with a moon head guys
bring fucking net. That's ridiculous.
I'm saying that is the funniest shit.
L okay.
Moon face. Even more than
Jay Leno used. You know,
I bet that Moon Phase I met that Anton
Anton Dodson Dude. He's the dude who uh,
his house got broken into.
So hide your kids. Yeah.
Hydrawise yeah, that guy is like
doing all kinds of shit now from it.
That song is good. Yeah. This
song is legitimately goody Antwan.
It looks like your bench.
Um,
Antwan Johnson Song is legitimately
good. Yeah, it really is. Yeah. It's um,
I mean it's amazing though, how these
things can, can become viral like this.
He bought his mom a house
from the proceeds. He, I
guess they split the money 50,
50, and Antwan got a lot of money.
His Mama's house. It's incredible.
From a viral video done from the local
Nan. He's doing a bunch of other shit.
He did some shit for the UFC. He was
on George Lopez. I saw that. Yeah.
He's doing like ads and
shit now. It's crazy, man.
Internet celebrities, like a real thing.
Like I was made a couple of comics.
I mean they really has a,
I met a Bo Burnham the other night.
Did you see this Joe?
The hide your kids hide your wife a dog
that, is that on Twitter? Is that
what it is? Uh, yeah. Um, anyway, uh,
I met that Bo Burnham Kid. Yeah. You
know, I just saw him on pop revenge.
This show the green room.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I was on,
I was on the one afterward and um,
and I was there and I was,
we were talking to me and Eddie aft,
we're talking and one of the things that
this kid like was saying was that he
never had to like struggle.
He never went out and did like the
shitty one night or is he never,
when he was on youtube it was like Bam
right away. Famous doing big shows. Yep.
That's pretty crazy man. Yup.
Yeah. That's a new thing, man.
Who was the first Internet celebrity?
Like going back?
Justin Bieber's like the big
one, right? Well, no, no.
I mean first like 10 years ago,
15 years ago,
like was there an AOL celebrity back in
the day when you two first started was
the history of the dance guy became one
of the ones that was the first youtube
sensation really to start
commanding high dollar.
He guy was the front most famous guy
on the Internet to go to guy. Yeah,
his buddy. Oh I wonder who that
guy is. I mean it's a guy who's a,
he's got his bought whole face and the
camera is wearing a wedding ring and he's
stretching his asshole out.
Like pulling it like it's rubber.
Yeah.
Peering into the darkness into the event
horizon of his butt butthole and it's a,
you know an Internet meme.
It's been on a million different things.
It's all over the place. Yeah. All right.
People make photoshops of it
and in cloud patterns and shit.
Ill make your Binion and cry
but no seriously,
if you think of like the first real legit
celebrity that was made off of
the Internet, it's ea Keela.
It's pretty, yeah Tila Tequila is a
perfect one. She's straight, you know,
just right from the Internet. Nothing
button. Right. You've got mail. She,
it might've been the first. No, no,
no. There has to, I mean that's,
you're talking about like seven years ago,
I'm talking about like the Internet came
out a long ass time snowmen like Tila
Tequila that made their way into
the public and became [inaudible].
Yeah, before, I mean video and
then social networks. Yeah.
I'm just talking about the Internet had,
was always a spot for celebrity to go.
Like I used to look up,
I think some of the celebrities have
brothers and shit like that and there's
like Ricky leads revolt,
a John Travolta's brother and so
he has a website and I was like,
there was a lot of funny
shit on it back then.
But nothing like there is
now at the content audio,
there's a sound you can go
to soundcloud and youtube.
I mean people are putting out,
nobody had the devices either.
Nobody had flip video cameras.
And so it was a whole new age of
when you introduce the small camera,
that's when, and easy to upload
with a UC, a USB connector.
My fit just right in
immediately HD phones. And uh,
so you didn't have to have that technology
available to just a regular guy.
So now that it's easier to launch a blog
and video and look out when she goes
viral, I mean a lot of people are
talking about the voice. Yeah.
Yeah.
And Antwan Dodson,
I mean it's a lot of fucking
money to buy your mom a house.
I don't care if it's in Alabama
where it was really big of that song.
Those guys who created that,
um, that auto two song,
which guys are very talented musician.
Sure. And then just auto tune, I mean,
tune is fucking hilarious every time.
Yeah. You're a Carl Sagan is auto tune.
No, what I have you
heard that, um, the, uh,
I think it's the woo song.
It's a local dues in San Francisco and um,
they, I guess there are people
who are putting these mufflers on.
Oh yeah. Woo. Yeah.
Yeah. They go down and it's local news
on a tune for that. So that's hilarious.
It's all anything auto tuning the news
is funny. Yeah. You can't deny it. I
think garageband is pretty amazing too,
the,
that the program where you can pretty
much make your own song pretty easily.
Don't they have programs like that for
your phone now? Oh yeah, absolutely.
Absolutely. Like there was, I don't
know if we ever talked about that.
There was this, back in the day
of my space, somebody linked, uh,
one of my songs on there,
a myspace page and like
stole it from my web host.
And so like when you went
to their myspace page,
it automatically played a song
from your show for myself. So I,
what I did is I took that file,
it took it down and then I'm made up a
quick song and garage band about like, ah,
Stacy from, you know,
Hollywood, California.
I want you to suck my Dick and made a
whole song just set about how I wanted to
fuck this girl and stuff like that.
And I replace that song, that file,
what the original file.
So that when people went through her
mind space page just started playing that
song. Yeah. [inaudible]
that I just love. I don't know how
that, why you thought about that,
but it's pretty funny video.
That's funny when you can do that with
hot linking and speaking of my space,
I think the yesterday one
officially really just downsize.
They shut off at Germany and why space
Germany is dead. Somebody tweeted me,
my space cut all their
employees like three months ago.
I like half of their employees. They cut
Jordan and they just did it again. Jordy.
Yeah, Jordy was roots and now is your
lucky day and age with comedy central,
but they, yeah, use working
memory. I'm going to come.
My sweet comedy was thriving.
I'm sure you did. One of those secret
shows. Did I do well? The secret shows.
I'm thinking about deleting
my mind space live on the air.
What do you think do it if they're
going to cut show and rune.
You know it's funny how we did it with
a, I think, I forget who we did it with,
like Jason Tebow or something like that.
Somebody deleted their my space the other
day. Live on air on an old, on podcasts.
Christ.
I can't even come up with one original
idea but watch how many steps it is.
It's pretty hilarious. I it was Ari.
Ari did it and it was like three steps.
Like they make it really hard.
Like are you sure you yeah.
Are you guys still have people on it?
Try and talk to you? Very, very, very,
very few. Almost all of it
is completely dead as well.
Do you want to go on and
mind also will duel duel one.
I paid some money to have my tricked
out too at one point. Saks? Yeah.
Did you have glitter tags?
I don't know what it seems like you
would probably use a fake name on juice.
I can even say it.
So if you want to delete your myspace
now too and we could have a double my
space and I'm going to keep mine. They
hide this mother fucker. It's not easy.
I don't even know where to go. Um, here,
I'll tell you guys where to go. Hold on.
Um,
more delete my space.
Can't even tell you. I don't even know if
I know my past. It's time to let it go.
You know what I mean?
It's like that girl that you dated 10
years ago and there's phone number still
in your book. Throw that
shit out, son. Move on.
Um, it's in your book. Listen to me.
Your book, who has a phone book anymore?
Phone books are worth nothing.
Fuck you in your phone book.
I want to write it on paper.
Like some caveman. The good
for standing on. You know,
why don't you just give me some burnt
sticks and I'll use it to carve the
fucking numbers on a rock. How to delete.
I think you do it and now I can't even,
can't even figure it out. There
we go. There you go. All right.
If you decided to delete my
space, what you do is more, um,
you go to my account and then,
uh, where's my account? Uh,
it's under more my stuff, my
stuff, account settings right here.
Account settings. And then you looks
different. I have to give them that. Yeah,
it looks different.
Logo this case.
Should we give him a chance now
that they redesigned everything
we committed to this bro. We've committed
to this man. We're going to kill it.
Everything in here it looks
like white label details.
Remember the,
Oh,
I constantly had those horrible
fucking ads where like people account.
Here we go. You know, try it. I don't
want to catch a smiley face or something.
Yeah. Brian is not just
cancel account. Right. It's
deleted. I want to delete that.
Oh you want to cancel account?
Where's that fine. Canceling. Yeah.
We're sorry you want to leave,
please let us know why to say cause you
can really help us improve my space.
There's not an,
it's over bitch option has board spam,
privacy and email. I'm going to go with
spam was the one thing that annoyed me.
Where is it Joe? Where's the
cancel? Cancel account under
settings. Under settings.
Under account settings
and privacy settings.
Account settings and
cancellation comments. Thanks
for the love and the last,
but it's over bitches not down there.
Yeah,
but they do hide it. They hide
it a below the fold. Yeah.
And then you just got to keep on
scrolling down again for bitches. Um,
and you know, it's even pissed.
The cancel account hose, it's over.
My request has been sent.
You will receive an email shortly with
instructions for confirming that you,
so
why won't you just let me walk away?
That's what they're doing.
A divorce.
You have to go to your email and click
on a link and it's like a divorce to do
it now because they don't want to,
they want to pretend they have more
people on my space. Spam continuing. Okay.
Finish him.
You know what sucks is that Facebook just
today has forced their new profile on
all the Facebook book accounts.
Neupro Fox as really hard because it
high. All right, when you go to Facebook,
at least how I do I, the first
thing I like to do is like, hmm,
this is person single is this,
you know, look at their photos.
Now they've hidden like the single part
and then it's just like this really
shitty, like it'll look, it reminds
me of what my space, they've,
they've moved it all around and now
it's just, Oh, you can change out with,
there's actually companies that do that.
Um,
somebody just hit me up from our
company to customize my mind space of my
Facebook page. Yeah. To make
it look all tricked out. Yeah.
Well now that they, they,
they used to let you go back.
We talked about having to have a marketing
degree to be a good standup comic.
Right. I try, I got two kids. I work
on them. You know, like I really,
I told you it's about my situation
website though. Website and cases,
what you're doing. I'm in
touch. If somebody emails me,
I'll definitely get back to Twitter.
By the way,
is Al Madrigal a l m a D R I
n g sauteing stuff happening,
but you should say it, Missouri. God,
especially if you go on before Willie
Barsana, you don't even see your own name,
right, bro? How many followers do you
have closing on 3000. Not too many.
We're going to blow that out of
the water today. Yes. Monitor here.
I can't jump you up to 5,000 you fucker.
How has been cancelled?
You got that kind of reached it.
I could just chop 2,835 you know what?
If I get people to sign on,
I will. I'm a funny guy.
I'll start putting shit out there.
I'm at war
with my neighbors right now. Are you
really? Yeah. What's going on? Well,
let's just sort,
I'm surrounded by old people and
I'm surrounded by these three guys,
isn't it a bit, this is real treat
three guys named Phil. I go old Phil.
Really old Phil and in Filipino Phil
as how I like a Filipino fills my ally.
Which one makes your banana credit?
No one there with the other
guys are goofing though.
Complainant banana cry.
It's going to be the new thing.
Do you want me to to make your banana cry?
See you talk about this on stage. Yeah,
I got to see the bit. So
anyway, I'm sorry. So I'm
surrounded by old people and um,
it's Eagle rockets and
upcoming neighborhood still
and there's a lot of cool
people that live near me,
but at the same time,
it's just rounded by all
people that are in my business.
I went on my roof to clean out my gutters
and it's like the all assembled below
me where like I was conducting some, you
know, double arp meeting and that I can,
they're all in my business.
And like I had at one
point I had three cars.
I still have three cars right now.
And then I have,
I got GM was nice enough to
get me a Buick onc, a enclave,
the holiday and let me use that.
Um,
it's just where like perked through the
Pr Department and this thing is awesome
and I, uh, it's really just talking
an incredible vehicle anyway,
so that shows up.
So I have four cars and the old people
are stopping my constantly and go,
do you feel a check conomical to have
three vehicles and I can't help but fuck
with them and hate them when they ask you.
Oh,
I have people in my shit constantly about
my hedges. My mean, and there's a guy,
old guy walks his dog by my house every
fucking day and is so in my business
like is stop.
If I even show my head,
he'll stop and start asking
a million fucking questions.
And so you live up here in this community
where it's nice and there's not,
I mean your neighbors aren't on you.
I have neighbors just on my end.
That sucks dude. I'm so not into that.
Yeah, no, it's not even like this.
I lived in the woods for three
months while I live in Colorado.
Was that it was the perfect place
for me. I was driving up, I was like,
this is how you do it. Did I
have old people on my shit?
And then also, you know,
it's sort of a little gangly
ish sometimes. So like somebody,
he'll write a mini truck will
go, you know, down the street.
You that guy like driving by with the uh,
really fast
for no, we won't worry about that
with your kids, the gang you part.
Well it's no gang adjacent.
It's not really not right in this shit.
It's close enough where it's going to
become an issue in their life. Yeah.
You can definitely stumbled down
to the wrong area and just get any,
well anywhere you can get
caught in the wrong time.
But here it's a highly
unlikely, you know, like again,
I mean I have a more realistic chance
of running into some bad people in my
neighborhood. Yeah. And a, yeah,
I worry about my wife being alone when
I gave you stand up and shit like that
all the time. Yeah. I know that
feeling. And even with household shit,
if anything breaks.
And you know,
we've had stuff where I've
been on the road doing standup,
I travel all just like not
as much, but I, you know,
I go out a fair amount and uh, yeah, my
wife's one with two kids and luckily,
you know, we got Filipino frank there.
So tell me what's your issues with your,
your world?
Let's try to come and trim my shit.
Like is you know how you have a hedges?
Yeah, my dog goes route and barking.
The other day my neighbor was secretly
trying to trim my fucking Madge lousy
trimming. You're just old and drunk
and crazy. Like just talk to him.
Um, no I might, they put, brought over a
letter c I, that's what I'm talking about.
I feel crazy about this. I'm like, you
want a war? I'll bring you war. God,
I didn't say that, but that's
how I feel. I say I like,
they'll get all pissed bent out of shape
if I am not talking to a neighbor for
two years because over parking we had
construction people over our house and the
Latino guys parked there and he came
running back to the old guy and fucking
start yelling into Latino guys to
move their car. It's a public street.
Anybody can fucking apart there.
I'm at war where I want him
to talk to the fucking guys.
I like Bourbon war really is
particularly in their turf.
And then the real issue is people are
not supposed to be on top of each other.
Like they really spread out apartments,
man apartments or where it's
really bright on top of each other.
I talked to the apartment
north Hollywood where I had a pool table.
Okay.
And I lived on the second floor and there
was this crazy gay couple that lives
on the first floor and he
was like the landlord to are
the, uh, what is it called?
The Superintendent.
So landlord now,
he was always controlling
things and it wasn't him.
He didn't know in the building,
but he ran it. So, um,
I had a pool table installed in my
living room. I had a big living room.
And the reason why I got this big living
room was because I could get a pool
table. I want her a pool table
in the living room, right.
So I had installed and he comes
knocking on the door, what is,
what's going on in there?
There's a lot of movement and there's a
lot of movement up here. And I go, Oh,
I've got a pool table because you're,
you jumping around,
are you working out or
something? I go, no, no, no, no.
I just walked around the pool table. Yeah,
he's talking making shots. And he goes,
okay,
I'm going to have to ask you to not do
that when I'm home because it's just like
I'm in the living room and all I hear
is creak, creak, creak, creak, creak.
And I'm like,
so you're saying that because of the
structural instability of this shit had
fucking apartment building.
You don't want me walking in my
living room because it's annoying.
Yeah. I started changing
my wireless password cause
they're right on top of you.
Right, right. So everybody in my, so I
changed my wireless. Now my network name,
I can change it to anything I want.
Right.
So I put like weeds your lawn that I
changed my network and then I looked on it
like, hey, we link cs. You're
bugging we, you line. Hey, hey.
Oh yeah, quit trimming my
bucking hedges. Wow. I like that.
That's fun. Or they trust steal
off your fucking wireless.
Yeah, man, that's creepy.
When you have neighborhoods,
man,
there's always that one kid that lived
down the Brock that's going to steal your
fucking shit when you're not
looking at, yeah, there was,
someone has some troubled
16 year old troubled youth
walking around. Always, man,
my friend of mine got his fucking bike
stolen. Some fucking kid down the street.
Kids are
walking up the block just walking up.
Just, you know, just looking around,
not doing. I'll say, where's that guy
fucking go? You know, he's walking.
I've arrived. Nobody. First of all in La,
very few people without a dog walking.
And I don't have, you know, chicks have
Lulu Lemon on or something like that.
And you know,
they're dressed in outfits.
I mean when you see just alone fucking
thug, it's like seeing an aunt,
just a wave from the rest of them to
live in a nice spot to live in a quiet
spot,
try to find a quiet nice spot.
And that's why somebody before
go to the suburbs, you know,
like you go to downtown Cleveland, it's
shutting down. There's nothing there.
The fly, every single store is
released and shit like that.
I couldn't find a department store
and my wife sometimes tells me pack no
underwear. So I got to buy
underwear and downtown Cleveland,
not a department store.
Now it's like Walgreens or Brooks
brothers and that's the only carry little
things that they had.
Cleveland's weird. Yeah.
Does everybody moved down to a
quieter place called what it is? Yeah,
the jobs disappeared,
right?
Isn't that what happened with quell plants
got shut down or something like that
in Detroit.
You know,
people went south and went to
Columbus and Cincinnati cause just,
I mean Cleveland used to be the,
you know, the biggest city in Ohio.
He used to be like the flat.
So it used to be the place to be the cool,
the cool part of Ohio. Now it's scary
improv down there. That's a real dump.
The, yeah, did it once. Well they have,
it's, they just gave out so many passes.
They completely ruined the room. That's
what a lot of comedy clubs don't do.
Is that just the quality,
they're just giving out pass.
And so they give out free passes to,
the tickets are free.
So they're selling booze and
they tickets have no value.
A lot of places believed that
are in the liquor business,
not the comedy business.
And they just want people
inside to drinking so they
can see their appointments.
You gotta just keep the fucking
wolves away. Sure. You know,
it's like for a lot of these places,
like in the middle of nowhere,
it's real hard.
And a lot of the comics that are getting
shipped down there are terrible. Yeah.
How many times have you like been
in a club and you look at the line,
I'd be like,
whether they got going on here and you
read their calendar and you're like,
oh shit, she, Jesus. Fuck.
And you just imagine these poor people
having to come and sit and watch this.
Some kid told me a quote there,
which I was working with.
He said he was at a show and his comic
was so bad. Some old black lady yells out,
you're ruining my free passes.
Oh my God, that was the best I can.
One thing that sums everything else.
They're ruining my free pass.
God's hilarious.
This for free. And I hate
it. This is horrible.
That's so funny. And that's why a lot of,
you know, like when people get, you know,
when you're, uh, like comedy
promoter, you do free beer.
Like there's always gotta be something
else that will justify, I can move.
Yeah. It's a tough fucking
businessman and he's sort of a bar,
restaurant business on a pool hall,
anything like that. Night and night,
nighttime business, those fucking things
are hard man. And when times are tough,
like they are now, the economy gets
shitty and then it becomes, you know,
they really don't want to go out.
They don't want to take a chance to just
go see comedy. You know, if you know,
they know someone is going to be there,
you know the bill burrs
in town. Okay, let's go see him.
You know I know who he is. Yes,
Stan help has that joke that he's done.
I was like,
how many people are here to see me?
How many people are here to see comedy?
And half of them reply and is like,
don't do that with anything else.
You don't go. Just roll into,
you know, many things. And
it's also, you know, I've said
this before but I'll say it again.
The real problem is that
generic label comedy,
it's like you don't go to see live music
and not knowing if you're going to get
Barry Manilow or guns and roses
or you know, a rap band, you know.
But with comedy you could get that and
you could get that all on the same night.
You can get like five different comments.
Can go out at the Improv and
they all at five different,
totally different acts and sure. Yeah.
John Reap and any Griffin maybe. Yeah,
exactly. Polar opposites.
Babo Shack, you know,
just these drastic Babo shack can't
call into the store anymore. Really?
Yeah. This, they told him he's too old
series going towards younger people.
What's his name is still can go there
every day and he's got his thing.
Wow. Yeah. Yeah.
That's your fucking job to Shaq is a
very funny comedy writer and a very funny
comedian. I mean, you should look
him up. He's talking incredible.
And also when you heard and listened to
a guy like that is a perfect talk about
alliteration and the story and find, I
mean just kind of, he's a great character.
Notch. Yeah. He's, he would
be a great talk show host.
He was, I think for awhile,
that's when he moved to Florida and he
was working on one of those good morning
shows is to, you're on him. He moved away
from la I'd say three years ago. Really?
And once you go be a,
you can type in Bombo shank on youtube.
And see him as a morning correspondence.
Wow.
And so that fell apart in that new big
Gig and they just moved back to Los
Angeles. Yeah. So Bob, oh, shack in
the morning or whatever. Kids. Yeah.
He has two kids, uh, at about
the same age as mine, you know,
and at eight and four range.
I can't believe they're
telling him not to get spots.
Did he play David Letterman and that
old movie? No. No, no. But he always,
he has this look about him like where
he really looks like a young Dave
Letterman, you know, emotion by
Oprah to be one of the top comedian.
Speaking of Volpara now
we were talking about it.
That's how we first met was over some old,
Oprah's a watching what we did stand up
together and we went up to my house and
just sat there baked 11 years
ago watching old Oprah flooded.
Yeah.
We were doing a bong hits in Al magicals
couch watching Oprah from like the 80s
when she had big hair. She's Richard.
Did she have plastic surgery?
What's happening right now?
Like we were just sitting there and
I think there were people around us,
but then you were just
sitting watching the Oprah,
like there was a little bit of a gathering
and people were talking to drink your,
your wife before she was your wife and
some other buttons. One other person,
a couple of people. And she would just
completely focused on this old Oprah.
And so we're barbecue and you know,
when something,
your barbecue is something like all
of a sudden like, wow, why have,
I never seen it like this before.
It was so strange.
It was like we were watching
like an alien film too.
Anyway. Oh, Shaq was on and
touted as one of the next grade
communions and nobody knows comedy.
Like that bitch.
Yeah.
Of whole new networks about watch
how comedy central own. Yeah. Yeah.
It's like the white version of def jam.
What?
Um,
so nothing on [inaudible] would have to
pull him over it so it doesn't matter.
It's all right. It's just another one
of those stories, you know, story.
It's been the interesting thing about
being a a comedian and living in La is
watching the whole,
you know,
the whole story of humanity unfold for
many different people in many different
players. And they all
just, you know, they,
they take their part in the game
and they all go through it and you,
you get to watch him and a lot of them
you get to learn from to learn from their
fuck ups and learn, even though you sort
of pick the path that you want to go,
it's like choose your own adventures.
Like am I going to be like that dude?
Am I going to end up like that?
And then you get to go,
am I going to go into the cave?
Am I going to choose to go to space?
Like you have to make choices
along the way and if you fuck up,
then you might go off in some other
positive direction. But not necessarily,
I mean, there's a lot of choices
to be made. I've been on,
like I was talking about,
I'm talking six pilots or something like
that at this point since I've taught,
you know, we've met and not one
of them has really taken off.
It's been weird and one of them could
have taken off immediately. Yeah.
You ended end up like you can
like get super duper lucky. Um,
and not to see you're lucky on [inaudible]
news radio. Just no Garrett, no doubt.
I was lucky. I, the first two
things I ever auditioned for,
I got the first two shows. I never, I
didn't go on like a bunch of auditions,
like a lot of actors. I auditioned for
one thing when I was living in New York.
I got it came out to California that got
cancelled. I auditioned for news radio.
I got that. Bam. No acting experience
at all. It's total luck. There's no,
no getting away from them.
It was just,
I was in the right place at the right
time when they were looking for stand ups
on sitcoms. That's all it is.
So it's a lot of luck, you know,
I could have had the same thing as you.
It could have been six different pilots
and nothing happened or could have been
one and actually had that part before
you talk to news radio. Yeah. Yeah.
He, he had it, but I
didn't take it from him.
I took it from the guy who took it
from him. Aha. That's even better.
They decided somewhere along the line
that they were going to go some in some
different direction and you know,
meanwhile it turned out to be the greatest
thing ever for Ray Romano Fuck News
radio. I mean, Ray Romano,
me $800 million. If somebody
saw him the other night.
Did you, do you know him? I know
real well and uh, he was, uh,
seemed like you incredibly
humble and he's a very cool guy.
He's as down to Earth as possible. He
hasn't changed at all. He's the same guy.
And uh, he was talking about something
that I can totally relate to it too.
When I was, we were at the taping of Paul
prevents his Green Room. He did it a,
the night before I did it.
And by the way, kitties,
I had a conversation with Mark Marin.
We're both gonna do each other's podcasts.
Yeah, that'd be [inaudible] no real beef
there. Yeah. This is a big Twitter issue,
but uh, so anyway, um, he, yeah,
people keep asking me to do it and
what it looks with. The other thing,
I don't want any beefs any, but
I hear you. It's distracting.
It's a waste of time.
That's all it is,
is a waste of time.
And you really think about a pride and
shit like that. It's like, shut up.
We would have who go to work,
you know,
it's like the wars wanting to do
my shit. Yeah, I hear Ya. Yeah,
exactly the same way. Anyway, I'm, Ray
Romano was talking about how, you know,
you know, uh, even after all
these years I do these shows,
it sounds like Kermit the frog eight he
said even after he does all these years
and he goes, does, is he
shows at the Mirage in Vegas
or wherever he goes and uh,
you know, massive fucking crowd. He said
he still feels like a fraud. Imposter.
Yeah.
He feels like when he gets,
he's stepping out there that all these
people are, sure. I think he goes,
I think at any moment we're going to just
turn around and just point a finger at
me and go, you're a deck and we
don't really like you. You know?
And that is what it feels like. It's
a, it's a weird thing like as you know,
do comedy all these years and you know,
and people are there to see
you and they're all psyched
up and they're cheering
when they're bringing the name. And as
you're walking to the stage you're like,
what the fuck am I even here in ceiling?
Tom Papa told me great stories about that.
Like a,
he'd work to sell out comedy clubs and
he started selling out some comedy clubs
in any move to the smaller theaters.
And then as a guy in a smaller theater,
he didn't take a moment to go, this
is it. I'm in a smaller theater.
He started thinking about getting in
bigger theaters like bad was his really
like we're, are we feeling this one? Okay,
we're filling this theater and then
we're going to move to a bigger theater.
You know, he wasn't satisfied
with the little theater. Yeah.
Where I'm thinking, oh my God,
if I can get to a theater,
I don't give a shit what size it is. Yeah.
That's like the jump off point. Yeah.
For comics. So you always want
aspire to users. Yeah, exactly.
Theaters are a lot of
work though, man. Sure.
It's a lot of work to try to sell them
unless you've got this giant following.
You know, I was on the road with
Mitch Hedberg and he tells us,
just told a story about him and Lynn
trying to think they could do a theater on
their own and they didn't need a promoter
and it was sold down at this comedy
club forever and they were just going
to try and do and he said it was an
absolute disaster.
We only like half full.
They lost money or barely
broke even while the,
pretend we didn't have the Internet
in full effect, but no, not at all.
Mitch Hedberg website was bunk.
It was like look like somebody put it
together at a Netscape navigator that
build a website page.
Shaylee did that,
you know Shane Lane that goes around
with Stan Ho? Yeah, Gray Shaylee.
Did that website terrible website. It
really is. It's the older style changes,
all the updates going
on there. Right. And so
he didn't have like a regular blog
or he didn't have a message board or,
so it's hard for him to get the word out.
You've got to have a lot of shit going
on. Yeah. A lot of different connections.
Now there's also so many
different applications that
you can use that allow it,
you know, the communication, it'd be
just, you know, it's a lot easier.
Well before you're doing,
you know,
just emails if you're doing that or
some sort of weird email newsletter with
asterix, you know, as a
separation points. You know,
there's a lot more out there
now. It's easy. I mean,
you gotta be a fucking marketing major
to do all this shit. I got Twitter,
I'm going to keep a track
of all this other stuff.
And then you're trying to about tricking
out on Facebook pages and we just
deleted on myspace pages. It's like
staying on top of his shit. Well,
it's gotta become a part of
your life and it really does.
And I love the fucking news stream.
I did that with them. I in um,
Dallas with house barks,
he dropped by sparks was here.
We had them on the podcast.
We had a really surreal thing.
We were in a strip club at triple the
lodge, you know, that plays the lodge.
Where's it at in Dallas. Addison is
and um, there was a monkey there,
so me and Hal and a monkey
and fucking distributors.
It was really fucking weird. We went
to dinner with the guys radio show,
a big Dick Hunter, you know.
Okay. Hunter. Yeah. Good guy.
And so we were there and
his wife works at the lodge,
which is a great strip club. It's,
we're talking about B, you know,
strip clubs being CDF. Do you have
kids? And she didn't like that.
This is a really fucking nice one.
It's top notch.
I mean that's the thing
is they higher quality.
I seem to enjoy everything
luxury at this point. Yeah.
I want everything to be top notch.
I've seen the best hotel room,
you know and shit like that and everything
is going to be held up in comparison
to that at this point. Once you fly for
his class, it's difficult to bugging.
Go on a southwest flight,
crammed in in a mirror.
When you realize how things can be
nice shit, everything can be nice.
And the same thing as with
true with strip clubs,
you know like there's bad ones where
we in, it's disgusting. Like you said,
becoming a Germaphobe, you know, and I'm
thinking about all these other dudes.
I was in Tempe and I was,
it was early on in my comedy career.
I went to a strip club during the day
that you do check writing guide during the
day. And by the way, you know, have
3,148 followers. That's amazing.
That gave you like 400 followers
easily. Bam, boom. Like that.
His response equipment like and respect,
I'm sorry.
So you went to a strip club during,
during the day and I was never
a good sign of a good time.
I remember going to a Bachelor Party
and Mr Club was one of the best places,
like fantasy sequence, two girls
at one time it was half off beers,
half off lap dances who are five lap
dances for one or some crazy thing where
I've loved that. No, it was a dream
sequence for a strip club. Perfect. Uh,
Asu chicks well before being
married and I go in, yeah.
And I go in there and um,
the during the day when I was by myself,
old guy just in the corner
in a wheelchair and his girl,
he's regular in this girl is really hot,
goes up to him and starts rubbing on him
and I was looking at her before and she
starts like, he's, Hey John, how are you
today? Did you get the grilled cheese?
And like having small talk and she
spends like 30 minutes with them and then
comes directly up to me afterwards
and goes, do you want dance? They go,
I looked at her, I go, no, absolutely not.
What the fuck he see what you just did?
He just rubbed up against death and
I'm going to fucking get a lap dance.
It's disgusting.
So I'm saying this place to the lodge and
Dallas is actually really bug and nice
and beautiful. Not like that now. Like
the place would be old routine visit.
Tricky thing man with old dudes,
man.
Old dudes like they get taken at
strip clubs all the time. You know,
they become like a, a part of the
landscape. When Eddie Bravo used
to be a DJ at a strip club, I used to
go and visit, of course he was. And uh,
for years, for like 10 years
and so awesome. And uh,
I would go and visit him
at work and uh, he had, uh,
like you get to know the
ecosystem of the place.
It gets to know how it works and you
get to see like he was dating this girl,
right?
And the girl was over by the DJ booth
and I'm talking to her and I'm my castle,
what's going on? Blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. You know, we're just talking,
she's talking totally normal like this.
And all of a sudden this guy walks in
and the guy had like a poster poster
workers jacket on. So he's not a guy that
makes a ton of money, right. As you know,
it works for the post office. So he
comes in, he's got a baseball hat on,
it looks like he's
probably about 50 and she,
she all of a sudden turns it on and I
saw it and it was like, it was shocking.
It was like when you see your cat
kill a mouse for the first time,
you ever see a cat kill a
mouse and you love that cat.
But all of a sudden bang that candidate
fucking this mouse up. And it's like,
Whoa, you evil bitch. Like, I never
knew this about you. Well, you know,
I'm talking to her. She seems totally
normal and this guy comes in, she's like,
hey baby.
And she comes running over to this guy
and you can see ways poor fuck is just
smitten. He is just so sad. And
she's like, oh my God, you're here.
And she puts her one hand on his lower
back and one hand on his chest and he's
got his arms around her,
both of them class behind him and she's
like rubbing up against them. I'm like,
Whoa, I'm watching. I'm watching a victim.
Like she's going to inject him with
venom and suck all the money out of it.
But this guy had bought her a truck,
he bought her a Yukon Denali.
She had was having problems with her car,
so he bought her a fucking car and an
expensive one was super luxury doubt.
Denali's still like just like
Cadillacs and escalades. No,
just as nice but just trunk
space. You have to, dude, it was,
it was the craziest thing ever. It
was watching and it was like, whoa.
Like this is like, but this
isn't nature man. This is,
this is just as just as natural
as any other thing, you know,
just as natural as a,
a bug that gets caught in a spider's
Web and get zapped with venomous.
Well, and also marriage, you know, the, a
lot of these guys married way too early.
I mean,
just think back then they were getting
married to 2025 so they're trapped in
these relationships that grow
into different people. Right.
No wonder there's so much divorced,
so then you're trapped with this woman
who just becomes fucking nasty and then
they get those mom haircuts.
They all look like they have that little
lesbian mom hair cut about and like
denim jeans and all kinds of things
about what your mom's going to give up
altogether on their bodies and then he
can go to a strip club and be with a 10
and all the cost is maybe $22,000 after
you get that car wholesale and here he's
got this 10 that's just all
over him on a regular. Yeah.
Basically that was his,
apparently his modus operandi,
this guy's thing was to come there after
work and just hang out and hang out for
hours and hours and hours and just
give this check all of his money,
like literally gave this chick all of his
money everyday was like a new thousand
thousand here, a thousand there are
a thousand here and I can never do.
That's another
part was true clubs is I'm too worried.
Like I started thinking,
I'm like if I took this money
and went to Aashe I could get it.
Okay. Yeah. Orchard
supply hardware. How supplies. Yeah, I do.
I'm still work on my place. Stripper
money. Money's got into my home. Yeah.
That's mad money. That's like, um, um, you
know, that's, I'm a ball. Seriously. Yeah.
Taken it and thrown your way. This
throw away all this blood. Yeah.
I think about that all the time.
Even if it's going out
drinking or something like
that. I'm like, Shit, I just,
you know, went out to eat
and I spent, you know,
$60 I could have went and
bought a fucking groceries up.
I hate this. You can go with the best
steak ever at a supermarket for 20 bucks.
20 bucks. Yeah. Well if you got a big
fat thick one, aren't they like 20 bucks?
Yeah.
To like 20 bucks.
Well that's like also it's like riding
the wave of these comedy careers.
Cause sometime point you can get like
look at like a guy like Elon gold,
you know, the comic. He's
always been on shows.
He wasn't an show stacked with
Pamela Anderson. He was on, you know,
he's been on sitcoms. She's got four
kids. Wow. Does it really? Yeah,
he's got impressionists or you look back
Ilan gold, Seinfeld and shit like that.
He does a lot of good and very easy.
Very good impressions. Very pleasant.
Good impressions of comics.
Yeah, he's very funny. Anyway,
so he like as on the shows
and the shows go away,
he has just sort of ride it out and
save as much money as you possible can.
I'm in the same boat. It's like I got
a deal then I have nothing in that.
You know you have the key is to keep the
standup going so that you always have
something.
Yeah.
You know that if you're standing up as
strong and you headline all over the
country and you get a big
following and you know,
especially develop an internet presence,
then you don't have to ever worry about
things because he always got money
coming in and you can always
sort of hustle on and I'm
not making a ton of money
doing stand up, but you
can, I can make living.
I can definitely make what somebody,
that guy in the post office,
but you could but listen to, you could
be making a ton of money doing stand up.
You have the stent,
the comedy chops.
It's just a matter of getting your
comedy out there to more people.
That's the thing. I'm going to have
a great product. No, no, no, no.
That's the thing that people
come out to see me live. It's,
it's nothing but good
shows a build borough.
I talked to him a lot and he told me
it's killing an obscurity. He goes,
2001 to 2006 was my killing
you obscurity, faith. He goes,
it was just crushing it every where you
go, nobody knows who the fuck you are,
and then it just starts to snowball and
snowball and you get on this thing and
that thing happens and it's just getting
the people in the notoriety to have
people be familiar with your
shit. And then, you know,
we'll just all start to fucking happen.
The key is to keep doing comedy.
When I was on a news radio,
like I was always constantly get
encouraged by people to not do it anymore.
They were like, [inaudible], you're
on, you're on. You're an actor now.
Paul Riser, who's just could have
been, you know, Seinfeld kept going,
all of these guys, Ray Romano was
still does stand up. G Kevin James,
I think is still going out there.
Doesn't do it at all anymore.
Riser just stopped all together.
It's like,
thank God I know what working with Helen
Hunt for 10 years rushes every comedy
instinct you have every day. You probably
like, what the fuck am I talking money?
I mean, Michael Keaton was a stand
up. There's all these actors.
Didn't Michael Keaton Woosah?
I don't.
I haven't seen any of Michael Keaton
standup on Batman was a stand up.
What happened with Michael Keaton? Stop.
No, he's working for a long time though.
He stopped. He stopped. Yeah, he, uh,
he dropped you off and they dropped.
She came like this, uh, kind
of like character actor guy.
He went from being like this main
movie star too, like a break.
And then now he's a character actor,
which is really kind of a fascinating
transition. Well, he was in the movie,
the good guys with, um,
the other guys would, uh,
will Farrel Farrel and see that
he's really funny. And then yeah,
he's bringing up a TLC references. That's
it. It's just weird that, you know,
he was, he was a giant movie star at
one point in time. I remember the,
the colon moving Batman three
men and a baby. Was he in that,
wasn't it Tom Gutenberg was in that, uh,
Steve Gutenberg. Steve Gutenberg, sorry.
And Dad's a Steve [inaudible]
story. Steve Gutenberg, you know,
he's lost his mind and he, yeah.
And he used to be another one.
It used to be a big movie star.
And now that God can't get arrested,
he doesn't do anything. Well, the
day Phil Hartman was murdered,
Steve Gutenberg shows up at Phil
Hartman's house and he didn't know Phil.
I mean if he knew him, he knew him
like casually, like he didn't know him,
like I knew them or like you know,
someone who worked with them on
Saturday live might have known him.
He barely knew the guy.
So he shows up with a fucking suit and
tie standing in front of Phil Hartman's
house,
um,
and acting as like a liaison between
the entertainment industry and the press
and trying to ask the press to,
uh,
to use respect and to use
good judgment and say, yeah,
his family loan is trying time.
And the way he did it was easily move.
He was so creepy, dude. It was
so like this poor fucking guy.
Like something happened. Like he'd be,
he blew a fuse or something, something,
something he had.
He must have had some sort of a breakdown
because the idea of him even doing
this and to the neighbor or
anything. No one near him. Wow.
There was a few famous neighbors too.
He lived down the street from Sam Adams.
I'm not Sam Adams at the fuck Samuel
Jackson Jackson. Yeah, Sam Adams.
The fuck's wrong with me.
I mean,
you had a bunch of famous neighbors
and you know, it wasn't, you know,
someone saying, Hey, you know,
let's, this is my neighbor.
Please leave them alone is a guy
who just shows up and he says, the,
the cameras are going to be here.
I'm just going to get on camera
and I'm gonna speak for the end.
He thought he was like, yeah,
it's some sort of a message.
But the real message that everybody
was getting out of it was like,
why the Fuck is Steve Gutenberg there
with a suit and tie on it to save your
seat?
Brian Holtzman at the Freddy Soto
Memorial. Did you ever hear about that?
Know where he goes? Uh,
just yells out and um,
have you motherfuckers here?
Don't even know Freddy.
Just trying to fucking see if
there's a manager or an agent.
Fuck, fuck it all you mother fuckers.
It's true though.
He's right.
Freddy's friends.
You never wonder for each friends
admitted to never being a virgin.
Right during the memorial. He
goes, I knew Freddie would, oh,
get the biggest kick out of this, and
so I'm going to do it. And he goes,
I need to tell everybody right
now. He goes, I'm a virgin.
Holtzman goes up after him and goes,
first line it goes, I'll fuck that virgin.
Please go, fuck it's memorial. The please.
Oh course.
Yes. I mean, that's so funny.
Holds me. It is. Anyway, so he, um,
but then proceeds to say, look
at your mother fuckers. Like, oh,
looking around like
somebody here and then, um,
Joey Diaz has the best thing that the
Maryland Martinez memorial went off on
this guy, Jeff Valdez. Uh, I
think he's just, look, everybody.
Jeff Valdez is there. Fuck
you. Jeff Valdez. You know,
just walking you cock sucker.
Maryland fucking hated you and we all
fucking hate you. Why at the memorial?
Whoa. Maryland would love to fuck. And
then I'm doing this for you now, Joey.
It was one of the, um, wow.
I have my hands on my face.
Thank you Joey. Sankey douchebag.
He's like one of these guys. Who would
you step on your own fucking mother.
[inaudible] yeah.
Wow.
Who's pretty cause he knew
Maryland would love it.
That just like that guy
told us where he goes,
Maryland would want me to do
this and she would and she would,
I went on the road with her.
I was like, this is weird.
I mean I've been on the
road with Maryland Martinez,
Mitch Hedberg. So other
guy, um, passed away. Uh,
Dan Crawford and I was very good friends.
Was in San Francisco, which is horrible.
We do a benefit if you ever just San
Francisco Punch line to Dan Crawford
Memorial Fund. You know, we
give a comic of free liquor,
light a tab for the whole year,
but they really, the scholarship,
because this guy was just a great guy,
great partier.
And he was one of my good friends and
he just fucking died. We went to, sorry.
Yeah, Brian just moved away.
He went to the hospital,
he was a comic living in
his dad's basement and he
went to the hospital with a
headache. Public Hospital. You didn't have
insurance. He's a comic, 24 years old.
And they said, no, we can't help you out.
And they said away and then he went
back and said, it's really bad.
You got to help me.
And they give them Vicodin.
He went back to the garage and they found
them convulsing on the floor cause he
had bacteria had gotten in his brain.
And if had they seen him the
first time when he walked in,
he would totally be alive.
Wow.
And it was just a comic can usually
kind of kid without health insurance.
So I mean if anybody's up in the bay
area when I'm doing the Dan Crawford
scholarship thing in March and we raised
money to give to like find out about
the date Twitter, um, yeah, I'll,
I'll definitely put it on Twitter.
So Twitter. Wow Man. You know,
that shit happens all the time.
So I've been around all these
guys. I mean in Greek, Geraldo,
did you know about Jerry
Redd? Wilson didn't, do you
know Jerry Wilson? You know,
I heard that happening, but I didn't know
the guy. Wilson is another great guy.
I knew him from the scene in New York.
Really funny guy because
really a lot of ethnic humor,
Irish kid and they call Jerry Redd.
Wilson gets a pilot,
his pilots in the middle of shooting, I
think it went, what it did got canceled.
Anyway, the kids, he's always
working, he's in the mix
and um, he's got a headache.
He's got some fucking problem.
It goes to the hospital and he's waiting
in line.
I guess he's waiting in the waiting
room for like an hour and a half and he
can't take any more.
Fuck this.
I'm getting out of here and he has
to go to Hawaii to film. Um, the, uh,
fantasy island, the new version of fantasy
island. And by the time he gets there,
he's so fucked up that he dies.
He had meningitis and he had like
green shit leaking out of his ears.
He had like some serious fucking infection
in his brain and he just let it go.
You need to find a place for, you
can go get checked out. Well, yeah,
money does the problem. Yet he just
went, he just ignored the shit he was,
you know, he was one of those
inpatient guys, fuck this,
I ain't got time for this.
Let's get out of here. You know, he had,
his career was taking off at a
million things going on. You would,
he was one of those guys.
You would talk to him and he was just
so obsessed with it. He was like, well,
we've got a deal right now at universal
element that doesn't get picked up and
got them all. Yeah. You know, he was
like hustling and Fassler. Yeah, yeah.
He was making it happen.
So for him,
that hour and a half sitting in that
waiting room was just killing him.
So he leaves and he fucking
dies. You know, Shit.
And you're not supposed to
fly with a sinus infection.
They tell you that all the time. You're
not supposed to fly with that shit flew.
I flew once when I had pneumonia. Oh my
God. Cause I got to get to a stupid gig.
Yeah. And I just want you to, I'll fly
when I go to the Pacific northwest,
it feels like my head's gonna
fuck, next one. Wow. So, um, you,
you do that shit all the time. And
do you, I mean, you've got to find,
I sometimes get a little overboard
hypochondriac a little bit.
Well, you know, I got sick for the
first time this year in fucking years.
I haven't gotten sick and I slacked off.
And here's one of the reasons
why I take a lot of probiotics.
I drink like Kombucha.
That's Kombucha tea.
It's fucking super good
for your health is healthy.
The coconut juice is great too.
But what happened with Kombucha is they
got in trouble with whole foods because
they're, their shit was more than one half
of 1% alcohol, so it has to be labeled.
So they watered the fuck down their water,
their formula like seriously wandered
down where it tastes like shit.
It does not taste near it's gts.
Kombucha. It used to taste awesome.
It was like very carbonated, very
strong. And I really enjoyed the flavor,
but then it became like this,
like literally it feels like it's half
water and half what it used to be.
And I just, I think it's not, it's
not nearly as active, like the,
the probiotics in, and I don't
think they're nearly as strong.
So I got sick like for
the first time ever.
He really think that's why you got
sick. Yeah. You know why? Absolutely.
This is why I think it,
because I've never been sick before
and I've been drinking that shit almost
every day. So it, it changes
within a month of it changing.
I go and I get sick for the first time.
I, um, I really think that makes sense.
So I went to a vitamin SHOPPE and I walked
in there and I was deathly ill and I
said,
what are you selling all the time that
works for immunity and I stuffed line off
the shelf,
what is it?
And he took me to a thing called Saba
call black elderberry shit that you drank
and there's pills for it.
I would take Dan on a regular basis
whenever I get sick cleaned right off.
I mean,
it really does work.
There are definitely probiotics and what
they do is they attack all the negative
shit in your body. All the
unhealthy bacteria, you know,
it's like you're keeping healthy troops
on hand. Acidophilus is a big one.
I hadn't taken acidophilus in forever.
I will see that reason is
because I was drinking this
Kombucha all the time. I was like, I
don't need to supplement with acidophilus.
I'm getting plenty of probiotics from
this. So then once this stuff went bad,
I started taking acidophilus again now
to Gas Davos every day. That's the milk.
Yeah, it's an, it's a milk culture.
Yogurt. You could buy it and pills.
It'll live for me. You have to keep it
a frigerator, you know? But it's uh,
you know, especially
as you get older, man,
he started reading real
cognizant of your health.
Yeah, I started thinking about
it. I go to the gym and I was,
I've been trying to go every single day.
I get my resolution is holding up so
far and I even if I could just go for a
little bit,
I get my heart going and I stretch and
I can just trying to keep everything in
shape cause I'm on,
you know
you don't talk into the microphone
dude. Your votes varies. Oh is it? Okay.
I forget. Sorry, I'm looking at you at
the same time. No, that's all right.
Let's turn.
So we don't have to do that because it's
like your voice is like real low and
then all of a sudden it's real high.
So that people on the ecliptical machine
right now with their headphones in and
like this fucking owl magical.
Tell them where the Mike is. Right?
That's not a dissident. See where the
sign is, where the words are. Yeah.
That's the part we should talk to you.
Perfect. That was on the top of it.
You were ready dude.
You were right there
anyway. So you go to the gym. Yeah.
Take taking your better care of myself.
I feel like I could,
when I saw that UFC fight for the first
ready felt like I can fucking get in
there, lock somebody up. I certainly
feel like I have the mindset for it.
Like I really feel like I can kick some
killer. I used to fire people, you know,
that was my job when you
first met me and said,
I like up in the air with George
Clooney. Yeah. I used to be, I'm avid.
I terminated over a thousand people.
Yeah.
I'm just saying that was my job and my
parents' family businesses that I used to
be the fucking hatchet man.
Karma shit going on.
Well now they deserved it for the most
part. And so, but sometimes you headed to,
you'd send an unfortunate time.
It's like it's not,
it's like a privilege to be
working in having somebody pay you.
If you had a fucking employee and
you didn't have the money anymore,
there's nothing else we can do.
It's,
there's a bunch of different
ways of looking at this
economy being all fucked up.
And I see some people who
are very pragmatic look at
it like, hey, you know what,
these jobs,
these jobs that these people are losing,
these jobs weren't important in the first
place. These motherfuckers, you know,
we lost all our jobs overseas and what
we need to do is strengthen our economy
and this is just a
symptom of a bigger evil.
I see that but an individual
one on one basis, man,
whenever I think about these people
that are going broke and people that are
losing their houses and people
that don't know what to do,
especially if I think that they're
dumb and that their, you know, their,
their occupation options are limited and
then they have children and shit too.
It's like fuck man,
these poor Fox were led to believe that
this whole thing that this ship was
going to sail and it's going to be fine.
Well also it's what you were
talking about with stand up.
If you just decide to check
out and work and you just like,
you reach a $30,000 job and you say
this is, it is all I need. Right.
My father in law did that shed.
He's the type of guy who would go and
sit in a big recliner and get like a
thirsty to ouncer just fucking sit
there and watch TV, no aspirations.
Did you do anything? And he plays
golf, but people are looking like that.
There's a lot of people like that.
A lot of people like that.
You just become complacent. You're
like, this is good right here.
I don't know if it's bad.
I think there's a machine going on man.
I think we're all little
pieces of this giant machine,
you know?
And I think you can look at it like what
you're doing is very important and then
what you're doing has meaning to it.
But really it has meaning to you.
And I was meaning to the people
who like it. But what is,
what is its place in the overall grand
scheme? I don't know man. I don't know.
I mean these people sit in there
with drinks. They might be honest on,
often they might be on to something.
The guy who was the bouncer
just devour and no job.
That guy was not on the something.
I don't, I don't believe that.
I think that kind of needs
to get a real fucking job.
Certainly 40 year old sewers.
Genius.
We need all the super genius is telling
people not to puke on his shoes.
Good projects. Yeah, no hats. Yeah.
Super Genius. Yeah. No hats. No hats.
My favorite is like they tell you how to
wear your hat. Like no hats backwards.
Like I like wearing hats backwards.
That's how I wear actually,
because when I play pool,
I can see the balls better.
I don't want a big fucking floppy bill,
but I went into a pool hall
wants and the guy's like,
you gotta turn your cap around like what?
You've got to turn my hat around.
Like really? That's your rule. That
sloppy and had around in front ways.
All that's fucking someone's
[inaudible] remember one. Yeah.
Especially when you wear it
up high a little bit. Oh,
the other thing was no wallet chains
could have wall chains either.
I had to put my wallet chain in my
pocket, choke out God, Gotham comedy club.
I remember that. Did they
have no wall chains? No, no.
A new hats allowed at Gotham comedy club.
I'm like, yeah, it's like a comedy club.
And they were still getting it on me while
you were filming there. And I'm like,
no, I'm with Joe. And they still were
like, man, can you take it off? Wow,
come on. That's so silly. What
looks worse? A hat or a hat head?
Definitely hat head. Well, who's
getting offended by hats? I mean,
it's one thing if you wait some crazy
fucking Phyllis Diller thing with the
feathers. No one can see
behind you. Fucking Charlie
Chaplin was the last person.
And be offended by a hat,
you know,
or somebody back in the day where
they take off hats every time you eat.
Here it is, it's sort of a
three stooges. Like you know,
they invade the rich people's party.
And another one of my favorites is when
you go somewhere and they say you're
sure it has to have a collar. Like,
oh, we talked about that before,
the podcast about what it's like
in a, uh, a lot of parks in la.
It says a big science has no soccer,
no parties,
and like no soccer, no parties.
Why not just say no Mexicans?
We use Mexicans elsewhere. No soccer.
Why would not you not want soccer?
I guess people are trying to have
picnics, right? Playing soccer.
If you're white, I think you can
sort of do whatever you want.
If a Latino soccer game breaks out, which
they've been known to in Los Angeles,
they stop it. They stop it. Arius,
man, it's a fucking park. Is it the,
are they thinking that they dominate the
park and they make it unsafe for whites?
I have no idea. They just, you're there.
I know the old white guys at the top
of that. I can. He's making that.
Is that what that is? It's gotta be, yeah.
Trying to bring it back the
way it was in the 50s sure.
No Latino Park disturbance. I've
watched a, a bad men where they just,
they're in a park and they take their
big blanket and they just dump the thing
and shake out the blanket and all the
garbage just goes everywhere and then they
just walk away. That's how they should
do shit. Just litter and fucking the,
you know,
in our public parks were just complete.
What you were talking about
earlier with the water supply.
That's how people used the rocket.
Just if I can throw a coke out the window,
the window, it's, people still do
that all the time with cigarettes.
Do you do that Brian? Please
say you don't know. No, I, I uh,
knocked the cherry off into a, uh, uh,
usually have like a can in my
car and then I just, I've seen,
I've seen people throw burger king
bags out the window. I honked like,
what do I mean I did, I don't know why a
honk, I just walked in Hawk, right? Like,
Hey, that's fucked up. And a big hand came
out and just went, yeah, of course. Yeah.
There's a lot of cons out there.
We were forced them on
teenagers and I see a lot.
I see he's fucking Prius's
those Toyota Prius's.
And then I see the person driving the
Prius, flick a cigarette out the window.
I see that shit all Athens high,
save the earth tight.
I mark it down. I see it so
many times. I mark it down.
I've seen it seven times,
seven times over the past three years
that I've been looking for it. Yeah,
it's definitely something that,
that people do in other states all the
time in California and they don't do it
during the drive. Less littering
quite a bit in the Midwest. Yeah.
You didn't even think about it in Ohio,
that sort of what everyone does.
Like I didn't get it until when
I first moved out here. And you,
you got mad at me cause I
flick my cigarette on the
ground and he got mad at me.
I'm like, what? It's just a
cigarette. And then you were like,
pick that up Brian and blah blah.
I'm like never heard anyone
telling me to pick up a cigarette.
But there's a lot of people,
I mean there's the cigarettes are going,
there's a lot of people burning street
burning trash in their backyard as well.
Like that shit's happening.
Yeah, that's happening.
I mean I'm sure people are listening
where that's commonly done or you have all
this douchey behavior. How do you
stop it? What the fuck do you do to,
to change people? What do you do to turn
people around? How do you, what do you,
what do you do? You just kinda just
concentrate on yourself. I mean,
you volunteer or something and try to
help. I mean, you could go the extra step.
I mean, if you can't control
your own shit, first of all,
like my wife has recycling.
Like everything I get yelled at for not
putting something in a fucking resize to.
Yeah. Okay. But meanwhile some Chinese
guy down the block is burning a tire,
you know, it's fucking,
what the fuck? I mean,
how am I supposed to really care
that much? She gets separated out.
The homeless people are coming by two
of my neighborhood and rooting through
everything. They're like sorting it.
It'll get sorted out eventually. Shit.
So like, anyway, but how
are you supposed to care?
You can only worry about yourself.
And it's the same thing.
We stand up and like that's what we've
been talking about the entire time.
And she was right.
But as a whole,
if you looked at the human race or it
looked at just the human race in America,
you know though, the ones
that we understand, the
culture that we understand,
how the fuck do you fix it?
How do you fix this culture?
Is everyone getting organized to going
one common goal of living in harmony and
login in a safe and clean environment?
I mean there'll be no crime and
she'll throw in burger king bags.
I was window and giving you the finger.
How do you connect to that?
I don't think there's any way can take
connect to that guy because that guy
would maybe was brought up in a house
where it was a homeless kid and didn't
have any games.
You had this horrible fucking life
that you know and to just a Douche bag,
just a fat Douche bag in his dad's a
fat dude. I've got all kinds of things.
Like when I see people on pay phones,
I'm like,
there was no reason why you
shouldn't have of og and cell phone.
No,
I'm just talking about like,
I mean they're giving them away and
like if you're broke and you're on a pay
phone,
it's used for something illegal.
Tap every single fucking one of those
and just arrest those fucking seriously.
Funny. That could easily
just be broke people dude.
Or if someone loses their phone,
40 ounce, like an elitist,
a 40 ounce, 40 nothing
good has ever come. Great.
If you want to watch
superfly and review it,
that the best thing to drink right
now is that once with a buddy of mine,
we watched the country club. Country
Club is another one. What is it?
It's another malt liquor. They'd say,
Oh yeah, we had old English and um,
there was another one,
fuck, I forget what it was,
but there's a bunch of those that are
only there really marketed something.
King Cobra, I think it was marketed for
the black community, like straight up,
you know, taste to go down easy.
Like even the way it's written,
like the ads are written just like
just straight to the African American
community.
And when you start drinking that stuff,
those are so strong and they're so
strong and you don't give a fuck.
You drink that shit. You don't give
a fuck. He started drinking Boone's,
is that what it's called?
Like strawberry farm billion.
There was night train engineers. Is that
Boone strawberry farm or sweet wines?
Sweet wine. That was like
marketed to taste really good.
Grape one like grape juice. Grape juice
for purple drank and really is. Yeah,
they could, yeah. How do you
fix that? Well, there's also
Cisco and all that Shit.
Let me just really high all alcohol
content. We know that Loko four Loko.
Do you hear about that one? I had it
pulled it off the market. Oh yeah.
Somebody had it on new years of that
will wasn't sure that I was telling you
about. I took a shot of it all
night was help a heart palpitation.
Whoa. I really felt like it was
a four Loko really fucked me up.
I've heard people died off.
Yeah.
A couple of people are saying it's a
band and somebody had a big ass can Audi.
You got to try it for local coach band.
Oh go. I'll just take a sip of it.
We took one sip and a jacket. Dude.
I feel like it fucked my whole night.
I had the most surreal new
year's Sacramento punchline a,
it's in a strip mall next to us.
Sleep trained and I intend to uh, um,
how about Arden Mall? It's in a
strip mall. It is Barbara College.
You've been to that place, have a
phone, a cell phone store. A yeah,
in a strip mall at the upstairs,
next big mattress store.
All kinds of weird shops. Red lobster
next to a Tony Roma's next to an outback.
Like nothing.
Right.
And I mean there on new years and people
had paid $50 a ticket to go to this new
year's show and it was a good shot. I mean
I really, I didn't get up and half ass
50 odd ticket,
but it was weird.
Then spending your New Year's
in login strip mall dancing.
Some guy who are dom Perignon strip mall
and he's trying to show off in front of
his girlfriend and a fight broke out
because somebody spilled it. Wow.
There's a whole weird,
and I was filming the whole thing.
I was filling this one lady lip.
I really was on my flip.
I'm going to add the video, I'll make sure
I put that on Twitter as well. But um,
people came up to me, he's
like, are you filming our mom?
I go, no, I'm not familiar.
I sorta was filming their mom, not
really, you couldn't make out who it was.
And my flip camera and then the kid
who's the son of the mom who was dancing,
it was dancing really fucking
funny with his young Latino Kid.
And she was old and this Latino kid was
just dry humping or on the dance floor.
So I'm like, this is my new years as you
know, what a horrible fucking new years.
And uh,
they came up and the guy says,
I've been looking for an excuse to
kick your ass the whole night. Oh,
I know what the
why. Where'd that come from? I
haven't fucking done anything like
it was a horrible fucking new years.
Sounds better than mine though. What do
see where outside of the house stayed in?
I uh, Brian had a fight with his
girl on the ears, man. Girl left.
Scroll left him on new years, man.
That same girl you're talking about.
Not only does girl leave him on New
Year's trashy vixen, it's a long story.
I'm sorry. That's not
cool. You don't have to,
we'll have to play that prince line again.
Trust me.
It's for the best at this time or
last time. Uh, she broke up with them.
We had to play the prince on.
I got a broken heart again.
You really feel bad about it?
No, I don't feel bad at all.
This is what I described it as the same
way I described people who are do should
you on the internet that it's
like a little bit of snake venom.
It a little bit of snake venom
gets you immune to snake venom.
So that's named after a bite you three
or four times after. Why? Like, Hey,
get the fuck outta here. You know,
poisoning me anymore. She was, yeah,
she was one of those relationships where
like we would break up and then you
know,
something happened and then I would take
her back just because I know how broken
she is.
And then this third time was
just like so quick and fast like,
like we started dating again and next
thing I know she's almost moved in.
She's talking about getting married and
like this is like in two weeks and she
just got out of a relationship with this
guy like cheated on her or something
like that. And it was the most
intense zero to 60 in two weeks.
And then one day I was just out of
nowhere, she just started going crazy,
picking fights with me out of nowhere.
I'm like, what the fuck is going on?
Next thing I know next day she's
tweeting her ex boyfriend like pictures
together and like are
you fuck is going on?
Oh and I keep on finding all this shit.
She left at my house.
And one of the thing is is like she had
a memory card in my camera that she must
have used my camera.
And the funniest thing is,
is like pictures of her and this guy
and then the next day pictures of me in
her,
it's like do I he exact same poses like
arms around each other and it like two
days it
was actually a photo shopped
in over that other guy. Yeah.
Well you know what it is and this is,
this is how I describe it to you.
There's some people that are addicted to
that charge of an initial relationship.
When someone is just in love with you.
You know when you meet
someone man and you, you know,
you fucking really click and you're
hanging out in your fucking like four or
five times a day and you just kissing all
the time and you can't wait to see him.
That's like an intense fucking,
you know, intense romantic thing.
And then I got married. Yeah, that
works that way sometimes. Yeah.
And then when you are in a situation
where, let's be quite honest about this,
the girl, perhaps it might be a bit above
you on the food chain, right? Not a lot,
but a bit, right? Well then yeah,
then you're stepping on eggshells because
you're afraid of offending her because
you're in the situation. You're like,
Jesus, I don't want to fuck this up.
Like this is the greatest thing of
all time here. This is so perfect.
She's got the perfect body.
They're not going to find one of these
and telling all my friends, dude,
look at this picture. Can you believe
I'm fucking this? This is the same.
And so then you know,
they get addicted to that really intense
part of the relationship where you just
enamored by them and then as time goes on,
you get comfortable with each other and
then she becomes your girlfriend and
when she becomes your girlfriend,
then you just kind of like lack
of days ago around each other.
You don't care if your hair is fucked up,
you don't care if your breath smells,
hey, you know you pay with the door open.
You know, you have a flat box each other.
She doesn't give a fuck either.
And so you know it,
it becomes some weird thing where you
just get real comfortable with each other
and you don't fuck as much.
And then some other guy comes along and
that other guy shows the same potential
for being the guy that's so in
love with you. And this is it.
It's supposed to be about us.
We've had some problems in the past.
We're going to fucking stick
together forever for till death.
We're going to have babies.
Yes.
And then the range is on again and
it's just as mad fucking crazy.
Dash from one person to the next
who can provide the next charge,
the next beginning of the
relationship. Thunderous, you know,
orgasmic type of a interaction.
And it sucks because I've gotten to the
age where I totally know that, you know,
and, and so I am like, this person
gets hurt. And I'm like, you know,
I want you to know,
I can tell you what happened to
our relationship and you know,
we can really work this together and
I'll do the stupid take girl back from I
need to, I need, I don't
know, I just need to stop.
You know what man is stop
dating girls started dating guys
and they're like all this shit that's at
my house. And I'm like, Oh wow, a sock,
a bra. And I'm like, I need to date guys.
Cause then they can leave things like,
oh Gillette sensor blades razor are,
you know, like a video game. Oh,
he left me a video game.
I hate the shit that,
that girls leave over relationships
36. Oh, that's good. How old are you?
39. Oh, you see, I thought
you were way younger than me.
Yeah. Um, I think, uh,
you know, look, it's,
it's hard to find someone that you fucking
drive with all the time and sometimes
people can keep it together for long
stretches where they really are.
The perfect girlfriend for
like two weeks is crazy.
Bitch really is the perfect girlfriend.
She's a lot of fun. She wants to cook.
She's hilarious. She cracks jokes,
going to look forward to seeing her.
And then after that two weeks
they'll fucking crazy comes out.
And after the two weeks,
it's what am I going to do for a living
and what am I going to do for this and
what happens when I get old and what am
I going to do when I'm 50 and foc and
show these licks are not going to last
forever. I've got to kind of a strategy.
I got to figure out what I want to
date a blind deaf girl. Not only that,
you've got a date dude, ready for
this. You've got a date. Civilians,
civil [inaudible] aliens. Absolutely.
My wife says, you're a great teacher.
Bengo perfect civilians. Listen,
you are, you're a creative Weirdo.
Okay. And if you're dating
another creative Weirdo,
she's going to be just
as fucked up as you are,
but in a way you can understand
because she's going to be a woman.
That's what the hardest part
about living in California though,
is because 90% of the populations out
here to be in the same entertainment
industry. There's a lot of regular
nice sound. I know a a or something.
My wife's teacher friends that are very
single and available, they're painted.
They're tainted. They're out here.
Listen. They know how magical.
He's probably in Texas anytime
soon. Joe. We gotta move.
You gotta move to Colorado with
me. I'm moving back. Back. Yeah.
I want my kids to be
raised in Colorado tax.
I don't want my kids to be raised in
California. I think this place is just,
it hums at to higher frequencies
to share. Yeah. That's,
I don't want to go further out.
I want to live on a ranch, dude.
I like living in the woods.
That's where I live.
I want to live by a lake in the woods. I
like to be around nature. I want to wait.
I want to see deer that if shit goes bad
I can shoot those bitches and eat them
that exist. Why don't you go out
to palm springs or desert man?
You know what's out there? Meth and
gay people. What about arrowhead?
What about arrowhead? No, that's good.
That's a move. That's a possibility.
A lot of you love to arrowhead places
and you can get here quick to two hours.
Yeah,
I might look at like getting maybe like
a vacation now someday in their hand.
That would be the shit. And
you just, I want to just like
living in the woods, man.
I loved,
I loved living in Boulder.
I loved the idea that I would see like
fucking deer every day driving home that
there was eagles flying overhead.
The tiers that you see everyday is going
to jump in front of your car and you're
going to fuck deers and yeah,
but you know,
just get a big ass bumper and you're good.
What about you didn't want to drive
my car? Yeah, that's the problem.
The missus Rogan's not so fucking
good at driving and snow. Yeah. Well,
why even early somewhere where
there's snow. That's why he said go.
He go on the road and you should a
stranger out there on this cabin.
That was part of the issue.
And then our dog got eaten by a mountain
lion that the real thing that sent us
home though was that we were 8,500 feet
above sea level and uh, she got pregnant.
And when you're that high above sea level,
if your bodies,
even if you are living
there your whole life,
the kids still going to have
to go on oxygen number kids,
just scary number kids.
He's stopping off at two and my loads are
still fucking devastatingly good. Hmm,
I'm ready. She got another one
in that testing is hard man.
Just taking care of two little babies
at the same time. You know, one,
two and a half and one nine months old
or seven months old. It's tricky. Cute.
It's the greatest thing in the world.
People don't.
I always tell people that
kids and mushrooms are very
similar and then if you've
never experienced it,
if you never had your own kid and if
you've never really done mushrooms,
shut the fuck up. You really don't know.
I used to talk about kids, you know,
I didn't understand what it
was until you have a kid.
And the other thing that you understand
is that there stopped doing that.
Whatever you doing.
Anything cool that,
that the other thing that you realize
when you have a kid is that you change and
you hit some weird new next level of
evolution where there's so much more at
stake now and there's some you, you,
you become a more serious person.
It's really weird. I feel like a real
man to, I feel like man. Exactly.
I'm still very silly and I
obviously make a living. Sure,
sure, sure, sure. You know,
and I still smoke a lot of weed,
which is also a weird thing with a lot
of people that's like, they think some,
for some reason another,
you're not supposed to smoke weed.
You know that like smoking
weed when you're a father,
like said some sort of a weird
example or that it's a bad thing, but,
but you know, I'll go, well, how come I
can go to a restaurant and order a beer?
And nobody even blinks, you know? That's
fine. Nobody says a word about that.
I go and get some wine, you know, with
dinner and nobody me, nobody looks at me.
You know, they asked me if I
want it, you know, if I said no,
but you guys got a place where I could
hit this joint, they'd be like, Whoa,
what the fuck you children are here,
by the way, if you bake though,
if you get too drunk, I mean, not
even just get wasted. Of course,
some guys just fucking crushing
it and enabled to operate.
Like if I had too high.
Yeah, I can't function.
And also I'm really bad with booze to
two drinks. I'm fucking tipsy. I'm drunk.
Yeah. Well that's good to
know. You're a lightweight.
You're a, you're a cheap date.
No, no, I am. Yeah.
No, I definitely don't.
I don't think you should be
drunk or high around your kids.
That's not what I'm saying,
but I'm saying like I'm not going to
change like who I am. You know the guy.
I don't have to like become this fucking
straight edge person just because all
of a sudden I have children.
If I thought there was something
wrong with smoking pot,
I would have stopped doing it because
I think it's bad for you if like it was
detrimental to my health or to
my mental wellbeing or something.
If I thought it was something like
an issue that I needed to deal with,
I would deal with it as an issue,
but I don't think there's an issue.
I think it's beneficial.
I think it helps my personality.
It helps me enjoy life.
It helps me write like crazy.
It is like steroids for writing. When
I get high and I write, I am just,
I just strap in and ride
this wave that I connect to.
I get high and I go into
the isolation tank and I,
I rethink my whole life and it becomes,
I come up with new strategies and new
ways of behaving and I and I have a new
appreciation for everything in a new
respect and love for my friends and my
family.
I want to,
I'll end up calling people that I haven't
talked to in months just getting out
of the tank and go like, dude,
I just want to tell you man.
I mean we don't hang out, but I'd love
you man. We're Sharon's in, you know,
I get these crazy conversations like I
just got to make sure I say all these
things that I need to say like it, it re
reinvigorates me, but also being a dad,
I hope that, I mean that was
two. Yeah, that definitely does.
The combination of the two things.
People don't realize that that's there
is that you do feel like taking a step
back and not taking things so seriously.
Even though I still get fired up,
I keep everything in perspective
very well too. I mean,
I'm not making too many fucking
stupid decisions over here. Yeah.
You get more in tuned with love,
you know, and that fucking very
gay gay.
But it is what it is man.
It's like you get more in tune
with love and that's honestly,
that's what weed is all about. To weed
is about getting you in tune with love,
getting you into with happiness.
We eat is a happy drug.
It's about friendships and,
and hugs and having a good time and
laughing and giggling together. You know,
it's not, it's on a bad
drug. It says and theologian.
And that's what people have to understand.
Everything is lumped together in this
one big stupid group called drugs and
included our caffeine and alcohol and
then dangerous shit like heroin and
fucking, you know, and, and
meth and all those are drugs.
But there's also drugs
that literally trained,
changed the way your fucking
mind works and in a good way.
And they're here to make you like
more humble, make you feel better.
And the reason why people have bad trips,
cause there's a lot of shit about
your life. It's Douchey, man.
You need to clean that shit up.
You know why you paranoid,
why you're freaking out. Well you
should be freaking out. That's why
we do a lot of drugs in college too.
When you're younger and you don't
have as much responsibility,
but I mean more and more responsibility
you have. And then when you do drugs,
he started thinking about all that shit.
That's why people tend to freak out.
Sure.
But if you're just more carefree person
in the first place and the college is a
perfect example because you really don't
have too many responsibilities and go
home by yourself and the first time and
not have anybody scrutinize you once you
get there. And so it's an opportunity. No,
no real bills to fucking pay. I mean,
if somebody is taking care of the,
so less responsibility and you can
just fucking let go completely and,
but more and more shit that you've got
going on like a daughter and we talked
about the porn, they went to
die. Like you just start to put,
you have more shit built up.
The thing about porn is,
you know,
I don't want to say why anybody
gets into porn cause I don't know.
I'm not a girl when I grow old,
it's getting fucked on camera.
I don't understand that.
You may be,
you really are a healthy person and
it's just fun for you. That's possible.
Dr Drew says, no. Um, but
like, then again, I said I'm
not, I'm not, I'm not a woman.
I'm not a doctor.
I don't really understand it.
But I think the ones that
I've come in contact with,
almost all of them had some fucked
up childhood, almost all of them.
I think it's pretty much mandatory. Yeah.
There's no other way to do it. Right,
right.
It's like the reason why you got into
it in the first place is not a healthy
reason.
So it's just this massive evidence.
And even if you're the coolest
person to hang out with ever,
like a lot of them are, you know, a lot
of them really fun to hang out with your,
there's still you're this way
because somebody was shitty to you.
That's what they were talking
about. Think about that. Yeah.
They were talking about that on that
green room show with Paul preventative
before the one you were on and they were
talking about how everybody's, you know,
Al Comics Dads, you know,
or some shit like that. Like
yeah, there is some comics,
some
dads Shit, dad shit. Yeah. Well you don't,
you don't ever become a comic or
anything like that, a singer or any, any,
anything where you're,
you're,
you're asking for this
exorbitant amount of attention.
Like this really unbalanced
amount of attention to say,
I want to be a comedian is to say I want
to be the one with a light shining on
me while everyone else is in the dark
with my voice amplified and I want to be
above them and understanding
above their head.
Think of it like that at all. Yeah.
That's what it is. That's what it is.
That's what we did is you want
to be above the crowd. You know,
nobody wants to do a show where everyone
is in the balcony staring down on you
and your,
your one level below them.
You would feel disconnected if you
didn't have that floor filled in,
you would feel disconnected.
It's the whole thing is a,
is a really ridiculous request.
And so to want to do that for a living,
you have to have some giant deficits.
You're trying to make up for some
fucking crazy hole in your childhood.
Yeah. But none of us really think, I
don't think I have it that bad. You know,
it's a, I mean, it was pretty,
you don't have to have it that bad now.
And I think one of the reasons
why is because your self healed.
When you have a family of your own and
you have your own children and all of a
sudden that shit goes away and you
don't need your daddy anymore. Man.
I don't need my dad get hit in
the head by a fucking media,
not my Stepdad who raised me, my
real dad. I don't even know. Um,
I wouldn't give a fuck. Like I don't
need a dad, you know, I'm a mom,
a dad and myself. Thanks. Thanks.
Take care. I got it. Oh, sorry. Sorry.
You got hit in the head by a media, you
know what I mean? But when I was seven,
it was devastating when I
was seven like that guy,
like the fact that my dad wasn't in my
life anymore, it was just like, whoa.
It was just crushing and
so that whatever's sets you
off when you're seven or
whatever it is, what age it is
that you have this, this dad issue.
That's what gives you this incredible
energy and desire to pursue this,
this standup comedy thing.
The key is somewhere along the line you
have to shift your motivation and your
motivation has to go from,
I want all this attention to,
I want to produce all this
art and make people happy.
shit that people love.
I want people to come see how magical
and concert and I'm gonna give them a
fucking rocking show where they get all
excited and can't wait to see me again.
I think about what my,
one of my kids,
I can't help but think about this.
I think about my kids looking at my
standup when they're 18 years old and
looking back and seeing what
I did. But you still smoking
cigarettes? No, I'm done.
You're done? Yeah, the
completely, I quit almost,
I feel like a year ago. Right
around now. Let me tell you,
how many times a day do you
think about it? I don't know.
This mother Fucker,
he quits and his cat hurts her foot.
The cat hurt her foot. So he was at
her? Yeah. Yeah. Cat hurt her foot.
She jumped off the fridgerator and hurt
her foot. So he got so stressed out.
He started smoking cigarettes again.
Yeah. I mean, it's always
something for me. I mean,
it means if it's a relationship problem
or if it's for my cat and get hurt
problem. It's all, it's all
excuses. I mean, cigarettes, I even,
I know you say that you're over and stuff
like that, but most people, when they,
even if it's been a year, I still
thought about it at least once a week.
The reason I saw, I actually saw a
commercial that had made me quit. Wow.
One of those nonsmoking
commercials and it was great. One,
it said you was there for you then you
know you did it after you smoked in the
morning, you smoked at night,
you smoked after lunch,
you smoked when your daughter was born,
you smoke to here,
you smoke there cause you did it,
you tried and you're done like that and
just put it to you. You gave it a shot.
Like I smoked, I really did
smoke and I'm just done with it.
I think if I have kids, that's, that's,
that's gonna be a real big pushy thing.
But when you're hanging
out at a comedy club,
drinking and every
single person's smoking,
it is almost impossible to fucking quit
smoking unless you have something like a
kid at home that you're like, okay,
I'm doing anything. But this is,
especially when you get a couple of
drinks and you're like far, yeah,
but everybody else is smoking
and you're sitting around.
It's also an easy way to step away from
a situation. Like if I'm at a party,
one of the best things about
smoking for me, he say,
you were in a party and
I got to walk outside.
Just sort of collect my thoughts
and be by myself for fucking,
and it may be he's out
there and there's cool,
not cool smoker guy tag or what's up,
what's,
how do you see the chicken
there or whatever it is.
And so you have a tiny meeting
away from the Vulcan event.
I used to see that back in Boston when
they had to do it and it was fucking zero
degrees or degrees.
And these poor junkies,
we're standing outside these fucking
queer laws, smoke in the circuit.
We've fucking game smoke inside anymore.
What's next? You just go into each,
the ability to step away from shit. I
really did miss. That's what all meetings.
Little tiny meaning. Tiny
meetings. So that's funny.
So you're in a little tiny club.
That's kind of interesting when you're
looking at a club where you meet with the
regular people at the work of time.
So you see Teebo who I'm sure you've had
cigarettes with cigarettes with Jason
Tebow. Oh yeah, all
the time. All the time.
One of my favorite cigarette smoker guys.
Exactly.
So he has his regular cigarette guys that
he sees and he knows vcs court McCowen
he can get a cigarette off him.
He knows if he sees this guy ran as
easy used to smile. Can you just quit?
So if you see Steve Reynolds easy, you
can smoke. You know he's got cigarettes.
Isn't that a part of it too?
That you support each other?
Like you give each other,
you want to bomb a cigarette,
you always give the guy a cigarette.
Cause you know that if you see him
and you don't have a cigarette,
he's got a scissor and integrating lot
of bartering and I you see you maybe
we'll do that at bars too, that don't even
know people. You've got a spare. Yeah.
I ask you for a fucking free cigarette.
Like that's like saying can I have
a dollar? You know what I was,
I was at take two guy. I cause I knew
he'd need one for later on for later.
Yeah, there you go. I didn't do that.
A lot of that to Daryl last night.
Do you know what you like a guy a lot.
You see, you see a Tebow I to here,
you know what, diva have another fucking
bust out three, you know, and go yeah, no,
just put one behind the year. Did you, uh,
did you ever go the natural cigarettes
route where you try to get them like
Derek Parliament light hardpack and I
smoked a marvel lightheart back and that
was it. And what happened? Brian? Those
natural, that's not the way to go. Uh,
supposedly are better for you because
they have only tobacco in it and no
pesticides and none of the whatever,
102 chemicals,
but I still drag of a twig.
Yeah.
It's so hard and rough that I actually
felt like more shit the next day.
Waking up on that shit takes 15 minutes
to swung on a regular cigarettes.
You about seven minutes, not even seven
and a half of it is just explosive.
Chemicals are sucking in. Yeah. You know,
there's 599 FDA approved
chemical additives that are
in cigarettes and Joe was
always on me. Not to smoke or you have
children. I know, I know you were on it.
And then also when I did,
before I had children,
you hear that sound lazy before you
had children of okay, I'm not doing,
that's the volcano.
It's come alive for go to request
request is to fuck you up. We're talking
about smoking and there's a, you know,
a lot of people say, well
marijuana, you know, you're smoking,
that Shit's bad for you.
That's not good.
Well there's a thing called the
vaporizer ladies and gentlemen.
And what it is is it looks like a
Ufo and it's keeping pop. Oh yeah.
It looks like it's making Jiffy pop.
But what's really doing is taking my
ground up plant material and vaporizing it
so that there's no smoke.
But instead it's a mist
and it's a t h c missed.
And what it does is it fills this
bag up with, is THC missed? Oh,
it's filling up now. It's looking
good. How long have you had that? Uh,
I've had it for a while, man. I think
I got it a few years ago. And, um,
cause your bag leaks a little bit.
We know where you're going to do.
That's a good gift idea.
If you want to get you a new bag.
[inaudible] I need a new bag.
Does it turn off by itself? No,
you just wait. Is it going to pop
and look at it now? Not Ready.
It's not ready yet. So it
can good though. Scary. Yeah.
This is don't be a bit like walking
around with balloons and not hitting the
ceiling. It's just vapor bro. It's
THC vapor and the thing is it,
it looks like nothing. Like when you
breathing in and breathing out yelling,
sometimes you don't even think he got
anything you want with the clear bag with
all bags are pretty much clear as you can
see. Two misdemeanor. Exactly. Well they,
this is just the same bag
that I've had for years.
I'm probably supposed to be replacing
them. That's why ladies, I mean, yeah,
it is a good gift idea. If you're
thinking about gifting. Yeah.
This volcanoes are fucking expensive.
Yeah. I think they're like $600 or
something like that. Is it real? Yeah.
I was thinking about getting one and
then I was like, so then this is the,
this is what you get out of it.
This a strange thing.
And inside the strange thing is,
I don't know,
going crazy
that she sticks around for awhile. You can
use that later. Yeah, that's it. Bam Son.
Pure THC. You don't have to
worry about smoke in for,
to worry about shit being bad for you.
How magical do you still go on your
children? Are you still going on the road?
Yeah. Yeah. Cause you can go, you go
with Ari. Ari comes all the time. Joey,
when you can count on him,
you'd never know what Joe Diaz cause
he might pull the Joe ideas and just no
show. What's that? I'm just no show. Um,
I actually started taking two people
on the road with me for the very reason
that I never knew of Joey
Diaz is gonna show up.
So Joey Diaz is the reason was that,
did you hear that?
Did you hear a feedback? No.
Do you hear us? Yeah. Hmm.
Interesting. You wrestling, maybe you
just kicks on when you sat down. Maybe.
Anyway. Um, I used to work,
take Joey d is on the road all the time
until we worked in rascals over rascals
in New Jersey.
And Joey just didn't show up.
It just never flew to New Jersey
and he didn't answer his phone.
He had a pager back then. It was
impossible to get in touch with them.
And then finally we got in touch
with them the next day and he's like,
I'm coming tonight. Don't
worry about it. I'll be
there. Don't worry about them that
don't worry, I'm, I missed my flight.
I fucked up.
I get stuck in Vegas,
so it's maybe an hour before the show and,
uh,
we finally get a hold of Joey Diaz
and he's still back in la or Vegas.
I forget where he was like,
I ain't gonna lie to you until I was done.
I never got on the plane and just,
he just, he just, whatever reason,
I just decided to go off and do his
own Joey Diaz world. That's great.
And he's done that so many times.
He did that in Phoenix. He just,
he just fucking vanishes. Telling you one
story of him at the Maryland Martinez.
Maybe there's somebody who
talked about that, but I mean,
it was just really one of the
best things I've ever witnessed.
And just telling somebody off at a
memorial, those fucking memorials.
They bumped me out, man. Yeah, I went
to Mitch. Yeah, Mitch was, I mean,
I don't go to anybody's,
I don't like funerals either.
I don't like the idea behind if I want
to celebrate somebody who wanted to
celebrate it on my own and think
about their life and you know, my, my,
my personal relationship with
them. And if, I mean, if I,
I mean it's cool with you if you want
to meet up with everybody and talk about
how great the guy was and celebrate
them. I get it. I totally understand it.
But to me it's just like, man, it's such
a personal thing. And when someone dies,
I don't, wouldn't have public
official died in Tucson. I mean, uh,
he saw all the people and Obama
spoke. Yeah. That was a lot of people.
How many people were at that event?
You know a shit load of people in a
university of Arizona probably in the
basketball stadium, easily about 8,000
people. It's weird. Right? And um,
well you know when that case though,
it's like those people need healing.
You know, those people are
obviously totally, yeah.
What's something that happened?
Like that little girl got shot like that,
that thing is so devastating.
And apparently the cops had
been called to this guy's house.
The guy who did that shooting in Arizona
where they pulled him over luckily
there. Jesus could they really, they pull
away. They got arrested for uh, yeah,
he had a some sort of violation.
He got pulled over. Oh my God.
And they didn't check that he's got guns,
guns in the bag. Jesus fucking Christ.
Anyone goes to load up.
Hey,
you went to Walmart and burnish
it a little bullets too.
I think you've gotta
be some check company.
Let's take a picture and sending, I'm sure
all of that's being done. I don't even,
I feel I feel bad for the cop that
pulled them over. Who has to think that,
you know, have you done a little
bit more of an investigation?
I just looked into this. He probably had
some inkling, but he's probably, you know,
whatever. Leave the guy alone and
other people talking about that at HP.
We'll talking about the fact that
he was stopped and I never heard it.
I didn't hear until you just
brought it up. That's crazy though.
The photos of that kid,
the mugshot photos just as
bananas as anybody could look.
I can't look into grazier.
Yeah, that's definitely,
again, with the pay phone shit,
it's like I would, yeah,
inspect them. Yeah.
Well then the other thought is that,
you know,
if you look at the whole machine of life,
if you look at all these different
things in life, the good and the bad,
there's a lot of people that believe,
and this is, you know, this is sort of a,
a staple in eastern religion said almost.
You sort of have to have negative in your
life to recognize the positive and the
Yin and Yang.
The reason why it exists is because that's
the only way anything ever gets done.
And like even events like nine 11
like they're terrible events,
but in some ways they bring people
together like New York after nine 11 after
that was like the friendliest fucking
place in the world. For the longest time,
senators holding hands on town. It
was just different, man. People were,
everyone was devastated. People were
shell shocked. They were horrified,
but there was this weird feeling,
an air of a,
a group of people that are
all cool mother fucker.
I'm weak now.
I feel better about mine text earlier,
somebody just to call me once. I swear
to God, I unplugged that fucking thing.
Anyway,
there was a sense of community there
that didn't exist the ways the right back
back reductionist, but for the longest
time, man, everyone was so fucking cool.
They're so positive. We went
there. We filmed a fear factor.
I think it was right after September
11 there wasn't far afterward.
It's like maybe a year or two
after and everybody was in.
It was back once when firemen
were fucking heroes and farming,
which just getting pussy
thrown at them everywhere.
Women wanting to go fuck firemen. They
wanted to go fuck heroes. You know, it's,
it's weird how that changed
but for that long time,
so it's like almost like a negative thing.
Like can oftentimes inspire like this
positive reaction the opposite way.
And there's a lot of people that think
that all these things are in place and
all these fucked up people are in place
and fucked up situations to get us to
appreciate the situations that aren't,
you know, to get us to really, you know,
to really try to be better in and help
us evolve so that we can get past these
unfortunate but
unavoidable situations where, where are
these incentives? We need homeless people,
homeless people. I mean,
you know, you'd have to,
do you need sort of
somebody on the bottom?
This will not, we'll see. I don't
know if that's true. I don't,
I don't necessarily agree with that.
But it's also like, you know, to,
to watch something really terrible like
that sort of like motivates you to not
let that happen to you.
People can accept a lot of shit.
A lot of things can happen to you and
you just sort of accept your situation,
then it gets worse. You started
except that. Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
Hoarders a perfect example.
Yeah. And you know,
because of that you just sort of just
all of a sudden you find yourself,
you know,
so many levels of accepting this bullshit
in a place where you never would have
just accepted it straight
up right off the bat.
You just kind of let it happen like that.
Next thing I know you're homeless. Yeah.
Pills and pills.
Credit gets out of control and all of
this and you're evicted and you just
fucking doing handle your shit.
Yeah.
You do look at that to get motivated
because this is the bottom.
Then I know I've seen the bottom and I
don't want to be near the fucking bottle,
so that's what it is.
I do not want that. I,
when I watch a hoarder's, me and my wife
actually watched one the other night,
and this show is difficult to watch
because it was you. You're right.
That they do gradually,
except that they have to shit on top of
fucking caprice on boxes or something in
their way and shit,
and it just stacks up around him and
they're just shifting and then we just
started living in one room.
They say that all the time.
Also, I think that we
moved to this room's, yeah,
we all recognize that our own brains
are just vulnerable as these people's
brains.
Oh sure. We just did. A lot
of people choose to fight a
little bit of Ra, you know?
I can just keep the shit clean and
it takes work. Everything takes work.
There's life's maintenance
needs to be fucking done.
You can't let shit get out of control.
But we've all,
we've all gone into this weird spiral.
I think anybody that I've ever met,
especially anybody that's ever
been in a tumultuous relationship,
you go into this weird spiral where
you don't feel like you have that much
control over your thoughts and actions.
You know when,
when guys get in like a devastating
relationship, you get your heartbroken.
You can't sleep. You can't think.
And especially when that happens,
young in your life, he, you don't,
you don't really have it mastered yet.
You don't know really
understand who the fuck you are.
You know that shit can send you on
some kind of crazy spiral, you know?
And if you go through all that and you've
got some sort of a history of mental
illness in your family and you know,
next thing you know done,
you're cracked.
Yeah.
I mean you don't want ever except
that it could happen to you,
but you look at someone
who's really devastated by,
by any sort of a fucking obsession
like that. Gambling obsessions. Yes.
No gambling people, dude. My
in laws live in dirty Vegas.
So you out near the airport pays out and
where there's all of those poker places
and the pawn shop poker place just
shut down fast food, fast food,
pawn shop, poker, poker,
poker and you go into one of those places
like a terribles casino and shit like
that.
And there's those car washes and you
go into like a PJ's poker place and you
just see these just guys.
You think like an Indian casino is bad.
There's regular casino, really nice. Then
there's a lower level downtown casinos.
Then there's like an Indian casino,
the shout in the middle of
fucking nowhere and like,
why would you go there and
they say it's like, oh,
it's a Morongo casino is we're real
nightlife is and you go in and it's just
like, like you know, weird grouping of
people in Morocco. They cool right here.
There's a lot of money in
Morocco. Come to Morocco. They,
there's so many hot chicks and I love
going to Marengo, man. Thank you. I can,
they have these commercials that come on.
It's like the nightclubs and shit like
that and it ends up being old Chinese
ladies in like mystical wolf tee shirts.
Fucking walking around with those walkers
with the tennis balls on the bottom of
the feet. It's disgusting.
It's depressing shit.
Is that gambling addiction as a
strange one man. Anybody whose spouse,
there's homeless people in my
neighborhood and bought a car.
What I watched and be homeless.
I knew they were going around
collecting cans and is one day,
you know how you got your eye on
the same homeless people at a time?
You've seen him around for a
regular basis? These two I can.
It's like a couple just from
people looking weird white
lady in this tall black
guy or is a top hat sometimes they
started driving around in a green minivan.
Fucked up green minivan,
but they got there and like saved up
enough cans like Marlboro miles to buy
their sleeping in his van though.
I'm sure they're cheating
in my neighborhood because
they have a place where you
can turn recyclables into money and
then every night I see them just fucking
going through all my,
everyone's recycle bins and just taking
out all the shit from the recycle bins
and then selling it down the street.
Yeah. Cheating, cheating. No,
that's like the marvel doesn't does a
Starwood points for homeless people.
I think that makes sense because one
way or one way you're not gonna make any
money. If you just put your
recyclables on the street,
you're not going to make any money.
And for them it's like free money.
I don't think it's cheating at
all out of my fucking trash.
I don't want you in my tracks.
He was telling me they were,
as long as they do a good job,
that downtown,
they don't make them like your identity
and you're going to downtown la like
shopping mall or something like that.
And they saw,
or an office complex and he saw water
fountains where people throw money in the
fountain and they were just
standing there going, oh my God,
what a beautiful fountain.
And then this Latino family came in,
just rolled up all those leaves and
went in and they found and just started
taking all the money out and
GCA because it's free money.
We're throwing money in water. Yeah.
What do you say to that? How do you stop?
I have zero money and there's
money just right there.
It's like a foot of water and it's like,
it's weird.
Like is it illegal to take the money?
Yeah. Yeah. Is it? I think so. It's all,
it shouldn't be.
No.
I think a lot of these fountains usually
have a charity booked around behind it.
Like the mall gives it to
a charity or something.
So really once it's that your con,
it's considered giving to
a charity then it stealing,
but it didn't know charity sign take
their money. You need the money.
They started doing it to a charity just
because people were doing it. Right? Yeah.
It's like the Mexican soccer said,
it's ridiculous that that's how fucking
rich this country as people can throw
money in a fountain.
The found enough money for food.
Like there's enough money
in that fountain for you.
Definitely to get something to eat.
You know,
it's always quarters
and nickels and dimes,
a comic that a cone and rider
that actually does that as a bit,
I'm sorry I'm forgetting his name,
but he goes,
imagine coming from another country
like where they have no water,
where you have to go to a,
well,
I don't really just out in the middle
of nowhere and there's a one water hole
and there's a fucking tiger there.
And then you come to this country and
you've gone to like a place like, um,
to city center with citywalk
citywalk universal city walk, right?
And there's fucking water shooting up
out of the ground and kids are fucking
frolicking.
And then we're taking our extra money
and throwing it in the voc and fountain,
just like, here's our money in our
water. It's crazy, right? Released crazy.
It really is. Well, we don't realize how
rich this country is until you watch,
like, and even talk to some
of the people that are in,
in certain European countries where
there's no resources and nothing to do.
Like there's a, there's a real issue
in Italy right now with young people,
like where there's no fucking jobs,
there's really nothing they can do there.
You know, people are graduating
and there's like, there's nothing,
there's nothing out there. Mom's already
manning the cafe or whatever it is,
you know, there's no, yeah, you
have to go on and find an actual,
have to leave the country. You have
to get on a fucking boat or something,
you know, you've got to go find your
shit somewhere else. You're stuck. Yeah.
And I think a lot of the smarter people
said there's free land over in that
other place. And a people were nuts,
man, let's go. The idea behind that,
we've talked about it before,
but how crazy you have to be to be
living in Europe and say, you know what,
fuck this.
We're going to get you know,
boat and we're going to go across the
ocean. It's going to take a long time.
A lot of us are going to die.
A lot of us are gonna die and we're
going to get some new diseases
when we get there. But good dying
is better than no, that shit.
They weighed that out. They
must have, there must have been,
or they're just running from the law.
We're a nation built by criminals
running from European law.
I wonder how many people were supposed
to be one thing when they were in Europe.
They came over here at Bob Smith. That's
my name. You know, just new identity,
new identity, new.
Everything's clean. Slate.
That's how to wipe out a complete
record of yourself, right? Don Draper,
the whole thing. Yeah. A lot
of them. Right? You can't
do that shit anymore folks.
That's going out of the way
soon. Soon you're going to
be, you're going to be you.
[inaudible] where are you at this week?
And now you gotta be chill.
I am actually doing the John Oliver
TV comedy Central Show in New York on
Saturday night. Cool. And then, um,
I'm going to be an Austin, Texas or the
Cap City comedy club. My favorite club.
And it would be at the Ontario Improv.
I've got those three coming out.
So it goes, can I come with you to
Austin, John Oliver, some bitches,
chicks in Austin. How confident
are you still? Some bitches.
Brian's like,
oh I have to do is go to Austin and I'll
just start a fucking heroin and shit.
I love them.
So I got to do is just go there like
rescuing them one in fast and are from to
Austin as the shit. Why
would it be rescuing? Yeah,
you're not dragging them because they
don't want to get world and they don't
want to get beat up anymore.
They're going to get in Twitter
fights with your ex-girlfriends,
Twitter war. How many people would
have in public like spats on Twitter?
It's so are they have relationships
are broken up on Twitter.
That's literally arguing with cheese.
That's another thing I miss.
I miss texting in my relationship
so I don't even know what it's like.
Where are you at when we,
you and I have no idea what that's about.
There's a few people that I follow just
because I know that they're in a famous
couple and then they'll get in spats
and when they get in spats like they'll
like leave like little vague shit.
There comes a point when you know that
you cannot count on anyone who's the,
who are the person I can't tell you
about mine. I tell you when we're off,
we're off air. But you know, I follow
them just because I want to hear them.
And then once that point has
been reached, it's over. Yeah.
So there's an echo in here.
I keep on hearing phones ring.
I think I'm just going more friends.
Right Buddy? That's my medicine.
It's your medicine folks
is fucking shows over.
It should've been over a while ago now.
We've got to get new seats when we do
these two and two hours and 45 minutes
shows, I forgot. How was
that phase? You're happy.
So you need to work on your core now
because these are the most uncomfortable.
I feel pretty good. I'm right. He's right.
Rather. Um, I, I, when I got to, yeah,
there's no back support. I'm going to get
us office chairs. That's the next one.
Really Nice one.
That way we can move around more to,
we're not married to this one spot and
we can face each other better. Yeah.
Listen folks,
this shit is ever evolving.
I'm working on some sort of a
TV and look at the youth stream.
Really does look like a professional
environment though with the microphone in
your face and it looks like, you know we,
I mean it is a very professional setup,
but I'm saying fucking raise this
shit. Yeah, we'll figure it out.
When we first started doing it,
man,
we just had a laptop and we had like
snow in the background and shit and
does a terrible ones.
If you can download a podcast,
those first 10 of them can't believe
anybody was still listening. Yeah.
We just would get baked and just start
rambling and nobody was paying attention,
so we didn't think it was a big deal.
But now there's like hundreds of thousands
of downloads and wanting to deliver a
quality. I feel like I
have to. Yeah. You know,
I have to make the
conversations interesting.
I have to bring on people like Al
Madrigal. I have fun town. Great.
Always barely.
You're an awesome dude.
I'm glad we've been friends
for all these years.
I'm glad I knew you back in
your salad days right now.
So I have a goal has not changed. I just
put down, what is it? What's it called?
It's called Cholos on a moped. Cholos
on a moped. Itunes. Franksville no,
it's just on my website. Okay.
It's, did they have to download?
They download it or they know they have
to download it and I just put it in sort
of a pay whatever you want it bottoms out
of seven 99 cause I think that's like,
that's nothing, but if people want to
pay 10 bucks or more, it's kind of cool.
I like that. You know, I've, I've
seen people do that with paypal links.
They say if you want to donate, you know,
here's where this is something to that.
I Dunno, I just, I'd rather people have
it than I make a certain dollar amount.
When before we go, let me, I
want to ask you about this.
How do you feel about like a online
piracy? What do, what is your,
what are your thoughts on that?
On I did actually like ripping a movie
and then distribute anything. Your stuff,
let's just go specifically
with your stuff. Oh,
if somebody puts a sign stuff out
online, wire takes my shit. I see.
I'm at a stage in my career where I
would like people to have the stuff more
than I like to bake. Well,
I'll write new shit, right?
I'm going to continue
to prove to producing,
I mean I'm just starting
to write now with this,
like a couple of bits that I have of
that the laugh factory put up on Youtube,
like the shut shit that I
really bucking enjoy doing.
So I just want to keep producing
shit like that in a high quality.
But at some point where there's
real big money to be made,
I'm sure I'll fucking want to sell
this stuff legitimately. Right.
I know what you're saying, but for the
most part I just want to get it out.
I'd give it to somebody. If somebody's
kid comes up to me after my shows,
I always say, pay what
you want. I don't care.
As long as you don't throw the fucking
dude, you look a hippie. Socialists.
I mean for the most, I see what you can
afford. The cheapest people give you a,
I'll take five bucks because
they cost three to make. Wow.
And so, and then if somebody put for the
most part, people give you $20 what is,
that's kind of cool.
What is the most someone's ever given you?
I had people in Tempe at the Tempe Improv
jumping up and down and it was one of
the last cds, but $40 $60 I think
for was like they were running out.
Oh, what are you doing Brian? What
does that museums are facing? Yeah,
sounds like a Chinese
restaurant, Bro. Chem trails,
but it sounds like the waiting area
for a Chinese restaurant. Yeah. Yeah.
You can make it louder a little bit.
There you go.
February 4th Mandalay Bay theater.
I am there with Ari Shaffir
and Joey Coco Diaz. Hopefully.
I know Ari will show up with Joey Twitter,
that full target to them.
I don't know. It's good flavor. Um, but
uh, w tickets are selling very fast.
It's going to be a fucking crazy show.
It's a big place.
It's like a, it's like 2000 seats,
something like that. 1800 seats.
It's a new theater in Mandalay bay and
that'll be the night before, uh, the UFC.
There's a link on Joe rogan.net.
You can get it there.
There's the link on my Facebook,
which is Joe Rogan, d, O t e n,
e t and a Al magical. You can reach
him at owl magical at Twitter,
a l m a D R I g a l and the
house pitches and amount.com.
I'll magical.com. Dude, thank you
very much. Thank you for everything.
Thank you for being a cool dude.
Thank you for being a great standup
comedian and thank you for being the same
guy that I met. We got high and watched
Oprah exactly the same 11 years ago.
It's pretty much not too much has
changed. Well, you're, you know, you're,
you're more of a dad and a man
now and all that good stuff. Sure.
But at the same doing same
guy. Yeah. I'm the same dude.
That doesn't always happen
that way. I know. And then,
and then you were telling me about Ray
Romano. That's exactly the same exact guy.
He's always been a great,
that's good to hear. Yeah, you
can keep it together. Sure.
You're going to keep it together.
I predict there's no used to be
all effected your the same thing.
It's like yes you could. You have
the right to be some like, you know,
affected fucking guy with people around
you and it's a mess that's fucks you up
more than the, the, the
ego boost is a fake one.
If you're a smart person that you don't
accept it and so you don't get a good
feeling out of it anyway. Cause you know,
it's ridiculous. It's ridiculous. Bitches.
We are in an atomic soup that no one
understands and it's been going back and
forth on and over from the big bang
to the end of creation forever.
And it's an endless cycle.
And we'll see you next week.
And fleshlight tall latch a boy.
Yeah. fleshlight.com go there. And um,
and just buy a bunch of them.
Just jerk off in the him and shoot
your loads all over the house.
There's special, they're good.
They feel better than beating off.
You will have long ball draining orgasms.
I highly recommend,
highly recommend it.
Also a Miami Improv. Ah,
fuck. I don't even know who's
going down with me. I'm 28,
29 and 30 and not Miami.
And probably I keep saying that.
I said that twice West Palm beach and
bigger, nicer. You know why I say it?
Because it's a half an hour from Miami
and I'll never worked in Miami Improv
ever again. So I'm just
terrified cause it's right there.
It's a half an hour away.
Yeah.
It's the only place where I was on stage
in the middle of a show and people were
so dumb. Like I had some joke where I
brought up the word Oscar de la Hoya,
like brought up his name.
And so all of a sudden this
fucking war broke out in the crowd.
We do no fucking mad. She'll
get Shane Mosley, fuck Mosley.
And then they started going back and
forth and yelling out at the top like it's
a cafeteria,
like who's the most bad ass boxer?
And they went on for like 30 seconds.
So these guys were yelling back,
standing up, doing these things
with their hands, yelling at him.
And I just had finally I said, I'm
never coming here again. That's great.
I was there in a woman's hair
caught on fire and she vomited.
Nice when in what order?
That's that first second.
And that lays is end of the show.
So a West Palm Beach Improv 28 29 and
30th you know all that Twitter details and
I have a lot
of Twitter followers as a result.
Do you had me red band,
your [inaudible].
He's talking to all the people out there
in the world and each one I need to get
past Taylor fucking Vicks. Sure. Brian
can say that. We say it three times,
she'll show up. Oh No, give
us all one candy man. Oh No,
you did. And on that note
folks, we'll see you next week.
Are you should fear will be joining us
on Tuesday and we'll see if we can get a
Brian Posehn or someone on a on Thursday
and that's it. Halacha boy. See you.
Love you bitches.
Oh,
good. It's so me. [inaudible]
oh, marvelous. No dyes.
Why you hi my bag now.
My mind keeps me up at night.
What you back to say?
Bye Bye Debbie.