Yee ha,
ladies and gentlemen,
he fucking Ha.
That's what I have to say to everyone in
America,
but dude,
when you get to call yourself a name
like action,
like how dare you.
First of all,
how dare you be so bold that that's your
name.
Action.
That's my name,
man.
That's who I am.
Who I was born.
How did you get this name?
Man?
Listen,
I'm just known to be doing things.
I'm just known for things.
It's just too cool,
too cool for a white person.
You know,
dude,
I've been watching your stuff on vice
and uh,
first of all,
what a great idea.
What a great idea to come up with that
Hashtag.
Fuck,
that's delicious.
Thank you man.
Because your,
your instagram picture is.
It is a one big fuck.
That's delicious.
Instagram page rather.
It's awesome.
You wouldn't expect it from a,
from a rapper slash food traveling human
being such as myself.
I would expect exactly that.
Yeah,
yeah,
that's exactly what I expect from you.
All right.
Yeah.
Good.
I think I've got you figured out.
They put the thumb on me already.
It's a good thing though.
I'm a fan.
I like what should do in the well,
do you think that people try to define
you?
Is that what it is?
It's like people look at you and they
try to dismiss you or what is it?
I don't think they tried to dismiss me,
but I feel that people try to define you
of course put you in a box for us,
but I'm not the one that's ever to be
put in a box.
You just,
there hasn't been any person like me
ever and they probably,
you know,
there will be someone like me coming
along but are use the white Kanye.
Definitely.
I'm the,
I'm the slightly 10 Audi.
I know slanty Aka Action Bronson.
So you're,
you're traveling around.
How many of these restaurants are you
visiting?
How many of these shows you doing for
advice?
Uh,
we already did eight episodes of the
first season.
We got picked up for a second.
We're going to be doing 12 episodes for
the second.
Shit.
I'm trying to sign a longterm deal.
Seven years.
One hundred $38 million around there.
A couple of incentives.
Well it's a great idea man,
and in the future as things like what
you're kidding on vice.com or these
youtube pages that people just can,
you can do your own show like that.
Yep.
And it can,
it can get gigantic.
Like again,
it can get almost bigger than I could
ever get on tv because you can download
it and watch it anytime you want.
Well that's the issue I'm having right
now because we've become such a global
show that we're now on vices television
network that is about to start on March
third,
I mean on February 29th called Viceland
and I have some,
some quarrels about it to say the truth
because it's only going to be in North
America and I mean people are going to
get what they want so obviously they're
going to download a touring or whatever
they're going to do,
but it's necessary for it to be on
Youtube as stressed.
I would.
Every video that I ever do it is totally
necessary to be on youtube because
everyone needs access to it.
You could be right here.
You want to show me something.
Boom.
Type of writing,
you could show it to me.
We don't have to go to the TV,
see what time it comes on.
You know?
I know they have on demand,
but still it's the fucking process
easier.
Yeah,
it's.
It's so universal.
It's where everyone goes.
Yeah.
It's like you wake up in the morning and
you go to youtube for some shit.
You listen to some music,
you put a mix on the.
You Watch some highlights for some shit.
Why you have it in your tv now you know
if you have apple tv,
it's just,
it's so easy to use.
It's pretty much making TV obsolete.
Well between that and Netflix and Hulu
and all these different online providers
where you could access.
It's super easy now on your television
and especially if you have one of those
apple tvs,
so easy to get and this is just what's
going to be like a decade from now,
man.
I mean you're got to be able to talk to
your TV and say action Bronson and
they'll just pull up room.
What would you like to know?
You know,
I would like to listen to his best shit.
That's right.
It'll his best shit.
Yeah,
I mean it's going to be,
it's going to be able to,
uh,
easily decipher what you're saying
because right now they're pretty fucking
good if you like,
fucked with Siri at all and ask Siri
questions.
Yup.
They,
I mean it's,
it gets pretty next level.
This guy right here is like the tech
guy,
so I leave it to him and it's like 7,000
apps and this shit and that is fucking
games all day long.
Do you have a flip phone?
I did.
Did you really?
Not.
My first phone was the STARTAC Motorola
Startac my friend Ari Shaffir went back
to the flip phone.
Yeah.
Yup.
He's like,
fuck all you people.
You're losing your mind.
He's like,
know what?
He's right.
He is right.
He's right because I'm a fucking slave.
There's no doubt about that.
I go on,
I'm on twitter,
know when I wake up I just put it on to
see what the hell's going on.
And it's upsetting.
Everybody's a slave to that thing.
That thing's monstrous but awesome.
Right.
It's incredible the amount of data that
you can just get on anything instantly.
Tell me about kettlebells.
Tell me about airplane.
Who invented the first drone?
Just boom and he just started going
through all this Chinese guy probably.
We were talking about this yesterday,
how like a youtube video now recommends
and starts playing the next youtube
video.
Like you just sit there.
It's sorta like Netflix does with like a
series.
He'll just start playing the next one's
like sit down bench.
Where are you going to wait until he
trapped you playing automatically like
playing for you and Youtube does that
all the time.
Now things related,
things that are slightly related you
would discuss.
I mean just from me to make music using
youtube has become a pleasure.
You know,
it's like a new age of digging in the
crates.
You'd have to search pages for rare shit
and see,
make sure no one,
no one else has used it and it's like a
never ending a catalog of musical talent
from all over the globe.
Now from blue,
from the early opera singers shift from.
You can listen to anything from any.
They have,
um,
from the early 19 hundreds of the first
recording somehow.
That's insane.
Know.
Yeah.
It's insane to think that they figured
out how to put sound on a black plastic
disk that made it so awesome and they
figured out how to do that when we were
apes,
you know,
I mean,
people were like in comparison to today,
like the amount of technology they had.
Then it was like the early 18 hundreds
of figured out how to do that.
Right.
Like what,
what year was it?
They invented the phonograph record
player.
Remember they used to have that big
hoop,
you the hook,
the big,
like a tube and you have to look into
fucking churned it and he would sit on
it and the sound would come off the
record through that.
The thing before that,
I was looking up right now in 18,
77,
edison had this thing that the recorded
on tin foil shape.
It looks slow.
So when eight cylinders,
it was a video from like tech tv where
some guy drops one and it's like an old
viral video from the early wow.
Jesus Christ.
He dropped it.
And broke it.
Oh No,
fuck head.
It's unbelievable.
Coronet Solo.
Well,
if that was done today,
I'd want my fucking money back.
I'd be like,
you shitty audio engineer you foot.
What did you keep your phone in your
pocket from there,
but listening to that.
It sounds good when you consider the
time.
It sounds amazing.
So what was the first phonograph?
What year was that invented?
Why don't feel like it was the 18
hundreds?
Am I wrong?
Or is it like way earlier than that?
I think it was at the end of the 18
hundreds.
The end of it,
they used to use look so wild with that
big tube thing that came out of it,
but they haven't really figured out how
to make it sound better than the record
does know what has the difference
because some people say it's bullshit.
Some people say it's just fetishism and
some people who are real audio file
type,
they,
they're all kind of agreed as like a
different kind of sound.
Well it's what everyone explains to me.
And now I understand there's a warmth.
Yeah.
There's a warmth to it every,
you know,
it's easier on the ear then say the
electronic music in the digital should
have today,
so a little bit more harsh.
The oldest stuff was toned better and I
don't know,
it was just the plastic.
The vinyl does something something to
it.
The page like audio freaks all seemed to
agree on that,
right?
For sure.
But there's something about tape
recording directly to two inch tape
using this thing,
this big machine nowadays we just go
right into the computer through
whatever.
I don't know what the fuck,
like m box or so what?
What Jamie,
you're.
You're one of the people that doesn't
think it makes that much of a
difference.
Right now it's just up to what?
At this point it's what you're hearing.
So like people today are trained to hear
things off of [inaudible] funds and
itunes where it lists like mp3s,
that compression.
We're used to hearing it.
So being told that something else sounds
better.
It's like you're trying to tell them
they don't lean on the compression.
Oh,
compression makes everything sound
smooth.
And is it possible that it's a more
familiar sound?
Is that why?
SORTA.
Yeah.
Like they're even mixing things now.
You'll see it's mastered for itunes.
It's mastered to be heard through those
little two ear buds,
not through a giant's sound system at
home.
Have giant speakers with subwoofers.
Absolutely correct.
Interesting.
Interesting personal.
No,
no one ever drives down the street
anymore.
Blessed.
And the music fuck happened to that.
You know,
used to go when you got the car,
he used to have to go and buy the
humongous speakers to put it in the
bitch.
I think people start going deaf,
whatever,
whatever.
If you're driving around with earplugs
on and you're blasting music,
it's kind of a Douche move,
right?
If it's so bad,
it hurts your ears.
You have to put ear plugs in his.
This guy in my neighborhood that just
drives around every Sunday in a piece of
Shit Cadillac with a bow in the front,
playing all types of Frankie Valli at
the loudest,
the loudest volume that could possibly
be and just singing along.
It's.
It's incredible.
It's just ritual every Sunday you really
are right.
Because it used to be like every
stoplight you would hear.
Yup,
Yup.
You'd feel like you're your car vibrate.
Those people that go crazy with the sub
woofers to the point where you feel it
in the air around you.
Fucking mirrors are rattling.
I love it.
Do you love it?
Naw,
I don't stare at it.
Have you ever been in a vehicle with the
ship?
Turns up all the way.
If you sit in the back seat with a
Subwoofer is.
It feels like it's coming through your
chest.
Like get your fucking heart is about to
explode.
What that base.
Especially if you play like dipset of
something like some sort of a,
some sort of Edm.
We,
you know,
like some crazy house music.
You literally go into a trance.
Well you know what else went out dudes
with the crazy,
the crazy wagon rims,
those wagon wheel rims.
Everybody was like,
how many potholes we're going to hit?
Add another rooms.
You can't have a 28 inch rim.
Is this,
these ridiculous ribs and tires are like
a piece of bubble gum.
The run flats,
thin nose.
I can't do it.
Man.
I got some Schmidt's on my car.
What's the Schmidt?
There's some German rooms that you could
fucking tank would roll over them shits
and there'll be all right.
You can literally drive the car without
rubber wheels on it.
Just on the rims.
What?
Yeah.
What kind of real wheels in these day
was Schmidt's?
You could look him up as this Schmidt.
Um,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
Some drive them on the road over there
on the left up.
Yep.
Those,
that's what kind of car do you have?
A BMW wagon five series 95.
That's a nice.
Those,
those,
uh,
those years of like the nicest years.
Yeah,
for sure.
BMW five series.
It doesn't.
Tony have one of those.
Hinchcliffe has one of those.
They say that like,
um,
like they'll five series bmw from like,
there's like two errors.
Like there's the one they have now,
the one they had before and then they
want to have before that.
And that's where you're at.
Yeah.
I'm in the 95.
One is the,
is the one right before they changed the
body.
Yeah.
Those are like classic cars.
Mammon.
There's.
Tony has a five series from there and I
have another friend who was a three
series from there.
Like those cars were something special.
Man.
They just figured out a way to make
them.
They handle so good.
They break so good.
That is the right amount of weight.
They're not too heavy.
Exactly.
You get like a good movement with them
and that metal site.
Yeah.
Look at that thing.
That fucking metal.
Exactly.
That's the [inaudible] from that era and
that car was a piece of genius.
That's the beauty of it too.
There's a fucking crazy video that
someone put out that I could barely
watch.
Man.
It's some asshole in some other country.
I don't know what countries in,
but he's in an m five,
one of those that series and he's
driving to traffic like a fucking
maniac.
Like you watch it.
You just go.
Cheeses.
Yeah.
Holding onto the chair when he burns it
into the oncoming lane.
Cuts in front of people.
I mean he is doing some fucking crazy
shit really fast,
but driving like a wizard,
like going around corners sideways.
He must be a race car driver.
There's no way he's not a race car
driver because,
oh,
this is it.
Jesus Christ.
Jamie,
how dare you this,
this motherfucker is nuts.
Look at this and watch this.
Look at this.
Oh Shit.
He's just drifting.
Yeah,
he's drifting.
Oh,
that's a beauty too.
Going around people and I mean,
look,
I always driving.
Where's this fucking guy?
Speeding while people are walking across
the road and he doesn't give a fuck,
this oncoming doesn't give a fuck.
This guy is fucking crazy shit.
Just killing it.
Look at this.
Where's this?
Austria.
I don't know where it is.
It's something they have those crazy
long European license plates stuff,
but look at them like this motherfucker
drives.
Oh,
what is this?
Jamie's for people.
If they want to watch it.
The BMW m five need to need for Dr. Com.
Last illegal street racing and drift
driver.
Georgie [inaudible].
He just died.
Look at this.
Did he?
Yeah,
he just died.
I think he just did some shit in the
whip.
He died in this car actually.
Come on,
check it out.
Oh my goodness.
All right.
P,
Georgie or Giorgio Tevye.
Z.
Yeah.
Georgia z think he's dead.
He died in the Burgundy.
Bema riced.
He died in the infamous BMW street.
Drifter dies in crash.
Hot outside of Barclay.
Oh No.
Holy Shit.
He was 26 years old.
Yep.
What are not man?
He was leaving a restaurant in Georgia
with a sober driver at the wheel.
The MTI skidded at what appears to be a
high speed into a tree on the right hand
side of the car tabs.
Xie Xie died.
He wasn't.
The driver wasn't driving traffic shit.
That is ironic tale.
It's not like Atlanta last Morrissette
Ironic,
ironic.
Not Ironic,
but it's a,
it's kind of fucked.
So you know,
like Kennison was killed by a drunk
driver and Kennison used to have those
bits about drinking and driving.
We're gonna do it.
We're going to drag.
We're going to drive.
We're going to pull it off.
We do it every fucking night.
The crowd would go crazy and people get
so mad.
They were like,
this guy is encouraging drunk driving
like what the fuck?
And then boom,
he gets killed by a drunk driver.
I like fucking comma.
Yeah.
I don't know if Karma is real,
but God damn is a lot of evidence out
there,
you know,
was just to say,
one of those things saying,
I swear to God a real,
but it's one of those things like an
American slang word Karma is a
motherfucker though.
It is and that,
that,
that statement.
Karma is a motherfucker.
It's like one of the best statements as
far as like,
when shit goes down like that,
you're like,
oh man,
you know,
nobody wishes that on somebody.
Especially if you're a driver and you're
like me.
And He's probably like,
pitch.
This would've never happened if I was at
the wheel.
Never fucking Georgie the way that kind
of drives.
That was insane.
I mean,
it's horrific to watch.
Definitely shouldn't be allowed to do
it.
What about the videos of the fucking
Russian dudes climbing the buildings?
I was just going to say something,
some new dude.
I put one up on my instagram page.
I put like two of them in a row.
They were fucking freaking me out.
And this dude,
uh,
contacted me through twitter and said
Hi.
His,
uh,
his,
his stunts are,
he's insane and he's got youtube videos.
These things to you just,
they're insane.
He's on like the Eiffel Tower or some
shit.
Right?
I saw that one.
Is that,
what is the,
is that in Paris that he's on that top
of that tower?
He's fucking palm sweat.
Mixed.
Like what the fuck to the mix.
Every fucking cell on your body just
starts vibrating really savvy.
I don't get that man.
If I was in that shape and I probably
would try to.
What'd you really?
Yeah,
but they're in crazy shape.
You see them doing.
Look at this.
Oh my God.
Oh,
this is in New York,
I guess.
Is this New York,
Dubai?
Others like,
oh my God.
Look at the age.
This is not good.
James Kingston's,
isn't he?
He's crazy Mexican dude.
Oh my God.
You know what?
A guy like this,
I would just like to hit for him to
retire right now.
Look,
you did it.
Congratulations.
Let's not keep doing this.
This is not.
Keep doing this.
Look their fuck.
Oh my God.
Look at this.
Oh my God,
he's doing chin ups on this thing.
Oh,
please stop.
I can't do this.
Oh,
fucking Christ.
Oh my God.
Dude.
Too.
For people who are in his name,
James Kingston on Instagram,
that's his page and I don't feel so good
that way.
He was holding on.
The blood was thick ass.
Boy.
He's got with one arm and he's hanging
with one arm and he's like a mile in
this guy.
Dude,
stop it.
Jamie's.
I can't do it.
Stop.
Cut it off.
Fuck man.
Oh my God.
What?
Flint.
My God.
He just jumped from one building to
another.
Look at this.
Not even a running start.
This is insane.
That is insane.
How does he do that?
Like I would splatter.
I would never make it that far.
How's he making it that far?
He has some good thrust.
The momentum than the thrust and that
seems like an insane amount of distance
to travel,
doesn't it?
How the fuck does he judge that?
How does he jump and land like that?
You got a crazy one.
Look at Jamie's face.
Look at this.
Oh,
there's no way.
He just jumps across a building.
How is that possible,
man?
How is that possible?
And this is one of his favorite jumps in
the city apparently.
Come on son.
And you know like this doesn't make any.
Doesn't make any sense.
At the end of the day,
man.
How is that possible?
If I could,
I would.
When skateboarding,
like once Tony Hawk does the 900,
once you see it done,
everyone else can just start doing it.
But I just looked.
I'm shocked by the distance he's
covering I guess.
I guess what's going on?
It's like
the distance of one building.
It's,
it's,
it's far away,
but it's also higher.
So in his leap if he get a good
spraying,
his arc will carry him over,
but he's got a judge that perfectly like
you have to you.
There's no room for error whatsoever.
This is what it looks like sideways.
Oh Shit.
To look out far.
He's jumping,
man.
That's insane.
That's an insane amount of space he's
covering.
When it lands on that edge,
like that kid,
he must be like.
I mean,
I don't know how much you ways,
but he must be insanely strong for his
weight and he can just throw his body
through the air like that.
He must have just ridiculous explosion
out of his legs.
Land so lightly.
That's freakish shit.
I guess it's those things like if you
just concentrate on only doing that,
you can do it in a way that doesn't make
sense to someone like you or me or.
No,
I can't even ice skate.
Skate at all.
Well fuck.
I'm.
I cannot escape incredibly man.
I'm fucking again.
Ice 80 five.
Yeah.
Good day.
First of all,
I can't find it.
Shoot when I don't have my own ice
skates so I have to rent.
Ice Skates is for the same reason why I
couldn't answer.
No.
For years I can rent.
Those are fucking shitty.
Well it's not even just that my feet are
too wide,
so if I had a regular size 11,
my feet,
I have someone in my background fucked a
monkey when it was fucking big foot one
time ago.
Like when you shouldn't be able to fuck
monkeys anymore.
Someone just went back in for one more
shot,
fucked them monkey guaranteed.
It was like the last,
like last call evolution last car in one
of my ancestors just snuck back in and
cut one more nut off.
Um,
but my feet are just too wide,
so I get in those things.
I'm just in agony and I just never
learned how.
And I'm not gonna I'm not interesting
enough for me to go out and buy ice
skates,
you know?
It felt like this is it.
It's just something I have to conquer.
Then I would have to learn how to ice
skate.
It was much more exciting as a youth.
Yeah.
Fucking roller.
Not Roller blading.
Fucking ice skating to green day shit
like that.
You know what I mean?
That's right.
They play loud music and you spin around
the ice.
Yeah.
See,
I guess hockey would be the reason to do
it.
Like if you wanted to learn how to play
hockey,
you say you pretend you're doing hockey
moves and like you're on the ice.
Snowing when you stop and you throw the
snow of people,
you know that that's a cool move.
Yeah,
exactly.
So you were the hockey skates.
You definitely don't where the figure
skating ones.
No chance.
No,
you don't.
What's the difference?
Well,
they had the spikes in the front so you
could do the triple toe Lutz.
You know anybody what?
You don't want anybody seeing your
spikes.
You're gonna.
When you go straight you have to lift a
little bit and you're going to fall on
your face.
The hockey is a little curvature,
like a running shoe.
It just allows you to maneuver,
to dice so it allows you to maneuver
better,
but it doesn't allow you to do tricks.
Can't do.
You can't do a stop and then tripled
toilets or like Scott Hamilton flip.
So were they doing flips and when they
do those spins on the ice?
They doing them with like special
skates?
Is that what the deal is?
Show a Brian Boitano.
Remember South Park by Brian Boitano do
love it.
That was one of the first episodes,
right?
Was it?
The first one was funny,
man,
that was going around as a vhs tape back
in the day.
That was one of those things where a
buddy of mine said,
you have to see this.
Check this out.
These guys made this video.
It was Jesus and Brian Boitano,
right?
[inaudible].
Who else was in it?
Santa Santa.
That's right.
Whatever it was.
It was fucking hilarious.
And it was way before its time.
You know what?
What was the year?
The first south park tape was made.
When you find out how long those guys
have been around.
Nineteen 92.
Jesus Christ,
dude,
they've been killing it since
[inaudible] 92 92 South Park came out in
[inaudible] 92.
That the spirit of Christmas.
Oh,
that was the 97.
Okay.
Yeah,
that much later.
Really?
God,
it was so funny.
I must've got it after if they did it in
[inaudible] 92.
I didn't move here until [inaudible] 94.
And I know that I got it.
Um,
when I was living in Encino because I
remember popping.
And then when a friend came over,
it was amazing.
You had a ball.
He hit a lend you the tape.
Somebody gave it to me.
I don't remember how I got the tape,
but I remember somebody gave it to me
and said,
you gotta watch this.
And um,
then I remember popping into VCR for my
friend.
It was so ridiculous.
It was super funny.
It was really crude.
I almost wish he would go back to doing
it this way,
you know,
because it was so obvious that it was
just really shitty animation.
Like,
look at the mouth movements.
It's more,
it's still shitty,
but it's more sophisticated now.
Right.
We just did shitty.
Yeah.
And this is a,
I bet the amount of time it took to do
this.
It's probably ridiculous though,
you know,
like the team America,
I think he said he would never do a one
of those movies again because it was
just way too time consuming.
I mean he was a pretty incredible
fucking movie.
It's one of my favorites ever.
Yeah.
That's one of my all time favorites.
We were talking about like movies that
are funnier than tropic thunder and
it's,
it's
probably none are funnier.
Like in moments I,
it's as funny as a movie gets,
but there's other really funny movies to
teach.
That's the funniest of all time.
One of them.
It's one of the funniest.
It's stupid funny movie team America to
Zulu lenders.
Really funny.
Yeah.
There's a lot of.
There's a lot of fucking Talladega
nights and now I lost all credibility
right there.
Jamie,
when I first saw the fucking board,
pretty much shit my pants.
Yeah,
Porat.
Even Bruno.
I didn't see Bruno.
I still haven't seen it.
My Albanian father.
Fuck it out.
Beatty and father.
Immigrant hardhead only knows one way a
neanderthal thinks that's one of the
funniest movies ever.
You know what I mean?
It's just weird.
It's a crossover hit.
You know what's a.
Oh,
like an underrated funny movie.
And Adam Sandler's don't mess with the
Zohan.
Oh yeah.
That one's a good one too.
Rated funny movie man.
Like,
because a lot of people,
they put Adam Sandler movies into like a
category,
you know,
sometimes you can get a little,
they can get a little dismissive of an
Adam Sandler movie,
but that don't mess with the Zohan.
It's classic,
it was a good one.
Yeah.
So tell me how your show works,
man.
Do you just decide where you want to go
to somebody else's suggest where to go?
Well,
a lot of the times it's A.
I go on tour for my music and then while
we're there we ended up shooting the
show.
If that's not the case,
I just tell them,
listen,
I want to go to Sicily and then we're in
Sicily,
you know,
it's that simple and we just,
I bring my boys with me and we just go
in,
they put the camera on and we just act
how we act.
Sub B us.
Wow.
Then you just get to pick where you're,
where you're eating and just.
Well yeah.
Were a chef at one point in time was.
That's how I really started.
I was uh,
my,
when I was like 18,
I went to culinary school and fucked off
after that for about a year and a half
or two and had a child and went back
into the kitchen and started working and
that was just said I thought I was just
going to be a fucking short order cook
or chef or whatever for the rest of my
life out of nowhere.
I broke my leg,
just slipped on the floor,
broke my leg.
I was working a little bit with music
before that,
but not in any capacity where I thought
it would be where I am now and shit.
Here we are,
you know,
that took me out of the kitchen
professionally,
put me in a recording studio all the
time.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
fall changed your destiny and straight
up,
broken my right leg,
my right ankle from a slip,
a very like I've snipped much worse,
much worse than myself.
And this one just got cracked,
cracked.
That's so interesting.
How something like that can happen or
something that looks like a bad thing
that happened to you.
Turned into like this amazing door that
opened up.
Yup.
And then all of a sudden you could do
what you really want to do.
It's,
this is what I wanted to do my whole
life.
Nothing,
you know,
just what I wanted to do.
So what is this?
We're watching Jamie Niamh jam or does
that.
Oh yeah,
this is a,
this is me in,
in Jamaica.
Oh Wow.
I went down here to do.
Would that go down here and do.
I went down here to do some sort of
exhibition with Mario Vitale,
but he was in no condition to do
anything with me that day.
So I ended up just hanging out pretty
much at the beach the whole time.
Oh,
so you were supposed to hang out with
Mario and he got fucked up pretty much
he,
I was hanging out with him,
but we were just sitting at the bar
hanging.
He was,
you know,
he was doing well.
He just didn't feel like doing anything.
He just wanted to hang out.
The weather was too good.
Oh,
I get it.
The weather was just too beautiful.
So he just didn't want to participate in
a show,
but no,
not this one.
Just in the entire events of the thing.
I feel like we're dancing around the
store.
He was pushed you on the bottom line.
I was fucking eight a macaroon,
like one of these edibles and I was just
demolished walking around.
Did Mario get demolished to now?
Maryville doesn't get demolished.
Like he's just,
he just drinks one that's too bad.
Yeah,
he's missing out.
He is.
I think that he's had this year.
You think?
So how would the same?
He's done.
Um,
I would say I got to get back to the
fucking kitchen,
got to cook the shit out.
Some food I can't have,
I don't have time for these deep soul
searching.
We trips now.
He's just hanging out,
man.
He's just living his life.
He's like a fucking superstar.
He's a rockstar.
That guy to world.
The world of chefs is a very different
world.
And when I was younger I didn't really
appreciate it like as an art form.
I think I just thought it was almost
more like a,
you know,
just a cool thing that someone knows how
to make really good food because you can
go to that restaurant,
you can get it there and didn't think of
like who is the creator of that food and
what is that?
Is that an art form?
You know,
because I think it definitely is.
And guys like you and like you look like
a chef,
which is like you're all tattooed up
like you a lot of chefs and chef.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's the date.
Like they can be artists.
Yeah,
for sure.
Well that's today chefs chefs are,
you know,
young,
crazy,
tattooed motherfuckers.
You can't really cool who's the chef,
you know,
but a classic chef is usually the French
guy with a handkerchief around his neck
and a big hat.
It's not like that anymore.
The chefs are now rockstars.
Well,
they definitely have become because I
think a lot of it is because of
Bourdain's show that definitely become
more highlighted in that regard.
Like on his show,
he's always like interviewing these
weird funky people in Portland that are,
you know,
raising their own chickens and shit and
farm to table type restaurants.
He'll,
he'll hang out with a lot of like weird
experimental chef people and a lot of
them look like you.
Yeah,
no that's,
that's a good thing.
He definitely opened a door for a lot of
people,
but I feel like the celebrity chefs
started with emeril Lagasse and people
like that,
like earlier with.
Excuse me.
What about Julia Child?
Exactly.
There you.
Oh,
excuse me.
Excuse me.
You can't go Mro.
You can't say it started with Emeril,
but I'm like in this era,
you know where it really fucking took
off.
Julia child was really the only one and
that other Guy Graham Kerr or some shit,
whatever the fucking guys name was.
So was there like a calm before the
storm?
Before emeril arrived?
Man,
I don't know the child and there was
nothing in the world searching for a TV
cook.
I was fucking driving around in fucking
jettas and shit.
Smoking weed and Queens.
I had no idea watching.
Saved by the bell at 7:00 AM.
Emeril was supposed to be a super nice
guy that emeril lagasse every blow by
all accounts,
like one of the nicest guys in the
world.
Bam.
It says Bam all the time,
Pam.
He gets hyped by all accounts.
Like one of the nicest guys.
He just keeps scallions in his pocket
and every fucking time he says band.
Just throw scallions in your face.
Yeah.
It's also interesting in the world of
food and likes and cooks and chefs that
there's different schools of food and
cooks and chefs.
There's like the really experimental
artistic people make maybe even
alternative and their musical choices.
And then it was like Guy Fieri and he
was like,
you know,
a big bolster.
Its American drives a yellow corvette.
It's got frosted tips.
It's like he's got his own.
He's a fucking classic character.
White snake version is a leopard.
Equally entertaining.
You know what I mean?
Like I'm a white snake fan,
you know?
I love him.
He's,
he's,
he's incredible.
It's funny how those guys like don't
like each other and they board Dane and
him go back and forth.
Has a beef.
It's hilarious for Dane is fucking
hilarious.
He's hilarious.
He's like a comic.
He's.
He's 100 percent.
Only works in New York kitchen his
entire life.
He still.
He started Jujitsu at 58.
I know I see 57,
58.
She's doing a good job.
He's rolling around over there.
He got a blue belt.
Really?
Yeah.
He got his blue belt.
That's a legit blue belt from Henzel
gracie academy.
That is about as legitimate blue belt as
there is in the world.
You have to earn that.
You don't just get that.
He that guy.
That's very impressive.
That's very impressive to do that at his
age and apparently he's just doing it
every day.
Man Becomes addictive,
right?
Yeah.
And I,
I looked at your instagram page.
You're,
you're working out.
You have someone trains sometimes.
Oh yeah.
You know,
like I,
I've been athletic my entire life.
I played football.
Fucking high school baseball.
Know as time goes on you get lazy.
You know.
When I was younger I was fucking
juicing.
I was taking steroids and shit.
I was fucking buff.
I'm serious.
I believe I was squatting like six.
I was fucking bench in my highest was
100 pounds straight up.
No shoes on belt,
no wraps.
Just in the bucket.
You don't want to wear shoes,
no shoes.
You know,
you gotta keep the flat flat shoe.
Six hundred pounds with no shoes.
That's crazy.
That's a lot of weight.
It was out.
It was like 22 years old,
23 years old,
but it was,
it was probably because of the steroids
will do in a show like this where you
traveled around the world and you're
eating all that food.
I would imagine it would be so easy to
just get lazy.
Just literally lost 50 pounds and I just
gained another 20.
So,
um,
my whole life is fluctuation.
I just need to get to that point where I
need to get past that fluctuating point
and just go down and start seeing all
these fucking abs that I have under
there.
You know what I'm saying?
I have like 32 ab muscles that you know,
you could possibly see.
All it needs to be done is shredded.
Do you really want to lose that much
weight?
Of course anybody that's overweight
wants to have a fucking six pack before
they die.
The fact,
is it a fact?
Yeah.
I have one vein.
I've,
you know,
you know when you gauge working gal you
if you can see the vein or not.
Yes.
I have that good one vein over here.
The squiggly upper shoulders.
Exactly.
The squiggly one.
Yeah,
that's a good one.
Like a.
What was the bodybuilder?
The fucking French guy forgot his name.
The French guy told delay.
I don't know who that guy is.
That's secure reference.
Obscure stroke man.
References on types of bodybuilding
references.
Yeah,
that's a ridiculous one.
Look up.
Pulled the.
It tells me that he doesn't have that
fucking.
He's famous for the squiggle.
So have you thought about like hiring a
nutritionist?
I know what to do.
You know what to do.
I don't know what to do.
It's just not easy doing it alone.
I need someone to,
you know,
literally.
No,
you can't do that.
You can't have that at one in the
morning.
You can eat a fucking in and out right
now.
You can have fries right now,
just do,
just stick to it.
It's hard to stick to it.
So is it um,
just a selfcontrol thing?
Yes,
but I have self control in spirits,
which is weird.
There is Paul delay.
Here is guys bodies sad.
It doesn't even look real.
Oh my God.
What's with the suspenders?
There's two pictures of the road with
him wearing suspenders.
They always have suspect outfits on and
fucking body they help is wearing some
wild.
Like where did you get that?
Oh,
it genes with the best.
So that's definitely call Kanye dude his
wall.
He's so sweet.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah,
that guy's so big.
I used to look at magazines and want to
be like that.
It's just crazy.
It's like Ronnie Coleman and fucking
insane science project or really that's
it.
That's a science project.
It's amazing how many of those science
projects exist though.
I mean that's what all those magazines
are.
It's the weirdest conspiracy and it is a
conspiracy that all those,
like if you looking at those
bodybuilding magazines and shit that
none of them like,
I don't know,
maybe they do now,
but back in the day none of them were
talking about how they did steroids.
You're right there all dancing around
it,
but they were also talking about like,
you know,
I take creatine muscled Dick hard
corporation and let's a team is
guaranteed to pack on 30 pounds a mass
and they were all like pretending that
they got all that muscle from some stuff
that,
you know,
it's like barely works.
Like creatine works a little bit,
but if you get to the Paul delay levels,
no way.
You can't look like that as like a human
being.
Can't look like that.
I don't think people understand that.
No,
and I don't think I understand why the
fuck they used to not talk about it
while I was just so taboo because it was
illegal.
It was legal and everyone knows what
you're doing.
It's like more out in the open now with
all the baseball shit and this.
Yeah.
I don't think that it's wrong.
Every baseball player he looks like now.
That's crazy.
Oh,
that looks like a meme that you know,
that looks like something on the Yo.
What the fuck?
That is insane.
What does it say above that,
Jamie?
He already experienced some atrophy in
his arms and back,
but why?
What had happened to him says he's
clearly off anabolics and stuff.
Oh,
I see.
Wow.
Jesus Christ.
Well,
you know that guy,
when he was as big as he was at the top,
he had to be on just staggering amounts
of that stuff.
That's what people don't understand
this.
You even if you.
I do know one dude though.
I have to be honest.
I know one dude that I know who never
took anything.
I know he didn't because he didn't.
He wouldn't even eat vitamins.
I eat all his vegetables.
He's a very smart guy and he got really
big,
like ridiculous.
He was my friend Brian Frazier.
He's a writer.
He's a comic out of Boston and at one
point in time he was fucking enormous
and I know all he did was work out.
That's all he did.
He was just a,
a dedicated bodybuilder dedicated to
lifting weights.
He was fucking gigantic.
And so he was cleaning out those
genetics,
but he was.
No,
it wasn't even genetics.
He was just dedicated,
just dedicated,
just dedicated hard work.
And he got it,
read it,
read it while I was entering
competitions.
He was ridiculously
swoll so much.
So that one time you went up on stage,
he had a,
uh,
like a,
like a golf shirt on like an alligator
shirt and he came off stage.
I pulled him aside and said,
dude,
listen to me.
You can't go on or short sleeve shirts.
And he goes,
why?
I go,
your arms are way too big.
Way Too distracting me.
I'm like,
I'm your friend and that distracted me.
You're,
you're up there like,
you're so intimidating,
like crazy because he's,
he was so swollen.
I was like,
you can't,
you can't go on stage like that.
Nobody wants to see that.
I feel like that's how I wanted to be at
one point.
I feel like that's what I wanted.
Yeah,
but maybe it's this.
Maybe it's the height thing,
we want to be wired that way and because
you know,
you know a little bit shorter than the
normal men,
you want to be.
Exactly.
We can't go north south,
but I think that if you really wanted to
do it though,
you would be like,
Brian,
you would be dedicated to it and you'd
really want to do it.
You get into it,
but it's one of those things where you
want to do it,
but you're also like a guy who really
enjoys life and there's too many things
that I have to be dedicated to math.
It's fucking hard.
You're not to be dedicated to music to
this,
to that.
It's a fucking everybody family.
Just like,
come on man.
You know how many more things I have to.
But I think if you do decide to do
something like that,
I think what you're saying is what's
really the true thing that a lot of
people that we're trying to avoid when
it comes to losing weight or changing
your life,
it's like you have to be dedicated to
that.
It can't be something to do like,
Hey,
I'm dedicated to my music.
I'm dedicated to,
you know,
whatever my golf game,
but I'm out.
I'm going to lose weight to like,
no,
you have to be dead gas.
That has to be your main goal in life is
to be doing that.
You have to focus on that.
Pissed to one of them are going to try
to change your chemistry and when people
do it,
it's so fucking impressive.
I mean,
how many people have you met that have
lost like a hundred pounds and you just
want to just shake their hand and go,
dude,
you fucking did it,
bro.
He lost 100 pounds.
I lost 80 and I gained it back and
there's one truck and a bad.
My fluctuation.
It's crazy.
Have you ever thought about.
I mean I know you love food,
but if you ever thought about like
changing the kinds of foods you eat.
Yeah,
of course.
Just,
you know,
I don't think it's the,
it's the defined foods that I eat.
I think it's the refined sugars and
disgusting shit that I decided to eat.
Why don't you try to wish that I had
last night?
What'd you have?
A chip?
Which with the chip,
which it's a fucking to toll house
cookies with ice cream in between.
That sounds awesome.
It was good and it was melted and I
still ate it.
Damn fucking disgusting.
It's piglets shit,
right?
Shit.
We actually.
He actually had it in his pocket for
about a half an hour before I.
before I hated it.
I'm like,
God.
Yeah,
so I bet it was glorious.
It was who?
My friend Aubrey has the best way of
looking at it.
We were talking about it and he was
like,
it's so crazy that just just a few
moments of mouth pleasure is worth
fucking up your entire body like your
body,
the thing that carries you around in
this light,
the thing that you need more than
anything and just for a few moments of
mouth.
Pleasure.
Long,
long.
Oh,
and then you feel in your whole body
going,
what did you just throw in here?
And have us deal with you ass crazy.
It's fucking asshole.
Fucking nuts.
What a cruel,
sick,
fucked up joke nature has played on us
to make the things that are the most
delicious going down the worst for your
body out.
That's a fucking conspiracy.
What I want our current nature is they
just dirty guts.
What a bitch you imagine man,
like,
like if you're eating fried chicken with
waffles.
Okay.
Fried chicken with waffles is one of the
most fucking bang up meals America's
ever created.
Like a good solid to put butter on the
wealth.
Of course like Roscoe's Roscoe's chicken
and waffles.
Just the sheer amount of sugar you are
taken in with the want drink.
You're going to have to have a diet
coke.
You gotta get the fucking the fucking.
It's like Koolaid.
What is sense it.
It's like an orange drink.
Red Drink and yellow drink.
Mixed is throw them all together.
That's the sunset.
It's fucking stupid.
But then if you want to get nuts,
do you throw butter on the fried
chicken?
Maple Syrup definitely.
But then you have to have the grits as
well that has made butter in it.
And uh,
you know,
it's like when does it end?
I think the issue is the sheer grams of
sugar you're taking in from the waffle
and the Maple Syrup alone,
you must be taking in an ungodly amount
of sugar.
Yeah.
Straight off that stuff.
Yeah,
because I drench those things to the way
I do it.
It's like if I'm having some maple syrup
I'm going to go in.
Can Be covered.
I went in,
yeah.
I'm not going to drizzle it and go.
I wish I would've had a little bit more
maple syrup,
but I'm pink.
Sensible enough.
Fuck that.
If you're eating Roscoe's,
you know it probably already made some
critical errors and you're doing a crazy
dire right now.
Right?
Right now.
So that's what I'm saying.
Like if you,
if you will,
you can't even have a cheat day.
Kenya,
you're not supposed to.
I had a beer yesterday.
That's what I'm saying.
Like it's supposed to have beer but
have.
See you didn't go all out.
If you have a cheat day,
just like,
yeah,
I haven't gone all out.
I've just decided to try it for 60 days
and you know.
Well,
I want to just see what it's about.
I don't,
I don't think you really evaluate.
I think I've,
I've been eating pretty healthy but one
way my whole life and I took some time
off of gluten for awhile and I liked
that,
but what I liked about it was that I
felt like really what was going on was I
was just taking
in way less sugar by not having pastas
and breads,
which I really love.
I was just taking them way less sugar
and I lost weight.
My face got thinner and I was like,
this is interesting.
It's like how much of what I'm taking in
is sugar.
So I went back to occasionally eating
bread and just trying to avoid it.
And then from the last 15 or maybe 16,
15 days,
something like that,
I've been doing this where I'm doing
nothing.
No grains,
no pasta,
no bread,
no sugar,
nothing.
That's just nothing other than plants,
vegetables,
fats,
coconut oil,
shit like that and meet.
That's it.
So it's Kinda like that.
It's kind of like the Atkins died from
back in the day,
right where you just sort of.
But more fats,
fats,
fats even than proteins.
It's actually what the Diet is saying is
that we use too much protein and that
like if you want to do some extreme
power lifting and you want to get to be
the size of Paul dillet,
delay,
delay those Arnold Schwartzenegger.
How about that?
You gotta you know you have to eat a lot
more than the average person,
but for the average person,
the average person,
it's like reasonably athletic.
You'll probably doesn't really want to
process all that extra protein and what
it really needs to burn.
It's fats and so your body will convert
anything in the energy that you put.
If you live off of a carbohydrate based
diet,
their argument is you know you're
subject to more fluctuations.
You're your levels,
rise and fall.
That's when you crash after you eat and
when you know you haven't eaten in a
while,
you're starving and a lot of that I
think is also related to gut bacteria
and I'm starting to learn more about
that,
but not enough really where I can talk
probiotic stuff,
probiotics,
gut bacteria,
and just the amount of different things
that you eat,
like what?
There's certain types of gut bacteria
that thrive off of unhealthy food and if
you're eating a lot of sugars,
apparently what they're saying is that
there's different types of gut bacteria
that crave that sugar and so when you
haven't had in awhile that gut back to
you,
even if you're full,
you might have like pot roast and mashed
potatoes and vegetables and it was like
nothing.
Nothing fucked up at all.
Right?
You eat that and your body's like,
hey asshole,
where's the sugar?
Come on,
come on.
Because they're craving craving it.
Like those rumbles that you would get.
So I don't know what.
I don't know if that's the case with me,
so I'm just giving it 60 hold days,
see what it's like,
you know?
And if I,
if I like how I'm feeling after 60 days,
I'll tell you right now though,
just a couple of weeks in.
It's awesome.
I feel great.
Um,
I feel I don't feel very hungry in
between meals,
which is interesting.
So go eat and then I guess once you get
fat adapted you don't,
you just don't have as many crashes.
I just don't know if it's like what I
want to do sustainably because it's hard
when you go to a restaurant or something
like that.
It's hard to tell them he
can't even have rice.
Like there's a lot of delicious deep
dishes that come with Rice.
Like you can't even have rice with a
meal.
Like that seems so extreme.
So unbelievable.
But so far so good.
Every time have attempted to lose
weight.
It was like I did that Atkins Diet back
in the day,
but it felt like I'm eating eggs and
sausage and all this nasty shit and
still losing weight.
Yeah.
I didn't understand that,
but I fucking ate a piece of bread and
it would be over.
I put five pounds on [inaudible] not
crazy.
And it's just,
it's not worth it.
And then you feel shittier than you did
because you gain all that weight and you
ate all that disgusting stuff that's got
to be sticking to somewhere,
right?
Well,
it's just hard for your body to process
exact,
become sugar and not fucking makes you
shit really badly,
really badly rich.
Like you can't leave the house.
You have to run to the fucking bad.
But the Atkins is,
uh,
a little bit different than this start
that I'm doing and that this guy just
has more fat.
But you still go into that same thing,
right?
To ketosis.
That's what they want you to do.
That's the point of these guides.
Yup.
Yeah.
So your body starts burning fat.
And it's fascinating.
The most fascinating thing about it is
seeing people argue it from both sides.
Seeing people argue that this is bad for
your health and you're,
you're,
you're fucking up.
And don't do this.
Like people get upset,
like they get upset,
like to try and Satanism,
you know,
it's like all of a sudden like,
oh,
well I'm thinking maybe Satan's maybe
saying he's got a point.
I'm going to go meet these guys and I'm
just gonna.
See,
I'm just going to see what's going on.
Like that's how they're behaving.
When you talking about just going on
this key to genic diet,
they pretend like you're doing something
evil,
like don't do it.
You're going to fuck yourself up,
man.
Cut it out.
Yeah,
like anyone really fucking knows.
And then they start posting all these
pro car like you know,
more carbs.
Hashtag carb up.
Carb is brain fuel or come on,
but he just relax.
Relax.
I said I'm trying to for 60 days.
I'm not going to lie.
It's not the easiest thing to have to
give up those sheep's milk on your
little day in the fucking Nilkie.
I know New York is very good stuff.
A hostile linguine with clams sauce as a
place that just opened up directly
across the street from my house.
Incredible.
It has one of my favorite dishes ever.
It's like,
Gotcha.
We peppy just cheese and pepper with
pasta.
Oh my God.
But she does it with the pink
peppercorn.
So it's like you're eating a bowl of
flowers.
Wow.
One of the most incredible things in
life.
I crave it.
God dammit.
This diet's bullshit.
Exactly my bad.
I'm sorry about.
It's definitely about pasta.
Please keep talking.
Take my pants off real quick.
Pasta,
whore.
That's what you will.
There's just something about pasta
that's.
It's like a.
it's,
it's the real comfort food,
you know,
for you.
For me,
for sure.
Yeah.
Like Ravioli's.
Just cheese.
Ravioli's with like a good sauce.
Like a fried fried,
fried Ravioli.
I've never had it.
Just fucking do it as if you were doing
the chicken cutlet.
Put it into the egg.
Really?
Breadcrumb.
You'll thank me.
Trust me.
Wow.
Like a chicken colors.
Unbelievable.
Fried Ravioli.
Woo.
Some unbelievable.
Jamie shaking his head.
You've been all over this country.
I'm surprised you've never eaten.
Fried Ravioli.
Submit Western thing to some standards
that I have that I have to like stick
with.
Like,
you know,
like if I go to Philly,
I'm having a cheese day.
One hundred percent standard.
What does that.
Do you eat pork?
Yes,
but what about the pork sandwich?
That I feel like the cheese steak is a
bit overrated over there.
I feel like my guy listen to me,
the guy at my Deli in queens makes a
fucking better cheese.
Steak,
watts.
Then who?
Then?
All Philadelphia.
Not.
No,
no.
Let's,
let's not get crazy.
But that's what you're saying better
because they're not.
They usually not flavored.
Oh,
okay.
You know what I mean?
They just do the steak.
The cheese.
There's no salt.
That needs to be salt a little bit.
At least a little bit of salt with me.
It was always good and you know,
it brings out the flavor.
You know,
I don't want to have to drench it in hot
sauce or ketchup.
Imagine that.
Like you're telling everybody.
Everybody's fucking up.
You need salt.
Get it together,
bitch.
It's just that simple.
It's that simple.
And they've yet to.
Well that's Fogo de Chao.
You have read it.
I have it.
One of the things about Fogo de Chao
when you get a nice piece of Pecan.
Yeah.
From them it's always got salt on it.
It's always got a nice salty.
They have like a base that they based
the the meat on when they put them over
the fire place to protect this
incredible.
So good.
When they bring out that whole side of
beef rib and they just.
Oh,
that's ridiculous too,
because you just get right after it.
You sit down to one of those places.
They have a red and a green on your
little card,
like a poker chip.
Just flip it over.
Whenever you're ready to party.
Like let's do this.
He put it on green.
These dudes just start swooping in on
you with skewers.
Straight up with me and swords.
Yeah.
Have you ever flipped it to read flipped
a tourette?
No.
Have you ever flip to read?
Have you ever flipped the thing to read?
Oh yeah,
definitely.
Fuck.
That stays on green.
Wow.
Until we literally got a waddle out.
You will.
And this explains my issue.
Yeah.
We're all different.
We all have different needs.
I can't feel like a knowing that now I
feel a little bit down.
Don't feel down.
Red should.
Fears are undisputed world champion of
continuing to eat at Fogo de Chao.
No one's been able to touch them.
Rel Beats.
He already eats joey.
He always.
He'd always tell me he just keeps going.
Ari Shaffir can put away food.
Like probably almost no
one I've ever seen at one of those
forgotten child.
He's ridiculous.
He just keeps it coming.
I'm like,
where are you putting this?
Because it just keeps it coming because
he go get the rice and everything.
I just goes for the meats,
a couple of pieces of lettuce.
He's there.
He's there at parties.
You know that dude just,
he keeps that fucker grain like we all
tap out and like Jesus,
sorry.
And he's in the guys like coming by with
like some lamb chops.
He was like,
sure we're going over different.
That Joey,
Joey,
what it is.
What is the Jelly?
The Mint Mint.
How many of these?
You've spoken a lot.
I'm usually hitting the oil,
you know,
all day long.
Hitting that pure oil,
taking some fucking mushrooms.
I just got some nice mushrooms and
yesterday he'd be like,
food mushrooms are magic.
Magical ones.
Yeah.
[inaudible] mushrooms.
How long before those illegal.
How long before after pot becomes legal,
we all just get together and go,
hey,
cut this shit.
All the people that made it illegal,
they're all dead now.
We know there were liars.
I don't.
I don't even think it's illegal.
I don't know what you.
Illegal.
I just think is legal.
All it is is it's something that grows
from here.
Honor.
May I speak with my client.
Just didn't,
didn't know I wasn't.
What do you want me to say?
You were registered voter.
Okay.
You already got.
You have a driver's license.
You have to know what is and is not
legal as far as like what you're being
arrested for it.
Bad citizen.
Can't say that to her.
You say,
let's try this again.
Have you ever been hit in the head once?
Try to come up with some real.
We.
I've reasonable believe my client has
sustained a head injury earlier in his
life and virtually never recovered.
What he needs is our care when he
doesn't need is our judgment.
I'm like Vincent Gigante,
he only feels going around like I'm
local.
He only feels normal when he gets
mushrooms in him.
That's when therapeutic use of mushrooms
is on its way,
folks.
There's no doubt about that happen.
It should have happened a long time ago.
It'd be better for all of us.
My girl and studying that.
So is she?
Yeah.
She's into like holistic medicine and
healing through psychedelics.
There's a lot of people that are
involved in that now,
including maps,
the.
I don't know what it is.
Multidisciplinary Association,
something Psychedelic Studies,
but these are acknowledging it,
right?
Oh,
they've made some massive strides in
getting.
Trying to get therapeutic use of a Mtma
for soldiers,
excuse me,
and other people suffering from ptsd and
they're showing all these applied uses
of like really excellent compounds that
have been demonized and and because
they've been deemed my demonize,
people that could really use them,
aren't getting them like can you abuse
them?
But I think we've already established
that's a dumb argument because you can
abuse anything.
You can go to a store and buy a hammer
and you can build houses or you could
hit yourself in the Dick.
You're fucking stupid.
You can do whatever you want.
Right?
Like you can't.
You can't.
That's not a good argument that someone
could abuse it,
so it shouldn't be legal.
There's massive amounts of shit to abuse
all over us all the time.
So stop cars.
You get anything?
Bikes you can abuse everything.
I think the use of them,
their magic.
There's a reason why we call magic
mushrooms.
Absolutely fucking magic.
You can,
you can have incredible experiences on
them and the fact that we are not
allowed to.
Then we have to worry about someone
locking us in a cage for doing some shit
that's not hurting anybody.
It's not even hurting you.
Like mushrooms don't hurt you.
You have to take some insane amount of
um,
for it to be like the ld 50 rate.
It's like you have to take pounds of it.
Right?
What's The ld?
50 from micro from a psychedelic
mushrooms or psilocybin?
It's really high.
It's like something stupid like you
can't,
you almost can't even eat it.
How many pounds you have to eat.
So this two grams had me on my fucking
ass.
This is from mice.
You killed mice with mushrooms.
Oh my God.
First of all,
that's what they go.
And have it.
Here's something fucked up.
Scroll up,
scroll down again,
scroll up again rather.
So I could see this study.
Um,
the name of the study was the name of
the study at the top.
How many dried mushrooms,
what I have to eat to die from an
overdose.
Silicide.
What is this on?
What website is this shrew?
Marie Marie is.
How fucking crazy is that?
The dude asks,
he asks,
how many mushrooms do I have to eat
before overdose?
Using the data for rats and accepting a
medium of a median of one percent
potency,
it would require the consumption of
1,680 grams of mushrooms to reach the ld
50 for a 60 kilogram rat.
You have to eat a lot.
Whoa.
That's a lot of grams.
So,
but rats are tougher than us.
Rats can eat rats and they don't die.
Exactly.
Same each other mckinney even go off
that.
I've told this story 100 times.
I killed a rat once in my driveway in
my,
uh,
garage.
Went out in the morning to clean the
trap and it was gone.
They had eaten them the others.
The others had eating them.
Yeah,
dude,
I mean down to nothing.
Sounded like the tail and insane.
Yeah,
savages,
man.
It was just so.
Yeah,
but it was so creepy to think that I'm
sharing my house with cannibals,
like these are roden animal that when
one of them dies,
the other ones just burned through them
and there's.
There's a bunch of them around me.
They were there in my ceiling.
I healed crawling around in there.
They're in the house.
They're just too small or too small for
them to kill me as Shit freaks me the
fuck out man.
At a squirrel in my house one time and
the wool and you hear them three and no
more.
I'm sitting at three in the morning
naked with my fucking just watching
sports center
and they started fighting screaming.
I'm like,
Holy Fuck.
Is that in the ceiling?
In the ceiling.
I'm like,
what?
I started hitting the ceiling with a
broom.
Oh my God.
I stopped.
I started hitting the closets,
like trying to scare them and then
eventually the motherfucker eight
through the wall.
One day I was laying on the couch and I
just suddenly opened my eyes and look up
and he's just fucking looking at me.
We make eye contact and it's like,
it's a fucking.
It's a of,
is about to be,
you know,
like a Mexican shootout.
So it was,
it was crazy.
So then my,
uh,
bad.
Then my Greek landlord decided to put
traps out and I think that he
literally slaughtered about 60 of them
from the neighborhood.
Oh my God.
It's not his fault.
It was in the trap,
the trap or listen,
they did bad things to the neighborhood.
They would eat through lines grow.
Nobody gives a fuck about rats.
If he killed 60 rats who had been like,
good kill 60,000 and I now feel bad
about that.
Don't feel better because why is it?
Why is it if you kill squirrels,
people get bummed out.
But if he killed rats,
people were like,
yeah,
you go kill him shit and fucking kill
anything.
But at the end of the day shit happens.
Yeah.
But if you're,
if you're killing something with a trap,
you're definitely trying to kill it.
Yeah.
Well,
I had no involvement,
but I'm just wondering why we so readily
accept killing rats,
but not squirrels.
Like how to rats.
It's viewed as vermin.
I feel like squirrels have viewed as a
lot of people.
Yeah.
I feel like that's the case.
Like an issue,
like a big federal hug.
Same Shit.
In certain parts of the world,
they're considered just as much of a
nuisance as a rhet.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Where certain islands,
Jamaica as rats,
what they think of him.
Like rats.
I feel like squirrels like in just in
New York,
a lot of people just fucking scared of
squirrels will do.
You know the difference between like
tree squirrels,
those cute ones that everybody likes and
those ground squirrels.
Ground squirrels are fucking crazy.
Ground squirrels.
I was on this ranch in California and
they have a ground squirrels problem and
we're driving down this road as we're
driving down this road.
You're watching these little tiny
creatures pop their head out of the
ground,
run across and jump into another whole.
There's holes all over the place and
craps over there.
They would try a bunch of different shit
that grow in there.
They have have cattle that are grazing.
They have a bunch of different things
going on there.
You can't do anything about these
things.
There's so many of them.
They say there's so many ground
squirrels that the biomass of these
things is like a biomass of like a giant
herd of cattle or something like that.
There's so many of them.
It's like a 100 cows,
like that's how many of these little
fucking ground squirrels just running
around this area.
So what do they do?
I saw that they do these like where it
gives them a shock.
They had these things where they put
food in and it kills them humanely.
They shocks him.
I don't know how many there are.
I don't know if they know,
like if you're driving down the road and
you just keep seeing these little heads
pop up and run across.
There's another one that's another one.
Bang,
pop up,
run across a little tiny thing they'll
tell you wrote and boom.
Jumped into a whole,
jumps into a hole and your wife's up.
Scramble all.
Consequently you're like,
whoa,
if these were rats,
I would be freaking the fuck out.
Right?
Nipping,
I'd be going,
Jesus,
fuck it.
If you were driving down New York City
and that's the kind of.
That's what you saw with rats.
Just pop it up and running across.
Popping in the whole.
Everybody be like,
let's get the fuck out of here.
Fucking run.
We got to get out of the city.
It would be like that scene in aliens
for the dude was talking about nuking it
from orbit it up.
You got to get out of the city.
We're going to poison everything.
We're going to take five years off the
city and then we can return.
Just poison everything there for five
years.
Heavy,
but these little ground squirrels,
they're a little cuter,
slightly cuter,
so they're more accepted like all those
little animals.
A cute little rats.
Not that cute.
Not really into them.
There's something about him that just to
untrustworthy the true rat,
like people that have rats for pets
though they love them.
It's the same thing.
I mean,
if you have a domesticated animal and it
grows up with you and it's care for its
entire life,
then you become like family,
you know,
just like a dog or a cat.
But if you've ever been around a feral
cat,
have ever been around a feral dog,
like Ooh,
they can.
That can be really scary.
I had a cat.
My mother rescued a cat when I was
younger in the fucking cat attack me.
It was a feral cat.
It was,
it was a white cat and it was,
it was abused.
Jesus Christ.
It wasn't like,
you know,
I was fucking with it a little bit like,
that's scared rabbit.
It's neck and shit and like,
you know,
the back which skin and he fucking
snapped and bit the shit out of me and
scratched me.
Jesus went nuts.
She would've stopped.
Fuck man.
Right Randall?
I slept with them.
I deserved it.
They can be terrifying now.
It's,
it's amazing how powerful a little cat
is that ferocious there.
Yeah,
it's nonstop.
The two quick,
you don't know what to do and you panic
because like,
what the fuck is this fucking thing?
He's attacking me.
What is this?
Yeah,
it's not a human and they'll,
they're going to go full bore.
Whereas you're gonna Kinda pull back.
They're gonna.
I mean there's just such a better design
as far as like killing things.
Their bodies are so well designed.
When you watched that guy that was like
jumping across those buildings,
cats would be like,
bitch,
I do that.
All the easy,
easy.
They do that so gently around my house.
You know,
they just leap.
All of a sudden,
boom,
they're on the couch.
Leap book there on the table,
right.
Walk across leap.
Boom.
They're on the ground.
They walk on railings.
Balancing Act on railings.
What about those?
Um,
I love watching those shows on national
geographic.
Like when they make the kill then they
drag it all the way up into the tree.
Birds know,
like,
you know,
like lepage,
dragging it,
and a moose up into the fucking like,
you kidding me?
They're so scary.
Gotcha.
That's a design.
He grabbed them with their teeth.
Look at this level.
This is the recent one.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
This was in India,
right?
It got loose was just jacking people.
Look at that.
Oh my God.
I just jumped up and bit that guy.
Can you jump in the water?
Is that safe or no?
I can.
I swim.
I don't swim.
I think that.
Let's jump into woo man.
Oh my God.
Look at this thing.
Biting him,
man.
That guy got someone threw him a fucking
stick.
You saw someone throw a mystic.
Jesus Christ as terrifying man.
That is fucking terrifying.
That animals so powerful too.
That's a big cat.
I think looked like it was 150 pounds.
At least.
Just imagine a 150 pound house cat.
Fuck yeah.
Fuck all that dude.
You know,
Uhm,
were so poorly designed when it comes to
like being able to defend ourselves
against something like that were so
poorly designed.
It's amazing.
Other animals have such a way better
shot athletically.
Even chimps.
Chimps are so much stronger than us.
They have a way better shot at surviving
and Capitec fucking swinging from trees
going nuts.
That was one of the things.
They found them out,
those big giant chimps in the Congo that
they nest on the ground,
like gorillas,
gorillas,
nest in the ground because nobody wants
to fuck with the gorilla.
Cats don't want to fuck with the grill.
It's like too much work.
You can easily get your jaw broke.
Your leg broke.
Yeah.
They can't fuck with gorillas.
It's too hard.
They might catch a baby slipping,
you know,
they might be able to catch a baby,
like you know something.
If it gets separated from his mom at the
ripe,
you know that that's possible.
But like a regular size gorilla.
Good luck.
No fucking way.
They don't have to be stucking yeah.
So they sleep in the ground where chimp
sleeping,
the trees,
chimps,
you still got to be careful,
but they found these big giant chimps in
the Congo,
the column a,
the billy ape or the Bondo ape.
And um,
they were just a legend for the longest
time they were in that.
That book,
Michael Crighton's books that it was the
Congo.
Is that,
who wrote that?
Who are seeing the movie?
Was it quite in the road that you see
that movie?
Congo?
Yeah.
It's kind of silly.
It was that.
Yeah,
it was terrible.
It was terrible.
But the guy with the accent,
you know,
the one is always in all those movies,
the Weirdo,
which guys are fucking weird guy.
He was like,
the flavors,
the guide,
he was terrible.
He's like,
I don't remember the,
you'll see his face.
He was,
fuck you guy.
It was just not a,
not a very good movie.
That guy,
that's not a,
that's on him.
But that was after the Congo.
Whereas the doctor,
her.
Nah,
this,
there's another one,
the one who was looking for all areas.
What?
Who,
where he is.
Timothy,
that guy.
You've seen them.
But that was great.
That's the guy from rocky horror picture
show.
Exactly.
As slugging.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah,
I like him.
Well,
the movie dealt with.
See that monkey up there.
The one picture that's supposedly what
these giant chimps look like.
So in the movie they were these
fictional animals that will look super
smart and they were really big,
but it is based on this thing.
This is a real one.
Wow.
This is a real one that uh,
someone had killed,
like at the turn of the century,
that's one that they shot in an airport,
uh,
in Africa.
Look at the size of that thing in
comparison to those men.
You're talking about a chimp that could
get to be like 400 pounds.
There are enormous.
It is ridiculous.
And so they,
they sleep on the ground just like
gorillas do.
And there's a small population of them.
They just recently found them.
Well,
there's a Swiss,
I think for Swiss wildlife photographer
named Carl or mom and he took some
photos of them with a camera trap.
Put up a photo camera trap.
Bondo.
Ape.
I think I'm saying his name right.
Carl Armaun.
But he,
um,
yeah,
the upper left.
That's it.
Th.
Those photos.
Yeah,
that's the same thing.
See,
I'm one of them.
What does it say,
Carl?
What's also in,
just for everybody,
it's a,
excuse me,
Carl K,
a r l a m m a n n and he got these
camera trap photos of them walking
upright
and that's.
That was the most fucked up thing about
it.
Really.
Shit.
I didn't even realize what I was looking
at.
A six foot,
that's a six foot tall chimp that's
walking upright.
I mean they're really big.
They're way bigger than a regular champ
and it's.
They have a crest in their head like
gorillas.
Do you know gorillas?
Gorillas are one of the few primates it
has.
If you look at it skull,
they have a crest in the skull where
these massive chewing muscles fighting
muscles all sort of congregate on their
head.
They have these huge jaw muscles and
these huge clampdown muscles and they
have this cleft in the top of their
head.
I pull up Bondo,
ape skull and they'll.
They had a.
They found the skulls of these things
and at first they were like,
okay,
is this a hybrid?
Like what is this?
See it,
see how it has like crest at the top of
the head.
So now that they know that it's a real
animal,
they're like,
well,
this is the first chimp they've ever
found that has a crest like this looking
at.
And it's also,
it's,
they were thinking that it was some sort
of a hybrid.
They were thinking like maybe it was a,
maybe it was parked gorilla part champ.
Is that possible?
But then the,
the genetics we have gotten,
I think from stool samples and some
other,
some other methods of acquiring them.
They,
uh,
they think that it's just,
it's own kind of chimp just to breed
that only exist in this one area.
Pretty fucking crazy.
You think about it like they've only had
photos of this thing since the,
this Guy Carl Amman in the,
uh,
I think the nineties he did that,
right?
What does it say?
Four is when he first got the photos on
it.
I guess it's apparently have been like
legend,
but the Congo is giant man.
It's like the United States.
It's huge.
Like the Congo,
rain forest,
if you look at it on a map in,
um,
you know,
like they'll take like a,
uh,
the actual size of the u s and put it
like in the Congo and he goes,
oh,
well in the Congo you almost can.
It's pretty close.
It's basically the size of the United
States give or take,
right.
I mean,
even if it was half the size,
it's fucking crazy.
Who the hell knows what's in there?
Yeah,
exactly.
Like can never find everything that's
there.
But this one area where this thing lives
is a,
of course they're probably like making
cell phones out of there or something
like that and pulling minerals out of
the ground that they need for,
uh,
you know,
the Iwatch or something.
So who knows,
I mean this is how big it is.
Two thirds the size of western Europe,
two thirds the size of western Europe.
Jesus Christ.
What does it look like in comparison to
the United States?
Had a picture
of it and covered about half of you,
but I think it was the demand,
the Dr of the Congo.
So I'm not sure if it's a different
side.
That's a fucking pretty heavy duty piece
right there.
Oh my God.
You know,
Midwest.
I definitely exaggerated,
but it's still unbelievably huge.
Just look at it goes from the bottom of
the United States all the way up to
Canada.
Um,
but only I would say like,
like a third of the size.
Slightly bigger than Alaska maybe.
Definitely.
The last one is pretty big too.
How about how much is it?
It's not really half.
Doesn't really have to me it looks more
like a third.
Like scroll down a little so we could
see it better.
Yeah.
That doesn't really live like half to me
does.
It looks like slightly.
Yeah,
slightly less than half.
Maybe 40 percent or something like that.
And almost 80 percent of people have
aids really sort of says 80 percent of
the people in the Congo have aids more
likely are likely to have HIV aids.
Wow.
Heavy duty.
If you go into the Condo,
the Congo where a condom,
right?
Well we knew that you got to wear the
full body condom,
like fucking naked gun.
It's just insane.
How to help diverse that part of the
world is like the amount of different
animals that exist in that one crazy
rain forest area.
They have all sorts of wild shit and
there we were looking at videos that
thing last night.
That shoe Bill Byrd,
that giant prehistoric looking dinosaur
bird that lives in the Congo to the one
with the long.
Yeah.
Crazy long hatchet face.
It's got like a.
like a long battle ax for face.
It's like a five foot tall bird or scary
fucking things.
Michigan chased down by one of those.
Yeah,
there it is.
Just two days in a row.
The shoe bill is made a look at that
fucking size of that thing.
Oh,
that thing looks crazy.
It just looks like he's demented.
One doesn't look nearly as tall as five
feet.
It's five feet as big as they get.
Look at the fucking eyes in that thing.
Mesh is given him a rat like that.
Stupid.
It is to idiot.
It's so dumb.
Just a dumb old dinosaur.
That's a dinosaur man.
I mean for real.
What are we looking at?
Is this a real animal?
Are you fucking shitting me?
This looks like Avatar.
This looks to be some Avatar Shit.
It really does.
The fact that that is a real animal.
This lady is feeding this animal rats
it.
It's gulping down mice and fish and
shit.
Look at this.
The face on that thing.
Look at Nice.
It's like fucking hatchet face from
crybaby.
It's fucking.
It's like,
I don't believe that.
You really can tell how intelligent
someone is if you look into their eyes,
but I do believe you can see when
something's dumb as fuck.
You know,
like you can't tell looking at somebody
how smart they are,
but you can definitely tell.
Looking at that thing,
there's not a whole lot going on.
There's like some simple wiring,
fuck that thing,
but Jesus Christ,
that's crazy.
Oh,
Jamie just pulled up a photo of this
bird has a pretty fucking amazing
looking dude.
Someone needs to make a horror movie
where these things just,
you know,
someone that lets him out of a lab in
Florida,
Florida University lab and they get out,
they start breeding and they start
talking to each other.
That looks like one of those angry birds
from the things from the game,
right?
They use one of those.
The eyes,
shit,
those dead eyes,
those dead dinosaur eyes.
Those eyes are the reason why.
That's fucking creepy.
Oh,
who the fuck out those eyes are?
The reason why we have houses and
weapons was houses.
The reason why we figured out fire and
communication,
it's we had to figure out how to knock
it eaten,
eaten by shit like that.
Look at that thing.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Now imagine that this is in the same
sort of vein as far as animals go,
is that Tara Byrd,
except it's considerably smaller where
that Tara Byrd was like seven feet tall
and lived in North America,
lived in North America while people were
alive.
These things were gi,
ent,
and they were running around like,
look at the photo of the soldier there.
Jamie.
Look at this.
Look how big these fucking things were.
What?
Yeah,
what the fuck these things lived while
people were alive,
right?
Gwen?
Did these terror birds exist?
Fuck that thing.
Just fuck that shit is crazy.
Look,
nine feet tall,
so nine foot tall,
giant fucking bird man.
And when did the thing live?
One point 5 million years ago.
Is that what it says?
That's not that long.
Does it say what's this say Jamie?
Fifteen or one point five.
Two point 5 million years.
Two point 5 million years ago.
All right,
well,
so that's definitely not people.
Someone was there.
Someone was there,
some silly monkeys.
Something was there,
but what?
What year do you think monkey started
figuring out how to start using weapons
and shit.
Like what year was it that they figured
out how?
Like the very first sub human hominid
that was smart as fuck.
That was figuring out how to like make a
weapon.
I would have to have been picking up
some sort of branch or some sort of rock
and throwing
it.
Maybe that's the first thought of using
a weapon.
No rock.
Maybe I would wonder if it would be that
or a stick to beat something with a
stick or to throw a rock like which
would be the first one they figured out.
But what do you.
What year do you think?
I mean,
I wonder how long it was ago that our
ancestors first started developing a
weapon,
like something to you to kill something
to eat or something defend themselves.
I'm looking a little farther.
There's some reports and from Uruguay
saying that these might be dated to
450,000 or 17,000 years ago.
Seventeen thousand years ago.
Still being debated.
That's what I entered the realm.
That's what I had heard it was.
Um,
uh,
I think I had heard it was like 35,000
years ago.
They think that some of them were living
in North America.
Well,
it's written in Spanish or something.
I can't get through that.
So
it was all pre ice age either way
because the ice age was 10,000 years
ago.
This whole motherfucker was just frozen
solid.
That's hard.
That's hard to imagine.
Listen,
I've,
I questioned everything.
I don't know what the fuck is going on.
Who knows what's happening,
but I like watching ancient aliens.
I do too.
I wish it was real.
I wish it was all real.
I wish it was to the right.
I hope they're right about a lot of
shit.
I would be so much more fun if aliens
had been here and contradict,
contacted us and left information.
It would be so much more fun to be
incredible then to actually be alive to
find that out.
I think it's.
It's totally possible that something
could get waste smarter than us and can
travel from some other place is also
totally possible that it's never
happened yet.
It's totally possible that people were
just full of shit.
It's also totally possible that our
experience on earth has been broken up a
bunch of times by huge disasters and I
think that this is one of the things
that this Guy Graham Hancock is trying
to prove and is doing a fantastic job.
Sort of documenting what the way he
describes it that were a civilization
with amnesia.
It's really interesting stuff,
man,
because he's.
He's saying essentially what probably
happened was human beings invented a
bunch of really cool shit,
developed a bunch of great technology,
had made sophisticated societies and
cultures,
and then boom,
a fucking rock from this guy comes down,
start over,
flattens everything,
kills a giant chunk of the people,
fucks up all the infrastructure,
chaos disorder,
and then things are fine for another few
hundred years and boom,
a new one hits and they're all
throughout Europe.
They've proven it now that this is
nuclear glass shit all throughout Europe
and in Asia as well.
Gentrification and it's all around
10,000 years ago.
Crazy is that.
It's unexplainable.
It's insane.
They think that that's what happened
that to 10 to 12,000 years ago they
this,
all of Europe was like pelted with
rocks.
It's fucking nuts and that people had to
start over after that and that all of
our stories about cataclysms and the
dough in the arc and all that shit about
keeping,
keeping societies alive,
whether it's like the epic of Gilgamesh,
all these different stories that are
real similar,
real similar tale of someone like trying
to keep humanity alive.
Face of this chaotic disaster.
All of those represent the same stories.
All those represents the things that
ended the fucking ice age rocks from
this guy 10,000 years ago.
Jamie.
Heavy Shit.
Too heavy for me.
You got me too high.
This fucking three joy's left.
Well,
that actually is for.
Oh we can't,
we can't keep going.
We'll forget what we already talked
about when we repeat ourselves.
We are a society with Amnesia.
Oh,
definitely wouldn't smoke in this kind
of.
We'd get all kinds of amnesia.
He says fire to know that about them.
So when you go in on these,
um,
these trips,
do you base these trips on like places
you want to eat and he bases trips on
your already tour in there and you say,
well fuck it.
Let's combine the two together.
Yup.
Pretty much.
You know,
like I get to go to cool places for
music.
I get to go to a lot of amazing
countries.
I've been to Africa,
I've been pretty much on love and not
yet,
not Asia yet,
all over Europe,
all over America.
And pretty much people want to take me
out to these restaurants because they
know I appreciate it.
They know what I'm about.
They threw my lyrics and through seeing
me and getting to know me on,
on that type of level where you almost
feel like,
you know me,
people feel like they,
they need to show me the right way in
their city.
I have to be taken care of,
you know,
and it's only right.
I like to be taken care of and you know,
I have an incredible team over advice
and munchies and Viceland that uh,
you know,
they get the job done.
They work well.
Once you start doing the Charlotte this,
then people start hearing about it.
Then you know,
you get all the people that are
contacting you with great suggestions
and it sort of makes itself like you,
you'll,
you'll figure it chart just based on all
these people trying to get you grow
their spots.
Right?
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
a lot of is organic though.
People are genuinely fans with the music
and genuinely fans of the show.
A lot of the times they don't want to
ask to be on it.
You know,
I,
I feel I see people,
you know,
throwing the little hints like come come
by,
you know,
bring the guys.
Is this something you planned out or is
it just like something that Sorta came
along?
It just seemed like a natural thing to
do.
Yeah,
it just came along.
You know,
I was,
I was filming,
I was getting filmed in the kitchen
cooking and it was like,
it was kind of cool.
I always,
you know,
growing up watching these shows being
fucking ever these dudes being rock
stars now.
I was like,
why can't I do that?
Look at fucking guy for Yeti theory.
Yet I go with my bath guy theory.
I'm setting with the and fietti is that
I suppose to say so,
right?
It's this little accent.
Look at him.
Look at this guy.
What?
What else is he going to do besides
nick?
What he does?
He can be in nickelback.
He could be a nickelback.
He could be in a.
What was the one?
I'm an all star.
He smashed me.
He looks like the lead singer of
smashmouth.
No.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Um.
Oh,
he's got it figured out.
His own spot.
Can you just scroll up for a second?
Go to the one with the flames on his
shirt to the right.
Yes.
He actually,
they were like,
get crazy while he was taking these
pictures and he did that and that's
forever.
It's just hilarious in time that he's
got such a crafted thing going on.
He's a Rockstar Rockstar Cook.
God,
let me ask you something.
Do you think tega night sky that ain't
no,
I.
that's what I'm saying.
Do you think that this is a shtick?
Like he's smart.
He decided to like make himself look.
You look at a guy like Donald Trump.
Everybody knows that he has this crazy
hair.
You don't think that Donald trump could
get a better haircut?
Oh yeah.
He plays into it for sure.
He's ridiculous.
It's part of his flair as that.
He's pulling it off with this goofy
haircut.
He's got billions of dollars and he's
got this hair helmet.
Same with Don King.
So legendary here.
Don King Man.
A lot of guys did that.
They looked.
They had like sort of a wacky look on
purpose.
Right?
I thought of this yesterday.
Is there a chance donald trump's
trolling and some sort of performance
piece for like A.
I think it's definitely.
I think Donald trump is a guy who has
full belief in his ability to run this
country.
Whether or not he can actually run the
I don't think it's an enact.
I think he has full belief that he can
do it.
It's.
It is bizarre city because it's a.
it's freaking people out,
but I think one of the more fascinating
things about this election is how people
are so freaked out that he's.
He's pretty much in command right now.
This thoughts,
there's like panic that he could.
That is a possibility.
It could be the president.
Oh,
it's very likely if you think that
there's very likely.
I think if,
if things keep going the way they're
going right now,
it looks to me like he's going to be the
president or the others putting their
fucking foot in their mouth.
What is the issue?
Why is he shining?
I don't understand.
Is it the Internet age?
Is that the social media age that's
making this guy into this figure?
Almost like the Jordan face,
the Jordan,
the meme.
It's like an iconic thing.
Do you know about to pull up the Jordan?
Donald trump is becoming the fucking
Jordan face man.
The crying Jordan.
Well,
here's the thing.
When people looked for someone to be
president,
whether it's rational or not,
they look towards someone who they think
is going to be a leader of the crying
Jordan face.
Yeah.
That's like the,
Oh,
they put it on everybody's,
if you fuck up,
you get to crying Jordan face people
look towards someone that they want to
be a leader.
And the problem with Donald trump is
that he said a bunch of ridiculous stuff
about like Mexicans and in some,
some stuff that like not measured stuff
about Muslims coming into this country,
not measured and rational and,
and you know,
it was way too showbizzy,
you know what I mean?
He's the guy with the Mexicans.
They will shut the country down.
Restaurants will be closed.
It'll be over.
Yeah.
Things will be done.
Yeah,
very likely.
Plus they're nice.
They're great people.
We're not having a lot of problems with
Mexicans.
Like this idea that Mexicans are causing
all these problems.
If they were really causing them any
problems,
we would have a lot more problems
because there's a lot of Mexicans all
they ever do,
they just want to come over to the
country so they can make money to send
home to their family.
I worked with guys that literally slept
and Shit,
hold rooms just so they could send their
salary that $300,
$400 from washing dishes or fucking week
back home for their family,
their lives of the people that you want
to keep out of the country.
Like the,
the,
the honest,
the working men riding his bike back and
forth to work every day in the fucking
snow,
rain,
whatever.
You know.
It's upsetting.
I worked close with these guys.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Well you kitchens right,
and kitchens.
Yes.
Mexican guys want to pee and chefs and
incredible ones too and know that you
could teach them any cuisine.
It's just um,
it's just unfortunate that he would say
things like that and that people will
respond the way they responded.
You know,
people got kind of excited that someone
is filing a close the wall,
you know,
close the borders and just fucking snow
people out there.
They all come out when you know,
the freaks come out at night.
Well,
it's just this bad people in every group
and every group and the idea that these
people,
because there
are more poor and because they're,
they got stuck in this one spot,
they should be,
they should be trapped there forever
even though it's connected to us by
dirt.
I mean there's like a clear path between
us and Mexico right there and we have to
stop people from walking across to get
jobs.
Like imagine if Americans,
if you made them walk across the desert
to get jobs.
Yeah,
right.
How few of us would be employed if you
had a walk across the yard to get in the
river.
He had a fucking way to cross the river.
It'd get to the other side,
holding your baby over the rapids and
then once you get to the side you got to
climb a wall and then you've got to walk
across the desert and then you gotta
find a job.
What?
You don't have a job for me when I get
there.
No,
no,
no.
You better know somebody too because you
know you can't speak their language.
What?
Yeah,
I'm going to live somewhere where they.
They don't speak my language.
Do you want money or not?
Okay,
I'll do it.
No one's going to do it.
No American do it.
You know he's fucking kids coming out of
college today.
There's no jobs.
There's younger generations.
Fucked the wall.
Just got 10 feet higher.
Is this is new statement a couple of
days ago after he wants something.
Oh my God.
He's hilarious.
It's hilarious.
The president of Mexico yesterday,
or the experts prize,
whatever,
whoever,
who cares?
He said,
we will not even consider paying for the
wall.
You have to understand because.
Okay,
you ready?
Who's going to pay for the wall?
Who?
Oh my God,
a hundred percent.
So I get a call from one of the
reporters yesterday and they said,
the president of Mexico said they will
not under any circumstances pay for the
wall.
They said to me,
what is your comment?
I said,
the wall just got 10 feet higher.
True,
true.
He fucked it up with the.
It's true.
He should have laid back on that.
Had a strong delivery.
It.
He had a strong delivery.
Just panics while I was getting the
chairs.
He got hired.
That's how you can tell he's a fucking.
He's not presented prime for the spot.
What the fuck?
That's your hype right there.
When he heard the collapse.
That is crazy that a guy can say
something like that.
Like that is so not measured.
Did you see that?
Uh,
please clap moment with Jeb Bush.
No.
And it pretty much ruined him and he's
now out of the race.
Know what happened.
I'll show it to you.
He,
he's given a speech somewhere and,
and uh,
he gets this real riled up moment and
he's waiting for an applause break and
it doesn't come.
So he literally says to the crowd,
please clap.
Oh my God.
Oh,
the poor bastard gracious.
Oh fuck.
He's probably so happy to be out of it.
Have the back the military.
I won't trash talk.
I won't be a divider in chief or an
agitator in chief.
I won't be out there.
Blow harden talking to big,
big game without backing it up.
I think the next president needs to be a
lot quieter,
but send a signal that we're prepared to
act in the national security interests
of this country to get back in the
business of creating a more peaceful
world.
Please clap.
Oh,
I thought that was humorous.
I actually thought that was humorous.
It wasn't terrible.
I thought that was humorous when the way
he did that,
I thought he was like.
It was awkward.
I saw an older guy in a Yamaka,
so a bunch of really old people there.
Maybe they just didn't catch it at the
time.
I thought he was being funny.
I mean,
I would think that that would be a good
way to end it.
You say please clap.
No,
but maybe I'm just optimistic.
He's definitely not the guy.
You just.
You can't talk like that and be the guy.
You know what focus is.
Fuck.
That seemed like.
I think he probably saw what happened to
his brother,
saw what happened to his dad and he was
like,
fuck,
this will be different.
And they're trying to put.
No,
I think they're trying to push them into
a job.
It doesn't really want.
I don't think he really wanted to be
president.
Just didn't seem like it to me.
Just to be a carpenter like Bernie
Sanders seems to want to be president.
I believe it.
I'm convinced Hillary Clinton wants to
be president.
I'm convinced trump wants to be
president for sure.
How about that Rubio guy?
Because he want to be president.
Chris Christie didn't want to be
president.
No Way.
No fucking way.
Just fucking scumbag.
Is He?
How dare you,
Izzy?
I'm not really sure.
This is what I hear.
I don't really know politics.
Yeah,
that's all I need to know this.
The judge judges spoken.
Yeah.
I just don't know.
I don't know what's going to happen in
this country.
If that guy wins,
that's going to be very weird.
like someone who could say shit like
that winds.
Wow.
Who knows,
man.
What would happen if he got into office
and then immediately gave like a calm,
sober presentation and explained that he
did what he had to do to win,
but he's absolutely serious about being
the president
whenever,
if that's possible.
America is pretty liberal.
I feel like.
Give him a shot.
He hit the wall.
Just got 10 foot higher.
Like what?
What?
Is this?
An episode of a movie as of a movie.
He's a sick fuck.
Yeah,
he is.
He's a sick fuck.
He says anything you sick like 100
percent.
He has one of the littlest dicks in the
world.
There's no doubt about that.
I can't believe what I'm hearing and
tell how he's talking.
First of all,
say allegedly.
Allegedly.
He has one of the tiniest.
Piney is a micro penis.
I don't think that's the case.
I bet he's got a giant hog.
Think so.
I bet.
It's shocking.
That's why he's so confident.
I bet he pulls it out and when he bought
the fucky showing me and he bought it,
there's no doubt realistic nude painting
of Donald Trump will make you gouge your
eyes out.
Okay.
I don't know what you're putting up
there.
Jamie came up.
I thought that's where he got it.
I don't know.
I just.
Just by his actions,
by the way,
he,
you know,
he's fine.
He definitely has micro penis syndrome.
I bet he's got a giant hug.
I.
He's too cocky,
but that's the thing.
If he has one,
he fucking bought it.
It was one of those where you have to
fucking pump you're nuts,
you know,
to,
to.
True,
true,
true.
It's like a Turkey.
Basically.
You keep at puppet up.
Can you all the Mexican actors?
Got It from the soap operas.
All of them.
That's what I heard.
I was looking into this for when I get
older.
That was the liberace had the
mechanical,
mechanical pump,
like the Reebok pump.
It was in the movie.
Did you ever see that movie?
The Hbo Movie?
Who?
Wait?
Who was he was.
It was?
No,
it was Michael Douglas and Matt Damon.
It was called something that candle
opera beyond beyond the candle opera.
Is that what it was?
It was fucking amazing.
Really.
Liberace was freak.
It was amazing.
It's so good.
First of all,
Michael Douglas can act as ass off,
man.
He's a good.
He's falling down.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
One of my favorites,
but this one,
for whatever reason,
I think they made it for hbo or maybe
they just sold the dates,
pof.
They made it.
They might've finance it themselves.
I don't know what happened,
but it was incredible behind the
Candelabra Oh wow.
It's so good,
man.
I looked incredible,
so fucking good.
And Matt Damon was his boyfriend and
it's just like,
Holy Shit,
I'm going to have to watch this for sure
dude.
He was a freak.
It's fucking great.
He made his boyfriend get surgery to
look more like him.
How about that?
Wow.
His boyfriend was this handsome guy and
he made his boyfriend and fuck his chin
up to be like more like liberace.
Chin.
Got It man.
I'm good.
His Chin done.
Dude.
That's fucking sick.
That's love it more.
No,
no,
I'm good.
Just keep coughing.
You're in a constant state of marijuana.
I enjoy it pretty much all day.
Yeah,
for sure.
Do you take days off?
Yeah,
but how many a year?
Not many.
Five Year.
No,
no,
I,
I don't know,
less than a year,
man.
Maybe not really sure.
I think this,
this year
I took off,
I think maybe to two days because I had
surgery,
but then I was right back at it.
I would think that would probably be
good for reducing inflammation.
Causes coughing is no good when you was
stomach,
you know,
so the coughing is.
Oh,
this is when you had hernia.
Yeah.
That,
that's a,
that's a super common injury man.
This shit happened in Alaska to.
Oh yeah,
it was crazy.
I was in Alaska doing a performance and
um,
I was playing NBA Jam against my boy and
he was the supersonics and he just
fucking dunked on me and I got upset and
I felt something in my stomach and jam.
The video game.
Tournament edition hernia playing NBA
Jam.
The video game.
How fucking crazy you want to talk
about?
Ironic.
That's the layer I was the knicks.
He was the sonics that I wasn't happy.
That's wow.
Yeah,
it might be.
I might be the only one to ever get a
hernia from playing a video game.
I doubt it.
No,
Nah,
I bet people have died.
I bet.
I bet they've contorted themselves.
Slipped,
broken their head open on the coffee.
Yeah.
People have died.
Played millions ways of dying.
Yeah.
Getting a hernia,
Africans.
You're freaking out.
That's a slight injury in comparison to.
I'm sure some of the shit that people
try avoid things.
They fall and fall out a window and fall
16 stores their death guarantee you shit
has happened.
You're right.
I've heard about these things.
Yeah.
People.
Ridiculous.
I'm going to stay away from fucking
windows.
Yeah.
Don't go near windows while you're
playing video games.
Don't.
Don't blow it.
Your Hernia.
Now deaths please.
If you haven't had a hernia surgery and
you're like,
Oh man,
fuck.
I don't want to get it operated on man.
I'm scared.
It'll take me out.
How much does it take you out?
Takes you out for a couple of months.
Does it mean you'll never feel?
I don't know.
I guess it's not like I could go back
and start power lifting right now.
It's just not going to happen.
How long has it been since surgery?
Uh,
had in November.
So a few months,
so I feel good and like now I feel good.
So now you're at the point where it
feels normal.
Yeah,
that's good.
I feel normal.
So you would recommend it to someone
that also has had a hernia.
A hernia?
Yeah.
Just chill out.
Get that surgery.
Absolutely.
If you,
if you have the umbilical one in the
stomach.
Yeah.
You hear that Doug?
Stand up,
get yourself stitched up,
bitch.
You know,
you always fucking walking around,
pushing your stomach in and it's
fucking.
It's not cute.
Especially if you have the other one.
Fucking your intestines go into your nut
sack.
It looks like you got elephant titus.
Yeah.
My friend Eddie had it and he used to
have to push down on his abdomen when he
would talk.
Like he was talking loud because it pop
out.
Yeah.
It's one of the worst things ever.
For feel like if you're in a loud place,
you know,
Jack jackhammers going off,
he would literally have to push his hand
into his abdomen to like keep it
compressed and go.
Not performed.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
I performed for three,
two or three years already with that
wiping out.
Oh my God.
It was crazy.
I don't know how to fuck it.
Oh,
so you waited a long time before you got
it fixed.
Now I got to fixing it.
It broke once.
Oh,
now to get it done again.
They put a plugin so you.
All right,
so say the.
The cut is about.
I mean the,
the hole in your stomach is about an
inch or whatever.
They put an inch of Mesh over it.
It's obviously going to fucking burst
again.
You have to cover it with a little bit
bigger piece.
So that's what the Alaskan doctor did.
Oh,
so you had a shitty doctor?
I had a shitty doctor in Queens.
I love.
I tell this story all the time.
I'm in the fucking waiting room first.
I shit myself because I don't know what
they gave me.
Second of all,
they made them clean me.
Third of all,
I'm on the operating room about to get
put under fucking guy goes to doctor Yo,
you know who that is?
My Dick is so shriveled because I'm
scared.
I'm scared that I'm holding the blanket
above my stomach.
Obviously I'm going to get knocked out,
so I'm like,
ah,
fuck.
I thought that they were going to take
pictures of my shriveled Dick.
That was the last store that I had
before going under surgery.
Think about that.
How rude blew my mind.
How rude.
Debbie.
Yeah.
Well you gotTa,
you know,
people could definitely do that.
I'm saying it were terrible people.
Whatever.
If if they did that,
would I have grounds to sue for
defamation of character?
Definitely.
Because I wasn't at my finest.
No.
Poor representation of your horse.
Exactly.
Joe was terrible.
Why know that people have.
There's definitely been people that have
gotten in trouble for doing terrible
shit to like dentists doing terrible
shit to their patients when they're
under.
I heard about that from the Jerky boys
years ago.
It pulled my bow,
wake up with my badge down.
That shit.
The jerky boys,
people forgot.
Forgot how funny some of those fucking
recordings where Frank Rizzo says little
chest.
Those were funny man.
These young kids,
if you've never heard of the jerky boys
go and listen.
They would call people up and pretend
that things were going on.
Greg Fitzsimmons did some of those.
He did some of his own and he did one of
them where he called this rental car
company with like this heavy Boston
accent.
It was telling them the card they rented
was on fire and he's getting
cars on fire.
His fucking solly we went to the fucking
gas station.
His asshole didn't bring the fucking gas
tank.
So we had pots and pans filled with
gasoline and the Qa people are going
what?
You had pots and pans filled with and
the car that
you listen,
the Kas on fire.
You got to get over here.
Frank calls are always good Chinese
restaurants,
wherever you could call.
What do you remember?
Um,
Jimmy Kimmel had a television show.
Cranky anchors.
Oh,
you remember that?
Yup.
And it was all prank calls done with
sock puppets.
I remember it was funny as a flood,
it was funny you could,
you use to be able to do stuff like that
in Vegas.
Like Nevada had like a different rule.
Like you could use people's calls for
something like that.
Whereas he can't in California,
you'd have to tell them,
hey,
I'm going to use this,
I'm going to record this call.
And then everything after that,
you could use anything before you said
that you couldn't use it would be under
admissible inadmissible.
Excuse me.
Inadmissible.
Yeah.
I mean,
I know there's a lot,
you know,
I've been caught out there like baby
mother trying to start drama with me
over the phone,
have me on three way and I say some
crazy shit.
And then like six of a fucking family
members here,
boy,
that should be inadmissible in life to
set up.
You want the freedom to say crazy shit.
I mean at the end of the day,
like if you provoked me,
it's funny because there's two ways of
looking at it,
right?
So like you want the freedom freedom to
say crazy shit.
She wants everybody to know how fucking
crazy you really are.
That's true.
So she wants to have people listening to
you.
You know how crazy this mother fucker is
screaming and yelling.
And she's like,
see,
I told you,
yeah,
I'm an asshole.
Well,
pretty much.
I'm a fucking asshole.
Do you?
Would you want to change?
Do you want to come to Jesus moment?
Uh,
no.
No.
You're happy with who you are.
I'm ecstatic.
You don't seem like an asshole right
now.
It seemed very friendly.
Thank you man.
Appreciate that.
Were high.
That helps.
But I wasn't when we came here and we
started playing pool.
Very nice guy.
I was all right.
A nice guy.
Yeah,
I'm decent.
I'm,
I'm all right.
Once you get to know me,
you won't like me anymore.
No,
really?
Nah.
I'm a good guy.
No,
I think you're a good guy.
I am.
How high are you right now?
I'm not that way.
I'm high,
but you know,
I'm like,
I'm normal level.
I feel like we were getting trapped with
the first few sentence.
Three words of the sentences were saying
and they,
we're committed to these sentences and
we don't know exactly what we're going
to say when we started talking.
So we're making it up as we go along
that high.
That's how high we are right now.
Shit.
All this about.
Good guy.
Bad Guy shed.
You don't even know what you're talking
about and neither do.
I have no clue.
I have no idea what's going on.
So don't commit us to any of these
quotes.
Latest Jello and that's my point.
Leave action alone.
He's not a bad guy.
I'm a great guy.
Good Pool player to man.
Not a play.
Some pool.
You got a good grip on the queue.
I'm decent.
I'd.
It used to be better.
I could tell.
He definitely,
uh,
have,
more than casual understanding of how to
play for sure.
I was still,
I spent some time in pool halls and
queens,
you know,
stood on the wall.
Those places are important for sure.
That dying out stopped billiard fucking
millennium billiards on Fannie Lou
Boulevard with the Asians,
with the fucking polo shirt,
with a collar,
popped Asians with the collar blue light
blue motherfuckers having drag races on
the Strip and the mustangs civics.
Acuras it.
Chelsea billiards in New York.
There was always a lot of like really
strong Asian players that gambled a lot.
Oh,
for sure.
Go in there talking mad shit.
There was a bunch of these dudes that
were really colorful guys in the pool
community that were these Asian cats,
Koreans,
uh,
one guy was like,
one guy was Chinese.
It's one Korean dude though.
Gambled like crazy.
You need to come in and talking mad
shit.
And he was just like that Polo shirt on
looking preppy going right into the
heart of the jungle and the pool
culture,
which was Chelsea billiards.
Yup.
That's crazy man.
They to find a culture.
It's,
I dunno,
Asians in general.
I feel like they're good at like
precision games.
Definitely good at pool.
Yeah.
Some of the best players in the world
are Asian.
That,
that girl,
the black widow.
Yup.
She's incredible.
There's a bunch of guys,
Kopi men,
so I think he's from Taiwan,
a bunch of guys from Taiwan that are
really good.
Lot of a lot of Asians,
especially Filipinos,
Filipinos.
That's pretty much the number one
country of the United States have like
the greatest pool players ever.
Really?
Yeah,
for one spot.
It's tough to fuck.
With the Philippines,
they have like some of the all time
greatest just from one,
you know,
it's a bunch of islands.
I think it's like a thousand islands,
right?
Yeah.
Isn't it crazy?
But uh,
a gang of them come from the
Philippines.
The US Gis apparently dropped pool off
over there when they were in like world
war.
What was it to World War Two,
they were in the Philippines.
They brought pool tables over to
entertain the Gis and that's apparently
how Filipinos got involved in pool.
That's allegedly the story that the
pool,
the pool community a says,
well in Vietnam seems like the Gis
brought funk music to fucking Vietnam
and Thailand and all those,
like wherever they were because there's
some funky mother fucking music that
comes from the seventies and in the
Vietnamese like Vietnamese.
So music that sounds like motherfuckers
from Harlem of playing,
you know.
Wow.
Incredible stuff.
And it's in their language,
which is even crazier because it sounds
amazing.
What is,
give me a name of something,
just look up Vietnamese or Thai.
Pop were Vietnamese funk.
There's this one specific,
um,
album,
I think it's called Saigon Rock.
It's pretty next level.
There's a picture of a woman on it on
the cover.
I'm going to find that.
I find that.
I love.
There it is.
Bam.
Jam on the ball.
Saigon Rock and managed to establish
some of those.
Oh my God.
Nineteen 68 to 19.
Holy Shit.
Wow.
Whoa.
That's just.
Sounds crazy.
Wow.
I was listening to,
uh,
this,
I don't speak Spanish and I don't.
Obviously I don't speak Vietnamese
either,
so when I'm listening to that,
it gives me this,
uh,
it gives you like a little extra kind of
cooled charge to it if you don't even
know what the fuck they're saying and
you're trying to,
you try to mimic it.
There's,
I'm just making noises that sound like.
What does Joey Diaz is band Jamie Cho
ideas.
His nephew's ban or his,
his cousins band.
Is it x off?
I've got them on my,
uh,
my music here somewhere.
I'm trying to find it though.
Would they?
Um,
they had there a.
I'm a band out of Cuba.
Is Joey's families out of Cuba?
X,
Alfonso Mal Fonzo?
I think it's x though.
No Bueno Vista Social Club?
No.
Well that's one of them.
But uh,
there's uh,
the um,
the band that they're in is X.
Alfonso.
This is from his twitter is where I got
that.
Oh,
that's his cousin.
Yeah.
The band that this I haven't seen,
but there's a band that I was listening
to.
It's called x Alfonso.
They are fucking bad ass dude.
Oh my God.
They're bad.
And I don't know what they're saying.
It's,
it's just,
it's really cool because when you're
listening to it,
these are guess joe is cut.
His cousins may not loose
in the bottom and the bottom here you
comments and I says,
all I know is xcel fonts,
so thank you.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Someone asked him what the name of his
cousins rock band was.
All I know is xcel font.
So that's just a couple of years ago
too.
Okay.
Um,
so I guess that's his cousin,
but whatever,
man,
they're fucking bad ass.
They're cool too because I like
listening to stuff like this when I
write because I don't know what the fuck
they're saying.
It's just cool.
You know,
I don't,
I don't have to like follow their
narrative.
I get just enjoy it.
I can just enjoy the sound of it,
you know?
Absolutely.
I agree.
Yes.
This is a more of a traditional song,
like they have some crazy wild rock and
roll shit.
See if you can find like,
I don't want to give people the wrong
impression.
Like what kind of music they have
because I fucking speak Spanish.
I understand what they're saying here.
See if he could find revert.
Yeah,
revert.
This is a really cool video to the is
really amazingly shot,
like really bright graphics and
so what they're doing is they're playing
this song forward and backward.
Did you fast forward it to like deep
into the song about 30 seconds.
Interesting.
Shit.
So this is Joey Diaz,
his cousins.
So I guess it's fucking talent and
mjeans.
Have you been to Cuba yet?
Nope.
Are you going to go?
I would like to.
I want to go there before it becomes a
tourist trap.
Yeah.
As soon as four g lte gets there,
it's over.
It's over.
I don't want to be able to use my phone.
Well,
you can use it in some spots apparently.
Apparently there's some spots where you
can go where you could use your phone.
Fucking whack.
It's weird,
but I want them to have phones.
I'm torn.
You know,
phones are phones won't work is if their
phones don't work.
That's true.
So yeah,
they should have phones now that now
that to my attention in that manner,
they should definitely have phones,
but there seem to be.
They did.
They put together a pretty amazing
culture without it.
Shit.
No,
it's legendary.
It's classic.
Look at the architecture and all those
colors and old cars.
The old cars.
Yeah,
just a musical.
If you watch that winter,
this social club stuff and that
documentary,
it's really mind blowing.
It's is actually very beautiful.
The music that they make is unreal.
It's unbelievable.
And just the way it's shot is like
magical.
Yeah.
They,
they definitely have a sound in the
style of their own and to think that all
of that was taking place over the last,
you know,
50 or so years,
just 90 miles away from us.
We had no idea and on top of that
they're like,
we weren't even allowed to visit for for
50 years.
We were kept from going to a spot and
with no reason that makes any sense were
kept from going where you could get in
trouble,
man.
Like in the 19 eighties,
if you traveled to Cuba,
you could get in fucking trouble.
The big daddy government told you where
you could visit.
Think about that.
You could go to Africa,
you go to the Congo,
they wouldn't give you a hard time,
but if you go to Cuba,
they could lock you up just for
visiting.
I want to see what it's like over there.
I want to see some people not allowed.
You can't it?
That's the most ridiculous thing ever.
It's sick.
There's no reason like you,
it's not for your own safety because
there's some super dangerous spots you
can go visit right now.
You know?
No one,
no one's going to stop you from flying
Iraq,
Nicaragua.
No one's going to stop you from flying
to a lot of places in this world that
are in terrible,
terrible state of civil unrest.
You could just go.
He can go a Cuba.
No.
Yeah.
Can't go to Cuba,
but we can now.
It was Russia's fault.
Fucking Russia.
I like Russia.
That was there last year.
They went hard at us to give it a shot.
It was really great to tell you the
truth.
Yeah,
it was a fucking very great place.
But Gray,
like the Weatherman,
like the color with the weather,
like the way it looked outside.
Yeah,
like not nice.
Like No.
No sunshine you.
And it was,
it was sunny out and it was definitely
not sunshine.
It was a hard place was you could tell
there was hard times.
They breed some hard fucking people.
Some fucking Joel has been that.
Joe's a fucking defined some of the
scariest MMA fighters ever fatal.
Yup.
And uh,
out of Dagestan Dagestan is another
place where just developing these
killers,
this,
this guy kid his fights in the UFC kid.
Man.
Man Gentlemen,
Habib number got madoff.
He's an ad monster.
Monster Animals.
Ridiculously good.
Grappler.
Just just destroyer.
So fucking so good.
Think about the all fucking old men over
there.
Just fucking wrestling all day long and
the bond and the fucking wet and the
cold.
So all told with this show,
do you have a deal to do it for a
certain amount of time?
Are you just doing it for as long as you
enjoy it right now?
It feels like it feels like it could be
going on for a long time.
If it hits,
I feel like it's gonna.
People are gonna.
Enjoy it as entertainment.
You know what I'm saying?
Shit.
You're just to view if it's nearly as
good as your instagram page with the
photos of it.
It's good.
What was
the slight instagram pages?
Light work.
What was the steak that you ate that you
have in your instagram that like age for
seven months.
That was at my man.
Mario Batali steakhouse in Vegas where
you need to go because you're there a
lot.
Seven months,
seven months,
right in the Venetian.
That's insane.
Carnevalino,
how do you do that?
How do you age something for seven
months?
He just leave it to you.
Just leave that shit there and it
becomes blue.
All that.
That was a good picture.
Chris grow.
So my producer took that picture,
man.
Oh Shit.
So that's Ribeye.
That was 70 day aged in like what's the
temperature when they know that?
Seven,
that seven months,
seven months,
not 70 days.
That's a premature child.
I don't want believe it.
I don't want to believe it.
Seven months.
What's the temperature?
They put it out.
They fucking grill it.
Very,
very hot.
No,
I mean to keep it to aging.
The aging,
I would.
I think that it was.
They wouldn't tell you exactly,
but I would imagine it's in between in
the forties,
really 30 to 40 has it not turned into
just rot because there's so much fat cap
on it that the fat protects it and the
meat just rots inside and all that fatty
tissue breaks down and just becomes
nutty and unbelievably fucking
delicious,
you know,
and deep and incredible depth of flavor
and developing all this earthiness and
it's this Umami flavor you can't really
explain,
but when you eat it,
it just melts and it's like,
what the fuck is going on?
Whoa.
Yeah.
Seven months of rot.
To me it's like that.
If that wasn't real and we found out
that the Romans used to do that.
Oh,
they didn't be like,
of course,
but I'm not with refrigeration.
If we just found out that they used to
do it,
we'd be like,
what in the fuck are these assholes
doing?
They would let them meet rot away for
seven months so that they could slice a
sliver off the inside and presented and
present that.
I mean,
how much meat goes to waste when lot.
There's a lot of waste in like what
percentage you think maybe 30 to 40
percent of the product because the bone
is huge and then the meat is just meat
is like this.
That's how much missed?
About five inches long and paused and
three inches wide out of the whole cow
at the Ribeye.
That's that rebuts the fucking read.
It has the big ass bone.
It has that thick as fat.
They have to cut off so they must lose a
substantial amount of me.
That shit is like a fucking $200 an
inch.
Wow.
So that's like the worst ecofriendly
meet ever.
But it's sublime.
Sublime tasting.
It's like.
It's bizarre how far people will go out
of their way to try to like rig the
perfect steak.
Something like this where you're letting
some meat sit for seven months.
That means they had to take it up until
like a year and then they back off.
We can't eat this shit.
Now there's this 12 months,
there is 12 month men.
How big is it?
They serve it to you.
It's,
it's,
it's.
Yeah.
It's about the same thing.
It's a little.
It's a little bit smaller than that,
but the last remaining cells that
haven't turned to total shit,
exact area and the new aids runs rampant
through your cooler and that is the most
delicious bite of food on the planet.
Apparently.
God,
according to these motherfuckers and I
just had that the seven month there's
like food like you can't believe,
and so there's a big difference between
the five,
the seven month and five months later.
One hundred percent are you fucking
kidding me?
How much better is the one that's a year
you need to try it.
I haven't tried that one yet,
but I feel that it's going to be very.
You can't have too much to the size of
like a flip phone portion.
Not the smaller one.
The smaller one.
Oh,
smaller iphone.
But like I said,
they're going to give you like a quarter
inch or half finished piece because it's
too old.
It's like eating a whole thing of blue
cheese.
White in one bite.
Oh,
it's like the amount of bacteria.
No,
no.
I'm saying like the taste.
I love blue cheese.
Almost.
Tastes like you're eating silver.
Oh yeah.
You know what I mean?
Because it's fucking fungus.
Exactly.
That's,
and I love that shit.
I love that.
I love Funky Shit.
Cheese.
We were in Paris eating two year old,
three year old,
eight year old cheeses.
Boy She used.
That's been buried and shit.
Hey,
all kinds of craziness.
You have the Paris folk.
I've really figured out a way to make
that stuff stink.
It stinks.
Love.
They love that stuff.
Know that was like one of the main
ingredients we used to use on fear
factor to make things smell worse.
Cheese,
expensive cheese.
Rarely.
Yeah.
They would go to um,
they would go to like a place in beverly
hills where they have like a,
just a giant selection of the grossest
rankest fucking funkiest cheeses.
We opened the cart and you're like,
what the fuck?
And it's super expensive and that stuff,
I don't remember what it was called.
They would throw that stuff in the
blenders to make like bugs smell worse.
No wonder they fucking threw up all the
tabs there and just start throwing up.
Yeah.
The bugs itself was not nearly as bad as
bugs blended in with cheese,
a funky ass cheeks.
The smell was just,
especially if you didn't know what
you're doing,
like if you smell certain cheeses,
if you didn't know what you were eating,
you'd be like,
what the fuck,
get this out of here.
But because you know it as a pleasant
taste to,
you know it's cheese.
Your brain goes,
yeah,
oh this smells funky.
Like you'll smell some.
Some really weird cheesy like,
oh wow,
yeah woo.
But then you eat it like,
whoa.
Oh,
you feel that,
that interesting flavors in your mouth.
So you associate with a good thing.
Even though it smells funky.
There's lot of cheese that had literally
smelled like six day old nut sack,
you know?
And but like fat,
nuts,
sag.
Like when you're overweight like mine
and it's not pleasant and it's.
But once you get down to it,
taste is very sweet.
Yeah.
The task is my nut.
Sack of pattern.
How dare you.
I'm listening.
I got to get the fuck out of here.
Let's get outta here.
I gotta go eat something.
I,
I can't.
I have players going into Ketosis,
family stuff I have to do.
No wait,
when are you going into.
You're going into the other one.
What's the other way?
I don't want to go into it.
You don't want to know what the other
one is one.
You don't want to go into whatever the
one,
the Carbo one.
Psychosis.
A Action Bronson.
Thank you very much sir.
Thank you.
It was fun.
It's cool hanging with you.
Grabbed one guy.
Good Times.
And uh,
your show.
If people want to watch it,
how can they catch it?
Fuck,
that's delicious.
It's all over the Internet right now.
Go to youtube.
Type in fuck.
That's delicious.
Type in my name.
Action Bronson.
Google me.
Action motherfucking Bronx.
February 29th.
Viceland launches were taking over
history to channel.
So we're going to be all over the place.
March,
Third Thursdays.
10 o'clock.
Fuck.
That's delicious on cable.
Every network possible.
You understand me?
I understand you.
Thank you sir.
Thank you.
Thank you brother.
Tonight,
tomorrow,
Duncan trussell.
Tomorrow.
See you later.