Bam,
Bam.
We live cool.
Beautiful.
We don't need no fucking stinking music.
We don't need it,
man.
We've got us.
Yeah.
We were just discussing referee's
letting guys get choked unconscious.
It's only Egypt.
Educate that dude from
this previous weekend.
Yeah.
We,
I think I'm some guys who
never been choked out.
I think that's one thing.
Even if you,
uh,
you don't,
have a martial arts background,
you can be in referee.
You're aware of that,
right?
You can be,
yes,
you can be a referee.
All you have to do is
understand what's going on.
You take like referee
classes and you'll learn.
You can start out taking referee
classes as a complete total novice.
I think you should have,
I think as a ref you should have at least
been choked out once and been knocked
out once.
I mean,
Herb Dean had a profile.
I think he had several profiles,
couple and herb dean roles all the time.
Herb deans,
a real martial artist,
Mario Yamasaki black belt.
So it was John McCarthy.
He's a black belt in Jujitsu.
All those guys that we fee just so his,
um,
uh,
Josh who's in jail right now.
Gotcha.
I'm pretty sure he's out.
Josh has very high level brown belt.
He knows his shit.
If you're a vendor stripe white belt,
you know what the Hell's going on?
A little bit.
Especially on a rear naked choke.
I don't think it was a Doris or
something of a hit and you can't see,
well he was face up to,
it was a real naked face up.
So it wasn't like,
you know,
it like sometimes guys get choked out
and the guys on top of them and they have
their back and they got a belly down
and you can't see the guy's face.
But when the guy's face up and
you're looking at his eyes,
Jesus had,
what are you doing?
Yeah,
he was out for a couple seconds.
You know,
sometimes people just
don't make good decisions,
you know,
they just,
they error.
It's not that they're bad people,
it's just the earth.
It doesn't work.
And in that case,
look,
if I fuck up,
it's not good because a bunch of people
are listening and they want the show to
be smooth and they're attaining.
But if I fuck up,
it's not that big a deal.
No one's getting hurt.
Right.
If this guy fucks up,
someone's going to get choked asleep,
you know,
that wouldn't get choked asleep or
someone's going to get beaten a few extra
times,
which can make a huge difference.
Then the beatings for sure.
I mean the good thing it was in a joint
manipulation submission because then
you're talking about someone's arm being
broken so they're just getting choked
out.
Well in that situation,
no,
don't you let the guy fight out of it.
Like I let a guy fight
out of a full arm bar.
Cause the way I would feel is that if
his arm pops that's on him and guys have
gotten their arms popped in one fights
for Jon Jones got his fucking arm popped
against v true.
If you watched it,
yes.
Did fuck yeah,
he got his arm completely
hyperextended yeah.
By then the trans whole body.
Dude,
it was bad.
This is probably a of,
well if we play the video of the podium,
there's,
there might be a picture of it.
You find that an image of it,
but at full extension it was completely
hyper extended the other way and John's
elbows fucked up for a long time after
that because I remember he had the,
uh,
coach,
the ultimate fighter and like that's
one of the things they said like,
well this is good anyway because you
can't really train right now because his
elbows fucked up from the Vituro fight.
So he will you in tab one of
the closest he's been to losing.
Huh?
Pretty.
Besides the decision
was that was Alexander,
but it's definitely the closest.
Yes,
probably he's been in for sure.
For sure.
That was a bad,
bad,
bad spot vi towards nasty dude.
You know,
a lot of people are taking him for granted
versus Weidman because the whole TRT
thing,
I don't fucking buy it,
man.
I don't buy it looks
good and it's pictures.
It looks way better than he used to.
Like there was a period after he got off
TRT where he deflated when we saw him
at those Wayne's,
he looked like a straight welter weight,
but it looks,
he looks a lot thicker now.
It looks way better.
So I know he's been doing a lot of,
uh,
they say that the way you
have to jumpstart your system,
one of the big ways you do
a lot of compound exercises
like cleans and presses,
forces your body to produce
less testosterone and estrogen.
Testosterone.
Yeah.
Big,
big things like he was
doing searcher squats,
which is where you know you like,
it's almost like you do a,
you put your hands
together like you're in,
make your arms,
like you're curling,
you put the Bar,
you hang it from your arms
and you do your squats.
Like that tough man on your core.
Yes.
Yeah,
yeah,
I do too.
So he's doing all that kind of crazy shit.
So,
you know,
I'm,
I'm hoping this is how it,
uh,
how he,
this is one idea how strong Jones is.
He's just so weird.
Strong.
He's ridiculous.
He's draw but veto or
caught it at a perfect spot.
You know,
he might've,
he might've been able to win the
fight if he didn't let up on it,
but I think he let up on it when it a
popsicle and he said he let up on it and I
believe him.
And then he got some instinctive.
Yep.
He got come Morad John Kamora him.
I mean after his arm got all fucked up.
So his right arm was all blown out and
he still uses it to a Kimora him later on
in the fight and then he's fucked
up for a while after that fight.
That was one of the
reasons why he a coast,
the ultimate fighter right there.
Well,
Chelsea had jail so he
just wasn't training.
Like he'd walk by him and Shelby training
twice a day I'll follow squat and John
and walked by Christmas clean.
Just nice and showered and like,
what is he training?
Maybe he wasn't.
It wasn't,
he wasn't.
Yeah,
just chill.
Said that's when he realized that
he's just not as good as John.
He's asking.
He said he got in there,
he said 30 seconds in.
He goes,
I want him to come out of that ring so
fast because I just couldn't believe how
strong he was.
Jon Jones Jones a Goddamn joke.
Now think about him and then think about
what Anthony Rumble Johnson versus him
is going to be like,
like that's going to be the
most chaotic God damn fights.
I that's not my number one fight all time.
All time.
Yup.
Dang.
That really has thank God.
Why?
Because he's got such a knockout power
and time makes a mistake and I'm,
because I've been thinking about it,
I've been thinking about all the great
matchups like there's been some great
match ups,
you know for sure like um,
like Bj Penn versus George Saint
Pierre when it first happened.
God Damn,
that was a big build up,
big match Tito chocolate delvers deal.
But those,
I had a pretty good sense
of what was going to happen.
I had a pretty good
sense cause they trained,
ESPN was too big.
I think GSP is too big.
It was too hot.
His wrestling was too good.
And I knew the beach.
I just didn't,
that was before the Marinovich has,
he didn't have that work ethic that he
has for a very short period of time when
Bj was in just insane shape,
like the Sean sherk fight,
he was in the same shape that
was actually before that.
But he was in insane shape for
that fight to Diego Sanchez fight.
He was a destroyer.
Kenny Florian.
Yeah.
Um,
who else?
There was a couple of other fights that
he had one who was in like the best
shape ever as a lightweight,
you know,
but when he bought a George,
I was like,
George is just too big.
This is just not the right file.
So this is for you.
This is the biggest one to me.
This is the one where I
don't know what the fuck.
First of all,
I think John is the greatest light
heavyweight champ of all time ever.
Right.
I agree.
And I think he's also still
growing and getting better.
That's what's scary.
Spectacular talent.
Cause he,
he just moved his entire camp to
Albuquerque because he used to live in New
York.
Now.
He bought a place in Albuquerque
and he's training full time now.
Yeah.
He was just going to
Albuquerque for camps.
Huh?
Y'all crazy.
That's going to be crushing me.
Comes after a beats Anthony
Rumble Johnson cane.
That's what he's got to go.
Right.
That's the question is if it's not after,
because I don't know what the fuck is
going to happen when Anthony Rumble
Johnson puts myths on you.
I don't know.
I don't know who's going to
be able to withstand that.
I don't see the problem is is John is so
much longer and the reach is a factor.
So I listen,
I thought Glover was going
to be an issue for unboxing.
Offered nothing because of that length.
It's tough to deal with.
Man.
Clover is very good.
I said Glover is like at a,
at a possible like standup challengers.
When I was looking him
coming in against John,
I was like,
he's got like really heavy hands,
especially really experienced,
especially at the time.
Well he took a step back.
He's not training with,
uh,
he wasn't training with
Hackleman for this last fight.
He did it all in Connecticut.
A lot of yeah.
And his own,
he had his own camp that he did down
there and a lot of people thought maybe he
wasn't prepared as when he fought John
Though there was a ton of hype in the UFC
pitch.
I'm like,
this is the guy chocolate
l signed off on it.
Dana White,
you know,
everyone I felt,
again,
I felt like it,
I mean I felt,
I feel like guys are as good as
they are in their best performances.
Right.
So like if you look at him
like his best performance,
like he gets clipped by
Ryan Bader in seconds later,
he puts Bader away.
Yeah.
You know,
you look at the way he,
uh,
beat up Kyle Kingsbury.
That was a scary guy.
Damn fight.
The Kyle Kingsbury fight was scary.
He just came out and he shows
you what the fuck he can do.
What you're like,
whoa.
And you know,
the Kyle Kingsbury who's a very
good athlete and a really cool guy,
wasn't at the best of the best.
He wasn't at that level.
You know,
he was dominated by,
um,
uh,
Pat Cummings had come into play recently.
Recently.
Yeah.
So it's,
you know,
there's levels and then,
Rumble Johnson as bad times at one 70.
But you got to think that a lot of that
had to do with him starving himself.
Sure.
And when you're looking at
him as a light heavyweight,
you know,
the way he fucking destroyed Nogueira I
was just like Jesus and then taken out
Gustafson like that in the first round.
Well that although I wonder,
because he did Headbutt Gusta
Synagis and fell to his knees.
Roof slate looks like
you're wonder at that point.
Cause I,
I mean Gustin is still killer and I don't,
I don't know,
we just didn't get a
chance to really see it,
you know?
Yeah,
definitely a factor.
But she'll be effective for both men.
Right?
I mean they're hitting
each other with their head,
but I feel like every time John has a,
a new opponent,
it's like,
oh,
this is it.
This is the one looking at DC.
I thought D I legitimately thought DC
was probably going to beat them in a
decision three to two.
That's,
I thought he had the perfect setup,
the perfect pedigree to beat Jon Jones.
And then,
I mean,
John Destroy Him,
took him up by the hips.
It really wasn't,
that really wasn't that close of a fight.
So then now it's like,
oh,
here's Anthony Johnson who,
and I love Anthony,
he's a monster.
But I feel like we go through
this every time until,
until he fights cane.
I think once he,
once he does and that's going to happen.
I bet when he fights cane
now we're talking well,
I think Kane has to stay healthy,
you know?
I mean that's one of the,
I think he beats Cain.
He wow.
He might.
I do.
You never know man.
Look,
he looked,
he might very well beat Johnson.
It might be very well,
one of those things,
you look back on it in
hindsight and you said,
well,
you know,
maybe I should have,
figured that this could have happened or
that John would have an advantage here.
But Dude,
when I watched that too late mid Sandhya
people always tell hardest hitter at
two oh five by Shane happen
when that guy's hitting you.
That's,
I don't think that Anthony Rome,
that Jon Jones is here on a peep
out of him wrestling wise though.
I think Jon Jones will dominate.
I mean if he grabs him,
hold on him,
he seems to just shut the fuck up.
Did you see him fight Phil Davis?
Yeah,
Phil.
He the sprawls.
He hit Phil Davis with ferocious spa.
Did you see what he does
with different Time Olympian?
Phil Davis is a very high
level restaurant close to it.
Not not like Dan Courtenay,
Dan [inaudible] Olympian and that's true.
Sure.
But Jones literally,
I couldn't believe he
picked him up by the hips.
Boom,
dumped him,
dumped him again just out
wrestled them and and me.
I said,
this guy is so much bigger than
you think when he's hanging on you,
whether it's leverage or whatever.
And Daniel Cormier is a guy who picks up
heavy weights and throws them on their
head like a,
what's his name?
Josh Barnett.
No doubt.
I don't know if you guys look call me.
It wasn't a good matchup for him.
John figured it out right away that he
could take them down once he took him
down the first round.
So was like,
oh yeah,
once that happened that
you're like holy shit.
Yeah that's a,
that's a damn wake up
all anybody who was it,
who knew a lot about wrestling said is
there's no question that Jones is going
to be on his back when
Courtenay grabs him.
See what you know what,
when you got a guy who's super fucking
talented and his big derailment is a
family.
I mean that's what happened.
He had a kid and then he,
we got out of competitive wrestling
cause he had to feed his family.
But if he had gone on the wheat,
what I'm seeing out of this guy,
like wrestling with people,
but he would've been,
he was a dare go national champ.
Juco,
national champions.
Not punk man.
And no,
not at all.
What does Juco actually college,
the junior college national champion.
But I think like he would have given feet.
People fits as a,
as a wrestler.
I mean,
anybody in the world who
would have given them fit,
I think it would have all been
dedicated or like how much,
how much time you dedicated to
it and how much energy he did.
But if he was in a situation where he
could train 100% of the enough to support
his family,
he would have been all I call
seriously world class amateur wrestler,
if not the best slush in his weight class.
You look at what he's doing in the UFC,
if he decided to focus on wrestling,
you'd be the best.
He's a fucking with this mentality,
man.
And then you know,
you look at what Johnson has been
able to do when he hits people.
Man,
John doesn't do that.
There's a difference between
the way John Hits people.
John,
it fucks people up.
Make no mistake,
John.
Spot tougher guys though.
Fuck yeah.
Hundred percent.
Yes,
he's,
John's fought everybody.
John,
John fights a little nog.
It's not going to be pretty.
No,
it'd be ugly as fuck.
Especially now.
He'll be so confident coming into it now.
But you know,
if you fought them back
when no Garrett gave,
um,
uh,
like let's think about like his
best performance in the octagon.
Uh,
Brill's Michael's Brill's shod.
Rashad was a good one.
Rashad was a good one because he shut
him down with his boxing and Rashad was
tentative like afraid to commit.
Like people don't realize like no little
nod was a like an actual champion in
Brazil and it's like really couldn't
box both of them killed as an amateur
boxer.
Yeah.
He medaled in like the Pan Am
games or something like that.
Now he's legit,
super legit bus rumble at that stage,
like rumbles coming up little nog or is
good at an older in the dressing room
while a little nog was warm up cause I
was corn and Pat Cummings against the
king's Bay.
And uh,
what was that?
Sacramento,
I think San Francisco.
Anyways,
um,
little nog was warming up and he,
I'm telling you man,
I was like,
oh no,
someone should stop them
from going out there.
He could,
he couldn't even hit the mitts.
You can hit the Mitzi so stiff.
He just sat back until Burt said
his name and then he started going.
A lot of those guys,
by the time they get to a certain age,
they've,
their body's gone through so much trauma,
like so much physical trauma,
so much damage.
Somebody kicks,
somebody punches somebody take downs.
It was just Mike Rowe and
they're not that aware.
No.
Him and his brother and not
that old they had for Roche,
especially his brother had for Rucius
was brother that fight with Bob Sapp.
Whoa.
Oh my God.
There's never the same.
After that fight,
his neck was always fine.
If you watch that fight,
it's hard to believe.
He got through that.
He got pile drive by 300 plus pound
Gyri hundred 75 super athlete.
They offered him the fight again.
He was like,
no,
I beat him and he was like,
it doesn't make sense to never
fight together that big again.
Break his back,
man.
He could have broken his back.
Dude,
he piled drived him.
I mean,
and just an all natural
Bob Sapp just fresh off
dude.
You're going to get us written up.
And my main magazines,
again,
this would be printing shop
says Bob Sapp was on steroids.
I should probably address this fader or
thing cause people keep bringing it up
because we,
first of all,
um,
I think it's weird that we have to,
every time we have a podcast
and we just talk shit,
it becomes like stories getting trouble.
Yeah.
It's Larry us their stories.
And one of them was that I,
that it was probably,
it
was highly possible they'd fade or
could have been on performance enhancing
drugs.
I'm not saying that because he was
cheating and everybody else wasn't.
And when I say that,
I'm just saying it only
based on the environment that
that guy was competing in.
Where do you look to the contract?
It said specifically we
do not test for steroids.
Does that mean in anybody's on steroids?
No,
it absolutely doesn't mean it.
But that doesn't mean
the possibility is there.
The positive,
if it comes out and he says,
I never took steroids.
This is a fact.
I have no reason to disbelieve him.
But we look at the environment that
that guy was competing in and there's no
doubt about it.
We're just brought up Bob Sapp.
He's the major one.
He's the number one
major one where there's,
there's the best evidence you ever
need that no one's testing anybody.
Come on you gotta Guy
hold is not even a human.
Three 75 three 75 with ABS,
6% body fat or something like that.
[inaudible] Jack Beat,
Ernesto hoost outweigh one of the
greatest kickboxers of all times.
Uppercuts junkie in the armed.
Him just smashing with muscle
and just test and d ball.
Whatever the fuck else was is fine.
But it's like you look at,
there was a lot of guys who
were doing stuff back then.
If you talk to the people that competed,
even people that are clean,
they'll tell you,
man,
I saw dudes that I know for
a fact we're doing shit.
I know a good percentage of went to it.
It might not have been fader.
It's not crazy to assume it's not crazy.
It's not ridiculous to assume that second.
So,
first of all,
the big important point,
it wasn't even cheating.
It's only cheating by our laws.
We're talking calling,
cheating by United States laws.
They didn't even have
it in their contract.
Like it's said in the contract.
We're not going to test for stories.
They're telling you.
It's basically says,
yeah.
So it's like if the look,
let's put it in perspective with
this whole Tour de France thing,
the big argument bill burr had a hilarious
segment on Conan talking about it is
like everybody was on juice
that it's a dirty sport.
The are psychopath beat your psychopaths,
but you're out where everyone's
cheating and he's right.
He's right.
That's the,
that's what if everyone just
admitted what they were doing,
then we would just be able to deal with
that in the fact that well to do that
bike race,
you need to have all
this shit in your system.
That's the only way these guys could do.
We can tell kids that don't feel
inadequate next to Mr this fuck guy.
He's got scientists cause this guy's
got EPO in his veins and we should tell
people this is the only way
they can do this and compete,
you know.
But we make sure that their levels don't
get above a safe amount and then you
know you let them compete that way.
There's a lot of people
that feel like that.
Like if you have like such a dirty sport.
Whereas like when he had to give his,
when Armstrong had to give a shit back
and they should go back 15 that was like
15 plays.
The guy who didn't test
positive for something.
So it's basically a level
playing field level.
They're all cheating.
It's just who's better
at hiding the cheating?
Right.
Who's got a better team behind them?
I don't think that's necessarily
the case with fighting.
Like I've said,
I would bet $1 million at
Bj Penn never took shit.
I bet a million degree.
He's the guy.
A lot of other guys,
I think if they got injured
like this is Anderson's thing.
He's saying that he took it because he
was injured and he was trying to heal is
like he still can't do
it because it's illegal.
Like you can't,
it's like it's not in
the rules because they,
first of all,
they've shown that if you do take it,
I believe that you're only
taking it to heal your leg.
Don't get me wrong.
But if you allow people
that sort of loophole,
there's certain stores
that you can take that in,
they alter your body permanently.
Like you're going to take steroids that
they've done tests on these and it might
be a small amount and that small amount
might be not even close to like the
advantage that someone like has John,
like John Jones has over
someone like Eddie Brill.
You know what I mean?
Like just insane genetics
in Saimaa athleticism.
Like even if you do take steroids
and you keep a little bit of a bitch,
still not as cheesy,
actually stronger than you,
like your Foxville with nothing,
with no,
with no drugs,
he's way stronger than you,
so you're fucked.
But you just can't let that,
he can't let that be something that
everybody does because it's not because
you'd have hit no cause you'd get into
what you'd have to define what an injury
is.
Now suddenly people
would all have injuries.
Well not only that,
people would do in the off season and put
on crazy Strang and Americans will use
some of it.
Good.
Hate the sport.
If they knew it,
everyone was cheating.
Exactly.
Related to the Gills.
It's just not pure.
People want assume they're,
they're heroes and the guys they see
on TV or gals or supplement free.
Yeah.
And if we got to a point where
everyone is like doing like it's all,
obviously they do it.
What do you like?
It's listed in their stats.
You know,
he takes 15 milliliters of
this fucking Tamil goal.
I oxy Maca fate and he tells like the
whole stack that he's on and it's all
about getting the right stack.
Let me in a really nice,
I'm really important for it take.
But it raises a very important question,
which is as we are pushing way beyond
our biology and it's becoming exponential
and so you're going to
have high school kids,
like Ray Kurzweil says,
who can inject themselves with tiny
little robots that that that like the red
blood cells that basically
oxygenate your blood,
they can sprint for an hour.
Oh,
but Brian told me the other day that
technology to create a bulletproof flying
drag.
I was just saying there's
a saying synthetic biology,
they probably all fun.
But I mean we're probably a hundred
years away from them being able to create
organisms.
Craig venter says 25 years,
but the point is just smarter than me,
so I'll go with that guy.
The point is that you're getting
to a point where you can,
where,
where biology and technology
is is just getting to it.
How do you deny it?
You're going to gene doping,
do all this stuff.
So then what,
what does that mean when you're
competing against another guy?
Is it actually like race cars?
Race cars have a whole team of mechanics,
but work on that,
Angela,
it's like race cars.
You have a very specific amount of
cubic inches you're allowed to have.
That's true.
Everything is a limit
to where they run into.
So it's all of the skill of the driver.
Huh?
Like the sophistication of the
team that puts it together.
I mean they have their justice suspension,
calibrate the dampers,
make sure that everything's correct as
far as the weight balance and all this
other jazz.
And they build a solid engine.
But the engine has to be like,
you know,
whatever it is,
500 horsepower,
you'd have to have a,
you can't.
And here's a little news flash.
If every girl in the division
at one 35 took steroids,
they're still not beating Rhonda.
You could be juice to the gills
and you're not beating Rhonda,
you guys at two oh five
juice all you want.
You're not beating John Jones.
He's just not going to happen now.
Right?
Isn't that strange?
This is like there's guys that,
and by the way,
that might've been fade
or it's very possible,
but when I say this,
I say this,
I have like a few all
time favorite fighters.
Brendan Schaub of course,
cause he's my friend.
Um,
you didn't,
you never saw me do taekwondo.
All right.
I Dunno.
National Video.
I guess we'll get to the but,
but the,
the top two,
like there's maybe like
three or four like that.
They're interchangeable and one of them's
Vandelay just cause every fight was
chaos.
I would job be a Vandelay
Silva Fan to the day I die.
You Aco was a maniac in pride when he
fought rampage and he's standing in front
of them,
like bobbing his head back and forth.
A fucking leave time,
do this fucking thing.
The gloves do.
I can very clearly remember Eddie
Bravo and I sitting in my living room,
cross legged on the couch,
hands sweaty.
When Vandelay was about to fight rampage,
it was a
couple of balls.
Investors.
God Damn,
he was good.
he was chaotic.
He was just,
he was just so ferocious.
So he'll always have a
special place in my heart.
But then when it comes to technicians,
there's two guys that are interchangeable.
It's Anderson and fader.
Those are my two favorite techniques.
Anderson fell out of my top
because of the steroids.
I give him a break.
You give them a break.
I give him a break on
his past performances.
I give him a break on the spectacular
knockouts like the Vitor Belfort front
kick to the face choking
out Dan Henderson.
When Dan was dropping bombs out,
people,
I give him a give him a break,
you know,
before it's Chin went before the,
the Weidman fight.
When Weidman caught him,
Weidman fucking hurt him too.
He hurt him bad and if you
watched that second fight,
it just does not look like he takes
his same punch that he did in the first
fight.
And during the clinch she gets clipped
and he goes down and I looked at him,
I go,
man,
here's a guy is struggling.
Like this is the end of the car.
Like he's 39 yeah,
this is what,
this is how we look at athletes.
You know what I mean?
There's the reality of if
you're going to be natural,
it is the reality of athletes.
They get to a certain point,
especially after a few knockouts
and they're 39 years old.
Like that's what you're looking at man.
You're looking at the,
the deterioration of the master.
And at one point in time Anderson was
the fucking master to say anything else
the best.
He's the best as far as everybody,
as far as performances.
I look at the way he put guys away too,
like the Stephan Bonner fight.
Like Jesus fucking Christ.
He did it like he's a magician.
He,
he's standing with his back
up against the wake him over,
waved him over and then when
he decides it's time to attack,
crushes him with one knee.
Flexis confidence.
You have to have to do that.
Huge to Donna's six
for 10 35 was on juice.
Water tested.
Positive.
Yeah.
I mean obviously the bond
is not the best example.
I mean,
he's the best fighter that uh,
Andrew,
no disrespect,
but he's not the best
fire that Anderson's face.
But you at what he did to rich Franklin,
rich Franklin said,
tough motherfucker,
man.
Look at rich Franklin with chocolate dot.
How about Forrest Griffin?
Right?
But do you think the rich Franklin that
fought chuck Liddell was better than the
rich Franklin fight?
Anderson?
Cause I don't know.
There's no,
no.
So the Anderson that fought rich Franklin,
he fought the best rich Franklin
ever and just ran through,
stood in front of them,
dropped his hands and let him throw
kicks Adam and just died a fucking
championship fight in a
world championship fight.
His hands are down,
the guy's throwing kicks in his head and
he's bobbing and weaving like it's not
even happening.
So you got the Anderson over Fado
I go out to Anderson overall.
I have annual number one always.
He's your favorite.
He's my number one Anderson's.
My favorite has to be.
He's one.
Who's your favorite?
Well,
this is just my,
my opinion,
this is my opinion and in that mix,
in that mix of,
of those great guys is Anderson and
in Fader I say Anderson overall,
but I had some fantastic
enjoyment watching fade or fights.
What I'm saying and what I said about
it being possible that someone might've
done performance enhancing drugs.
It's not an accusation.
I'm just highlighting the reality of
the environment that they were competing
it.
That's it.
As far as my respect for him
as an athlete and as a fighter,
I'm a huge,
huge fan of that guy.
I've always been a huge fan.
There's a video of me on youtube with
that huge UFC hated because I was talking
about what a bad motherfucker he is.
This is what he's fighting
for the other organization.
It's a highlight video of me just ranting
about what a bad motherfucker he is
like I've always thought he was amazing.
Everyone's top.
I have to be honest.
I'm honest about everything
and even if it's,
if it could be possibly
perceived to be disrespectful,
it's not my intention.
My intention is to look at the reality.
I don't know whether or not someone
took a performance enhancing drug.
I don't know.
I have no idea.
I could take a wild guess,
but it's all bullshit unless I see it or
unless we know for sure because someone
tested positive traps are
ridiculously large as well.
Even then build as soon
that though it's not crazy.
No one should write a story,
but you exactly,
exactly.
It's like assuming I'm the only
one that tans in him on his shit.
You guys are white.
It's not ridiculous to assume I tan.
You Know Dimitri?
Yeah,
Dimitris Ukrainian.
Yep.
And he's built like a brick fucking shit.
This dude and I had been
friends 15 we competed together.
We were in the same taekwondo team.
We try.
He was the heavyweight.
I spotted that dude.
All I know.
Brian,
you're on the same circuit.
I didn't,
I couldn't actually,
I'm what I like missed a
national tournament ones
cause he kicked my Shin and
snapped my fucking not the Tibia.
The fit,
which is the fibular that Timmy.
Timmy is the fat one.
The fibula,
the painful ones.
He's up.
My point is,
is a stone that mother
fucker never did anything.
I know he never did anything.
We're friends,
we're friends back when he's competing.
I mean they didn't test anybody back then.
Like they tested you if you've got to
the Olympics and taekwondo would know if
he was on some though.
He wasn't on Shit.
I know he wasn't on Shit.
Juicy.
Can't do that and I wish the public could,
could meet certain
athletes where it's like,
no,
these people are actually
born different than you.
You meet Tim Tebow,
you see Tim and it's just like he,
he,
he won't take protein powder
is worried about Ronda Rousey.
You hangout with Rhonda?
No,
she does nothing.
And she's just built different than us.
He's just a freak.
Brock was at the UFC this weekend and I
shook his hands and he picked me up in
the air with a handshake.
What do you mean I'm not bullshitting?
Dude picked me up in the air
with a fucking handshake.
I go,
what's up big man.
I clapped hands with
him and all of a sudden,
C'mon Dude,
I'm not fucking around.
He's a monster.
I mean,
he kind of touched me with his
left hand while he picked me up.
That was just him.
Sack of potato industry.
Giant has giant his,
my hand disappeared.
It was like a laptop.
It was like,
oh,
shaking hands.
A little shame.
Carlin who picked me up
and started to squeeze me.
You were there and I was like,
oh,
it's happening.
He,
that's,
I just hear him night year,
that's 20% bro to Shay's
squeeze my body and Shane,
we'd be on his boat,
his hands so big.
We'd be on his boat and I'd be like,
Hey Shane and the other berries,
like I got one brother appeals handbag.
I like,
Damn Bro,
can't fuck with doc kind of genetics.
You can't fuck with that kind of genetics
are just too big and I wish people
could hang around with athletes
of this caliber gets like,
no,
I'm telling you,
they're just built different.
No matter what you ever do,
you're never going to be on the sanctuary
gain equal Mike Tyson in his prime.
You mean just get the fuck outta here.
He didn't even do shit and all he was
doing with working out who's getting up.
I run at five 30 in the
morning because it's dark.
I don't know what the film that my
opponent feel sleeping and that gives me
extra strength.
I feel confident and just fucking
running just to just fucking diesel.
Diesel's square headed,
destroying machine,
credible,
fast twitch,
muscle fiber,
an anchor,
and finally in his life he's become
special after years of neglect and that
special talent is knocking.
Motherfuckers out was a
hundred mil in the bank.
And can you imagine him in his heyday he
had 400 million at one point then loss
at all.
Why don't think y'all
had it all at one point?
No,
we had 400 million,
but I think that's like it's total
that he pissed away over his life.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Hey,
how he had tigers.
Charlie Murphy was on my podcast
and told the story about Mike Tyson.
Fucking tiger.
Just a video of it.
Pull the video of it.
Somebody made a video.
Find out who the video is made by.
Some fan did it.
He did an animation of Mike Tyson
in his fucking tiger got tight.
Charlie Murphy pulls up and no one
wants to get out of the limousine.
They're all sitting there.
Tyson's house.
This is when his brother Eddie
Murphy was fucking gigantic.
You know,
he's still is.
But when Charlie and people
didn't know Charlie was,
Charlie was hanging out with his brother,
who?
His friends,
I'm not close.
They're pretty close.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They're clothes.
I ran to them just
totally randomly in Maui.
It was the coolest shit out both of them.
Yeah.
I was at the,
I was at the counter
checking into a hotel and uh,
his cousin rich was there.
I was like,
what's up bridge?
What are you doing man?
Cause we went on that together,
the Maxim conduct,
right?
He goes,
Oh shit man,
what's up?
You just Charlie's here.
Eddie's here.
I go,
no way.
So I went and hung out
with Charlie and I had,
I sat down with Eddie Murphy.
I was like sitting down with
Eddie Murphy having lunch.
Cool Dude.
Funny,
Nice Guy,
man.
He's so nice because
Charlie's a standup guy,
right?
It's Charlie is a fucking
prince of a human being.
Really.
He's a gem.
I love that.
That's good to hear.
He's such a good dude.
Like I had,
I hung out with that dude.
We did 22 shows together and
I liked him more every night.
He's as just a solid stand up dude.
Charlie Murphy is from those to New York.
Charlie Murphy,
a legit martial artists too.
Oh really?
Oh yeah.
He's legit black belt in karate.
Yeah.
He fought in like,
well his dad was a [inaudible]
shit back in the day.
But he's well immersed in martial arts.
Like you talked to them about martial
arts and he just recently got pretty
popular.
Right?
Cause,
well not recently,
but because the Dave
Chappelle show was on there,
but that's where then it's like,
oh cool.
Charlie Murphy or I think,
I think his dad was a boxer
and Eddie Murphy Works Out Bay.
That's he boxes,
you know,
I don't know if he's,
yeah,
but his dad was like,
no,
I don't think it was a pro,
but I think his dad was pretty close.
Well,
I don't know,
but I know that Charlie has been
doing martial arts since he was young.
We had some great conversations about it,
but just about everything,
man.
He's just,
uh,
he's just one of those dudes that you
listen to him like you want to hear him
talk.
He has great stories.
Could there be anyone bigger than Eddie
Murphy at the time in his Hay Day?
Eddie Murphy was so big.
Yeah,
that donkey on,
what is the Israel trek?
I think he made the movie made
rag
the voice of terrorist.
No,
he's the Shrek and he's a donkey.
The donkey where you live in Saudi
Arabia when all this shit was going on.
I know who he is but no ma'am.
No,
hold on.
The donkey is where he made a ton to me.
$13 90 hit the brakes real quick.
One of Eddie Murphy,
standup comedy specials raw,
which I saw live.
You saw like you were in the audience.
I know that's a minor tickets.
My friend bought him for us.
It was a surprise for her brother's
birthday and it was incredible.
Greg Belasco and his sister Amy
and we went there and I had,
I was so I was probably,
what,
1819 when it comes out
in his leather suit.
Oh my God.
And I,
these are seminal moments cause you
could see them on the screen too and his
acting and the things he did was shocking.
How good.
He was shocking and they were all going
crazy and he went to one side of the
room and he put his hand.
It was here.
Then the next is here and I was like,
well that's the coolest
dude on the planet.
The idea that I do that I lot in a
small way that I'm a comic is still
incredible to me.
Washers highlighted his career's
not trek being the donkey.
You didn't let me finish what I'm saying.
They were talking about how
much he made for university.
Definitely fucked up right man.
Guys won.
You won with Shrek guys.
You don't think he fucked up guys.
Hold on.
I'm sure he made a lot
of money but guess what?
It was already rich as fuck
kitty Murphy come on site
for a while though.
Did listen dude,
settle down.
What is dry spell?
What are you sitting back
counting how much money he had.
He got done.
He probably counted about a thousand
dollars a day and he got bored after a
while and then he said,
oh,
let me start doing movies again.
And he did that movie with Steve Martin.
Everybody goes,
Oh shit,
I forgot Eddie Murphy is one
of the funniest guys ever.
Ever.
Brian's like the donkey
and what'd you say,
Jamie?
Yeah,
doctor Doolittle.
No,
the dogs are like little kids' movies.
I got to go back to like trading
places and could know like 48 hours,
eight hours,
48 hours is the big Beverly hills cop.
Three nicknames come on.
Him and Nick Nolte said,
Shrek man,
you didn't let me finish [inaudible] him.
I was saying,
he said he effortless.
He made some insane amount of money just
being a donkey and was telling you kind
of 13 million.
He didn't need it.
I know it went in a pile somewhere.
Right.
He doesn't even feel that.
Have you seen this girl?
No.
Have you seen his girls domestic?
I'm over on the planet.
Sure.
He was still beautiful.
I saw him at the beach or like,
it looks great.
He doesn't look like whatever old he is.
He's older than he is.
Great.
But I look older than him.
He is also a Germaphobe.
He,
he'll use a bar soap once thrown away.
Rich.
That's our sneakers.
Charlie get sneakers.
W they're in a box before
a show puts him on,
throws those bitches to that.
I'm rich.
I'm gonna wear socks.
One son,
I don't wear socks.
Was the video of Charlie at Mike Tyson's
house cause this is how fucking Goddamn
Funny Charlie Murphy goes.
I bet he has such good stories.
Jason,
that Tyson document,
is it just called Tyson?
You see a man,
it is fucking incredible when
he reflects on parts of his leg.
Strong man like that.
You got to realize that
whatever was on it was no joke.
Yeah,
it's incredible.
That's a man.
One time I went to his house and it was
five or six limos and nobody would get
out the limo and I said,
how come nobody's getting out the car?
They said you don't see it.
Lane standing behind tasteless lane,
his front yard like hang over starts.
The only man who's house
I haven't went over.
There was a lane in the front yard.
He was on the steps.
They district heavyweight
belt [inaudible] Kit Kat.
That's fucking real tasting in the lane.
A male or female.
The main,
the lane in his front yard.
Loose Shit.
He was at the end of the yard.
Oh my God.
They came out and started
wrestling with him.
Jog.
Damn.
He ran.
So how big was the lion?
It was big man.
It was
grabbing him and started tussling them
and all this stuff and everybody was in
the limits to the land.
Could come up to the limousine and
buster window open and come in here.
Oh sorry.
Easy.
He can just go out and
get a booth and come and
everybody was in a car.
You couldn't back out cause
it was all like five limos.
It's everybody's in the car.
Her fat thinking it makes
me get me to be eaten.
He plays with them and he'd put,
takes him in the back.
I back out and that was like,
you know what,
I'm never going to be
around another man in life.
That's going to do that.
I'm saying
that's incredible.
Who is the animation?
Telepath slane at telepathic void.
That's the the line back in Lima Sla.
I N at,
what is it again?
That's the way.
Ah,
ah,
shit that she could just say,
just say booth.
I just want to give these guys credit.
What does,
what does it,
what did it say at the very end there?
Just want to give the guy,
cause it's really cool.
It's funny.
Animation to telepath void.
So slain at telepathic void.
Yep.
Okay.
Thanks buddy.
Thanks for making that.
But
I've never,
I never heard anybody use that expression.
Elian heavyweight belt.
Every windmill as the first time.
I'd never seen something
like this again in my life.
Imagined seeing him sitting
there with a heavyweight belt.
Imagine of the experiences Mike Tyson
hand in his hay day and Eddie Murphy and
his heyday.
God.
Yeah.
Excess in Santa Damn.
That kind of celebrity
brings out the aphrodisiac.
Damn.
Oops.
There's so many crazy fucking dudes in
this world that have competed in MMA so
many crazy worlds that have fought
so many crazy dudes that have fought.
And boxing there.
Their whole life stories.
If you had to like accumulate the wildness
of like a Roberto Duran Tappia you're
seeing the Johnny watched the
documentary on Johnny tap.
Really meet a loca drug
addict fight world champion,
Aaron Pryor,
same things.
Pillow.
So many of these great fighters.
Just crazy,
wild lives.
So much nuts,
chaos and ending sometimes like
Arturo got to getting shot and killed.
Kill it.
No,
he got strangled.
It's fucking girl.
His girl killed them.
Send them out off in Brazil.
It was all in Brazil.
Set them up for the insurance.
Right.
She apparently he was hit
on the head and choked.
Yeah,
and they're saying he did it to himself.
Come on.
Yeah,
it's his family thinks she fucking killed.
they got a picture of
her getting out of jail.
She's laughing and smiling like
that's not how you may feel.
That's if you,
if that is really your husband,
you miss him and he's gone.
You,
first of all,
you feel horrible that someone
put you in jail for that.
When you miss him so much and
killed himself and second of home,
when you come out,
you don't,
you're not smiling.
You're like a celebration for this.
In his celebration,
you're still depressed because your
husband is dead because he killed himself
and you were just accused of doing it
and people still suspect you have it.
You should be depressed.
You should feel terrible.
She felt at the whole world is calling
bullshit on you and saying that you
killed him.
You should be like,
you should be under pressure.
I says liquid.
She's under pressure at all.
I saw statistic today that said in Mexico,
if you commit a murder,
there's less than 5% chance
that you'll do any jail time.
Oh,
it did.
That's awesome.
Because of how insane is that?
The people doing the murder are a lot
of times so well connected and you're
talking about cartel violence now
the cops are involved and everyone.
So I keep my ass and yeah.
You know what,
man,
I have a real,
real terrible feeling about the way our,
our worlds connected.
We'd like these borders of countries
and we won't let people in and we keep
people out like on in some sense,
I kind of understand what
people are trying to do,
trying to manage what we
can with our own space.
But if you're not managing your
fucking next door neighbor,
if you're not helping,
you know,
like say if you live next to a crazy
broken down trailer and there's some fuck
and you can't move,
this is like you're,
you have a permanent permanent house.
Yeah.
This is your neighbor,
man.
What are you gonna do?
You're gonna help Matt.
You know,
his kids need some food.
Maybe it needs a little money for gas.
Like,
yeah,
you're doing a lot better than him.
Just give him a little every now and then
just to sued this motherfucker's life.
This Mexico's issue is not that Mexico's
the issue though is institutions and
the integrity of those institutions.
Professor Cowen add it again.
It's really true though.
Okay.
But I was,
I was making a point.
You fuck no,
but what I was trying
to say is these people,
we should,
they shouldn't be like another country.
They're right there.
They should be people that we consider,
you know,
to be in a bad situation
and try to help them,
whether it's help him
politically help him financially,
but the idea that we're just,
we're separate from them.
Like there's,
this should be like a lot of emphasis
on trying to fix Mexico and a less
emphasis on fucking with countries that
are on the other side of the planet.
Well,
you want to fix him.
You legalize marijuana overall in the
United States because the cartel drug
wars,
what's feeding all this chaos?
That's part of it.
That's a big part of it for sure.
You know,
and there's a big part of it is
probably going to be like a lot of the
corruption that you're saying like Pr.
Probably a lot of that's going to go
away when things become more and more
transparent because of the Internet is
going to be harder and harder for people
to pull off the kind
of shit they're doing.
Her Russia right now where you see Putin's
number one enemy got just got whacked
level shot right in public
with his girlfriend.
So someone just came up here.
Good.
He's so much homeboys 55 and he's
got this smoking Russian girlfriend.
She's 23 he's been with
her for three years.
Well hello honey.
He's walking down the
students totally love.
They're very compatible.
He's walking down the street with her
and fucking car pulls up but just unloads
on him.
Kills her two or nothing.
No,
didn't shoot her.
I think more than one guy shot her,
shot him rather he was the head
and she's just standing there.
Why they just shoot him
in front of her like bang,
Bang,
Bang.
It's horrifying.
It's dead and you know,
and now they just left her,
let her leave and go back to their
country and they allowed her to think she
cried or she's like,
Damn.
She probably was freaked out.
I mean,
that's a terrible thing to say.
It's probably completely freaked out.
I mean,
as you imagine,
you're dating this dude and he gets
assassinated because it's probably loved
them.
He was a really charismatic,
awesome guy from,
you know,
he was all about reforms.
He was a big critic of the,
I'm sure that's why she was with them.
Well,
back then.
You know,
who knows what.
It's cultural.
Everybody's got a different
way of looking at things.
Please question girlfriend,
what are you doing Jimmy?
She is ready.
That's what I'm saying.
That's crazy.
He's,
I've ever seen hit red
hot murdered Putin critic.
That's the murdered Putin critic.
Magic.
Imagine if that's like your
title after you're dead,
you're the murdered Putin critic because
that's all people are going to remember
about that cat when we'll
on CNN stuff on American.
When I was doing the ice bucket challenge,
I did it out there.
You're benching 315 pounds,
right?
You did the ice bucket
challenge while benching count.
Pour the water on me and the only thing
I was concerned with is I said if it
slips like it cut,
falls off and hits me
in the neck and I die.
Will it be on CNN will be like,
guy tries ice bucket challenge dies.
That's the only thing I was worried about.
I'm going to die from 315 pounds.
I want to track and drop it
on Monday to totally drop it.
Like your arm's going to stop
working well with the water.
Let's say it slips off yet.
Have you seen that the
USC football player,
it's not going to be good either way.
That guy was benching some
stupid amount of weight,
like 600 plus pounds,
right?
Wasn't he?
No.
This dude,
the homeboy had I think maybe 400 300
something and it slipped because the way
they would do it,
they went wrap their
fingers around the bar.
They're just like this.
Oh and his arms failed and it fell.
It just slipped off.
No,
and he dives off the bar.
he was,
uh,
he's supposed to be a
pretty high draft pick.
Fell on him off season.
I really can't do anything.
And it was just like Jack the McMahon.
Freddy can't talk anymore.
Broke,
broke his neck,
trachea,
everything.
Can't speak.
Fuck.
I've started different one.
I saw it.
It was a white guy.
It was a power lifter dude.
Well,
I've seen that.
He was so fat.
I think he's good.
You know,
there's an advantage to be in that thick.
Well,
a lot of guys get punched in the belly
when they're fat and the punch and
everyone reaches them.
I mean,
they've got fucking five inches of layer.
It's crazy.
Like if somebody punches
you legitimately Sony,
like you could fuck somebody up at one
of those taekwondo body protectors on,
you know,
I've seen people get kicked
and go to the hospital,
to the body.
But if you're a fat guy,
you've got to,
you're walking around through
life with a Jak one body,
you ain't,
and Roy Nelson was a liver shot.
Roy's going laugh.
You hit him to the body.
Especially to this,
the front of the body.
Yeah.
You.
No one is ever going to
the front roundhouse kicked
that dude in the stomach and
really fuck.
He's the biggest mystery
fights over him next.
That's a good fight.
So that's in Dallas.
Dallas.
That's going.
It's a big card.
That's a good car.
What are you doing that weekend?
You're around what?
We kind of March 13th
and 14th I will be in
Chicago at the Schomburg Improv
and this weekend for you,
but will I be this weekend?
I don't know.
You tell me.
Come on man.
It's just do my advertisement.
Blacks,
Brian,
Callan off Broadway comedy.
Oh,
is that the name of the place?
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday.
I'll songwriting Kentucky.
Ryan Collins really off.
It's very off Broadway by the way.
Talky far a shit away from Broadway.
Next want to do comedy
on Broadway and less.
It's only you and you open with
the exact same shit every night.
Can you do it as a performance piece?
You'd have to do a
performance was a box of wigs.
Yeah,
it's for them.
It's very important.
If you're going to do a one
man show performance piece,
like guys just stand up like this.
There's guys that have made a career
off of doing stand up as a one man show
like that defending the caveman.
He's made a fuck load of money also.
You might be a redneck.
He did the same thing over and over.
Yeah,
man show he did that.
Uh,
you're talking about Larry the cable guy?
No,
no.
Larry.
Jeff Foxworthy.
Oh,
you didn't even know you got damn fella.
He,
he know.
He was always the Katana by thing.
Wasn't he Foxworthy your show for a while.
He's still a standup.
He was part of the is he still,
is he still doing stand?
Fuck yeah.
Kill News.
I'll never stop dude.
Well,
fucking Larry,
the cable guy killed.
Nobody talks about Larry.
The cable flies under the
weather under the weather.
Under the radar of the way,
right?
He's gotta.
He's gotta fucking,
there's a picture of that.
Josh will showed me Josh Wolfe and
him did a tour together and they did a
goddamn football arena.
God and it's him.
It's him standing on stage.
Josh Wolfe took a Selfie of him
standing on stage in front of who?
Hundred thousand fucking people,
whatever the fuck it is.
One of those 90% let's say it's 50,000
how many they get one of those hundred
thousand okay.
Eh?
Held for Larry the cable guy.
What
is it?
2004 look at that.
Look what you're looking at.
That's the crazy.
When you're looking at,
that's Nebraska.
That's up to the gas state
and you shit and big red.
Look at the size of that fucking crowd.
Is that from a Josh Wolfe's
Twitter feed or something?
Okay,
dude,
you get that?
Look at that dude.
That's a sea of shoes.
That's an army.
He could start a war.
He could take those Larry,
the cable guy a [inaudible]
and send them overseas.
They can conquer countries.
One of his crowds.
I didn't know.
I gotta be honest.
I thought he was dead.
Yo,
that's the entire dare you.
That's the entire population of Boulder,
Colorado.
Yeah,
that is for real.
It's 100,000 it,
I don't even know.
Honestly,
I didn't know.
He's still doing standards
that all the time.
If he does that all over the country.
Yep.
He doesn't do that like once a year.
That's not like the once a year.
Larry the cable guy.
No,
he's dude.
Do you think he's that redneck
when you just hang out with them?
No,
it's not even who he is now.
[inaudible] Whitney,
he's,
he's a real look.
Pull the video.
There's a video of him doing
stand up and you have to watch it.
It's him.
Before he did the Larry,
first of all,
he's a great guy.
Not dissing him at all.
He's a super
nice guy.
Always cool.
Very down to earth.
Always has been.
I met him like way back in the day in
Montreal before he was ever famous.
He was cool as fuck back.
I've heard that we had some drinks
together and hung out at the comedy works.
Just very,
very cool guy.
He might have a line at his front door,
but he had a,
Oh,
he's killing my game.
Fuck he's married and having
family and all that shit now.
But if he wanted to,
yeah,
he could.
But my point being is that this guy like
create a character and was doing it on
the radio and then that character became
super successful and that's just like
who people think of him as.
Right,
right,
right.
But it's a kid like him.
This is him.
This is him doing stand up here.
I'll tell you what you don't mind.
I just went to visit my grandma.
She's got Alzheimer's disease
trying to put her in a home.
It's a nice place.
It's called the pack.
Wow.
So I've let it just born pure redneck.
No.
Well,
it's just like nobody gets
along with their jeans.
You just like,
see,
just for that reason,
not fair to him to play
this whole material.
So let's just cut it
right there at the point.
Nobody wants a scene.
Anybody's material from 1987 I,
it's still doing comedy today.
When you started at like two years in
and you're on some terrible TV about when
he's having a bad day and just
has to play a redneck dogs,
a kite.
Rip The fucking snaps off.
Gimme this Mollison
that dude's having fun.
He's having before this happened.
You don't really get sick
of playing a redneck.
No,
because he's,
he's farming.
He's,
he's a character.
It's a really funny character.
Super Funny.
And he's,
he's got good jokes.
He's always writing new stuff for it.
I can't believe he's selling
out in Nebraska stadium.
He makes over $20 million a year.
Easy.
Yeah.
He's a Jack for sure.
He's gigantic just doing standup and he,
you know,
he's his own boss.
He does whatever he wants.
The goal now is to get a
line in my front yard that's,
and you won't go in and on.
I do go halvsies on w apex.
I'll have it.
I'll have it Monday through Friday.
You get it Saturday,
Sunday you go around,
the kids got kidnapped.
Cat's going to have some fucking problems.
It's gonna feel weird and not know where
it's real houses the guy in the New
York City and have to dens.
It's true now the dude in New York
City who had a tiger in his apartment,
he had a crocodile too.
Did he?
Yeah.
Alligators and shit.
Meeting it wholesale.
What did you think was going to happen?
We'll go with a best case scenario
with this giant alligator in your town.
You might want to plan,
you might want to plan for it.
You got to call the cops.
He had to cough carves,
man.
Blood to tiger.
Fucked him up.
The tire scratched him.
Yeah.
Tiger was like,
bitch,
I'm out.
I'm living in a fucking apartment.
I need some exercise.
It was being a tiger.
Yeah,
you can't have a tiger and you got
damn apartment in Harlem is one bedroom
studio.
Yeah,
the line.
The Tiger freaked out sun.
You could fucking run.
See some like crazy dude who like thinks
he's neo in the matrix and he's got
some long coat on and he
doesn't want anybody to know.
He's got like extra bolts in his door
and he'd go inside and he's got a
menagerie of fucking animals.
They're tigers and lions
and shit and it's apartment.
I told you I got a tag in my house.
He's like,
his mother fucker really
has a tiger department.
His dark cloud over
his head is constantly,
I when nobody knows.
But I,
when I have the best pet,
I have the strongest pet.
I don't even know that he's the
fucking neighborhood mystery.
You know,
nobody wants to be,
he has,
he has zero friends.
If you have an alligator in your
bathtub and your best friend's a tiger,
a pet tiger,
you have zero k.
But let me look at it
from his point of view.
What would you rather have an alarm
system that you know no one's gonna give a
fuck cause the cops are never
going to answer it anyway.
Like you're,
they kicking your door,
your alarm goes off,
whatever the fuck your dad is.
Fuck.
Okay.
If someone's going to try to harm
you and you're in the Harlem,
they're going to the cops.
You got to stand outside until the dust
settles and then move in and they're not
there for crime prevention through.
They're there to write tickets and shit.
Okay,
so would you want an alarm system that
everybody knows is bullshit or a fucking
tiger in your house?
I'm going to say,
oh,
how confident are you with a pistol?
You can walk out with a stereo while
you're holding off a tiger bitch,
bro.
It's on Q was trained.
It's like,
all right,
someone's breaking.
I better at this tiger out that
tigers fucking the robber up and you,
no one's getting out alive.
Well would probably once it realizes
how fun it is to fuck the robber off,
it'll just want to fuck you up to man.
It'd be like,
wow,
if this motherfucker to crack
open a can a handle for me.
They just decide fuck him up right now.
I want you stupid chicken base and
they just decide what they want to kill
things.
That's what we ignore them.
We put them in zoos.
The most tortuous aspect of zoos.
It's like taking a man in his prime
when he's just unbelievably attracted to
women.
Right.
And then putting him in like a glass
zoo and closure and parading naked women
around him back and forth.
And some people say that that's not,
that's an unfair example,
but it's not because nature has reward
systems and the cans are the cleanup
crew.
When you get a limp and you
fucked your design didn't work.
Well guess what?
People would thicker anchors.
They survive.
Yeah,
but thicker ankle people survive.
You thin ankles.
Motherfuckers gotta go,
okay,
can't go fishing.
I heard
fucking Samoan babies that can run fast.
I mean that's what's going to survive.
Tigers are everywhere.
And the San Diego Zoo,
there was a Jaguar and the woman who tends
to the cats was there and I said that
if I walked in that cage with that thing
a attack me and she said it would kill
you.
And I said,
you didn't seem to hesitate.
She goes,
nope,
it's a Predator will kill you.
And I said,
what are the chances you think of a
human fighting or something like that.
But she goes,
well,
she said what it would do is it would
bite you and it would keep adjusting its
grip because it's,
it's canines,
whatever you call them,
have nerves where they can
sense when the juggler is.
So just keep adjusting and then get
on your juggler and you'd go to sleep.
My boy,
Cody Donald and worked at the,
he was like in the morgue in the hospital
where they put the bodies in and then
at the Denver Zoo,
the lady at night who would feed
the Tigers and all that shit,
she didn't lock the,
she didn't lock it good enough.
Like she whatever through in the fucking
t bones or whatever they give them and
then she thought it would
automatically locks and it didn't,
something messed up the door from closing.
So she's wheeling the car is five can
jaguars sneaks out from behind the home
and they said she died instantly cause
it's big ass canine went all the way
through or scroll through
the back of her neck.
Boom,
got a coat wool Cody at to get the body
and he said they had to look and it's
just like this giant hole from,
from the cat's canine
straight through Jaguar too.
I mean that's not even a particularly
well or they're pretty big.
They're a couple hundred pounds.
Did I lie?
No Jackson.
Not huge though.
Tiger.
They're bigger than a leopards
and they're very powerful.
They think that that,
yeah.
Le Jaguars are way bigger than
they are in South America too.
Yes,
they're gonna creep.
What you know about sleeping
the most pound for pound.
I believe a Jaguar is
the most powerful cat.
I think the multiple cat
cow for pounds a house cat.
I think they said have
house cats were big.
If they were big like a lion or tiger,
we will be fuck yes.
Are you serious?
Yes.
You never attain them.
You never domesticate them.
They they,
they,
they still have all the
same traits as a jungle cat.
They're just smaller.
They're very powerful.
Like when you see that,
how far a house cat can
leap for its body style.
Well,
if you've seen that video with the tiger
that jumps like 12 feet in the air to
get a piece of meat,
there's a video of they're holding this
meat like above this truck for this
tiger.
This tiger leaps through
the air to get the meat.
We'll look at how high the wall was in
San Francisco and the kids are shooting
that tiger was miss rockets
were throwing pine cones.
That what?
It was an entire,
it was like,
I'm going to,
I thought that what they were
shooting with risk rockets?
No,
they were throwing pine
cones on it supposedly.
Yeah.
I mean it was a bit and from my
act and he got had to get about it.
Tiger getting out and look in the guy's
face when the pause at the topic level.
That's right.
Like you can't and you
don't know who you are.
Daniel Day Lewis.
I don't care who the fuck you are like
you like I would have loved to seen that
guy's face because no one can pretend
that killed one guy fucked up.
Another one guy.
I think one guy,
I don't know if the guy tried to
help his friend or what happened,
but the second guy got killed.
Not the first guy that got attacked and
these were the guys throwing the punk
thing jumped the fence.
Apparently they can jump 14 feet,
but this,
this fence was only 12 feet and there
was a big lawsuit because our suppo
threatened to big lawsuits.
I don't know if it was settled,
but because they're fucking
fence was too short.
Man.
The tiger just had never jumped before.
He never gave him a shot for sure.
So needs to map that out.
Back my bit was if you got a monster
in a box in the middle of the city,
put a top to the box.
Be like you went through all this trouble
to build all this shit this way and
you're like,
is that high enough?
Yeah,
let's get out of here.
Like at least someone,
someone decided to 12 why
don't put a fucking top on it?
You got to fake rocks.
It's true.
You got to fucking pooling their forum.
How about a roof?
Fuck heads so it could jump out.
That's so ridiculous.
That's the dumbest fucking thing ever.
Zoos are laymen general though,
man.
What's the last name with the zoo?
I went to San Diego Zoo.
That line was pissing on everybody.
Piss ant man.
Walking back to a,
as a zoo can get back.
I don't like,
that was the most exciting part by far.
It's good for little kids.
I like,
I take my kids that makes sense.
Like to look the animals,
but it's depressing if you go bums,
bums me out,
man.
Yeah,
the press,
especially the primates,
it's very depressing.
I was surprised at what,
how poorly they actually eat.
Especially the primates.
They're not fed the kind of food and
that it's very hard to feed them their
natural diet,
especially in certain ratios.
I don't think they feed the chimps.
Um,
like the first of all to give
them mostly like vegetables.
Right?
They don't allow,
a lot of them developed diabetes
in captivity because they,
there's no real set standard
for how to feed a chimp.
Like as far as national zoo,
you know,
and what do they eat?
All of those different,
I read,
I remember reading about,
I was so shocked at how
they fed these chimps.
It was not good food.
It was not,
you know what they'd really like to eat,
man,
they really love to eat monkeys.
That's right.
A little monkeys too.
It's hard to watch.
You know,
they didn't know it until the
1990s I think there was a guy,
David Attenborough,
is that who it was,
did a a nature documentary in the Congo
or some shit and they follow these
chimps and they,
they had this hunting party,
they took down this monkey and they're
ripping the monkey apart and eat and
it'll lie.
We'll call this monkey the
see the thing screaming,
the look on his face.
What's eating it?
Like asked first chewing on this thing,
pulling it apart.
Like that part the monkeys screaming like,
I can't believe it's getting even is one
of the most fucked up disturbing videos
I've ever seen.
Even like I can't hand you see
them looking up in the trees,
you know the main one looking up
in the trees and they're there,
they're mapping where these monkeys
are going and they cut off as a group.
They want they,
they,
they cut them off,
they funnel them,
they be it trees and they'd get them to
go in a certain direction and then they,
they box them in west side story and
then they just take it on pause for,
they also found that monkey chimp,
young male chimps will band together and
go kill other chimps from other trucks.
Like your mother.
Yeah,
the league.
And occasionally cannibalize.
They'll cannibalize people
from other George chimps.
From other tribes.
Yeah.
Our ancestors are assholes,
you know,
and so are people on
times they do a lot worse.
Well of course,
but I mean bipolar ape,
we're not killing eating
people though really?
Well.
We are,
but so many are in lunch.
But if you look at the numbers,
see how many fucking chimps there are in
the wild and they're doing this fucked
up shit.
The monkeys.
And then look at how
many people there are.
If there was as many people or chimps,
is that where people,
it would be chaos.
You wouldn't be able to leave your
house if there's this many champions.
There were people you would
never be able to get to your car.
They would mug you.
They got,
they would rip your fucking
feed off and fuck your ass.
They'll do whatever they want to do,
whatever they want to.
I think that would be the one animal.
Actually.
You definitely don't
want to have a counter.
You May as well choose a crock
because I'll kill you right away.
A chimp will just take your face
off and do the genitals off.
Yeah,
it was a less likely to attack you.
they're fake.
You don't fake charge you and
you have to stay in charge.
I want you to get the fuck out of here.
Just get the fuck out
of you staring at me.
You crazy ass chimps.
Gonna rip your Dick and faith,
but were so soft.
We think it's okay to look
at a wild animal in its eyes.
That's so stupid.
We are.
Hi
Challenge.
We're cool man.
Well,
from National Geographic Society,
we just come to make
sure your baby's okay.
Fucking crazy.
800 pounds,
silver backyard long through the trees,
right in your face.
He's got bangs and only eat vegetables,
only designed to fuck you up and you
couldn't even imagine what an 800 pound
gorillas strength.
It's like,
because you would think of
it as like an 800 pound man,
but it would really be more like a 3000
pounds to twist your head off like this
man.
Like she'll repeat a pieces,
probably more than 3000 probably like a
5,000 pounds or some ridiculous number.
Look at the muscles on
a 200 pound chimp man,
when they,
when they have one of those their hair.
Aw troll looking fall,
I'm beast stared at those muscles forever.
If we had as many chips
as there were people,
everybody's always down for chimps and I,
and I'm,
I look,
I'm not saying we should
exterminate the chimps,
don't get me wrong,
but let's just be realistic.
If chimps were everywhere
and they had full freedom,
the way people do what,
you got serious problems.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well the first problem with so and
said that was okay for those chimps to
fucking hang out with us.
And if you don't think chimps,
we'll steal babies and eat them.
You haven't been paying
attention to the literature.
That's Grad Center.
I haven't been paid attention.
They will still babies.
Baboons will still be fun that Jones.
I knew baboons are wild as fuck and evil.
Evil country on your back.
It's not a good idea.
Baboons are creepy dog
fucking monkey things.
Nobody's got a pet bat.
Boom.
Now,
some people do they?
Yes,
I did.
He brought about nearly two in Africa.
I know.
There's like baboons with fucking masks.
I'm terrified.
I know.
Every time.
Last time I left his volcano,
he's like,
you're gonna die any minute.
Keep away from volcanoes.
Don't run for office in Russia.
It makes,
makes you get that book because
it will challenge you eventually.
We keep the chip population to a minimum.
Yeah.
Everybody was down for chimps
have chips Ahoy squirrels.
You'd be fucked.
Yeah,
you won't be fucked of.
Chimps were one and through
the fucking muscles look good.
This is my favorite.
Look at that thing.
Look at the muscles.
Oh my God.
They're so strong where
there's a male where,
look at that.
Look at that and what's really,
that's the same chimp I,
yeah,
but what's really fucked
is later balls on it.
He's got some balls and that's
what they all look like.
We just usually see them covered
in hair and we don't realize it.
That's right.
It's got some thick wrists on that guy
and those hands built for brutality is
not built to pull your eyes out of their
head with no Dick for she has a dick.
He's probably playing with it,
man.
He's probably holding it up
with his extra long fingers.
You're not putting them
in a rear naked choke.
We are not doing anything to him.
Oh my God.
He would laugh at you.
Oh,
look at that Gorilla and Oh my God,
so big.
Oh my God,
it looks so big.
Six foot 600 pounds.
Again,
not messing with a very big piece though.
Oh no,
they have tiny dicks.
It's not a matter of fact.
Does it?
Difference in,
notice how he says a tiny balls too.
Here's what's interesting.
Can you a little science?
There's the dessert with primates.
There's a direct relationship with the
size of the testicles and the permissive
ewas ness of the surrounding women.
So the more the women are just fucking
everything buck wild up in here,
the more the dude's balls
get big and that's it.
That existed cultures as well.
For sure.
I live in La and my best
humans have the largest Dick's
though of all the primates.
Port per capita,
you know,
poor per size.
Probably measure if you
measure this pound for pound.
Our dicks are the biggest
cause we're the biggest hose.
Yup.
Not necessarily like us and Bonobos.
Fuck a lot on.
But our dicks are bigger.
The thing about gorillas,
dicks and balls is the grills are so
fucking unchallengeable they could have a
little tiny puds and they
still get all the pussy does.
No one call.
There's no giant gorilla just stroking it,
sitting by the side of the fucking pond.
Eating bamboo shoots with a giant show.
Lailey gorillas know like
Lingham get over overflow.
This one inch killer you've been fucking
with cause it grills have one inch.
Dick's.
It's so disappointing.
But if you look at it in a grills way,
a big Dick is a big target.
You want me to dig bit by a snake might
be the difference between survival and
death.
When you're out there living
in the fucking jungle.
Okay?
You want a tiny Dick
with a pee hole so small,
the one of those little ball eaten fish
can't swim up there and eat your ball
sack out from the inside
like they're known to do.
I heard back in the day,
like in the Roman times,
uh,
a big Dick.
You were made fun of.
It's like look down upon.
Is that true?
Same today.
It's like the Internet.
The Roman days were like Twitter.
If you have a big Dick on Twitter here,
but you fucking the blood goes.
Do you become a retard
proven the body can't support a dick.
That big statues request to keep the
penis small cause it took away from the
body and how hard it was to chisel like
that realistic body and foot and all
that out of the marble.
So you kept that area [inaudible] story.
I bet there's a bunch of dudes Jackin
off on a statue of a giant cock took the
cock and they were but fucking the
statue in the middle of the square,
like backing each other up
on the statue of this giant.
I just heard back in the day,
if you had a big old
Dick in the Roman times,
like they made fun of you.
Like you're an outcast.
No,
that's hilarious.
I don't think it's fun.
Make Fun boys.
Go ahead.
Oh,
real funny fellas.
Funny Man.
Dick,
did you imagine if that,
that is the one that's the one group of
humans that will never get sympathy if
you mock them.
Cause Dude's a big dicks.
I know what,
no matter what.
I mean,
just different races,
different nationalities,
different genders.
There's all sorts of
categories where you are,
uh,
you're,
you're not allowed to mock
people because that's a rude,
even white people.
There's people get mad that
you're mocking white people like,
man much fuck,
leave us white people alone.
You know all the privilege
that white people have,
it's still not enough for
you to be able to mock them.
Take it for judge [inaudible].
Dude's a giant dicks.
You got a green light.
You could find something about
that guy that you can make fun of.
You can make fun of that dude.
Nobody's going to back them up.
We did know that he was
going to come along and say,
hey dude,
with the female Dick,
you know man,
I feel your pain.
It's a bullshit.
They're mocking your giant
super fucking Alpha Hog.
That giant Dick at all.
The women want that huge veiny monster
of destruction that you're swinging your
pants,
your giant,
your giant pool.
The one thing that a
dude cannot own up to,
I mean we just can't.
No,
no guy.
No matter what you do,
you make all the money in the world.
The guys get a giant Dick and if he,
if he bangs or she's going to remember,
we did.
We did.
I remember that thing and
you can't pay for it either.
I do.
We did love line and the open
forum was does size matter.
It literally every girl,
but one was like absolutely do
to tell you it doesn't matter.
It's wishful thinking,
but everything matters.
Dr Drew is like now it doesn't
matter how silly boy or like,
well,
no,
he said it does matter.
Well,
he's got a piece on him apparently.
Well that's what they told us,
but at the end of the
day it was funny proof.
I need a dick pic dot piece.
Yeah.
It was like guys,
I took karate in high school.
Okay.
Define peace.
Well,
I've been doing martial
arts since I was a kid.
What'd you do?
You and your brother hit a brick with
a fucking flashlight and your backyard.
Every guy exactly.
The bench and how fast
to run or they were.
I ran a four or five 40 mm.
Well,
the NFL,
how much your friend goes?
Yeah,
I ran a four six in the
40 [inaudible] well,
no,
you Dan.
And he goes,
oh,
I benched three 85 though.
Three times in high school though.
Why would he say that though?
The Z admitting the first one was a lot.
That was bullshit,
but I'm an eagle scout scout.
I made that shit.
I didn't make Eagle Scout.
I got a badge.
I saw grown man who was an eagle scout
at the airport and he was pushing 45 and
he was an eagle.
So using the full getup.
Sure.
Well he's molesting kids here.
Well he's a scout master.
He,
is that what it is?
Yeah.
I mean he might have earned
the rank of eagle scouts,
boy scouts anymore.
He's like running these scout trips.
He can make it can make the
fire out of two sticky shit.
Oh Dude,
weird guy joined the military.
I remember I was a kid,
I was a kid and I was in the boy scouts,
so I was probably like between,
I would guess it's between,
so when I was living in Boston,
so I think I was probably like 13
that was when I was in the boy scouts.
So it was only in it for like one year,
whatever it was 13 I was a
week living in Jamaica Plain.
And my mom took me to the boy
scout thing in this fucking dude.
He was a scout master.
Was he hitting on my mom like hard and
my mom was like blushing and she was
trying to be polite about it,
but I remember like,
this is creepy.
This dude's hitting on my mom in front
of me and I've got to go camping with
this asshole.
And he was like,
Hey,
what's up with your mom?
Like she's married to my dad.
Fuck off,
get getting extra marshmallows and shit.
I didn't get any extra modules.
I went to camp with a
bunch of fucking hoodlums.
It was a scary camp.
I didn't do any of the
shit we're supposed to do.
I hid during the day like we're supposed
to do all these different activities
and took my fishing rod,
went down to the lake
or I checked out early,
show the individual check out right away.
Well,
with the two doors ricochets okay.
Dudes were,
he gave kids twos and they're shooting
at rocks or hanging out there,
but there was like an archery range.
And while we're hanging out by the
archery range out here and I go,
what the fuck is that?
And someone goes,
it's a ricochet.
I go,
what do you mean until ricochet?
They're like someone over by the
rifle range probably hit a rock.
I go,
it goes all the way.
The fuck over here.
Like what are you talking about man?
Just keep fishing,
bro.
Is the boy scouts in New Hampshire.
Okay.
Listen,
it's survival of the fittest.
They would take kids,
pull them out of their cots,
like pick,
pick their concept and tie them up and
leave him in the middle of the woods and
it was pitch dark.
You couldn't see your hand.
I went to camp out there.
I got molested.
Did you?
Yes.
What happened?
Oh,
you talked about that.
She doesn't tell a story on the podcast.
I don't know.
It doesn't matter.
It wasn't done.
The lesson.
When you look girl,
you're going to tell us the story.
Tell the story though,
Denise.
Well,
yeah,
I'll say Greg,
suck your Dick.
So well no,
I woke up with Dan.
His name was,
uh,
with a felt full of my dog and uh,
and I own this fall.
I had,
I had a morning boy
hard on and I was like,
what's going on?
And he was like,
doing this.
I was like,
I do this.
You just say,
why is he doing this?
I remember going,
I do this.
Why is he,
I didn't even,
it didn't occur to me.
So I go to my buddy Danny,
I go probably 11 and I go,
I've got my buddy down and go,
hey man,
this guy,
he don't me.
I'm like,
this guy did,
was playing with my Dick
and my buddy John goes,
he's playing with my Dick too.
And Donnie goes,
he sucked mine and I go,
I'm telling my mom.
So I waited like a little
tiger in the tall grass.
Mine.
Yup.
Donny.
Yes.
Dick Sucking ass done repeatedly.
He wasn't like real quick island.
Helen got molested as a kid.
Sure did.
I wasn't a violent guy.
He was like,
he was probably a guy who,
he had a beard.
I remember with Baldhead,
terribly athletic.
Not Athletic at all.
I threw a ball at,
I mean he and he clapped like he
was clapping at a bug and then he,
he just loved boys and
I went and told my mom.
What would you tell your mom?
How'd you tell your mom?
Well,
my mom wasn't there so she
didn't come for about two weeks.
He kept asking me why I wasn't going
on more trips cause I was just taken,
I was like not sign up
from any more canoes.
It just that one time,
because you were there for two weeks.
It was just great for longer than that.
I was in camp for two months.
I believe I can suck your Dick.
No,
he never suck my Dick.
And he just,
he just had it.
Well,
he was hard.
We were all in the tent.
It was probably me and like a couple
of years and he had his hand in my,
in my sleeping bag playing with my little
wiener gimme like Jujitsu position.
Does he have you inside control?
Nope.
I'm lying next to him.
He's looking,
he tit,
tense or small pill.
There's three kids.
He's probably like this too.
May sucking done and you off.
Well,
I know that I was looking
at threesome with Dani.
I was looking,
I will feel up like this.
I wasn't a threesome properly.
And uh,
this explains so much.
I know
why you fucking rubbing your head.
It's gotta be an Internet meme.
This explains so much,
so much.
I was molested.
It's fucked up to laugh laughing at that.
It's so,
there's a big going to be the
lesson and NBN fucked and so for me,
and I just knew minor league millennia.
Crazy.
If you don't think Dani
was fucking them too.
No,
I think Donny,
Donny didn't want me to
tell anybody and I was like,
I'm telling my mom,
I almost got molested by a girl.
Came real close.
It didn't realize that the guy was
creeping on me until the very end he did.
I thought it was nice.
I thought it was nine
but he was getting weird.
It was getting weird and
was showing up drunk.
I used to go fishing near this place
called Jamaica pond and Jamaica pond.
Was this a place in Jamaica plain where
I live that had really good fishing.
Like I could walk to it.
It seems weird,
but that's,
you know,
Boston and rains lot of like ponds
and lakes and shit like sometimes near
cities.
And this was a real legitimate trout pond.
And we'd go fishing there all the time.
He'd catch bass,
they're trout,
but they would stock
it with Rainbow Trout.
And I loved fishing back then.
I fish all the time,
the fish everyday afterschool.
So much fun.
It was just peaceful and
it's fun catching fish,
you know,
it's like one of those
things that kids love it.
You know,
when I caught my first trout,
I was like,
Holy Shit.
Like I brought it in and I
picked it up and you know,
I took it home and I cooked it.
I couldn't believe I
caught a fucking trout.
And then it,
it was very exciting to me.
Anyway,
this dude used to jog by and he used
to talk to me and my friend Josh,
Brendan can't stop laughing.
We used to go,
uh,
we used to go fishing at
this place all the time.
Dudes probably dead now because I was,
it was before I moved to Newton.
I moved to Newton when I was 14,
so I was living in Jamaica Plain.
I was probably 13 ish,
somewhere around that.
And he's probably in
his like late fifties.
So it comes around and um,
you know,
he'd ask us about a fishing,
like,
what do you catch?
Like sit down with us for a
little bit and talk with us.
Very friendly and they take off and he
kept doing it like over and over again.
Come by.
Very friendly,
softening,
softening us up.
Feelers.
He would offer us some food.
He would give us some food like,
or like a cake or something.
We'll probably like rub his balls.
I have no idea.
Right.
Probably give you like a cookie.
It just had deep in his ass.
No idea.
I ran it over my crack.
Who knows what he did.
Right.
But I didn't know any better,
man.
I was 13.
I just didn't know any better.
I had one experience when I was younger,
when I was like seven years old.
I was at a library in
San Francisco and uh,
I was looking at his books and I was,
look at these monster books.
This guy came up to me like,
you like monster books?
And I go,
yeah.
And he was like a month,
two books out of my car and go,
Oh really?
And I start going out to this guy's car.
And um,
the lady who's the librarian screams out,
Joseph,
you get away from that man.
Dan.
Dan just got out of jail.
So I run away.
Damn Brian,
probably going to,
who knows who the fuck knows
most likely molest man,
I dodged.
If,
if it's a good bark,
could be killed me like seven at the most.
Most made you,
I don't know.
I'm a little kid anymore.
Scary Shit.
So I had,
I had that in my past.
Like I remembered that,
that a dodge,
that bullet.
So this dude,
man,
I'm so stupid,
man.
I had lunch over this guy's house before.
Just me and him.
Uh,
I,
this is the word started getting weird.
I peed in his bathroom.
And one of the things he said to me,
he goes,
you're very developed.
And I said,
what?
And he goes,
you your penis,
your penis is very developed
for a boy your age.
That's a,
that's a very good thing.
I was like,
oh,
okay.
But he didn't get creepy with me.
I mean,
I was top,
it was creepy,
but you know what I'm saying?
Like you'd be as fuck.
He didn't try to fuck me.
He didn't want it to whatever it was.
It was real.
It got real weird after that.
So that was the probably the
beginning of the weirdness.
Yeah.
So,
yeah,
so I,
uh,
I,
I definitely told Josh,
I was like,
dude,
he say,
he said that,
not like my dick was developed
and he's looking at my Dick.
And Josh was like,
whoa.
And Josh was an interesting character too.
Like he,
he,
that kid knew a lot of shit he
knew about like weird sexual shit,
like way early.
Um,
because,
uh,
his mom was a lesbian.
There's always one of them live with this
woman who looked like a truck driver.
It was,
it was hilarious.
Like he,
he knew,
he knew he was a sharp kid.
He's like,
dude,
he's trying to fuck you.
This is going to get ugly.
And you know,
we were talking about it like,
do you think he's a pedophile?
Like it was like some weird shit.
So anyway,
I started avoiding and dude,
and then one time I'm fishing.
And um,
there was two areas.
There was one error which make a pond,
was,
was the big area.
And then there's this other
smaller pond that was off like,
you know,
like a few blocks to the left.
Sometimes we would go to that pond because
if no one ever went there and it did
have some good fish in there.
And every now and then like
get a different kind of
fish that had like pick role
and most difficult fish.
So he shows up.
It's just me and him.
And this is a kind of an isolated area.
There's a lot of trees and shit.
It's not like Jamaica pond,
which has this big running track sweats.
So sketch,
this is a sketch and he
tells me that he loves me.
Yeah,
yeah.
And uh,
I don't know what to do.
Like I'm sitting there
fishing and I'm like,
okay,
well,
you know,
I like you too man.
And he goes,
no,
I love you.
And there cannot be no true love.
There can be no true love without sex.
Holy.
I remember him saying that
and I remember going what,
like what and I remember how to knife.
Uh,
I had a Swiss army knife when those little
red plastic handle Swiss army knives
and I had it in my pocket and I put my
hand on the knife and I didn't want to
pull it out but I I,
but I wanted to have it on me,
you know,
and I remember thinking I might
have to fucking stab this guy shot.
I did go.
I Dunno.
I mean first of all I'm
probably going to get killed.
I'm 13.
I then know how to fight
back and he's a big,
it wasn't big.
He was bigger than me.
He was an old guy,
grown ass,
grown ass man,
a sweat.
And if he knew how to fight it off,
I was fucked.
I didn't have any martial arts experience
back then is one of the reasons why I
started getting into martial
arts is after this I just,
I figured I have to know
something like this guy,
if he beats me up and fuck
fucking kills me and stabs me,
like no one's going to hear me.
I'm out.
I'm in this like really
kind of wooded area.
And so,
uh,
I told him,
you better fucking leave me
alone or something like that,
you know,
whatever words I was able to muster,
being scared of my mind at 13.
And then,
uh,
years later after I had moved,
this is where it got really creepy.
He sent a letter to my house and I was
like 16 or 17 or something like that.
Yeah.
He sent a letter to my house many,
many years later he found where I moved to
found out where my house was.
I could never told him
my house the first place.
And this guy sent me a letter.
It was really creepy,
man.
I read this long.
It was almost like a love letter to me.
Oof.
It was really creepy.
And I just think if I see this guy,
Jesus Christ,
he was truly and red alert.
I might,
me and my buddy Michael and Saudi
Arabia in love with that Dick,
he saw my juicy deck.
That's what it was.
That's the turning point.
That's
one of the most traumatic
experience for me.
I was in Saudi Arabia,
my buddy Michael and it started,
there was nowhere to place.
He would just go play in these
like abandoned lots and you know,
whatever.
We find cars that were all,
but he'd bring them up as you doing
with 13 year olds do 1413 and I'll never
forget,
I see a guy,
I couldn't understand
what the guy was doing it,
the trunk of his car.
I was like,
what is that guy doing?
And I realized as I got closer,
it was the most bizarre thing.
There was a guy in the trunk of the
car with his ass out of the car.
So he had his ass sticking
out of the trunk of the car,
this giant hairy ass.
And another guy had his robe lifted
up and he was standing there,
Saudi Arabia fucking the guy in his ass,
so I couldn't,
I could just see an ass sticking
out of a trunk and he had his,
I was 13 and my friend
Michael and he was jamming.
He was fucking him
standing up and I was like,
and I go there.
I go,
oh,
it's called cold either of us too.
And I go,
I see it.
He looks at me and he didn't say anything.
He just looks at me with
a blank expression as he's
just drilling some poor GIM
in the in in some Cadillacs and hyper.
I go,
Michael,
let's run away.
I just,
I've never run faster.
You know what?
You can't feel your legs.
I was just like scared man.
Yeah,
Dude.
I don't have any molest story then I do.
I have another one.
I was in crazy one though to that guy.
What did he do when he saw you running
away from not try to finish her fence?
Just looked at me with heavy eyes.
I kept banging.
The dude kept thrusting.
What do you think would have
happened if you just stood there?
Like unimpressed,
like
style.
Still dumb down.
Let me know when you're done.
I'll show you how it's done.
Let me know when you're finished.
Audience member ever at a comedy club.
These guys.
Oh,
that's like the last thing you'd ever
want to see you doing that to him while
he's fucking the guy
in the ass and a trunk.
See better molested again.
Broke.
Well,
no,
I remember I was,
I met an older dude and we were,
we were,
he was cool guy.
We hung out.
I always starts with a older dude.
We were in Wisconsin sweatsuit,
we're in Wisconsin.
The Northwoods of Wisconsin
didn't summertimes.
And I remember I meet this
guy and there was this girl,
they're all two girls
older and we were like,
oh,
we were there.
I don't know,
who cares?
Let's say 14,
13 or 14 it was so hot and I was 11,
10 something even younger,
younger.
Cause I'll tell you why.
I know I was younger so I,
I'm hanging out with this and uh,
can we,
can we keep,
we keep and I'm,
I was such a little pervert.
How old is he?
Well,
I'll tell you,
I don't know,
but I'm going to tell you how
I know he was a lot older.
Ready?
This is how you,
this is,
this is why I'm going,
this is the point.
So we start,
I actually say we should
try sex with those girls.
I'm trying to conspire,
I don't know how old I was
on or at least I was like,
we should try to see their boobs.
I don't know what I was saying to him.
He goes,
yes,
that's a great plan.
So,
so we're talking to come,
we have to go to the woods
and come up with a plan.
So No.
Yeah.
So I'm like,
alright.
So we go to the woods,
have Devin and no wonder
you've been molested several.
The next thing I know I,
this is coming through me now.
The next thing I know,
he pulls his pants down and
I notice how Harry is acid.
So I go,
that's weird.
If there is,
there's this dick and his ass and
he and he lies down and he goes,
do you want her to want
to rub on top of me or no?
And I go,
I don't think so.
I was like,
I was like rub on me or no,
and I was young.
I was young.
I was young enough to
have to think about how,
imagine if that's,
he's like fucking go too long.
I swear to God.
How do you get these
kids to fuck you dude.
This is all you have to do.
You lie down and you go,
do you want to rub on top of me?
No.
I saw it was just start fucking you.
Couple of kids go spit on your
ass and start pounding away.
They all do it.
It's like hypnosis.
What he laid down with her place straight
when he wasn't like he was bent lakes.
They don't you want to
rub on top of me or no,
and I go,
I don't think I was just hearing ass.
Yeah,
I saw the crack and I was like,
and I was like,
do I say yes?
I was like,
this is vaguely sexual.
And I go,
no,
I don't think so.
So then he gets up and he goes,
all right,
we'll just hold off for
a second and he starts,
I'm going to show you something.
And I go,
all right.
He starts jerking off and I go,
Oh,
I've done.
I take all my two,
two,
two.
I used to rub it on the bed to
test when my mother called it.
So I go,
so he's,
he's,
he's winking off and that
was the first time he goes,
hold on,
ready,
ready?
And I go,
yeah,
and he comes on you,
he busted in your face.
Not on my face.
He just shoot.
And I go,
what the fuck?
I go,
what's that white?
I couldn't believe as soon seeing white
stuff is the first time I saw somebody,
a jacket.
Hold on.
Jeez.
You were watching this dude jack off
in the woods for a solid four minutes.
Hey Man,
what were you saying to him?
I don't remember.
It was so long ago.
He goes to Jim on,
hold on.
You called this Mr. Yeah,
He was like,
watch this,
wait for it.
Wait a minute,
hold on.
Wait for it.
Yeah.
And then we went,
then we left and we went
and spied on those girls.
You hung out with him after that?
I did a shirt that you watched a
grown man Jack off bus near you.
Not on your face.
Then you went to go find chicks.
So you know what man,
when you were 11 years old,
Weird Shit can happen to
this 11 year old hockey.
Hell No.
You got lucky.
But I'm not saying that
would have happened.
You would've stood around
while the guy jerked off.
But I am saying it's possible that a guy
when you were 11 could have lied down
and say,
Hey,
you want to rub on top of me or no?
And you would have been like,
what the fuck you would have said no.
100% no I didn't say no for sure.
No,
I don't thought about it cause I
thought that looks like pure Breslin.
The guide be down there.
You might be surprised.
I was surprised.
10 that's a girl I could rub against that.
If it's a girl,
what?
Wait,
hold on.
You revealing.
Just like,
is this a confession?
You want it to last a little bit of it
out and we were talking about funny shit.
You're like,
no,
no.
I still have to add some stuff that I did.
That was because I was thinking about
this just last week guys and I looked
like the iron sheik in his prime
gets fuck
monster hairy asshole smells like woods.
Another fucking bothers me about the
story is you watched him for several
minutes,
Jack.
Sure did.
I didn't know.
I just didn't know what was
found a video of the guy.
We have the guy pull up that video of my,
uh,
on my Twitter feed of the Russian dude
doing kettle bells in the snow with no
shirt on.
This is why you shouldn't
fuck with Russians.
There are different kinds of human and
everybody's freaking out about this Putin
stuff like Putin assassinate or allegedly
Putin is actually investigating it and
he's quite upset that he's,
and he wrote a letter to the guy's mother.
So anyway,
bottom line is to,
Russia is a different fucking,
it's a different beast.
He's,
he's still stuck on the
jacking off this dude.
There's a video.
This dude,
he's in the fucking snow in Russia
and he's doing the man maker.
It's on the Keith level.
Weber,
a Kettlebell cardio workout series.
He does the entire,
uh,
the entire man maker.
No fucking shirt on.
Run the winter.
Hard to tell how much that
kettlebell ways it's he,
it depends on the construction of it.
It's either 35 pounds or 50 pounds.
That honored bill.
No,
no.
This is the motherland.
They don't want on it up there.
It's probably about,
it's probably,
it looks about 50 pounds
right in shape too.
Yeah.
Oh fuck.
He is.
Watch them do this shit,
man.
The dude's stacked.
He does this with no shirt on.
He ain't fucking Russia in the winter.
And he talks Russian to
his dog who waits for him.
You know why?
You know,
why different briefs?
That's guys throwing this fucking
50 pound kettlebell round.
Like it ain't shit.
And he's doing it over and over again.
Switch hands and neck size.
Russian history.
That's was a distillation process.
Deep.
Some warrior genetics
you're looking at here.
This guy's all fucking stud.
Oh by the way,
he might be 70 on both of you are lucky
this then the guy who's trying to fuck
both of you.
Damn right about that.
Well he listened to like a tall fellow.
He's not a very big phony short for sure.
But this guy's a tank cause
he's rattling these fucking,
I mean I don't know how much that weighs.
It might only be 35 pounds
heavier.
Looks like a 50 to me.
I looked like a sound.
How fever?
No,
it would be 72 I think.
70 or 72 heavy Joe.
I don't know.
It might be the size of his head.
Yeah,
but there's some ones that they
make that are really light.
It looked like that,
but they're really light.
I'm going to say that's heavy.
Like if you see those colored ones,
he ever see the that are colored
light.
It's fun and they're big.
They look like you're,
you're using superhuman strength
and it's like 30 pounds.
But that same,
that thing is as big as that.
His Russian hat,
he's got a Russian hat that looks like a,
like a real,
a dragon door style or
one of the Onnit ones.
It's all cast iron.
If that's the case,
that's probably 50 pounds is just
way tough for them to look at this
motherfucker.
He's just switching hands clean press
the whole entire time we've been talking.
This guy has never taken a break.
It's just thrown around this 50
pound Kettlebell kinda awesome.
I gotta I gotta take my Kettlebell
workouts way more serious.
Those ankle weights and fucking
let's get physical socks.
The people behind them freezing
a lot of raw live there.
Better wins.
That's a good time to live there.
Huh?
This guy's an animal.
This is the best way to
stay warm in the winter.
Just keep doing this.
Maybe this is a strategy.
You know how you go to those cryotherapy
places and they keep the inflammation
down?
Maybe if you do like fucking
heavy workouts like this
while you in the middle of
a snowstorm,
it might actually aid your performance.
Bad idea.
You know what I'm saying?
Because like you know
what this guy's doing,
this is all about the burnout.
These are all like high rep exercises.
He's doing everything flowing,
had blood's flowing,
pushing the inflammation out.
He's doing one arm presses
and then full deep squats.
So this guy in the course
of us watching him,
we're assuming that's about 50 pounds,
has probably done like what?
30 or 40 deep squats with that 50
pound kettle bell over his head and he
continues to do it.
He's an animal.
Yeah,
he's in there.
I look at them,
but doing it like this,
watts freezing,
I would no shirt on it.
Also,
it makes you keep the pace up.
You don't want to get cold.
Those socks.
Chow.
That's a child.
The dog is a child that isn't gentle.
Socks are perfect.
He's got Olivia Newton,
John Blair and his Russian built car,
I think their ankles,
my Funko windmills,
son,
windmills.
After all this with that 50 pounds,
that shit is not easy.
I guess that's a challenge.
It's one of those,
yeah,
that's what we're pushing
dog and that's a chow.
It's 100% chow.
100% chat.
By the way,
are they rushing to say,
oh,
there they are.
Chinese.
Yeah,
he's right next to Russia.
A good point.
All right,
motherfucker.
Dead thing wandered into his yard one day.
Come with me,
your friend.
Comrade.
You live with me.
I give your scripts.
Get little bells.
You Bark when people come to me and die.
Kill a little bit on this.
I see as this one.
The fuckers working hard.
That's a hundred reps deep though.
Yeah,
he's working hard,
man.
Yeah,
he's a stout little man.
This is a savage fucking workout for a
no shirted man in the middle of the snow.
That dude once rape kids were all fuck
that dog doesn't give a fuck about the
cold.
By the way.
I look at him.
That dog might have no experience on.
Yeah,
it's pretty dope to be a dog like that.
And I live in a place like that.
Everybody else is suffering.
Let's take this thing and do you think
homeless dogs have the best just the best
lives of any dog?
Cause they're outside all the
time and so they do feed them,
but they're out.
You know what I'm saying?
Like this raise their
dogs are pack animals.
So as long as they have a pack to be with,
yes,
they're alone.
No,
no,
no.
I'm saying they have a owner,
but he's homeless.
This Russian mother fucker
has not stopped at somebody.
He's a dub us talking about this guy
over his video and send it to them.
Respect,
respect,
respect.
We give to you respect.
Sure.
He's a bad ass.
Fucking savage.
Look at him.
He's still going.
That guy.
That's a lot of Goddamn reps.
This guy's got a really good shit.
He's a crossfitter.
Please.
Little didn't salt the pleas from mother
lent these sorts of kettle bells then I
do.
Gosh,
I drink vodka all night.
Have you ever seen that picture of
young fade or in front of kettle bells?
No.
Maybe one of the best pictures ever
have a fucking post training session.
Really that training session,
great super athletes cause the kettle
bells being a Russian invention.
You know,
like you see fade or widow.
His kettle bells around him.
It sort of signifies like this was a
different motherfucking man made from iron
sambo champion.
Oh,
booking photo God damn son.
And he was thin while he
had very little body fat,
but he was very thick muscle.
Look at them back on that.
He had a less body fat
back then but more muscle.
He was a big fucker.
But that's also,
he's pumped.
Like he's probably just worked out and
once you get real thick cause you're all
pumped up,
you don't get more masculine Danette.
That dude?
Nah.
How about the fact that he
never gave a fuck about his gut?
He's rushing.
Give a fuck.
Just one in there dropping bombs.
He married,
he's been married and
divorced a couple of times.
He does paintings and shit.
Yeah he does.
He does art like drawings and she goes,
not the best shit you've ever seen.
Well it's not bad.
It's like cartoon weird.
It's weird.
It's like the shit like a
real serial killer thinks.
Oh for sure.
Well no they're not.
They're smashing people's heads and his
brother's a fighter and was spent a lot
of time in jail.
I think Wright brothers,
a maniac,
call level prison tattoos like his,
his on his back.
There's a picture of like the
angel of death holding a baby.
Well that's not case prison tattoo shit.
You never seen it.
We'll get,
we'll pull that up.
Alexander a million INCOSE tattoos.
He's in jail right now for rape.
Oh No.
Yeah,
I don't really buy night.
He did it,
but he has,
he's definitely an alcoholic.
He definitely gets drunk and he's very
different than fade or was fate or is
like completely composed,
like very disciplined.
Alexander also had some like
some significant losses,
like he lost in pride to Mirko.
Mirko head kicked him.
Yup.
Yeah.
But this is like,
look at his back.
It's like the angel of
death holding a baby.
It's weird.
Yeah.
He's got weird.
Like he had these ones on his,
um,
on his shoulders,
but he had them taken off.
It was like they had these
gang tattoos on his shoulders,
but he had them removed and
change to some sort of pattern.
He's a,
he's a,
you think anyone's fucking
with that guy in prison?
Jesus Christ.
Not a good idea.
He's got kind of knocked James
Thompson out in about 15 seconds,
right?
Yeah.
He's a beast dude.
Alexander million.
Nicole was abused,
you know,
I mean he got knocked out by cro cop,
but he fought cro cop when
cro cop was just on fire.
Do you think that there's,
there's dudes that just like,
they hit this like Bj Penn level,
like Bj Penn when he beat Sanchez.
Bj Penn when you know,
he was like at his very best.
Like this is only like a couple of years.
You can keep that intensity.
I think it's only a couple of fights.
I don't even think it's a year.
Yeah.
Do you think that maybe that's
where Cain is right now.
That's why he's getting
all these injuries.
That's his fucking junior dos Santos wars.
We just so insanely taxing.
I think junior junior is not the
same after those awards either.
No,
I don't think so either.
But you got to remember too,
back in those pride days,
those guys were fighting
a lot more frequent.
So we got the seed the very best when
they're at their prime and now in the UFC,
you know,
you fight,
if you,
if you're a start two times a year,
maybe three granted people and say,
Oh cowboy that I'm talking about.
You know when a guy got a superstar,
he's fighting maybe twice a year
now think it was back in the day,
we'd see him three,
four times.
And you remember when they
used to make these fights,
they there put the fight together within
like three or four weeks of the fight.
Yeah,
it would be like,
it would be like what happened in the UFC
when there's a fallout would happen in
pride all the time.
It would happen in pride instead of like
you having like eight weeks to prepare.
Like they would tell you
like a couple of weeks out.
Like occasionally there
would be like a long wait.
You knew like when uh,
the Open Weight Grand Prix tournament
pretty much we knew who it was.
But then last minute like guys,
we're getting added.
Josh Barnett I think was a
one of the later additions.
I might be wrong about that though.
But I mean you look at that lineup,
Barnett Nogueira Cro,
cop hunt like Jesus,
fuck the same price in those days
cause motherfuckers on the planet.
Yeah,
it's,
it's interesting when you
think about that time,
the wild west days of a,
of pride.
No head stomps and soccer
kicks on the ground.
When Vandelay fought to Maura,
it was holding off the rope
and stomping on his face.
Bro was cro cop fuck Ron.
Ron Waterman and soccer
kicked him in the face.
I forgot about that flight.
Yeah.
And Brian wanted me to ate it too.
He ate a couple of water,
a lot of them.
It was one of my first training partners.
Big flat me out with his titties.
Got It in my garden.
Just smothered me with this.
Teddy's that strong man.
Oh,
it's broke my nose.
Yeah.
I knew nothing at the time.
My training partner was Ron watermen
in Shanghai with my first two training
partners.
So they were just rotating
on me and just dismantled me.
Terrible idea.
I wish I was your friend back then.
That'd been
nice.
No one says,
Shit Dude,
this Shane Shane was like,
now it's making the tough man.
I'm like,
I know.
I know man.
But he liked tap me out with his
titties and super embarrassed.
It's happening.
You have the titties is
the least of your concerns.
That is the least of your concerns.
We didn't spar.
I'll thank God.
But you know what Ron?
Ron used to whoop my ass and then
four years down the road be shoveled,
work on stand up.
And he comes into spar.
Yes,
me and Shane put it on him.
Well he was a big guy,
but he didn't move that good.
No,
he's real stiff but so strong.
Crazy strong.
Do you remember Dan [inaudible]?
No.
God Damn Damn Bovis was
dude who was in the,
he lost a Mark Kerr in the UFC where Kirk
got on top of them is stuck his chin.
His eye socket.
Well used to be allowed to uh,
stick your chin in someone's eye socket.
So Dude's would get ahold of your head.
They would shove their chin like you get,
like they'll get the mount
or something like that.
You know,
any position where they get on top of
and they can balance out and they would
get their hand behind your head and
then get your fucking Chin right in your
eyeball.
Just squeeze and you know your,
your eyes on fire,
you get blowout fractures,
your eyes guys are seeing sparks and shit.
Shit,
you got a giant man like Martin never
thought of that and that's fine.
If you could find that is a mark.
Kerr taps Dan Bobe ish with his chin.
Yeah,
it was there,
dude.
I interviewed him afterwards.
There was the glory days
when I lie jacked up.
Oh yeah.
He had a tap man.
Suddenly you have the best body
and those American flag shorts.
Any bird.
Nice guy too.
Yeah.
Great Guy.
Cruz,
this guy mark marker two 62 60.
Always a very,
very cool dude.
Regardless of what was
going on in his life.
If you saw Mark Curry was your
boy Ken shamrock explaining again.
Yeah,
he's fighting Kimbo.
Yeah.
And you don't want to
say I liked about it.
What he said,
he goes,
uh,
I've earned the right to fight for fun.
He goes,
yeah,
I'm doing it for money.
You know,
you know I'm a professional,
but I've earned the
right to fight for fun.
He goes,
I don't want it.
I don't want to go play golf.
He goes,
I don't want to go hiking.
I don't want to go hunting.
I don't want to go fishing.
He goes,
I like fighting.
I like the comradery that comes
or preparing for a big fight.
I enjoy it,
but I'd love the way he
said it and you know,
it's like very honest and
refreshing and it's true.
He did it.
God Damn all times legend.
He's a legend,
you know,
and all the famous,
and he had some fucking great
technique back in the day,
man.
Ken shamrock man,
go to the early UFC.
He tap Pat Smith and fucked his leg up.
That heel hook can Shamran
dropdown for that heat.
Pat Smith had no idea what
the fuck was going on.
I was fighting in Japan right way
before fight in Pancrase fought.
He fought a bunch of cars.
We Fun Pride for a while.
He had some good fights in pride.
Man.
Ken shamrock had some,
he was developing some pretty decent stand
up like remember that fight where um,
you know,
like the PD,
my heart,
like you had something
going on with his heart,
like his heart was beating too
fast and one of his fights,
I remember that like
they stopped the fight.
I think it was Fujita but he was
putting it on them before that.
Like I was really impressed
with his star is striking.
Like Ken Shamrock doesn't
get enough credit because
he fought Tito Ortiz when he
was already past his prime and his knee
was fucked up when he fought Tito the
first time he fought Tito.
He basically didn't have an ACL.
Wow.
Like he was fucked up.
I was at that fight with you and
after the fight it was crazy.
Like,
you know,
Tito is still mad at him.
And Ken said to him,
he's just real honest about it.
He goes,
hey man,
we made some money.
You know,
we made some money so let it go you,
you won.
Congratulations.
And he gave him a hug and like,
you could see Tito like notice
what we calm down and he'll,
Tito was still mad even
after he kicked his ass.
Cause all the trash talking.
Ken's like,
look,
look what happens.
Like all this trash talk.
We'd both made a lot of money.
It's over you one,
you know,
like,
yeah,
but then we can very
mellow handled though.
Then they the second
money get mad.
Yeah,
you're right.
Get this money son.
I remember you and I were,
we talked to Tito after that fight.
I remember that long time ago.
We went there.
Well,
I ran into Ken at a diner at
like one o'clock in the morning,
the night of the fight
he was eating and uh,
identify that before it like,
you know,
it was into the morning.
I just want to talk in the morning,
the day of,
if he's going to fight the next
day when he's out at a diner.
And uh,
he was real,
he had been through so much,
just fought so many times.
He goes,
hey man.
it only hurts after it's over.
Yeah.
That's going.
He's like laughing about it.
He's like,
so I'm going to go fight tomorrow.
Like that was his attitude about it.
This is Mark Kerr and Dan mobish.
Let's see if we could see the video of
him putting his fucking chicken is eye.
So he got them in side control.
Beautiful back.
Certainly did and but Dan
Babish is God damn enormous.
I look at it,
look at,
just to see the way he's
grabbing his head with his arm.
So he gets inside control
and he gets on top of him.
Can you see it?
They have a good angle.
Poor production team back then.
Full mouth.
Chin in the eyeball.
You can't see it and that angle,
man,
I'll maybe can't see it.
I don't think.
I don't think they have a,
he goes to mountain here will be.
That was it.
I mean that was the tap.
It's over.
But this is the full sequence.
Let's see it.
Look how strong.
She's like,
bitch,
you ain't going nowhere.
Mark Curve back.
And then I saw that one 88 in college too,
by the way.
Well,
you know what,
man,
he had a lot of Korean team in his diet.
He certainly did.
And um,
he's,
he's fine with pride and he
definitely didn't take steroids then.
Right?
Is that true?
It'd be crazy to assume that.
Well,
you know what man,
that documentary,
it was super brave smashing machines.
Super brave of him.
I mean he basically left them document
his ascension into drug addiction and a
lot of that came from fighting
like painkillers and shit.
He got addicted to and it was everything.
Steroids,
painkillers,
like he's a great guy.
And let me seen that documentary.
It's good.
Yeah,
it's pretty good.
This is actually pretty
fucking good technique here
for the day or passing guard
is Kurt was a hell mouth.
Our big collegiate wrestlers,
we sound like boats.
He can't really see it here,
but he's got his chin in.
His fucking eyeballs are going to
grab his eye looking at grandma's.
I look at him say,
yeah,
I remember that man that was back in,
look at the size hard.
God Damn,
that's a big man.
Yeah.
Cause I said you wrestled at one 88.
He goes,
yeah,
put a little miracle grow on my cereal.
I don't really,
yeah.
Yeah.
Just different animals.
How's he doing now?
I'm not so good.
It was selling cars for a while.
I lost a shit ton of weight.
Um,
he fought a few times since I got
knocked out by King Mo and he looked like
really?
Actually that's right.
King Mo smashed him in the first round.
It was really not fun to watch.
It looked bad.
He went to sleep and you could tell
like he was in a bad spot and then um,
and he wound up retiring from MMA.
Sold some cars.
Dan,
I don't know what he's doing now.
Hoping to him.
Well I hope so too.
He was a good dude.
He's always a good dude,
but he definitely had his demons,
man.
Like a lot of those dudes.
I mean you were talking about it,
you know that it hit you for a few
months cause God damn pain pills
man,
you can get,
you can get those demons can fucking
haunt you when you can get stuck day pain
pills and the most
dangerous drug in the world.
Hands down.
There's nothing more dangerous
than prescription pills.
They're trying to slow that down.
They're trying to cut back in America.
I mean there's,
there's,
there's started passing too
much money should be made.
What was too much you're talking about,
cause also oxytocin,
all the hot and Oxycontin,
oxytocin.
But the,
um,
the thing being,
there's still so much profit.
Even if they cut back,
there's still over this,
there's just too many.
I mean I get the,
I get the idea like what would you rather
do if you had like severe pain all the
time?
Would you rather be addicted to opiates
and just deal with that pain and be
fine?
Or would you rather be absolutely
miserable and sober all day long?
And I think you have the right and as
an adult to choose to be fucked up on
opiates,
but they're addicting.
Like you have to depend on them.
And then you also got to realize
when you take painkillers,
it sends a message to your body.
It says,
oh,
we're doing fine.
It's healed.
We don't need to send those
receptors to heal the muscle or bone,
whatever it is.
So you're fucked man.
Or You could smoke marijuana,
God damn dude.
Damn.
Or you can eat marijuana.
You know,
whichever.
You can really get that CBD oil
that people are using to help tumor.
It's crazy.
Inflammation,
pain,
painkillers.
You get stuck on him.
You're in trouble.
Yeah.
It's,
I think I've come up with a way to heal
injuries that they don't have today and
we're going to look back at these
days like it was the dark ages.
Like you know how we look at
back at using leeches and shit.
When they had a saw people's
legs off and they broke.
They didn't add up then and
I'll put rods inside your bone,
like Anderson Silva's leg,
guess what's on?
We're going to have to
take that sucker off.
They would do back then
it would faster and rot.
They wouldn't know what to do with it.
You die most of the time
for antibiotics and see,
probably braced it and
some people survive.
What are the odds that you are
getting both legs connected perfectly?
I mean it's like both bones rather.
It's like snapped in half.
I had an orthopedic surgeon
tell me that if you,
if you're like in the wilderness,
somebody gets a compound
fracture and I said,
what do you do?
And he said,
Paul,
what do you mean?
He said,
your bone wants to go back in place.
Take that ankle,
pull it out,
pull it out and,
and the bone,
we'll reconnect.
And then splits.
They're just supposed to line it back up.
Yup.
He said pull that fucker right out.
Oh,
and that's exactly what they do to you.
They will pull.
Really?
Do you ever see somebody that a doctor
reset a shoulder when it comes out of the
socket that's inefficient.
Break up my arm and I was a little kid.
I remember them setting it
freaked me the fuck out.
He should pull your up.
My arm went like that.
Like it was like bent up that I fell
on the monkey bars and I try to block
myself with my hand and it just,
my forum just snapped and just went crack.
Oh yeah.
It happens a lot happened to my daughter.
I have all the jobs.
Yeah,
lot of kids.
My friend's daughter and happened to um,
another kid that's
they're friends with half.
But when you're a kid swinging good,
right.
Cause it's so young,
they heal so quick.
It's amazing.
Their bones just go.
They just fuse up.
They take the cast off in three weeks.
Soft and everything.
Yeah Dude,
they grow like whoa.
And the,
the thing is I'm with little kids.
What's one of the big issues
is not even the bone healing,
uh,
that quickly cause it
heal so quickly that it,
as long as it's set correctly
and heals very quickly,
but it's the stiffness but you don't
want to lose the range of motion.
So that's like my
daughter had issues with,
she had to go through some range of
motion stuff that takes a couple of weeks
before their motion comes back.
But you compare it to like the way you
would be if you broke your arm at 48 long
time,
but take a long fucking time.
You know,
it's,
it's rough.
Especially if you don't use help,
which is one of the reasons why I
was willing to forgive Anderson and,
and not,
not forgiving.
You understand.
He doesn't need my forgiveness.
I'm just saying like one
of the reasons why I go,
look man,
I'm,
I'm judging the dude before
he fought Chris Weidman.
I'm judging them up to this point when
she's 38 years old and he gets knocked
dead by this young stud.
Agree.
I go that guy before.
That is the best hour.
Yep.
And this guy is a host fail test.
There's the post failed
test is what sucks.
I can't,
I can't speak about this cause I know
some shit that I'm not supposed to know or
that I'm not,
that's not out there yet.
And once it does get out there
and then we can talk about it.
But the person who told me about it,
a jet legit and we don't have time.
We just missed this one thing for sure.
For sure.
He took some Shitty,
wasn't supposed to take to
make his leg healed for sure.
Can't explain it.
There's a,
there's a really goofy explanation.
I'll explain after the show.
Cool.
But it'll all come out.
Albert Watson.
I don't know what happened there man.
I heard a couple of different stories.
I've heard story but I'm just
saying we don't have details.
It just sucks.
He's gone man.
Yeah,
he quit.
Apparently that's the
word is that he quit.
He got in an altercation
with someone or something.
I Dunno what happened or
he just got tired of it,
man.
The guy was traveling to fucking China
and traveling all over this place and
that place in Brazil.
He's the manager of Joe Frazier.
Yeah,
he's been around a long time.
Crazy.
Right.
And really one of the best
human beings you've ever met.
One of the nicest guys ever.
I Dunno what happened.
They don't make too to Burt Watson's.
Yeah,
I agree it replaceable.
I gave him that nickname
babysit to the stars.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That was my nickname when he got on stage,
when he would get on stage,
say a Burton Watson Babysit to the
stars because that's what he does,
man.
He babysits everybody.
He makes,
he makes everybody's experience
with the UFC smooth and easy.
It takes care of all your shit.
And so that like when
these fighters would fight,
like they would have this welcome
feeling of like being at home.
Cause Burt Watson was
there to take care of.
You were talking about that
how when you'd see him,
everything would be okay.
Yeah.
I mean when you're going to fight these
monsters and you check into the fight or
hotel and it's like chaos.
There's fans and then you see Burton.
He's just like,
what's up baby?
Everything's smooth.
Made me just feel calm.
Even in back in the lock room.
Don't leave it to the judges.
Like before I fought Travis Browne,
remember La,
don't leave it to the judges.
Boss.
Don't leave to the judges.
They made you cry last time I
told you and he talks to him.
There's this comfort level where I don't
know if anyone else in the world could
do it,
man.
And he was so damn good at it.
He's a,
he's a genuinely,
really nice guy,
great human beings.
So when he's doing that,
you know,
he's pumping everybody up.
That's his nature.
His nature is to pump you up,
to make you feel good.
He wants you to feel good when
you see Bert Kreischer every,
there's not a time that I
saw that guy that I didn't
give him a big giant hug.
Bert Kreischer you're
talking about referral,
right?
I'm sorry,
Watson,
but Watson who said crusher crusher?
I was like,
yeah,
well he's another one.
I was like,
that's probably going to be here tomorrow.
He's a great guy.
Nice.
But Bert Watson,
sorry,
[inaudible] guy.
He would make guys on the new card
feel like they're the main event.
You would every one you felt like you
were literally the only guy fighting that
night.
Like you'd just amazing.
But every time you'd
see them you'd hug them.
Just like that's what it was.
Just such a switchable,
listen tangible.
Some people just have that,
that quality that makes sort of,
well you know what the problem is man,
it seems like a job that
other people could do.
So it says like,
you know,
maybe sometimes you think
you always appreciate.
It seems like when you look
at it like what's he doing?
It's so important.
You know?
Like,
why is this guy,
why is he getting all this attention?
Like sometimes they look on paper,
what he does.
You can't like it's not,
there's not a job description.
Okay.
Oh you deal with divas and deal with some
of the toughest guys on the planet and
you,
you know,
he makes sure their weakest,
smooth.
I get it.
Yeah,
I can do that.
I'm telling you man,
it's going to be a beast.
Yeah.
I mean I think other people probably
could do it but no one's going to replace
him.
He has his own unique
individual and you know,
he's a beautiful guy to be around.
Like I just think that's worth something.
You know,
I don't know.
I would've never let the dark,
I have a weird,
like this guy we used to train American
bulldogs to for attack train and he had
this dog on a leash called acts and we
went and saw all this dogs cause at the
time I was thinking about buying an
American bulldog and he said he can't go
near that dog over there.
I said okay guys.
Hey,
he's,
he's by trainees and amazing
mean boy in and everything.
And then they were talking about how
there was a guy who just could walk up to
every single dog he had in that whole lot.
He had a bunch of them.
And uh,
one point acts is just the only person
that acts that's near him is this dude.
And they didn't tell him not to go up to
ax and he walked up to ax and the next
thing you know,
he saw the guy get down on his knees and
opened his arms and acts and acts was
wagging on Max's wagon.
I said,
rip his,
he just had a,
he had a thing with dogs.
That's matter how Sam's experience,
some people just have a,
I wonder if it's an the retarded,
the dog recognizes they're
too stupid to know any better.
Yeah.
So talk to us and fight their face off.
God,
man,
who knows when I was going to do a movie,
when I was going to do
a movie a long time ago,
I can't remember the name of the movie,
actually got released and it was about
a French soldier in the desert who meets
a leopard and they have directed
by a woman named Lavinia career.
And I had a meeting with her and she said,
well,
we're looking for an actor.
Um,
the only issue is that they,
the leopard will either like
you or it won't like you.
If it doesn't like you,
it will never like you.
If it likes you,
you'll be fine.
And that was a huge part of
getting cast in the role.
And I said,
what does it,
how does it know?
How does it know?
And she said,
we don't know.
It's maybe a cent or however your move,
but it likes you.
You get the part.
So getting the parts one thing and then
you'd have to go through the leopard
tests.
Oh,
I was like very,
did you go through the level
of depth?
Sure.
Didn't.
I didn't know.
So what were you thinking when he
gets on his knees in front of the dog?
I'm sorry,
I didn't see that.
I didn't see it.
I was just told the story.
I don't like those stories that you
weren't there for tell those guys store.
Yeah,
those are not good.
You know why?
Because they might be bullshit.
I hate those styles out there.
Yeah,
but it might have been exaggerated.
Dogg might've been super friendly.
So video is a wiener dog.
Red At all my friend's dog
house and they're like,
yeah.
Everybody's like,
oh,
it's dog.
Scary on the quick cause this is German
shepherd as a family doc comes over
wagging its tail.
Everyone thinks their sweet.
Well,
we're talking about the difference
between a liar and an exaggerator,
right?
Yeah.
You just,
you just took me down a
journey where you don't know.
You have no veracity.
Your likes your tent.
You're Brian Williams of the podcast and
saying you'd see escaped one.
I'm Ronda Rousey's our virus.
It's called really nice.
Fuck when you're in these guys.
Six months,
man.
What the fuck ever,
dude,
it's over son.
You guys a crazy America.
Forget,
oh no press conference.
No one can do that.
Listen,
if I'm wanting to be a
fucking newscaster tomorrow,
if it wasn't for my checkered past
tomorrow ain't doing it tomorrow.
It's a clean wreck.
This way too many endorsements of illegal
drugs of mine on and I are friends.
We're friends.
If you found out,
I told a major lie like that
Doug story of the Taekwondo,
which one?
I mean I've told a lot of stories
and you found out that I was just a liar.
There's a big difference,
man.
That's where you go.
I've got to reassess everything now.
Brian Williams is doing it for ratings
like there's a lot of competition out
there and he went,
yeah,
I was in this helicopter.
He heard of a helicopter crash
and he's just putting himself,
giving them too much credit.
I think you're,
you're,
you're saying that he's like,
this is a calculated move,
but that's stupid.
You know why?
Because the true story is still awesome.
Okay.
Here's the true story.
The true story.
He's in a helicopter.
There's a helicopter convoy
of three helicopters.
The one in front of them
gets hit with an RPG.
They have to force land in a fucking
sand storm and they're stuck in the sand
star for two days.
That stories awesome
and that story is true.
That's a true story you're missing.
What you're missing is is he was three
and a half hours behind the one that hit
with,
I heard what you said,
but this is what the fuck the pilots said.
The pilots said that's not the case.
The pilot said they landed an hour late
because they had to get rid of their
cargo.
They had a full load of cargo.
They landed,
they got rid of their cargo and then
they met up with the other helicopter.
I got hit by the RPG.
That's why they were an hour behind it.
Yeah.
They were all story then,
but this is,
the guy says they were all in a convoy
and the helicopter pilot even said that
the,
the helicopter that Brian Williams
was on took small arms fire.
Okay.
Then when he landed he a,
or then when he told his story to
other people came out and said,
no,
they were the guys that were flying,
Brian Williams
around and he didn't fly him around.
And so he's like,
you know what?
I don't even know anymore.
He said,
I have suppressed this so much and this
is a guy who was a totally legit guy and
he said,
I'm starting to get nightmares again
and I had already put this behind me.
Now you're making me relive
this experience from 12
years ago and I'm starting
to question my own memory,
which is super common in traumatic
situations like for Brian Williams,
let's be real.
I don't know that dude,
but I guarantee you he's a pussy.
I guarantee you whatever you're selling,
he's never been in a fight in his life.
The way he apologized,
the way,
I mean this,
I mistakenly plated the two stories.
Maybe you did,
maybe it didn't.
That's not the way it Goddamn
man apologized and fucking up.
He should have done was instead of doing
it online or that way where you're in
some constricted time of 15 seconds,
they allot you to try to clear your name.
You should do it on a youtube video.
You should put a goddamn
camera in front of you.
And as long as it takes to get your full
thoughts out about how this possibly
could have happened or a debt you did
lie or what it was or that you got caught
up in it and somebody repeated it and you
almost forgot because you kept telling
us to whatever the fuck it is.
The actual story is pretty God damn good.
Yeah.
At least according to the helicopter,
the helicopter pilot said that is,
and then the helicopter pilot came out
the next day and said he's not even sure
of his own memory and so he doesn't
want to talk about it anymore,
which is,
that guy's fucking prerogative.
So what do you think should
happen to Brian Williams?
You don't think she read
your news.
You're not telling me the news.
Your rescue artists do something outside.
Go host a talk show.
Yeah.
It goes to talk show.
He's the first one ever to lie,
not,
but you can't get caught.
You can't get caught as a,
as a news liar,
you know what I mean?
It's like he's the face of NBC News.
Okay.
How about this?
What did you found out that a dude was
pitching for the world series and he got
paid off by some gambling
organisation to throw the game.
Would you ever trust that guy to
fucking pitch a legit game again?
Would you ever know?
But Anderson Silva told
me didn't take steroids.
He's still your number one guy,
but Brian Williams can't
tell the news these days.
I think it's fun and Anderson Silva at
the end of his career definitely did take
steroids at the end of this girl.
I'm different though.
It was when he had a broken
leg and he's 39 years old,
which you,
he'll slow as fuck and I'm with you.
I get all mad did you shouldn't do it,
but it's totally illegal.
I'm with you.
I,
what I'm saying is when I say
Anderson's the best of all time,
I'm not taking away his
previous accomplishments
because he fucked up when he
was 39 years old.
When I'm saying is if I look at him in
his prime from Chris Liebing all the way
to Vitor Belfort to
fucking the Stephan Bonner,
if I look at his fights,
Dan Henderson,
and we assume he's clean,
we assume he's clean.
All right.
Do we do not know.
Okay.
We obviously don't do not know.
Do not.
I'm not saying he did.
If he really was clean,
I,
I give him the benefit of the doubt.
He never failed a test and I
say that he was the best ever.
The benefit of the doubt,
but fate or has more benefit because
fatal or never tested positive.
True.
Even though he was in a dirty league,
I mean we could call it a dirty league,
right?
We pride 100% hundred percent.
Right.
We nosing fighters.
When we say dirty,
we don't mean that disrespectfully.
It was still the environment
that they were competing.
I say,
okay,
so fade or has way more benefit of the
doubt because he never tested positive,
but yet it wasn't even tested
until he came to strike bro.
All I'm saying is,
so Brian Williams basically
tests positive for this one time.
The whole line is,
so we're just giving assume hall.
It's bullshit.
You Trust Brian Williams to give,
to deliver information.
He is a journalist.
That pupil is,
Helen did journalists credibility
and an organization's credibility is
everything when it comes to the news.
When you're a journalist
and you have a story,
you have to have,
I think that depending on where you're at,
they they cross check your references.
You've got to get very,
very good sources and I think an
editorial board has to okay it.
That's why we trust
the news in my opinion.
When someone like Brian Williams lies
and he blatantly lied and it was self
aggrandizement,
it was about making himself look not
only like a sympathetic character,
but a grandiose character.
He exaggerate will more
than an exaggeration.
It's a lie.
It's an absolute blatant lie,
and everybody uses these
euphemisms and and like,
well,
he wasn't forthcoming.
No,
it's okay that you lied.
It was a fight and he really thought that
he was in the helicopter that got hit
by shit too bad.
Right,
right,
right.
But what if it's like
the Oj Simpson thing?
Like people thought that Oj
Simpson literally believed
at the end of his time as
a free man,
that he hadn't killed his wife.
There's people that knew him
that had said this in interviews.
They said,
I really believe that he
doesn't believe he killed her.
Like he got it in his head like he,
he 2010 his brain,
he didn't know.
But then who knows?
But that,
that would be the not civil,
the civil lawsuit.
He was true.
But the courts have recognized that too.
Right?
They recognize some,
that's the degree of mental
delusion or whatever it is,
and saying,
Brian Williams shouldn't
be out of a job for lying.
I don't want to hurt the guy.
I don't think he said should those little,
let's be honest about this.
First of all,
he made a dossier of Brian Williams
lives investigating suspense accounts.
Okay,
he's,
there you go.
He's done there.
If they're doing that with,
what's the date on that again?
Boy,
boy.
So he's like more than once.
That's all done.
He's dossier,
but that's how it screws is.
That's how it always is.
That's maybe just exaggerate this
one time and let's do it that way.
That's not human behavior.
That's not human it when people steal,
when you,
somebody steals money from you and
they go in and they take money,
they got a history of I disagree.
Well we don't know the situation.
You don't know if you're right.
Sometimes there can be
desperate for money.
I can understand that.
I'm just saying that typically when
people behave a certain way and they get
caught,
they've probably done something
like that in the past.
You disagree?
I don't think you know,
it's,
it's very possible to be as what
it is very possible that he hasn't,
but if they do have a dossier of lies
and I'm 10 years suspicions have kind of
been confirmed.
Yeah,
he screwed.
he's fun.
But it's also,
it's like it doesn't
mean that he can't work,
and by the way,
he was making $10 million a year.
He's bald is fine.
Just make it a lot of fucking money.
That guy is going to be fine.
I really don't give a
shit if my newscasters or,
oh,
you're crazy,
man.
I don't want that to make you angry.
You should get a watch this puppet,
this fucking state run puppet.
All of them are about this.
They're not,
they're
not all puppies do you mean CNN didn't
read all those guys spending $10 million
because you trust him because
he's a face of credibility.
The reason Brian Williams made $10
million a years because he was the face of
NBC News and when you brought them into
your living room like everybody did,
what,
what happened was you do that
because when you get news from him,
you believe it.
Oh,
that's why you're watching
or not watching fiction.
I didn't trust them from the get go.
I don't want assume these are
worldclass great Americans give,
delivers the news.
Well,
we're a dummy for basically a corporation.
We're telling you what to say.
You exaggerate the news.
I mean,
you're being,
you're also being sympathetic
simplistic about this.
Okay.
But he's not really,
because all Brian Really
Williams credentials.
I mean,
what,
what does he need to be able to do that
you can't do or that you can't do with
it?
I can't do so reading off,
I'm not good at reading off teleprompters,
but that's all he has to do.
Telegenic is used to doing that.
He looks like someone's Dad.
He's a good height.
He's got good facial,
are reserved for that.
That's what they hired his speeches.
But he's not particularly a brilliant guy.
I had a conversation off the record once,
uh,
I won't say the guy's name,
but he's one of those news guys and I
was shocked at how dumb he seemed like we
were having a conversation about,
and I,
and I questioned him on a couple of
things were just like throwing some,
you know,
just shooting the shit back and forth.
And I forget what came up
or what the subject was,
but I remember thinking,
this guy's nuts.
He's not that bright.
What was he?
Was He hesitant or what was it?
Clumsy.
Clumsy,
like clumsiness thinking.
I can't really tell you what it is.
Then you'll know who the
fuck I'm talking about.
He's not a bad guy.
My favorite author,
he's good,
but he,
you know,
look,
Anderson Cooper is a,
is another one that was
considered by people.
I've only read this,
I don't know and I
can't give you examples.
He was crying.
He was recognized by a lot of people who
wrote about this afterwards as a pretty
good journalist that got
him to where he was to,
but got them to be an anchor of NBC.
He had,
he was a credible journalist
who did good work,
who did,
who wrote good articles and good did
good investigation and that's why it was
such a bummer for so many people
buy a lot of other accounts.
That's not true.
Other is not true.
There's other people that
said that he was an asshole,
that he was a pretentious.
I mean,
who the fuck knows?
Whenever something like
this happens who sides,
you're going to get
bullshit on both directions,
but all I know is when we
don't really need those guys.
We don't need someone
that's a credible voice.
I agree.
We need information.
That's what we need and it's almost
worse when it comes from a personality,
especially if we think that personality
could potentially be manipulated.
It's charismatic father figure
that's reading you the new escalator.
It's actually kind of,
it's kind of creepy in a way,
but a free honest and open press and
knowing that you can trust the information
you get say for it from the New
York Times because they have a,
they work very hard at making sure
at least what that the stories or the
information,
not the stories of the slant but
the information presented so,
so for example,
somebody gets shot a 12 year old gets,
we know that's true.
We're not going to say
they're making that up.
There has to be a certain amount of non
cynical trust in a society where we just
give people the benefit of the job.
You can't go through life believing that
CNN and dateline is the best source of
news and they have no hidden motivated.
Absolutely.
They certainly do.
But here's the other part of the problem.
The format is incredibly
flawed and antiquated.
Yeah.
The format of getting the entire world's
news in an hour with 18 minutes of
commercials is ridiculous.
You can't get it that way,
cause they're going to pick and
choose the things that are exciting.
It's an entertainment show about events.
That's what it really is.
Yeah.
It's an entertaining show about events
and that's why you have this asshole with
a tie who speaks like
your girlfriend's father.
Like,
oh,
this fucking guy again.
You know what I mean?
Like this is,
this is who he is and he's the reason
Kim Kardashian posting a selfie sign a
deal for $100 million is
the start of the news.
That's the,
if it bleeds,
it leads.
That's what they say.
And there's no doubt that that political
leanings by journalists bleed into the
news.
I mean,
there's too much credit.
It's a shit on.
Assume they're does shitty
way to get information.
That's not how any of us should get
information and they shouldn't have it
anymore.
It was important back in the day when
they didn't have fucking reading,
you know,
and they would get on TV and nobody,
I mean you'd read your newspaper in the
morning and then the afternoon you would
listen to the news or
you would watch the news.
It became on television.
That's we are at war with Japan.
What's his,
you hear on the news,
we're at war with Japan now.
You would get Twitter alerts like
way before that shit would have,
when you see rob Walter
Cronkite back in the day,
it was just very matter of fact,
he got on and read the news.
And one of the things,
there's a famous story I think about the,
the guy who was ran 60 minutes
and he came in and he said,
good news and bad news.
Good news is got very
high ratings last night.
And bad news is we've got very high
ratings last night and the news will never
be the same.
So in other words,
we now have a lot of
pressure to get ratings.
And what does that mean
sensationalize things?
What does that mean?
Focus on what's wrong,
not what's right for fear.
It's an input.
It's a disproportionate in a non and non
accurate view of the world because by
only focusing on these negative things
and not focusing on the fucking hundreds
of millions of positive things
that are happening all the time,
all over the world,
you're getting this distorted version of
reality that threatens people and makes
people alert and uh,
react to stress.
You're reacting to danger.
A sense of fear.
I feel like isis lives next door
and run and more importantly,
I'm going to get a fucking lion killer.
Let the guy fucking rant about Isis and
Jesus Christ and you just can't stop.
And Keller,
he's trying,
he's trying to do some comedy.
[inaudible]
says,
no,
you got this man can,
are you guys going on about
Isis in fucking Marina del Ray?
You're like,
hey,
yeah,
but my,
my uncle,
no,
I wasn't.
I was going to say that.
What,
what I think that the damage done is
that you don't get any real information.
Like,
like I was having a conversation,
somebody who really knows the Middle East
and they were like,
nobody ever talks about.
The biggest problem with two
things with first of all,
the Middle East is the Sunni Shia schism.
The idea that you start there,
some we don't even know
where to start with a debate.
We start talking about Isis,
we start talking about the problems that
bother us and we don't actually really
know where the source of the problem is.
We don't know how it
started because we're not,
you don't get it from
what you were saying,
you don't get it from,
we get them from CNN and dateline
suppose does that you're not supposed to,
you didn't,
you know,
it used to be you have to wait for the
news to come out yet to get a newspaper
and then you get alerted to the important
stories in the radio or on the news,
on the news,
on television.
We don't need that anymore.
It's just antiquated and it's dangerous
because it gives you a version of the
world.
It's not entirely accurate.
It's very slanted because
that's what you're scared of.
So that's what you're tuned into.
So that's where they can sell advertising.
Hey,
we scared the fuck out
of a hundred people.
Did you see nightcrawler?
Yes,
it's fucking excellent.
Excellent.
And it's all about this.
Nightcrawler is all about this.
First of all,
Jake Glue and hall is a bad motherfucker.
How did he not win a,
he should have won an award.
Think awards are stupid.
I agree.
He's,
he's just,
he's just excellent.
It's an excellent movie.
It doesn't mainly really,
really,
really dope ass.
A dodge challenger makes the hands right.
It's not even starts balling.
Yeah.
What is that ball?
And it gets red challenger with black.
Get there faster.
I love how he talks to his sidekick.
Yeah,
it's an amazing,
Jeremy.
If don't,
don't,
don't give it.
Don't spoil it.
Folks that are listening.
Oh my bad.
Goddamn a spoiler alert.
And I see every movie shit,
man.
Tell him I go,
don't tell me about the fights
or whatever you've done.
14 seconds.
That's all I'm going to say.
It pisses me off when he misses the fight.
So I text him all the results.
He says,
you know,
that's part of your job is
to be a pay attention to.
I'm aware of that and
when he doesn't see it,
I'm like,
fuck that noise.
I'm aware.
Tape taping a defensive stance because
fucking Cobra for impact because I get
mad.
I'm like,
Brennan,
don't tell me anything.
Work waterway to play.
I don't want to play volleyball.
I go,
don't tell me anything.
Cain Valasquez ends up winning.
He punches him in the face.
Man,
I got to teach you.
You know,
what are you doing?
You're out there in the wild dude.
My workouts are at night.
A lot of times it's hard to just beach.
Think about death.
The Alexander Emily Yanko workout.
Not The fight or what?
What's the difference?
Just a lot.
A lot of back work and crime.
A lot of packers,
shit,
ups and crimes.
Is Crime just to cry?
Oh man,
that's hilarious.
How about Brendan's apart?
It's beautiful.
It's got a God damn full head of hair.
If I had that much hair,
I do weird shit.
You don't want a man because you know,
I've been taking a break from training
and I haven't grown my hair out since I
was in.
I Dunno man.
So for me to grow it out,
she can't have really
hairstyle trained a ton.
Putting Gel in your hair.
Feel like you know dude,
I've been a,
I don't know.
I know you got to,
you had a neck injury for awhile.
I've been getting this.
Uh,
this
dude does rolfing and he uses a,
he's got this fucking crazy,
it's like this metal piece that's wrapped
in like a soft plastic or got thin
sheet of plastic around it,
you know,
so it's like semi soft on the outside,
but underneath it's iron or steel,
whatever the fuck it is.
This shit breaks up.
Scar tissue.
Woo.
This shit hurts.
Soggy.
Okay,
so now here east of he
and sit through that.
Oh,
I had it done on my hands to get done
once a month or once a week or gangster.
Not Mom once a month.
Once a week.
Know what's weird is people be like,
oh shop,
your neck hurts and this is my fault.
We'll have random people that got,
let me see it and I'll just sit down and
they start cracking in and this random
girl was grabbing my neck
was like your ribs out,
your ribs out.
Oh I'm sitting there,
her weight's on my shoulder.
Push on my head.
I'm thinking I don't know this woman.
I let her do it.
You can't do that.
You can't.
I know man,
we know you know a lot about this stuff.
What do we know about like when you,
if my lower back hurts,
is that a function of inflammation?
Well here's the deal and you
don't know until you get an Mri,
you need to get an Mri.
Okay.
I got an MRI recently cause I
wanted to get a look at my back,
no exact what's going on
and everything's cool.
Just some disc degeneration,
minor disc degeneration,
a little bit of soreness and inflammation
is really nothing to do for that.
No,
not much you can do.
So it's all,
it's all fine.
Like it's fine to push myself,
but you got to know that
you're fine to push yourself.
Yeah.
Badge if you don't you say that.
But if you don't know,
it's just guessing like
people that have psychiatric.
I'd be like,
they keep going.
Oh my sciatic nerve.
Well,
do you know what that is?
That's a bulging disc that's
pushing on your nerve.
Like you're making it look like
your nerve is acting weird.
You know you're nervous
being washed by your fucking,
just the,
the soft shit in between your bones in
your spine is pushing into your fucking
nerve.
That's serious shit.
And people that ignore that or try to
work through it like you can fuck yourself
up.
I know three dudes that
have had significant neck
surgery because of impinged
nerves where it was causing
atrophy to their muscles.
Three dudes,
very close guys from my gym.
I know one dude that can't,
he can't do Jujitsu anymore.
We can't,
we can't roll.
Can't do it.
It's a fine line though.
Like a lot of guys,
there'll be messed up and like,
Nah,
I'm not going to see a doctor.
And then now you know
the UFC insurance policy,
I'm like,
damn,
my wrist hurts.
I get an x ray.
That was damn my nose hurts.
I get an x ray,
you should do that fucking
professional fighter,
man.
The UFC must be like fucking shop man.
What's wrong with him?
He jammed his thumb,
man.
You're not the only one.
A lot of dudes are doing
that and they should.
They should.
That is a giant part of
what you do for a living.
I have awards.
You got to know
the years they sound,
they're silly.
That's silly.
You can look this is what you like that
that's antagonistic sort of relationship
with people when they have injuries.
Yeah.
That's a very fucking tricky
you think to beats me.
It's weird though man,
because you,
you know like back in the day it's like,
oh I want to be tough.
So now like it's my own ego
when I have to call my manager,
but like dude,
I,
yeah,
am I,
I got to get my neck checked out.
It takes usually three or four weeks
for me to talk myself into getting the
doctor cause it's like this ego thing,
right?
I want to be a bitch man.
Like,
like,
like metro was in town.
He's like,
you want to train?
I really can't go real
hard wrestling right now.
I want to with him and Barnett,
I just can't.
And so I was like,
Oh,
I'm busy man.
That's smart man would
do to try to ignore pain.
There's a lot of dudes,
I try to ignore pain there.
Their bodies,
why not fallen apart?
We had John Wayne par on and he
was talking about Ramon Dekkers.
Ramon Dekkers date got him to a point
where they fused his fucking ankle to his
shinbone cause he had broken,
it's so many times just full power kicks.
He would kick so fucking hard and smash
into elbows and knees and shins and he
shattered his ankle so many times from
his right kick that they had a fuse it so
he would hobble,
when he walked new tape that fucker
up and get in there and they told him,
they were like,
you can't kick with this and we're going
to have to fucking amputate your leg if
you break it again.
And he would wait a little while
fighting a southpaw and say,
you know what?
Fuck it switched dances and
just start attacking with me.
Dude.
Fumes,
a bad motherfuckers
fucking ankle didn't bend.
He still,
yeah,
he passed away right at 43.
Oh No.
Died of a heart attack at 43.
Oh boy.
Riding a bike apparently.
And he was one of the all time great dogs.
Phenomenal.
If you don't know who he is,
resets a compromise.
It gets in your artery.
Ramon Dekkers woo.
He was good.
Oh Dude.
Just the most average savage,
so,
so aggressive.
And he was like,
he was a Dutch guy,
but the Dutch people were very big.
Yes.
Like the average height for
a Dutch man is six feet tall.
It's people in Europe.
Yeah.
The tallest people in Europe and
a lot of big and he was little.
So he,
he had to be tough.
Uh,
and he was one of the first guys to go
over to Thailand and beat the ties and
tie boxer.
You think about how tough he is,
your ankles fused to your fucking leg,
man.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Your foot,
knee and your ankle,
like all the way down is one piece.
Yeah.
That's not good.
Don't use it.
Definitely don't use it.
And then gets in a fight and fuck.
He's definitely a guy who doesn't
know what to do with his time.
Like he,
he's just not going to quit this.
Tell Him we might have to amputate your
leg cause you've shattered your bones so
many times.
The whole thing is like you to be honest,
it's not that it's gonna be like,
Ooh man.
It's Kinda how I feel about Madonna at 56.
Sean her ass off like an
old fighter who won't quit.
Just take a look at this.
How dare you make that comparison.
Sorry.
No,
he fucked the whole thing
up with Eddie Murphy.
Shrek thing.
Yeah.
But this might just be just sad.
Madonna's an oddity at this point.
I think so.
When people go to see her,
it's an oddity.
She's a 60 year old
woman in her underwear.
I was dancing around with a bunch of gay
guys following her everywhere she goes
and hanging on her.
Every word.
Yeah.
Yanked off stage the other day.
Well,
I know that,
I don't know.
I think fucking Brian Williams was me.
What happened?
Ah,
she uh,
that she was dancing the things
was like yank the Cape off,
but like God,
her neck.
Oh my God.
Gangsters.
Bitch.
Right off this stage.
Is there video of that?
Oh yeah.
Oh,
we got to see them play it for us.
Play it again.
Jamie.
She gets to cap.
She'll be 80 Sean her body off.
Should you best that she fired whoever
made that case was brought by her dead.
Oh yeah,
he's probably dead.
He's probably Dutch.
Probably beat him to death.
He's remember Madonna beat someone
to death with a hammer and they just,
you see the body just
scoop out the back door.
It was like the 19th,
the little hammers.
It was the 1930s.
Just had a carpenters hammer.
Just fucking impaler.
Oh Shit.
Let me see that again
one more time please.
Oh,
look at this bitch.
Ah,
oh.
Oh my God.
She's old dude.
When you fall like that and you're old,
you could break a hip
champ.
Oh my God.
That's crazy.
She handled that really well by the way.
She fell really well.
She really did.
She could have got her that tailbone up.
She has zero as she got her,
got her a muscle on her ass.
I was filming this movie
and Kevin James Zookeeper.
Yes.
Boston chasing scene.
We had a bike chasing scene and I kept
hitting the front brakes on the bike
because the front brakes
where my left hand,
the back bakes for my right hand and
I'm riding this bike and I'm hitting him
with this thing and I hit the front
bags and go flying over the handlebars.
All the concrete like
tumble into the grass.
I did it like three times.
So you're doing that.
You did your own stock in other words?
Yeah,
I did all of it.
One where a guy jumped meet a bike jump
where it was a stunt man right where he
had to,
he had a ride down this hill and then hit
this ramp and jump over this flight of
stairs and land on the ground.
And the,
he did that.
He was like a stunt jumper but all the
other shit I did and they wanted to have
a stunt guy do the fall like cause that's
what would eventually happen was was
he was supposed to jam his flag into my
wheel and then I go flying and he takes
off.
But I fell so spectacularly that
they use my actual fall in the,
in the actual movie body.
And did,
did you do a judo roll or what happened?
I got to see,
oh look at you.
You're sick.
I think I rolled in one of them and one
of them maybe I fell a bunch of times.
One of them.
It was cool because I landed in the grass.
Like I hit the curb and went flying.
I got to see this reality.
I can't believe I've been,
Jane's a Good Dude,
Huh?
He's a very good dude.
He was very,
very kind.
The great guy,
dude.
How about stuntmen?
They're fucking crazy man.
Stunt men in a crazy,
I have people tell me all the time,
I'd probably say once a week,
dude,
you should get into some
stunt were no fucking cool.
That's easy.
That's how boss hurt his neck.
It was one of the things I was going
to get to his boss when he was on,
I think sons of anarchy.
Yep.
One of those shows,
he did a stunt and he's doing his own
stunt work and they landed them on his
head and bang,
it just fucked his neck up.
And then he had to get his discs fuse.
Didn't you have a friend
who does stonework?
And he like was in a coma for grid,
can't taste food anymore.
You got to hit the back
of his head and uh,
lost his sense of taste and
smell and it's never come back.
And his testosterone,
my,
so we had to go on.
But,
um,
I,
I was doing,
I was doing the Goldbergs and
this girl had to fall down on her,
just fall on her back.
And I thought,
and I said,
she was a girl and,
and I,
and it was on a linoleum floor,
like a real cafeteria floor.
And I said,
how are you going to do that?
And she goes,
just fall.
And I said,
I know,
but then she just boom,
just hit,
hit,
hit it five times.
No,
she was a stunt woman
five times and I said,
I said,
how are you doing?
She goes,
I'll be sorta mall.
She was falling.
I remember when I did death
valley and I had a judo flip,
this giant guy,
Joe or na's,
this guy Joe or Knaus who is a,
well this,
this was crazy.
It's got [inaudible] who's a giant stunt
man on death valley and I'm awesome.
Works all the time.
Just pig,
big judo guy.
And He,
we had this desk like this uh,
thing and I,
he's a vampire.
He jumps on me and I had to flip them
over and I thought it was going to break
away furniture.
It really wasn't breakaway furniture.
It was as hard as it gets and I just
would throw him and he would flip over me
and throw him slip and fall on his back.
He did it over and over and just,
you know,
they get paid well to do that.
They get paid well,
not well,
not well enough.
I would never do.
It depends on what you have to do.
I mean,
if you have to do something like
that is definitely not well enough.
Oftentimes they were padding
and they do their best,
but look,
they're taking bumps no matter what.
And they're,
their head's getting jostled around and
dragged by a horse they say is the most
dangerous resolute.
Fuck that.
And they have to do that
for some fucking movies,
man.
There's not much you can do about it.
You get dragged by a horse,
you,
you got to do it very specifically and
you gotta be really careful because they
can't really stop the horse.
They've got to be,
how do you control the Horse?
You control it with another horse,
but you got to let that horse go for
a while and they spooked the horse.
The horse is trained to run and
you get dragged and that is,
they consider the most dangerous.
How about car shit?
Well,
they're doing car chases and shit
like fucking hangover to listen to.
Someone was in a movie.
Oh Jay Quillen hall.
They were saying that that fucking movie
there was not CGI when they did those
car accidents and that movie.
All the car accidents in nightcrawler.
I'm pretty sure it was him.
See,
please Google that.
So it wasn't that he
was in too much crazy.
What about the fucking high speed chase?
I don't want to say anything more.
I will say that the one time there's
some serious shit enough so that you like
get the fuck Outta here.
Like this is real.
This is not CGI.
Apparently that was one of the things
that the director wanted to do.
I'm pretty sure that's the case.
And you know people clown and Tom
Cruise for kind of being a sissy,
but he did all his own stunts
and mission impossible.
I heard when he hung from that building,
that's pretty gang.
He does his own driving stunts too.
Does running and,
and he's a powerful guy.
Whatever the fuck that movie was
that he did with Cameron Diaz,
he had some crazy movie with whether,
Oh,
I like that movie and
if days or what it was,
no,
no.
That's a great,
that's a great movie to know.
The edge of tomorrow.
That's very underrated.
Good movie.
That's a movie that almost
suffers from him being too wacky.
I agree ma'am.
As a beast of a movie.
Yeah.
Like if that movie was like someone else,
like will Smith,
will Smith's a little
wacky to [inaudible] movie?
Yeah.
If you,
if like,
who would have been,
who would like Tom Cruise
killed it and that movie,
by the way,
edge of tomorrow.
He kills so good.
Oh yeah.
But if someone else did an
equal job of killing it,
like okay,
here's one Travolta Daniel Day,
Lewis of Daniel Day Lewis was,
he's too serious though
for a fucking year.
Saifai crazy movie.
That was a realistic
Scifi movie that wasn't,
you know what I mean?
It wasn't like so stupid that you put,
you put that heart throb from Thorin there
that things he knew well that boys up
a what man?
Tom Cruise.
I did a reading with him and
I took his body and I took,
I spent a good four hours,
Tom Cruise [inaudible] I spent
a good four hours with him.
Well,
he'll tell you he was there.
We talk.
How tiny is he?
He's not,
he's not as tall as I am,
but he's very stout.
He's got wide center of gravity,
thick hips,
fixed shoulders,
sloped shoulders as you asked.
I would make out with them,
make out with them while if all went down,
if you were like canopy,
well,
under a canopy,
you've got to push back.
Guys made a corner,
put me in a corner,
don't you?
And you were playing a
gay lover and a movie,
but in the movie you don't ever make out.
Right.
But he wants to make out
with you just one time,
just like pretend that this way we're
going to look and where together we're gay
lovers.
Well,
this is our movie.
I,
after I did the rating,
I see him six months later at
this big Hoity toity party.
I talked to him for a good hour,
maybe hour and a half to wake up over
the past 10 I remember saying to myself,
five minutes,
even an hour and a half brokers like,
oh fuck.
Half an hour and a half by himself.
Just,
we talked about one on one for an hour
to have killed Americans for an hour and
a half.
Oh,
I kept it.
I kept him though.
You ain't lying a little bit though.
I got an,
I got a witness.
Jeremy Pivot.
You tell him.
Anyway,
he's got a funny story about it.
It doesn't matter,
but we're sitting there
talking for 15 minutes and he
and I remember looking at him going
and he was complimenting me on my job.
I did it in the reading and Jeremy was,
he said,
you did a good job 13 times.
I said,
13 he goes,
yes.
I said,
good.
So we talked for a long time.
They've talked about kids,
everything else.
And I remember thinking to myself,
this is so lame.
And I was a grown man and
I remember thinking myself,
I'll go,
I just really want to be his friend.
I hope.
He says,
let's hang out again.
I remember saying,
I would love to just,
I was so star struck and I really liked
him and he was so nice and I figured,
you know what's,
what happens when you give them a list
kind of friends now I kind of know him
kind of,
Eh,
that didn't happen.
And I remember I said,
no,
I was going to happen.
I looked at my house,
I go,
I know I,
this is what I said to him.
I go,
so how you been?
What's it like just to be the king?
Is it just generally
boring or a lot of fun?
He just looked at him and then it's a,
you know,
it is what it is.
And,
and we started talking.
I tried to make them laugh and I did.
I've seen him in person at Tom Cruise.
He was the first time I've ever been like,
I was at this party.
Everyone was there,
athletes and I was going to the bathroom.
I was going to expect any him and I
saw much when it first time everyone.
Oh Shit.
Tom Cruise and he was tiny,
tiny like five,
six,
uh,
yeah,
five.
Yeah.
Five six one 60 yeah.
Tiny I think thicker than one
60 I think I get five days,
but then again,
he's in shoes.
Probably might have some
weird shoes probably,
but he's thick.
He's thick.
He's got a fan.
I'm a fan man.
Run the a fan.
He's got a deck on them.
Kids get it.
We did take a piss together.
What about us?
How long pice together?
You didn't look at his dick.
I was at the urinal right next to him.
We were talking about he
took a long pice together.
What the fuck does that mean?
We talked about Dan cables run.
How long you're pissing.
We've talked about Dan Gables
wrestling camp cause I went to,
Dan gave us intensive
wrestling camp in Iowa.
My between my junior and senior year of
high school and he said he would have
loved to have but he couldn't afford it.
We are holding our dicks and I remember,
I remember thinking I'm not
pissing with Tom Cruise.
I pissed with Dennis Miller ones.
That's not bad.
That's my story.
Doesn't mean somewhere like
NBC or something like that.
Hey Joe,
you got a hit on your hands there?
It was like fear factor
first got on the air.
I'm like,
Oh shit,
I'm pissing right next to desk Miller.
I wanted to ask him,
man,
what's it was all his
fucking George Bush shit.
You're buddies with George Bush.
I didn't have the balls.
No,
I'm wanting to ask him.
That's when it became George Bushes Buddy.
Is there anyone now that would startle
you or make you star struck a lot of
people.
Really?
For sure.
Yeah,
I got you.
I got weirded out when
I met Anthony Bordain.
There was a few years back,
but I got weird about all the UFC is now.
A lot of them are Trans
Jiu Jitsu every day.
Wow.
He trains you just to every day.
He does two hour classes every day.
He does an hour of classes
all over the place.
Even when he's on the road,
he was doing wrong.
He was rolling in Budapest,
Hungary.
I'm a big fan of a picture of him on
Twitter with his fucking white belt and a
geeky showing up at this fucking Jiujitsu
pleased to Carlson Gracie's place.
Told me he was doing all top game.
He said he was shitting
how bone fragments.
God Damn.
He said they all have old school.
Carlson Gracie top game.
Oh my God.
I said I'm shitting out bone
fragments and you gave me so,
so you're a little star struck the
who would you be starstruck with free.
I got starstruck when I met Arnold
Schwarzenegger and he knew who I was.
Oh you did?
Nice to meet you.
So,
oh,
I know.
I was like,
what's up dude?
I got that camera.
Very good job.
I was like UFC fan.
He's a UFC fan.
Arnold.
I mean,
yeah,
it was a big one.
That was a big one.
Um,
if I met Clint Eastwood,
even though I think he's a silly bitch,
you know that thing he did with the
Obama when he's talking down to them in a
chair,
it's still Clint Eastwood.
I mean,
he's a crazy old man now.
Kind of Clint Eastwood.
He's give him his props.
Rog Josie Wales.
Great movies period.
It's on pumps and much of our
live in boy o high plains drifter.
Come on.
So I gotta be honest with you guys.
I'm a lot younger than the clinics
was not that big of a dance hall dude.
It's a shame if you're a family
dollar million dollar baby.
Unforgiven gypsy the unforgiven.
No,
I didn't do the good,
the bad,
the ugly.
It just goes on and on.
Then you guys know he was before our time.
Man Clean.
She's old as fuck,
dude.
Don't try to put it as he's older.
His Clark Tori.
You guys dirty Harry.
When we were kids,
when we were like little kids every
which way was loose every which way,
but loose was the big enemies,
which meant that he was already so old.
He wasn't doing the cowboy movies anymore.
He was like this old
bare knuckle boxer too.
Back in those days.
Oh my God.
Amy Puts set.
His girlfriend was in every movie here.
This chick Sandra Lockhart was,
she has with the bond,
every fucking movie he did.
Every movie he did dirty shit.
That was his girlfriend.
Motherfucker had this one was in the,
they put her in every movie.
Every movie was him and his girlfriend
until they broke up and when they broke
up,
like part of their breakup was that he
had to get her some sort of a development
deal and then she sued for,
she sued him because she said that
like allegedly I should say this is all
allegedly I'm reading this online.
It could be all be bullshit,
but she thought that he was blocking
her movies from being made dad.
It was like it was an ugly
composes his own music.
All the jazz and there's all the scores.
Sure,
sure he does.
He composes in and now what's the movie?
A high plains drifter.
That's his,
that's his score.
Have you seen shortly,
have you seen interviews with him?
Why?
He's very old now.
I don't,
that's what I'm saying.
He did American sniper.
That's what they say or was the onset
and they just know he directed it.
You know he's not,
he's not so old that he can't do that.
That's what he's not all up in there.
Like frick you think
he's all you American,
right.
My mind.
Your p's and q's about
claims would do me a favor.
What?
Chris cow motherfucker.
I think he lied.
Hold on.
Hold on a second.
It's not hating on someone.
It's tell the truth.
It's hating on the rest of the population
to pretend that truth doesn't exist
and to not take those facts
into consideration when
you're discussing a story.
I can't say,
hey,
hit that,
but he's the greatest
American sniper ever,
ever.
Whether he's lying or not.
That's true.
Those are facts.
What do you know about that?
I know what America tells me.
What do you know about Clint
Eastwood directed American sniper?
What do you know about it?
For sure it's a movie.
That's what they tell and it's a
good movie according to some pizza.
I haven't seen it.
You want me to tell you what happens?
Ours for your fucking hated it.
I have a video of Ari Shaffir
and Thompson girl arguing.
Thompson Gara says it's amazing
and Ari Shaffir says retarded.
I listened to it on your show.
Hate on it.
It's fucking crazy.
Well,
Teesha join us.
If what he said was true.
Does he not have a point?
Was there a rubber baby that was
like obviously a rubber baby?
Not really.
I thought it was a real baby.
It was a real baby.
Jamie has something to say to them.
I don't,
I don't go to the movies and be like,
God damn,
that baby looks fake.
This is ridiculous.
Clint Eastwood come on.
That is splitting hairs.
Well,
that's just one thing.
I mean are you had a boost in my
worries when I go to the movies.
The famous baby,
the big baby.
Come on,
get the fake baby.
That looks real.
Hold on.
We'll see.
You just saw it for a brief second.
If you're staring at the baby.
Picture the fake baby right now.
It looks like a baby.
I'm cool with it.
It seems fine.
I'm not really paying attention to it.
Okay.
That was it.
And your boy,
he's hating on it.
No,
there's more apparently some real
fake baby shit going on later.
Oh,
here it goes.
Okay.
That's fake as fuck Louis Thumb.
Oh God.
Mark is.
Fuck it does look,
you don't
drastic Parkman like that.
T rex,
man.
I'll tell you why they think
you're being dishonest.
You don't think it's ridiculous looking
at his thumb moving show that the sat.
No,
it's not even.
That's a joke.
That's someone being silly.
They're joking around because
it's a fucking rubber baby.
Oh,
come on.
The baby can only work a certain amount
of hours and they got union rules,
so it's a bad movie
because that baby's face.
I had to work with babies.
It's a pain in the ass.
Listen,
I don't think it's a bad movie because
I don't think it's a bad movie cause I
didn't see it,
but I definitely don't
think that just look,
you got to,
I don't want to pay attention to the baby,
but apparently the baby
was only one issue,
that's for sure.
Just look terrible.
I didn't see the movie movie
was implausible was ridiculous.
I was just disappointed that
I didn't see it at that,
that he,
he,
he lied a lot about certain
things and I think that's a bump.
Fuck.
He still is the greatest
American sniper ever.
Okay.
That's a weird thing to say though.
Like you don't give a fuck.
So you,
you were not willing to overlook
Anderson Silva a pass on doing steroids.
Interesting.
It's interesting and Brian
Willing to pass though.
Yeah,
that's true.
You're very inconsistent
that
we've gone with the wind.
Just kind of like a blind tire
career blind patriotism to that.
Right?
Like you recognize that he's
a greatest American sniper,
so all the other stuff you
just don't want to talk about.
No,
I'll talk about it.
But him being a great American sniper
is the biggest thing that that should
Trump all of it.
Yeah.
He lied.
He didn't take out people,
uh,
during that trip we say Katrina.
Yeah.
He didn't do that.
He didn't beat up Jesse Ventura.
Yeah,
I know.
Cool man.
But just killed 160 terrorist.
Yeah,
I'm cool man.
I'm gonna overlook some of that shit.
You're still a great American
and they're both true.
It is true.
I don't,
I don't know what's true.
Obviously I'm talking about interviews
and people's books and all this different
shit.
I didn't really,
unless we were there,
we really don't know what
the fuck actually happened.
But they can both be true.
Like I've met people that were movie
stars that were also tremendous wires.
I mean,
I don't want to name names with the dude
was a movie star and he's a tremendous
liar.
Just makes up stories about all kinds of
things and you would never believe you
like this stuff.
You know,
it's just a complete fabrication.
Things that never happened to him and
the guy's worth millions and millions of
dollars.
But one thing we do know is he was a navy
seal and he was a sniper who killed a
lot of people for,
for America.
He risked his life for America.
Hold on.
So he's okay with,
hold on,
hold on.
For sure.
Relaxed.
He had,
he went to buds training.
Yes,
he became a navy seal.
Very difficult to do and he's
really good at killing people.
Uh,
that's a skill set as a sniper that I'm
sure it takes a lot of things I don't
know about.
I don't think that that necessarily means,
and I'm sorry to say this and that,
that means he's a good guy.
I don't
think that necessarily means
that girls aren't getting,
it doesn't mean he gets a pass for lying.
Uh,
and direct a making up stories
about not only killing looters,
New Orleans who are stealing stuff,
which is already illegal and considered
murder under the laws of this land.
But he didn't do it so well,
but that's what he was
saying he was doing,
which is very strange.
I haven't read the book so I don't want
to talk too much and I haven't seen the
book or the movie.
All you do is no his name.
Let me play devil's advocate here.
Just as a,
as a person who like,
let me just be completely
objective ticket,
a wild shot at this.
Now this might not be the case,
so I'm just put that out there in the
advanced would if he decided to tell all
these tall tales because the book would
be better and he wanted to sell a book
and make a lot of money selling a book
and he didn't understand the kind of
media storm and that these checks,
these are these stories going to
be checked and double checked.
And when he decided to do was add a
bunch of fabricated shit to a real story
because you know,
first of all he's probably psychologically
damaged from shooting a hundred and
fucking 60 people.
Like I don't think you'd
get away from that for free.
I don't think you'd go to war.
And I don't think anybody
rides for free anymore.
I think you do.
You take in a lot of psychological damage.
Everybody says that.
So it could possibly be that the guy
just said all that shit because he wanted
to sell books.
It's possible.
And is that crazy?
Does that make him a bad guy?
Because I don't know.
It was government's not
paying them very well.
Right.
Good point.
He's not making much money,
so he fabricates his stories.
His book is a New York Times bestseller.
He gets all this money.
Is that,
that's the deal.
It's all possible.
All I'm trying to say is this.
I'm not,
I don't know Chris Kyle.
I didn't,
I don't know anything about the guy.
I don't know if he's a bad guy,
a good guy.
I,
I'm,
I tend to be pretty patriotic,
so usually,
yeah,
so usually he gets,
he gets,
he gets a lot of leeway with me.
When you're a soldier and you went
to Iraq and you do all that stuff.
Yes.
For me,
that's how I am,
but I do think that I still have to
at least like what Joe was saying,
when you found out that
you made up these stories,
that's kind of a bummer for me.
It's just disappointing that he
did lie about something like,
I don't give a shit trying to
sell blue for whatever reason.
It could very well have been that he was
trying to sell books and he could also
very well be that we were talking before.
Maybe we need to understand a little
bit better since none of us went to war.
What kind of mental toll that takes on
a person and that you kind of shouldn't
expect them to be completely fine with
everything when they come back and some
of them are going to make shit up and
maybe they're making shit up because
reality is so fucking crazy that they
don't want to deal with it anymore.
Or maybe so they just,
he thinks it's real.
Maybe he maybe had a situation where he
was in New Orleans and you thought about
shooting didn't happen,
but he goes to war.
Something happens like,
yeah,
well it's good for the book.
Right?
And by the no one could understand what
the fuck that guy's life was like except
for him.
And it's not even given him an excuse.
What we're saying is we're just
looking at the possibilities,
right?
Like instead of saying,
Hey,
this is a guy that was full of shit,
he lied about that
and he's a bad person.
This is a guy that was forced to do
some anti human shit for the government.
People are complicated.
And you and I have talked about this.
A lot of people,
we know certain people that are high
profile people that get criticized a lot
and they're hated on and you know
them pretty intimately and it's like,
yes,
they've done some things.
There are also complicated people.
They also do incredibly good things
for people that nobody knows about.
So there's,
there's no question that people
generally are not black and white.
They have a bad side.
They have a good side.
And I know I do.
I know I do.
I know I have a lot about,
I haven't,
I know a lot of things about myself.
I'm not that proud of.
So if this is black and white,
this is very black and white.
If you didn't like the film,
American sniper hero,
fucking terrorist diseases,
we should fear is a Jew.
That's what they should do.
They should.
This is how they should check.
If you're a terrorist.
We've uh,
been,
did you like American sniper?
No.
Go to the right.
Did you like American sniper?
Yes.
Go to the lab is when you
go to the right though.
You don't get on the plane.
Dammit.
Brennan arch fear would chew you up
if you guys had this conversation.
He gets sun,
so anchoring it sunny.
I get an eerie tune in to hear him
ranting with the Thompson [inaudible].
It's hilarious.
The two of them together.
I got to eventually put this online,
but they get so fucking in
each other's face about it.
They're like yelling like at something
like really important to talk about.
I do think it's,
it's,
it's important to be charitable about
just how complicated human beings are.
Yes.
It doesn't mean you
don't call somebody out.
Just so contrived at all.
The fact that they didn't show him
getting shot was actually a good choice
and then at the end of like he
was killed that day and writing,
oh,
we play the whole thing.
I'll put it on.
I'll put the whole thing in
Boston winters communist,
they big go.
They go at it for like 10 minutes.
He was mad that at the end they don't
show him getting killed is mad about
everything.
You thought it sucked.
He brought a bunch of people from his
Twitter feed to go to the movie and heckle
and they all went,
they filled the audience,
the the entire audience
already best friends.
I would've got a recipe like UFC
fighter beats the shit out of Bahrain.
His friends during the Mexican side,
not the time to get arrested.
This is not for you.
Don't do that man.
Beat up a bunch of chairs.
Coffee forever,
son,
Chris Calvert.
Hey man,
terrorists.
I can be swayed.
When did you see the movie?
I did and I haven't read
the book or anything.
He knows nothing.
No bad,
no nothing.
I only read.
All I read is that the,
I looked at all the stuff
online and I was like,
wow,
that's interesting.
I haven't read it.
I don't know.
I'm,
that's incredible.
So swimming,
pinning on anything.
When someone has killed that
many people for the government,
they give him a green light to kill that
many people and to kill 160 people like
the idea of like telling
a lie about something.
It's like really no big deal.
Well that guy killing 160
people doing all these tours,
you know in war should be,
should
get $1 million from the US
government for the rest of his life.
He should be financially set
for the rest of his life.
Yeah,
no kidding.
Right?
Like how much,
how much do they actually
get when they retire?
My Buddy Buddy's Delta force was
delta force and he said that I heard,
and I don't want to say online
because I mean it's so pitiful.
It's called hazardous duty pay.
You don't make any money,
you,
you don't have enough to live.
And if you are,
if you go to a divorce,
half of that money goes to your
wife and your personal life,
your fuck cause their divorce
rate's like 96% it's not cool man.
They should definitely
get more money and stress.
The same with cops.
Stress that's tress is insane.
It's,
it's,
it's like,
it's an unprecedented
level of success of stress.
It's so hard to deal with.
It's also really hard
when you're a sniper,
you're,
I don't know this,
but I do know that a combatant can be
even a child running munitions to a
mortar,
and if that child is doing that
or a guy's looking at you with,
with binoculars and trying to
get a beat on your position,
you take them out.
That's hard.
That's hard for a
soldier who gets command.
Take that guy out.
Should that kid shoot that woman
because she happens to be San Francisco.
The enemy,
if you watch the movie,
it's sucks.
Word hard is not even a,
it's not a good enough word.
No,
it's not that.
It's hard.
It's almost impossible.
It's almost impossible to reset from
that and be a normal person without some
help.
I'm sure that's something go from doing
that to fucking walking through radio
shack with your wife.
What the hell?
That's why you know all these
guys coming back from war I,
you know,
that's one way to make America a little
bit more polite and running into a bunch
of people that just got back from
killing a bunch of other people.
Like,
you know,
people have a different attitude when
you've been to a war is a different
mentality and we have to respect that
and I think we have to consider that
that's an important as a culture,
as a society that sort of wants to gloss
over war and wants to glorify it and
make it out to be this
all this John Wayne Shit,
we have to look at what the
fuck is really happened.
These people psychologically absolute
same and the same thing with cops.
Everybody wants to shit on cops because
cops do occasionally do they do bad
things and for you that have
been done wrong by these cops,
they couldn't handle that job.
I 100% feel for you.
I 100% feel for it.
I feel bad.
I think we also have to consider the
fact that being a cop is insane job.
Some people beat calm
fucking insurance salesman.
Some people sell cars,
some people become artists.
Some people would come cops and you're
out there in your fucking pulling up to
pulling sideways a guy shooting a rifle
out of a fucking window and taking
people out.
You've got to figure out how
to sneak into the building.
He called the Swat team.
You're hiding behind your
car here in fucking bullets,
bouncing off the street.
Cops have to deal with some
issues getting shot at.
So I'm going to have much experience.
And you know how few of
them know how to fight.
That was the thing that always shocked
me when I would train with guys who had
been police officers and they
didn't know how to fight.
I'm like this is insane.
Like you don't,
you don't know any Jujitsu.
You know nothing.
Like if you get into
scrambled with somebody,
what do you do?
Do you know how to get it?
Like they don't know anything.
Yeah,
they freak out.
You could sign up for being a cop,
you could be a cop and you
have to just be in reasonable
shape and not completely insane.
That's it.
Yeah.
And then they get in trouble
cause they get put in these lists.
I'm not defend all cops.
Some cops are scumbags.
I get that.
But in general they're good people
and they get put in these situations.
Why do you think in general,
all people are good people.
I agree,
but then you get put in these situation
where they have no experience.
They don't know if this kid's
going to shoot her in us,
so like,
Dang my life,
his they shoot,
and then there's this big uproar.
It's similar to what we were
talking about earlier with referees.
Referee's make a mistake,
you're making a mistake and a guy's
going to take some fucking punishment
because of that mistake.
You're not designed to handle those
high pressure situations or you're not
qualified because you don't understand
martial arts or you're just not good at
your job,
but for whatever reason,
not focused,
whatever the fuck it is,
it makes you fuck up.
But if you fuck up as a referee,
it's way worse than if Bruce Buffer
fucks up as an announcer at Bruce buffer
mispronounces Brian Cave.
You know,
you're like,
Oh God,
my name.
It's not that bad.
You know what I'm saying?
If a cop fucks up,
someone gets shot and dies or he gets
shot and dies or he sees someone gets shot
and died,
that he could've prevented.
All that stuff is too much for people
to tough just to manage and to have that
go on day after day.
What do you have to look forward to
when you're 25 they give you a watch.
What do you look at?
All the friends that you've had along
the way that a blown their brains out or
drank themselves to death
or we'll fill in the blank,
done all kinds of crazy shit.
My,
my buddy,
my buddy was a swat team sergeant and he
said he knew he had to get out when he
was sitting down next to a body that they
had shot and the corners are doing all
their vests and he started eating
a sandwich and didn't occur to him.
And he was like,
I'm sitting right next
to our body and I'm this,
not this,
not phased I,
I've been so I become
so numb and the view,
my job,
the view,
and cops too,
it's not like,
you know most Americans and they're like,
oh hell,
he had cops man.
Sweet.
Most than when they drive by.
Most people,
especially the ones I hang out with,
they're like,
no,
fuck,
come.
Americans don't want tough,
hard,
long Americans always have a problem.
And it was an interesting article that
I put up the other day that again,
I don't know if it's true,
but it was that this private,
this town in Texas hired a private
security firm and crime dropped by 61% and
that with no financial incentive for
there to be crime because they were just
compensated for their job,
for what they do for the hours on the job,
they found less crime.
They also patrolled areas that had the
most crime instead of just arbitrarily
deciding where people went based on
whatever the fuck it was that they had
decided on before.
They targeted it like very tactically
and they cut back on crime by 61% and it
costs less money.
I'm trying,
I'm confused.
So they hired a private security.
They have a fire.
The cops in 2012 right?
They fired the cops.
They said this police force is retarded.
This government police force sucks.
We're going to hire,
we're going to hire
our own security force.
We're going to vote to do this.
So they decided to do this.
They hired a security firm to become cops.
And because these guys don't have the
incentive to write tickets because they're
not getting,
it actually costs less.
It costs them less.
It cost them less and there's less crime.
They're not getting as
much revenue from it,
but they're also not arresting
people for fucking nothing.
So the P,
it's gonna adjust the attitude of
the people that live in the city.
They're not going to be upset at cops
all the time because they're not thinking
to think that cops had just trying to
pull people aside because they have,
you know,
they have criteria they have to meet,
they have quotas.
They have to make,
which is they did the
same thing with that.
They did the same thing with road signs.
Jamie,
see if you could pull that
article up cause it's on my,
it's on my Twitter feed is,
it's pretty fucking interesting.
Yeah.
There was an intersection in Holland.
It's really,
really busy and the guy took all the,
all the road signs out and cause there
were a lot of accidents said watch this.
I'm going to take all the all road signs
out and people figured it out on their
own and he does this
experiment where he walks,
he puts his hands behind his back
and walks backward into the busiest
intersection and of course never gets
hit because people figure out how to
navigate that crazy space on their own.
For sure.
That guy's going to get hit for sure.
I was there,
said the best story team,
61% seal security solutions.
They hired a bunch of fucking people
that were former seals and shit.
Oh well.
And they gave him a job.
Shit of course it makes sense.
It's fucking guys have experience.
Look at that high stress situation.
Reduce crime by 61% in just 20 months,
you know,
and also then you don't get to deal with
the militarization of the fucking legit
shit.
Yeah.
This is legit.
Just written up by the operation.
The seals,
I dunno.
I'm just reading what I'm reading online.
I've done very little actual
research out in the field.
I didn't take any plane trips
down there when it on the ground.
When you prioritize and gravitize an
area that the solution goes when we
privatized and area,
that tends to be policed better a lot
of times then if the government wants,
but now this is where fucking
some Alex Jones shit comes up.
This is what you want,
America,
you want former military garden.
Your straights holding a
gun to your children's head.
And who do you think they,
who do they listen to when
the shit hits the fan?
Fema.
God dammit.
I got plastic coffins
out there in the field.
I've seen it with my own eyes.
You this.
We have a guy with his babies.
We support our troops by
hiring many employees.
I served our country.
Dude,
I'm not mad at this at all.
Sound bad.
It's,
look,
if it works,
I think that there's a lot of things
that they do better when you take out
bureaucracy,
when you privatize that,
when you offer them an incentive to be
successful and when they have the support
of the community because it can,
community actually likes them.
Yeah,
for sure.
For sure.
They live in the community too.
Those are fucking sloppy.
Overweight,
out of shape curves for sure.
Three out of shape.
Yoked up.
Roy It up,
dude.
Yeah,
I want three.
Ronnie Coleman's just Jack.
Jack doing shit.
Yeah.
I would go like more of a thinner,
but Ian Freeman in the
machine with you man.
Damn,
I like that.
They have dogs.
I like those big canines.
They can,
they can smell out anything.
Yeah,
it's a good idea.
Use Canine.
You look at the a bomb detection,
drug,
drug detection.
Look points dropped.
The drug detection.
All right,
let's let that slide.
But the shine.
But I think that,
uh,
look,
I think there's a lot of things that
can be taken care of better by private,
by the private sector.
Look,
that's what you see with education.
Yup.
I mean,
you get a way better public,
private,
every education in most schools,
uh,
you know,
will you deal with um,
really high level private schools?
They're going to have a better
education than the best public schools.
That's just not an insurance incentive.
This man,
it's about incentives and the
teachers are more qualified,
the private schools,
right.
And a lot of day and paid more.
It's a lot of times there's some
really good public schools out there,
don't get me wrong,
but if you had to look
at them all per capita,
like what's going to be
the most formal education?
What's going to be like the
most comprehensive education?
There's a lot of people that have a lot
of money to take their kids to private
schools because they think that their
kids are going to get a better education.
It's college too.
You're looking at private universities,
man,
it was the beast.
I mean,
the good thing about universities is
that people can get scholarships if they
prove,
you know,
academically that they're superior,
that they're excellent
athletically or athletically.
Those are good things too.
They get an opportunity,
but you know,
privatizing shit though.
That's the thing that I have that
guy on the podcast fuck is his name,
Peter,
the fucking Peter Schiff,
very,
you know,
financial genius.
And he was saying one of the
big problems with colleges,
the reason why it costs so much is
because it's all subsidized by the
government.
And because it's subsidized,
he's fucking loans and these ridiculous
interest rates and nobody gets roped
into these incredible payment
that they get stuck with.
You get saddled up in debt before
you even get out of school.
You get at school,
you already oh fuck.
Tons of money.
You also have to have,
the good thing about privatization
is you can innovate according to your
circumstances.
A lot of times when you have top down,
you know a bureaucracy telling
you what to do regardless,
it's hard to innovate.
It's hard to move if you see with huge
corporations versus smaller companies,
you've got to be able to
change with the times.
And where I'm torn though,
man,
I think every kid
deserves a private style.
Education.
Every deserves it.
I know it doesn't sucks,
but I think that's where the problem is.
I think every kid deserves
the best possible education,
but we said like the best
way to make America great.
Everyone's like,
let's make America great.
What's guard our borders and keep our
criminals now this is the best way.
Make less losers,
less loser.
Put Shit tons of money on community
programs and education and counseling and
try to help people that
are in bad situations.
People that got a Shitty,
you know,
that's been societies.
You know,
it's been society's problem
from day wise always.
What do you do with the people that,
that that not losers as
his and you're a loser,
but the losers in society that
people don't get a piece of the pie.
That's always been the issue.
There's no issue at the Middle East.
We're never going to solve their
biggest issue with the Middle East.
You've got a group of people
who have no young men,
angry.
Young men know where to place
their energy and you want it.
You want to go through
the list of wipe fine.
It's just,
it's essentially governments
that are not representative,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
It's a major problem.
What do you do about it?
I think what you do about it,
if I,
if I'm obviously not a
fucking financial planner,
but if I was,
if I had a look at the country like
far as allocation of resources with tax
dollars and you know,
how much money do we have?
What do we spend it on?
I would say let's triple,
quadruple even more the amount of money
that goes into education and anybody
wants to go to college,
she'd be able to go to college.
The idea that you get go to
go to college and get saddled,
and it sounds contradictory
from what I said earlier,
because the best schools,
a lot of them are private today,
but still,
I still think that the public education
should be so much better than it is now
and being a teacher should
be worth so much more.
It should be like a,
a very prestigious position that's
difficult to get initiated with a lot of
money.
You may not need me to my teacher.
What about a really good one?
What about a really good teacher
teaches you about physiology,
about explosive,
fast twitch muscle fibers that shows
you how to get better at the one that
teaches you like kickball and fuck.
Why do we have to have that though?
Why can't awesome,
but why can't you have that kind of shit
where you have a little kickball game
with kids,
but you also explained to them this
is what's going on when you're getting
tired,
this is what's going.
This is the dog you eat has a different
effect on the way your body performs.
A lot of it doesn't take money,
but sometimes it takes
a change in approach.
Give him some fucking money they've given.
She's out there.
They get paid 50 cents an hour
has to be a standard reality.
Reality is happiest standard.
You can't understand
every dumb ass school.
A private school.
It's not easy to be a doctor,
right?
It's fucking really hard.
It's really hard.
You got to go to school.
A lot of schooling,
a lot of fucking education,
a lot of education.
You gotta it's difficult.
Most people fall out.
They don't,
they don't hack through it.
Big Committee like that
to be your teacher,
it really should.
Finland,
Finland has probably the most,
but like according to the lot of ratings,
the best school system,
they don't test.
They,
I think they have one test here.
The teachers are responsible to a large
degree in making their own curriculum.
They don't have this core curriculum.
Everybody has to learn the same thing.
But I have some good teachers,
man.
And,
and they,
and Matt,
more importantly,
they pay their teachers and their teachers
have a great deal of esteem in the
society.
And Finland school system is always
outperforming almost every other country.
And when I had the guy on who wrote
this thing called Finnish lessons,
a book,
he said,
I don't even like talking about rankings
because that's already the wrong way to
look at it.
And the problem with testing is
that that's what happens is you,
instead of focusing on understanding,
and the other really,
really interesting thing,
as he said,
we've focused on teaching people
how to solve problems as a group.
Because if you think about it,
you do the a lot of that when you work
in a corporate function test at some
point.
Because if the teachers for,
let's say they're teaching for a year,
it's like,
well let's see if these
kids learned anything.
Learning to anything.
You have to test it.
You learn,
well actually they do because they have
to rely on each other to solve problems
and we'll give them a problem and then
they'll kind of let them solve that
problem and they try to
mimic as closely as they can.
The real life situations and problems
that they're going to come across when
they are.
For example,
working for a company
like Toyota or no care,
like just that.
I don't like that,
that new age teaching men.
Why it's not new age,
it's more practically,
I think it's more practical.
I think you still have to have history.
They have to learn all that they do and
they do have testing but not nearly as
much.
Oh,
so they do have some,
they have they,
I think they have two tests.
He said no testing for
the most part they don't.
But they had the ask Brian
Cowen the way he talks.
Yeah,
no,
literally no test.
And he said they ended up tents,
just afraid of shit.
I said they have one test a year,
maybe two tests here.
Well,
there's a lot of people that do
think that you shouldn't have that.
That shouldn't be your incentive to get
a high score to absorb knowledge and
then it becomes confusing.
People say,
well,
the becomes a competitive thing like a,
my daughter got a 98 and my
daughter got a 100 sorry.
I bet you forgot your daughter's man.
You need competition like sports too.
It's like,
you know,
you can't play tag anymore.
Can't play dodge ball anymore.
They don't want losers in certain games.
My daughter played
softball and no one lost.
That's where I'm like,
I watched people.
No noise man.
How come?
No one lost but there were four and
they're barely hitting the ball.
I'm the dad keeping score.
No one.
Nothing.
That's real life to nothing,
Janine.
You're out.
Get the fuck.
You only get three swings.
Ain't home learned that losing's.
Okay,
because that's how you try harder.
Because it feels bad to lose like
no one wants their kid to feel bad.
Everybody won except teared.
You're preparing them for life.
That's that Calabasas Shit,
man.
It's not Calabasas.
Calabasas going on out here,
going out across the country.
Fox,
the little kids,
the way to shoot live underwater Colorado.
You struck out and you struck
out and got made fun of.
What's it Gallagher Bassett's.
I'll bet.
I bet there's places today in Aurora,
Colorado and all over the country
that employ these ridiculous ideas.
I don't think it's local.
I they don't know.
My life is basically,
I think life is,
if you look at your life,
life is working really hard to get to,
to accomplish something and
losing to a degree anyway.
Yeah.
Learning how to navigate those failures
are what motivate you to never feel that
shitty feeling so it
gets you off your ass.
Yes.
That's why people who are born
rich or they win the lottery early,
they're fucked.
That's why we hate those people.
The motivation just slides away.
You know?
There's very little motivation.
If you're already wealthy.
It's hard for me to relate to a dude who
just grew up super rich and he's never
had any struggles.
It's hard to sit down and
have dinner with that dude.
I feel bad for me too.
I feel too,
because they have no idea.
Especially you don't,
you know any friends that are rich that
were raised by like their nanny and
shit?
Oh yeah.
With a mom and dad are both working 20
hours a day and no one's ever home and
they are fucking weirded out.
A lost man.
Oh yeah.
Those rich guys who,
who,
who are surrounded by yes men and they
come up like wearing a shitty holiday
sweat and you're like nice fucking
sweater and it ruins his night.
You know,
you'd like no one ever
hangs out with guys.
Must've.
Yeah.
No one ever busted bog.
True sweetening.
Sweet.
You hear cut.
That sucks.
Or night.
We were playing a cold,
the silly game like running charades
like a group of us and I made fun of the
guy's boyfriend,
the girl's boyfriend.
We said that's not a word.
He had some stupid movie and he dropped.
He dropped the hat and threw his hands
in the air and went off in the balcony.
We were like,
what?
This salt that has grown from,
cause he just gets really sensitive.
Wow.
And a mouth.
That's what happens.
We don't keep score and shit.
I was on a Sitcom once and this guy
was adlibbing to something as an actor.
It was a couple comics and an actor and
the actor tried to ad Lib something and
it wasn't funny at all
and we stone faced it.
We were like,
what?
Like he just wanted to
try something different.
How about I bought it.
I say this and that,
but it was really,
he was not a bright guy and a,
I remember we just looked at
each other and we're like that.
No,
I don't think that works.
He throws the fucking script up
in the air going well with Dan.
Always said is,
I don't think that works.
You tell that to a comic.
They go,
yeah,
suck.
Something fucked up about it.
Right.
Can you tell?
It's even a lot of funny.
People just have good senses of humor
and we started laughing so hard.
Brennan pitched an idea for
this thing we're gonna do.
And I was like,
oh,
and
then I go,
let's get out of here.
Is that you're having to go?
That's,
I couldn't stop laughing.
I was like,
that's not funny.
I can't stop.
Like we do all that,
but we bust each other's balls.
Do you only thing,
I won't stand for it if you
guys made fun of my talk.
Well no,
that's the only thing I put my foot down.
It's not your life.
Do you ever,
have you ever gone back and read your
notebooks from like your first years of
comedy?
Sure have dude.
I have a notebook from
when I was driving limos.
I found it the other day.
It's amazing.
It's been awesome.
It's unbelievably bad.
I should have quit.
I bet it's awesome.
I can't believe I kept going.
I should have fucking retired so bad,
like my ideas and to this
day like sometimes I'll write
ideas that are dog shit,
but I write the ideas that
are dog should hoping like,
man,
it's some fucking something.
Write down like a half a concept and then
I'll sit down and start working on it.
Yeah.
So it might've been that,
but more likely I was just a 21 year old,
retired with a pen.
I want to tell you want to tell
story but I'll make me sound bad.
Too late.
Ah dammit.
Right.
I'm just going to tell it.
Don't judge me two minutes ago,
this better not be someone else's.
I was in Jamaica and I don't do drugs.
I don't smoke weed.
Getting high in Jamaica story again.
I know.
See I don't want to tell it now.
No,
go.
All right.
If it's someone else's story,
I don't can try finding it.
I don't get done cocaine use at all.
I was in Jamaica and
somebody gave me some,
I may have may or may not have done it
all night and I then I wrote all night
and kept waking up my
girlfriend who you know,
my old girlfriend and telling her
what amazing bits and she was like,
Huh?
I was like,
and God's a roster Farhan and I was high.
I was doing last and writing,
writing,
writing and I looked at my notes and
it was basically one long bit about God
being a roster.
Florian and I thought it was the greatest
thing I've ever written in my life and
it was just fucking chicken scratch.
And the motto is historic kids just don't
do cocaine in Jamaica because you are
never going to write anything funny.
Brian Cowen will be appearing at
some club and in the Lexington,
Kentucky,
Broadway better jokes than he
just damaged us fighting God.
Joe Frick.
Exactly.
Yeah.
This is a setup.
It's guys best bits ever.
It's ever just wants you to like really
low expectations create to exactly.
I read every,
every team got a guy fighter in the kid
podcast is kicking all kinds of ass.
You got to be happy about that.
You guys are storming the
fucking sports charts here.
The only thing that's on sports,
it's funny you have it.
It's the shouldn't be.
It should be a comedy podcast.
You cheating by being on sports.
You know that I barely talk about sports.
Yeah,
you guys should need to move over to
comedy and that's talk about sports
occasionally because the people are,
we do it.
Look for funny shit and they miss you.
They might miss a good point.
Yeah,
because Fox is,
I did do sports.
You gotta cut that tit on after and
break off the fighter and the kid.
shop.com we're killing it with
merchandise by our hilarious with the
merchandise.
Go buy the shirts.
Go a download the podcast for sure.
Subscribe on Itunes for sure.
I'll tell you my,
I'll tell you my story.
If you do a bone Brendan
Schaub on Twitter,
Brian Cowen on Twitter.
That's it.
You dirty fucks tomorrow.
Bert Kreischer.
See you then until then,
much love,
big kiss pays.
Okay.