Oh sweet. Jesus were added again. Yeah.
These headphones, they're a little tight.
Yeah. I need something a little more
relaxing. I need something fuzzy,
more Mexican, less Asian. Something
with like fuzzy, like a fuzzy ear.
Things like ear muffs.
They'll do make that like some like
fuzzy comfort that I need to make one day
and like pillows that are like set carpet.
They should make one out of like coyote
skin. Ooh, you don't like coyotes?
I don't like how you have these people.
Like why don't you like
Cody's man tell you why?
Cause they live in the
country and they eat cats.
He fuck silly pitches to people.
Like coyotes don't have to
deal with coyote stealing.
They're fucking animals from their,
from their leash and looking
at your kids like their dinner.
One of them attacked a fucking
little kid in big bear last year.
Five year old kid gets attacked in
front of his dad. Buy a fucking coyote.
Coyote can suck my Dick and if I
can make ear muffs out of those Fox,
I'll do it all day.
Make cat ears that are headphones.
They're really comfortable like soft
ones. Not like cat. I like cats. No,
I mean just make work. Coyote years. Yeah.
Coyote gets pretty much the same thing,
right? No. You want this side,
the pelt where you know the,
the thicker stuff on the side.
That's what you want on your ears.
That'd be pretty bad ass. Can
they do that? Yeah, absolutely.
Heated would be upset.
They'd be like, look at this fucked
up show. They have coyote ears on it.
This episode of the Joe Rogan's Franz
podcast is brought to you by audible.com
if you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you can try audible free for 30 days
and get a free audio book if you haven't
used audible. It is an excellent service
and I can recommend it very highly.
They have more than a hundred thousand
books and I have for years been a big fan
of books on tape,
way back to audio cassette books.
I used to listen to back when I was
a loser and I was living in revere
Massachusetts.
So I'd sit by the pool and I was trying
to jazz my future and I listen to
Anthony Robbins books on tape for
real. Seriously fuck yeah. Yeah.
I learned a lot of shit
that didn't apply any of it,
but I learned a lot of
shit from that dude.
I had to figure out my own sort
of path through this life. But um,
I became a big fan of audio books
then and back then they, you know,
used to have on cassette and uh,
get them,
but don't get Stephen King when he's
reading his own books. Just don't do it.
The motherfucker is so boring.
He drones on,
he's the one of my favorite
writers of all time,
but God damn does he suck when he's
reading his books. His books are awesome.
If they hire like a professional
actor really knows how to read it.
An audio book. But if you get
one that Stephen King writes,
what's the best reading you've heard of
someone else reading one of his books?
That's a good question.
I would have to go over them and
let Steve Martin and I immediately,
Steve Martin, uh, hit him reading
his comedy book was amazing. Uh,
born standing up or they have a lot
of history books like, uh, you know,
like this woman on audible.com,
uh,
listening to a history book about
World War II. Uh, I've never got,
I need to get into this because I'm an
auditory learner. You know, as they say,
it's like hard for me to listen
and people are like, who's that?
That's been Hoffman bitches respect.
Hey.
Then often you're in the
middle of an ad for audible,
but I want to get into books on tape.
Yeah.
Or now they call it books on whatever
self audio books and I w I, man,
you just sold, you just sold a
subscription. They're really, um,
it's great for traffic for,
you know,
if you're on an elliptical machine for
half an hour, what are you going to do?
Are you gonna Watch fucking Charlie's
angels on some repeat on that stupid four
inch screen in front of you and be bored
out of your head or listen to a book on
tape and get sort of an
educational experience that
are fun experience, you know,
if it's fiction, you know,
enjoy yourself and uh, you know,
reading does something
weird man. Um, you know,
like there's some enriching creative
aspect to reading that doesn't get
duplicated when you're just watching
things. I don't know what it is,
I don't understand it.
But reading like when you really,
like you read a great book,
like if you read Lord of the
rings or something like that,
the descriptive nature of the pros
just does something to you, man.
I don't know if it's the same listening
to it as it is actually reading it and
like sort of making the
inflections in your own head,
but I think it's way better than
just being stuck in traffic.
You're still getting that
knowledge into your brain,
getting that knowledge and your Dome Sun.
And if you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you can get a free audio book and you
can also get 30 free days of audible
service. Again, it was more than a
hundred thousand titles on there.
So what was the book about?
World War II that you were checking out?
It's called Pearl Harbor.
Pearl Harbor. Yeah. Um,
another one I can recommend that I've
been recommended to people that have them
been, uh, coming back to me,
telling me that it's really,
really helped them is the war
of art by Steven Pressfield.
Steven Pressfield, uh, I've
recommended this before,
but I can't recommend it or not.
If you're a creative person,
it's one of the most amazing
and inspirational books ever.
But in Steven Pressfield was a guy who
was kind of a loser by the time he was 40,
and then he really got it all
together and he's gotten two bucks.
One of them was called the war of art and
the other one's called going pro and a
man, I love this book so much. I,
I used to buy like 10 and 12 at a time
from Amazon and I would just stack them
up in my house and kill people.
Yeah.
Ryan Kelly have it and
she's still at dirty bitch.
She ain't got no respect for you.
So you're going to go over and take her
and then Cox lab or just to let it just
to regain your territory tonight.
Yeah. You got to mark your, uh,
the Front Door to pee on her front
door. I took pitch, no done that.
You see that thing there that says
whisper sync for voice in that Ad.
And that's an amazing app
that they have for um, it's a,
an Amazon app that works with audible.com.
It's,
it's fucking incredible. Um, the,
the whisper sync for audible.com, uh,
not an Amazon zone. It's
a android rather. And um,
it also works on the
Amazon kindle fire HD,
which was their beautiful high
end HD tablet. Works on there. Um,
but it works on Amazon phones to our
Google phones right there. And what it is,
is as you're reading it, whisper sync.
You read the book and say you shut the,
shut it off at night.
Um,
when you go back in the
morning and get in your car,
it's sinked up to where you left
it on, on your, your reader.
So
what'd you get that far?
Because you're listening to your
whisper sank. Then your car. Oh,
well you're okay listening. You're
not okay dialing phones. I'm like,
why are you promoting crashes when people
as if a good book is going to make you
drive into a fucking corner point of
audio book? So you don't do that. Yeah,
you dumb ass. That's not
something a kid about your fucks.
There's times to use the crash. That's
not one of them. Um, anyway, uh,
whisper sync starts the audio companion
book to whatever book you're reading.
It starts it exactly where you
left off. It's a really cool, uh,
application and that's available.
So go audible.com page and open Anthony's.
Every single one of their
shows is on there. So if you,
if you will hear something cool about,
you should get into opening the Anthony.
I'll be in Anthony's the greatest show
on radio. They want it tomorrow morning.
Really? Yeah. Good. First Time. Are
you flying the red eye tonight? No,
I'm just going to call it.
Oh,
you're calling it for a baby bird
when you were there. They're great.
They're great.
They're the,
they're the easiest guys to
hang out with on radio ever.
You'd go in there and it's just like a
bunch of dudes sitting around talking and
everybody's just having fun and
everybody's, it's great. Like,
I didn't want it for myself, a plug about
myself into the intros here, but, well,
opie and Anthony are pals.
The shows are no being Anthony's channel.
We're on there on Sirius, on
Saturdays, uh, annual all. Anyway,
audible.com forward slash Joe free audio
book free, 30 days of audible service.
You'll enjoy the shit out of it.
We're also brought to you by [inaudible]
Dot Com it's o. N. N. I t today.
We just recently got in the primal bells.
If you haven't seen these things,
they are, uh, they're there.
This is the first of many of our,
uh,
crazy sculpted artistically
rendered kettle bells.
I want to collect these and I don't
even know if I'll use it, but I want it.
I want to collect. These are,
these are, they are so bad ass.
The first one is almost sold out
already. It's um, it's a chimpanzee.
It's just a binary lick and
chimpanzee. Um, but we, uh,
we have other ones on the
way as well. We have, um,
I can't even tell you what they are.
I think we have to keep it a secret,
but they're all equally bad
ass. Um, various things,
not just chimps but various fucked up
cool things that are also kettle bells.
They're also balanced.
One of the things that
was really important about
making these is we monitor,
make sure that if we produced an artistic
kettle bell that it was also exactly
functional because there's some
kettle bells that look cool,
but like people have done designs
on them before, but they're,
they're not balanced correctly.
So when you use them,
they're not like universally
or uniformly balanced.
And we had to a specially
designed this to make sure
that it works really
well as the kettlebells.
And one of the things that works really
well is it has a nice wide base and it's
flat. So it's great for doing like
renegade rows and pushups. And um,
this is, um, only this is the first one
and it's only a 35 pound kettle bell,
which a lot of people like, Yo, bro,
you don't know how much I lift. Okay,
I totally understand if that's your thing.
But you can get a ferocious workout
from a 35 pound kettle bells,
especially if you use that
Kettlebell DVD that we sell,
which is the extreme kettlebell
cardio workout by Keith Weber.
Fucking tremendous Kettlebell DVD.
And that one is,
I use it a 35 pounder and
he kicks my ass every time.
But we've got some big ones coming up,
including a gorilla wait to you see
the gorilla. So the people that,
oh shit, they're fucking
fans like gorillas. Awesome.
You need to make a tick to a giant tit.
That wouldn't motivate you though.
I'd work out.
He just starts sucking on it.
It's just jacking off and
sucking on a metal tit.
We'll make it a blackboard and you won't,
what the fuck are you saying?
If it's too black doesn't look realistic.
It looks like a gorilla tit, you know.
That's what I'm saying. Yeah. Okay. I
got you. Nice recovery sort of anyway,
if you've made it flashcard. Yeah. You
don't want to make it sexy so you're like,
oh I want it. Yeah. Okay.
Anyway, primal bells,
they start today.
We,
I believe we were almost sold out
as of like an hour ago. So if uh,
if you want to buy one right?
They buy one right now because I
think that's pregnant dude. Alright.
You won cause that really
do want to collect these.
Yeah, they're pretty bad ass.
Look, if these things can actually
force Brian into working out,
it would be the most amazing
creation we've ever come up.
I'm just thinking at
home alone type thing.
Like somebody breaks in my house and I
have these like hang in and then knocking
them on the head type thing. Yeah. That's
a good, that's a good weapon. Yeah.
If you could fuck somebody up,
if you've got good technique,
if you know how to deliver a kettle bell,
yeah,
but if you don't know how to sling it
right, he might just take it from you,
stuff it up your ass. You got to think
about that too. Fair. These can't imagine
another web.
If anyone makes a cartoon about your job,
they have to use all your on
it. Uh, weapons. Like that's,
it has to have kettlebells,
battle ropes, suicide.
These are now ladies and gentlemen,
these are not welcome weapons.
All of these things that we sell are just
pieces of fitness equipment that could
double as weapons.
But the most important aspect of it
is the fitness aspect of you. Uh,
go to the website. You'll
see the different things.
We have like a battle ropes,
which are,
if you've never seen like videos of MMA
fighters doing strength and conditioning
training, they use these gigantic heavy
ropes and you whip them up and down.
And I've been using them a lot lately.
My new trainer, Justin, Milo, Suze.
I'm also a fellow student at 10th Planet
Jiu Jitsu has been training me and one
of the things we've been doing is a,
uh,
a lot of kettle bell battle ropes,
a lot of like box jumps and shit like
that, all stuff for functional fitness.
That's what I'm really into.
And uh,
that's the kind of things
that we concentrate on a at,
on it along with the best
supplements we can possibly buy,
whether it's food like
the, uh, the Tonka bars,
which are these delicious buffalo bars
with cranberry animal or hemp force
protein, the most, the most expensive
protein powder that we can buy,
the highest in protein content, the
most easily digestible, the smoothest.
It's, it's delicious. It's
got rom raw cocoa in it.
It's also gotten Maca and
it's sweetened with Stevia.
It's the best tasting protein
powder you'll ever try.
And it has like one gram of sugar and
it's super healthy. I started off, um,
a or a rather end off every
workout with a glass of that stuff.
It's fantastic pitches.
Check it out,
use a codename Rogan and you will save
10% off any supplements. All right.
You have fucks. Ben Hoffman is here.
We're fend to get busy with it.
Ice House Friday. Oh, that's right. Ice
House. You got to show this Friday night.
Yeah, this Friday. Who was there?
We have Tony Hinchcliffe who's going
to be joining you in Indian yet.
Indiana soon. Indianapolis, Indianapolis,
Indiana so that it is an Indiana. Yeah,
but that's pretty unspecific. Kevin,
somewhere in the state. Kevin Christie
is going to be joining us. Awesome.
Kevin Christie and Alison Shula. It's
going to be back. I don't know. She's,
she was on this episode one side.
She almost died and so we're going to
talk to her about that and she had like a
crazy staph infection. Yes. You got crazy.
They didn't even know what was wrong
with her. It's crazy. Staph infection.
It wasn't she in the hospital about a
month and so it's now just getting back to
doing comedy. She, she also was in a,
she is a musician now has I have a CD
out and a book that was in the top 10 of
iTunes. So she's like no fucking kicking
ass. And they have books on iTunes.
Ebooks. Oh, audio books. Audio books.
I'm sorry. Oh No, no, no, no, no.
She had a book. Itunes. Yeah. Uh, I
mean the still owe the iTunes store. Oh,
I see. Okay. The APP stores what
it is, write that book thing.
So she considered iTunes. What is
that considered? Yeah, movies, books.
Very cool person and a, anybody else? Uh,
there's some other people that I'm just
waiting on. Yeah, there's a lot of 'em,
a big name guys that already
in La this weekend was.
So most likely we'll have some tests.
They'll have some guests.
I will not be there. I'll be in Nashville
with a great Tamisa girl. Mommy. Yeah,
my pal and a hilarious comic.
You never seen Thompson Aurora.
This is really two headliners.
Tom is not by any stretch of the
imagination and opening acts.
He's opening for me just because we're
buddies and he had the weekend off and I
tried to take the best guys I can
with me. Like if I, if I can get Joey,
I get Joey. But Joey is almost always
busy now because he's too fucking popular.
Yeah.
You know Ari's so popular now too.
He's doing really well. But um,
but Thompson girls, it's always a treat
to work with them cause he's really like,
he's a super top level stand up. He's
a, and he's a super good guy too.
Just a sweetheart.
And he has his own podcast with his wife,
Christina P who's also funny as shit.
Yeah.
And it's called your mom's house and
you can end up, she's awesome. Yeah,
she's awesome. Very funny. Um,
and for a chick that shit's rare.
Yo Harlow,
did he just say, Oh yes
I did. It just means that
the ones who do it, it was there.
They're even better. Um, all right,
so that's Nashville xannies Friday,
Saturday night, then Hopkins here.
Cue The music.
Okay.
Experience
Joe Rogan podcast.
My night all day.
Powerful Ben Hoffman.
What? Joining us buddy.
What's up guys?
How about that fucking David Lee Roth.
Did you like that? Dude?
Here's what I loved about that.
I'm not saying this to me.
I didn't want to start with the ass
kissing, but I'll do it anyway. David,
isn't he the kind of the king of the,
just like the interviews were just like,
again,
nothing against him,
but like he is his normal interviews or
just like kind of one liners and like,
yeah, he's, he's covering up
for something. He doesn't know.
You prepare in this kind of scenario.
He can't, yeah. For two hours.
You can't just sit here and do like
Stephanie Bop and stick stick is the word
I'm looking for.
He just does.
I've seen a million David
Lee Roth interviews and he
just does his fucking stick.
I'm like, who is this man? You
don't know anything. Right, right.
But he came in and you're stuck
here for two hours, you know,
like in a good way or bad way.
But God,
that was a great fucking
David Lee Roth interview.
Yeah. We found that the,
yeah, it was, first of all,
it was surreal as fuck. Yeah.
Just sitting there and
talking to David Lee Roth it,
that's really David Lee Roth
shows up by himself. Okay.
Zero entourage kind of Ben Hoffman style.
Are those things called the
suspenders? Oh No. Um, overall.
Overall I used to wear that
shit and no underwear. Dude,
he's cool as fuck.
He's just a regular guy that happens to
be one of the greatest rock stars the
world has ever known. I mean, he, the,
the things he's seen men and when you say
it to him, you know, like, well, you know,
listen man,
you're one of the greatest rock stars
the world's ever known was like, yeah,
I guess, you know, he's like,
I mean, he's not a fool.
He's well aware of who he is, but he
doesn't let it get in the way of anything.
But it is what in Japan.
Yeah, that's what he was saying on
thing, but it was just weird to see him.
It was almost like out of character. It
was like seeing him as a human, which I,
you don't think of him as, he's like, he's
like a superhero. Right? I know. Yeah.
This is
co well,
I was really fortunate that I hung out
with him one night at the comedy store,
so I got to see the Real David Lee Roth.
He came,
it was one of the weirdest things ever.
Like you don't even know who's in,
who's in the crowd when you're on stage
because the lights are bright and he'd
get off stage and all of sudden
you see someone and you go, Oh wow,
you just watched that, you know, and David
Lee Roth comes up and he goes, hey man,
I just want to tell you I didn't
think you were going to be funny.
Like what the fuck man? He blew my mind.
He was like, it was so nice. He goes,
I just assume like that's not a fear
factor guy. Seems like a nice fellow.
How funny can you be?
Holy Shit.
And he was like just super
like charismatic and hilarious.
We hung out with them for fucking
hours, right? Yeah. Like two hours.
Just chip away at the store a
few years back and we have it.
Actually I have it all on video.
The conversation,
the whole entire thing is on video
somewhere in this humongous pile.
The are on a lunch.
Yeah, we should get that. So I went
back. I don't think we, he wanted that.
I don't know. His manager contacted
like that shit on fire actually. Yeah.
Oh yeah.
It was already just I take it back,
do a little compensation.
Margaret talked about Paul, her
Joe your shirt.
It's so bad and you can show your
boss real quick if I can see the shirt
house Rogan. I got this from game of
Thrones today. They sent me this box.
It says a house Rogan on it and uh,
I guess they're sending these to all
the supporters of the game of Thrones
people who are like super fans and I
couldn't stop talking about the show ever
since I started watching it.
I had been tweeting it like crazy
and apparently it got back to them.
So they sent me this fucking amazing
box that says house Rogan on it.
And when you open it up,
it plays the theme song
and it has two DVDs in there too,
right
to the first season in the second season,
which I already showed the Scooby Doo
Doo Scooby Doo. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's a secret.
Yeah.
Button.
When you press a button,
this thing pops out in a
scroll kind of HBO boner.
I guess you would,
you would hide your drugs there after
he got rid of the DVDs if you want.
By the way,
just to clarify,
I'm guessing they're not
sending it to all super fans.
Just the top tier of superfans
probably get the giant. Right.
I know patent got one.
Patton Oswald.
That's how I knew what it was before I
opened the box because I looked like a
cigar humidor. And then I remember
seeing patents photo and I was, I was,
I said to my wife, I'm like, I told
her what it was before I open it,
but I was like, God, if I'm wrong, I'll be
so sad. Right. So, uh, this is the scroll.
They, they, they, they put a
scroll in a secret compartment.
They have to press a button.
It says loyalist of House Rogan.
The new season of game of
Thrones is almost here.
Show your passion for the series and use
this limited edition case to share your
exclusive game of Thrones
content with your followers.
If you've been waiting for a reason to
catch up, consider this. It Ral your fans.
March 31st cannot come soon enough.
Wow. Yeah, pretty bad. Awesome.
Coolest Symia girls use
panties or something and
that show girls big fans that
show girls. It's like sex in
the city for us. Younger Age,
sex and the city for girls.
Yeah. Is it good for younger,
younger crowds?
Entourage for girls on sex in it though?
Entourage with sex in the city. The
guys. Oh right. And this is this.
His entourage for girls
entourage never did a goddamn thing
for me. I don't know what it was.
I tried to give it a shot, but I
would watch entourage Hong Ago. Okay.
I like the scenery.
May everybody looked pretty.
Girls had straight up porn in it though.
Like it's pretty much watching a porn.
Yeah, they got, they wouldn't, they
would show shooting on the, on the chest,
like loads on the chest and everything.
You know what? I'm going to go buy that.
They show loads on the chest. What?
Wait a minute. How did they do that?
I don't know.
Cause it's a,
so like the girls coming her
tits and you see like Jesse,
the afterwards of aftermath
of him shooting on her chest.
You actually see it hit a,
I can't remember. I think
it was just on the chest.
So you just see it. You see her tits,
raw tits. I can't, I can't remember.
I'll find your acting like he didn't
rewind. It ain't your fucking dredging.
Good bets here. What happened?
What really happened?
Did you see loads on Ted's saw?
Look, you see loads on tits.
I don't remember if he was showing it
shot on the her tits or if it was just
after.
And so this is just about
a bunch of freaks lived
together and fuck the shit out
of everybody and pretty much is
it good? Yeah, just got into it.
So it's just,
uh,
you heard the part about loads on
chest all over the Internet, man,
that's 90% of the Internet.
It's funny how little that's
represented in the real world.
It's like finally loads are starting
to represent and then modern media,
it's a big part of people's life.
Online loads are a huge part of
people's life online. But, and you know,
on comedy central you rarely,
rarely see loads.
Do you think it would screw you up if
you were a kid not watching all this
internet porn and you would think that's
how every, how sex is supposed to end?
Well they say that a lot of girls are
having anal sex now because of that.
That it wasn't really nearly as common
in the eighties, nineties. What have you.
It's crazy.
It's just crazy to me to think like it
doesn't every porn you watch basically
and like in the face, most of them
do. Yeah. Like if you're a kid,
if I was watching it, I'm like, that's how
babies are made, I guess. You know? Well,
I don't think they're
thinking about making babies.
I think that thinking about fucking,
and the problem with that is you're
watching people don't fuck like people
really fuck,
you know,
like it's not normal for a girl to spit
on your Dick and then you just shove it
in her ass. Right. That is pretty real.
Sam. Sandy, weird to be a kid nowadays.
I wonder how that would feel it pin it
fucks with your hardcore, well look,
porn has made one dominant victory in
our culture and that's in the world of
pubic hair poring through
dominated crabs is going away.
Did you hear about that really?
Because of that?
Because everyone's shaving
no more crabs that STDs.
You're more likely to catch STDs when
uh, when everyone's shaved. Really?
Yeah. So crabs over STDs. I think
it'll take crabs. I guess you're right.
Why is that? Because you're closer
and more contact and stuff. Yes,
I gas then maybe the natural flora and
your pubic hair access some sort of a
preventative barrier. Like while
you're supposed to have eyebrows,
it keeps the sweat out of your eyes. Yeah.
That's what it's there for. Right? Yeah.
So yeah. And I don't know if that metaphor
works, but that's what it's for, right?
I mean, that's exactly why
it's above your fucking four.
I'm not sure if that's the pubic hair
metaphor works and people that are in from
really funky climates.
That's why they have that unit brow.
It's for the whole face.
They don't want it on the nose.
You don't want it rolling
down into your eyes.
You don't get the unit brow and the blonde
communities because they're freezing
their dicks off up in Iceland. Okay.
Right, but you want to go to Persia.
Those motherfuckers are
hot. It's hot there. I never
thought about it like that.
That makes perfect sense. Yeah.
I'm dropping science on you,
Ben Hoffman.
I had no idea pubic hair was
supposed to attract birds. Actually,
I was saying before, I need to learn
more about eyebrows and pubic hair.
Pubic hair was supposed to attract birds
and they were supposed to make me an s
on your crotch.
You need to think about some of the shit
before you sat and wonder if it's worth
doing because that one wasn't. I say
no, don't you want to ever meet? Fuck,
save that shit from muffs set. Okay.
And this podcast and once your a game,
I'm so game of Thrones,
they also send you a, hey,
I'm a flash drive with a bunch
of images and social media.
They give you like a banner that you
could put on your Twitter page that says
house Rogan. That's pretty bad ass.
Oh, it's got your name on it. Yeah.
Crazy. Yeah. I'll throw that
shit up before the premiere
should have the premiere.
It's doing its job too. Yeah,
they're fucking bad ass man.
That is a really clever use of marketing.
Hbo Knocking it out of the park.
Yeah,
HBO is on top of Shit.
They have so many fucking good shows
and they show loads on the chest to
apparently allegedly I'm not buying it.
I got it. I would have heard about that.
This motherfucker Suntan Lotion.
He thinks it's loads,
loads of sex and hits his head right
straight over here and gets on the Mike.
Did you hear a little research?
Did you hear about that kid in
Ohio that weren't wearing the Ohio,
that killer shirt and
all that shit shut up.
He shot up and killed I think
three people in a, in a school.
And then he got a life and
he's getting life in prison.
But what he did is he took off his shirt,
he had like outside collar shirt on.
And during the like hearing the last
hearing he took off his shirt and it said
killer. And then he like looked at the
victim's eyes, like his last words.
It's like, I want you to know like
this hand that shot your kids.
I used to masturbate every
night or something like that and
thinking about them,
you know. And they said,
well look at this fucked up kid man.
When was this? This was yesterday.
And uh, and yeah, it's this big thing
right now because now that, you know,
like they're getting,
oh the people are getting in trouble
cause how did he get that shirt past the
security guards and stuff like that.
And I guess, you know, just uh,
just cause you know, all the families
to burst out in tears and all this.
I mean this kid is a fucking
piece of shit and his sister,
are you talking about this?
Because we were talking about it like
how porn was affecting kids earlier and
I'm just talking about like how kids
have been like these crazy kids now.
Crazy. Yeah, man, I don't really don't
want to dwell on this guy though.
I don't like talking about this kind of
shit. I think the worst, not only that,
this whole serial killer thing,
it feeds off of you talking about it.
That's how these guys get
this idea in the first place.
It'd become special because they know
that if they do something really fucked up
a bunch of people, we'll talk
about it. And that's an inevitable.
But there's a lot of things to concentrate
in this life if you want to start
concentrating every day and how many
fucked up people the wrong in the world.
You Become Nancy grace.
Yeah. I'm just saying this is what's
hitting the news. If you heard it yet.
That's fucking,
that's what I talking about porn though.
No,
I'm just saying how how
fucked up kids are nowadays.
Most kids are not with the school.
She was the greatest time to
live ever as far as violence.
There's some people that are fucked up,
but the amount of them in comparison
to the rest of the human population,
it's way less. There's, this is
the safest time to ever be alive.
It's 300 million fucking people in this
country and every now and then one of
them blows a fuse. I like your view
though, of not giving him the coverage.
That's an interesting way of doing it.
Don't give them the the fucking
a time of day. Well, you can,
you can concentrate on
that for every show,
every day if you want it to.
There's enough out there.
There's constantly fucked
up things out there,
but that kind of shit like someone trying
to fuck with the family after he kills
him. I don't want to talk about that
guy that that's not, I don't like that.
I don't like hearing about it.
It's the whole idea behind it that this
kid can get away with something like
that. If we, if we live in
a world that makes sense,
when someone does anything
remotely fucked up like that,
you beat them to death.
You don't,
you don't bother feeding them and
housing them and taking care of them.
You beat them to death. That's what you
do and you, you saved money doing it.
You do it with a fucking club and he
just smashes diseased brain and then you
move on.
But we live in this pussified world where
a cut like that can say that in front
of those people and not have the normal
re normal, healthy, relaxed reaction,
which is just killing him.
He's broken. That's a damage.
Human being that will never get
better and you have to kill them.
You don't house them,
you don't feed them.
You don't put him in a fucking special
room and they can't touch other people.
You kill him because there's no
reason for them to be around.
There's nothing you're
going to learn from them.
All you're going to do is find out what
made them fucked up and you're not going
to prevent that unless you got fucking
cameras and everyone's bedroom from the
time of kids born to the time they
finally escaped their current parents and
become a psychopath and go
roaming through the streets,
killing people to try to fill some hole
inside of them or whatever the fuck is
wrong with them,
but we don't do that and that.
That's what drives me the most
crazy about watching those things.
It's not just that people like that exist
is that people like that only exists
because we don't have community anymore.
Our system of government,
our system of laws,
when it set up to deal with bad people,
we for whatever fucking reason,
when someone's a horrible
piece of shit like that,
want to show that were humane
and show that we have, you know,
we have a morals and we have laws and
we have a a certain way you shouldn't do
that.
You should beat that guy to death and
let everybody know that you can't do that
to people.
You can't torture and kill people.
You can't try to hurt the victim's family
by saying something fucked up because
you're a mass.
Just get that thing dead,
get that thing dead and off the planet
and let's say I'm with you on that one.
You got to do with all of them,
all pieces of shit. You gotta.
There's gotta be a real reason
to not be a piece of shit.
The problem is they're raised by horrible
people and then the other problem is
who's to say whether or
not a person's guilty.
Who's to say whether or not
a person really did do this.
When you have a case like that where not
only did you do you know the guy did it,
he's joking around about it.
Just talking about it. Yeah,
that's a dead man and
if he's not a dead man,
we live in a pussified society that's
allowing people like that to exist.
They should never let
them get to that point.
Somebody probably knew he was
fucked up a long time ago.
They should have got together,
had a little conversation
and put his lights out.
You seem to staircase.
No one is that this documentary
about this guy who killed basically,
it's not definitive, but he basically
killed his wife. You got to see it.
It's the best fucking documentary. It's
like this what? Like think eight part.
No one here seen it. This eight part
documentary that was on Sundance,
he claimed his wife fell down the stairs.
I don't want to give it away because you
have to watch it and it's like you find
it all this crazy shit. But he
says his wife fell down the stairs.
It turns out, actually, I'm not going
to say the next part is the same.
It turns out he had it.
He had another woman he knew years before
who also fell accidentally fell down
the stairs.
Mr. Well to do like a really wealthy man,
a novelist who like you
would never suspect,
but they had cameras
running the whole time.
It was foots fucking and they just aired
a special to hidden camera's running.
When they interviewed him, you mean? No
cameras running in his house. The whole,
so there's a whole trial.
They the first thing,
as soon as they found out about
it, they went to his house. Can we,
can we document the whole process?
Whoa. And they have the whole thing.
It's the staircase you can get
on Amazon. It's, it's awesome.
So do you think he's innocent at first
and then towards the end you start
thinking that it's good.
It, it's enough. He throws you man. Cause
I have friends who've seen in store like,
you know, I think he's innocent so it's,
there's enough up in the air that maybe,
but there's too much coincidence for me
personally. Two wives fall down a store.
The first one wasn't a why it was a
friend. It's one of his best friends.
It's the whole thing. I mean there's
just, it was a girl. Yes. Both girls. Yes.
And one was one he adopted.
Again, I'm giving away too much.
Probably kill someone pretty easy by
throwing them down a flight of stairs.
I bet most people would die.
But of course it looks like kicked him
down a flight of stairs but need guests.
Why do you want to know the ending?
Sure. He's off. Really. Yeah.
Whoa. They had just this, this
documentary aired like my five years ago.
So you believe he's guilty?
I do is my belief. But,
and he was in jail until like a year ago
and they aired the special addendum to
it. Then you go, wow.
Yeah. People get away with Shit, man.
There's some psychos out there and there's
also people that live with horrible
people and that you fucking just feed
off each other's hate and you get to the
point where
it's, the thing that throws, throws you
about this documentary is his family.
Seems like all great people. It
throws you, especially the kids.
What was the white flight though, Wayne?
I never saw she, she was, she was dead.
Who knows?
Maybe the wife was a problem.
He had to kick her down a flight of
stairs. Yeah. I mean, yeah, maybe.
Maybe you had a good reason. I don't
have to smell good reason to do that.
They hire you. I'm Jake. I'm J K
and these are just jokes. Fine.
We're just trying to find a way to talk
about this. Um, yeah, there was a show.
Do you remember HP pose?
I'm Dr. Michael Baton.
The autopsy shows number does,
do you ever see those bright?
Yeah, it's disgusting. I mean, I didn't
watch full episodes, but I will
try to watch him. Well, he,
he busted a lot of murderers
because he would, uh, you know,
through friends and Kevin and
they'd find like one small thing.
Oh man,
it was seven years ago,
several years ago.
A lot of really creepy shit on it.
But one of them was this
guy's wives just kept dying.
He's fucking people,
man. It's like they got,
and my lucky day got away with it once
and he figured, well, fuck it man.
I know how to do this and probably
wet your appetite, I'm sure.
And I bet they also feel like as
long as they don't go to jail for it,
no one's even going to look into it. Like,
oh look, they said it was an accident.
She died. Oops. And then also the next
one dies and it was, I don't know.
The other one was an accident.
Okay. I told you it was an accident.
There's one was an accident
too. Like, Ooh, that's when
people closing on your son.
But these kind of documentaries
too, when you see, cause you get,
you get thrown cause you
see the prosecution and the
defense and you hate them.
Both. Both lawyers send, you're
like, who the fuck is right?
Because both of the lawyers are so fucking
annoying. It's like which side do I,
I hate them both kind of.
It's gotta be hard to be a person that
operates in the legal system and tries to
get bad people off.
That's your job.
And then you got to go out and face the
world knowing that like what if he got
that kid with the tee shirt? What if he
got that kid off to be that kids lawyer?
Right. That's what if somebody got that
kid off on a technicality. You know,
what if there was like some contamination
of evidence or what have you and that
that fucking kid got free.
At what point do you like to say like,
I just can't do this.
I don't know if that kid had,
it was on prescription medicine,
like all the other ones.
I want it.
And there's fucking girls supposedly that
are tweeting that they're in love with
him cause he,
I think he's cute.
Oh that happens a lot, man. Yeah.
That guy, the um, Richard Ramirez,
he got married in jail or people
love fan. Yeah. He's the night stock.
He would stomp girls' heads in and crush
their skulls and he's got people that
visited him in jail.
Mickey Mallory Knox.
Who is that you meant that the movie
natural born killers where they glorified
as superstars on this.
Well,
to a lot of people that live in a world
of shit and that that is a problem with
our society, that lack of community
that we talked about. That's,
that's a big problem.
And when people are allowed to
grow up living in a world of shit,
when there's not enough people to be
around, to be friends, to love, to,
you know,
to,
to support people when you're just on
your own living in a world of shit and
abuse and he grew up to be a monster.
You know,
we are this disconnection that we have
with our neighbors and disconnection we
have with our coworkers.
And you know, this,
this lack of like real deep being full
friendships that so many people out in
this life that's a,
that's one of the big holes that people
have over and over and over again.
If you find like really angry people,
you find out that they're loners,
you find out that they're rejected.
They don't have loved ones,
they don't have good friends.
It's ran kind of a loner.
Now I'm getting worried about myself.
I'm glad I got you from the
moment I met some friends.
I'm not one of these crazy, you're not a
loner. You know what I'm talking about?
Like being alone with the people that
are just like keep themselves at work.
Don't have conversations.
We will.
That's the guy who's going to come in
with a gun and shoot everybody. Right?
There's something about humans where we
desperately require each other and we
have to be aware of that. It's, it's,
you can say, you know what, man, I don't,
I like to be alone. People Annoy
me. Know you'd like to be alone.
Sometimes we all like to be
alone. Sometimes you do not
want to be alone forever.
You don't. You'll be horrified. You'll
be terrified. You'll be miserable.
You can live where people
are around you all day,
every day for the rest of your life.
You can live fine.
Maybe it will be annoying sometimes,
you know?
Maybe you'll be looking for some peace
and quiet and you won't get it as much as
you need it, but you'll be
fine. If you live by yourself,
you'll go fucking crazy. You'll commit
suicide to jump off a cliff. You'll,
you'll become friends with the
volleyball. Yeah, like Tom Cruise,
Tom Hanks, Tom Cruise manager
of Tom Cruise was in that.
I feel a lot more screaming, I guess.
Say it again. It'd be 20% 20% more gay,
at least at volleyball would have been
popped a long time ago if I brought,
would have lipstick on it and
holes in it. Not all your name. Oh,
why don't you put lipstick on your bubble?
What was teaching it? What did they
teach you over at comedy central Sun.
I don't know.
That takes me crazy
teaching and crazy shit. Um, so thank
you to HBO for this, this hookup.
It's what the coolest thing I've ever
gotten ever. This game of Thrones thing,
and thank you for the tee shirt.
It's pretty bad ass. That's,
that's how I promote things.
The other way to promote things is
come on this podcast, Ben Hoffman.
Oh Shit. What is science? What an
intro. That's a segue side show.
Thursdays at 10 on comedy central.
We got nothing like this.
How many have you done so far?
The, the third aired last week.
So people are watching this live, right?
Some people are watching this live.
People are getting this.
If you're watching this live,
there's a special sneak peek tonight at
10 30 after workaholic, but on Itunes,
this is going to be nothing to you because
it's going to get it tomorrow morning
on it's on tomorrow.
It's on Thursdays at 10 for everyone else
and we got five more episodes left and
I think they're funny, but actually
I've, I have mixed feelings.
I'm not a big Ben Hopp and fan,
but overall I think it's pretty good.
How many of you aired so far? We've heard
three and there's five more and it's a,
um,
I'm trying to,
it's like a sketch comedy show mixed
in with like may on the street.
So you see me in my real life.
If like we were shooting right now,
I'd be shooting this.
There's a clip gangsta granny.
So you would come in and do it.
We'd be shooting this if this is yeah,
if I was shooting the show.
So it blurs the lines. This,
yeah, this is a fake audition.
So they can they watch this, right? Sure.
Tough talk. You're a gangster granny.
You're pissed off and uh,
let's do it.
He's a real old ladies trying
to audition for a part.
Listen Up.
And they asked how goes because
the guy was coming for us.
They're going to cover this place
with their run up to the ground.
Well,
fucking big money business company.
Ah, sit here, you know,
shitty diapers.
Or we can exercise our second amendment
rights and get some mother fucking guns.
Wow.
That was really good
bro, bro, bro, bro, Bro. Respect
the elderly mother fucker.
Perfect.
Got to turn my hearing aid off.
Shit's about to get loud fuckers.
Time to move into a home.
That was great. Really Great. And the
last one is I came here to do two things,
handout hard candy and blow some mother
fucking dicks off and I'm all out of
hard candy.
I came here for two things
to suck some hard candy.
Perfect.
Okay.
Yes. So we put that out.
We put out this kit,
we put out this cast and call little
over la that we're looking for this new,
we're doing a new movie. We didn't
tell him it was comedy central show.
We said this new movie
called gangster granny,
but a tough talking grandma and we need
old ladies to come in and audition and
we gave him sides like,
you know,
I don't know if they're going to read
this and every fucking, you know,
people want to work. They all read this
fucking thing and then so we felt bad.
So then we shot a scene from the movie
when you got to realize that the grandmas
have today, if you're dealing
with a 67 year old lady of today,
that lady was like rocking it in
the 70s you know what I'm saying?
That not the grandmas of when we were
children who were like in the 50s there
was a seventies grantees, so they parted
their dicks off. Ready? They were like,
haven't they were all, they were having
a blast. That was the weird thing.
Every audition he said like that exposes
just how fucking easy acting really is.
Oh did we did,
we did,
we did four different fake audition
things throughout the series and cause
listen,
I've been a million of those auditions
and I as as bad as they were and as funny
as it was,
they were no better or worse to me.
Like they would have beaten me in any
role. I mean I just got lucky and got the,
a lot of people out there that auditioning
for parts that could do it easily.
That's why I love when someone like
Justin Timberlake becomes a big actor
because he's not an actor.
He's a fucking singer.
I love when like an athlete does,
it becomes a really good actor
because it shows you it is not hard.
It's one of the easiest things to do ever.
You're a member of the words and then
you pretend and it's not that hard to do
and some people do it better than famous
people and they easily could be famous.
Yeah.
That's why I wanted to put a lot of real
stuff in the show cause I'm just like,
aren't real people just as
funny as fucking most of my
actors. Yeah. There's all,
there's all a lot of funny
fucking people out there.
They just have never figured out how
to make a living off of it. Totally.
Growing up like didn't I always tell my
friends like were you the funniest kid
growing up? No, exactly. Like I
was. I hung out a lot of funny kids,
but all my friends were funny. I just,
for some reason decided to get into it.
I wasn't even close. Yeah. But there was
so many funny kids who were just like,
what they wanted to be a doctor or
work at a bank or, you know, whatever,
whatever it was.
The funniest person I ever met in my
life was a private investigator. Really?
Yeah. This is still as, his name's Dave
Dolan. Dynamite. Dick was Dave Dolan.
I worked for him when he lost his Dick.
He used to call himself
crazy dynamite ticklish.
Dave Dolan, who's, oh,
he's crazy and sober too, by the way. When
I met him, he had just lost his license,
uh,
from drinking and driving crashes,
car a tunnel and try to run on and flip
from the cops. Holy Fuck. It's crazy.
And he was a private investigator,
so he needed someone to drive him
around because he lost his license.
There's this, is that not
a Sitcom right there? Yeah.
Fire investigator who can't drive and,
yeah.
Well, I, uh, I responded
to the job, you know,
it was like some newspaper or something
like that, and I called him up,
asked him what it was all about, what the
hell we're supposed to be doing. And, uh,
I started working for him,
so I worked for him for whatever it was,
90 days or something like that until
his license was, uh, brought back.
Might've been six months.
Uh,
but then he got his license
back and didn't need me anymore.
And that was by then I was
sort of starting to get gigs.
He started it.
But you still hang out with him?
Yeah, yeah. I'm still friends with
them. I, I go back and, you know,
talk to him whenever I'm in Boston,
the kind of tickets to the UFC.
He's a great guy. He's an awesome
dude, but he's fucking hilarious.
He was always hilarious.
We would go on these things and
most of what the insurance, um,
or most of what the private investigation
businesses is insurance cases.
It's a people that are, they're getting
workman's compensation and they're, uh,
they're lying and working on the side
and you catch them working. Uh, that's,
you know, or they're suing and they
say, Oh, my back is horribly injured.
And you catch them doing something like
carrying something heavy. And so we,
that's a lot of money. They're saving if
they busted. Yeah. Well a lot of people,
they'll claim to be injured if on the job,
you know they have some sort of a job
and so we would have to sit in front of
people's houses.
We would get there at like four o'clock
in the morning when it was dark out,
parked the car and sit and wait for this
guy to go to work cause we had a follow
the guy to go to work.
So we'd be in this car bored out of our
heads and we just start talking shit.
And then you know,
it'd be like,
yeah I knew this one girl and she was
so fucking crazy and he would tell some
story about a girl he dated. We
would just start howling. And I,
I remember thinking like
crying in his car. He, me,
he and I just sitting there
five o'clock in the morning.
I was already doing it at the time.
Yeah.
That was one of the reasons
why I needed a another job.
It's because when I was right when I
was working for him is when I stopped
teaching martial arts and I
stopped competing as well. I,
I got to this point where I was like,
you know what,
I got to pick one thing or the other
and this comedy comedy is what I really
want to do and I don't fighting,
it's just going to give any brain damage.
Like I got to get away from that and I
got to really focus my energies on this.
I need some sort of a job.
So I quit teaching.
I was teaching at a school
and I was teaching at Boston
University and so I quit
all that and then got this
private investigation chop.
What was the craziest thing you
saw on the junk? Nothing crazy.
It really wasn't that crazy at all. We
never, we never really were in danger.
We never really saw God work in you get
to like confront him or anything? No,
it was that you never would confront them,
you know,
you would just take a picture
of him or you would uh,
confirmed that it's them or you know,
it was kind of sad.
Like one time we got this one lady,
if I were told the story in the podcast
before about we had this lady and one of
the ways he would get information was
he would find someone's address and you
know,
like he would know who they were,
he would know like from the
insurance company. Wonderful.
Was a woman who was injured
on the job working for Delta.
And there was a reason to suspect that
she was still working while she was
collecting a workman's compensation.
So we got her address and her license
plate number and then he wrote on a piece
of paper her license plate number followed
by a bunch of license plates numbers
that were similar to it, close to it. And
then he knocks on the door and he said,
oh yeah, I'm, I'm, I'm
hoping you can help me out.
My girlfriend was in a
car accident and the cops,
they wrote down the license
plate number for the witness,
but someone's spilled some coffee on it.
So it's either one of these four numbers
and we checked these two and I'm hoping
it's you. And uh, she would,
he would describe an injury that was the
exact same injury is the one this woman
had like, you know, Shashi
herniated a disk and this,
I just recently had that. You're
kidding. Wow. So the woman goes,
which you guys like to come
in and have some coffee.
Okay. We're fucking men. Okay.
Two men and you know, and I, I, I don't,
I would have never trusted
me at 21 years old.
I looked like a fucking psychopath
and he was a nut, you know,
he was this crazy nut. It was one to
crash his car and I'll fucking tunnel.
And then Ron foot and this nice
lady just invites us into her home.
So we're sitting in a kitchen,
but you like some coffee.
Sure. Thank you very much.
Uh, really, I really hope you can help
me here. You know, because uh, you know,
Katie or whatever the girl's name was
that he made up, you know, she's a,
she's such a good person and
a, you know, I this, this,
this whole thing is just such a tragedy
and she's, well, you know what, honey,
I've been through that exact same injury
and I think she's going to be okay.
What happened to you? Oh, I fell on the
job. You know, all you're getting paid,
right? Oh yes, yes. Not
only am I getting paid,
but I started working for another
airline and my maiden name.
So she gives up the ghost, right. And
I'm just sitting there shaking my head.
And so we leave, we get in the car
and I go, you can't turn that lady.
And she's too nice. Goes
Fall car. He goes, fuck her.
She goes, that's what he kept
saying. I go, really? He goes, fuck.
She'd go, she's a fucking crook. He goes,
that Nice lady is costing that company
money because she's lying to them about
being, Gosh, I'm working with him.
That's a shitty thing to do. She,
she's such a nice lady.
I felt I still to this day feel kind of
clever way of doing it. He was a wizard.
He was so good at that. He
was so good. And we would,
it would be different
things for different people.
Like if it was a younger woman,
I would talk to her and you know,
he would say like, you know, like,
you know, make it like, you know,
you're interested in her and then get some
information out of her. Like we would,
would find out things about like, people
that work there. Do you know Mike?
Are you Mike's Friend and
like, um, do I know you,
I'm Joe a Mike's Friend. I know
you. You're Mike's Friend, right?
I never saw you with Mike.
I not fuck where do I know?
I'm know you from somewhere is
Michael k? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mike's okay. Yeah. Is He, did he
get compensated for that? Yeah.
Or they're taking care of them.
Oh, that's good. That's good.
But I already was working for his brother.
She goes,
I think that's under the table.
Oh, all right. Yeah. Well fuck.
Tell him I said hi Tom.
Joe Says Hi and then the next thing you
know you know about Mike working under
the table.
That sounds like a fun.
I know it probably wasn't at the time
cause no jobs are fun but that sounds like
a fun job. It was not the worst
job. It was fun because look,
any job could be awesome if you
work with awesome people, you know?
I mean I remember I had a job at Newport
creamery when I was in high school and
so like an ice cream place
that flipped hamburgers.
But the boss was a fucking funny guy.
He was a cool guy like,
and what I knew he was working
like a certain manager.
I'd be psyched to go to work
because it was going to be fun.
You're going to get to have fun.
I always had this shit.
I don't think I've ever had a fun
job ever. I've met quite a few.
I've been real lucky and, but this was a
really fun one. That is, you know, it was,
it wasn't like these had to be up at
four o'clock in the morning because you
have to catch people
before they get in the car.
The funny guy being a private investigator
would be like the most fun job.
It's scary though. I mean, he's
been attacked before. Um, you know,
I think he got attacked in a case. I don't
remember the story. I think it was, uh,
a wife thing. Oh, that was one really
fucked up one. There was this one guy, um,
we, uh, we went to uh,
investigate his, uh,
his girlfriend or his wife.
He had a feeling that his
girlfriend was cheating on him.
So he hires Dave and Dave goes and gets
pictures of the girlfriend with this
fucking stud.
This guy's just of gorilla,
just some super athlete.
I don't know what the fuck the guy did.
Six foot three, 240 pounds, solid muscle.
Looks like he lives in the gym.
Okay.
And he's making out with the girl
was squeezing our, picking her up,
she's wrapping her legs around,
gets all these pictures,
brings him back to the guy.
And the guy starts crying,
he starts crying and he was like,
cheaters. Yeah, yeah. And he goes, okay,
keep following him. And he was
like, what? She goes, he goes,
I just want to know that this
has happened more than once.
It wasn't just a one time. Thank
you. So then he gets pictures,
this guy just gorilla fucking this
shit. God just, just, uh, and he goes,
I want you to keep, he goes,
listen, you sick. Fuck. He goes,
I'm not going to keep following
them. And he goes, you look,
you got to do what you gotta do, but this
is, I'm done here. You crazy as hell.
You're not, that sounds like a fun job.
I don't know. I wasn't a part of that.
I want, I wasn't a part of it. That was
like wow was working for him. I was,
you know, it was in transition and
then like it was like, oh fuck,
I do that for free on the Internet.
But this was the crazy one. You know,
where he could've gotten, you
know, somebody catches it ticket,
that would be a more popular one then
the insurance claims. But I guess,
you know, know his well, his, that was,
I believe that one came because he was
referred to them by one of the companies
that he was,
that he had been successful with.
And so a guy either that worked for the
company or owned the company was the guy
who was, it was a rich guy who
he was using and this woman,
he had taken care of her,
he put her up in this beautiful place and
the guy was like super, super wealthy,
but he couldn't stop at giant Alpha
Dick from getting in there and said,
he just got fucked. He wanted
us to, well, we want a Dave.
This was like, it was like right
when I started working for him.
Like I'm maybe hadn't actually
started working for him,
but it was like when we started hanging
out together and it just happened.
And He,
uh,
he had given me that if that's a weird
fetish that he wanted the guy to keep
filming it, the Guy Definitely had,
uh, he had a kink going on. There was,
there was a little something he wanted
Dave to keep taking pictures of them.
It tastes like, Hey, fuck you. You
know, this is all third job is over.
I'm not giving you jerk off material.
You know,
he's just picture this guy with a finger
up his ass just screaming as he comes
looking at those photos again,
you're just pitching movies here.
It's pretty, yeah, it's
pretty solid script.
I'm thinking of add Werewolf who plays
the guy who fingers is his ass. Um,
Oh, who's the guy that played um,
pig vomit and how it turned blue. Oh,
I sat next to him on a plane recently.
He's awesome. What's his best
fucking the guy from sideways?
Come on. You know, I know it.
I know it's on the tip of my tongue.
I'll pull up sideways. I just sat
on that like literally sat on
a fucking plane with the gun,
but he would be a good guy for
screaming as he was coming.
I don't want to talk bad about him.
What's wrong with that?
It's not bad about them at all. Paul
Giamatti I blanked on that. He's,
he's fucking amazing. That guy is, he's
like my favorite pissed off guy ever.
I was sent on a plane with,
I didn't really talk to him,
but a friend of mine who,
who knows him, I emailed
afterwards like, Hey, you know,
I sat next to your friend on, on the,
uh, on a flight home and she's like,
emails back. She's like, she said
that you were a very nice gentlemen.
So I bragged all my friends and they
told me that was the lamest thing to brag
about. Did they ever heard that
I was just a polite guy? Like,
I'm not supposed to be
an asshole because I do.
Paul Giamatti thinks I'm a real nice
gentlemen. That's a good thing. You know,
it's probably one of the things that he
says. He was a nice gentleman, basically.
Basically what he's saying
is he didn't remember me. Oh,
you're probably nice to him. And I was
listening to stern in my headphones.
That's hilarious. The odds. And so I go,
you know, it just, I didn't want to go.
I didn't want to say anything,
but you know, you're great.
And that certain movie.
He's like, oh thank you. He's like, it
was, it was a click in his ear to like,
all right gotta stop talking to this guy.
This guy knows who I am, let me know.
But he was very nice.
Well I'm sure it gets annoying every now
and then when people associated with it.
You are the character that you played
two called pig vomit and super asshole
boss. You are the best asshole ever. Yeah,
he was so fucking great.
And he was,
he was good at being that piston sideways
to this whole train of thought came
from uh, the uh, the question of whether
or not you were funny in high school,
whether you were the funny guy.
That's where we got to my friend Dave
and all this shit that I was saying that
too.
Like,
cause that seems to be the question is
everyone thinks if you're a comedian,
like you can listen to me right now
and know that I'm not that funny.
But you could, but you could also like,
I think if you ask my friends back home,
you'd be like, Oh yeah, Ben was funny.
But they wouldn't go like, dude,
he was the funniest fuck gun from
Kentucky. Right. Um, I'm, well,
I'm wearing the UK hat to,
to a problem for the UK to promote the
fact that they lost in the opening round
of the nit yesterday and are completely
out of March madness. But by the way,
I don't even know what the fuck. And even
what you just said me, you don't know.
You Watch college basketball. Well,
there's people listening right now.
We're talking shit about me. So I decided
to show some, they were now there.
There'll be talking shit when they hear
him hear this. Well how rude of them.
Yeah. Those fuckers up. I was going to
ask before to, not to not talk about me,
but you're a, you're going to
Nashville. How do you go there much? No,
I haven't been there in a while.
That's when my mom's from.
I go there all the time. I love it.
I love it there. But there's, I've,
I've just put out a new special
about a couple months ago, September,
something like five bucks, right?
Yeah. Five bucks on Joe rogan.net.
It's called live from the Tabernacle.
And uh,
I basically put together
the next hour or running,
but I have a bunch of new
shit that I want to work out.
And so the best way for me to do that
is to do a club that I don't go to very
often. Cool. And I haven't been to
this place and like more than a year,
like I think it's like two years
since the last time at van.
And this club's Zane, he's in Nashville.
You ever been there? I remember I just, I,
I go to my grandma's house and
shit. I don't really, again,
Zany is fucking awesome comedy club.
It's like really tight seating.
There's a balcony but it's low.
It's like they're right on top of you.
It's an amazing club. And Nashville
is like, it's a rare town man.
Cause it's really smart.
It's a weird combination of southern
and smart and hip and a lot of musicians
and artists and in Nashville it's bad ass.
Ralphie may lives there now,
doesn't he? Like he splits
time. I think he goes back.
There's a lot of rock stars living there
now. Did you know that? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Well honey, honey just moved there too
and black keys there and all those people.
Yeah. Yeah. Well it's a great creative
environment for that and I don't know man,
I guess for comedy to you all you need
for comedies like one club, that's good.
And they have that. They got Zucchinis,
which has been there for 30 years,
you know,
I think they just saw addicted a whiskey
and they just have to be near Jack
Daniels or something. You can
get that shit everywhere. So on.
That's not difficult to get.
You wouldn't have to move close to get
anybody here hear like old country level
country Merle haggard. You been to the
country Music Hall of fame there? No,
I had never been, but I was there
one time. Usually I stay with family,
but it was a family member's wedding,
so there was no place for me to say.
So I had to stay at a hotel
and I had the day off.
So I went to the country music hall of
fame next door. It was fucking awesome.
Wasn't really, it was. I thought I
was going to be stupid, you know,
and Garth Brooks Shit and all that.
It was like old school Hank Williams,
like a lot of the old, it was really cool.
If you've got time I would go to the,
Brooks is slowly becoming
some classic so like you know,
hey you have classic rock. I got
friends in low places. Could be a car.
It's weird you say that.
Cause I was,
I was at the capitol records
building a while ago,
just kind of friend and worked
there and they had this,
these plaques on the wall of like every
album that has sold 10 million copies.
Right. Which is not that many.
So you go to the capitol records,
they were like four Beatles records,
dark side of the moon and
just a wall of gardens.
Like you don't realize how
many fucking albums, his stuff.
So he had like six albums that sold 10
like you wonder why you don't hear from
him anymore because he's got more fucking
money than any music in Vegas now.
I think he's started doing
concerts in Vegas like,
but just with an acoustic guitar.
I think really like it's just him with a
guitar. Yeah. Listen, he's a weird fuck,
but he's undeniably talented.
Oh,
you can't sell that many records
and not have something going on.
I got friends in low places
is a great fucking song.
If you've got a buzz on and that song
comes on and you don't get happy,
you're a cunt. Well, if you're that,
that's a little harsh, but I, I agree,
but know where I'm from.
If you're,
if you're drinking and somebody
doesn't put that on the Jukebox,
like something's wrong.
CanNot take that. So
of course he can't. You're from Ohio. You
probably heard it every day. Your Life.
Where in Ohio,
your alarm clock every day.
Do you remember when he
did that weird thing?
Garth Brooks stood where he put on a
wig and pretend to be a different dude.
He was Chris. Chris Gaines.
Yeah, something like that. God,
that was the weirdest thing ever.
Fuck was that about when I see
plaques on the wall at Capitol records,
I'm like, no wonder he did that.
He was just,
yeah, look at that. Come on, man. Who Let,
who let you do that? Garth Brooks,
he grew a little flavor saver.
He little flavor saver
under the lower lip.
Any went total emo Weirdo,
like brooding that looks like he was in
an argument with his label. He's like,
look, you fuckers, I could sell
albums doing anything. I'll fuck.
I want changed my name. Put a Goto
and then that's what he thought.
He really did believe that. I think
that wasn't it. Was that his last album?
Boy, that's a shitty way to
go out. If that's his last.
That was like the does fix yourself.
I'm all with the hair just perfectly.
That's fine. If we don't
know it's a fucking wig man.
You can't just wear a wig.
Okay.
That's ridiculous.
That looks, but remember for a while
and SNL that was like the Goto joke.
What it was doing weekend update was
like every joke has like a Chris.
He's like,
go fucking silly.
He is the idea that he thought that he
could pretend to be someone different,
a different personality.
I'm not the happy country guy anymore,
even though it's the same guy inside my
heart. When I'm Chris Gaines, I'm Moody's.
Fuck, okay. I'm all dressed in black
and white flavor. Say Rive died.
That and my hair. It's all thick and
heavy even though you know I'm going bald.
Don't think about that. Don't
think about the wig, man.
Think about the persona. I'm trying
to sell a persona. I got this down.
It's God damn character.
You're going to love my new CD.
It's Chris Gaines is moody as fuck.
That's what it's called.
I want you to concentrate. I want you
to concentrate on the shitty music.
This time. My shitty looks
to of me, but one hire.
Who Do we become when mood and
like who wrote these shitty songs?
Chris Gaines. Brooks. Yeah.
He became like one of those Stephen
King characters were fucking,
his eyes glaze over when he starts
writing and he starts going to gloss over
Lelea and writing a bunch of shit down,
like the dark half memory had
a tumor or something like that.
Yeah. I wonder if he's one of those
guys like you know Michael Jackson,
like someone who goes super
crazy when they get super famous.
I wonder if he did that,
but just did it out of the spotlight
because he was as famous as those guys in
his hay day and you never
heard of a freak out from him.
Oh, maybe that Alpha, this version.
He left his wife for a while and got
some new hottie or something like that.
Another singer for something. But that
shit's normal. That's impossible to avoid.
When you got the kind of Garth
Brooks Pussy, you going your way?
What are you going to count? Pussy.
They're thrown at him. Pre-Internet son.
All my goodness. It was just
tsunamis. Pussy and country.
Pussy is hard to avoid man.
Sweet girls with like [inaudible] son.
Don't lie to me. Ben Hoffman was
coming your way. Country my way. Yeah.
Solid d natural tits that defy gravity.
What am I saying son?
I grew up in Kentucky and with that all
around me, none of it offered to me.
Not once. How about now? How
about you got a little TV show.
You got a little little
sun coming your way.
It's not helping as much as I was hoping
it would. You don't have a regular gal?
No. Um, Ben Hoffman. That's
ridiculous. Hey handsome fellow.
You're quick with your wit. Hey ladies,
if you're on Ustream and you're not to be,
I got to live tweet my show tonight
so I'm busy to like till like eight,
but after that we'll meet up and we'll
have a few beverages drinks on me. Whoa.
Drinks on him. Yeah, he got my own show.
I got money for drinks. Yeah. And
you could find them on Twitter.
What's your Twitter handle at the Ben
Show? Which is a mistake by the way.
Just cause I realized now I shouldn't
have my Twitter name be the name of the
show because it will show people say,
well no I don't care about that.
Which why would you not care about that?
Because I think dementia is quit.
That'd be cool. Yeah. No, I don't
want, I don't want to shake it. No,
I'm just saying people say follow or
it's like watch at the bench show and
they're, what they're saying is watch
Ben Hoffman. You know what I'm saying?
So it gets confusing. Watch the watch at
the bench show on the bencher. Ooh. Yeah.
I'd never thought about that. Change
it. I know people changed it before,
but then I changed.
Mine acts,
there's some loser who has been Hoffman
and he's got 30,000 followers and he
follows 50,000 people. How does he have
30,000 followers? Because he fought.
I'm sure he followed all those bots
who followed and followed them back or
something. I tried to get his name from
him, but I, he won't give it to you.
Twitter.
It'll give it to,
do you know that Twitter will
just steal it from that guy? Yeah,
they do that for celebrities.
We got to see if we get a season two
before we start stealing Twitter.
I think I knew. I think I need some
more power before I get that season two,
what you need is Ben Hoffman's name
you got, that's your name, right? Yeah.
You're Ben Hoffman. Yeah. Fuck is
this guy really been bad than an hour?
And he asked my name. Huh? No, I'm
kidding. Is this Guy Really Ben Hoffman?
Is that his real name?
He's,
he claims he's been Hoffman got to
find out when we take care of this.
I've got my people get on it right
now. People move in on him. Yeah.
Cause you're right. At least making them
uncomfortable with a few emails. Yeah,
I did that once.
Someone had Ben hoffman.com
and I threatened to sue
him and he's like bring it
on. And I didn't have lawyers. Right.
Cause I guess like I guess
his name Ben Hoffman. Yeah.
Oh then you can't sell them. I know.
I threatened to out him that funny.
Like you would think they
will because you're famous.
You're Ben Hoffman name was worth more
than his. Well I check the ratings.
I'm not sure how famous I am. You know
how long ago was this? How famous I am?
How long ago was this that the guy
had been hopping before I had a show.
So you weren't famous at all? I
was nuts. Thread is trolling paper.
But that was back when I was, it didn't
have a show. I pretended to be famous.
I would email him like, listen, I'm a big
celebrity and you can't have my website.
I was on another show at the time, so
I was like, listen, I have, I'm on TV.
Belbin they're like, we don't give a
fuck. I don't care who you are. And like,
and then I did you think you actually had
to like a, like you could do something.
I knew I was talking shit.
I was just hoping that he would get
scared and be like, Oh shit, it's yours.
And he was like, had half a brain and
it was like, damn it. Leave me alone.
Half a brain. Shit. That's fucking half
brain. I mean, he had the brain I have,
which is,
you know,
you have,
there's a guy that's on the Joe rogan.com
and apparently I did not ask for this
and please stop doing it.
But people send him horrible things
and including like someone brought some
whole thing about him. He's a
real estate agent. Wait a second.
He has Joe rogan.com
[inaudible] name's Joe Rogan.
Joe rogan.com it says name
your Joe rogan.net. Yes. All
right. It's his name. Yeah,
you wanted to sell it to me,
but he wanted just some fucking ridiculous
amount of money rides. How much?
It was more than $80,000 or something like
fuck off. Something crazy. It was like,
what I, it's not hard to find me.
You know Madonna one that
lost find me through Google,
but that, no, it's his name.
His name is Joe Rogan,
but people sent him,
if they wrote something up about
don't do that pride and take that off.
Take that off. Come on. I
don't want to pick on the guy.
It's just his name.
You know the guy is a real estate guy,
but people send them rude shit. Whoever
sending him rude shit, please stop.
It's not a bad guy.
Just doesn't want to give up his thing.
So he said he would give it up for a
shitload of money and he doesn't have to
give it up at all. Why should he do it
for less than that? He doesn't want to,
it's this business, you know, I don't
have a problem with it. I'm with you.
But that, but saying that large
amount is to me I knowing,
but I get what he's saying is I
don't want to give it up. Yeah,
he doesn't wanna give it up.
So he says,
oh I'll give it up but I want like a
year salary. That's like, you know,
there's nothing wrong with it.
I guess it makes sense cause he's like
this is how I could make my money,
my business. If you're going to pay for
my business, I'll give you the name.
And as far as like website domains go,
like there's been website domain names
like business.com it wasn't that sold for
like millions of dollars.
Oh there was a bunch of people right when
the Internet started who made millions
like before that was became
because that's illegal now.
How did you not do that Brian?
It seems like something you would be
jumped on a bunch of cool domain names and
sell them.
I have like 30 domain names.
I just don't sell them. Yeah.
But I mean like a really cool one
that's valuable. I have a bunch,
I have a Coca-Cola dot com yeah,
but why wouldn't you like put them
up for sale if you have a bunch that,
cause I think,
I think it's something that it's fun to
collect kind of like like a old comic
books,
but I'm not really sure yet if any that
you think could make some serious cash.
Yeah, I think so. Well one of the
funniest lines with Brian ever did was it
then called Pepsi Spice. Do
you remember? Pepsi spies?
Pepsi spice was some fucking bizarre
idea that someone at Pepsi came out with
where it's like it was
like a holiday Pepsi. Yeah.
It was like just the name sounds gross.
It was gross. It was gross. So anyway,
Brian Buys Pepsi spice.com and puts up
this daily blog of him slowly darn of
horrible disease.
Ease
these spice for 30 days. Pepsi's spice
for 30 days. It was one of my favorite,
like things supersize me,
but with Pepsi Spice Spice and this was
probably before supersize and this was
right during supersize me cause I
actually got it based off that. Oh,
you got the idea from that. Okay.
Yeah, because I was like, all right,
I might do something where he's
Dad, what you was supersize me? Uh,
I think it was, well this is a, that came
out, this was like 2002, right? Yeah,
it was 2004.
2004. Yeah. And, and I,
you know, if there was,
it was on like all the websites I got
interviewed and rate for radio stations
and then it got to the point
at the very end where, uh,
the girl I was living with, which was
the Lindsey Lohan at the time, uh,
she said she was saying that
it was a really sick and
dying. Lindsay Lohan. No, no,
that's what I said in the,
in the blog
I had about 50 questions clarify that
Lindsay's people on the phone right now.
Lindsay says, hi, Lindsey is over and she
is helping me drink my 10th, two liters.
Ended up coming to La for the day,
right over some mo cane,
which was when I used to say
that I used to break up, uh,
mushrooms and mix it with
cocaine and snort it.
And I used to call it and cocaine.
I mean,
Lindsay would sit around and do mo cane
all the time. Pepsi Spice Blog. Yeah.
And then I ended up just dying and I
started getting like clogged armpits
because there was so much Pepsi spice
that armpit started getting this huge rash
and they're getting clogged and then
bow wow was helping me out with money or
something. Like I can't
remember, but it was really fun.
Here's why I liked that so much too.
Why is that any different
than supersize me really?
Because why would you think eating
nothing but Mcdonald's is any more or less
healthy than Pepsi spice? It's
almost mocking that movie. You know,
a lot of people have disputed that
supersize me guys claims I know a lot of
interesting. Um, I want an, you know, I,
I would have thought that there's no way.
Like he wouldn't be bullshitting.
Like the,
there's the results wouldn't be that bad.
I mean it seems similar or
would definitely be that bad.
But then I watched a show, Marie had
that show 30 days. Yeah. It was kind of,
I saw some fuckery in that show.
No,
I felt bullshit when I was
watching the documentary.
Like what he threw up very early in
the film. I don't know if you remember,
you were studying it to build. Yeah. Yeah.
I, you know, I never really thought of it,
if any of the show being fake because I
actually watched all of his shows like
the 30 day shows and I
actually enjoy all of them.
I never really looked at him like,
oh, this is fake. No, I know. I know.
One of them is fake and
this is how I know it. He,
he did one on hormone
replacement therapy and he used,
while he tried to use a doctor
that I know and the doctor said,
there's no way I would ever do that.
He goes,
do you're asking for something
completely unethical? He goes,
if a guy wants to get on hormone
replacement therapy, first of all,
why would he want to do that in his
thirties he guys like 33 years old in this
television show and he goes, and second
of all, you don't do it in 30 days.
He goes,
he,
he wouldn't even start it from months
like before you do anything where you give
the guy hormones,
you got to figure out a way how to
optimize his own body's production of
hormones. That's the most,
the only way to do it,
but I'm sure there's doctors that would
do it. You know Hollywood doctors.
I know how the doctor that
does not listening to me,
but the reason why it's
bullshit is because the only
types of doctors that were
willing to do what he was asking them
to do, we're completely unethical.
So they made these conclusions on the
show about what replacing your hormones
are all about.
Completely based on unethical doctors
willing to fit within their production
schedule. That's an unethical show.
That's a show. That's bullshit. Because
the dot. Yeah, exactly what you're saying.
The doctor who did it is fueling
lies to me to be on TV, to get more,
and you're spewing lies in
order to produce a show.
Then the parameters of your 30 day
time limit, it's stupid. I watched it.
I was gone. No doctor would
just give you testosterone.
They don't look at your test levels
and say, oh, your levels are low. Uh,
you're 35 years old. What's
going on? Do you sleep?
They would start looking at
you. You're fat. First of all,
you've got to get all this
shit out of your body. Okay,
what are you eating? Okay,
stop eating that. Starting this. You
need to eat spinach. Do drink water. Oh,
they would be crazy to do that.
You're going to break the guy's system.
You would never do that.
And so in the show,
the guy that gets angry
and starts fucking throat,
well there's somebody just shot
him up with testosterone. I'm like,
he doesn't know what the fuck is going on.
This is not a balanced that in his body.
And he doesn't even know.
I remember watching that. I mean,
I dunno if he could be a good guy.
I mean Nice Guy, you know,
whatever. With music,
I started watching like
watching the movie, like some
Mcdonald's is bad for you.
That's the, that's the takeaway
from this film. I mean,
that's why I like the Pepsi Spice thing.
It's like no shit.
If you just live on mcdonalds,
you'll vote on Pepsi spice.
You're going to fucking, exactly. It's,
you're not supposed to be something
that you live on every month.
I don't think the President Mcdonald
would say eat at every meal every day for
it.
30. But the, uh, the, the
idea that his whole life,
he was like ready to die because
of it. Man. I'm not buying that.
No. Well, I was, a
friend of mine was like,
I was going to go see the movie and
he's like, no, that's bullshit. I said,
well how do you know?
He's like, cause I was,
I lived in this apartment once and my
dad had a job out of nowhere and I didn't
have a car.
So I had to live right by Mcdonald's and
I ate McDonald's every meal every day
for like 60 days,
and I'm here to talk about it because
of what the fuck are you talking?
Yeah. Okay. There's, there actually
is quite a bit of criticism
of that online of the, that
movie. Yeah. Oh, I'm sure.
Yeah. Supersize me is not the scathing
and factual indictment of the fast food
industry that Morgan Spurlock
wants it to be. Yeah. There's a,
there's quite a few people that, that
looked at this and said that this doesn't,
doesn't align up sponsored by Mcdonald's.
Yeah. Look, it's interesting, you know,
it's always interesting when you
find out how little nutrition is in
positives. If it gets the word out, the
fat, you shouldn't eat a lot of fast food.
That's a good thing. But you don't
want it to do it through. Right.
Bullshit. We have a real sickness in
the society where we, we need fast food.
You know, when you're
in your car, I fucking,
he was pulling and grab a
burger real quick. Like,
I mean it's nice that you can do that.
But man,
we need to figure out a way to
fucking relax a little. You know, the,
the older I get, especially when I'm
running around, I need to get a coffee.
I gotta be here on time.
Do I really need to be there on time?
Do I really need to get a cup of coffee?
What I really need to do is not be,
it's fucking busy like this,
this craziness of being stuck in traffic
and not being able to get home for two
hours.
So you pull into in and out Burger,
whatever we all really need to do is
figure out a way to never be in fucking
traffic for two hours every day of
the week. Cause that's craziness.
And that's a big part of everybody's
reality. And if that's your reality,
then it's also possible that your reality
is cheeseburgers that grab a quick
meal,
coffee
in the morning because you're
fucking sleeping. You know,
you got to throw down a 20 ounce coffee
on the way to work just to wake the fuck
up that damned espresso machine I was
telling you about that my parents got me.
That's ruining my life. My wife got me
one for Christmas a couple years ago.
I use it more than anything anybody's
ever bought me ever except this game of
Thrones box
your luck. It's bad
ass. That's really cool.
Sorry. It's pretty, you're
a bed show box show up yet.
Not yet. It will be there. So what's that?
Um, not season two. It's all the calm.
They scraped off from that show.
Girls put her in a mayonnaise jar.
It's imagine if you saved all your com.
Has anyone ever done that from the time
they were like a young man tough today?
Like no, it's mine. Just have a
jug by the bed. He Jack off into it
cause I, I, I've done that
and that weird that I'm here.
I've done it for a couple of weeks.
It's a kid a couple of weeks. Yeah.
Where you would to like
have like a mountain dew can
not when you're a kid you'd
just like to throw it in. By the way, are
you not joking now when I was younger,
when I was younger, like when I'm
saying 38 something like that,
like I remember you and you're fine with
this on iTunes and Ustream long as it
doesn't get on stitcher and other thing.
Is that what was even grocer is that I
even have a bit about how I used to fuck
pillows and I would fuck my pillows all
the time and then my mom would have to
take my pillowcases off and I just
remember looking at my pillow cases like,
man that looks so gross. It's just like
covered yellow and it's gotten hard.
My housekeeper found one of my old
tee shirts wants that wasn't a fun
conversation. What did she
say to you? Yes. She's like, I
know she, she just cleaned it. She was
like, here's your shirt. I was like,
I don't want to wear the shirts.
Good to me. That's it. You're scared.
He's scared of the loads. Know, but that's
not a shirt you wear to high school.
I always thought it'd be a funny thing
if like you're in a hurry in the morning
and you just grabbed a shirt real fast
and you get to school and realize it's
your comrade. You have to,
where are we playing games?
Jerk off. We're pretending he
doesn't jerk off. We all jerk off.
You might as well go to school with a
fucking load stained shirt. Who Cares?
I think I might have one on right now.
That's a new cool thing.
I'm going to come on this house Rogan
shirt and bring it back tomorrow.
I don't give a shit.
We should wear each other's shirts.
Fuck you man. He just creeped me out.
You're wearing a higher prime nature,
by the way.
Those who have been restocked higher
prime at all of them had been restocked.
Yeah. That's a dope one. Cool. Sure. Yeah.
I got a tee shirt company. It's small.
Mostly monkeys and psychedelics.
That's the whole thing.
I love to call higher
primates, higher-primate.com
not on the website. Yeah.
Then you do real estate too,
right? No, not anymore. Now I'm,
I catered only to the gay community.
That's somewhat something someone created,
like the whole pamphlet about this kind
of catering only to the gay community or
they put it out online.
Jayda pull your new
kicking ass on that pole.
I think since we talked about the poll
yesterday, you're, you're now up, oh,
let's hold,
oh,
Annie's the training MMA fighter.
Okay. Okay. Can I get your back
on that for one second? Again,
I don't like to kiss ass,
but I saw that interview
because I was listening to that one.
But I also saw there was with the hands,
but I was watching the clip that they
were apparently who was somebody was
pissed at you about that. I
don't know. But you were very,
you were almost like knew that the clip
was going to get out on most and you
were like very politically correct.
And what you said in a weird way,
like you don't forget,
you said transgender.
Even like there's nothing controversial
about what you said. Well,
I'm not, you know, I'm not an
insensitive person. You know,
even though I'm a comedian, when I'm
talking seriously about a subject,
if I was on stage,
I might say tranny,
but I don't want to be disrespectful
to what someone's choices.
If I call you a tranny, I wish we were
good enough friends. We could fuck it.
Take it. Okay. I wish that
I could call you a trainee
and you would, uh, you would,
you would laugh it off and
just be happy to be who are,
but just the fact that you knew to say,
cause I'm learning this on comedy
central through standards and practices,
what you're supposed to say and that
suppose not trying to say training,
but I was impressed.
He said transgender and
all you said was that, uh,
they shouldn't be this woman.
You even called her a woman shouldn't
be allowed to fight or this, this, no,
you called her woman. You said she,
she shouldn't be allowed to fight men.
That's not fair.
Well,
no, she shouldn't be allowed to fight.
We'll fight women. Yeah, I'm sorry.
And by the way, she fought women without
disclosing the fact that she used again.
So that's lying.
And there's doctors that are saying,
this is something that we talked about
this yesterday, but just in the, you know,
the possibility that no one
heard that or people listening,
some of you haven't heard that there's
a mechanical advantages to being a man
that are absolutely undeniable.
The size of the hands, the,
the width of the shoulders,
the,
the fact that you've had testosterone
freely flowing through your body for 30
years. 30 years. Yes. When
you go on hormone replacement
therapy and take estrogen,
you lose bone mass. You, you most
certainly lose some muscle mass.
You definitely change physiologically
and become closer to a woman,
but it's not a woman. And
people will say, well,
what about a woman who's
just naturally strong?
What about like a Serena Williams,
like a super athlete woman? Okay,
that is who she is.
We're not talking about allowing
someone to go from the most vicious and
powerful sex,
the mail sacks and compete in a
violent sport against the softer sex.
There's an aberration people.
But what, but what year, just
to clear it up, you were saying,
you were saying nothing about
the transgender community.
You were not saying that this particular
person should not be allowed to fight
women fight
women. That's it. Even if it's a race,
if it's a big game of basketball even we,
we joked around about it. There's
a 50 year old man, um, in um,
California that's a,
a transgender and has joined this college
basketball team and is playing women's
college basketball as a six foot six,
220 pound man.
He's enormous. That's insane. It is
insane. But I don't have a problem with,
no one's getting hurt as
long as he doesn't start
like hard fouling or bullying
people or something like that and using
his size and it seems like they all like
him.
I don't have a problem with it.
If it was my daughter and she got hurt
playing with him cause he knocked her
over, I might be like, hey man,
that's kind of fucked up or
something along those lines.
But for the most part I think in
non contact sports it's probably,
you know, I mean I think the Olympic
should probably have a standard,
I don't know what it is. If they've even
figured it out yet. I think they do.
I think they do have it.
I think it's two years.
You have to have two years
of hormone replacement.
But I do not think that that should apply
to violent combat sports. I just don't,
what if, if like Rhonda Rousey was like,
look, I want to fight this trigger.
You know what,
which drainage or transgender women
or I don't even know what I mean.
Yeah. That's his safe words. And I say,
do you think,
do you think she should be out?
Shit, shit should be, should
that be allowed though? Like
if Ron, Ron, first of all,
Ronda Rousey is obviously,
if you're looking at the
spectrum of powerful female,
she's at the very top of the spectrum.
She's a world champion woman's
cage fighter, you know,
she is a fucking legit certified Badass.
So this guy that became a woman was never
as skilled as Ronda Rousey when he was
a man. And the, the strength and
the skill that Ronda Rousey has,
I'm pretty sure she'd be
able to overcome some, uh,
transgender average person.
But you know what,
if you found out that Ronda Rousey used
to be a man and that's why she was so
bad ass and flipping people around this
transgender has knocked three women
brutally unconscious in cage fights that
did not know that she used to be a man
and she's stopping them like
inside of 30 seconds. Okay,
that I've watched the fight.
That is not the way a woman moves.
That's the way a man moves.
I'm watching the way she's
beating up on these people.
The mechanical advantage is still there.
If you look at her,
her fucking shoulders are wide.
Her.
The deception is a part of it because
you should be able to say who you are.
That's a thing.
This is that there's a real problem in
the transgender community and in the
super progressive community
that supports transgenders.
They don't believe you should even
have to disclose that used to be a
transgender. When you attain
it, they don't think that
you should be able to just,
you have to disclose it for work.
They don't think you should have
to disclose it for competition.
And I say bullshit
because it's not a woman.
You're saying it's a woman because
they've changed into a woman and they're
injecting woman's hormones into it.
But if you look at them chromosomally that
is an x, y chromosome. That's a man. If,
if you talk to them individually,
they, for the most part,
they don't like my brother's gay and
knows a lot of transgenders who he calls
trainees,
but I'm not allowed to say training
because I'm not gay because they know
because it was, yeah, exactly. But it
suck a cock just so he could say, yeah,
I should unclos talking brothers
Cock and then you're done. Listen,
to be honest with you.
Exactly. How do you know?
You don't know my or my mouth has been,
but like every transgender who
I've met through my brother,
totally cool. They always joke about
they, they say trainee, you know,
they say like, ah, it used
to be, it's a joke, right?
I guarantee you all these people I'm
talking about wouldn't give a shit about
what you're saying is a lot of the people
that are getting super upset or not
even transgenders, that that's what I'm
saying. We're more more of those angers.
I don't think the anger is
coming from Huc community.
There's this weird left wing
anger thing going on. You know?
That is where people think that if you're
not progressive and you disagree with
them in some way,
that it's cool to call you an asshole
or a caveman or a piece of shit or
whatever, and I haven't taken
a lot of this on Twitter.
It's hilarious from people where I
have been nothing but supportive of
everything except of man who
used to be a man fighting women.
That's what I'm supporting you.
That's you.
Because you went out of your way to just
say this specific person and you ain't,
she even called her a woman.
Yeah. Well she's not a woman,
but if she wants to be a woman, I'm
cool with that. If you want to be a her,
that's cool.
You are a transgender.
That's what you are and
you're a transgender woman
and I am totally okay with
whatever you want to do for a living,
whatever you want to call yourself.
I'm okay with all of that.
As long as you can't beat up women because
I really don't think that it's fair.
So why wouldn't women's groups come
to your aid and say we don't want,
I think this is a relatively new issue.
First of all,
this is a relatively new issue,
but Misha Tate,
who's a high level women's MMA fighter
has already said she's going to be the
coaches on the next ultimate fighter.
She just said she would never fight
this check. And she just said, you know,
she wants to,
she would need to hear more about genetics
and test or a body composition and
testing. I have, you know,
like on that same token,
like I have gay friends who like hate,
glad, they're like, they're just taking,
they're put in to making us sound
like we're proved and stuck.
I think they just take it too
far. So like, it's like, you know,
just everyone needs to
come to, well this, this,
there's this thing in the progressive
community where they're really aggressive
and shitty with people that has an
opposing opinion and they like immediate,
like one of the, like I've had
disagreements with people, uh,
about rules and regulations regarding
cage fighting about decisions for cage
fights and have many more people be way
more polite about their disagreements or
I felt that he won because of this
reason. But Hey, thanks for the, uh,
the forum to discuss this are people
pretty fucking cool and rational,
but it comes cage fighting fans.
But people that are upset with me that
disagree with me about this trainee thing
universally have been
insulting almost universally.
And I looked at how many tweets you
think you've gotten about it? Hundreds.
Hundreds. Just, I don't know. No, no,
no. Put it away. I don't even care.
But if this has been less than
how long? Um, I dunno. Well, we,
the David Lee Roth thing was last
week, but less than a week. Yeah. Well,
whatever it is. Um, it's,
it's interesting that so many people who
consider themselves sensitive left wing
are also like really quick to
insult you for no fucking reason.
Like really quick.
Even if you,
and even when I've responded
to them without insults,
you get more back,
asshole shit had Dick Wad just
over and over and over again.
You fucking insensitive
pig. You know, like,
like I'm an honorary.
I'd be the first to tell you if I thought
you were being insensitive or if like
if you were saying shit about, you
know, certain know I would say,
I would say I wouldn't
bullshit you if you,
if I thought you were making fun of gay
people or transgenders or whatever it is,
but that was not what you were doing.
That's what I'm sticking up for you.
Well thank you.
But that's sort of my point.
My point is that there's a bunch of
people in this society that aren't really
outraged.
What they're doing is choosing to be
outraged and they're outraged about a lot
of shit. They're outraged about
the state of their own life.
They're outraged about the progress
they have in their career, their,
their romance there, whatever the
fuck it is, their weight loss program,
they're outraged about a lot of shit and
when something comes along where they
have the green light to
be upset about things,
then they feel like it's
on Twitter waiting to get
upset and they feel like it's
cool to like lash out. It's
cool. It's cool to like let,
I'm taking a stand,
fuck this and fuck that and fuck you.
And whoa.
Like we're just talking about a guy who
gets an operation and now is allowed to
beat the fuck out of girls.
And I'm just saying that I know a lot
about beating the fuck out of people.
I'm a professional cage
fighting commentary.
I've been involved in martial arts my
entire life and I know a lot of trainees
and I know trainees that look like girls.
I met a trainee once,
she was tiny,
she weighed like a hundred pounds and you,
you would never know that this was a,
this was a girl or it wasn't a girl.
This was born a guy and I made
that mistake a couple of times.
I've had it happen a bunch of times.
We had one on the man show,
she called herself vanity and
she was a beautiful man. Really,
really pretty.
And she also had a dick that looked
like a plays and monkey cock.
It was like black and it was like she
was slowly poisoning it by feeding an
estrogen tastes the same. I don't know.
I didn't even, I was drunk at the time.
The um, this woman, what we had,
we did, we had this show called,
this is one of the things about
working for comedy central.
I'm sure your experience is probably
more positive than ours because we were
coming in sort of to a preexisting show.
Yeah.
And they had a lot of ideas about
what it shouldn't, shouldn't be.
One of the things was we had a show
called make previous regime. Yeah.
Those fucks, they're done.
They're done yet dead. The, um,
we had a show called make me hard
and make me hard was we would put a,
like a box onto your cock
that was supposed to like
recognize when you've got a
boner and there was a light bulb on it
and light bulb would flash red whenever
your dick out heart. So we would have
things like major seat and bananas.
Of course you dick would get hard
and just really ridiculous shit.
So we had this woman who was, yeah, she
was in a bikini and I'm telling you,
there's no way you would not know that
she was born a man.
She hot as fuck.
If you were stuck on a
deserted island with her,
you wouldn't even care that much as
long as she kept her pants. Dot. Yeah,
she's preop. Okay. So she's, uh,
she's on top of this guy and she's pouring
whipped cream all over her enhanced
breasts, which looked amazing. Um, the
guys suck in the whip cream off of her,
her breasts.
Everyone's going fucking crazy.
Then she pulls her fake or pulls
her pants down to reveal her poison.
Dick is withered. Bonobo. Monkey. Dick
looks like mine. And of course then the,
the light starts flashing like crazy.
The guy's Dick a hard as a rock and the
audience let out the one of the most
tangible moans I've ever heard,
like one of the most like visceral,
like down to your DNA, Moen. It was like
as soon as the, the, the cock came out,
I was like,
oh.
It was just like thinking about the fact
that this guy just been sucking on this
girl's tits, whipping know
whip cream, sucking lip cream.
I for tents like seconds ago, all
the way. By the way, he's tied up.
He can't move his boxes on his cock.
It's crazy. It's crazy. Cause I might, my
show, they have to, is it up there? No,
we're not talking to you that they,
they,
we did audience testing of our show and
one of the first bits I did on my show
was my buddy Brian, who's gay. I get you.
You're not as bad as other Brian's in
the world. You fuck. Yeah, exactly.
You're my buddy now. But he was
my buddy still. He, uh, he's gay.
So we this, that APP Grindr where you meet
guys, uh, you know the APP. Grindr. Yeah.
So I get on Grindr. I tried to get
him late through the APP. Right.
So we send that the show,
the audience test.
This is what I heard cause
I'd never saw the results.
It's like once the audience
saw that scene, they were done.
Like they will not watch this show.
Like they just,
they thought the whole show was like,
it almost made me not go to air because
the lights just like this is a gay show
in that crazy to think that like, like
they couldn't, what happened? What I,
what I heard was that the, you know,
people stopped, you know, they,
they move the meters and I'll let shit,
people just tune like they're done.
Like there was funny stuff after I
thought that piece is really funny,
which is actually airing.
Wow. It's going to air. It is.
So I give him credit for airing it, but
they just stay too. They're just like,
this is gay and I don't want the
testing people to think I'm gay,
so I'm not going to say I liked this show.
It's not even, it wasn't even, you know,
just
me trying to get my buddy let you,
first of all,
you have to think who's testing the show.
Those are the people that don't have
jobs that they pay to sit down and watch
these things.
And a lot of those people are crazy.
I give credit to the network
for ignoring that data. Yeah.
That just cool of them to say,
listen,
these guys didn't like the
show cause they thought it was,
there's a gay scenes of buckets.
I think one of the things that we've
learned is that there's only one way for a
unique vision to get on to television,
whether it's or in any form,
whether it's a movie or,
I mean it's gotta be this one
person's idea. Ben Hoffman,
what do you think is funny? Go with
it. And if you're good and if you,
you understand boundaries
and if you understand how to display
something that might be controversial and
allow people to sort of see
where you're coming from,
they'll accept it or enough people
will accept it and then also they'll
gravitate towards it. They'll go, hey,
this Ben Hoffman, this guy's for real,
his shows.
I appreciate that.
That was the whole vision of the show,
which is people always ask me like,
how'd you get this show on the,
it's crazy you got this fucking
thing on the or how would you do it?
And I'm not making this up when I
say this, the goal of the pilot,
because I was getting a lot of starting
to get more writing gigs and I wanted to
get better, right. And Gates, so I
decided I'm going to make a pilot.
That's just to get me better. Right. I'm
saying this to be completely honesty.
I don't want the show to get picked
up. That was my mode of thinking. I go,
I want to make the most of the craziest
pilot ever that people will see in the
industry and say, who the fuck is it?
I gotta meet this guy, we can't air,
this is unairable.
But I got that note at one point.
This is an Arab oil and it was, it was,
it was not like, it was not for air,
just going to be totally me. So instead
of having to send writing samples,
I could send this comedy central pilot
out to people and then he'd make me seem
more legit than I get a call. Like, Oh
shit man, you're not gonna believe this.
They fucking love the Bible is
that they need, which is great.
But at the time it was
not even a goal of mine,
which is almost the best way to do it,
which is I'm just,
I'm not going to listen to fucking
anything there. I, you know,
can't as it got,
you know,
guy running things over there and
he's really into an individual voices,
which is, I'm hoping that's
why I'm hoping the show were.
And there's a lot of that stuff going on
over there. And I again, I Kent Alterman,
he's been fucking great.
He's like, do your thing.
He gives me notes that make the show
and I'm not saying this cause that's,
cause he's not little,
he's probably not listening,
although hopefully someone
will give this to him. Um,
he's given me notes that makes
the show more me, you know,
so he's going through the thing. So
it's, it's, I was, I'm really in a,
I'm hoping people watch the show
obviously, so I can keep doing it,
but I'm really in a rare place
where I can do the exact,
there is nothing I've done on
the show they don't want to do.
That's perfect. That's the
only way to do a show, right.
Wants to get you think you're talented
and then support you.
The problem.
The only downside is when like these
Twitter things and that it's extra per,
it's I gotta I have to ignore it of
course. But they really are insulting you.
Like if you've gone when you go on stage
and do your standup and they had people
don't like it. It's harder for different
than you because people are coming in,
they're paying Mital cause
they liked your show.
But if you put yourself out there like
on your like standup specials you've done
and people don't like it, they are
insulting you as a person. It's like when,
if they insult my show, they're insulting
me. Like my, my actual dad's on the show,
you know. But that's good. I love it.
I mean it took me a couple
of weeks to get used to it.
I'm not going to lie to read that Shit
and get used to personal cause it,
all this stuff I'd done was like,
I was part of a show or writing on a show,
producing show being having
a small part in a show.
So to have my name in the show and have
you don't think about the time cause
there's no live studio audience,
but to do a show, you know,
kind of with my friends and kind of on my
own, do my own, put myself up, you know,
you know, out there for everyone to see
without again, without a live audience,
you just don't know. And
then it like month, a couple
months later dare. It's like,
wait a second,
I really fucking put myself out there
to do that though.
Because that's the honest reaction.
That's the people that aren't paid and
some of them are going to be assholes,
they're going to hate everything.
But the other ones have good
points and then be better.
Exactly.
And also,
but if if let's say a 60% of the
people like it, that's still,
it's plenty audience. Oh yeah. It's
more than enough. He's more than plenty.
40% hate it. You can't make
everybody happy. Exactly. What I've,
I've learned that at the heart,
right?
There's music that I love that I've
talked about on this, on the podcast,
and I'll get people fucking hate
tweeting me that fucking pussy shit.
One of my favorite bands,
honey honey that we've had on
the podcast a bunch of times,
every time we have them on,
I get a fucking hundred on the tween
from a punch of people out there.
They're just miserable.
And the crazy thing is these
are people who listen to you,
who just listened to your show
and they want to just get,
so their fans insulting one particular,
there's always gonna be that.
And especially because the
anonymity of the Internet and the fact
that they can just interact with you
through text on the screen.
This,
there's very little like reason to
be kind. There's very little to,
it's weird. I saw one of your tweets the
other day and it stuck with me. I was,
cause I was reading like, you know, I
got a separate in this shit I think.
Although it's sometimes fun to read
even insult, but your, what'd you say?
You saw Oz, the wizard of
Oz, the new eyes, blue eyes.
And you're like got bad reviews.
Just a reminder that uh,
most critics are said cons.
Isn't that weird?
You said something like that.
It just reinforced my notion,
my belief that most critics are sad.
That makes me feel bad.
Like that tweet calm me down
for about 30 to 35 seconds.
The reality is most people are critics
who are critics because they don't have
anything to contribute. They're not
artists. They wanted to be artists.
Almost every critic wanted
to be something artistic,
whether it's a writer or whether it's
they want to do screenplays are novels and
in fact some of them have and failed.
They're not the right people for the job.
The only right people for the
job or regular people. Not yet.
We get paid well and don't get me wrong,
I wasn't making like when an Asian woman
crosses a street and you hear me see me
hit a gong, like I wasn't
going. This is critics gold man.
This is like when people are
going to be funny. All I'm,
the whole point of show is just calming.
It's all it is.
W we do that in stand up and we do that.
And you know, on a podcast you don't,
you're not always saying things because
it's supposed to be the most brilliant
thing ever. He just, you know
what the funny thing to say is,
you know what the funny thing to do is?
Yeah. I mean this is, I
like these kind of like von,
these kinds of podcasts where I don't
have to be funny all the time. Again, I'm,
I'm, I'm not going to dead if
that's the case. But you know,
like when you have time, you want to make
a show, you just want it to be funny.
You're not thinking about like,
well, this reached the artistic,
it's just like fucking be fun
playing to the back of the room like that.
A super dangerous,
that's like some UCB shit where you
see comics that will survive there,
but they go anywhere else and
they eat a fat, played a decks.
The reason why is because you're
trying to be this like, you know,
really eccentric playing to the
back of the room inside joke,
you know, very verbose,
you know, very articulate.
You're trying to appeal to the critics.
You're trying,
well, I think I've noticed that recently
to meet the death of comedy is cool.
Yeah.
People trying to be cool.
It's killing comic and that's just
so much of that shit nowadays.
It's like those cool indie bands,
you know, these cool indie car.
There's just so much
coolness trying to be cool.
There are certain people that are just
cool and it's just who they are. Like,
you know, Chris Rock is cool, right? What
are you going to do about it? Exactly.
But he Chappelle's cool. He's a cool
guy, but he knows how to bring con.
I'm not saying you can't be cool. I'm
just saying can try to be cool. That's,
that's what the,
the,
these people are worried about making
an ass out of themselves. Right.
They're getting in the way of their
comedy by trying to be cool. Well,
there's that thing too
where they show some cool
does that thing too where they criticized
physical comedy and they criticize
anybody who tries too hard or they
criticize anybody who's animated on stage.
Like, oh, he's one of those comics.
And you're like, what an entertainer.
But someone's actually,
yeah,
I was watching Jim Carrey
on this interview the other
day and he was this inside
comedy show on showtime
is actually pretty good.
And he was talking about how like
ace Ventura came out and like have,
obviously it's not the critics. Critics
don't go, hey, go see ace Ventura.
But he gets,
he got calls from Steve Martin and all
his favorite comics were coming up to him
and telling him like other comics were
saying, God, this movie is brilliant.
And he was like, I can, who gives
a fuck about what that critic,
you know Steve Martin
called me on my phone.
Like my favorite comedian
called me and said, he called,
you know what he's saying?
You have to talk. I was,
I'm carrying Jim Carrey right now.
Jesus Christ. Brian, no cheap.
Martin didn't call me, but it would
be called people tuned in. Right?
You just woke up. See Martin called
you. Who are you? That's what happens.
You fucking playing solitaire over there.
You're following whatever.
But now I take it personally.
Maybe I'm being so fucking boring.
Listen man, you're not going
to your art, whatever it is,
whether it's a TV show or a stand up
comedy act, it's a work in progress.
It's always,
you're always improving it and you're
constantly getting better and part of the
input is criticism,
whether it's a positive or negative,
the input of the audience,
whether it's laughter or people
sending you a text message.
Just saying racism hurts
you the most though.
Is there any that hurts you at this
point or no? It shouldn't hurt you.
If it hurts me, I'm telling you
what hurts me is when they're right.
That's what hurts me. Yeah. If I,
if I did something where I knew it was
lazy or I did something where it half
assed it, if you tell me something sucked
and I'm like, okay, you say it. Sorry,
I just heard a thousand people laugh
their asses off and they enjoyed it and I
liked that kind of comedy. The
okay, that's how fine. You know,
you could say it sucks. This is not
your style. I know what I'm doing.
I know my style, I know
what I enjoyed doing. What?
What would bother me and what has in
the past is when someone would say
something and I knew that they were right.
You know,
I hadn't been working hard enough at
something or it was lazy or the bit was,
you know, it was a cheap ending to the
bid or whatever, something like that. So,
but those have been super
important over the years.
Like that negative criticism oftentimes
helps you more than anything.
That's interesting.
I never thought about it like that
because that I'll bet there are some that
really stung and got me really pissed
because they were probably going to stand
up. Do you do, I don't do standup.
Okay. That's the thing you see
when you're doing stand up,
you're constantly getting
reactions from the crowd.
You're constantly getting in plenty.
I did a lot of,
you know I did sketch all
the time so I was, you know,
I've been in front of those non laughing
audiences. So that's just an important,
similar, the difference being of
course, that when you're standing up,
you're completely on your own up there
and you've got nothing to talk about
other than what's inside your head
and trying to relay these ideas to the
audience. And some people can
do it and some people can't.
Some people can do it some days and
can't do it the other days and wouldn't,
especially when you start out,
there's a long process from the time
you first started out to the time when
you're like a legit
headline or a 10 years plus.
And along the way you have
to bomb you literally,
there's no way to do it right.
Every time you're going to fuck up,
you're going to be insecure.
You're going to get in a fight with your
girlfriend and you're going to fucking
have a bill that you have
to pay that's on your mind.
He's going to be a lot of shit and you're
going to have to learn how to navigate
and negotiate every one of
those particular situations.
Yeah, I mean that's kind of why I didn't
get into state and I just, cause I just,
I just knew, first of all, I didn't
want, it's not what I wanted to do.
I knew I wanted to do TV,
so I didn't want to be one of those
guys who did stand up to try to get
something else out of it. But like
I just knew I wouldn't be good at,
you know, it wasn't my thing.
So that's why he started.
You don't do it in the writing and all
that. I wanted to work my way into TV,
although my, my TV is kind of,
you know, that's my standup,
which is me putting myself out there.
Well there's a lot of people that have
become like sort of Internet stand,
you know, like they do like youtube
videos and shit and they like,
they'll have like a million hits
on them and you'll find it and,
and they're just a funny guy who's got
to take on something going to the movies
or this or that.
And I think you don't need to only do
it live in front of an audience with a
microphone. It's just, that's what
I like. That's my, I enjoy it.
But I could totally see a
bunch of different outlets
for kind of the same thing.
It's like what is, what is your
point of view? What is your or your,
your way to create a product,
whether it's a video or an audio clip,
whatever it is that you think is good.
I just, I, when I, when people ask
me to do live stuff, I just do it.
This one bit that I have
from my show life and that's,
I went until standup Saturday.
Like I forgot how fun it is to watch
like funny standup. It's fucking great.
I just go very rarely.
I mean my favorite, uh,
I don't know that I've ever laughed
harder than watching norm macdonald do
standup. He's, he's, he's,
he's my favorite standup to
watch prior to finally guy,
awesome guys and new podcast to
with Adam from Tempe Improv. Oh,
it doesn't really? Yeah. Oh, that's
great man. He wants to come on the show.
I think he's on the bench.
Oh, by the way. Um, and uh,
but just watching,
just knowing I can't do or let go as
a kid watching Richard Pryor movies,
like I can never fucking do that.
You could do that. Yeah. That's
not true. It's just a
matter of time, you know?
But I asked Richard Pryor wasn't good
when he started out either. I, nobody was,
you start out and you
still figure it out. Yeah. You
know, it's like anything else.
Like what do you choose? I'm
happy where I am, so don't,
I don't want people to think
like I'm bitching and moaning.
I don't think anybody does.
Well, I kind of do. Do you? Yeah.
The thing about you receiving
feedback though from the audience,
it's just you don't, you're not getting
that feedback every weekend in a club,
you know?
So when you're doing it,
you're putting together
your editing it and boom,
throwing it out there and
then you get the feedback.
So it's more of a slow reaction
to the work you're getting any,
but you get it all at once.
You get that night and then it kind of
slows down and every Thursday night I get,
we need all saw a new guy to
the new guy thing. It's like,
who's this fucking new guy? Yeah.
And I've noticed that over the,
even over three weeks I've watched it
dissipate, which is very good sign for me.
I've watched it like the haters leave.
They don't watch every week.
They were just like,
you interrupted my fucking favorite
show with your dumb shit. I hate you.
They go laid and the new then the
people who like it sticker. I just,
even even me, it's hard for me to get used
to a new show, you know, in a new guy.
It's hard. Yeah. It's um, it's, it's
really hard to get into new shows.
There's not that there's,
there's a better selection
of shows to watch now though,
that I think I've ever been before.
And also is that there's a new show
after mine called Nathan for you starting
Nathan fielder, which is another
really funny show. Same kind of thing.
He's just being himself and uh,
we're both kind of in the same boat,
which is a new night, you know, new faces,
new comedian. What's it called? Nathan.
Nathan for you. It's really
funny you for you. He takes,
he takes on to small businesses and gives
them business advice that he kind of
doesn't know what he's doing. It's really,
yeah, you should, we should watch it.
It's really good. So his name is, last
name is Nathan fielder fielder. Yeah.
So me and him have are,
are, you know, I'm at 10,
he's a 10 30 Thursday.
So it's Kinda this new night of comedy
for comedy central have to unknown guys.
So it's a slow build but
they're bringing back the cause.
I think that it's so
important to have new faces.
I think it's so important to new ideas
and new like, like your show, like the,
I love the idea of the hybrid between
a reality show and like strip mugshot
shit. But funny, like that clip was great.
I'm really looking forward to watching
your show now because of that one clip.
Like, that's like, well, you,
you, you, you, you showed a cliff,
you tweeted a clip about my, I don't
even know if you knew it was my show.
That last text ad thing.
Didn't you tweet that? Uh,
the wheelchair tweeting, talking
about, uh, the last texts he ever sent.
Did you send that at least
not the titties? Yes. That
was my, that's for my show.
I know. So you're watching it. You don't
even know you're watching it. That's good.
Um, yeah. So you're a good sign. Yeah. So
people are watching it and tweeting about,
and they don't even know my name. That's
awesome man. Yeah, that's really cool.
Including Joe Rogan. Well, it's
beginning, you know, I mean that's,
everybody starts from a beginning
point and you're, you're,
you're off to the races.
So I'm psyched about it.
But I think it's cool that comedy central
is trying like new ideas and taking
new chances like that for what
the new regime, it's, yeah.
It's like a lot of the same guys over and
over again and were getting like a lot
of stale
shit,
you know? Yeah. I mean, I, you know that
old regime, but I didn't know anybody,
those people,
but
this is how bad it was. You know the show
make me hard that I told you about it.
Yeah.
They wouldn't let us use the word hard.
The argument was it's
too mean or too vulgar.
Let's make it make me Steph. And I
go, are you fucking serious? I go,
are we really having this conversation?
You're really telling me that make me,
Steph is less offensive than make me hard.
You would like us to change the sign.
Yes. That's how we feel. Women. Nutty.
Crazy fucks. This is post nine
11 boners right though it was.
That was even before
the Janet Jackson thing.
The Janet Jackson thing happened in the
middle of Doug and I do in the Manchild.
Oh, that was the craziest thing
I've ever seen in my life.
I thought that was going to
have no effect. I was like,
why would anybody give him a Fox?
She pulls her tit out in the Superbowl,
whatever. But meanwhile,
these people were scrambling.
We showed up on the
set on Monday and they,
we had to have a special meeting where
they killed like half of our fucking
monologues, half of our thousand
crazy time. Just cause you know,
it was a bunch of weasels who were
worried about losing their jobs.
So they start scrambling to appease the
world and then the advertiser going,
what is the way the people,
the American people are
outraged at television. Oh,
we're going to show off and everything up.
Well,
I want to keep my job and I want to keep
my nice house and I want to buy a boat.
So we're going to polish
it up and we're gonna,
we're gonna give the American people what
they bought. What do they want them on?
No tests, no tests, no tests.
So we had the man show and we had all
these nutty fucking sketches that we
wanted to do. I was craziness and naked
people and shit. No, no, no, no, no.
They started, they started to hacking
at it. Everything controversial.
That's crazy. I remember at that Lou
Reed, while walk on the wild side,
they edited that song for radio
after the Janet Jackson thing.
That song been airing for 30
for 30 years on the radio.
God took out a line from that song on the
radio and Lou Reed fucking flipped the
line.
There's a line,
it's slipped in there that
that's something about
something giving head. Yeah,
and it was his given head. It's
never, it had never been given head.
Hey Babe,
take a while.
And He'd been erring on the
radio on regular rock stations.
Perfectly fine for 30 years after
Janet Jackson's Boob. They edit it.
Yeah, there's a crazy, there's a weird
clamp down in this, this world today.
And I think part of it has
to be attributed to the
fact that people know that
the world is insane and the,
the more they can sort of tighten
things down and regulate and stop and no
assault guns and no drugs and no swearing
and know and the more like control
that they can have over over people,
what they do,
what they say or what,
what sort of ideology gets broadcast.
The more they can do that,
the better because then it allows
them to believe somehow or another,
they've got at least a small
hold on this fucking craziness
that's in front of them, which is
the human species right now. I mean,
you look at the Internet and you see what
the fuck people are really all about.
Yeah. Trust me, I've been there.
It's loads and head's getting cut off and
car accidents and fucking lion attacks.
That's the Internet. Goddamn, it's 30%
porn. My first buddy you've got got the,
got the Internet. I remember
going and he's like, dude,
the first thing I saw in there, just look
at this a guy's head inside a vagina.
Yeah. I'm like, dude, I don't know what
the Internet is, but I'm already on board.
I like this. I like where this, where
this business going. I want stock. Yeah.
You can find out a lot of things that
are possible that you would like.
There's no way. Come on. Porn, uh,
represents 30% of the Internet.
I find that that even sounds a
little bit small, but that's a lot.
No, someone gave me a list.
Someone gave me a list of the uh,
the top I think it was,
and we were doing,
trying to figure out marketing
or something for the show
and the list of the top
websites in the world.
It was the craziest,
I knew everyone. It was like, I'm
not even kidding. 12 of the 20,
it was like porn hub and then be
like five down cnn.com it was like,
like stuff that I found out about later,
like x hamster.
If you ever heard of x Hammes yes.
X Hamster was like number three
or something and like, you know,
a Google was below, like it was insane.
The real porn or the real internet,
that's where the real money is quite
charging the have the internet.
If you think about it is more,
I mean 30% is like a weird number,
but if you stop and think
about what it really means,
it's almost a third 3% I still think
that's a conservative number, but even,
let's say it is a third,
he said you really do one at a three.
I think it's higher than that.
Most Internet traffic,
more than one a three is porn just
from the numbers I've seen before,
but I'm saying, yeah, for me it's 90
but you, but you know you're wrong,
but something wrong with you. Of course.
I know I've got, I've got issues man.
But you know that you don't represent
most people? No, I think I see.
I think because I'm open about it,
I'm probably not as,
I'm probably not as dark as
the most people. Most people,
it's probably 98 comedians are one of
the few that are allowed to talk freely
about beating off without fear of losing
our jobs to that's true, but let's say,
let's see, let's say it is, it
is a third. You're not even,
that's crazy to think that one third
of the time spent on the Internet is
looking at porn. Yeah, that's
insane. That I think it is a third.
I think a third is probably pretty well
the or 30% good if you think about it,
that you have to use her so much for
email or work stuff and there is a lot of
regular stuff you have to do. So
maybe that is right. I don't know.
We were definitely entering tane entering
into some weird area where people are
trying to like slow down like
free expression. I think. Oh,
there's some debauchery out there,
man.
I mean I listened when you go on those
porn sites and you hit the wrong button,
which I've done many times
or maybe maybe the right,
but how's he going to
say a lot of the night,
some nights it's the right button
hole. The man, if I seen some,
like I didn't curse on that one.
Yeah, I've seen crazy shit on,
uh, uh, most of which, uh,
you know, I'd rather not talk
about, but yeah, because, well, it led to
masturbation. It's, it's interesting how,
okay, if that's true, that's
30% of the Internet. Um,
which let's assume that's true.
And then those people who are watching
this porn on this massive amounts of
downloads and all this stuff,
they're going to regular jobs
where they have to be restricted.
They're going to regular jobs with Amy
the 30th right, but again, that's a lot.
It's a lot.
But the idea is that when they're at
work or when they're interacting with
people for the majority of the time,
they have to suppress all of that.
Like all of that is inside of their head,
but the internet doesn't represent how
you communicate in the corporate world.
It doesn't communicate.
It doesn't represent how you communicate
in in your average everyday experience.
You're like way more like conservative,
way more buttoned down,
way more like suppressed.
That's why I love comedy because
not to go back to my show,
but we do a bit on the show.
We have a barbershop quartet countdown,
the top internet porn videos of the week,
so like you would come into our office
and the writers and the prisoner all
around just look watching porn to find
the best titles. That's a job, right?
We get paid for that. Just to look
at, just to look at funny porn titles.
I fucking love it. Yeah, it's a, there's,
and there's some really fucking
funny ones, man. We, we pull,
we were talking about Annabella
Chong yesterday, who was
the first woman to do a,
a gang bang. And she,
uh, she actually, yeah,
she actually did it because
she was, um, she was a, uh,
a woman's studies, uh, students,
I believe at a USC. And
she was, uh, trying to, uh,
trying to figure out like,
like what's,
she wanted to be like a female stud,
like the female version of a stud.
So she fucked like 69
dudes and a in movies.
But when you look at like this,
it wasn't that many years ago.
Uh,
95 at the age of 22,
she became famous by engaging in 251
sex acts with 69 women are six 69 men
rather over a 10 hour period with the
resulting footage being promoted as the
world's biggest gang. Bang,
Huh? Yeah. But they're,
the names of the titles were
fucking hilarious. Um, yeah, no,
we have some, my favorite
was, um, my favorite one that
we, of course, I don't know,
he'd have to bleep it.
It was chubby honey has a bushy pussy.
Not chubby honey has a bush and
hearing a barbershop quartet singing,
it's pretty great. But just, I mean, you
can't write anything funnier than that.
Yeah. I'm trying to find her,
uh, when I was in San Diego,
this is what was on the TV at the
Hoover tower room. Joe Ass factor.
Oh No.
Is that Eisa Assa probably as harsh.
She takes it up the butter all the time.
Yeah.
They could probably go to jail for that.
That you stealing fear factors thing.
But that's a, they always, um,
have really funny names. Like,
here's one that she was in.
Uh, Annabella [inaudible],
sergeant pepper's Lonely
Hearts Club Gang Bang.
I would watch that right now.
Here's another one.
What's a nice girl like you doing it?
An anal
movie?
Legitimate question.
Yeah.
Um, anal queen. I can't
believe I did the whole team.
Whoops.
Yeah.
When there was no gang
bangs and I was a kid,
there's a really good
porn I would recommend.
It's called tonight's girlfriend and
it's this guy that just like pays porn
stars to be hookers for the night.
Wow.
And he makes a video on it.
Yeah.
That sounds a little bit like that Boogie
nights scene a little bit where she'd
stops in the limo on the side of the right
on the street. Yeah. It's Kinda like,
uh, like he makes some shower, uh, at
the beginning of every thing really.
What's it called? It's called, I believe
it's called tonight's girlfriend.
And the reason I like it is
not that because of that,
it's just filling the rather,
he does a good job of filming it.
So what do you like the way it's like
the cinematography? Yeah. It's, I mean,
some people just have better, I like good
cinematography, so I'll check it out.
Yeah. Wow. And this
guy a, is it a website?
I don't know if it's a website.
I've just seen a few of the videos online.
So a lot of those girls will work as
escorts. Right. Is that how it works?
I think he, he, I think the
idea is that they're not really,
they're playing escorts for the
movie or at least most of them.
But then if you think about that they're
actually getting paid to have sex and
they're actually being so kind
of a prostitute. Anyone? Yeah.
So kind of,
well, I read one girl saying that she
was, I read an article about a, um, uh,
a brothel,
one of those Nevada brothels and there
was a porn star started working at the
brothel and her attitude was,
well,
porn is just sort of like a revolving
brothel anyway. And I was like, Ooh,
it's true. How is it not true? Yeah.
And it was weird like listening to her
talk about her attitude towards it.
Like as long as she gets to go
home to her man, she was fine.
She was talking about that, like,
so then the guy was asking me, well,
do you do like weekend trips?
Do we who do? Well, you'll
do that. And she goes, well,
it would have to be a ridiculous
amount of money to keep me from my man.
I was like, oh honey, I'm sorry.
I got to go make a couple of couple
of g's suck in some cock. But uh,
when I come back,
I'm going to buy a motorcycle.
I would take that deal with Jim.
You say that now? I wouldn't,
I would not be able to do that now.
We had an escort on the show
and I was asking her like,
what the differences between escorting
a prostitute in which you say,
and she's like, nothing. Well, this
escort that they blur out her face. No,
we got to be showed her and she said,
I'm, if I'm a, basically she goes,
I'm just a prostitute. Wow.
Differences a camera man. Yeah, yeah.
She's allowing you to film that week.
But we got it.
But we got her number through
legitimate sources. You know,
it was like online legit prostitutes
source. No, no escorts. Escorts are legit.
Oh yes. We've got an escort. She comes
over, says she's just like, yell,
fuck you for whatever. She was
attractive. I wet chatted with her,
with my dad on the show, showed her
to my dad. My Dad's like, you know,
that's a very attractive. So you never
met her in person, you just web? No, no,
me and her are web web chat with my
called my dad back in Kentucky. Oh,
you were there right next
door and you called your dad?
She was attractive and my dad even
said as much and she was a prostitute.
She tried to hook it up with, you know,
she knew I didn't have, she didn't,
she knew it was,
it was,
it was a young show and I didn't have
the cash that she was looking for.
How much cash you looking for? What
did she say? Well, here's the thing,
you don't want to go down that road
because all of a sudden you were chipping
Norton. I can't speak for
him, but I'll speak for him.
I'm not shy. I, uh, it,
it felt like, it felt,
it would, it would have been odd. I'm
kind of a pussy. I didn't want to do it.
I get freaked out by like germs
and stuff. So I thought, Oh,
you're one of those guys. I thought
it'd be weird to have sex with him.
When you first meet a girl and before
you get busy do you started asking
questions?
So I asked him like in subtle ways,
I don't ask him like if you asked a girl
that you get kind of a slap if you're
really not slap, but apparently you don't.
But you know like just kind of like,
you know like, like you know like
do you like to party or like coke?
Yeah, exactly. Like I
tried to figure it out.
Like you just smoke or like other things
that would like lead them to a road of
debauchery.
What would you feel like if you were
with a girl for a long time and then you
found out a few years back just to
the gang bang movie but she quit.
It was bad experience. I would just let
down. I mean what about I would flip out.
You would flip out and totally. Would you
be mad at her? No, not mad. I would just,
I don't know that I can be with her
if she was awesome. Other than that.
What if like up until that moment,
like this chick's perfect check.
I mean did she go through a lot
of therapy after the gang? Nope.
She just realized, you know what gang
bangs or not for me, I'm moving on,
I'm going to time to start
teaching Yoga Gang Bang.
Like you just don't wake up some morning
gang bangs or not for me. Maybe you do.
You know what I mean? People, my friend
Dave, I told you he crashed his car,
never had a drink again. You know,
went to a little bit of court,
ordered a alcoholics anonymous.
But I think other than that,
you know what in your scenario and your
this scenario that she's a completely
new person, I'm going to give her the
benefit of the doubt. I mean not really,
but I just in theoretically,
yeah,
but if you went down on a little extra
salty would you worry that's just some
load creeping out and go to the gang gang
had been camping up there for a while
and I would check myself into an
emergency room and stay there.
I stayed there for probably two years
and I would pay for it on my all myself.
You couldn't watch, right? You
wouldn't want to watch the gang bang.
But someone told you about
it and they sent you show.
Even watching gang bangs in general
me numb. Yeah. It's not a gang banger.
I'm not even a two on one sort of a guy.
I don't like watching that either.
I think it'd be able to talk to these
guys like us who are more open talking
about porn, who probably watch it
the least. Maybe. I don't know.
Miami. I think it's the same
people who were quiet about it,
who are the real sickos probably
the least fucked up watching it.
But then I have daughters.
So porn took on a completely
different dimension since uh,
since I've had kids. It's, this is a weird
thing where you're looking at a porn,
like you know for a fact that
that used to be a baby. Yeah.
That was someone's little girl.
There was some oh daddy and hugging on
to and now she's getting plugged in the
ass and the mouth and she's
gagging and that's reality man.
I mean that girl you putting it up and
she's got her tongue out now on some Jews
just fucking jizzing all over her face.
That used to be a baby girl.
There's no way to get around
that and then babies of your own,
it totally fucks with your,
your, your vision of it.
I guess so. Yeah, so that, that's,
that's why I don't want to have kids
because I want to keep watching.
Like you want to keep
checking off the porch.
That's when dudes move on to milfs see
the four guys who were really in the east.
It's like you can't even think about
them being a baby anymore because it just
like 40 and only likes black guys now
have you noticed that when you watch porn
though that's like,
it's like every video was a different
girl but it's like four or five guys
total and all of the same guys,
the same guys over and over.
They say a lot of that is because
it's hard to do like it's hard to,
I'm sure guys to get it up in front of
strangers and cameras like and know that
people are going to watch your Dick and
be comfortable and you say you could.
You think you could seriously please.
You panic when you stand up.
Little half of black little, a little
bit of black power in me. I'm fine. Yeah.
You say that
people find out small. Your Dick really
is. They would go, what the Fuck Brian,
you said it was big. Jesus. What's wrong?
You don't tell the truth about anything.
Ever said it was big.
That's all I've been in here.
He can do pour certainly said it
was big. No please. That's big.
Yeah, that's big. I just said
a little bit. What's average?
What's the average ticket you've socked?
I would say like five,
but honestly though,
not even as a joke.
How would you know what averages nowadays?
Because all the only gets you see are
on porn and those are guys who are
professional.
The only things that you see,
this dude is always asking
people to show their tech.
So he's got some constantly
going around measuring. No, no,
I definitely not my tape. I definitely
have the Internet, so I've seen all sides.
That's what I'm saying. And your
defense and your defense, the Dicks,
you're seeing the cream of
the crop. Don't to know. No,
you're seeing the best dicks in the world.
If you ever know the juiciest
most delicious, you're seeing,
you're seeing the guys who
get paid for those dicks.
Don't compare yourself to that. Talk
amongst yourselves. I gotta pee mostly
comics dicks nowadays. Those are
probably smaller than yeah, yeah.
I don't know. So, uh, you, uh,
you're on your fifth or sixth episode of
the show. You've really been listening,
man. Jesus Christ. You
know, how many third,
third episode, three episode five more.
Uh, but how many of you recorded, oh,
we're done.
I actually came from the editing
studio just now to wrap the last one.
Like we're wrapped as of today,
right? And we're done with all aid.
Now you with the clip that we
saw was completely uncensored.
Like the language and everything like
that. Are you getting the beat treatment?
We're getting the bleeps but um,
you can watch them all on a little.
Most of the clips around censored online.
I wasn't talking to them like most of
the clips are uncensored online and um,
there's a pos,
there's some talk,
I don't want to say yet that we may be
able to show some uncensored versions
late at night or midnight
or I don't what the rule is,
but I don't want to promise anything.
But there has been chatter about that
so I want to get a buzz going about it.
Right. But I don't want it to
be official, you know? Yeah.
Well I mean South Park did
it, you know, they are moving
south park, you know, they,
and also south park
is TVMA cause they were
just like we don't want it.
You can't Air TV and
maybe before 10 which is,
you know when they say shit and fucking
stuff so that you can only air the new
South Park's after 10.
But they said they don't give you no,
we don't care because those early,
those early reruns are,
uh, um, what's going on,
Joe of get through the curtain and we
have these new curtains in the studio and
like, it's just like, you
know, have to try to find the
opening of a curtain. Yeah.
The Joe Rogan experience without Joe
Rogan's it'll get a little weird. Um,
are you, are you, like
you said you're, are you,
are you like the kind of person you don't
like to shake people's hands and stuff
like that doesn't bother
me as much anymore. I mean,
it used to a little ass play as play is
different because that's a nice clean
ass. You've wiped it and everything
maybe I did is not really cleaning it.
Well imagine if someone's smooth shit
on your face and you just took a little
piece of toilet paper and wipe it off.
No, that wouldn't really work. Yeah,
really clean that shit. Really. It's,
it's really a shower is the only
thing that way to clean it up.
We've got to get in there. Well, I
got one of those Japanese toilets.
I still have him fucking installed
it. Yeah, cause I'm so God damn busy.
But one of the ones that you
and I experienced, right. I
always wanted to try one.
It's the best I should
have had it here for you.
You just stay on the toilet longer though.
Like you find yourself and you
just want to feel the water shit,
squirt it in your ass and you just
don't want to stop it. I need,
what if I get a season two
that's my first charge.
Warm the seats warm and it blows air
on your asshole after cleans megahertz.
Stern talking about that.
It's a whole thing where it like
goes up and the whole thing.
Some ladies that finds her butthole and
that shoots it right in there. Yeah.
This has reminded me to go get that
fucking thing out of my garage and having
installed installed here. Yeah. You
got the be, if you've got it installed,
we're almost a studio's almost done.
We've got the curtains up now, Ben,
and you're here to break in the curtains.
Yeah. I'm here at this exciting,
it feels like show business, right?
Curtains. Something about show business.
It's about time with the big,
we've got the big animal outside and uh,
that's a werewolf buddy. It's on
animal. It's a werewolf. Look, sorry,
we got everything. It's cool. There's
a song that I really want to play,
but I don't know if we should play by ear.
You remember the dance floor Dale?
Yeah. There's another guy,
uh, that makes us made a song.
His name is Mike Diva and it's called
I'm on crack and it's just like that and
it's so fucking good song
that's like registered like,
or is it on the, you know,
I think he's just one of those guys that's
on youtube that just makes these cute
little like minute videos
based on really good.
As long as it's not like on like
universal records or something like that.
You know, were some big record
company. Say what it's from.
He just does like a weekly
video. Everything. We can do
it. I think we would like,
it was just, well, what's his name again?
His name is on Youtube. It's Mike Diva.
It's all one word, you know, a million
people going to listen to us easy.
So it's kind of fucked up that we even
have to, you know, like we should,
we should be good. We're
helping, we're helping people.
But you have to worry the Internet.
Isn't this, have you had problems? No,
but we have insurance for it and we
have, um, we also have lawyers now. Oh,
here we'll play, we'll
play. Let's play half of it.
So you would show something of
it? Yeah. Okay. So we're, we're,
we're also signing up
to a couple of programs
back
to
the club will feel master. I said fuck
that shit on. Went back to the bullying.
I kept that
right, right, right, right.
Okay. Hold on. Hold on.
This show is,
this music is unless inable it's so bad,
but the video is really fast. I actually,
Mike Diva just made the video. Uh,
that song is by a side project called
the left rights mindless self indulgence
side project. Oh, okay. I mean,
in this particular environment,
it's mainly visual videos. Impossible
to listen to. It's got cats and crack.
I love it. It sounds hilarious. I can't
stop living around how many views?
A 1.8 million.
Oh yeah.
I just loved the doctors possible that a
guy could just put out a video and it's
why does it have 1.8 million? Because a
bunch of people said, you got to see this.
It's pretty wild to watch. Yeah,
let's do it, Mario. Yeah, it's great.
It's a great video, man. It's a great
video. I liked the song. I might buy it.
When you go to a video and you see
it's got 18 million views and like,
what the fuck? How do I not know about
this? How are these people? Well,
I've seen the ones with the
hundred million views and
I'm like, oh, how's that?
How's that even possible? I am style. What
did that get up to? A billion, billion,
billion, billion. This is Mike
Diva. Actually. All his videos,
I have a lot of hits because he hit
that really has a billion views. Yeah.
What are we now at 2.5 billion about
total humans? Yeah. Whoa. More than that.
Seven. We're at seven. Seven, 7 billion.
Yeah. What'd I get? No, 2.5 in no dice.
I was thinking maybe America
write no America, 300 million.
Where do I get 2.5 minutes laughing at me.
You made it up.
Unless you live in the fifties I'm from
the fifties I mean you just gave up
million people in the world. Yes.
Well there's a billion in China alone.
There's more than a billion in Africa.
Africa is 1.5 billion.
I didn't know there was a building.
Yeah. So okay, I fucked up. Yeah,
it's getting at least to start,
we're going to lose.
You won't be recorded for
life. It's getting crowded.
Lack a mind. Fuck. And yeah,
that's a lot of people.
Maybe Gangam style is not that popular.
Well what's really funny, really a
billion people. It's 500,000 assholes.
We've watched it repeatedly ad nauseum.
No,
but on different computers though
cause he has to be different.
I think it has to be different servers
really do you think really gives a fuck
where the hell are coming from?
It would want to elevate that had that
problem before because people were
putting their videos up and just pressing
refresh all day and night to get their,
their counselor. It attracts
the IP address. So like it,
it counts as one view.
If you go to it,
like if you watched the here and ain't
at home, it would count as two. Oh, okay.
But if we have different computers at
this Ip address, it would count as one.
Correct. Okay. And the head of you.
So that is, so that's a very pop.
There's ways around that though. How
do you get around, uh, you use, uh,
use proxies, proxies. You just
get this list of priorities.
They must have had to do that
though for advertising purposes.
Because I sell advertisement now that
makes sense because they do it by CPM,
but how many downloads I get?
Totally. Yeah. Well if you buy it,
if you say you've got millions of views
and some company buys your shit and it's
just some dude click it over and over,
they're going to be pissed, you know?
Have you thought about doing a podcast
at all? I thought about, I don't know,
I'd be a good accompaniment to your show
and that some people are telling me I
just, I'm not really a talker I think.
Are you talking about, I mean I dunno.
Yeah,
I don't feel like I would.
Okay.
It's, I'm the wrong guy to ask
because again, like I said,
not a Ben Hoffman Fan so I'm the wrong
person to be asking you about this.
But I just feel like I've kind of talked
out and I don't really like even on
this show I feel like I was done. I was
done in an hour. What do you do at home?
Like when you get,
when you get home tonight or you do,
you just watch a lot of movies?
Hobby tonight. Cause I have,
we have an airing tonight so I have
to live tweet a new episode tonight.
That's a new thing is you tweet along
with the show. Like that's nice. Yeah.
Which is fine I guess. But, so I have
to go, but I don't have direct TV,
so I'll have to go to my friend's house
who has direct TV so I can watch the
east coast feed to live tweeted.
A couple writers will show up and will
live tweet the shows. So that'll be fun.
But uh, what was the question? I mean
like what do you do you have a girlfriend?
[inaudible] listen question. I've
been talking to you with my therapist.
What the fuck am I doing
with my team? Yeah, yeah.
Even going to a therapist
10 years. Really? Yeah. Wow.
Oh Dude, I got issues. What's the
number one? Do you, can you tell us?
The number one would probably be OCD,
but what you're showing your hand.
I got to say like even today,
like I did shake your guys' hands when
I came in here and I just now remembered
that I did.
So it's working I guess because you dealt
with the fact that he shook our hands.
Didn't go immediately wash yourself.
I'm saying not a big step for me is just
now remembering that two hours ago I
shook your hands in the old days,
I would've thought about at the time,
like my hands are like toxic or something.
Not that you're,
it's has nothing to do with the person.
Do a meet and greets after shows,
like theaters and I'll shake a
thousand people's hands. It never,
it never occurs to you, you
know, then I go eat. Really,
you don't wash your hands before
you were a case. You're, you,
you look at you need to and you shouldn't
be scared because there's nothing,
there's nothing bad about it. I'm going
to kill me with your sweat, but uh, no,
but see, I'm cured. I'm not
that cured, but getting closer,
I'm, no, I tried to wash my hands
after I do that, but I have,
there's been times where I
haven't, you know, for sure,
especially if I've got a buzz on, I'm
like, yeah, fuck it. Let's go eat.
You know? I mean, literally, I've been to,
I was talking about this on another place.
I don't want to get into it too much,
but I had been to behavior
therapy where they actually,
where you literally get your hands dirty
and touch your face, touch yourself.
That's how they teach. Telly.
Telly teach you to do it.
What made you feel like you needed this?
It was interfering with my life.
Literally. Like I went to go
to the, I would be in my car,
I'd go get gas and that would be going
out to get my meet my friends and I had
to go back home to wash my hands.
Wow. Home couldn't go to a bathroom.
So then by the time you get through all
that shit, your day's gone. You know,
it interferes with anything.
All I care about is anything
that's interfering with my life.
Do you have like hand sanitizer?
I don't, I don't touch this.
I need to get your guy to Howie Mendell.
You know how he's, yeah, I know he's like,
but heroes. But he, he sounds
like he's not dealing with it,
but he talks about it though. He talks
about it, but do it. I did work past it,
dealing with my issues.
You know what I like about that?
What you're dealing with,
that you're willing to talk about it.
I think that's Super,
oh, that's the thing is it
was never shy about it, but I,
but that's huge shooting people,
but I had no issues. I like to,
to be open about it and deal with them
and that helps me kind of get rid of them.
Well, it also helps by gauging
other people's reactions,
whether or not it's a real
issue or whether or not it's,
well it was so bad, but yeah, family
members noticed it. That's how I knew it.
And I'm like, maybe this is because
I didn't know what OCD was. Right.
And I'm like, I read about
it and I'm like, shit,
I have this time to a hundred you
know, this is bad. And like there is a,
I can fix this and improve my life. I'm
like, that sounds interesting to me.
Yeah.
It's,
it's really bad to keep that stuff to
yourself if something's really fucking
with you.
Because I think that there's a lot of
insight that you get just from talking to
people.
Like I've had conversations with people
where they tell me something about
something fucked up about themselves
and they go, you know what?
I realize I'm not fucking doing
that anymore, man. I've, I've,
I've seen people do though.
A friend of mine quit smoking in front
of me once he was, um, he was smoking.
We were about to go do a Gig and a, I
go, you are you smoking? And he goes,
I only smoked before shows.
I go,
but do you do shows like fucking four
days a week? And he goes, yeah. He goes,
I go with some, it seems like
you're smoking. And he goes, well,
I like a cigarette right before I
do a show. And I go, um, does it,
have you done many shows without
it? And he goes, yeah, I mean,
I just started doing this. I go, God damn,
man. He goes, you know what? You're right.
What the fuck am I doing? I'm like,
well, yeah, what are you doing?
And so then he put his cigarette out and
he quit and he tells me like every time
I see him, I haven't smoked since.
No, it wasn't even that I helped him.
It's just that having that conversation
in front of somebody who reacts to it.
Like if someone says,
Hey Ben,
stop washing your fucking hands every
10 minutes you need to go see a doctor.
There's something crazy about that. And
you're right. You know what? Yeah, I do.
You like the,
basically what you're saying is exactly
what happened and just opening up and
talking to a doctor about it. It's
like fucking fix it. You asshole.
Like you don't want to do this your whole
life. Like someone like Hyman again,
I don't know how met Adele,
but wouldn't that get in your,
wouldn't that be annoying
when you want to get it fixed?
Well,
I'm on the subs to the opposite end of
the spectrum cause I've done Jujitsu for
like 16 years.
Jujitsu is men sweating in your mouth.
You Girls Hassles. Well, I mean
I'm not averse to that either.
If the young ladies willing to
clean herself up. Right. But my,
my throne other subject. But you put your
OCD, you saw that is not healthy either.
I wonder how many people have
gotten sick from eating ass.
You eat raw horse meat, so that's
like, I'm way more chimpanzee than you.
My Body can digest that
horse meat without a problem.
I very rarely get stomach aches.
Um, is that true? Yeah. Yeah. I,
I ate me. Yeah. I was in a restaurant.
They served us raw horse meat.
I was going to say didn't enter the new,
the new thing.
Like apparently we're all eating
horse meat. No, no. That was a,
in the UK there was uh,
some food company got,
it was like a Lasagna
or something like this.
Like he had kissed Swedish meatballs.
Yeah. And they had pushed me to them.
By the way. The horse meat.
Delicious. It's really good for you.
And people looked through [inaudible]
horse meat. Yes and no. I mean,
isn't it fucked up to eat a cow? Isn't
it fucked up to get a goat? Yeah.
I'm from Kentucky where they
take their horses very seriously,
but I wouldn't if I was hungry, you
know, what am I going to this one?
Most people throughout history
have eaten horses. It's been,
it's been a guarantee.
Yeah.
I mean the Mongols eight,
their horses. I mean,
people have always eaten horses at
Ikea once, so I'm sure I should really
was the sweetest. I thought that was
in the UK. Wasn't that over there?
I don't know. It might've been over
there, but I heard it was here too.
I think it was, well, they're
just starting to, um, I think
it was, there's an Amish,
a horse company company that deals with
the Amish where they're getting horses
in.
They're slaughtering them now,
like older horses and they're
slaughtering them for meat. And uh,
the idea is they're doing it
through the Amish because the Amish,
they don't believe in the steroids or
any of the things that you would worry
about a horse having in its
body if you ate it. Yeah,
that'd be more people are fucking super,
you have a Pete do you have to pay
or something? I just look anxious.
People are super attached to
their horses though, man. I live,
I live near and this a question center
and I'm taking my daughter to go ride
around on horses and shit. And there's
a lot of people there that would like,
I mean if you told them that you were
going to serve people some horse meat,
they would,
they would fuck
freedive. I again, being from Kentucky,
I live friends who make their living,
you know, doing that kind of it so
I know where they're coming from.
Are you a horse person now?
No, not particularly. I mean, I
don't hate horses. I liked horses.
I was never that interested in like,
I mean I think it's a fun way to travel,
get on a horse and go on a trail. It's all
good. I like it, but it's not something,
I mean,
I could get into it.
I could see fallen in love with a horse
and taking it, you know, like, oh,
this is such a great horse.
I love having this horse and cleaned it
up and brush it and feed it and he'd be
your buddy. I could totally see that, but
I haven't had that personal experience.
And I feel like
at the end of the day that
the justification of eating
animals is pretty sketchy
at best anyway.
And then really we're just
fucking murdering all these
animals and eating them
eyes.
It really matter if it's a horse or a cow
Vegan for one year for no
reason. I wasn't like, you know,
like an animal rights person
and I just like, I wanted to,
I wanted to see what I just, for some
reason it was kind of during my OCD,
just like animals or like filthy and
Phillip Bacteria. So I stopped eating.
It's not healthy. I don't
like I was, I got really,
really thin and like really tired all
the time. Like I didn't do it correctly,
probably.
Well because of that I'm sure.
But there's also, there's,
there's certain needs that we
have and one of them is, uh, the,
the function that cholesterol has and
brain function, you know, cholesterol,
like it's not all bad for you as a
matter of fact. And they do. The test
doctor gives you the test, he tells
you your good cholesterol in your bag.
Yeah.
But the good cholesterol comes from
animal protein comes from fish.
I felt like shit, most of that time,
some of it's from plants you can get,
you can balance it out if
you're really diligent.
Two are vegans who know how to do it
correctly, but it's a lot of work.
Yeah. Um, there's very few high
level athletes that have done it.
That's what I was, I was gonna say
there's gotta be none. The only, I mean,
the only person I can think of,
well known didn't Clinton built in Bill
Clinton become vegan because it's hard
heart issues and he was about to die.
That fat fuck was just fucking eating
cheeseburgers constantly. Yeah.
Cholesterol plays a critical role in PR
and brain function and cholesterol comes
from animals.
I mean that's where it comes from.
I don't know of cholesterol was
even available in the, um, in,
in the plant community. The plant
kingdom. Is it? I don't think so.
You're asking the wrong guy. I think
cholesterol only comes from animals.
I'm pretty sure I'm
cholesterol is a substance.
Genetically I'm painted as black by
the medical and scientific community.
But the fact remains that is a substance
that is innate to the body and forms a
critical part of, among
other things, key hormones,
vitamin D and cell membranes.
It also,
it's also very concentrated in the brain
where it contributes to the functioning
of synapses,
tiny gaps between the cells which allow
the nerves to communicate with each
other. That's one of the things
that we had with um, um, uh,
Dave Asprey talked about this
and uh, Rob Wolf from, uh,
Rob Wolf who's a primal diet
advocate. He's a advocate of the, uh,
um, well it's uh, his, his
whole, I, it's all the um,
uh, Paleo. The idea. Yeah. Look, there's,
there's a lot of logic behind Paleo
diets when it comes to the human body not
being designed to consume wheat,
not beings designed to eat pastas
and designed to eat lean grass,
fed protein and vegetables.
Like, that's really what,
what's the date where you can,
it's all has to be the stuff.
Stuff that you eat with. Use your hands
to eat. Is that what I'm thinking?
No. Paleo. You can use forks.
Yeah, but they're so funny, man.
He lends itself some new die.
It's like
the caveman diet where you, it's the only
things you can eat. The caveman would,
he's probably an idiot.
I didn't say he wasn't an idiot.
No reason to not use a fork. The forks or
so on nutritious, I think. I think he's,
I think he was like the idea of anything.
Like you only eat stuff
that cavemen woody. Oh yeah.
Well I think you're misreading
what he's saying. That's Paleo.
That's fairly Olympic error. That's crazy,
man. I'm thinking about the right thing.
I just, I just said it incorrectly. Well,
no, this is not about utensils is what
he's using that as a way to
explain it to me. Oh, okay. I see.
Because I don't understand things,
but the idea is that genetically we're
not much different from the people that
live 40 50,000 years ago. In fact,
we're probably exactly the same.
You could take a guy from 50,000
years ago was a Homosapien,
dress him up in clothes and stick them
in a movie theater and before the movie
starts, you wouldn't even be able
to figure out who the caveman is.
It's just once the movie begins and he
starts fucking screaming and running out
of the room, then you know that's
the case. But depending on the movie,
you might be me. Yeah. You
think that's screaming and yeah.
More than a caveman who's never seen
a movie before. Yeah. If I write,
what would be the one movie that
would make you scream like Les Miz?
Probably Miss. Yeah. I don't know.
I saw that lame ass thing. I'm like,
if I had to choose between Kona jail
where nobody talked to me for 24 hours or
watching Les Ms for 24 hours straight.
I think you did cite it.
So take solitary for a day. How was
it? I have a thing. I don't know.
I have no idea. There's no way
I'm going to see that. Okay.
Now I want to see a movie.
About a bunch of people crying that
lived in the day where there was no TV or
internet and they were all fucking singing
everything and crying. I was draining.
A friend told me that it was so bad that
you should maybe see it then. I'm like,
but I'm, I'm, I don't know about you
guys. I'm not one of those guys who likes,
I don't get enjoyment out of things
that are so bad. They're good.
That's not fun for me. I do out
of some things like, um, the,
do you ever see the day after tomorrow?
No.
It's that really bad movie
about global warming where a,
it becomes like this crazy snow storm
that covers north America and everybody
dies except Dennis Quaid who
goes camping. Uh, he's outside.
It's fucking a hundred
million degrees below zero.
He's got a 10 east fines sipping coffee
and shit. It's like, get over here guys.
That's his voice through the whole movie.
Weird voice.
Like it sounded like a
South Park character and I
thought talking about watch
that movie and think of South Park
and top sounds so much like a self.
Totally making something. I'll pull
up. Pull up a scene. All right.
Hold up a scene desk. Wait, you just
totally made that up. Oh yes. Yeah.
First of all,
he's a fine actor and you are disparaging
that man's name and reputation. Uh,
the day after tomorrow, Sky's
got insurance. You can't
disparage his name. Yeah,
you can't do that, bro. I have a
fucking podcast look out for it.
Can't just be making shit up.
I just think, shut up man.
Stop it with the gay voice.
Stop at Gay Voice. Listen,
Paris Hilton is already mad at me
or the other one that Perez Hilton,
one of those guys, check this out and
tell me if this does not sound like a,
like somebody from South Park's is doing.
Dennis Quaid voice is better not be a
parody site. You took me til you fuck.
Got It.
Century Fox presents 10,000 years ago,
one store
change the face of our planet.
That is true this year. Maybe not a
store. Maybe it's an asteroid impact.
It's pretty short.
You see is
JPL was battered by the loggers?
Yeah.
If you're listening to this at home,
this is not nearly as interesting
as watching. What can we do
there? Go. The safer they'll be
DT for him to suggest this plan.
What's happening here in Washington.
His son is a Manhattan.
I'm the director of still,
so that's it.
That's his voice. What should we do? I
will come for you. Do you understand me?
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
Shut it off.
He made things up again. Turn it back
on. You may turn my voice on you made it,
made it up again. You're fucked.
There's nothing wrong with that guys.
I will shut the fuck I'm for you
not to go with Joe Rogan on this.
Just wasted our time. I'm just
saying that my opinion, Dennis Quaid,
his voice sounds like he sounds like
Trey Parker. That's what I'm saying.
That's all I'm saying.
You just take it to that level and for
some reason you are absolutely incorrect.
He does not sound like treat you with
that. That's my opinion. Oh my God, Brian,
we all heard, hey, if he sounded
totally normal, you're like, hi guy.
If that is not what he sounded like and
we, we, we, we listened to one sentence.
By the way, if you don't put
on some headphones and you
play it and you find me a
representative of what the fuck you
were saying and if it's not true,
we're going to hold you down.
True thing. I'm just saying,
I think Dennis Quaid his voice sounds
like Trey Parker doing south park.
That's all I'm saying. I'm saying
you might have brain damage. No,
I agree with me on that.
Yeah,
that'd be a mediator on this three or four
crazy fucks out there going, yeah. Bam.
I'm on your thigh.
Your persecuted on I show you're totally
correct in your assumption that he
throws like pre park and you said
when you do you sell just like,
don't you sound like Dennis Coy?
You just know
like what I wanted to sound like the,
but that's a good,
uh, a good example of a movie
that's so bad that it becomes funny.
See, I haven't seen it all now after
seeing that Promo, I do one on one.
Have you ever seen either you show
girls? Yeah, that's a good, that's,
that's an example of a good movie.
That's fine. Have you seen the room?
What is the room? You don't know? You guys
know about the rule. Yeah, yeah. Oh yeah.
I have that.
Have that on video.
It's made me buy it. It's the
best. It's hilarious. It's so bad.
I can't get through it though.
It's tough. But I, in the
theaters it's, it's almost like,
I never saw a rocky horror picture show
or anything like that in the theaters.
But this is like,
you go there.
I think the theater's gone
actually where they use to be.
Well,
the one in sunset or it's there.
It's now it's different
theaters or something. Yeah.
For folks who don't know what
we're talking about, the room,
there was a billboard on La
Cienega. No, no, on the brayer.
And the billboard was up for years.
That was the room, the movie,
and it was this guy's face,
Tommy Wiseau,
who's this weird looking dude who
looks like like a monster or something.
It looks like strange and it gets
naked in the film. Well in the movie,
he like gets to fuck all the girls
and he's like the star of the movie.
He wrote the movie for himself,
apparently
paid for it all apparently.
And he uh, um, yeah,
paid for the whole thing.
It was what happened.
Here's the story I was
told was that he put it,
he put it in all these film festivals
and some stone kid at Ucla went to like
the UCLA film festival by himself and
just walked into this film and he comes
back to his dorm room. He
goes, Dude's, I'm not positive,
but I think I just saw the
best film ever made it.
Will you guys come back to tonight?
They're playing it again and like went
back to the 10 friends and they all
thought it was fucking, that's
the ad. Is that ad still up?
But he paid to have it, uh,
you know, to put it, it was,
he paid the money to make it
in competition for the Oscars.
The unit costs a lot of money
to like make your movie.
Did he try to get nominated?
And it is. I remember, uh,
but I used to go to the screenings when
they had like a few years ago and it was
a funny thing.
He would do Q and A's before he would
go to every screening and while people
laughed at his film and he would
go do a Q and a beforehand,
I remember one guy goes,
they would make up questions secret,
see what kind of crazy answers he
would come with. And this guy goes,
is it true that your film
was funded by Nazi gold?
And it's so crazy the guy he was, and
he goes, he gets goes, no comment.
Wow. Like he like, you're supposed
to say no dude. Yeah. Like he did.
Obviously the answer's no,
but he just doesn't,
I don't really understand the question
is that he doesn't understand it or is it,
he's just so fucking stupid.
He's so dumb and then a play cool.
Cause I, uh, I, uh, I went there for my,
with my friends for my birthday and he
signed my poster, don't, happy birthday.
Ben and I was walking, I went to the
bathroom with the poster man. He goes,
you want me to tell? I'll do
graph for your poster. I'm like,
you just did five minutes ago.
He's like, I'll all right.
And he picks it out and you autographs.
I have a poster of him
with the autograph twice.
Wow.
So there's something wrong with them.
There's something really wrong,
but he's got a lot of money and his money.
That's the thing. No one
knows. Hmm. Not, not. Well,
it could be not to go if we don't know.
He didn't.
Whoa. So maybe he's on
your vampire or something.
It had had the vamp,
like people are trying to find pictures
of him in the daylight because people
claim he's available.
Well, he looks like a vampire that's got
a very, your empire. Look at the movie.
The, the poster rather the, the room.
The movie. When I was on the road,
I thought it was a horror movie.
It looks like a horse because he's
brooding is his hair is long.
He looks like Chris Gaines.
He claimed his gains if he was, yeah,
he was the whole time. Garth Brooks,
his new role that I think a fucked up
when I told them it was Garth Brooks,
if I just make movies as this new dude,
I'm telling you man,
we didn't,
they remake and Moody sometimes it didn't.
They remake the trailers of the
room and turn it into like a comedy.
You wouldn't be found out. People
were laughing. They made it.
Apparently he tried to pretend that he
meant to do everything wrong with the
room and eight minutes or less spoilers.
The Oh, awesome. This is great.
Written by Tommy was and the
Holy Ghost look the weird. Okay.
He comes in and there's a really
hot girl this time Tommy said yes.
Hi Doug. Hi Babe. Oh Hi mark.
Hi to everyone.
He's got this weird look too. Guys
got long, obviously dyed black
care and he looks like he's probably in
his like late forties but like really
like a harsh features. But he's
playing like a 23 year olds. Yeah,
but he's playing like this stud and so
he hooks up with all these girls in this
movie.
So he's always like banging.
He's like banging left and
right and this movie, Oh,
I love this song from laying down
the soundtrack. The record skipped.
The flower shop owner doesn't know
what's Johnny even though no one on the
entire earth looks like Johnny,
you're my favorite custom.
So what was up with not recognizing me?
You're my favorite cup.
That wholly at Denny is a creepy
bastard. It's just kidding. Holy Shit.
Denny is a grumpy bastard.
Tawny was El reads lines.
He wrote like he doesn't understand them.
Think I will ever get it.
They betray me,
but they didn't keep their promise.
They tricked me and I don't care anymore.
The best way to be someone who doesn't
drink is a combination of scotch or vodka.
Scott's in fact, that was
his drinking scotch. Scotch.
Scotch gun is not your mother's cooking.
You do not need to lie about
Scotchgard at some. No cane, no cane.
Yeah, it is a weird, I recommend that
movie to everyone. It's the fucking best.
As someone who doesn't
like that kind of stuff,
they had screenings all the time
still I guess. Where are they now?
I began invited all the time and I
think maybe the silent movie theater or
somewhere like that.
That's probably where it is.
It cause it was at that sunset five and
now that's like Robert Redford theater.
Yeah, it seems like it would
be a good thing to go to get,
get a little drunk and go with a
bunch of friends. It is. It's fine.
Until that theater closed, they would
have like four room. No, no point.
You're like four different screens going
on at once and pack the place for the
room and people and the,
and he would be there.
Why people are laughing at
his moody. It's crazy. Wow.
Well I guess for a guy like that he
must be so torn because it's obviously
getting a lot of a tank,
getting his money. Man,
he's getting his money back and he's
becoming famous yet I feel like it's fee.
Don't you feel like it's famous?
It's like died down that
like it's Kinda old news.
Maybe he'll come back again because he
was telling people he's doing a new movie
with De Niro, which is
obviously made up, but I haven't
heard what he's up to
as always. You never know. Man.
Deniro has been doing some fucking,
I think he's doing movies lately.
I don't know.
That's that one that he did with with
Sharon Stone where he's a wizard or
something like that. No, it was,
that was that movie pull up the,
the, the photo. Just the,
he's done some fucking
clearly gets paid movies.
I guess the DVD of the
room that they did that,
the commentary that director's
commentaries gold really.
I can only imagine.
I'm sure talking about his
motivation and each individual scene,
someone posted online to the
auditions for this, for the movie,
which I can't watch. Well, one of
the things about moving to Hollywood,
I moved here in [inaudible] 94 I had
no experience whatsoever with actors.
I didn't know any.
I knew comics who a lot of people will
say that comics are a lot like actors
because they're very needy and
they're very self centered,
but I don't find that to be true.
I think the really good comics especially,
they're really interesting people.
They're fun to hang out with and talk to,
but actors,
I've met some actors that
were so bizarrely self
centered and so bizarrely like
unaware of how a normal person would look
at them and how they behave that this
kind of the room movie
thing makes sense to me.
If you didn't live here and
didn't know these people, right?
Real life we have you say that. I wonder
if you were not in La, if, if he would,
it would be.
It's funny you're laughing at it because
it's because you live in Hollywood and
this is worst representative of that
guy. Know that guy. Totally. Yeah,
and it's probably a piece of me and
that guy, a very small piece, but still,
you know, like I would, I've sure I've
auditioned for shit worse than that.
I'm actually not worse than that.
But you know of a district or some shit
met people that were completely crazy
that were making their own movies and
coming up to you with the,
I know object or trying to do,
I know a lot of people still, Mike,
if you ever seen when he said heat,
it's just going to say the same thing.
Reminds me of windy city.
What the fuck is funnier than windy
city? What's funnier? Well that guy,
the problem with when he said he is,
I know
God that guy is always around.
He was always around the common story.
That guy was annoying as fuck.
And they're like,
they sort of legitimized him in
a way and gave him some juice.
I do it cause I just did, again,
not to brag, but I was, I did,
I did Kimmel last week. And so
like all the writers, you know, he,
he produced that film and uh, so all the
writers and producers and stuff or like,
you know,
there'll be nice to me and I'm just like,
it sells Saul Steinberg would screen,
but you know, I'm like, you know, uncles,
cousin sal, like I know him from
windy city heat, right? Like mole.
I know him from the movie and stuff as
opposed to like their jobs on Kimmel.
I've watched 20 city heat.
So many folks have done a new one.
I keep praying about it. Uh, they
filmed the, about five years ago,
they filmed the beginning part and like
I like, I like that just to try it out,
you know,
like the idea of Johnny Knoxville was
supposed to Jackson by her as scary.
Perry and I actually got to
sit and the filming and I
sat next to Jimmy Kimmel watching this
and it was beautiful. And then scary.
Perry comes in and goes, I'm scary Perry,
you know, and stuff, and I don't know,
whatever happened happened to it because
they also made a Ding Dong show movie
that immediately got shelved.
For some reason,
only a few people saw it and
I heard it was [inaudible].
Oh, there's a windy city heat pog big
three podcasts. It's really funny,
but I don't listen to movie.
The problem that Ding Dong movie would
be that I guarantee the people in the
Ding dog movie probably protested them,
put it in the movie, mocked like that.
Yeah. If you never heard of the Ding Dong
show, Don Barris, who's a buddy of ours,
does it show at the comedy store on a
regular basis where he brings the worst
acts known to man, like this Guy
Peter Chin and these like terrible,
terrible comedians. And they saw a
big three from what he said, he him,
and he's always been doing this.
Don's been doing this almost like there's
this constant running art projects
since the beginning of time,
since as long as I've known him,
he's had these shows there
where he would do these,
these ding dongs shows where he just has
these unbelievably bad comedians and he
treats them like they're artists and
you know that go up. I know, I see.
I still haven't seen it a lot, but we
did the podcast at death squad. Yeah,
he does. Uh, how many, if
he's done, how many so far?
We just finished our 13th I'll listen to
that. Yeah, he's a great guy too. He's a,
and he's in when he said he hate to write.
Yup. He's, he's one of the big three.
He's a star. Dawn Buress is
awesome. He's a great guy too.
He's like one of those guys
that like, he's like, to me,
he's like a hidden treasure in the
world of entertainment. I was like,
how do I fuck the more people
not know about Don Baer?
Yeah. I mean, I mean watching
him every night, it's,
it's amazing that he does what he
does every single fucking night. Yeah,
he does that and I mean he's
there every night, three units,
Kimmel and then he goes straight there
and he's there every morning till three
in the morning. Just like entertaining.
Like sometimes two people in the audience.
Once I was the youngest people
in the parking lot. Yeah,
he'll do a set in the parking lot. He's
hilarious and he's a great guy. He just,
for whatever reason, the world
hasn't found his place yet. But no,
I like when he said he,
he is different than the room.
I'll show that to friends like back in
Kentucky and there'll be cracking up and
they give it to their friend. Have you
seen showgirls? Showgirls, right house,
but where do you said he to legitimately
good move. Yeah. Yeah. Well when the city,
he was good on purpose. Yes,
exactly. Whereas showgirls
and Roadhouse, we're like,
showgirls is probably the best
example of what we were talking.
Roadhouse is the best example
of a cocaine movie. Well,
you know that they were on coke
when they were making that movie.
Like there's no other way you could think
this was good. You got to be cooked. I,
I'll go, oh yeah, fuck yeah.
Tell him paint don't hurt pain.
Don't hurt most of the eighties movies,
showgirls to showgirls, breach of coke.
Certainly in the writing.
Yeah.
Well in the performance to
the whole thing is just chaos.
It's just like you thought this was what?
And he took the girl from saved by the
bell and what and how come? No Way.
We've talked her into doing some squats
before this movie. Exactly. Bullet,
but what? Well, how much did it, how
much of a, it was a horrible bomb, right?
Oh yeah.
Well I think it made money though.
It had to have so many people over time
that those special additions now where
you can buy it with like the comes with
like the stripper stuff and all this
scene
where the fuck was she fucks that
guy from, what was that? That uh,
what was that show? Blue Velvet.
Was that Mclaughlin? Yeah, that guy.
Remember she fucks him in the pool. Holy.
It's the most ridiculous thing ever.
She starts flopping around and slapping
the water like a fish while he's banging
her and he's just like,
yeah,
it's a long way down from blue velvet
and you're like, what are you doing?
No one fucks like that. Stop
this. This doesn't make any sense,
but in the movie it totally
made sense. The water, she's
wild. She's unpredictable.
God getting my trailer suck my cock.
We'll get it.
Heart,
get it hard.
We got to film this fucking movement and
finish this movie so you could suck my
cock more. All right. Actually I'm
fucking chaotic. Crazy movie.
Have you seen grizzly man?
Yes. I would say it's better
than showgirls. Yes, it might.
Maybe the greatest movie ever made. It
is a great movie as far as documentaries.
When I recommend to people if they say,
if you recommend a documentary,
I say grizzly man.
It's weird because mine would be the one
I said before is the staircase and that
you got to see that when bums me out,
man. No, you'll love it. You'll love it.
I'm trying to think. But yeah, I spent
most of my, if I'm going to watch a movie,
I'll watch a documentary
way before any kind of,
that's all I watched his documentaries.
Yeah,
I've been watching quite a
few of them lately. There's a,
this is a good time for documentaries.
I love that.
I have the apple iTunes or whatever the
fuck it is. What's the TV? Apple TV.
Apple TV.
And um,
you go to the documentary section and
it's just documentary documentary.
I saw this really good. Uh, Dave
Grohl made this sound city movie.
I didn't watch it yet. It was really cool.
He got the thumbs up over here. It was,
it was great man. It was like the, the,
the story of this, uh, recording studio.
I think it was in the valley, right?
It's North Ridge, I believe. Yeah.
It's like all this, like nevermind
was all these classic albums.
Fleetwood rumors is made.
They're like the story of all these great
fucking albums and Dave Grohl made the
movie.
It's fucking great.
But [inaudible] doesn't get nearly enough
credit in the world of great albums
and people don't talk about like Fleetwood
Mac there. What's better than rumors?
It's fucking phenomenal.
You and Elsa is great too.
I just talking about this with a
friend Tusk is pretty amazing too.
It's pretty fucking good. Yeah. Both due
to Fleetwood Mac was bad at their height.
There wasn't much better. Yeah, I was
listening to the other day, you know,
jam band is all about timber lake over
there. That song you make love and fun.
God Damn, that's a good song. Well,
the rumors is spotless. Yeah. Yeah.
And I say Tusk is too, but some people
would argue, but I love that. Um,
just because I heard them,
Gene Simmons made a quote or made
a tweet about a video that, uh,
I've been meaning to watch for a while
called searching for sugar man. Oh,
I tell it how it gets
rich. Really good. Um,
I have a very cynical view
of documentaries sometimes.
So I'm not sure how much,
but I actually,
I googled it and I didn't find much.
What I do is I watch documentaries
and I Google it and see how much,
like if there's a lot of
talking about how it's bullshit,
right. And the bullshit meter on that
one was pretty low. So it could be,
well then tell the top people with the
story, the pendant, the guy who was it,
he was a musician in Michigan.
It was like may two albums
that no one had heard of.
And he went and he think he worked at
maybe some kind of factory or something.
No, he was unknown for 30 years. It
turns out his albums had taken off in,
um, uh, South Africa,
South Africa, and he was,
it was part of the apartheid
movement, really was his,
just the soundtrack to his,
of his albums. And he didn't know, he was
so famous over there and Elvis fan base.
And people thought the story had come out
that he died. And like 20 years later,
someone heard the news that he wasn't.
Dot didn't die.
He was living in an apartment in Michigan,
Detroit, and they brought him back. Uh,
you know,
it comes back,
it's almost like an anvil type thing
where he comes back and he's like,
goes over there and just plays the
stadiums now. He played Letterman.
I think he's now going on
tour and playing any gigs.
He was huge. And meanwhile
just had a family, normal guy,
raised his daughters
but had no idea that he,
he was told that these albums were bombs
that they didn't make a penny. Well,
meanwhile there it's good
music. It's pretty good. Yeah.
I buddy might just saw the
show here instead. It was good.
We were talking about our
friends, honey, honey. Um,
I found out about honey honey through
a guy on my message board who, uh,
just sent me a dude named balls of steel.
That's his name. Sent me this link.
And so this is going to be your new
favorite band and I'm one kind of music.
It's like country rock, like
sort of rock country ish. It's,
it's very hard to describe. But when we,
when I listened to it I like, I went,
how the fuck are they not famous?
Like every now and then you'll
hear music and the whole,
they have two cds and bolt of them are
excellent and I'm going to go listen to
this. The, the, the new, the first one
is called First Rodeo and then the, um,
the second one, I forget what the name
of the second one is, but whatever it is,
it's, it's a, it's fucking amazing. It's
like you, you listened to it and you go,
how the fuck is it on iTunes? Famous?
Yeah. Yeah. It's on iTunes. Check it out.
But I think it's hard as fuck to
make it in the world of music today,
especially because of the fact that
there's not that much out there as far as
like radio. There's no dude,
it's admits and pie. If you,
if you want to play instruments,
if I forget,
it's not that much as far
as like being able to sell,
being able to sell videos and shit,
or being able to sell records
like a good fucking luck man.
Although it has spread out.
Yeah.
Till you can make a, it's easier to make
a living like a low, you know, low money.
There's more, there's more bands
making like 50 grand a year,
then they're everywhere. But there's
nobody making that like big money.
That's the thing.
Well
band, um, they, you know,
they've been touring around the country
and they're slowly starting to take
steam, but it doesn't make any sense when
you see some of the shit that's famous.
And if some of the people are famous,
like these guys are like completely,
totally legit. Like how
were they? Not huge.
Well I don't even listen to
the radio anymore. I mean,
do you listen to like
music on the Radio K rock?
I listened to in La on occasion, but
for the most part, no, but it's just,
it takes more than being talented today.
Today we're in this weird like void area
where what you're starting to get his
people that become famous through the
Internet, through people retweeting and,
and, and sending their, you know,
youtube likes and stuff like that.
Like you're starting to see that,
but like put out,
putting on a CD and just releasing
it in a record store, it's not,
doesn't happen me.
So those days are gone. It doesn't exist.
You have to have an internet presence,
which, which is cool. If you were a band,
let's say from a small town in Kentucky
and you wanted to get your music out
there, it's a different world. You can
get it to get it everywhere. But yeah,
it's harder to make that giant leap.
Yeah. Well, um, but you made it dude,
look at you. Yeah, exactly. Can
comedy central the fucking biggest.
I'm the hottest comedian. Chavez live
in large. Did they let you into the, uh,
Daniel Tosh Hooker factory? Where are
you going to see all the process? No,
I've never met him. Give you
the golden robe. I listen.
I got to get some higher numbers
before I get to that. Yeah.
Tosh apparently can sell
out stadiums with one tweet.
Seriously puts out one tweet and he sells
out like 20 stadiums in a row. Yeah,
he's, he's balling the lead
into my show is a rerun.
If his show that beats my shot. I mean
like an old raven fucking good show, man.
Anybody who has anything to say
bad about that shows a hater.
That's a good solid fucking,
sorry man.
I can't say anything bad about a show
that, that my show that paid for my show.
You know, what am I going to say? Hey,
I recommend tosh point hole by the way,
which is called the movies
at the hotel in San Diego.
It's a gay tosh recommend that.
Stop. Was that really in a hotel?
That's not cool. How rude you
fuck. Um, this Friday night,
Brian is going to be at the Ice House
in Pasadena with Tony Hinchcliffe.
Who else?
Kevin Christie Shula and there's a bunch
of people that are going to be added to
the show in the next day or two.
But tickets or at ice house,
comedy.com it's t at,
uh, 10 o'clock. Yeah.
That place is the ice house.
If you'd never been there to us.
Like right now that's like our, our base.
That's pretty much our home base, right?
I mean that's, that's kind of a
mecca for comedians these days.
It's a really unusual spot. It's a
beautiful club. It's in Pasadena.
It's the oldest club in the
country, I believe. Yeah.
I think it was in the 1950s
that they first opened.
And became a comedy club in the 60s,
51st anniversary.
Jesus Christ 51st fucking anniversary
mean. That's, that's insanity man.
Yeah.
That is a long time.
And that Steve Martin used to do it in
his book that you can get on audible.
He talks about the ice house throughout
that whole thing. I read that book,
but after your recommendation, I want,
I want to listen to that book. Yeah.
Well we're there all
the time. I'll be, yeah,
they're a probably again, uh, next
week when I get back from, um, uh,
Nashville this weekend I'll schedule
something and we try to do it.
Like last time was Ari and Ian and Brian
and we just tried to do like all of our
friends. And so it's a, it's a beautiful,
awesome club to, to just to be in.
It's a part of comedy. He
history. It really is. And
uh, and we support that place.
Like it's
like it's a god, that was a
great show, man. Last Wednesday.
That was a great show.
It was pretty fun, man. Yeah. Oh
yeah. That was the drunk name. Yeah.
That was the whole fucked up on stage. It
was funny. We were all fucked up. Yeah.
Yeah. I don't know. Yeah, Shane,
I haven't talked to Shane since.
I called them to apologize the next day.
I'm like, I might have yelled at you, man.
I don't know what I did. He answered the
phone. Did he text her call back? Oh,
we did. Is that right? It's just,
but I think I yelled at some other dude
named Matt. It's a lot of craziness.
Do you drank then? I used to drink a
lot. I'm still like not on purpose.
I just haven't. I'm just getting too
old for it or something. I Dunno.
I'm 37 hope dare you. Yeah. I
just started drinking Jackson.
I just, I don't know. I can't
hold my alcohol anymore.
It's just the weight of the last like
five times I drank has been really odd,
but then you need to party with
some loose reminded people.
You need to hang with us a little bit.
Let's do it. Ice House. Let's do it.
Let's do it. Ice House. They're going
to happen on there. Ben Hoffman.
Thank you for coming on board, man. Thank
you so much. Thanks for having me, man.
Folks, Thursday nights, comedy central,
wash the shit out of the Ben Hoffman
show cause it's fucking awesome.
It's called the Ben show and you
can catch it every Thursday night
at 10:00 PM on comedy central.
Con,
the new comedy central comedy
central is taken off bitches.
They got it together now.
And if you're watching on Ustream, watch,
cut. Should I save that? Watch on you.
Stream live. Watch tonight. 10 30 Eastern,
seven 30 here after
workaholic season finale.
What's the Ustream channels at the time?
No,
I'm saying if people are watching us now
they can watch it. Another episode is,
it is a new one tonight and you're
going to live tweet tonight.
Come to the live tweet tonight. That is
the Ben show on Twitter. The Ben show.
One word. Ben Hoffman. You're a
prince among men. Thank you sir.
Thank you very much for
having me at a blast.
Thank you to the house of Thrones
for sending me this amazing gift.
That thing costs Rogan. I'm, I'm honored.
I can't wait for March
31st for the new season.
Holy Shit plays
this theme when you open it. God, we're
living in the future in the future.
Your Fox, thanks to audible.com
for sponsoring our podcast.
Go to audible.com forward slash Joe four
a free audio book and for 33 days of
audible,
audible.com service a hundred more than
a hundred thousand titles to choose from.
Amazing audio books,
election. Very cool company.
Please support them as they support us.
Um,
thanks to [inaudible] dot com that's
o n and it makers of primal bells.
That's right.
You dirty bitches.
We got kettle bells with a fucking angry
chimpanzee face on and that's just the
beginning. We'll have some more crazy
stuff coming soon. Kettle bells,
DVDs and lots of groovy
supplements for health, fitness,
welfare and cognition.
If you use the code named Rogan,
you will save 10% off any and
all supplements. All right folks,
we love the Shit Outta Ya.
And we will see you next Monday with the
great bill burr. We will also, uh, have,
um,
Dr Chris Ryan will be joining us again
on the podcast and a Stanley kripner
would be joining us on
in a special Saturday.
The very prestigious
scientists, prestigious, uh,
old, well regarded scientist who's
going to come and talk to us.
We got Douglas Rushkoff coming in.
We've got a lot of really
cool guests coming up.
We appreciate the fuck out of all
the positive energy and tweets.
We're number one right now on iTunes
and the comedy department and, uh,
don't think that we don't appreciate all
the love and all the support and we're,
we're completely, totally committed
to keeping this fucking train rolling.
All right. I'm done. God Damn, man. I
can't talk forever. We love you. You,
you keep it together. You
fucks. We'll see. You know, a
couple of days or something.
Yeah.