It's just like that the Joe Rogan
experience podcast is brought to you,
brought to you by a bunch of
different things. All of them.
Embarrassing when talking in front of a
new guest. One of them is the flashlight.
The flashlight is the number one sex toy
for men and people. That's ridiculous.
That's preposterous. Why would you want
to be involved in something like that?
Yeah. Cool man. Why
not? Well, the issue is,
you know that there's
something pornographic about
it cause it's like, you know,
it's a visual vagina too.
It's not just a masturbation device.
I think some people have issue with
the fact that it actually looks like a
vagina. I think it would be less
offensive. It was just a hole.
But there's something,
there's a pornographic element of it
being a fake vagina that some people are
uneasy with. A Brian ease back, bro.
Everybody is into pulling things
open these days. What's that about?
Stop that. Um, anyway, it's,
it's a great tool for masturbation and
you're going to masturbate, cut it out.
Everybody does. Let's be real.
This is way better than your hands.
Many ways to masturbate. There's actual
masturbation you can get real fun. Aw,
you can get four on all
these various various ways.
Don't you feel like there's some people
that get off on bragging and they can't
wait to talk to you?
They tell you all the awesome shit
they've accomplished and like every time
you're around them,
you just like waiting for it and
then they just get it off on you. Oh,
it's like they just came when your tits.
True.
Yeah.
Well,
I think that we all have a desire to be
understood and to be acknowledged and
appreciated human things.
So I feel like if we can try to be
compassionate to that idea than we should
have, give it, give it to people. Like my
friend always used to tell me, just just,
just give it their all. Doing the best
they can. We're all doing the best we can.
Good way of looking at him.
And that's a healthy way of looking at it.
Just give it to them. Yeah. I wouldn't,
don't, don't resist. Right. Yeah.
They're not doing anything terrible.
It's just silly. Yeah. Well, you know,
Jason Silva dropping knowledge
on you bitches. Anyway,
we're still doing a commercial,
unfortunately. Oh, I didn't realize that.
That's how we do it, dude. We sneaking
up on people. It's Ninja style.
Uh,
go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for the fleshlight
and enter in the code name Rogan,
and you will get 15% off.
The number one sex toy for men were also
brought to you by [inaudible] dot com
that's o n n I t.
Makers of Alpha brain,
the cognitive enhancing
supplement or nootropic.
Are you aware of nootropics who we're
trying that stuff? Um, well, you know,
I'm a big Fan of David Pearson is he
didn't his stick imperative where he's
talking about genetically rewriting the
human genome so that bliss becomes the
norm of mental health.
Know talking about using technology
to augment consciousness, but do it,
do it in a sort of,
how freaky would that be?
If we got to a point we could reengineer
the mind so that you are in a state of
ecstasy all day. Like you're on.
I'll do. Why not? Steve Silberman,
who wrote that article about Steve Jobs
talked about performing a metacognitive
hack of the human operating system.
Whether you use like yoga or meditation,
to use the mind to watch the mind and
ultimately to upgrade the mind whether you
do it,
you know,
our thoughts shape our spaces and our
spaces return the favor like we build
environments and turn go.
We engage
in feedback loops with those environments
and they changed the way we think.
My iPhone changes the way I think my
blackberry changes the way I think the
Internet changes the way I think.
Movies I watched changed the way I think
to you or go out of your way to take
like healthy foods in your body and
all about brown rice supplements.
I take the eyes follow
Kurzweil's like pill. Yeah, I do.
I do as well.
Yeah.
There's a certain dramatic thing about
Kurzweil in that I wanted to talk about
this after we're done with the documentary
or done with the commercial, rather.
His documentary was so
fascinating. Transcendent man.
Yeah, transcendent. So moving,
but also so dramatic because you realize
this guy's not getting any younger and
he's on this weird quest to be there
when it all goes down. You know,
he wants to see it all go down, man,
that guy. So Do, I guess I do too.
I think, you know, but the,
the idea that you can hang on until this
thing just completely fucking changes
right in front of our face.
Yeah. Well, you know, I think,
but it's kind of intuitive because it's
actually coming a lot faster than people
think.
And it has to do with one of the basic
tenants of his ideas is the exponential
growth curves of technology and what it
calls the law of accelerating returns.
I mean,
the fact that you're the cell phone in
your pocket today is a million times
cheaper,
a million times smaller,
and a thousand times more powerful than
a $60 million supercomputer was in the
1966 40 years ago saying that
it's a billion fold increase,
billion fold increase in
price performance. That's
not stopping. It's so crazy.
So in the next 25 years,
blood cell size devices,
trillion times more powerful than that.
Interfacing with your
biological neurons in real time.
And that's not even getting
into the spillover into biology,
which is now becoming an information
technology. Freeman Dyson who's a top,
like one of the top physicists in
the world says in the near future,
new generation of artists will be writing
genomes with the fluency that Blake
and Byron and Shakespeare wrote versus,
so it's this idea that the canvas of
life itself is the new instrument for
aesthetic design. Das On, you're
blowing my mind here, playing jazz,
playing jazz with biology.
Like imagine how we poverished the world
would have been if we hadn't invented
the technology of oil painting and time
for Van Gogh or the technology of the
instrument in time for Beethoven
and Mozart to unfurl through it.
So imagine now that the canvas of life
itself, what might we create with it?
I mean we use the alphabet to engender
alphabetic rapture with Shakespeare.
What are we going to make with life?
That's, that's where we're heading.
And if you go to Joe Rogan,
done that and click on the link for on
and.com and then to then Dakota Ne Rogan,
you will get 10% off all of our
nootropic product. And just, uh,
just as a disclaimer, Jason Silva is
not on this shit. He's on his own thing.
He's on his own mixture. Uh, but
uh, if you want to try alpha brain,
it's an excellent one.
I use it. I endorse it.
I have a financial stake in it because
I believe in it. It's awesome stuff.
It's fucking the best shit ever. If
you're hung over or if you're jet lagged,
I love it. Jet Lag. Jet Lag is, you know,
I hate jet lag. It's fucking brutal, man.
You have a dry sponge of a brain.
That's a terrible feeling. You know,
until you can pop your head back in.
It's really hard for me because I get
jet lag and then I have to perform like
you gotta to go on stage. Jetlagged
your sense, try to shake that shit off.
It's hard. But think about it. I mean,
think about what your
body is being subjected to
him. You're transcending. It's
the inherent limitations of time,
space and distance. When you're
crossing the world in just a few hours,
your body evolved in a universe in which
that was not plausible and now it is.
Can't be good for us. Well, it
can't be good for you. It's just,
it takes a little getting used
to it. It's, it's startling
I think to the system.
I think it freaks your body to fuck.
Exactly.
So for me in the alphabet is
one of the best things for a,
as soon as I land I take it and it
doesn't cure it. It helps. It sounds,
and this is no limitless pill, folks,
was just vitamins for your brain.
New Google nootropics. If you're into it,
go to [inaudible] Dot Com oh and n. N. I.
T.
We have a bunch of different shit.
Shroom tech sport is a great supplement
for working out shroom tech immune.
This is a immunity enhance supplement.
All these things are explained online.
We're going away out of our way.
They try to make it as clear as possible.
With all of these things are and what the
ingredients are, if there's any risks.
He was taking anything for anybody
and as I always say, if you're,
if you're interested in this but
you think it's too expensive,
I urge you to go online and look at our
recipe and copy it. I don't give a fuck.
Go buy the shit and bulk. Aubrey just had,
I have a new scientific and an advisor.
Yeah, I also did, I think you can go to
your website and there's a thread now and
sign up and go on the message board.
There's a thread where there's a,
we have a scientific advisor that's just
hired just to answer questions about
about anet stuff,
so we're trying to do this as clean
as possible and make it more clean.
Everything you order is a 30 day
100% money back to not, not 30 day,
30 pills supply 100% money back guarantee.
If you don't even have to return it,
just tell us he didn't like it
and you get your money back.
And we used to have it so that you
could whatever order you ordered it,
you get your money back. But
dudes, we're selling it on Ebay.
They hacked us and they
hacked our silly system.
So we had to change it to the first
30 pills. I ain't hating. You know,
you gotta do what you've gotta do,
you know? Um, so, uh, anyway, uh,
just go check all that stuff out on a.com.
O n n I t enter in code name Brogan. Get
10% off. All right, Brian, cue the music.
This is going to be certain.
Yeah, bank epic sense
[inaudible] then it becomes
a totally different thing.
[inaudible] I love it.
Dude. I love the environment you've
created here. Brian. Is that a Ufo?
You're fucking tripping me out.
The idea of artists using genomes
or jeans for for their canvas.
Dat is one of the most amazing new ideas
that I've heard that that that just,
that statement really makes you like
change the way you look at things like,
oh yeah,
really well especially when the guy that
said that phrase is Freeman Dyson who's
considered the world's
most eminent physicists.
I mean he's on par with
Einstein and when I mean,
but he obviously is also a poet because
the way he says it in the future,
a new generation of artists
will be writing genomes
with the fluency that Blake
and Byron wrote verses.
In fact,
I just saw him speak at dealed the in
Munich and he said that soon we'll have
the entire biosphere in the palm of
our hands. So imagine what that means.
We might be like evolutions,
secrets reputable, right?
Absolutely. It's inevitable.
If you look at the progress that's
been made, it's not going to stop.
What is great and man is that he is a
bridge and not an end said Nietzsche.
It's so amazing to be here right
now while it's all going down.
This is like the bottom of the funnel,
so know where it happening
so fucking ridiculously fast.
It is.
It's the first time in history that we
don't need time lapse photography to be
able to witness it. You know, it's
like a, you don't see a plant growing,
but with time lapse you can actually see
that the plant is alive and that it's
growing and that if you could see human
progress over just the last hundred
years through time lapse,
you would literally see that.
It's like our thoughts spillover
into the world. I mean,
that's what human imagination is,
right?
Our ability to conjure up
future possibilities, pick
the most delightful one,
pull the present forward to meet it.
I mean the airplane, the jetliner,
the Internet,
it all started in somebody's mind or
in a group of minds and then it kind of
spilled over. Like we literally live
in condensations of our imagination.
Terence Mckenna used to say that,
which sounds psychedelic
except it's literally true,
right?
I've always thought that it's such a
strange thing that the imagination is this
invisible, wistful thing that's inside
your head that doesn't really exist.
It's just your imagination. But from
that comes everything that's solid.
Everything.
Everything that's been created has
been thought up in the imagination and
somehow or another,
and it's,
it's so weird that we sort of have this
like flippant view of the imagination.
I mean we, we, we value creativity
for sure, but just the idea of what,
imagining it's almost like we get to work,
we value
creativity, but we don't give it the
kind of status that it merits. Um,
is it James Glick who
wrote the information?
It's a book that talks about
how the fundamental building
block of reality might
actually be information. He talks about
it from bit, so everything is information.
And he wrote a fantastic article where
he talks about how it turns out that our
neuro are, are our ideas. Ideas
are just as real as the neurons.
Dane habits and ideas.
It's like a new kingdom that rises above
the biosphere and the Denisons of this
kingdom. Our ideas, ideas have
retained the properties of organisms.
They have infectivity, they have spreading
power. They leap from brain to brain.
They compete for the limited
resources of our attention.
And here's the most interesting thing.
Even though ideas are
not made of nucleic acid,
they have achieved more evolutionary
change at a rate that it leaves the old
gene panting far behind.
So ideas you know to say that ideas
change the world or they transform reality
is not a metaphor. Ideas do
transform reality. In fact,
it turns form reality better
than biological evolution
did and Terence Mckenna
actually said that the moment
that we invented language,
biological evolution essentially
stopped and evolution became a cultural
epigenetic phenomenon because now we're
taking matter of little organization.
It goes through our mental filters and it
pops out as iPhones and space shuttles.
I mean this is all the human brain,
the most complex thing in the universe
that's producing the world that we
inhabit and so on and so forth.
Timber Possible. It's impossible to wrap
your head around. That's like the end it.
It's like
trying to figure out where
it's going to go from here.
It's like what the fuck
is going to happen?
What is going to be the next breakthrough
that makes the Internet look like you
know,
like like a lamp?
Well, virtual reality, right?
Terence Mckenna also said where each
increasingly moving into universities of
our own construction, right?
Paula Antonelli, uh, from
the Moma in New York City,
she talks about, she did an exhibit
called design and the elastic mind.
And recently they did an exhibit called
talk to me about how we interface with
our technological tools, which is
very much the whole Marshall Mcluhan.
Like first we build the tools
and then they billed us and uh,
she talks about existence maximum.
She says that, you know, personal,
personal iPods for example,
allow us to create customized playlist.
So essentially we can all
impose soundtracks on our lives.
So we're each living in different
universes because we each are scoring our
lives and instrumenting our
lives in different ways.
And reality therefore is further sort of
a separated into individual subjective
universes. So to say that we each live
in our own reality is absolutely true.
Instead of living in a sort of consensus
trans where each increasingly moving
into our own customized utopias, our
own lucid dreams. And that's amazing.
Is that really possible? Is that
really what's going on? Is it,
all of our realities are imaginary
things that we've created that are
interacting with others.
Well, Robert Anton Wilson talks
about your reality tunnels.
I mean certainly there is an element
of consensus reality where we sort of
respect each other and acknowledge each
other as other entities that we share
space with.
But um,
but certainly like how I perceive
moment to moment reality is a,
is edited by my preconceptions,
by my stereotypes, by the way.
I was brought up by certain belief
systems and so on and so forth.
These things act as filters that skew
how I perceive things and we're all stuck
in our reality tunnels and people talk
about illumination and shedding your
reality tunnels to seeing sort of
broader, more, you know, interesting, uh,
varied realities and um,
yeah,
I definitely think that we're each
in individual Rhea and realities.
Do you think that we're gaining some new,
uh,
cognitive functions and some,
some new abilities to read each other
and to have insight into each other
because of technology?
Yeah,
I mean,
I think that the first information
technology was language in the alphabet.
You know what I mean? People always
like criticize technologies. You know,
when we invented writing,
it's,
it's been said that Socrates use to say
that you should never write anything
down because it was
going to rock our brains.
And this technology of writing
was this terrible thing.
And then it kind of becomes so
embedded in who and what we are at.
JC rocks it too,
Jay z and Socrates,
cause Jay Z,
I've always been amazed that he doesn't
write a name of his raps down. That's,
he's so brilliant. He just keeps them
all in his head and it's, and, and w um,
Everlast is the same way.
It doesn't write anything down.
Yeah. Well, I mean, I mean
whatever works for each person,
but I think that what I'm,
yeah, they, they feel like they
should, as a, as a, as an artist,
the able to spew out all their best stuff,
but even, even language and thinking
in the technology too, I mean,
we're still depending on
various components of the
brain to do certain functions.
So I think this,
what do we call this skin bag bias?
I mean this assumption that it's better
if it's all coming from within us.
I think our actual mines are actually
part of a dance between our brains and our
environments and our tools.
I mean,
I outsource part of our cognition
to the iPhone. There's a whole,
it's clear he called the extended
mind thesis or the you literally,
you create artful change in
the world using the magic wand.
No one has the iPhone.
It stores part of your memory.
It allows you to interface with reality
and actually cause change in reality.
Amber cases, a cyborg
anthropologist, she says,
our smartphones basically give us
technologically mediated telepathy.
SMS is basically sending your thoughts
through time and space at the speed of
light. By pressing a few
buttons, you become telepathic.
All you have to do is embrace the
idea that that's a part of you.
It's the extended phenotype that
Richard Dawkins or talks about, right?
It's you know,
termites build termite colonies.
Termite colonies are part
of this termite species.
You know what we produce is part of our
extended phenotype. It's a part of us.
It's not separate from us.
I think that idea is,
so this is connecting us to us,
this is really just connecting us to us,
this Hanson who you are,
because you are the connection between
you and all the other positive organisms
around you.
And the more you can,
the more you can keep that
going exponentially that
happy or in the better your
life will be. Yes, this really
is an enhancement. Yeah.
Emerged and evolved the same
way biological functions
and features emerge and
evolve. You know, Kevin
Kelly's treaties on this,
what technology wants is a fantastic,
and he talks about how technology has
a direction that has tendencies and
whatnot. And, and Ray Kurzweil of course,
who's the, who's a friend and hero,
I mean he says, he says, our
ability to create virtual models,
virtual reality in our heads combined
simply with our modest looking thumbs,
was sufficient to usher in literally
a secondary force of evolution called
technology.
And it will continue at an accelerating
pace until the entire universe is at our
fingertips. And the
thing is people say, wow,
how poetic coming to fork will accept
what he's saying is these exponential
growth curves of technology and then
impregnating computation into matter with
nanotechnology or impregnating manmade
evolution into synthetic biology or
artificial life.
These convergence of these exponentially
growing technologies are literally,
you know,
it's like a steward brand says we are as
gods and might as well get good at it.
Like having invented the gods,
we can turn into them.
It's not to say like instead
of praying for transcendence,
let's engineer transcendence,
let's engineer ourselves
into blissful, you know,
utopic
existence hopefully,
or nuclear war.
That's the other problem.
The problem is a man is also wicked
good at blowing shit up. You know,
like it seems like at our
highest levels of technology,
the best shit we have is
the most impressive shit
because the shit that can just
wipe things out.
Like has there ever been anything
more impressive than atomic power?
Is there ever been anything
more oppressive than the
idea of you just a reset
button for a whole city?
That's insane.
Yeah. The idea that that became
an option. Yeah. I mean one, one,
one has to acknowledge that you know,
technology extends who and
what we are and you know,
you can use the alphabet to compose
experienced scientists or you can use the
alphabet to compose hate speech.
So something that extends your thought
reach envisioned kind of like a scaffold
and can be used in any direction,
but it's up to the cultural.
So that's what the cultural
conversation is all about.
And that's where the story of who and
what we are and that's where culture plays
a key role.
How are we going to use these tools?
The scientists all have almost an
obligation to chase down every idea.
Well that's what humans do. So for them
it's like they have that justification.
I'm sure they had it when they built the
first atomic bomb that we must build it
before the Germans. Right? I
mean it wasn't that what they,
let's probably what they wanted to make
sure that the Germans could have easily
done it to us first and then we would
have been fucked. And that was the idea.
Sure.
I mean,
that's I guess where a
change in consciousness is
as important as the power of
our tools, you know? Yeah. Easily
more important. Right? That some more.
It's like w we have to grow up first
before we can use all this crazy shit we
have. Yeah. And we're not necessarily
completely grown up, but yeah, no,
it's possible though, right? Well,
we're on our way. There is a great, uh,
Steven pinker did a Ted talk called
the myth of violence and he says that
contrary to the media environment,
that, you know, if it bleeds, it leads.
The reality is that the world is getting
safer all the time and the chances of a
man dying at the hands of another
man are lower than they've ever been.
And he chronicles the decline in
violence over the last hundred years.
And it's like totally counterintuitive
because it's totally not what you think
and, but you know, this guy's like
well researched and it's unbelievable.
Or Hahn's robling who has a website called
gapminder that actually shows you the
progress across the world and all the
people coming out of poverty and all these
things that are happening that
actually point to, you know,
things getting infinitely better
across a variety of indicators.
And yet this is not what you hear on
the news because it doesn't make the
headlines. Because if it bleeds, it
leads. And that's unfortunate. Well,
I think it's just a numbers issue.
I don't think we're supposed to have
access to 300 million lies because if
there's 300 million people and that's
who we're including in our news and this
happened here and that happened there,
you're going to get a lot
of fucked up shit. Yeah,
but per capita really
not that much per capita.
America's pretty Goddamn
Save. Totally. It's, you know,
even the world has never been safer.
I mean,
the world's never been safe for them
to have this many people and to be this
safe,
like the pessimistic all day.
But you've got to point towards
there's some progress going on,
some sort of social progress going on.
Well, I think that the Ted Conference,
that's why it's such a sort of wondrous
force in nature because I think that
they've brought back,
uh,
the academics and made them sexy and the
intelligentsia is out there chronicling
all the progress that has been made in
technology and entertainment and design
and also pointing to what's wrong
but in a sort of smart, mature way.
And that's a phenomenon like that like
makes me happy. Like in an age of,
you know, reality television.
Like we also have, you know,
the Ted Conference and the Ted talks.
Yeah.
I think I was thinking about
this today in my car. I was like,
this is the only time ever
where people really, uh,
as a whole group,
we're exposed to all sorts of alternative
ideas without having to continue your
education without,
without being, you know,
like I think for a lot of our parents
when they got out of school and you know,
and then they started working like,
what do they do?
They picked up the paper now and again.
You know what I'm saying?
Like what you heard, what Walter
Cronkite told Ya on the evening news,
like your access to what
the fuck was really going on
was ridiculously small. No,
anything they do or lost there were
thinking captain America was out there
saving the world. They were
like little children. Totally.
The difference between that and what
your children are going to have,
the access they're going to
have from birth, it's insane.
It's not even the same species.
It's not the same reality informationally.
It's like it's not even the same reality.
Totally spot on.
I don't what you're saying.
I don't think we even realize how crazy
it is because we're caught up in this
cyclone and we just have accepted.
That's why they call it a singularity
and that's why such a great metaphor and
you know it's not the only one. We had
a singularity when we invented language.
I mean life after language is impossible
to imagine. I think to people on the,
on the other side of the
line like pre-language beings
cannot imagine what life
after all, it's only been a hundred
thousand years. You had a brilliant thing.
We were talking online,
one of your videos where you were
talking about Manhattan. Yeah.
And how you were described.
Please say that, uh,
there's a new book by David Deutsch.
He's a quantum physicist and genius
is called the beginning of infinity.
And I read this New York Times Review
of the book before I even found a book,
but it was like, it was, the guy was
saying it was his mesmerizing intellect.
I'm just to give you an example
of where his head is at. He says,
if you consider the typology of
Manhattan as it exists today,
so the physical topography of that entire
land mass is no longer shaped by the
forces of geology.
Literally geology has been trumped
by the forces of mind manifested as
economics, culture, uh,
you know, human behavior.
So we're literally artifacting landscapes
now like mind over matter literalized.
And what he's saying is that that might
ultimately be the fate of the whole
universe.
And that gravitation and anti matter
only govern the universe at its least
interesting stages.
But where we're moving in terms of the
ability of mind to shape reality as in
the physical topography of Manhattan and
the world at large is that eventually
that will be the face
of the whole universe.
So sub straight independent
minds impregnating
intelligence into the COSMO's.
We're talking like death
star two we're talking,
we're talking death cause like shit.
I was going to say like a cosmic symphony
during the crescendo stretching on
forever like wow.
Or the death star or the debt's
never how bad ass the death star was.
Can pull up a whole fucking planet.
You better shut your mouth, bitch.
They built a fake planet
gone down. Shh. Come on man.
That's an amazing accomplishment as well.
If someone started building the death
star, they would have to keep going.
They would have to see if they
could do it. Yeah, they can.
You just can't fund that project. Folks
don't don't from the desk to our project,
noon is going to be that star. It's going
to be Dick Cheney's head out in space.
It's going to be a robotic.
Dick Cheney had actually space
is a very exciting frontier.
Now with the privatization of space,
we're going to see you like
radical innovation. I mean,
you have this new generation of techno
philanthropists. It has to be privatized,
right? You have to let people try to come
up with some crazy shit. Not only that,
but the people that are behind it are
people who have made billions in the
information age, who have the resources
of nation states and now individuals,
visionaries,
private individuals have the power
that only government used to have.
This is actually talked about.
You should have a peanuts would scares
people that anybody could just build some
rockets and just launch them on people.
You know?
It's like that's where it
starts from. I mean, the,
the money behind all these space ideas.
Yeah,
let's go up and stay all that shit.
It's military.
They want to make sure that they have
the ability to communicate, watch shit,
dropped bombs. Fuck you up, get
you quicker. I mean that's, that's,
that's what funds a lot of innovation
when it comes to, I mean, yeah,
at first a lot of innovation
has come from military research,
but it very quickly
translate down to consumers.
I mean the fact that because of the
money involved, right? Isn't it,
I mean the military contracts or junking
it's because of the resources required.
But I mean,
when you consider the fact that gps on
your smartphone today is largely free,
credible,
or that a person with a cell phone in
Africa today has better communications
technology than the US president
did 25 years ago. And you know,
a billion people buying
smartphones for the first time,
what they call the rising billion.
They're coming online,
joining the global
conversations, a billion new
minds coming on, coming online,
you know, joining the global brand. I
mean, it really is encouraging I think.
And uh, you know, you should have,
you should talk to Peter Diamandis.
He started the x Prize
Foundation and cofounder,
Singularity University with Kurzweil.
He's got a new book all about how we
can leverage emerging technologies to
transform the world for the better. Like
infinitely. So it's called the abundance.
So how come we make 80 and t
to keep a fucking phone going?
How can we can't get that? How come
we can't get a call to not drop? Yeah.
Is that possible? That's ridiculous.
Why is that still going on?
You know what phone calls
still drop from time to time.
Wonky system.
The incredible shift that we have now.
Why at and t why we just can't keep up
with the at and t Verizon doesn't fuck
me. Like they all fuck up. They all use
the same towers, don't you? Silly boy.
They have two totally different signals.
Well,
I'm not Verizon and at t and d but like
if you look at what's going on with
sprint right now and, and uh,
Verizon I think it is, uh,
they all should piggyback off each
other's towers and then I would go with
sprint to cause Verizon's awesome. And
at t and t can suck it. Yeah. About that.
I'm not a fan of both horizon in aids.
He's definitely better if you want to be
able to get online while you were on a
call. Yeah. Because he can't do it.
[inaudible] that is three gene technology.
You realize how great the iPhone is. If
you go to Canada, then you go to Canada.
There cells on system is way better than
ours. They don't drop calls up there.
It's fucking awesome. Like Rogers visit,
nobody wants juice. Yeah, I think so.
It's great. I think that the iPhone
is the modern magic wand. I mean,
when you consider the amount of
magic, well, Arthur C. Clarke,
sufficiently advanced technology is
indistinguishable from magic. I mean,
there comes a point when something,
when an instrument of man is transcendent,
that it literally change how
he relates to the to reality.
I think the iPhone is on that scale
of, of innovation. I mean it really,
or to show the iPhone to
somebody 200 years ago,
they would've thought that you are a god.
Right?
I mean that is a magical machine who,
where are you when you're on a telephone
call to the other side of the planet?
I mean,
they're hearing your voice or they're
hearing a representation of your voice,
except it's in real time and it responds
to feedback instantly. Are you here?
Are you there?
He just embodied Eddie Griffin
had the best bit ever. Yeah.
I'm the guy who invented telephones.
He goes,
how high you got to be to
be sitting around going,
I want to talk to someone
who isn't even here. Totally,
but see you just hit the nail in the head.
Just how psychedelic it's modern
information technology is,
you know John Markoff wrote a book
called what the dormouse said.
It's a true history of silicon valley
innovation in the 60s and it's all about
how a Douglas Engelbart and the Xerox
Parc and all these people that we're
trying to augment human
intelligence by any means necessary.
The birth of the computing revolution
and a and how they collided with the
counterculture and the
psychedelic movement of the
60s half of these engineers
were all like tripping out and computers
were all of a sudden reconfigured.
It wasn't these big like
government centralized machines,
but no computers could be
extensions of the human mind.
And Timothy leary came out in the 80s
and says, guess what? The computers,
the LSD of the nineties.
I mean,
that's literally what it was because
computers aren't what mind manifests.
Things like expanding your sphere
of possibility, expanding your mind.
I mean these are psychedelic
slogans being applied to technology.
And I think that that's spot
on. I think you're right. Um,
I think the interaction that
you have with social networks,
with Facebook and Twitter and message
boards and stuff like that, you're the,
it's, it accelerates your,
your sphere of ideas.
So incredibly, I think about,
not just because of people like,
uh,
people sending you fascinating things,
but other people's points of view
and comments on them. Well, you know,
you'll sometimes, this is one
of the more interesting things.
I'll watch a great video that I want
to read the comments because you know,
every now and then, you know, you go, wow,
that guy just put it in at
a unique perspective that
I hadn't considered before.
Totally. I mean, it allows, you know,
spaces for innovation where ideas can
have sex and it's like similar to genetic
recombination in nature. So ideas
having spaces and liquid networks.
As Steven Johnson talks about, uh, spaces
where they can complete each other,
where they can intermingle, where
they can and recombined. I mean,
we're having the primordial soup of human
culture creating a new replicator and
these replicators achieving more change
than biological evolution ever did. And
so that's where things get kind of crazy,
what they call the new Oh,
sphere is this new thing that rises
above the biosphere or psyche where mind
lives and, and guess what it mind is now
transcending time, space and distance.
We become posts,
geographical beings were shared,
passions can conjure self organization
and teamwork and collaboration and
cooperation and these open spaces
without like entropy getting in the way
without having to like get over there,
the Labor that it takes to get
over there to meet that person.
No.
What was the idea that Mckenna had?
That there's like some transcendent object
at the end of time that's pulling us
towards it. And as we get closer
to it, we become more like it.
Is that what it is? I think that
that was his, his, his, his metaphor.
Crazy way of looking at it.
Yeah. I mean, uh, the, the metaphor,
everybody uses a different word, you know,
Kurzweil coins at the singularity,
which is a metaphor borrowed from physics
to describe what happens when you go
through a black hole, which is to say
all the laws of physics collapsed.
So you borrow that to describe this kind
of event horizon that's just within our
reach where it almost becomes
impossible to define or describe.
Because at that point we're going to
be so deeply intertwined with these new
tools that are going to change
the way we think and perceive and,
and are basically, and mechanic might have
a different name for it, you know, uh,
this guy used to call it the Omega point,
you know,
Pierre de Chardin is Jesuit priests talked
about a move towards the Omega point.
I mean, all the metaphors are
there. And uh, I mean I definitely,
I mean w w w already there,
we thought we fly through the air and
talk on the phone and surf the web and
machines with wings on them over oceans.
Yeah, no shit. Where are we? Where are we?
That the plane thing is amazing,
that it's still the same thing.
It's still getting the tube fly in
the air. Like we haven't figured that,
that hasn't really gotten any better.
Well that someone that does economics,
it's just the price of what it
is. I mean, we've still, I mean,
they've become much safer.
I think the,
the chances of having an accidents
like 125 million, so it's, yeah,
it's way safer. It's just still the
same thing. It's still just crazy.
It's the scope teleportation.
When's that going to pop up?
Because it seems like this plain things
been going on for a while. Like really?
That's it. That's as good as we can do
it. I feel like there's some other shit,
you know,
that'd be cool when we
could transfer brains, like,
like you have like a empty soul over
on the other side. So you'd be like,
all right,
I'm just going to transfer my brain into
an adult brain probably of human copy.
Yeah. And that was
Kurzweil's idea, right? The,
to be able to copy yourself into a
operating system. Well, I mean, yes.
And that creates that fear.
Just philosophical conundrum because it
says if you scan your brand and you put
it in a computer, then which is you,
that one or this one. When he says that,
that's not how actually
how it's going to happen.
What's going to happen is more and more
of our biology is going to be replaced
by non biological components,
but it'll be millions of baby steps.
So first you'll replace 5% then 10%
and eventually after a bunch of gradual
steps, you're all non biological,
but you never felt any change.
So that's how it's still you.
I know a dude who has an artificial knee
and he was just telling me about his
artificial knee and I was
just thinking about yet
a knee replacement and I was
thinking about it. I was like, wow,
this is how it begins. He's just
walking around. He's got a fake knee.
Dude is walking around. Totally
is bionic. I know we're already,
we're already cyborgs. I mean, think about
it. Our cars, our exoskeletons, so our,
our airplanes,
these are suits that we put on that
transformed the way we interface with,
I mean, we're already looks like
a Mustang. Yeah. Really? Yeah.
It really is it just you,
that's why people want them to look cool.
This is my cool suit total around
it. And some people, you know,
some people get a little freaked out and
they're like, oh, but this is unnatural.
But it's actually not because the same
a biosphere that sprouted human beings
and sprouted flowers sprouted the
microchip. I mean Buckminster Fuller said,
start with the universe. If you
look at Earth as a planetary system,
everything that comes out of it is
natural. That means that the micro chip,
the iPhone is as natural as a tree.
What's amazing because it's
following the same kind of momentum.
I think that began with the big bang and
his self organizing properties that are
just sprouting. All these innovation,
evolution evolving don't involve ability,
I think is the term that Kevin Kelly use
that it's insane. It's insane. Right.
And it is a good antidote to
existential malaise, right? I mean,
th th the continuum of the
continuing fact of death,
the death sentence that hovers
over human beings makes life very,
we're very silly in
that fact that we will,
people want to concentrate on that
end and know it's coming. It's coming,
it's coming and like way
before it ever gets there.
You fucking Shit your pants on it. You
know? It's like, yeah, it's going to come,
but you've got to enjoy this.
You got to learn how to enjoy this.
The best way to be happy.
The only way,
the only way to truly be happy is to
do what you want to do and enjoy this.
Oh yeah. You, you,
you can make plans for the future and
you can discipline yourself and you could
set goals. That's all well and good,
but you better be enjoying this. Oh,
you have to, otherwise you're being
silly person. Yeah. Yeah. Well you got,
you got to find what gets you off and,
and try to make sure that whatever gets
you off is also functionally productive.
Yeah. So yeah, it doesn't
put anything negative out
there. Right. And I, you know,
Carl Sagan coined the term wonder junkie.
And I think that's like an awesome
one to describe. Like, you know,
the love of knowledge,
a lust to for ideas and ideas,
recognizing the erotic power of ideas
and to think that ideas are not these
abstract things, but they're actually a
thing that can change the world. Right?
You guys have, we've talked about,
and it seems like every day, well,
my ideas are just, it's weeds, ideas. It's
not even mine. I'm just borrowing them.
Pulling them out of the
sky comes through you,
but not from you and belongs not to you.
I'm an antenna for the mighty Shiva.
Well, Timothy Leary said
the brain is a transceiver.
But you know what's brilliant about
what you just said is because you are
creating a podcast now where you are
putting out a variety of interesting ideas
that reach all sorts of different
people and inspires all of these people.
So you become a node because
you reach millions of minds.
You infect those minds with new ideas.
Your ideas have virality, spreading power.
Infectivity.
So think about yourself as participating
in the evolutionary process,
spreading your scene as it were like that.
I should have not been so mean to at.
And. T. I'm sorry. I don't know
how hard it is to run a network.
You guys were the first to have the
iPhone. I appreciate you for that.
I've been a loyal customer for years.
It's not that bad.
I was just just making
comedy. Oh, I'm sorry.
I do have a little ATNT guilt
when you think about it that way.
Put out some negative energy.
I do like the fact that there was a
reason I have the at and t phone so I can
use the email and the internet
at the same you said more than you
would think too. I do. I use that a lot.
That is a feature I didn't think I
would use, but I do. I'm sorry at t and.
T I was just fucking with you. He was
very interesting that you, that you,
that you mentioned, um, that
you mentioned marijuana, um,
and something that helps you get
ideas or are you a cop? Ha, no,
we're talking about
stuff that's been published.
Yo. I think, yeah,
well I think anybody smokes marijuana.
Ert eats marijuana, especially eats it.
Anyone's going to tell you there's
an enhancement there. You know,
there's the idea of whether or not
it's a performance enhancing drug.
I say it is. I say it is,
you know, I don't think you
should be able to fight high.
I think if a guy got into UFC high,
he might have an advantage for real.
I'm not kidding.
A cognitive advantage.
The real problem with it is that you
could've gotten high a week ago and you,
there's no way you are
completely stone cold sober,
but when you take a drug test,
that drug tests will show that you test
positive for marijuana so you're not
under its positive effects whatsoever.
It's just the fact that it stays in your,
in your fat cells,
but that it's contained.
It's continued illegality is,
is a testament to sort of an intellectual
stagnation in our society. I mean,
even back in the day, Abraham
Lincoln, Abraham Lincoln used to say,
provision goes beyond the bounds of
reason because it makes it a crime.
And things that are not crying
by legislating a man's appetite.
You can't tell somebody what they can
do in the privacy of their own home if
they're not hurting anybody else,
particularly when so many artists are
talking about how it has helped them in so
many ways. Norman mailer used to say it
was divine for associations. Carl Sagan.
Okay.
My fricking hero used to rave about
marijuana freaking when Carl Sig and he,
he's so legit.
You gotta say file.
We can fucking hear Carl Sagan
used to enjoy cannabis. You know,
and there was actual article recently
in a, in a psychiatry journal that,
uh, they looked at marijuana and
creativity by studying semantic priming.
And semantic priming means
if you activate a word,
it's immediate associations that get
triggered in your head. So if I say bird,
you think of when you think of flight,
those are normal associations.
And it turns out that people that claimed
that marijuana made them more creative.
It turns out that it induced
semantic and I'm sorry,
and induced a hyper
priming effect in them.
So what that means is they cast a wider
associate of net. So when you said bird,
they didn't just think
of wings and flight,
they thought of transcending one's
limitations going beyond one's limit,
soaring above it all.
They just cast wider ways of connecting
the ideas to other ideas and isn't that
what creativity is all about?
So for the first time we were able to
physiologically quantify the claims made
by so many artists and first for society
to civil restrict that I think is just,
it goes beyond the bounds of
reason. It's not reasonable. I know
so many people that benefit from
it and yet it's still illegal.
It's completely logical.
It's clear evidence that
someone is suppressing behavior.
Someone is trying to move forward this,
this,
this same exact culture that
they're enjoying right now.
They don't, it's a cycle.
It's,
it's,
it's a psychoactive capability thing
as much as it is a thing about it as a
commodity, you know, that's one of the
things that people don't understand.
Marijuana is illegal because of its
status as a commodity as much as it is
because of its psychoactive effects.
Or there's a lot of pharmaceutical
companies that do not want it to be legal
because it's a,
it would be a natural commodity
that would cure a lot of ailments,
that there are prescription drugs that
are available for that people have
patents on and they stand to lose
millions and millions of dollars.
And that's where all their lobbying power,
their financial influence,
that's all that stuff comes into play.
And that's why it's illegal.
It's completely preposterous. And that's
very embarrassing. It is embarrassing.
It's very unfortunate. But I also think,
well all of our advocacy advocacy,
you know, people have never had more
power to create grassroots movement.
I mean the same fuel that is
fueling, you know, the Arab spring.
I think people can band
together and demand change.
I mean the same way we
took down Sopa right?
I mean people can get together and create
this advocacy and have ultimately the
same lobbying power as these corporations.
I mean,
that's something that the
Internet is allowing for.
So I think it's certainly moving in
that direction, right? I hope so.
It feels like it.
It feels like people are actually paying
attention to what people like the soap
a thing.
People are actually paying attention to,
the reaction that people are having on
the Internet and they're going, okay,
let's, let's step back here
and let's reassess things.
And I think ultimately it has to be the
way that people decide on things. Yeah.
We can't go through all these. Well, the
hive mind is deciding. Yeah, well, yeah,
it is the hive mind. I mean people go,
people are going to hurt. How many really?
How much is really,
you don't think they're going to be
able to fix the hacks and come on, man,
there's always going
to be a game like that,
but it's still red or
it'll be self correcting.
But that doesn't mean that you'd leave
it in the hands of these crazy fucking
Diebold people or any of these, you know,
you, you've seen those documentaries on,
on, on how they were able
to fix voting machines.
We able to change the results of all,
there's been a lot of controversy.
I grew up in Venezuela
where, uh, you know,
we have a president that keeps
supposedly getting reelected as he,
as he imprisons his political
opponents and appropriates,
takes over private property.
And rumor has,
it has been rigging the voting
machines. So it's a problem. I uh, I uh,
I know that story, that rumor all too
well, you know, I don't know who used it.
I don't know if it was used,
but they do absolutely know for a fact
that it's possible to change the votes.
It's possible to change the
number and the, the scary,
those machines allowed a
third party input so crazy.
So it's just amazing.
So they said they probably sold these
to these crazy dudes that are running
these fucking donkey
countries. But then, you know,
this strange countries in Afghanistan,
you know, I mean look like,
like those like warlord type dudes or
live in those places. You know what,
someone told me the best way they get
information from those guys as they give
them.
Like in Afghanistan they
give the dude's Viagra. Wow.
And then they give up information
on the Taliban like that
were so silly. Why at the end, at
the end of all of our technology,
just a by Agra to quick fix viagara for
it's crazy reward warlord type dudes
living in the mountains. Wow.
It's crazy. It's ridiculous.
Where do you think we're going
to be in a hundred years, man?
How are we going to be
living in some sort of a f
saturated with intelligence? Oh, virtual
reality I think is definitely coming.
I think once we hack the nervous system,
we won't have to interface with cyberspace
through the square little devices.
You know,
it'll be like Neuromancer you know
William Gibson says that cyberspace tapped
into our sort of instinct that this,
that disinformation world information
is spatial and we want to cruise these
digital realms and we want to be in, it's
like the matrix except not a dystopia.
Why does the matrix have to
be a cautionary tale? Right.
I like the idea of going into my own
private universe or like the lucid dream
and vanilla sky where the universe is
sculpted and based on my preferences and
moods and I render things into existence
at a faster and faster rate. I mean,
we already are living in a
world that's shaped by the mind.
It's just that the buffer time is
shrinking. As the tools get more powerful.
Eventually the speed of thought will
render things into existence at that sort
of lightspeed, that's where we're headed.
Jesus Christ. How far away is that?
How far away is the speed of thought
making material things? Well,
out of the ether, you're once
we can once Nano Delek trip. Oh,
it is like a psychedelic
psychedelic offers,
a glimpse of the world
that's created by mind.
We were already living in a
world made of language. I mean,
everything we inhabit is,
is an object,
objectification of the imagination that
Terence Mckenna is like Terence Mckenna.
You know, people say, oh, he was
just about advocating psychedelics.
He was about much more than that.
Terence Mckenna was a futurist, a poet,
and a technologist in many way. Who
understood that transformative power of,
you know, even if he wasn't, it was
cool to just listen to him talk. He's,
he did was such a head of such
a crazy way of phrasing. Right.
Thanks. And putting things together
is a really interesting dude. Insane.
You know, the first time I ever did DMT,
I actually heard him talk in my DMT trip.
It was the strangest fucking thing ever.
Wow.
It was so strange because I don't
know if you've ever done anything, uh,
you ever done anything like that?
DMT?
No. I can't say that I have,
although I've read a lot about it.
I'm very curious. Just haven't
found the set and setting in time.
Mckenna always just talk
about heavy psychedelic trips.
One of the things he said is,
did not give into astonishment.
That there's a voice inside the Dmt
trip that tells you do not give into
astonishment.
And that's the first time I did it.
I blasted through and you could
literally hear it, but you don't hear it.
You don't hear it, but it's sand. Do not
give into astonishment. I was like, wow,
this is
the craziest shit ever. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Well that's uh, I just,
it's like, yeah, I love the word
astonishment because it's like, well,
I mean it's like what he's teasing at is,
is, is this idea of astonishment, wonder,
awe. Like rapturous ought to be pulled
from context to you. Tom Robbins,
Tom Robins, the writer, he, he's a
comedian as well maybe or something.
But he wrote about this guy,
Tom Robbins was writing about
psychedelics and he said,
the plant Jeanie's as this,
the saint marijuana or psychedelics,
the plant Jeanie's do not necessarily
manufacture imagination or wonder men.
It's not that they make
you more imaginative,
but what they do or what they can do is
pull us out of context so dramatically
that we ended up gawking and amazement
that the ubiquitous everyday wanders
we're culturally conditioned to ignore.
But you don't need drugs
to be pulled from context.
That's just one way that some people
do it. You can do it by traveling.
You can do and falling in love.
You can do it by having the rug
pulled from underneath your feet.
Just be inspired. Yes. So we, you know,
but then we have this other
thing called hedonic adaptation,
which is what trumps everything that's
always around becomes invisible.
And that's why we always need novelty
because we don't appreciate what we have
because we got used to it because the
brain gets used to it. And so in order to,
that's a terrible disease.
He died.
I got updation is the first cure with like
bioengineering that we need to fix it.
We need to fix that so that we can
be perpetually open and in awe.
You know what I'm saying? But, um,
but really it's about finding ways
to remove yourself from context,
different perspectives, new thoughts,
new spaces, new new ideas, right?
That is the hunger for it,
the constant hunger for it.
I have it because otherwise I go down
into the darkness. Like if I'm not in awe,
I start thinking about human beings.
We're the only species that's aware of
our mortality and this causes cognitive
stress. What do we do with the fact
that no matter how much we create,
how many people we fall in love with?
We're all just food for worms. In the end.
So you're essentially like an
awesome collector of ideas,
kind of a friend of mine called intention,
a lot of creative ideas of your own,
but you have an awesome
collection of these, these,
these ideas and it's um,
you know, do you have,
do you feel like that's your
calling to get that out there?
You obviously have a very unique,
and you know,
and well studied perspective on things
can be when you're talking about all
these things and you're obviously very
passionate about it. Like what do you,
what are you trying to do? You're trying
to like get other people hip to this.
Yeah, we'll agree to everybody to strap
in and, and, and prepare yourself.
Come along for the ride.
Yeah. Well, yeah. Wow Man.
You start saying shit like this.
You know,
a lot of the things you've said
and these videos, you know, you're,
you're putting these little seeds in the
heads of people all over the world that
may not necessarily have ever
thought that idea before.
That's a powerful thing then. Yeah. Well,
one of my heroes is Timothy leary
and I also really love Bucky fuller.
And they used to call themselves
performing philosophers, you know,
inter galactic sized ideas and using the
power of media communications to spread
those ideas. People like Marshall
Mcluhan that it as well. Yeah.
And Canada as well. The candidate, it as
well performing philosophers. You know,
leary said in the information age, you
don't teach philosophy, you perform it.
If Aristotle were alive today,
he'd have a talk show or youtube channel
or a podcast like the Joe Rogan podcast.
I mean, you in a way are the modern
day Aristotle sping forth ideas,
inspiring people.
But I'm saying proof of concept,
people eat Animal Dixon on TV and I'm
sponsored by a fake vagina. Well, no,
but that's there, sir. Proof, proof of
concept. Basically saying that, you know,
we used to talk about ids in these forums,
these Greek philosophers and Roman
philosophers would talk about ideas and
people would just ruminate about
ideas. And that's, I mean, that's,
you're providing a space for
that. Yeah. That's kind of cool.
And I'm trying to do that too. In the
short videos that I launched, you know,
we call them shots of Philosophical
Espresso. Yeah, they're brilliant.
I loved them. Then you put, you put
a bunch of them on Vimeo and the,
it's just they're,
they're so stunning and there the
visuals are so in tune with what you're
saying. Thanks. Really good. How, what's
the best way for people to find these?
What is the, Oh, just chasing
Silva. Vimeo actually, yeah.
If they just Google Jason Silva, Vimeo,
my Vimeo page has all of the videos,
which is fantastic and they can
go so many. Do you have, oh,
I think I had like 28 videos in there
and have all different, have the, the,
the shots of Philosophical Express.
So then I have a series called the human
condition where I look at like, oh,
we're watching one. Okay Dude, just take
a bong hit and watch his shit. Right.
That's what I'm telling you, ladies and
gentlemen. That's what you needed to do.
This is a w. Oh, there
you are. There's the,
do you do it from the beginning so people
can hear this because this is such a
trip. This is, you can't, can't start
this while we're, here we go. Nice.
[inaudible].
I have pretty much an optimist.
I reminded of Brits and Doyle's line
from Darwin's pharmacy and he says,
dreams or not lack reality,
real patterns of information.
When the imaginary foundation says that
the role as you imaginations to conceive
the bullies, delight futures,
choose the most amazing,
exciting and ecstatic possibility and
then pull the present forward to meet it.
That is when we do, we would bring
our imaginings into existence,
but I think that as technology,
as
ways to outsource our mental
capacities to our tools, so much more,
our ability to,
I'll give you like the physical world
has increased in an exponential fashion,
so we've been able to shrink and the lag
time between our imaginings and their
instantiation, the real world. David
Deutsch speaks in his new book,
the beginning of Infinity.
He says,
if you look at the topography of
the island of Manhattan today,
that typography,
typography in which the forces
of economics and culture,
human intent trumped the forces,
geology,
I mean the topography of Manhattan today
is no longer shaped by mere geology.
It's shaped by the human mind and my
economics and my culture and subway.
David Deutsch extrapolate is that
ultimately that will be the effect of the
whole unit.
He says creditation and anti matter
might only universe and its earliest at
least interesting stages but eventually
the whole thing will be subject to the
intent of some street independent,
infinitely more powerful minds and to
conceive of that just makes me feel
static to shh.
Are you fucking kidding me man?
Are you fucking kidding me?
That might be one of the best
two minute videos on the web.
How many minutes is that? I think less
than two minutes is whatever that is.
That might be one of the best videos
on the web. That is a bong hit. Wonder.
Well you know it's, I used to, awesome.
The word that I always
love to use is epiphany.
I want to epiphany's people to give
them a download to give them a micro
psychedelic trip,
but one that is scripted.
So you don't want to be tripping in a
scrambled with space with no context.
You want a scripted transcendent
experience and I think with these videos,
what I was trying to do is take
inspiration, take an epiphany,
which is usually a lonely experience that
happened, happen, happens in one's head,
and what is the goal of every artist
but to try to communicate is ecstatic
vision through paint, through
instrument, through voice.
What I'm trying to do is
reverse engineer inspiration.
Turn it into a visual form and transmute
that putting you in my head during
these glimpses of Nirvana
that I'm literally having
and I'm getting you off on
off because that's how I get off on my
own. On the odd that I have when I watch,
when I make the videos will end. You
enhanced it all with these amazing videos.
The videos and images behind it were
awesome, was a really perfectly edited.
It was very compelling that, yeah,
I worked with a magnificent editor.
Her name is Maria.
She's from an entity called not this
body and it was wonderful collaboration.
Fucking cool thing about
the Internet, man. You could
just do something like that.
Boom, throw it up there. Pow.
People download it. Instant,
totally commercial people. No
commercials, no nothing. He is.
PSA is for inspiration.
It's, yeah, totally. Yeah.
And then think about all
the positive that that does.
That's a real ripple effect, man. That's
an amazing ripple effect. Absolutely.
I mean that's the big get off for it.
It's that people enjoy it.
That's when you really realize at some
point in time there's some bizarre
connection which we in all the human
beings on this planet, all of us together,
there's some weird sort of a
electrical, you know, some, some,
some connection that we all
share and if you disturb it,
if you put shitty stuff out there, you're
going to feel it back. You really are.
Yeah. But when, once we understand that
we control our environments totally.
We all just be really
fucking cool to each other.
We can like amass a whole hive
of people who get that concept.
Re Rich Doyle wrote a book
called Darwin's pharmacy.
It's about sex plants and the
evolution of the newest fear.
And he says that one of the things that
psychedelics do for some people is they
make us aware of the feedback
loops between our creative
and linguistic choices
and our consciousness.
In other words,
we become aware of the power of the
things that we do and the things that we
surround ourselves with and the power
that those things have to literally shape
our experience of reality.
Like the is seen different when it's set
to music or when it's set to a certain
kind of lighting or when you surround
yourselves by certain kinds of people.
I mean people think that inspiration
or living an inspired life is this half
half hazard thing that you can't plan
for a transcendent moment. It's not true.
You can curate your spaces the same way
you curate your Facebook wall or your
toilet.
People you follow on Twitter to set the
emergent conditions for serendipity to
constantly be in a state where like,
wow,
I'm just meeting so many
interesting people. Well,
because I've made the choice to surround
myself in vortexes of interesting
people.
One of the ideas that Mckenna
had when it came to psychedelics,
especially too with mushrooms,
was that what you are experiencing?
And one of the reasons
why it's so consciousness
expanding is that what you're
experiencing when you take it in
the mushroom is the accumulation,
not just a psychedelic experience,
but the accumulation of the psychedelic
experiences of all the human beings
before you that have taken it.
And that's one of the ideas why there's
so much wisdom in the psychedelic
experiments.
That's like one of the,
the humility has so much humility and a
psychedelic experience and also so much
of a, a perspective enhancer that
you're, you know, you're getting your,
you're taking in this connection,
which is why, you know,
I think you can pull information out of
it or hear people talk in. Sure. You know,
it's one of the weird things about the
psychedelic experience when he gives you
information, when it talked, when you
saw someone is actually communicated,
holding you. Well, one of my favorites
is Joseph, that you've read the hotel.
It totally, no, no. Joseph Campbell,
who's one of my heroes. Oh yeah.
I love about the hero's journey,
which is the ultimate Arkansas.
And they spent illumination,
he's done a lot of lectures about
the psychedelic experience as very,
very literally an experience of the
hero's journey. I mean, consider,
consider this steps,
you know,
cause the hero's journey obviously
can be a geographical journey, right?
Like go into the unknown, you
know, step away from the ordinary,
transcend obstacles,
have an apotheosis and a rebirth
and a realization about life,
and then come back and make the return
with that illumination. But see,
isn't that what happens anytime somebody
partakes in a psychological trip? Well,
while I was going to say is I think
that's what happens when I'm watched your
video, when I watched the video. I
believe that's a psychedelic experience.
Definitely. It is. It's your
manifest the mind. Yeah.
It's information coming through stunning
visuals and it's very, uh, it's, it's,
it's imprinted totally. You know, you
get the impact of it. Totally. Totally.
There was this really what it's, that's
really what the, the pull of it all is,
isn't it? I mean, what, what your, what
you did and you accomplished in that,
that sort of is what the pull
of all of this stuff is, right.
To get something that's really, really
inspires performance inception. Yeah.
To just poon. Yeah, just give them an
explosion of new idea. 100 when you,
when you hit people with that, when that
goes out there and blows up on them,
you're literally like
pushing them off one path.
Even if it's just for a few minutes until
sure. Bullshit kicks in their fucking,
you know, her husband calls them and you
know, the kids are screaming, you know,
but for at least a couple of
minutes, man, you're pushing them.
You're pushing them in the right way.
Well, it's amazing to hear you say that.
And there's,
one of my favorite films is inception,
which was absolutely magnificent. I
didn't really like that movie. Well,
you should read it. I love it. I
liked them a little. No, no, no, no.
It was some parts where I was like,
wait a minute.
This is like a video game you need to
see out and around shooting people.
This is silly. It's like he's on
slow mode. He's my child's mode.
That's not even a real, you know what
I'm saying? It was like an old movie.
Check out the book, the
inception in philosophy, but um,
cause it talks about there's
some layers in that film.
But one of the ideas is that the
entire film is actually a metaphor for
filmmaking because think about what
filmmaking is. You create a sh a dream.
You bring the audience into that dream
and hopefully they fill it with their
subconscious, which is what we
do every time we watch a film,
we relate to the characters based on a
set of experiences that we have had in
the moods that were already in when we
go into the theater and if the film is
successfully performed, a performance
of inception and it gives us catharsis,
literally the film breaks through the
screen and becomes real in the watcher.
And isn't that what happens when you
have a psychedelic experience and it
transforms you?
Or when you have a geographical,
you take a trip somewhere and
it transforms you. Or you know,
when you actually take a, or
when you watch a movie and
it transforms you, the Po,
or you have a dream and the dream and
gives you illumination in the transfer.
The points,
if you have catharsis in a dream or in a
film or in a psychedelic trip or in the
Euclidean meetspace, it's all real.
It doesn't matter how you get it.
That's why William Gibson says that the
so called distinction between the real
and virtual world is what we're going to
laugh at in the future because there is
no distinction when when you're watching
a movie and you're immersed in the film
and you're crying from the film, it
happens to you. It becomes real. So too,
when you, somebody might, you know,
be on a psychedelic and have a
transcendent vision and people say, oh,
that's just because he was on the drug.
No, the vision was real while he had it.
Dreams are real while you're in them.
And if the vision can translate,
you know when it wears off,
when you leave the movie theater,
then you know that you've found
something valuable, genuine illumination.
That's a fascinating idea,
right? It is a fascinating,
the idea and the idea that it's somehow
or another going to be three D it's
going to be all around us.
Eventually cinema films and stuff.
We're going to watch movies take place
like all around us. You'll be in a world,
a virtual world to being inside zookeeper.
Jesus Christ. That's incredible.
That's kind of amazing. I mean, we, you
know, we're the naked ape, you know,
Terence Mckenna says that we,
we ate psychedelics when
we left this event as well.
We left the jungles of African one
into the Savannah's. Our diets change.
We picked the magic mushrooms from
the cow dung. We started tripping.
He says it might've been a catalyst
for language. And you know why?
I think it's very compelling idea because
we don't exactly know how language
emerged,
but he points to the fact that some
psychedelics have a synesthetic effect.
It's an aesthetic means that
they blurs the different senses.
So you see sounds are you hear
sites and if you think about it,
language is synesthetic.
I use vocal patterns to
transmit images to your brain.
Wirelessly language was the first
information technology that allowed me to
transmit information through time and
space outside of just DNA having sex with
other DNA.
And so the synesthetic power
of information technology
might have been triggered
by the synesthetic effect
of the magic mushroom.
That's the stoned ape hypothesis and I
think it's a brilliant theory for sure.
Like that's a really interesting way
of putting it that I haven't heard said
that way,
that it making
noises with the images that synesthetic
yeah, that people don't realize this,
you know languages
synesthetic that's amazing.
And that's what chimps haven't figured
that shit out yet. And then the naked ape,
what have you just start giving chimps
mushrooms. Maybe we should do that.
Who should do that? Man, man,
we should have some just and
everything in the road to be honest.
Curing compound where we feed shrimp,
but just to see what's
up feed troops to chimps.
That would be the most bad ass scientific
experiment of all time and just a
total planet of the apes type moving.
Do you think,
could you imagine if you did it for
like three generations there until they
started becoming people and they're like,
stop,
stop the experiment or there's some great,
there's some great cartoons
that are seen on the Internet,
like illustrations showing the stoned ape
hypothesis and you see like a bunch of
monkeys like walking
around, you know, whatever.
And then they like the mushroom and then
they're like in their heads they start
seeing like rockets flying to the moon
satellites. It's cell phones and cities,
buildings erected from the ground.
I mean think of how psychedelic
that sounds to you know,
to early man like a city,
New York,
a jet engine next to like a caveman.
Right?
How do you make the leap
from that to that? Well,
you would think that that leap might be
more easy if the ape is tripping, right?
Yeah,
we should totally see how that works.
If they're willing to put monkeys and
cages and try Mascara out on their shit.
Really have,
but you think they'd been given chips.
There's definitely scientists in some
lab that are fucking giving machines to
manage.
I don't know,
but I don't know if you can advocate
that because if the chimp can't give you
his permission, so what if he has a bed?
It's true. So you leave the mushrooms.
If what happens happens,
hey, what the fuck?
I just think it'd be a
fascinating thing to watch.
Could you imagine if
they did it for like six,
seven generations of chip started
losing hair, standing up straight,
started slowly turned into people.
Then it became all this political pressure
when they started looking like people
closest one to a person yet and you'd see
this chimp will get me the fuck out of
here. They probably started talking.
Well Hollywood prepares us. Yeah,
they make a lot of cautionary tales about
that. I mean the cyborgs or you know,
until it wouldn't be amazing though.
If it was just mushrooms,
they probably would just go from like
throwing poop to wiping their poop all
over their own body castles.
You guys have probably seen,
I've probably seen 2001 a space odyssey.
She might think that maybe the monolith
when it first appears when the monkeys
finally learn how to use tools, the
monolith is just kind of a place holder.
It's this weird shaped figure.
Maybe that it's a placeholder on purpose
because it's a metaphor for the mystery.
What happened when we went from like
just being able to apes that use tools?
Well maybe that's metaphor.
Maybe that's the mushroom.
The monolith is the magic mushroom that
cuddle and catalyze the use of tool and
at the moment that the ape picked up
like a branch on the floor to use it to
reach a fruit on a really high tree.
He became one with his tools.
We used our tools to extend the boundaries
of who and what we are and then we
went to the moon and then who knows
what's next. It's while was a genius.
She has a gene who meat like putting like
meaning into scenes and having scenes
represent things that are actually
taking place in the real world.
There's a some crazy guy named Jay Wiener.
I think his name is who actually sat down
and documented all the connections to
the moon landings and all that,
all sorts of different things
in inside the work of Kubrick's,
the shining like to the little boy wearing
an Apollo rocket sweater to the room
number being like some number that has
something to do with the launch time.
And it was a really amazing thing.
Kubrick had,
he constructs a world
or did rather he's gone,
but he constructed a world that
was not just like the surface,
but there was hidden meaning to all
these different things that were going on
and he was like, he was way,
way, way ahead of his time.
He was just out there, man, that guy
had some fucking wild ass movies,
a clockwork orange. Are
you kidding me? Yeah, yeah.
I remember watching that movie going, God
damn, this guy's going deep. Yeah. Well,
can you be,
that's why
filmmaking,
I think is the most transcendent art
form of our times because we're literally
able to create virtual world that
can transform our consciousness,
like reprogram our brain. I
mean, I think, I think cinema,
I think a gifted director is like the
closest thing we have to a deity in a
secular world. I mean what
they, what they create,
what bursts forth in the cinema when
your brain is tweaked to the film in the
right way is to me the modern
version of a religious experience,
right?
Yeah. What's homeboy? The
dude who did alien, what's
that guy's name? Ridley Scott.
Ridley Scott. Thank you. He's doing
the new one. Be New. Oh my God.
Look what do you hear that Ridley Scott
is doing another alien movie? Yeah.
Ego Cop Tams is going to be a wild
two hours of my life. Exact sit down.
I'm going to watch some crazy
shit. Hopefully it hasn't.
George Lucas said, no,
he won't. He won't. Ridley Scott is not
going to do, he's not going to do that.
He's not going to do that.
He wouldn't do that.
That's what we used to say that George
Lucas, they made charge are too,
but he's listening. No one but Ridley
Scott was capable of that first one.
That first alien was a Mutha fucker.
That was one of the greatest
harm movies of all time, man.
That thing was fucking terrifying.
A thing that jumps on your fucking face,
shoots a load down your throat.
A monster emerges out of your chest
with an explosion and then just fox up
everything and no one can
stop it. Which, which aliens
said the Milky Middle Guy where he gets
ripped in half and on the milk came out.
Hmm.
You know what I'm talking about?
Like here's like a robot and he
got split open and all this like,
like robot juice flew over it. I think
maybe with aliens. Aliens. You don't know.
Oh No, I don't remember that
man. I remember there was um,
Sigourney weaver had like a crazy space
suit on that she put the fight off the
aliens. Remember that? Yeah. I remember
there was some like crazy robotics.
You pitch back off like she was going
to fight this fucking super, you know,
super sized beasts. Integrative,
regular aliens were scary enough. Yeah.
This was the crazy one.
And she's kicking
a queen's ass. Not as good as alien one
was. They went a little crazy right there.
Got a little Hollywood,
they try to outdo themselves more.
Much like the new fear factor.
It's like if you went back to the premise
of the first alien, the first alien,
it was, she was way scarier. That
alien was fucking horrifying. You know,
like you couldn't see it.
He didn't know where it was.
Then it would just jump out at San
Jac people and the second aliens,
they're killing them left and right.
Like running down a hallway.
The aliens are coming out and
they're like, they're stupid now.
You can just shoot him, you know,
before they would, you know,
they would sneak up behind you and they
were intelligent and they were all you
want. You want the film
to always be high concept.
I mean if you want to throw
out some action in there
to keep people entertained,
but you only want it to be like high
concept of if you're into the ideas,
you can also like be entertaining. Yeah,
way like metaphysical science fiction,
you know? The first one though
was on, on that level. The first,
the first one was just
absolutely brilliant.
It was a one of the greatest horror movies
of all time. There you go. You know?
But the second one, he got crazy. It
was good. And the third action, no,
I liked it. I, I'll, I'll
watch all of them do it. I
even watch aliens vs Predator.
I'm a sucker. I'm stupid.
I'm like a 14 year old boy,
my taste in movies. But that was a
terrifying movie. But you were right.
That guy has created a world. He's
like a god in the world. Yeah.
He's like a god of this mini world.
What comes to phase two?
What's going to be the next immersive
transformative entertainment technology?
You know,
someone was talking about James Cameron,
they were talking about how
demanding James Cameron was.
All James cameras like this fucking
paints the wrong paint. I want it.
This call I went to and you know,
there was like, Oh God, he's so crazy.
So demanding. I was like, that's the
only way you get to be a James Cameron.
You know? How the fuck do you
make something like titanic?
How do you make a movie that big?
You better be a bad mother fucker.
You better be running shit, dude. You
can't. You can't half ass and Pussy foot,
that fucking movie.
You're going to have a movie about a
giant metal ship that crashes into the
ocean and it's gotta be a
compelling movie as well. Well,
who wouldn't want to direct a film?
It could because essentially you're God.
You control every variable as you want.
Dude, we'll look at the titanic note.
Did it didn't just think of ship to
make that movie that was all digital.
I mean that is, you're going to make
that in three d they're releasing.
It's getting,
that's incredible.
The idea of that kind of
technology to recreate reality.
That's when your idea of recreating a
full reality. It doesn't seem so far off.
Not at all.
We're already doing.
We already do it, man.
You know a plane reserve.
I with a wireless iPhone,
make a reservation a few days later,
get them at crafted,
flies you around the world to a place
where no one knows your name and you have
no memories. Holy Shit. Holy
Shit. And indeed, you know,
it's probably going to be
like the next big jump is, uh,
being able to go to a movie theater in
control it, I think we've talked about it.
Oh yeah, I know what I mean. Yes. Yeah.
But what's crazy is that I think
actors are on the way out. I mean,
there's an only hope.
There was a video that was posted on
Vimeo the other day on Kotaku and uh,
it's just kind of shows you what
the next level of like x, Xbox,
playstation with the CGI
looks like for that. It's, it's very close
to being, look at this video real quick.
It's really close to being just scary
sketching like God. I mean it's,
it's like look how you can see the pores.
You can see like it's got a little cut and
from my shaving, yeah, it's incredible.
So this is an example of what the next
x box type playstation console would we,
and this is just fucking video games for
your house. This isn't even look real.
Yeah. It looks like Toby
McGuire or something like that.
Like someone's bullshitting
us. Like someone, uh,
made a fake video to pretend now I think,
I think what it is,
I think this is based on it.
I did new texture technology that's going
to be used in like upcoming platforms
for games and the need to make the
supermodel version of that. Okay.
That looks a little wonky. Just
a touch. Just a touch. Yep.
His eyelashes or lack thereof.
But what's cool is that this is just
one artist using the technology.
Imagine when we start having like,
like you know that really
good artists play with it.
There's painters that can paint a
face that looks like a photograph.
This is incredible.
If you,
what I was saying was that if you made
this like with a video camera with your
friends and pretended as
the new technology, it would
look similar to this. Yeah.
Just have a little shake cam
to it. I would totally look
around. Yeah. If you look,
so you captured the,
the newest technology.
This is what the government is doing now.
They're creating fake news. Yeah. Oh,
then that I think,
yeah.
The next paradigm will be like those
film experience that adjusts the choose
your own adventure film experience.
You know, based on your decisions.
I immersive immersive
virtual reality games.
You know like that movie exit stens
actually at a very interesting that it
Cronenberg film.
They could create a fake
Rhea one transmitted fake
reality and then a real one
that, but then like hide behind. Yeah.
And then go into it and
have like a journey and have
something that you have to
do and have something
you have to accomplish.
You can be like the James Bond or the
Indiana Jones, the narrative. Jesus.
What if you die in there though?
Maybe you wake up like crushed.
Like you're just like,
yeah,
what if there's like glitches every
now and then you'd die for real, right?
Like dying in a train. You can't play
games bitch DV Indiana Jones. Huh?
Do you think dying in the dream like
that we're not thinking of that can't be
good for you,
right?
There has to be like every time
you get your dye in your dream,
it's like getting hit
in the head really hard.
Like a part of your brain thinks are
dead or something like they don't like
dying in my dreams. It's very weird and
I'm always so relieved when I wake up.
Thank you. Isn't it funny that a
lot of people hate life? Like, God,
I'm so miserable, but yet they happy
when they don't die in their dreams.
You know, I didn't need to dreams
go God, you fucking pussy. You know,
it's interesting you talk about like
not appreciating life or hating life.
There's a great documentary.
It's called flight from death,
the quest for immortality.
And it says that basically it cites
the work of Ernest Becker who was,
uh,
if you saw Annie Hall,
it's the book that Woody Allen Gives Annie
Hall in the bookstore about the human
creation.
It's called the denial of death and a
to 1974 Pulitzer Prize winning book.
And it says basically that we're
essentially God's with
anuses with our minds.
We can ponder the infinite were
seemingly capable of anything,
yet we're housed in a heart pumping,
breath, gasping, decaying body.
So we are godly yet creaturely we can
write poetry and build skyscrapers,
but ultimately we're food for the worms
and that is the problem of the human
condition. Ultimately the ser,
the source probably of our,
the impetus to be so creative to tr to
transcend this condition symbolically and
artistically. But he says even
even romantic love in a way,
as a way of of dealing
with the human condition.
You turn your lover into a deity,
she becomes your salvation.
That's why all the pop song says she's
like the wind. She's like the sun.
She provides the salvation that God no
longer provides in a secular society.
Right.
Cause we have,
we have grown too sophisticated for
religion but we still need to work on our
existential problems.
So then we do it with our lovers or we
do it with through creative acts and
ultimately,
you know,
using science and technology to transcend
the human condition might be the
ultimate solution to the Becker dilemma.
That's why I'm totally pro and
Manhattan project to transcend death.
Like all about it. Yeah. Do.
Do you find that when you do the
calculations as far as like, you know,
human population growth of technology,
do you find a point where, I mean,
are you seeing where this is
going to like wind up? Well,
technology technology is a
resource liberating mechanism.
And people talk about scarcity,
but scarcity is contextual.
Something has only scarce until you figure
out the technology that makes it into
something abundant. And this is what
Peter Diamandis, his new book talks about.
So for example,
our dependence on fossil fuels,
we think that this feel
way to fuel things. Well,
once we transcend that technology,
we saw,
I mean we get 10 times more power
every day from the sun, you know,
that we could ever use.
Right?
And we just have to figure out a way to
capture that energy and people talking
about overpopulation.
But the reality is you can fit the
entire world's population in the state of
Texas. They're still be plenty of space.
The probably, yeah, the whole world.
Oh yeah. The problem is resources.
Billion People in Texas, Brian, I think,
imagine what the airport would
look like. Well, what happens,
it's an issue of resources,
right?
But if you have like
nanotechnology or in vitro meat,
tissue engineering grow all the meeting
could ever even pita supports in vitro
meat, you take that,
you can take stem cells,
stem cells from an and give it a
brain cells from an animal meats.
Sounds like it could be good stem cells
from Macau and grow all the meat you
could ever need with no nervous system.
So no animal is suffering.
Never killed another cow. See formula
away from the fleshlight people.
Cause like I met you. What? I'm interested
in that and some people talk about,
you know, and or, or have you ever an
Arrow, hydroponics, I have to talk about,
have you heard of aeroponics growing
fruits and vegetables in mist and these
vertical farming towers with
this special missed and you have,
you don't have to worry about like,
you know,
the poison and the all the spraying
and damaging the eco, the farming,
the land of missed content's minerals
and water. It's like hydroponics.
But in ms grown in missed holy shit.
Right?
And people don't know about this stuff,
but it's like absolutely insane.
That's incredible. That's a beautiful
idea. That's what I'm saying. Wow.
Growing vegetables in mist
and vertical towers.
You know,
we could just like grow all the vegetables
we could ever need in genetically
engineered to have better like vitamins,
you know?
But you can't live Monsanto do that
though. Let's not going to be Monsanto.
Just like,
just like computers used to be these big
centralized grids and now everybody has
an iPhone or just like a,
you know,
gps used to be this big government thing
and now everybody has ups on the phone.
These things will trickle
down and empower individuals.
Biotechnologies not going to be Monsanto.
Biotechnology is going to be to
the domestication of biotechnology.
It's going to be personalized medicine,
personalized software
upgrade of your physiology.
It's not going to be these
big government thing.
Be like a place where you go and you can
become a new person. Sure. Know Autumn,
I want to be a black chick
just for like a year. Yeah.
So you're a doctor to become your lover,
the lover, and become the black chick.
How about like having sex with your
partner and like merging your nervous
system's together. I mean, we've been
trying to merge into one another.
If you fuck a tantric sex, oh,
there you go. Come on mushrooms.
You can make some shit happen,
Molly.
There you got that two song
edible marijuana as well.
There's something about that makes it
very sensuous. Interesting. Mm hmm.
The connection to hive. Yeah. That's when,
when we can all jump into
the human pool, right? Yeah.
The human pool of thoughts and ideas.
The human brain pool when all of us are,
there's no cubicles, cubicles drop and
we're all on the same thing together.
That's going to be strange
to come will become gods.
It seems like it's inevitable, right? Oh,
absolutely. Yeah, absolutely. There's a,
one of my favorite quotes by
Alan Harrington, who wrote,
he was part of the beat generation and
he's staying out with all those guys.
He wrote a book called the immortalists.
He said,
we must never forget that we
are cosmic revolutionaries,
not stooges conscripted to advance
a natural order that kills everyone.
So we,
it's romantic and defiant to say we
will not go quietly into that good night
rage, rage against the dying of
the light. That's what we do.
What was the first sentence? We must never
forget. We are cosmic revolutionaries.
Could you imagine if you just
walked around a tee shirts
at cosmic revolutionary?
Hell yeah. People would be like, really,
dude, what'd you do today? You jerked off.
He watched the Carl Sagan
video on youtube. Totally
to a comic book store. Well,
Carl Sagan, evolutionary hunter.
Awesome. What a great fucking title.
I think I'm going to have to change my,
a message board handled
cosmic revolutionary cosmic
revolution. Yay. Hello.
You just think that's
beautiful. Yeah, dude,
we are away for the cosmos to know itself.
Sagan said it himself and also we're the
frontal lobes of the universe because
so far we haven't found anything
more complicated than the brain.
There's very few things more douchey
than calling yourself a revolutionary.
Fair enough.
It sounds like a myspace page.
You know what? I'm [inaudible].
I gotta drop the hand away.
You say we ain't call my,
so that'd be very hypocritical.
I've made fun of people for calling
themselves mobile revolution. I'm like,
someone's going to call you that man. Even
if it's tongue in cheek, like with me,
it's completely, you know,
cosmic revolutionaries either.
Then you've got to let somebody else
call you unless you have lightening bolts
in the background.
Maybe like everybody got a tattoo that
says cosmic revolutionary in lighting.
We
were,
but the thing is I think humanity is,
we are cosmic revolutionaries and I
also think we're nature's secret weapon,
right? Actually the other one of the other
videos I did is code or something it's
called to understand is to
perceive patterns and one
of the things that it looks
at is the recurring patterns that occur
at different scales of reality from
manmade systems to natural
systems and back again,
it's like these natural patterns that
persist in nature and are now popping up
in these big data visualizations
of manmade systems.
You know how cities are like capillaries,
you know, alleys are like arteries.
You know Jeffrey West and the Santa Fe
institute talks about this stuff and what
it shows you is that yes we are free
agents participating in this project.
Just progression of technology but
it's also, it's inevitable itself.
Organizing its evolution.
Like we are just participating actively
instead of passively in evolution.
You can we play that one? I would
love for sure. How does he get to it?
You think he has it right? Yeah.
Yeah. You've got a cute this,
it was the other one that we,
yeah, I think this one right here.
Yeah.
This one looking at the different,
the galaxies in the neuron
and the mushroom mycelium
in London from the sky and
the Internet. Visualize. I'll
share the Shang nuts. Yeah.
They all share the same Philip mental
structure. How strangers though
[inaudible]
do all your things start with
this? Yeah. Cause my friend,
I am my very good friends.
Patterns.
And of course what this means is the true
comprehension comes when the dots are
revealed and you get some Johnson long
view. When you see the big picture
patterns, patterns, recurring patterns
across different scales of reality.
You know,
Paul talks about the mycelial archetype
and how to get information sharing
systems that comprise the Internet look
exactly like computer models of dark
matter in the universe.
Look exactly like the neuron brain.
They all hear the same for
twinkle Philip mental structure.
It's the rise of network is big data
advocates talk about how the systems are
looking exactly like natural
systems and what we can measure.
The more we can visualize it,
that we can visualize,
the more expands our consciousness.
My seniors were occurring.
Patterns are scales of
reality blows my mind.
And I think that technology increasingly
is becoming an expander human
consciousness. It extends our far reaching
vision and revealing so much more.
It's like,
whereas once I was blind,
now I can see Geoffrey West from the
Santa Fe institute is telling us that
cities are really like organisms. You
know, alleys are like capillaries.
How is it possible that a
manmade artificial logical
system is behaving like a
natural system?
The more efficient it becomes,
the board started to look like nature.
Really interesting, weird stuff. Um,
you know, but, but it makes me optimistic.
It's like what Steven Johnson says, look,
if we can understand all this
stuff, I mean, any, anything
becomes possible. Right?
It's the adjacent possible standing
as a sort of shadow future.
A map of all the ways the
president can reinvent itself. It's
beautiful stuff.
Crazy. Another one. That's another one
that's [inaudible]. Awesome. That's great.
It's weird.
We could thought
that the human brain cell looks like
the universe. Oh yeah. Like the galaxy.
You liked the, yeah, the
neurons. The Internet. The
Internet too. It's terrifying.
Yeah. Well, but it shows you that there's
these patterns persist because they've,
they've, they allow innovation to occur.
Yeah. I mean, the city is the coral reef.
When I say terrifying, I mean just
winning in its magnitude. You know,
it's all the idea that
makes me feel mystical,
that the fact that
neurons and all of that,
it's just really hard to wrap your
head around exact call. Just one soup.
But doesn't that all relieve you of any
boredom? Yeah. Whoa. It definitely does.
That's why I do it.
I don't know how anybody could
be bored with any of this stuff.
It's mind boggling.
It's to some people it's a little
unsettling because they like to think that
this is where I get my coffee in the
morning. Right. Marge, how are you March?
Meanwhile,
Marjane strapped to a fucking giant rock
going a thousand miles an hour and a
circle.
You,
Marge is hanging on in space and that
the earth is not connected to anything.
It's just floating out
there floating and spinning,
winning like a motherfucker spinning a
thousand miles an hour around a giant
nuclear explosion.
That's right.
A big constant nuclear explosion
that will eventually die. Thank you.
S bizarres fuck right. It's
something, well, you know the, the,
the red sox are doing well this year.
Yeah.
Well they'll find a way to fuck that
up. Yes or no, and then they, they,
they know how's the tomatoes and then,
you know,
go back home and take a shit
and that's it. All right.
Let me just wait for the
inevitable while we spent.
Yeah. Why do we like
mundane things? What is the,
the [inaudible] there's
something comfortable in the
prosaic because the world
at large can be overwhelming to all of
us. I mean, those videos are overwhelming.
A psychedelic trip is overwhelming.
I mean a big city can be overwhelming.
And I think that some people thrive in
the spaces in which they are overwhelmed
and some people prefer to cower away
from it due to circumstances in their
lives, culture, preconceptions,
choices that they make.
And ultimately I think that,
I don't think we'd do well to judge
anybody for how they choose to live.
I think that what you do is you try to
do what you can to share many different
ideas and many points of views and they'll
find Dell find the astonishment that
they like best and partake hopefully in
that one. You know, Makenna talked about,
uh,
technology and once,
I'll never forget this thing they said
he was talking about different areas in
life where, um, uh, what he said that um,
a a failed symbiotic
is what a parasite is.
And that every parasite seeks to be a
symbiotic organism and seeks because we're
all symbiotic. They want to
keep eating. They don't want it.
They don't want you to
die cause then they die.
I mean people have all sorts of funky
living things living inside their body.
We're all symbiotic.
Yeah. And you know when,
when he talked about technology,
one of the things that I
thought always was that,
doesn't it seem like technology
is some sort of a symbiotic,
some sort of like a living organism?
It seems like.
I have,
like I always talk about how I have like
dead skeletons of the old shit laying
around. I found an old phone the other
day. It's an old fucking dead thing,
you know, like move past this. This
is a fucking mastodon. I'm looking at,
told me I'm looking at an old mac
that's a dinosaur bone, you know?
That's really what I mean.
That's why I,
that's why we call it the human
technology co evolution. You know,
I'm a fellow of an organization called
hybrid realities institute that says we
are already cyborgs and when comes,
yeah.
But do you believe in the Kurtzweil idea
that they'll be some sort of a sentient
intelligent life form? It will become
centered and able to move around.
It'd be able to think on its
own and that will be a new life.
So it really is a new life.
We're already a hybrid.
Somebody puts on a pacemaker in their
heart or they put in a chip in their brain
to help them with their tremors from like,
you know,
one of the Dick Cheney neurologicals
neuro know that I saw yesterday,
there was this new pump
that they put in a guy,
he doesn't have a pulse and pulse
that shits in the Bible son.
We live inside of the constructs of
our imagination. We live in the spaces,
we use technology, we use
electricity, we create phone card.
So water that comes to our house
through the pipes, you know,
I mean we were already, we already are
symbiotes in symbiosis. The differences,
the symbiosis becoming more and more
smooth, you know, the best technologies.
It's not technology that
gets out of the way, right?
It just allows you to do the artful
change that you want to make in the world
without having to fuck with it too much.
And that's what happens as these guys,
she acknowledges get smoother in the way
that they get in meshed in our lives.
The sort of hybridization just gets
richer and deeper, but we're already,
it's already happening. It's
perfectly natural, so that's not,
that's not a problem.
It's not something to be scared of it all.
It's something just to be refined and
and the [inaudible] well we make choices
right when we buy apple
products were saying we let,
we want things to have a sense of
aesthetic. We want them to be beautiful.
We want our symbiosis to be functionally
rich but also aesthetically beautiful
and that's important.
There's a thought that's been going
around a lot lately on the Internet.
The Internet is Karma Free Iphones,
you know I talked about it on this podcast
and people are talking about it now,
like the idea of making
conflict mineral free,
definitely possible and that's
absolutely going to be possible.
And with nanotechnology we can engineer
your own materials from scratch because
we are manipulating things
at the level of the atom.
We can turn dog shit into Pearl to gap,
call it the diamond age.
That's where Shit's going
to get a really weird cause.
Everyone would have a 10 foot
dick made out of gold. Oh yeah.
Order order an information file.
Print the toaster in your house
and you're going to have no,
what are we going to have
to pay for electricity?
Everything's going to be solar.
No, everything's going to
be abundant and infinite.
How are we going to pay for things?
Cause the monetary system,
we post scarcity age there. No, you
don't pay for it. No paying for things.
Abundance and how they become a baller.
He can be a baller.
You know you can't make it
rain if everything's free,
you can ever cut the ball or out of
society because then you're going to cut a
lot of the funny out. Why?
Because people love their status.
If you can't restrict with ridiculous
behavior, if you want to keep comedy,
can we create virtual simulations that
are indistinguishable from the real where
you can be the baller, there'll be
racist world. They'll be racist.
Do it in a racist way.
You got to let you gotta let ball kids.
You can't to judge.
How many people would become ballers.
There's a lot of white dudes
go ball or style, right?
Lot of white dudes get black guy tattoos.
You know what I'm saying?
Talk like a black guy.
You can't,
you can't factor that in the computer
simulation. You got to let that happen.
You know what I'm saying?
Like he was having the white
rapper do that. Uh, has uh,
all the platinum teeth.
Wait [inaudible] he's like one of the
most famous white rapper dudes is,
he's legit. He's like
download all of our cars. No.
Oh dammit. I can't remember
the dude's name, Chris.
My point's been shattered for, I can't
remember his name. I points my shattered.
My point is you couldn't be able to
figure that guy out in the computer
simulation gotta let that Guy Happen
in the real world. Yeah, definitely.
That would be the real problem you
got if we were strict. All, you know,
people really do evolve. We're going
to, it's like shit's not going to be,
it's funny. She's really
funny. I'm when I am right now.
Like it's like a, when I'm
William Randolph Hearst
wanted to keep cannabis down.
So because he as a commodity,
what's really why he made it illegal.
So he was an evil fuck and
William Randolph first,
it was just a bad motherfucker that
read newspapers and he also had his own
mills.
So he was going to have to convert his
mills over to Katie hemp because hemp
paper was like, who do you get four times
as much? You know, you at a, in a, um, uh,
an acre and it replenishes itself
every six months. You know,
it's not like you have to wait 20 years
to the fucking trees to grow back.
It's just like boom, it's there
again and you can redo it again.
And so as a commodity, this is going
to cost him millions of dollars.
So what he decided to do was just write
stories about weed and put it in his
newspaper. It's really an amazing
thing that the guy pulled this off,
that we're reefer madness and all that
stuff. All that stuff came from him.
You talking about Paul Wall? There are the
Rapper Paula. Thank you Veronica Ricci.
Thank you Veronica. Thank you very
much. Thanks. She's on a ball, dude.
What a good drill you've got.
Um, yeah, because that guy,
you can't predict that guy
in a computer simulation.
He's a great white rapper and he's
totally like town with black people.
He's got crazy platinum teeth.
You know,
you got to let that guy take place
because otherwise you're not going to have
the art. Kelly's of the world, right?
With evolution with our Kelly will
not be there. And then come on man.
If you ever watched that art Kelly real
talk video, have you ever watched that?
You've never seen that.
You've never seen the most brilliant
piece of human pop culture when you think
that the world is evolving still.
We're going to show you something right
now and let's get this might throw a
monkey wrench and all your theory. Sarah
Thrupp, some r Kelly. Real talk. Brian,
it's been so long. It'd be loud too.
Let's find out and it's fun. Now finally,
what happens? I'm feeling risky. I haven't
slept. There's so many of them now.
Like I,
I checked checked recently.
There's like 50 of them are Kelly is
down with people listening to his shit
online as a mine.
People getting mad at me because of this
whole thing where I said I'm a website.
I ask people to not put
links to pirated shit. I go,
you know just don't get me in trouble.
I'm not telling you what to do.
Just don't put that shit on my website,
you know?
But people actually fair for you to say
people act like you're telling me like
you're fucking shuttering me man.
They get so crazy when it
comes to this and and their,
their need to justify streaming things
talk to because I think it's a great
song.
You know what I'm saying?
He knows a lot of profanity in it but
profanity represents just how real shit
gets when you arguing with the girl
and Shit. You know what I'm saying?
So I did it on youtube but I'm going
to do this shit for y'all on Youtube.
I don't want him,
he drives to evolve any more than that.
I want this guy to always exist,
stole.
He's jumping off here so
we're going to be real man.
I'm just going to be rid of him.
We just don't roll the
film and we going to do it.
I'm doing this for the fans that I
know around the globe. They love.
We'll talk to me.
This is what, this is our Kelly. They'll
give me, who is he out there? You Sir?
Watch this.
Is that a club with,
let him see the full view
girl.
I'm not about to sit up here and argue
with you about who's to blame a call. No.
Only thing I'm traveling stablish
the Jews not establish steps.
This
in the club with some mother [inaudible].
Did she say that?
Hold on guys there.
Did she stay?
There were other guys were other guys.
Dan will tell me this.
How the fuck
she knew I was with the
mother when the whole plot
right here is good writers.
Good.
I don't know why you fuck with
them all jealous. No man having
real tall. He's really
tall. Some all bullshit.
I'm just trying to have the
town [inaudible] bullshit.
We'll talk.
Did Not just give you money to go get Joe.
He's the greatest of all time.
Damn money.
No one's more entertaining.
Limber. R Kelly. I don't,
I don't want us to ever not have
an r Kelly. Well, you know what?
That's what's great about the Internet
is that if you have the urge to share,
you can share. That guy's crazy. I
need him. I need him to stay crazy.
I want that. I want that guy. We didn't
even see some of the best lines in it.
That he's brilliant. Maybe he be sitting
here. It might be a parody. Yeah.
Even if it's not, I don't care. Whatever.
He's fucking rocking in his way.
Good for him. I love him. I'll be
at r Kelly fan of the day. He dies.
I hope you didn't really p on anybody
though. Now he did. I have the video.
She's really young, right?
Nevermind. I don't have that
number bad. Call her back color.
Yeah. Maybe we need to delay.
We needed put a delay in us. I don't have
it anymore. I hate it when it came out.
And is she, she, she looked
like she was younger.
Like I don't know how young she was, but
she look like old enough. Like she look,
she was dressed up like a stripper
and shit. You know. Wait a minute.
What are you talking about? Nothing. I
don't know what you're talking about.
Say we need a delay. I know because
of the art Kelly comment, right? No,
because the other day when a w Jimmy
fake phone number on the air, oh,
people got phone calls, some part, some
poor chick on Twitter. We hooked her up.
She's going to come to the show tickets.
That's hilarious. Took care of her.
I told her take care of her, her
tab two and a fucking asshole. Yeah.
So we removed it.
Let me ask you,
when did you become interested in
all of the ideas of the singularity?
I'm just curious,
but ray Kurtzweil is absolutely,
we should have ray here to talk.
I would love to come with them.
And Mckenna Mckenna was a
huge, huge influence because
he was just so compelling.
His, uh, lecturers were so
fascinating to me. And like I said,
the first time I did DMT, I literally
heard it, what was represented shirt,
his shirt, his words. You know
that nut too. I think, you know,
there's been very few people that
have put as much down as he did,
you know, as far as like those
recordings that you can get online.
Like there's so many of them, man and
they're so God damn interesting man.
He just had this really
weird way of phrasing things
and putting things together
and brain was wired on just another
level and he understood the power of
language. He also had a
lot about language, like we
live in a world of language.
He said, note how I use big words as one
of the things that he said. I was like,
Yo,
why has he gotten in trouble?
He's really fascinated and he calls
language and ecstatic activity of
signification. Yeah. Self defining
reality was brought forth,
intimated by language and brought
forth into being by language please.
But it is for sure. Totally is. I
mean we live in a world of mind,
right up world of psyche,
dance are so on flights.
So unfortunately Mckenna
died and before you know,
he could really see how crazy things
are getting right now. Yeah. You know,
it's such a shame. That's
what I say. We've got to fix
the death problem men. Yeah.
Cool.
It robs us of all these luminous beings.
So how many people do you
think the earth can support?
I mean if you were going to go into the
stars stars for sure. Of course we are.
That's the,
that's the human.
That's the next leap is didn't stand
Ingrid said that got him in trouble.
Well I'm [inaudible] cause he was
taking it. Nasa I think I was doing no,
he was doing really well
in the campaign trail.
They said who's going to go to the moon
and people like pitch fix Detroit I
think four. No, I do. I do think
we didn't stay in the caves.
We didn't stay with the limitations of
biology. We won't stay on the planet.
I mean I think I to be human is to
transcend our boundaries. Like, I think,
think if it's possible with that natural,
oh yeah.
It's all figure out a way
to Geo engineer's some
other planet and ship people
over there and we'll, we'll figure it
out. I mean I, man, I ain't, I'm Brian,
but how could you say that? It's
impossible. When you look at we've, we've,
we've been able to do here and just a
short couple of hundred years for $200 or
$300 you can buy an iPhone.
Something that the richest person on
the face of the planet 50 years ago
couldn't buy with all his
billions. I isn't that amazing.
What a crazy invention.
If everyone on the other side of the
country like woopty other side of the
country when we all lived on one side
of the country with the earth go out of
it's spent. Yes, the earth would
sink. It would flip over it.
Somebody's actually been out that somebody
actually asked when most of the world
is water anyway. Like it's mostly
empty space. The planet, right.
Mostly empty space and more,
more people are moving into cities anyway,
so it's going to be just more
and more just empty space.
There was someone who actually asked
that. There was like, I forget who it was.
It was like a recent thing. It
was a story really. Somebody acts.
There was too many people on an island
and he was worried if they had all that
people on one side, whether the, I
don't want to capsize. It was a real,
a real person actually asked that
question like, dude, you know what?
We've got to get you.
We gotta get you some tee shirts
from the imaginary foundation. Okay.
Do they exist
in the line of the day because
I'm visible. Here's a, here's a,
here's one of my favorite
teas. Loser. Yeah. No,
the imaginary foundation,
they make apparel that celebrates
the power of human imagination.
If you can go to imaginary foundation,
they're going, that is one of them.
The one you're wearing right now.
It's like they think it's actually
with a bunch of cool colors on them and
there's this like old guy underneath
like holding it up like, Oh wow,
that's pretty cool.
I mean there's stuff is like the most
gorgeous and inspired imagery that I've
ever come across because it's cosmic,
but it's also whimsical and psychedelic.
So it's like singularity meets
psychedelic rapture in image.
Yeah. Just I love them, man.
I want, I want, they'll say,
I'll get them to send you a shirt. You
guys. That'd be great. Sounds awesome man.
Yeah. Um, how did you meet a Ray
Kurzweil? I met him because um, you know,
for five years I was hosting
a television show for current,
which is Al Gore's cable in the channel.
Right. So that's what I was doing.
Heard that him and Keith Olbermann at Ben.
That's the rumor I guess. Rawling yeah,
squabbling squabble.
Then I left the network last year,
so I already knew about that.
Yeah.
A lot of politics of bullshit
going down over there.
They don't appreciate the talent. Did they
not see these youtube clips? No, I just,
I wanted to make content on a,
on my own terms.
And after four and a half years
doing anything that he'd done,
it got septation kicks in. So you just
crave something different. But, um,
adaptation. Yeah, we'll, let's just
like, you'd need to be hedonistic.
That's a strain he done got notation means
that something that gave you pleasure
stops being as stimulated as it once was.
You adapt to the hedonic nature of it
so that it's no longer hedonic. Oh,
so you're,
you're hedonism once you give into it
and you always constantly tolerance.
Tolerance, like drugs. So you
are a hedonistic, Chunky, well,
I've always thought that.
Don't you think like Alex,
especially a gambling junkies,
they seem to be,
it seems to be a hedonistic drug of
choice. You know that intelligence,
we're hacking,
we're hacking our fight or flight mode
and we're hacking our own dopamine
secretion. Why do people go to scary
movies? You might ask to be scared. No,
they go to scary movies because it says
it's very Meta. You know, you're fine,
but you also are tricking
yourself into being scared.
But because you know you're fine,
then it's okay to be scared
cause then it's exciting.
Or like roller coasters or skydiving
paying to feel like you're going to die,
but knowing you're not going to dodge,
you can only do that because we're
very Meta and uh, but anyway,
let me tell you how I met Ray Kurzweil.
One more point. The about the casinos.
Like I think that when you put a
casino in a one certain place too,
I think you alter people's behavior when
you let them know that it's like this
one spot way over there and it's only,
that's the only place
you're allowed to gamble.
They just go there and start gambling.
You know,
it's like they feel like
once they got there,
but if you allowed people to
gamble everywhere they are,
I doubt people would probably
wouldn't be as exciting. I'll just,
Marvin fruit is always kind of a,
that is a really interesting,
what'd you call it? The
hedonistic what? Well,
I was talking about he dynamic
Adam Thomas Adaptation.
What happens if you are anything
that's always around becomes invisible.
I gotta remember that phrase because
that's a, that really is what it is. Yeah.
It's a weird,
I've always wondered what that's for.
I guess it's because we're
always trying to push forward.
I think it's our brain's way of saying
that, you know, if tell late me, yeah,
if you don't stimulate me,
I will just make you a Zombie in return.
What do you think the genetic
reason for that is? You know, is it,
is it to push Kenneth Energy
forward to keep frozen, to bleed?
There must be some reason to get you
to continue to expand your sphere of
possibilities. And what is more rewarding
than when you do create something like,
look, you might choose videos.
I'm watching you watching
these videos and you're,
you know, you're, you're,
you get a little charge out of yourself
knowing that early, get off, get off. No,
you, you created something. I mean,
that's one of the best
things that a person can feel
isn't they create something
and somebody likes it. Yeah. You
know, it's really what really a,
it's a cultural equivalent of like
sexual reproduction. This, you know,
spreading the seed. And why, why it's
so hard for men to be monogamous.
Supposedly we'll, because we're wired to
spread the seed to spread information,
genetic information as as wide
across as possible. But guess what?
We've transcended at biological evolution
with culture. So now the seed is with,
you know what they call them,
memes. Mimetic content and
names are like organisms.
They're like sperms.
Their nuggets of information that are
spreading and leaping from brain to brain.
They're alive.
So in a way we no longer need to spread
our seed physiologically really anymore.
We do it culturally do.
I'm trying to,
you know these nuggets I called them
inspired nuggets of techno rapture.
There's just little nuggets.
They just, hopefully we'll do it.
Those are the perfect way to do it because
anybody could send anybody it's know
even if your Internet connection
socks right up really quick.
It's only two minutes long,
right? It's, and it's,
it's the right amount of commitment or
probably just go whoa, but that doesn't,
that require them to remember some
shit that you saw 20 minutes earlier,
you know,
two minutes shots of philosophical
expressive and then you put them on the
Twitter. Right. I logged into,
I registered for Twitter I
think like two years ago.
Oh yeah, yeah. At Jason underscore
silver by the way. But um,
I remember when I first started Twitter,
I didn't understand it because I
thought 140 characters are so limited,
but it actually makes sense in an age
of information when you're saturated and
so much knowledge that it forces you to
be concise so that you can alleviate the
sort of bandwidth,
bandwidth anxiety of being flooded
with just so much information.
People short keep it quick,
Goddamn verbose. You know,
people just ponder on as I do three
hour podcasts, let me tell you.
But that's why we love them. Do that is
part of what we love, but not in writing.
Writing. It's annoying. Why I'm making
me read so much. Well. Yeah. Well that's,
I mean that it comes to
like social interaction.
That's why I made the videos shorts,
because I don't feel entitled
to 30 minutes of People's
time necessarily because
I know that there's a lot of media that
is trying to suck their attention. No,
I feel like he did this perfect. Yeah. Two
minutes is a quick like, you know, it's,
it's a donation and Twitter maybe,
you know,
maybe you could pop it up to
like 200 words or 200 letters.
That would be about it.
It doesn't work on podcasts. I, I used to,
I do a podcast with Ari Shaffir caudle
a one minute podcast and it's just like
pretty much you just say hi and
then you have to say goodbye.
It doesn't work for a podcast. So he did
it on as a podcast. Yeah. Did you really?
Yeah. That's ridiculous. Yeah.
You can't, you couldn't even just
reading Twitter off a podcast,
you can't do that because then it just
say negative shit to get your attention.
Right. You know? We're just trying to
be the loudest, I don't like negativity.
It's very sad. So sad. It is, but is
it natural? Is it important? Is it,
is it necessary for us to appreciate
the good? Do we have to experience this,
this,
the ruin and varies school of thought
that says things only make sense due to
their contrast. You can only
appreciate pleasure if you know pain,
but I don't know, I think we can evolve
past that. I think we can you pleasure.
Just because it's pleasurable and not
need it's opposite. I'm not sure if we'll,
we'll get there. Why not? I hope
while we've gotten, you know,
it's all been positive up to here even
though our of horrific things have
happened along the way. You know,
it's not like the Ganga is con days.
We're doing a little bit better,
much lesser mind, a few choice spots.
Totally on the planet, you know,
unless you're in right now in Syria,
which is a really crazy, you've been
watching this stuff in the news. Yeah.
It's very, very upsetting. What's going
on over there? It's crazy. Um, but um,
I'm hopeful that the world is going to,
well, we'll, we'll get home. We need to,
you know,
the world needs to respond to them.
I'm hopeful we'll move in that direction.
It's fascinating how we're watching these
countries that have been controlling
people through fear, through
dictatorships, military dictatorships,
and we're watching them fold, boom,
boom, boom, just left and right.
And everybody knows and they're all
terrified. Yeah. You know, it's all,
how long can you hold down? How long can
you resist the movement and movement?
You know, that's gonna make you, you're
not going to be a trillionaire anymore,
Mr. Well, people, people,
people will persist and they'll,
there'll be successful. Actually Kurzweil
is also known for predicting the,
so when the Soviet Union would collapse,
did he really accurately, wow. Yeah. Yeah.
You figure it out. Well, because he was,
he saw the exponential growth curves of
information technology and he predicted
that basically the free
flow of information would
eventually be too much for
that insulated. Just put it in a
computer program or say, oh no,
he had predicted it. He, he,
he has an uncanny ability to
make predictions that come true.
It's the reason that he's called
the smartest man since Edison,
by all these people.
And when I met him was because I
did a short on current TV called the
immortalists. What's, what's,
what's focused on just the maverick
techno optimists who were trying to find a
solution to the problem of death. And I
became friends with him and I felt like,
wow,
this is the most brilliant guy and I
want to do everything I can to help push
these ideas forward because these are
the biggest ideas in the history of the
world. And, uh, and then, uh,
I became even friendlier with him because
I also became very good friends with
Barry Ptolemy who directed transcendent
man, the film about Kurzweil. And, uh,
and since then, fucking fell
amazing. Transcendent man is,
I've seen it several times. We'll
do really inspirational. Yeah.
It's a magnificent dock. And, uh, and if
you, you would love Barry, the director,
he's awesome and a shorter one.
And there's a feeling of a labor of
love because what we're doing is we're
evangelizing some ideas that could
transform the human condition and
unfathomably rich ways.
And you know,
you have Kurzweil who's just like what
he's lending us with these ideas and with
his mind is just, there's nothing short
of astonishing. As I was saying earlier,
such a dramatic thing to watch
to his pursuit of this, you know,
his pursuit of enlightening people as
to the consequences and the radical
possibilities that it's, it's such
food for your brain. Yeah. You know,
Kurt's while was one of the, you
know, there's so many on the Internet.
I mean it's, it's, it's a way,
it's an amazing time to influence by
people and to be able to repossess a blog
entries like literally like a day
after something happens. You know,
someone interesting, we'll blog
something and it just, it, I mean,
what a strange time we have.
Totally. It's, this is the strange,
strange time in human history.
We're swimming in it,
we're swimming in it right now. During
this time. The rate of change gets faster.
Evolution is telescoping basically.
So it took a billion years
to get to a certain point.
And then the last hundred years
we've created more change.
So the rate of things change and gets
faster and faster and faster until it's no
longer even quantifiable until we kind
of like merge with our technology.
Ever get recruited to speak at one of
those 2012 conferences. I'll do it.
I just spoke at digital life
design in Munich, which is like,
it's a super kind of technology futurism
invite only event. It was awesome.
Like Yoko Ono spoke and wow.
Sheryl Sandberg,
the president of Facebook's about Yoko
Ono spoke. Yeah, there's a lot of like,
I dunno what she spoke about it Mr. Todd,
but I'll show you.
She used to fuck a famous
guy. There you go. No,
but that was actually my video was
shown at the Economist magazine Ideas
Festival.
Oh Wow.
So you can imagine when you have
like a crowd of like the economist,
then you're showing them these
videos and then you know,
the best part they got it,
dude.
They didn't think that I was just like
some crazy hippies spewing forth these
ideas.
Rhapsodic they totally get it.
And I spoke at the singularity
summit incidentally,
which is the conference that's all
about the technological singularity.
And I spoke about the importance of art
design and aesthetics to come make stick
to sort of transmit with these ideas
because people only respond to what moves
them. You know, can only show them so
many graphs before they fall asleep.
But if you inspire them,
if you epiphany's him,
if you give somebody the goosebumps,
they'll remember it and I showed
the videos and sure enough,
like people really seem to respond
to them. So they're definitely,
it's creating a kind of,
I'm hopeful.
I think I'm going to be speaking at
Google in March actually as well.
A friend and friend to setting that up.
Let's Yoko Ono. Like I didn't meet her,
she was speaking in the other
atrium at the same time as me.
She was my competition.
Does she speak and Larry inside of a bed?
Like did they just like roll a bed up onto
stage and she says [inaudible] Graham,
John Lennon in there,
whether it's just like young John
Lennon and now today you'll call.
No, it's just a fucking tricky. It's
really, really darkly lit and they sing.
Imagine, would you fuck Yoko Ono? No.
She had an art exhibit that I
went to when I lived in Boston.
It was really bizarre. It was one
of the strangest art exhibits ever.
And one of the things she had was a block
of wood with a bunch of nails in it.
And uh,
there was a hammer and a box of nails
there and she encouraged people to pick up
the nails and contribute to the art.
Wow.
And she said that that's how she wanted
people to be enthusiastic about our art
by letting them contribute. And my joke
was, take the nail, putting your forehead.
I'd be a line around
the block. I'm, no, no,
nobody's probably going to hit the nail.
But it'd be interesting to watch,
you know,
if there was just her standing there with
the nail in her forehead and she left
a hammer there. Most, most people are not
going to kill you, but you never know,
man. You never know, John. That would
be an interesting art piece, you know,
that'd be a pretty fucking crazy thing
to do. Anybody please steal this idea.
Yeah,
and everybody else,
please don't hit him in the head
with a hammer that's fucked up.
You know what's interesting about art?
I always think the kind of
art I'm interested in is
that the art that is there
to kind of move me in some way. You
know, there was a great notion of,
do you ever notice why beauty? Sometimes
it makes you sad like true beauty,
like something really
rapturously beautiful.
Well I'm a man so that doesn't happen.
I'll get sad.
I'll cure like strip strip
clubs like [inaudible]. No,
I'm talking about sunset
something sublime.
That doesn't make me sad.
I look at true beauty like a,
like a magnificent gift to the universe.
So that's, that's what I give it to.
But you know why it sometimes makes
me sad is because they say that Alan
[inaudible] says that the reason
it makes sense because the beauty,
what beauty hints at is
at times the exception.
So it reminds us of a lot of the
mediocrity that surrounds us.
And then we're like sad because we see
a glimpse of the ideal and mankind has
been obsessed with the ideal ever since.
You know,
we started making the Greek statues of
David back in the day and that's all well
and good until you start getting gray
hair on your balls and then you know,
you start appreciating things
cause you will as the end is near.
Oh so sad. Right? It's just life.
No, I know. [inaudible] I appreciate,
I do not get sad when I see
beautiful things ever. Just entropy.
I love [inaudible]. I love it.
I love beautiful things too.
But he gets out a little bit.
Well I, they, beauty moves me.
Do you ever have sore
nipples when you see,
if you see like once a month it gets
sore and I'm just being completely
ridiculous. I'm sorry, I'm just trying to
be funny. Maybe. Maybe it's a Latin thing.
Comedians sometimes. Do you dye
your pubes show? No. Why? Why not?
Ship them off? Yeah. They're
only on the, on the sac.
The SAC is the only the gravy ones in the
bushes. All black. A jungle. Dark, sad.
Okay. So it's scary. See, it's telling
me in the box, I need to see your,
the documentary fear spirit. You say
that right there, man. You need to pause.
I'm talking about my boss.
Like I need to see your
40 and shit right there.
Sign. I didn't have to phrase
that like that. That's like,
that's like, that's almost in the same
category as making somebody flinch.
You're obviously not used to doing the
stupid show like this. No, I'm kidding.
This is amazing, man. Amazing having you
on, man. You're blowing people's minds.
Hey, you didn't pause enough. First thing
that either Joe, what happened blowing,
blowing or you're right. Very
good point. Very good point.
Um, anyway, you were saying
something about your documentary,
the spirit molecule. The dog
wasn't mine. All I did was I was,
I was like the rod sterling
of it and you know,
it's just all the stuff that they wanted.
I was,
it was an honor just to do it for him.
It's a,
my friend Mitch Schultz who did it
was really, uh, a very illuminating
documentary called Dmt, the
spirit molecule. A lot of
like really interesting,
intelligent and brilliant people who
have had DMT experiences and the time
that's available. I'm pretty sure
it's on iTunes. I know it's online.
You can find it. Google it by. It's really
good. You'll love it. Very cool. Yeah,
it's a fascinating, um, thing that there's
some sort of a chemical that you, human,
the human mind makes. It's the most
intense psychedelic known demand.
It's really weird.
You know,
it makes you ask all these questions and
why it evolved because there's a reason
that
when you were talking earlier about
the idea of engineering states of
consciousness that we're going to be able
to engineer a state of complete total
bliss. Totally. You know,
the idea that you're going to have a
DMT button on the end of your fucking
key chain is pressing
Du du, Du, Du, Du, Du,
Du Phil.
He is going into some fucking crazy
spiral of going to be like with no
boundaries. You imagine if we were,
but that's all anyone's going to do.
I'm just going to DMT
trip all that. Yeah. Well,
there was an article in wired recently
about an Djs using nanoparticles in the
future to get the audience like
literally. Hi. Wow, that's incredible.
Instead of using chemical
technology, electronic technology.
Oh, D people, man. Well,
I don't think [inaudible] o d people.
The song was so good. It made someone
to have a fucking heart attack.
Jim [inaudible].
Well, yeah, but then what? That nobody
would want to go. If that happens,
people will go for the ecstatic.
Yeah. There's a few policies. You
can't make it. She can't run up hill.
That sounds, yeah, that sounds ridiculous,
but the, the idea of nanoparticles.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
We'll like in your change the way you
think and chicken as a whole row of people
change the reality.
Yeah.
Did you must get crazy managing.
We're going down the rabbit hole for sure.
Which is this,
what if this is the future?
We all go into a gigantic airplane
warehouse, right? Like an airplane hangar.
They closed the doors,
they hit the button,
the nanoparticles come out and
all of a sudden we're in Avatar.
Yeah. We're flying through space ships
and shit. All of this is taking place.
We're just standing there. We
were in real life, real life.
We're just standing there. Why wouldn't
you? That's exactly what we engineers,
your entire imagination creates an
image that it is uploaded to your
consciousness and everybody experiences
it totally and that move around in it
and like reality. You can change it.
Yeah, you can change it and alter it.
Exactly. Dude. We're
all be world builders.
You can use imagination inside that
world because if you think about it,
that's already the world that we live in.
It just has taken longer to execute it
because somebody thought of an airplane
and then they imagined themselves flying
on the airplane and then they built the
airplane and then it worked and
then they flew in. Today we all fly.
It's just that because it
took 40 50 60 70 years,
it doesn't feel like we just
created the world that we live in,
but we didn't just create, we
literally just created it. I mean,
that's the craziest part of all that.
That's not a metaphor.
That's not an exaggeration.
We live inside of worlds that we have
created and yet we're still a part of this
gigantic thing, this planet, you know,
we're still a part of this hive of
organisms. How did we come about?
How did we emerge so prominently? I
mean, I know there's a lot of theories,
but what do you subscribe to? The stoned
ape theory? Do you have your own theory?
No, I think, I mean, you
know, it's difficult to prove
right, but I definitely,
I find it the most captivating account
and makes sense to me based on every very
captivating people don't know. Explain
to people what the theory is. Yeah. Well,
the stoned ape hypothesis basically
tries to explain at one point sort of
language emerged,
you know,
from a species that couldn't speak to a
species that could change the operating
system of the brain.
It's referred to as the first singularity
and Terence Mckenna says that this
occurred when early hominids left the
jungle for the Savannah's and in the
savannahs their diets change and they
were ruffling around for whatever they
could find to eat and the magic mushrooms
that were growing in the cow dung or
yeah, those were psychedelic. And
so when they started taking them,
they wouldn't have been able to make
sense of the synesthetic experience that
ensued because the magic mushrooms,
because synesthesia among their,
their hallucinatory qualities,
which means a blurring of the census.
And wasn't there something
about it increasing the
size of the human brain over
a period of like he talks about and then
food in the gut and brain size. Is that,
how real is that?
I believe so.
I mean there's an account of it and food
of the gods of how it literally changed
the structure of the brain.
But I think the most compelling kind of
like visual is when he says psychedelics
can be synesthetic and that
means seeing sounds hearing site.
We talked about this, right? And that's
what language is. Language is psychedelic.
Yeah,
it is.
I send images wirelessly into
your head by making vocal sounds.
I mean, I mean that's like, that's
like I'm, I'm already a cell phone.
I send thoughts to you telepathically
into your head. I mean,
so it's like where did that arise from?
And so it's an theory. It's definitely
like,
whoa dude.
Like it's not really well accepted
in the scientific community.
No rock.
And really it's a little too silly.
I mean I brought it up to people and
they've gotten that upset at me for it.
Preposterous. It was the idea that
it's a wonderful mythology though.
It's beautiful. It's, if it
was true, it'd be awesome.
And the thing that really
hits people about it as,
even though you know it's probably at
this point in time unprovable but hits
people about it is the profundity, is
that a word of the psychedelic experience?
The first time you ever have a mushroom
experience and you realize like,
well you're dealing with is so profound
and so powerful and so impactful.
Who's to say that if you didn't eat this
everyday wouldn't make your brain grow
bigger? It really seems like it might not
to mention that man has had a symbiotic
relationship with these plants for its
entire, for the, for our entire history.
I mean,
you know Francis Crick who discovered
the DML is said to have experimented with
LSD.
Like I said,
well also said to have come up with the
idea of the double helix while he was on
Lsd.
Okay.
But that could have be horseshit because
it was like after he was already dead
and it was like one of
those deathbed confessions,
it could have been that his friends
just really into acid does like,
I'm just going to fuck up everybody
by telling everybody to Francis Crick.
He told me he was on acid when he died.
Maybe it's not the drugs,
it's what drugs could
do to their thinking,
which could have been triggered
by other things as well.
It's a counterintuitive nonlinear
out of the box thinking, you know,
seeing the world in new ways requires
tweaking how you perceive the world will
bomb. Big Part of what the brain
is is it's a chemical reaction.
We know that when you were adding alcohol,
adding anything to that chemical reaction,
right?
It changes the result and the data
that comes in is perceived differently.
Absolutely, and we know that
we can tap into something.
When you give somebody
mushrooms or you get some,
you tap into this incredible blissful
experience and it's akin to a religious
experience.
When we understand the brain perfectly,
we will be able to insert
ourselves into superman.
Like that movie limitless was actually
very prescient because it actually didn't
end with a dystopia warning,
cautionary tale. It was like, no,
he figured it out and he
wins. Yeah, no kidding.
Do you, do you think that any
of this would have taken place,
any of this experimentation,
any of this would've without psychedelics
if there were no psychedelics,
is it possible that that an ape has
become a human and the human has become
almost immortal as well? Listen, here's
what I think. I think that we need
to live inside of minds that can go from
living in caves to flying through the
air and jetliners. We need to be able
to make leaps of thinking of that scale.
But we have to do it in
a compressed timeframe.
It took 150,000 years to go from
caveman to flying and jetliners.
I'm the less it happened. So if you,
if you do, if you look at deep time,
it's only a blink and
the evolutionary scale.
It's less than a blink in less
than a blink of a blink of a blink.
We went from naked monkeys to jetliners
and 1.5 billion minds during their mind
work in a space that is in
space called the Internet.
A blink of a blink of a blink.
So what's to say that the blink
is not going to be equal parts
astonishing and equal parts sort of
transformational dude. Fucking is.
Yeah. You just nailed it. Yeah.
God Damn.
A blink of a blank.
It's so hard to wrap your head on
150,000 years ago we were in caves.
That's insane,
dude.
It's really almost impossible to wrap
your head around how recent that is.
Blink of a blink of a blink of a blink.
So what the fuck happened?
How did we just take off one
like that? Triumph. It's amazing.
Something happened because nothing else
from back then is any different. Right.
Everything else from 150,000 years ago
is the same. Right. And where is it?
Where is this leading fucking
nuts might've such a blank
canvas for us to paint.
That's the hardest thing for
us to wrap our heads around.
Everything else from 150,000 years
ago is the same. Everything is sad.
Orangutans have the same habits.
We just shot away from the
pack and started building shit.
Slingshot can mown down.
Elephants was shot away.
We slingshot clear bombs.
Slingshotting and bootstrapping complexity
builds upon itself and it gets faster
and faster and faster.
Sexting Kim Kardashians show boom.
2012 it's amazing, dude. That's amazing.
It's so freaking fucking exciting.
Yeah,
it is in you're allowed to curse or
you should do is do like a lot of like
citing dude, like it's so
like, it's so, wow. Yeah.
Like it's so, wow. It's so happening
right now. You know, it's, it's,
I think in the future when we look back
on this day and age, you know, with is,
you know,
objectively as we can,
we were caught in a technological
tornado. Oh, you know,
and it's tsunamis happening in a
way that we adapt to it. You know,
people are very adaptive. Totally,
totally. We're awesome at, at, you know,
recognizing our environment has changed
and adjusting. We're really good at that,
but the fact that we're able to do it
with something as mind blowing as the
Internet is really incredible in the fact
that, you know, at this point in time,
you see societies all over
the world trying to be more
and more restrictive when
it comes to the answer to that because
they recognize this is their usurper but
you surfer is not. Yeah,
totally. Rick Santorum. No,
it's the fucking Internet
man. The Internet is going
to take over to the stated.
The nature is what gay people
to get married. I mean,
an organism wants to maintain the
status quo if it has been a successful
organism,
and that is cultural context or certain
businesses or corporations or business
models that have worked for certain
groups of people for a long time.
It's in their interest to want to persist,
but the reality is that we all need to
become cheerleaders for evolution and
that means embracing disruption.
Yeah.
That means also letting
gay people get married.
You fuckheads owe hundred cows in percent,
like 100% like gay marriage should
be 100% legalized everywhere.
Marijuana should be 100% legalized
everywhere this Rick Santorum do.
That's one of the things he stands for.
He doesn't want gay people to be
able to get married. It's like,
what do you fucking care? Well,
that's, that's the caveman mentality.
No, he's scared people. What I wrote
on my Twitter was that the only reason
why anybody would want gay
people who are not married,
either they're dumb or they're secretly
worried that Dick's are delicious.
I think that must be what it is.
I think that's a lot.
They're just worried that if there's
a lot of gay guys around, I'm writing,
you know, there'll be stuck in the
deck. They just don't trust themselves.
They're not that
sure that they're not yet
hit upon and look at that.
Look at a bunch of the behavior.
Yes,
his bone structure of the
way he carries himself.
He can be tricked you get that guy's not
an alpha running around telling people
up.
Okay. I think the biggest,
the biggest rule should be,
you should not be able to impose
your own moral rules on other people.
It's like censoring books or
censoring thought to each his own.
As long as you're not physically
hurting anybody else. If it offends you,
I don't care.
You're free to say whatever you want.
I'm free to say whatever I
want. We respect and tolerate
each other. But you know,
actually Bill Maher said to be tolerant
of intolerance. That's the problem.
That's why moral relativism doesn't
work. That's why you can't just say, oh,
and cultures in the Middle East where
they're stoning women to death. Oh,
that's just a different culture.
We've got to respect it. No,
you don't respect that cause that's
being tolerant of intolerance,
right? Yeah. He's, it has a brilliant, Tim
Harris has a brilliant talk about that.
Yeah, it's, it's, it's,
it's a strange thing, man.
It's a strange thing where people will
embrace this, this notion of fear and of,
of, of someone different
than them enough, you know,
that somehow or another this is going to
erode moral fiber and that your way of
thinking is correct and what these
people want to do that hurts you,
not one iota.
Right.
You're going to somehow another prevent
and do it righteously under the guise of
some fucking book. Right. Like, you know,
I wrote that in like a bunch of
people were saying, you know,
tweeted me back and like, you know, I'm
a Christian and that's, come on man.
Really stop. What do you give a
fuck of some gay dude you, oh,
because I'm a Christian,
because you're Christian,
you care about gay people getting married,
let him do whatever the fuck they want.
It doesn't make your thing any different.
You know, what does this divorce, not
they should, you know, just divorce.
I'll make your shit any weaker. It was
when 60% of the people get divorced,
doesn't it make marriage weaker?
Does it make it look more ridiculous?
You should be upset about that.
It would be,
should be upset about people who get
married that don't really want to get
married and fuck it up for the statistics
of the people that are happily married.
Because when you're happily married,
people always tell you,
you fucking search and then
divorced book loop, Dude.
You know what we should do is
prevent people from getting married,
not stop them from getting married.
Okay,
stop everybody from getting married.
Gay people, straight people, everybody.
Marriage should be illegal, period.
It's not the gay folks. You know?
If we're getting fucked,
they should be able to get fucked too.
That's my attitude.
If we're caught in this ridiculous Mays,
the gay folks should just jump right in
as well and if you want to keep them out
of the gate, it's just cause you're
worried about they're marrying you.
That's what it is.
Specially because at the roots,
like, you know, even Christianity,
it was all about like loving thy
neighbor as you love thyself.
I mean that should be like the only rule.
And you know what that means
is whatever your winks,
your neighbor happy should make you happy.
As long as he's not hurting anyone
else. Right? So, or I fucking
you when you go to get your mail,
that aint cool either.
You know,
it's like you're next to him
in the mailbox and you're
trying to get your mails
and yes, God damn boy,
you know that's not cool. Right?
That's a little uncomfortable.
And he's not really hurting anybody,
but he is making you feel weird. Right?
It shouldn't make you feel weird. But
other than that, what do you give a fuck?
It's just weird. And when I see that and
break that breaks aren't tentorium guy.
One state caucuses in three states, man,
three of them. Colorado was one of them.
Colorado, Missouri, I think Minnesota.
Well, I think that, you know, a friend,
my friend of mine says that evolution
also thrives when there's resistance,
because resistance forces evolution
to figure out a way to transcend that
limitation. So in a way that resistance,
the people wanting to teach creationism,
for example, now resistance, maybe it's
just part of the system because it makes,
it maintains the system to be more robust,
to find ways to transcend that problem so
that we don't get too comfortable ever.
Because there's always those sort of
backwards way of thinking that could very
quickly become cancers and stop the
innovation that we can't let that happen.
Yeah, it's, it's, it's very, it's a
very tricky situation when, you know,
and when you,
I,
the idea of being a Christian
is a beautiful idea if
you look at it in terms of
what the, the, the real teachings of Jesus
where, you know, he was a hippie. Yeah,
absolutely.
It was a kind,
loving hippie who hung out with all
types of awesome people. I mean,
what a great moral example.
Yeah.
But we have to recognize when in 2012 we,
we don't go on what people wrote
down thousands of years ago.
We'd go on what we know today and what
we know today is that there are people
that are just born gay. They just
are. I've met him. You've met him.
There's no fucking denying.
When I,
there was a kid that lived
up the street from me, um,
about 10 years ago and he was
five years old, five years old.
I know this fucking kid was gay.
He was five.
He'd be playing in my yard and he was
like super sweet to me and who would like
to give me hugs and he would like
to talk about like little dogs.
And his mother wanted him
to play football, but he
didn't want to play football,
you know, isn't in it. And His dad would
come over, you know, real, real nice guy.
He's gay now.
Of course he's gay.
He was gay then nobody tricked him into
being gay. He didn't get recruited.
He was born gay. Some people are born
with red hair, some people are born with,
you know,
awesome eyelashes,
[inaudible] human beings.
We should all,
like in Bryce who and what we are.
I mean our differences are what make us
interesting. They should is wonderful.
Like the real issue is some
people are not gay and so they go,
nobody could possibly
like what I don't like,
nobody could possibly really like that.
That's DV and that's disgusting.
And that's not freedom.
That's like authoritarianism.
Well it's a lack of education.
It's a, it's a lack of evolution.
It's a lack of information.
It's,
there's a lot of places in
this world and you know, and,
and thought pockets that are still
backwards. There's still, there's still,
but you think that's sort of a,
an enlightened human values,
like eventually Trump kind of
this negative way of thinking.
I mean if you think about like the,
the, the modern kind of pop culture,
like the mainstream films, the mainstream
media would never, for example,
like embrace creationism. I
mean, you know what I'm saying?
Like I feel like for the most part,
well like I'm saying like you
don't see like movies for example,
coming out like defending creationism.
Well I think someone
could do it really well.
I think if you had some master director,
like some Kubrick type dude
and a a great storyteller,
they could figure out a way to craft
something that would make you think that
intelligent design might be very well
the how the universe ones well it,
but if you do it in as minutes do it.
But if you do it as a poem like
turns Malik's tree of life than,
I mean that's a beautiful poem.
But they're not like making a documentary
looking at the evidence that creation.
No, I meant like a 2001
type movie. Like a movie,
like a piece of fiction thing is we're
all craving transcendence in rapture.
And the thing,
what's most beautiful about this fleeting
ephemeral sensation is that it's a
mystery,
right?
So it's better expressed as a mystery
then to sort of anthropomorphize it and
put in a man's face on it.
And a beard, like fall in
love with the mystery. That's,
you know,
a Carl Sagan.
Why do you have this weird long though
to believe that there's some secrets
written somewhere and this is what the
ancient, I think our yearning for the,
our yearning for the sublime,
we can't avoid it the same way.
The Yearning of Arrows, right? Like it's
just as embedded in us as the sex drive.
Is it, or is it because we know
like in our genes somewhere,
another that we have gone through peaks
and valleys of human behavior and human
culture and that we have had periods of
times where we lost information and did,
you know, lose touch with
our, our, the, the real, uh,
tenants of society and of
loving thy neighbor and all
that stuff. You know, this,
this idea of these secret stories
that we've forgotten. They,
what they represent is,
you know,
cultures that had crashed in universal
archetypes that Joseph Campbell talks
about.
And it's interesting because religion has
become corrupted and institutionalized
in many insects politics.
But there's also a great theory that says
that the origins of religion actually
lie in the use of psychedelics.
Sure.
Even the concept of God seems like a
vision straight out of the psychedelic
experience. If you embrace it
as the metaphor that it is,
which is to say that
something that transcends me,
something is that something that feels
that I'm part of something bigger than I
am and what I would becomes indefinable
you put a symbol on it and okay.
You can call that God.
Like that purple was probably born.
The religious rituals were always,
they,
you know those in native American
Cultures and native cultures that what use
psychedelics and their
religious ceremonies. I mean,
that was a part of it. Yeah.
People would like to dismiss it,
but I don't know anything more powerful
than I've ever experienced in life other
than like tornadoes and shit.
You can't dismiss it.
It's a fact that those things were used
in religious ceremonies is the beginning
of time. I would say an
unbelievable powerful force,
and just because it doesn't rip trees out
of the roots and make fucking cows fly
through the air [inaudible]
yeah, that's my point. You know,
I remember that movie altered states
with William hurt member it. Yeah. Yeah.
That was terrible. We'll try watching
it now. That's unfortunately terrible.
You think it's when you watch it and not,
it doesn't hold up at all.
It was awful. I was shut him.
I like the dialogue a lot though. Really?
Yeah. Well he talks about the self,
the individual mind that contained
some mortality and I'll tell you,
that was cool, but it was just
so, it was, it was just so dated.
It was really weird. It just
didn't seem that good. Huh?
I remember it being a monkey.
It's not that good. Yeah,
that's what I mean. I mean,
this is like, who the fuck
let you do this? Stop. Right.
Why is he running around
everything before that is awesome.
His whole search for the
transcendent than how he,
he has a relationship with
the girl and she says,
even sex as a mystical experience for you.
Yeah.
She says that she feels like she's being
harpooned by some raging monk and the
act of receiving God's so death,
sex and death as the connection to
the divine in me. It's all connected.
The drugs, the sex, the transcendence. Me.
I loved it when it first came out. Yeah,
yeah. Watch it now. It's just,
Whoa, this is fucking terrible.
There's just something
about, they've gotten so much
better at making movies now.
It's really amazing when you
stop and think I'm up to,
there's a piece of evolutionary
evidence right there.
We'll get culture culture from
1950 and culture from today. Watch.
No father knows best or
watching, no. You know,
calling car seven or what was that
fucking show they had? What was that show?
Do you remember? It was like a car 69
where are you? Or something like that.
Car 54 where,
I mean that's,
they had a show about a
fucking guy driving around in
a car who was a cop. Right?
Yeah. It's ridiculous. You know? I
remember they had Bj and the bear.
They had a show about a truck driver with
a chimp, right? Yeah. They had to show,
we've talked about before, if there
with a president that was a champion,
Ecog Mr. Smith or some where it was, yeah,
we've talked about this before. He was,
I must've been so great
at the time traveling.
It's crazy cause no one
remembers this show at all.
And I've tried to find out
youtube and I can't find it.
It's called mistress Samantha and
he just chimpanzee as a president.
He talked and he talked
like Humphrey Bogart thing,
hate bogey and everybody else was a
person. The chimp was just running.
Everyone just acted like that was normal.
Well okay.
Yeah. What is that about? I don't know.
What do you think about people that
say that the human being was actually
created by a genetic intervention from
extra terrestrials we'll at least.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
So 17 sexiest idea of all you can
imagine the planet being seated with the
primordial elements that would
then like immersed, you know,
you just set the emerging conditions
for complex life to emerge for that is
compelling because we are now doing that
with artificial life and with synthetic
life. I mean Craig Venter, when he
created the first synthetic life form,
you know the signature was written in
the DNA like right of his name. So okay,
so now you're creating life.
You know it.
We are doing intelligent design.
Intelligent design is actually
occurring now with synthetic biology.
And so to think that some far
more powerful civilization
might have created the
and seated and terraform the planet is,
I mean,
it's not outside of the
realm of impossibilities.
Certainly a compelling idea.
It's certainly like what we're about to
do. It's more interesting than, you know,
God created the heavens
and seven days it seems.
So unfortunately there's fucking asteroids
and comets out there because if it
wasn't for them, I'd like, we're
definitely going to win this race.
We're going to run this
race with technology.
We're going to pull through eventually
we'll get our shit together.
But that might not be the case.
We might be like on the verge of getting
it all together. No, no. But you know,
Freeman Dyson doesn't have to quote
him again, but he said that, uh,
with synthetic biology
and artificial life,
we're eventually going to
decode the genome of every
living thing on the planet.
And then we'll be able to
actually have with nanotechnology,
the entire biosphere and something
that's, Eh, a few micro grams in weight.
So the whole biosphere
in the palm of our hands,
and then we'll send those biospheres
in the palm of our hands into space.
As you talking about Adam and eve type
shit, sending it into space. The seat.
Well this is what it is. It's an
amazing, amazing, it all comes back.
And then the metaphor sentence, if that's
really what Adam and eve was all about,
that's really what of that's the,
that's the real creation. Holy Shit.
That eventually the intelligent
animal once you know,
becoming sentient and aware of itself
started on a fucking rape and killing
rampage until for the created bombs and
rap music than death metal and then,
and then what? Yeah, and then what, how
do we, how do we get out of this alive?
What's your suggestion?
Well,
I think that that's where the cultural
conversation that is happening, you know,
I think what's really exciting is
that the Internet allows minds to come
together based on shared interests.
And this will mean lol cats fans.
And it will also mean, you know, the
smartest signed, laughed many times.
Me Too. Lol Cat. That's what I'm saying.
I'm saying, I have you, Evan, and hi.
I love a good,
and I know cat and I'm not criticizing it,
but I'm saying the same thing that allows
millions of people to come together
over a shared delight allows also the
smartest scientists and astronomers and
physicists and philosophers and
thinkers around the world collaborate,
cross pollinate, you know all these
minds working together. You know,
it creates something that's greater than
the sum of its individual parts, right?
That's when something transcendent
emerge as you put things together in a
certain way and it leads to
something that's greater,
two plus two equaling five somehow.
Until I'm confident that because of that,
we will find innovative solutions that
help us address all of humanity's grand
challenges and that's,
that's happening secularity you have to
recognize each other as a super organism
first,
right?
We have to recognize each other as we're
all one organ systems thinking. Yeah,
that's the only way to do it.
Separate yourself from the
environment in which your body didn't.
At some point in time,
we're going to have to fix Somalia and
we're going to have to fix, you know,
100% fewer copia.
You look at the percent,
he's fucked up places where people are
starving to death and they're uneducated.
They're totally unacceptable as a human
entity, right? As a single organism.
We have to accept that this is,
we have to reengineer the
situation somehow or another.
And it sounds like eugenics. It sounds
terrible, but that's not what I mean.
I mean with education, love
and food and you know, I mean,
if we can put as much
money into going to war,
why can't these fucking piece companies
come up with some lobbying money?
But imagine if it was because think
about a better is profitable for peace.
If PR piece was more profitable than war.
Good ideas. I've never had it better.
Good ideas have never had it better than
they do to. Absolutely agree on note.
You know,
an idea for an airplane that was a good
idea and an idea on how to build it was
a good idea now. And so
I think that, you know,
maybe we can't articulate
what those ideas are yet,
but we certainly are creating the spaces
in which those ideas are more likely to
emerge than any other time
in human history. And that
is kind of a fact, I think.
Yeah, I don't think anybody's as well
as far as we know about human history,
the only thing that fucks me up when I,
I'm not willing to commit to that is the,
the Egyptian period.
There are some crazy shit going on
in each of those motherfuckers wrong.
They might, they might have been
on this level, on a parallel level,
there was completely different interesting
construction of the hieroglyphs,
the architects and architecture and
engineering of fuck. Well, you know,
eventually they died. You know, the
people that realize the highest heights,
it's very difficult to maintain that
tone for very long. I think there's a,
you know,
there's a certain revolutions per
minute that you have to be hitting as a
society. You have to be really completely
in tuned to hit such high heights.
And you know, you have to be
in tune ethically, morally,
but you're still a human being.
So in,
if that philosophy is not somehow or
another genetically imprinted into the
monkey in time with lack of discipline
and people that aren't going to raising
children, the ideas will be
lost. Well, but now all the,
all the world's ideas and all the
world's information is now digital.
The library of Alexandria. Yeah,
we'll ever lose that library again.
And the Internet is also distributed,
right? It's not a centralized network.
I don't think you can knock down the
ideas ever again that way unless an
asteroid hits theory. Yeah, that's
what I was just about to say. Yeah,
I think we can,
we can lose it all.
We could totally start from
scratch and we may have, you know,
that's the big crush there.
And you look at Egypt, they,
how did they get that far
ahead of everybody else?
That's how nutty thing, man.
I mean, it's almost like a joke, you
know, it's almost like, you know,
you think you understand
history, Tut, ah, look at that.
2,300,000 stones cut
into a perfect pyramid.
Used to be smooth limestone with a golden
cap all made back when there was no
fucking wheel. Good luck. Good luck.
Figured out. Well you know what the,
I guess back then they weren't global.
And so if that limited area was knocked
out, then it affected the whole,
now we're global.
So the only way that the whole thing
could be knocked out is with an asteroid,
not if you kill one pocket or another.
But I think eventually using the someone
real, we've got to go into space.
That's why we gotta go into
space. Yes, for sure. For sure.
Isn't it amazing that someone at one
point in time, what does it ever, it was,
it was Egypt and culture.
2,500 BC. Someone got that
far. Yeah. Isn't it amazing?
It's totally amazing.
Those struck people that don't,
I mean I've never been to Egypt.
I've watched a lot of documentaries.
I did go to the, um, uh,
to Cheech and Eatsa once,
which was maybe not as impressive as
Egypt because of the sheer size of some of
the things. But still pretty
fascinating that this was a,
an ancient culture that existed over a
thousand years ago and they made these
amazing buildings and you're
walking on the ground where they're,
their civilization took place and you
realize that these were like thinking
philosophically, people that thought
about deep things thousands of years ago,
profound thoughts about space.
And I am a nurse and that completely
fascinated by the completely fascinated by
the Mayan culture and the idea that
there's over a thousand Mayan temples just
out there in the jungle that they haven't
even discovered yet. You know, they,
they find these fucking things and they
just start digging into them and they're
like, Holy Shit. But
there'll be in Mexico City,
there'll be like build an apartment,
buildings and someone would go, stop.
We just found the biggest temple in the
history of the Mayan culture, you know,
and they'll find some gigantic fucking
things that are just underground or no,
it's like you've got to wonder
what the hell happened there?
They had achieved this incredible height
as far as their ability to construct
these things at a stone.
And then even before them,
there's somebody called the old Mex. They
don't even know who the fuck they were.
They don't even know what the
language was. They have no idea.
But they have these giant
fat African heads of your,
you know what it shows though,
it shows the tendency towards complexity
and the tendency towards development
and progress that might have been thwarted
by an existential threat or a war or
whatever it is that happened.
But the tendency is there.
So it's this idea that like
life moves towards complexity.
Life is actually anti and tropic and
wants to get more complex, more sublime,
you know, knowledge,
information wants to spread.
Sentients wants to perpetuate itself.
And so I think we're on the best.
We're in the best ride of our, of,
of, of history. I think we're, I mean,
I think they, they got pretty
far, but then they were thwarted.
You're totally right. I
just, I'm a retard. I have to
figure out how it happened.
You know, I'm like, this is what it was.
What, what happened was, you know, I,
I can't even live in the moment
when it comes to this. Yeah, I know.
I'm still trying to pick apart the
formula. How are we, we got to this point,
but this point is the most fascinating
point. If this point existed in the past,
if we were running around like, you
know, I don't think we got arms were, no,
I definitely don't think so.
But if we somehow or another we're
running around like the Romans,
I'm fucking horses and shit and yet nobody
ever figured out how to make a phone
and somebody found some projection thing
and threw up a movie of how we live
right now with cars and shit.
Oh my God.
People are standing in front of a fire
going and do, what the fuck is this way,
way crazier than anything
they could ever imagine.
A time lapse videos of cities at
night. Oh yeah. Because what you see,
it's like one of your videos, there's
that scene in the movie Tron, right?
It says they tried to picture clusters
of information as they flowed through the
computer. What did they look like,
or the circuits like freeways, chips,
motorcycles. And when you look at
a time lapse of a city at night,
you do see it's just particles of light.
It's just information being exchanged,
you know,
especially when it's time lapse.
Then you're going to see the individual
cars, but you just see the light,
the buildings and the light.
It's just information. You know?
It was Dawkins who says,
if you want to understand life,
don't think of oozing gels and
throbbing and throbbing liquids.
Think about information technology.
It's just information being exchanged
all the time. That's all it is.
If you're nursing information,
if you're someone who's flying into La,
I urge you to fly into La at
night, right? Lions, a motherboard,
dude's a motherboard. He can't
believe how right. Wild it looks.
How organized, how planned, how he
never laid a runner, blade runner,
right? You don't, we don't realize
how advanced we are as a society.
I really don't feel you give the full
perspective because of you flying to Los
Angeles and he died and adaptation.
Man,
my friend Larry had a house
up at the top of um, uh,
the Hollywood hills and you would go
into his backyard and it was like the
craziest science fiction movie ever.
Totally believe it was a real view ban
all like Christmas lights all throughout
the, you know, like the whole city
in front of him. And it was amazing.
It was a view that if I would
wonder if I lived there,
if I ever got anything done,
cause I might just get out there every
night and just stare like a fucking month.
You would hope so. But probably after
two weeks he wouldn't even notice it.
I just don't way I would notice it if I
smoke weed there. Well that's out there,
the joint. I'm going to look at
that and go, God damn. There you go.
You just hit the nail on the head.
Yeah.
That would be your way of getting rid
of the hedonic adaptation and returning
luster and wonder through your experience.
Do people always say,
why don't you talk about weeds so much?
Man. It's kind of annoying, you know,
got annoyed when you harp on weeds so
much cause cause it's worth talking about
now when people talk about yoga or people
talk about how much they love their
wine. Oh I love this. 1975
delicious red wine. People wait,
let's move porridge. He can't in
the wrong shit kid. I'll do it.
You can use food to nourish your body.
You can use food to become morbidly obese.
So it's really,
it's not the food's fault how you use it.
Tired of this bullshit society
not catching up. Jason,
how do we get through this?
How do we get through this?
Well,
I mean I guess I'm just trying to make
a contribution when you definitely do on
that. I'm putting forth mimetic
content to inspire people.
I think we do that content.
Never use that word because I love the
word meaningful. I need to, yeah. And uh,
I think that, um, I don't know. I mean,
Timothy Leary,
when he used to call himself
like a standup philosopher
performing philosopher,
it was this idea of embracing pop culture
and competing in the marketplace of
ideas.
So if you think that the marketplace
of ideas could lead us astray,
then contribute better ideas. I
mean, I mean you're, you're doing it.
You have 600,000 mines connected to your
Twitter account. Yeah. That's, I mean,
that's a wonderful opportunity. It's
fun for you to have fun, but also, man,
like you're, you can create waves
of positive, positive change.
One of the things that's amazing is how
nice people are on Twitter. To me, dude,
it's so nice. I very rarely get
Duisburg cable without a cable.
You are tuned into 600,000
mines. Yeah. It's pretty amazing.
Just thinks of amazing.
Yeah, it's an amazing time.
And how many of them were watching this?
It was only like a couple thousand shit.
The ultimately this
would be on the iTunes.
It'll probably be like somewhere around a
half a million. Oh, that'll be fun. Yeah.
Be Fun. Is All of our different
points of distribution.
We have it in unused treme. We put it
on Vimeo. Vimeo is the poem. I mean,
it was great. I loved it for video
quality. Yeah. And, uh, and you know,
we can put long ones on there.
Awesome. No problems then we,
cause Ustream hooks us up.
We have available on Ustream.
And so we have also in straight farm,
it's just make it as easy as possible. I,
I, this is my favorite thing to do. Oh,
you're a podcast pioneer. I mean,
you put it out there. People love,
they love your style. And
it's amazing because, um,
you guys talk about so many
different things, but um, you know,
just as many people that have seen my
videos and it'd be like, oh my God, dude,
you got to do something at Ted. Like
people watch the videos and they're like,
oh my God, dude. Joe Rogan needs to
see this. Like you, that's funny.
This is a symptom of the Kim
Kardashians era. I'm, I'm right there.
I'm part of the problem. Uh,
I don't, I think, yeah, I
think you're doing great. No,
I'm just kidding, man. I'm
a big fan. John. Devork. Uh,
do you know who that guy is?
John seed divorce? No. He's a technology
guy. You know he is Brian, right? Oh yeah.
I know who he is.
He was,
he told me that I have to get Adam Curry
on the podcast because Adam Curry is
the real pod father.
He's the guy who really created,
he's been doing it for awhile. He's the
creator. The creator, right, isn't he?
Didn't he help figuring out how
to make podcasts? I don't know.
I think they're ready to do hers.
Yeah. I don't know why I'm saying this.
I feel like I read that he had something
to do with the actual coding of the
first podcast. Might not. It
might not be true either way.
He's like one of the originators, so
I thought guys from techtv, right.
John Dvorak is the [inaudible]
technology called right now.
He still works with twit and seen
a bunch of his stuff. The podcast,
the podcast allows the technology to
actually get out of the way and what it
does is it frees your mind. Yeah.
That's why technology is psychedelic.
Your mind is free to roam from
600,000 miles to their mind,
to the friends,
their friends' minds and their
friends and minds and they're from it.
You are freed by the podcast, by
the tools. I mean, think about that.
Think about it like how it expands the
reach of each and every one of us and
then it's up to what we say that will
determine the size of the following and
the influence what you say. Sure.
Yeah, and whether you're not, you know,
people want to hear the real
communication, real talk. We have tau.
Don't you think I ain't
got enough bullshit.
People want to hear people really
communicating and it's not enough of that
going respond to authenticity. Yeah.
They respond to authenticity and it's a,
it's a beautiful venue for any comedian
or anybody who's looking to express
himself or someone like you or
anybody that has an idea. It's,
it's the most important thing is
I just got to get this out there.
I don't want to go through all these
different channels to get this out there.
I don't want to get it approved.
What did he say tonight? Well,
I'm going to say this, right.
You know, I think totally,
but you have to thread send it.
All of those rules and limitations
no longer apply and you know,
eventually you'll have more impact in
those like institutionalized forms of
putting things out there or
they won't exist anymore.
Then of course they're not going to exist
anymore. That's, that's inevitable. Yeah.
The form of government that
we enjoy in the future,
we'll have to be Internet based.
There's,
unless there's something else becomes
cooler than the Internet. Nah, dude.
It's going to be like the Libertarian
Utopia is the seasteading institute that's
building those man made islands where
we can have like libertarian utopia is
free of government control.
This has been a mind blowing podcast.
This has been such a treat guys.
I can't tell you how.
Thanks for hooking it up dude.
Brian Hoff's Dui and hooked
it up. Pick it up. Ryan.
Man,
the power
of the Internet. Brian's the
man dude. He's been very,
very fascinating guy of fascinating ideas,
man.
I think you man fucked a lot of
people's head sideways today.
A lot of people are on the
train right now, headed home
from work going, God damn,
she getting out of their car not
knowing what the fuck to think. Yeah,
this is a double listen. Slow it down by
50 yeah, this is one of those podcasts.
We tried to interject some,
some humor in there along the way too,
just to break it up a little
because you are, you are you.
There were so many ideas. You presented
them so well and so quickly, you know,
that was really enjoyable,
man.
You have a really good understanding of
people's attention spans and of being,
you know, enigmatic. And you know
when you're doing these video clips,
it's not just that you have great ideas,
it's that you have great ideas that
you figured out how to say with so much
passionate enthusiasm. Then it becomes
really contagious. And then on top of it,
this is the perfect visuals and it's like
really powerful stuff, man. I'm, I'm,
I'm honored that you came down and dude,
I am honored that you have me do it.
Thank you so much for your generosity
and your, you know what, I'd be like,
that's the thing. This is a
collaborative. It always situation.
I mean we are now helping those ideas
multiple and it's fun for all of us. Yeah.
This is a fun conversation.
I love the fact that I didn't
treat someone like you and
have these crazy talks.
It's just the coolest shit ever.
It's one of the real talk.
It's just one of the coolest things about
the internet and this new world that
we live at. Yeah. So, uh,
thank you very much for coming in here
and if you can catch him on Twitter,
follow him. It's Jason Underscore Silva.
Jason Underscore Silva on Twitter.
And please check out his Vimeo videos.
Just Google Jason Silva, Vimeo.
It's real easy to find and they're fucking
great. And there's how many of them?
28 I think there's like 20 plus videos,
20 plus videos of enlightenment that's
free and available on the Internet.
Got down the world's an
awesome place in 2012. Awesome.
Thank you very much for coming in.
Thank you brother. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you both. Thank
you to the flashlight for
sponsoring our podcast thing.
And please go to Joe
rogan.net/line the link flesh.
It's about flesh, flesh, flesh,
life. If the sex thing that don't
talk about it, man, trust me,
you want to distance yourself from it.
People don't understand. They be hating.
It's very controversial subject, Brian,
go into smell. Don't spread it open.
Don't make them smell it.
If you go to Joe rogan.net,
click on the link for the fleshlight
and enter in the code name Rogan.
You get 15% off. And thank you
to [inaudible] Dot com o n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain.
Somebody actually said this in
one of the message board threads.
I thought it was really funny.
He goes,
if Brian and Joe have been on
Alpha brain for the last year,
how come they don't see him any
smarter? I don't take it anymore. Yeah.
And you know what? I might get
too high before I do this podcast.
I'm gonna tell Ya, there's
is a fine line between, uh,
how I look and how I look. Now. I look at
myself and I'm like, ah, do your highest.
Fuck. That's ridiculous. You should not
be that high. And talking to strangers.
So I apologize for that. Came off
too high, but it wasn't faculty.
It was fantastic. Um, but I take
Alpha brain. I do, I love it.
It's the shit I wouldn't if I, if I didn't
believe in it, I wouldn't support it.
I don't make much money from it.
I do it because I believe
in it and I think it's an
awesome company. I think, uh,
the guy behind it,
my friend Aubrey,
is one of the coolest human being human
beings on the planet and he has only the
best intentions in mind.
And so do we.
So that's why I stand behind these
products and that's why I stand behind the
company. And if I didn't believe in
it, I wouldn't be attached to it.
Go to Joe rogan.net. Click on the link
for Alpha brain entering the code name,
Rogan, and you will get 10% off.
All right, fucking dirty freaks.
This show's over and we'll
be back tomorrow though
with the icehouse chronicles
that you can only get on death squad
top five on iTunes right now bitches.
So go to the iTunes and subscribe to the
death squad is the only way to get the
ice house chronicles through.
Also be a show here tomorrow night
at the Ice House in Pasadena.
Get tickets now.
Ice House comedy.com yeah,
because it's a really intimate setting.
It's only 85 seats,
but the fucking lineup is dynamic.
We got Brian Callin, my boy,
Brian Collin is coming down, one of
my favorite comedians. He's silly.
He's ridiculous onstage.
So much different than his warmongering
side that you see on the podcasts.
Is Fox News represented?
I'd love that dude.
I'm just kidding and I'm not
magical. Magical, brilliant,
brilliant.
Al Madrigal who's also now
have correspondent for the
daily show and I fucking
love him to death.
He's hilarious.
I've been working with al
magical for like over a decade.
I worked with them in San Francisco, in
the old room of carbs, the 150 seater,
their history, Brody, who else
is going to be on a Sarah t,
Jason, Jason Tivo, Sarah Tiana,
and there's a Sam tripling.
He might stop by Room Sam Tripoli as well.
And of course, I'll close the show up.
And so that's it. Um, uh, we'll see
you there. It's only 15 bucks and a,
it's the coolest audience too. It's, we've
got a great vibe there, so that's it.
You fuck with dirty freaks. Thanks
for coming in. Thanks to Jason Silva.
Thanks to the universe for aligning
things in such a prosperous way so that
everyone can be happy in bountiful.
It's the land of the free and this and
this strange world that we live in,
this global universe in 2012.
Right? Awesome. Pre Shiva,
British.