Hey Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
Don't fight over like two and three
pounds.
It's crazy.
I can make the weight different than
MMA.
In that regard.
MMA,
you're dealing with a firm middleweight
to light heavyweight,
which guys jumped back and forth.
You're dealing with 20 fucking pounds.
I mean,
that's madness.
I think there should be more awake
classes.
Yeah,
I've been saying this from the jump.
There should be a weight class every 10
pounds and they're like,
well,
if there's too many champions,
it waters down.
I completely disagree.
You're telling me some of these amazing
fighters that you have that are
superstars,
like a donald cerrone,
like a Diego Sanchez,
like all these different guys,
so it was just so amazing.
Guys that never won a title that are
huge fan favorites,
right?
If you look at all these different guys,
uriah faber and other ones,
you're telling me those guys couldn't
have been champions and you wouldn't
have had even more champions and an even
crazier thing if there were.
If there was a weight class every 10
pounds and a better product,
you're getting better performances
because Donald's not destroying his body
and make 55.
You're not having these monsters make
these weight classes and the actual
world champions.
There's the sponsorship classes.
Two.
Oh six,
two,
two 65.
How dare you?
It's crazy.
It's crazy to to it.
But what's interesting is the best guy
seemed to like flatten out around 2:42.
So my thought is let's make a to 40.
Let's make that heavyweight and then two
to to to 40 to 65 or a little champions
the better or all the way up.
The only time you can't.
It's like a little bit of a problem.
A problem is with Cyborg,
right?
Because she's like,
she goes,
I'll fight anyone at 1:40,
but at 1:40
I heard from my source,
it was a beast for her to get to.
I think she's the 1:45
pound invicta champion.
They have a 1:35
in the UFC.
One 45 and I think you can do one for d,
But why do it?
Why make her make it?
She's the 1:45
pound champ.
I know,
but there's not a lot of all the
superstars at 1:35
can make 1:40
to make him put on 10 pounds.
Ever build it.
They will come.
However,
if I would say right now Mr Rowe
breakdown right now.
You understand she's the invicta
champion,
so she's fighting people in Invicta.
Hey,
yeah,
look,
it's true.
She's better than all of them anyway.
It doesn't matter,
but you shouldn't be forcing her to kill
herself.
When 1:45
is already established.
Weight class.
Misha tate was the 1:45
pound champion.
Strikeforce.
It's good point.
Established way that you would fight or
two w.
it's an established weight class I think
at 1:40
though.
Well listen,
Holly Holmes fought people in boxing as
high as 1:52,
but 1:45
and established way closed.
Sign up the house.
How does Holly Holm Doing Cyborg?
I matched his.
She has the best chance,
right?
Because Cyborg is a ruthless marauder.
She's like a preserve or a tower shoot.
The box style.
Not this last fight.
No more tech related and those hits.
I was like,
Oh shit.
That counter right hand on the counter
right hands now.
So Leslie Hicks,
the mastercard.
Nice hard.
Of course she's mad.
Establish.
She's a beast.
She should be.
She should be celebrating that stuff and
she should.
She should definitely thank the referee.
The referee saved her from herself.
Yes,
but she just so tough fighter.
She's so tough.
She wanted to go out on our shield,
but she was already gone.
She doesn't understand ground and pound.
That shit is ill fate or days.
She was punching him in the face.
She's so much more advanced than anybody
else.
Crazy.
So much more.
And Get up to Perillo.
Well,
she's different than holly completely.
Holly is a counter striker and holly
also had a really brutal knockout in
boxing against a larger woman and have
watched it.
I was like,
whoa.
Is the kind of knock out that you never
really fight that way again because you
realize the consequences now,
like someone gets brutally,
brutally knocked out.
They're aware of that as a consequence
and I think she's become much more of a
defensive minded counter striker,
which was super effective against Rhonda
or better I think for her.
Right.
But it didn't look so good against
Meesha because Misha was fighting super
smart,
but it was also.
Well,
it's also because Meesha doesn't brush
after hiring stanley outside flat.
Amazing blast.
So for whatever reason,
holly didn't fight like herself.
She doesn't like,
it was like pulling the trigger.
She doesn't like to lead to lead and
she's worried about being taken down.
When she got taken down by me,
should we realized why she doesn't like
delete?
Correct.
They should took her down,
beat the shit out of her on the ground,
like destroyed her.
And that second round was on top of,
or most of the rounds just beating her
ass.
And so we knew,
look of me,
she gets her down,
she's fucked.
So then she fights like a,
like a craftsman to third and fourth
round.
She just fights.
Real smarts isn't the outside edges,
those rounds.
And then me,
she's forced to go for broke and the
fifth and Meesha want up taking her out
and choking her out story,
man.
So.
But here's the thing.
Cyborgs way better on the ground.
I mean way better on the ground and
strong way better way,
way better,
way better.
Cyborg wind,
straight Jujitsu competitions.
She is fucking strongest.
Your fucking face.
Suplexes she just made she rampage
dallen bitch.
And she gets on top of you.
Oh my God.
The her grounded pound.
She looks like a panther.
Like she looks like.
It's almost like she was put on earth
for one thing.
Like,
well when she's in that ring,
that cage,
you're just doing shit to.
You beat her.
Yeah.
She's,
she's built herself into that.
Taking so long for her to finally get
her.
Now she's here and everyone's like,
God.
And even when she's here,
man,
they did it in Brazil and they did it at
1:42.
They made her suffer.
I would have my personal choice.
I would have had the first ever 145
pound fight in the UFC.
Led a bunch of people sign up to be who
wants to,
who wants to get in there and he knows
that my man,
but that's the price,
but I think you've got invicta girls
that are agreeing to fight her.
So if you've got invicta girls,
they're agreeing to fight are you're
telling me those girls wouldn't take a
fight in the UFC?
Of course I'm telling no one would care.
Frank doesn't matter.
It's the Cyborg show,
dude.
It's the Cyborg show right now.
This is Mike Tyson versus people that
you don't know and you don't.
It's turning tubs.
Mike Tyson versus Tony tops.
See,
she has a ways to go for.
She's Mike Tyson.
She just got introduced to when you went
to see Mike Tyson versus Tony tubs.
Didn't think Tony tubs.
Gonna win.
I'm a Tony.
You went to see the Mike Tyson shot?
No,
I was there to see Tony Title,
[inaudible] manager.
And they're like,
hey,
we need you to find at 1:45
sidebar,
take Misha.
Misha would take that ticket.
But everyone else like that in a good
move that ain't no.
And listen,
you know,
Cyborg,
like go back to the Gina Carano fight.
Cyborg had problems in that fight so
people don't understand.
Gina Carano had her mounted.
Giancana was a tough fucking girl.
Hottest variable.
They duked it out.
Gina literally was on top of her head
are mounted.
Cyborg wasn't the same sideboard back
then,
but sidebar was way more shredded back
then.
She was,
she was like a bodybuilder man.
She's terrifying.
Like just the physical muscular,
the muscularity and the power that she
had.
There's a picture that I'll never
forget,
man,
is one of,
if I have like a list of all my iconic
memories of photographs in mma,
there's one we're Cyborg is grabbing the
head of Gina Carano.
She's got her fingers out,
she's got an MMA glove on with nail
Polish on,
and she's about to punch her in the
face.
And Gina's phases already fucked up in
cyborgs.
Holding her head.
I'm not sure about.
There it is right there.
Look at that.
Come on son.
That is an iconic photo.
Look at the eyes,
the cold in the background.
It shows the fucked up shit.
Boom.
She goes to sleep and dropping a right
hand on her.
Fucking crushing her.
Feel that bitch.
Yeah,
and this is,
by the way,
the Cyborg,
the Washington,
but look at the muscles on her fucking
shoulder and your arm and the Cyborg you
looking at today.
But Bitch,
the Cyborg,
you're going to say what?
Fuck this Cyborg up for sure.
She's better now.
She's.
She's fucking dedicated,
man.
Just doing the damn thing.