Ah,
the Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight.
Got a fun new way to say that, Brian.
I can't keep saying it that way. Back.
This last slide is our sponsored.
Okay. This is the deal folks.
It's been very controversial,
but they've been with us since
the beginning and we are, uh,
we are anything if loyal or loyal,
if anything, loyal. If anything,
we're loyal people.
They've always been our sponsor.
And even though it's a
controversial subject, we,
Brian and I both feel the controversy
is very silly. What's the controversy?
Controversy is being sponsored.
That's Ari Shaffir lays gem and are the
great.com being sponsored by a sex toy
that it's, it's stupid. It's ridiculous.
But I have to show is nonsense.
This show we're talking about,
we're talking about sex toys.
We're talking about nonsense.
It's not like there's this noble content
that's continuously being brought up on
the show and it doesn't deserve to
be associated with something like a
masturbation, do you mean? Right. Does
everybody must have to the fucking girls.
It's so silly to me.
I will never give it up.
I won't give up the flush like, fuck you.
You're ridiculous. They're paying us.
They've always paid us. There's
nothing wrong with what they're doing.
If you think there's something wrong
with what they're doing, you're crazy.
If you don't want to be
associated with them, good.
That means you're a silly person.
You're a silly person. What do you care?
It's nonsense. We are known to have
arguments like that. I'm always like, oh,
let's not even talk.
[inaudible] is ridiculous.
Really pretending that we
don't masturbate. Really?
Why would you not you silly person.
Have you ever pretended to masturbate?
No. When you pretended yeah,
like Ron Masturbate. Yeah.
Who were you trying to fool?
Will Brian,
do you remember the time you were going
to do that fucking movie and I talked to
you out of doing it,
man,
I'm just going to do a film where they
tied him up and a trunk of a car with his
girlfriend and I was like, Yo, you don't
want to have those videos out there,
first of all,
for people to get excited about what?
It's a very specific type
of porn. It's like a, um,
they want to see people that are kidnapped
and they want to see people that are
completely have fantasies of kidnapping
people they don't like maybe. Yeah.
And they don't,
they don't really go through with it,
but they want it like kidnap this guy
front of them, you fucking piece of shit.
I just allow guys to feel like that.
So they make it was going to be a fuck
film with you. Well don't you think of,
that's true. Michael C. Hall was somewhere
like, like shivering, crying, hiding,
you know, the guy that played Dexter
or somebody like that. You know,
all these people that are
serial killers all, yeah.
Do you think that your have
to think about that? That's,
that is a real legit concern.
I mean when you look,
I'm not in any form or any way trying
to say that we should have any,
any kind of censorship in this world,
but the reality is there's people
that watch a show like Dexter and say,
I would like to do that too. Oh, have
you seen my Twitter Avatar, Doug?
I in Kennedy got arrested for doing the
exact same fucking three's company to
[inaudible] the guy even
filming the people in the
doing completely Dexter style
and then, oh, they tried to copy
it. Oh, he did do it. He did.
He was inspired by Dexter, so he went out
and killed a bunch of people. Oh really?
Yeah. I tried to kill some bad people. If
you see my Avatar, what's your Twitter?
You would probably get really mad
at me if you saw my Twitter avatar.
Right Brian, where they were
going to keep fucking this thing.
What we're thinking of bucket fucking
this thing or is it just a film? No, no.
They were just going to kidnap
us and like tie us up and,
and then like going to do it for
money. Yeah. It's acting. Yeah.
Was actually seen that picture before.
Yeah. My heart's torn out and that,
that's like gory. You know,
there's blood dripping down my face
picture forever. Yeah,
it's gross. You should, uh,
you should be careful of those
things. It's, I mean, look,
it is what it is. I mean,
you're expressing yourself.
You feel the need to express yourself
getting murdered? Go ahead. Oh,
that's what I think.
There's a little something creepy about
putting out videos of you getting tied
up in your fucking truck.
Cause it might 99.9% of the people.
You're absolutely right.
That's nothing that's not going
to trigger anything weird.
But there's that one 10th of 1%
that just sees that and just thinks,
I would like to fucking do that to him.
Yeah.
Well I'm glad you talked me out of it so
I could torture my fleshlight like the
one that killed the president
cause of taxi driver. Exactly.
You can't really worry too much
about crazy flux flashlights.
A hell of a product. Torture you to
fleshlight fucking strangle that.
It was just before fuck stress. That
was the best fleshlight commercial ever.
If you're going to Joe rogan.net,
click on the fleshlight link,
entering the code name Brogan, you will
get 15% off. How's that flashlights?
Don't have hearts. They'd tell him, but
don't be mean to fuck it all. It's just,
it's a spiritual thing because people
that are mean to them and that's what I
get off on punching it.
We're also brought to you by
[inaudible] Dot com o n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain, the cognitive
enhancing supplement, new mood,
the five serotonin enhancing supplement.
We also have shroom tech,
sport and immune.
One of them is great for endurance.
The other one is a little pumped
me up for your immune system.
It's all explained on on a.com it's all
stuff that I use and we use and it's all
right. Now, today is
Monday is the last day,
March 19th until midnight.
It's 35% off.
If you just have a
single 30 count bottles,
if you just use the code on it
or excuse me, try it, try it.
So if you use the code t r y, I t just
today, if you're listening on Ustream,
iTunes, people probably mess this,
but there's always 10% off every,
every order.
You can always use the code named Rogan
and get 10% off and we stand by all this
stuff. And it's also 100% money back
guarantee on the first count of pills.
So if you buy like a 30 count bottle,
it's a 100% money back guarantee.
You don't have to return the product.
If you don't like it,
you just say you get your money back.
We are,
the most important thing is we are much
more concerned with not having a bunch
of people that feel like
they got ripped off.
Much more concerned with
that then with making money.
And it's all products that
I use and I believe in,
I've been a fan of nootropics and
vitamins and minerals for a long time.
And if you're interested in nootropics,
it's an o, o, t, r, O, p, I,
C S. And they're essentially nutrients
that a stimulate brain function.
They stimulate neurotransmitter's.
It's,
it's all fascinating stuff and it's
very controversial. Uh, but I, uh,
I've been a big supporter
of it for awhile.
So Google that go checkout nootropics,
checkout on it. Oh and and it,
and if you want to buy anything,
use a code name. Rogan,
get yourself 10% off our right
freaks are either great. Is here
my pal Ari Shaffir ready to break shit.
Damn.
That was one of the greatest
[inaudible] wait for that.
I realize that's just music started.
I'm like, Oh, I want to wait for that.
Dan was the coolest shit ever when he
did that in the middle of the fucking,
when he said that, I was like, wow, we
just got the best commercial of all time.
Nick Diaz throws his arms up in the air,
says Joe Rogan got mad at me on
Twitter recently for, for um, for uh,
going against the suspension. We're
talking ill of it. Really the B,
well if folks don't know Nicky has get
suspended or he's in the process of a
hearing right now about
as a use of marijuana,
he only tested positive for
the metabolites in his system.
And I guess what his lawyer is arguing
is that metabolites aren't illegal and
that the marijuana is
illegal and you're not,
you're not allowed to have
marijuana in your system.
But you don't even have a
law firm metabolite. Oh,
I thought it was like
metabolites only remnants.
And the last time he was smoking when
he got those remnants was when he was
legally smoking.
But the state of California,
the metabolite that actually was in
his system is an inert metabolite.
The metabolite that he tested
positive for is not psychoactive. Oh.
So the only thing that he tested positive
for was a non psychoactive cannabinoid.
There's, you know, I don't know
how many cannabinoids, I shouldn't,
I shouldn't talk about this
until I talked to Todd McCarthy.
Just let him smoke pot though.
It's not a performance enhancing
drug and it doesn't hurt the person.
I get in this argument with people. I get
in this argument with people. Um, and um,
a lot of people have been angry at me
about this because I've said that I think
marijuana is a performance enhancing
drug and it is, if you're good,
if you're good with pot, and it is,
if you're good with the martial arts,
it is enhancing it and it's, it's,
it's not necessarily enhancing.
Like you could give it to one guy and his
emotions and his nerves and everything
just because the fact that he's
about to enter into a cage fight.
It might overwhelm him and
he might just lose his shit.
But you could give it to like,
I guarantee you you could give some
weed to Bj Penn and he'd go out and fuck
people up. Yeah, Bj Penn. I don't think
he would have any problem with it.
He's an old gene. You know what I mean?
He's a veteran. You think he'd be better?
I think the Jujitsu, those
guys, those guys. Yeah,
those guys never roll sober.
You got to understand there's a lot
of these guys like high level guys
name any names because some people
don't like people talking about it.
So I'm going to tell.
But high level Jujitsu guys that
you've heard of [inaudible] videos and
everybody like mimics them with their,
their own game.
A lot of those guys smoke weed a lot.
Like,
it's a big picture and they smoke
weed and train. You know, and look,
I always go back to Eddie Bravo,
you know, cause he's my best friend,
but he's also one of the best
Jujitsu instructors in the world.
And I've never seen Eddie do
Jujitsu when he wasn't high.
It sometimes it gets so high, it's
really teaching. It's like any,
but he'll tell you,
he'll tell me that it enhances him.
He'll tell you that it
enhances the sensitivity. It
puts you in the flow better.
It lets you, okay, but so does, so does,
let's just say vitamin B or whatever else.
They're very different though.
Vitamin B is very good as far as
your body's ability to perform. Yes.
But not as far as being able to change
your state. The idea that, well,
the thing about marijuana is it's so,
it's so euphoric and it's
so mind expanding and it's,
it's what it does when you have the fam.
This is by the way, is not for everybody.
Obviously everybody's brain
works in different ways,
but with my personal experience,
I get this wave of understanding when I
get high and that prepares me for things.
Man, that's one of the reasons
why I like to get high.
Before I do big giant shows.
It slows everything down for me.
I played poker tournaments, Huh?
Yeah. Pool is fantastic. Hi.
I play a ball better when
I'm high. I really, yeah.
That's another thing you'll say at a
tournament, you'll see all the poker pros.
You know you're wanting to do their
cars at bricks isn't an enhancer.
It is an enhancer. It just is. Do you
think it affects your judgment though,
to do stuff like, like in Jujitsu, like,
I mean you watch a movie stoned and it,
you might think it's awesome the next day.
You think it sucks.
If you're doing Jujitsu
with somebody or MMA,
maybe you would do something you normally
wouldn't do because you're thinking
something different, you know? Well you
could, but that could lead to Pepsi.
What you're saying is like,
hold on a second, but we,
you're saying is that you
would like make a big mistake.
I think that what makes me stick,
you'd just do something that
you normally wouldn't do.
Well that would be a positive though.
A lot of times.
As long as you're good again,
as long as you're good.
Because if you're a good Jujitsu player,
if you're a good grappler and you have
a fundamental understanding of where
you're supposed to put yourself,
where you're in danger,
where you're not in danger,
what can be done.
You know there's all these
moves tie into each other.
You know when you learn
how to do butterfly hooks,
butterfly hooks, you know, you,
you, you learn how to
manipulate people's bodies,
that that all of a sudden becomes a way
to move people around just like with
your hands. And that adds to all
these other techniques that you do.
So there's like,
there's,
there's like literally in a limitless
number of moves and positions.
I mean there's so many
different variations,
so many different counters
to those variations that you,
if you long as you have
a deep understanding of
positions and as long as you
have a deep understanding of
what's dangerous and what's not,
you're not going to usually put yourself
in a bad spot. He'll occasionally,
if you're training with friends,
you'll like say, can I do,
let me just try to do this
because you won't worry.
Like if you get mounted
or something like that,
you know, you, you know like in a
competition where it's for your life.
Whereas if you were in a fight,
you wouldn't try this position.
But I think that's where
a lot of like new cells,
it helps you like with standard word
helps you riff a little more like let me
try this.
But that can also lead to a bad place
where like my nowhere lock up man all the
time. We all, we both do
it all the time. I mean,
I did it this past week and a couple
of times a, um, it's like 203 fuckups.
It's like plenty of, but when you do a
new shit, when you're doing new shit,
especially like at the Ice House,
I did a lot of new shit this weekend and
you know I'm preparing for this special
in Atlanta,
which by the way,
if you go out of my Twitter feed or go
to Joe rogan.net there's a link for it.
It's war at the Tabernacle on four 20
and I'm going to be filming my special,
she already to sell it one show.
The first show is gone and then the
second one selling fast. So if you,
if you want to get it and I would
love to have you guys come down.
It's going to be a lot of fun. It's
going to be crazy. I'm psyched.
I'm psyched to do it in Atlanta too
cause I haven't been in Atlanta in a long
time. What is a tavern?
Nippon Napal I called
Brian. That's in the video. It is the
terra now. What is it like? What is that
like a nut? Because everyone acts like
bags. Everyone knows what one of those is.
I have never had gotten rid of one. It's
just the name, the tabernacle choir. Yeah.
It's a nice, a nice name for something
for, well, it's like, I don't know.
I mean I should [inaudible].
I feel stupid for not knowing what it
told me. It was the tabernacle buffet,
I would say. Wow. It must be an excellent
buffet. I'm sure it's like it's fuck.
It's like Rolls Royce or something.
You know? It's like some name
a pedia residents are dwelling place.
Wow.
The Tabernacle Hebrew Bro. That's why
I don't, it's English. Your people man.
Yeah. Well that's what he,
the Tabernacle is a, a,
a residence or a dwelling place according
to the Hebrew Torah. Old Testament. See,
it just sounds annoying. Well, I
don't know how that got to Atlanta.
Is there a lot of Jews in Atlanta?
No. Christian started using it.
Is that what it is? Yeah, I guess so.
Maybe that was the English
translation for them. For a hut. Huh?
That's interesting. So
it's just a house. It just,
it's like a super fancy way to
say house tabernacle. Never.
I've never known what that word meant.
So that's where we're at Tabernacle and
it's on four 20 which is just so silly.
We had, it's perfect. It's
so silly. We had to do it.
When you told me you were thinking
about it, I was like, no, dude,
that's probably just do that. No, I'm it.
It costs us extra money to do
it this way because they want,
everybody else wanted to do it the next
month, but I was like, you know what,
it's for 20 it's just so silly.
Yeah, let's just get in there,
get it did film and unformed 20
it's just so perfectly goofy.
You know I, it is. You
know, I mean fucking,
I love how Doug Benson does is for 20
shows four 20 in the afternoon because
look, yes, it's pro posture. It's,
it's silly, but, and we all agree on,
he's cut out everybody,
but it's hardcore
fans. He's getting, you know,
he's getting on up at four 20
in the afternoon on a Sunday.
Hey darn casual Doug Denson fans showing,
do you guys ever have a screen name
that had been there for 20 in it?
No. Dare you. You did. You did.
She ever have one that had 69 in it.
I probably,
I definitely had red band for 2012 brill.
Yeah. No, I never, I never
did AOL or something. Wait,
let me ask you a question though.
Oh, fuck it. No. Ask Wash it.
If it just enhances your, why
should certain those things
being an enhancer. Well,
it's all in.
What does it look?
Doesn't it is a reality is everything
you take is a performance enhancer from
vitamins too. Minerals to
a good diet. Isn't it just
what's harmful for your body?
That's what they started out low trying
to outlaw is what they're trying to do
is to try and stop low
level physical engineering.
And that's what steroids are low.
This low level.
It's inevitable that they're going to
come out with nanobots. It's inevitable.
They're going to have the ability to
literally change your genome. It's,
it's inevitable.
It's Kinda how it's coming.
It's going to have dr and this
deep six nine, here we go.
He was all genome that he a bull's eyes.
Everything might not be in our lifetime.
And I mean, it might be in another
lifetime after, uh, after us,
but some time if you look,
as long as we don't blow ourselves up
or get here will make everything better,
we're going to make things better.
There's no way then there's no,
there's no technological
wall they're going to hit.
These fucking guys are coming up
with incredible discoveries and these
incredible discoveries actually make
those other incredible discoveries easier.
So many,
all the technology essentially
works together as far as
like computer processing
power and as far as knowledge gained and
learned and you build on that instead
of having to Redo those experiments
to get to a certain point,
you're already far,
far along the process.
And then these new minds just add to that.
They're going to figure out a way to
do something that's way crazier than
steroids. They're going to figure
out a way to make doctor Manhattan's,
they're gonna figure out a way to make
giant blue dunes with giant blue dicks.
And I mean it's going to be real. It's
going to be unstoppable. There's no,
once it comes,
once it becomes an actual technology,
once they get over the morals,
then it's only a matter of time.
It's like a hundred years,
is it 200 years?
We will be unrecognizable
200 years from now.
If as long as we stay alive
and keep getting more and more,
we're trying really hard to fuck it up.
We're trying really hard to eat every
fish in the fucking ocean and then throw
all of our shit in there and
plastic will live longer.
They accomplish more
things. Yeah. But we're,
we're trying to still trying to fuck
up the ocean and overcrowd this place.
That's an issue. You know the, you know,
they say you can produce enough food
and like one state of the country you're
going to take like North Carolina,
if you filled North Carolina with farms,
you could produce enough food to feed
the whole world. But I say fuck you.
You know, I say you're crazy.
I think your calculations
suck off.
Yeah.
He could barely have people scratch by
in North Carolina is not that big stupid.
And by the way, those people are
just going to make more people.
And then when are you gonna do you're
gonna move into South Carolina because
they go to and make with,
I'm going to assume,
assuming there was like a line up to
the door North Carolina right now,
I think we're okay and we'll probably
be okay for another generation,
but we're eventually going to reach a
point in time where there's too many
people.
I mean we're okay here in America where
there are certainly not okay in other
parts of the world. Population
bomb, population explosion, right.
Rachel Carson and her husband
wrote books about it. Know,
but that's the number one pop a
problem for our population explodes.
And the Kansas state itself. Yeah. I mean
it has to cause it, it rebuilds the uh,
exponentially and instead of geometric,
so it's not like too this year, two more.
Next year or two more. It's like two then,
then five, then ninth and 20, you know,
20 which just keeps going. Fuck.
So it'll be the last minute.
I'll just go route and we'll just
fill this place up and we'll all just
humongous plague. Yeah. That's
a real issue, right? Yeah.
How do you stop that rain is going
to come, you know, you gotta wonder.
You got to wonder if you
know, human population, uh,
has like a, like a number,
like a cap to keep it at.
I think that's what aids is really a,
it's the plague.
It's all just nature's way
of, um, of balancing it out,
trying to fight it. Well,
how come they play today then?
That doesn't make any sense.
There's way more people,
way more people will weigh less plague.
I think things come up because
of it. Well, I think Sorta,
but we combat that with science doing
nature's way of combating it. Well, we're,
we're greedy bitches.
You want to stay alive off certain
diseases when it's presented with too many
calls. It's like I'm out.
Right? It's all my white blood
cells are gone. Right? Yeah.
Wonder what I mean? Somebody actually
brought that argument up recently.
I forget where it was,
but the idea was that a virus was
actually engineered that viruses and by
nutrition nearby nature to attack
humans keep us us off. Yeah.
Not fucked up. We just have a thousand
words. That's all we got left.
Thousand words.
What does Eddie Murphy movie
making bad moments
doesn't have enough money.
It doesn't have enough money and
another 0% on rotten tomatoes to ah,
just, you can just not make any movies
if you want. What do you have enough?
It's can't be about the money.
It can't be go back to comedy as well.
But that guy was hilarious, so I know
he can do that. We get some moments.
We got to get them on. We'd got to find
him. He doesn't smoke pot kind of. Really?
His brother does. Charlie's smokes weed.
I never smoked with him once he tried it,
I'm sure. Yeah, I'm sure. How do
we think he didn't try and Charlie.
Charlie Murphy gets high as
full. Really? Yeah. He gets high.
He smokes blunts amongst those. Um, those
ones with the tobacco on the outside,
we got high. That was a totally
different high. That's weird.
That's a weird high man.
We were in the back of my tobacco's.
It make sense to leave by the way.
He had his bad. Here's the deal.
You're not supposed to smoke cigar leaves.
You just inhale the puff those,
but they're smoking.
They're inhaling them.
So they're taking these cigar leaves that
you're not supposed to be inhaling in
the first place and they're inhaling
them with their weed. It's craziness.
Like not the way to do it, man. You know,
they like to do those real Philly blunts.
Phillies fucked up like,
give me the worst shit. Just fucked
me up here. These are disgusting.
The idea that you have,
take one of those shoe cigars or suites,
Shitty grandpa cigars and
actually inhale it all my time.
Once in a while you don't do it every day.
I had a couple cigars before.
They were like sweetened cigars.
Have you ever had those reforms?
Swisher sweets.
Grape ones are good. Get a
nice buzz. Offers a guard.
That's what people don't know.
You know,
a lot of people don't know you can
get just as high off a good cigars.
You can off shit for cigarette every
like once every few weeks. You know?
Like when I'm just in
college or when I just start.
It was like when you have one it's like,
Whoa, that's a major bus. Yeah. Yeah.
The real deep tobacco buzz,
like especially real tobacco,
like cigar tobacco. It's
nice. It's a nice feeling.
I mean those dudes aren't doing
that just because it looks cool.
Like they're getting high,
they're getting high from that tobacco,
it's a weird high. You're
getting nasty. Sklar brothers.
I used to smoke before I play basketball
outside in the courts and I got picked
up on, so like, all right,
come on, we're starting.
So I had to like take my last few
puffs of a cigarette and this,
I forget it was Randy or Jason, but
one of them was like, all right,
you have to cut, strip, quit
smoking. I was like, I know,
I know it's bad for your health.
I'm like, I know. And they'll like,
it makes you stank. I'm like, I know,
I know. And like it's not cool. Like,
well that's where you're wrong.
Clearly it's cool.
That's the only reason anyone that's ever
started smoking. It's cool. It's cool.
How's it cool, cool people. That's just
always been a cool thing. It's been an,
I don't give a fuck thing. Yeah. You know,
that's the reason why people smoke
cigarettes cause they don't give a fuck.
I don't give a fuck.
You know,
you see a private investigator and a movie
and he's taken a drag off a cigarette.
That guy doesn't give a fuck,
was not even not, you know,
he's feeding his own monster, feeding
his own monster, but it's cigarette.
It's funny, but actors, it is weird
because he never seen him in movies do it,
but it's only when they're off.
I see a lot of them onset,
you seem to stamp out and I'm trying to
quit and they're always trying to quit
puffing the loss.
They just go until you're ready to quit.
And I quit one of the best attorneys
on a set and everybody's high.
When you get on one of those sets,
everybody's high.
All the writers are high and the
actors getting high directors high.
Those are the real
movies we did me and run.
It's easy to those tiger woods commercials
and so then he left and we had to
keep talking trash, shoretel ourselves.
We play the video game right.
And they were like one,
some beers look okay and they
just started giving us beers.
The production company,
you're talking trash,
whatever and like wanna smoke some
pot and we're like, you better not,
we're not going to get any work done,
but it's very cool. That's awesome.
Yeah. If you're with a good group of
people, man, they want to have fun.
That's the way to have fun.
You know what I mean?
Thinking about how we do the podcast,
you know we get high before
every single one of them.
W W rose doing the ice houses drunk. Yeah.
I brought a bottle of wine last night,
brought a bottle of wine. We're drinking
wine on a paper or plastic cups. I not,
it's fucking great man.
It was decent wine.
Kava Aretas Cabaretta has deli
in Canoga Park that place today,
that Italian place. Holy Shit.
Is that place good? Really? Yeah.
I picked up a bottle of wine
and some sandwiches. Boom.
It's the only place here on the west
coast where you can get like real east
coast Italian food Cabaretta is.
Yeah, it's in, it's in Canoga Park.
It's fuck. Sandwiches
are amazing. They have,
they have a sausage and pepper sub that
I can not not get get it every time.
I always say, well, I'm an
experiment this time. Nope.
I got to get the sausage and pepper
because it's so ridiculous to eat a whole
one. You have to be some kind of massive,
it's ridiculous. It's preposterous.
You have to be some just crazy
glutton to eat a whole one.
I have eaten a whole one, but
that's what I thought. Yeah.
I'm sure you have your own animal
and we took Joe. Really? Yeah.
I've seen you a greasy Tony's,
whatever those places where,
where you've got the garbage pail.
Yeah, whatever it was and I was like,
got the small is way too much for me.
Then you're just killing years. I'm like,
fries please. What's that?
That sub is, Dan was dangerous.
That was like grease utility at Gracie.
That was like liquid death.
Tony died of heart failure at 52 I only
had like seven and I think he was in his
sixties I think it was in his 60.
You might actually even been seven.
He actually looked good for his age.
He looked a lot.
He looked a lot younger than he was.
But yeah, he did die of a heart failure.
It's like 24 when a guy named
Greasy Tony Dies of heart failure.
But I'll tell you what, man, I
always love being around that guy.
We got pictures for years.
Tony's, this was in Tempe, Tempe,
Arizona, right across the street from
the Improv. There was this 24 hour, uh,
Italian joint run by this guy from
Jersey and he was a great old character.
We would just hang out there
after the shows. It was just,
he was sold like cool to
be around like just to,
to to get to hang out with a real
character like that guy, you know,
like you look in the walls was all
the kids pictures when he was young.
Like his sons are all flexible
picture of the Godfather,
a picture of the sign by Sylvester
Stallone and it's like so classic old East
Coast Italian.
It's like just any was so friendly.
It was like such a nice guy that
like you would go there. I was like,
you know like going over your
friend's living room or something.
It just happened to be behind the
counter. He was hugging you and shit.
Crazy. Tony was awesome. What a great
guy. And the food was fucking perfect.
When you're hammered and you coming off
of a two shows at the Tempe Improv. Yeah,
let's go eat.
And you have one of those subs,
those fucking steak subs that he had the
thing called the garbage pail that you
were talking about. What does it weigh?
Four pounds, five pounds? I don't know.
It was ridiculous. Gross and it was
direct. No bullshit. It was close
to two feet long. Let me soak
this an oil before you eat it too.
It was in the oil on not bullshit
and it was at least 18 inches long.
They were fucking huge.
They would cut him in half and
each one of them each half.
Would it look like a big sub?
Yeah. I like this is too much.
That's half is too much and I
would eat the fucker. That shit.
It was like the leg of Esther.
That's pretty much what I was like.
Whenever we order food at a restaurant
and you go first and then the waitress
was like, all right, thank you. And
she'll, she starts to leave you like,
and then no, no, no. That's just for me
to hear. My friends want have to show us.
She was like, what? Famished. I
get famished after shows. You know,
you think about the energy that you
put out when you're on stage, you know,
just focusing and managing everything.
It's a lot of mental energy,
physical energy around. It's
a lot of energy. You know,
it's a big burns, Alana.
Alana, lock on it.
You have to be in shape to do set up to
do it right. I mean everyone, I mean,
you could do it if you're out of shape,
but guarantee you it'd be better if you
were in shape. You know what I mean?
A guy like Ralphy look how much better
would Ralphie may be if he weighed 180
pounds? Yeah. Jesus Christ. I mean, his
timing, the way his brain would work,
the way his body would move.
You know,
it's amazing when I see a guy like you
could definitely a lot more physical.
I think about how many shows he does, how
much energy that is. That's incredible.
What [inaudible] pants sizes.
That's great. Well, yeah.
You had some serious health issues,
right? Yeah. He stopped smoking weed.
He said his doctor told
him to stop smoking.
I don't know if he stopped eating it.
No. His stuff getting it to really, yeah.
He said that's the stuff in there.
Say Goodbye to all that funny shit.
He doesn't mind if it's longer route,
but he, uh, yeah, his immune system's,
I'll shut the hell. Wow. That's
crazy. Yeah, man. He was, um,
obviously you, you cannot get
that bag. He's a Ralphie's. Uh,
even if you don't know Ralphie May,
he's probably about 500 pounds at least.
Right. It is the sweetest guy
in the world. He's so sweet.
That's so worried about him. Does he
sound all we all worry about them? Well,
it's a loses weight. They'll definitely,
it was voice will change for sure.
So having like a British
accent [inaudible] royal.
So you still smoking the
weed? Yeah, he uh, yeah.
I don't know what makes
someone get that big.
I would be out of my out
of school to talk about it.
I don't know if it's biological.
It's,
it seems to me that it's a very
recent phenomenon in human history.
I don't think people got that
big a couple hundred years ago,
is losing weight now. He, he, he got put
true stout, who's big chain pictorial.
Kristen is really fun in New
York comic. Massive. Those, wait,
I have to produce died. It's the same
thing. It's like wake up calls everybody.
Yeah. You know, it's very important.
It's very important to take care of your
fucking body. We're all gonna go man.
But you don't need to go early.
You don't need to go because that's going
to be a terrible feeling to go because
you treated your vehicle like shit.
That's not, that's not what you should do.
It this benefit in DC for
this comic who didn't have,
who had a stroke but
didn't have insurance,
every third common cause like,
Oh this will be for me in six months.
But it's like, it will be, you guys
are all getting fatter. Stop. You know,
and this really brings up a really
interesting point, um, because, um,
the ability when someone is
fucked, when they're, they're done.
When you're paralyzed from the neck down,
he can't move the ability to terminate
their own life and trying to decide like,
you know,
some of them can,
like they can blank and move a cursor
and stuff and they can like write things
like, I want to die. Please kill me. Yeah.
There was a woman who wrote this
article and this woman's name is Allison
Pearson and she wrote this
article about, uh, do any of us,
however ill have the right to die.
And this was her argument.
Her argument was that you just don't have,
it is one of the dumbest fucking,
most simple tin mouth diarrhea
takes on the subject I've ever read.
It's not thoughtful. It's silly. Of
course you have the right to die.
It's your own rights are given to us by
others in order for us to live together.
But it's like you can do whatever she
wants yourself. Yeah, I mean it's,
it's quite, what do you mean? It's
completely preposterous? I mean it's,
it's one of the dumbest arguments
than anyone can ever make.
And it's just a really, so what
she said, well, she saying, well,
she said that I didn't want to read
because it's, it's, it's horrible.
But the point is she contradicted
herself because she had actually written
another one. Um, uh,
another article a couple of years back
where she was praising a woman for
killing her daughter because her daughter
had a fatal disease and she was just
slowly suffering. So the right to kill
others, but not ourselves. It was,
it's preposterous. She also wrote a
really dumb article. We hired her.
She,
she writes for some English
newspaper and she's just ragging Bob,
maybe 24,
seven.
She writes for the any chance he meant
that as a double play on the word rag.
She writes for the Telegraph.
So here's my point. So, um,
the other day I look on my website and
there's a thread says women versus Doug.
Stan hope saga. Oh, what are the fucking
dog to this will be great by the way.
Doug's latest C D is fucking fantastic.
You know, they haven't heard it.
It's great. It has made me like, I, you
know, you know what's great when you,
you know,
you hear a guy and I gotta be honest,
his last one that he did in Norway,
the Oslo one, it wasn't my favorite.
It wasn't my favorite out of his stuff.
And I love Doug. He's fucking awesome.
But this one man,
it's almost like he rebounded from that
one just like with new renewed vigor and
hate and, and just fucking
and attacked. It's great.
It's so good.
Like there's some really fucking
hard laughs in it. Yeah, it's great.
It's one of my favorite standup comedy,
uh, cds in years. It's my favorite.
I think it's my favorite of Doug's. I
think he just, whatever the fuck he did,
whether I, you know, he even talks about
it. Oh, he turned a corner as a person.
He doesn't give a fuck anymore.
It's just trying to have fun.
He's not trying to change
the world. He's, you know,
he thought he was going to try to change
world at one time. I realized, dude, yeah,
he's just here to tell Dick Jokes
and, and, and it's fucking great.
It's great. And so I had, um,
uh, tweeted about it and, uh,
I, it's hard to follow everything
the fuck that's going on on Twitter.
So I didn't see this women
versus Doug Stanhope thing.
So I go to Stan, Stan hope,
read what this woman had wrote and uh,
let me find the exact quote
because it was pretty inflammatory.
Something about, uh, he, um, I think he,
he said that he hopes she gets a cyst
three, right? This, yeah. I mean,
he's just really angry at this
article and you know this,
that's a Stan hope. Does. He gets fired
up and he, you know, he wants to, uh,
figure out some way to, you know,
to turn this rage into comedy. Um,
so, uh, what is his exact quote?
I know shit. I can't
find it. I think he at,
he said that he wished a,
uh,
a cyst on her ovaries or
something like that. Yeah.
I can't even find it. He
might've actually tails, well,
he might have actually taken the
first quote down. Really? Yeah.
I got a lot of flack for it. I don't
know. That doesn't seem like camps.
What was the, what was the thing?
Women against Doug. Stan hope. Yeah.
I can't find it. That's not
backlash. Well, this is what's crazy.
So Doug Stan hope calls her a
cunt and uh, you know, he was, uh,
he said that she was fucking ridiculous
and there's a shit article and it's
about something that is very near and
dear to Doug because that's what his mom
had to do. His mom had to
take her own life. So yeah.
So for [inaudible] from the
Mancho, yes. So for some,
some smug asshole to,
to come.
And you know,
and just pass judgment like this and then
do it with such poor thinking. It just,
it's really poorly written and it reeks
of a mediocre mind. It reeks of an, uh,
someone who is just,
they're not capable of grasping how a
lot of other people are going to see this
and that they don't have enough
perspective to tackle this complex issue.
And that's, it's insulting.
It's insultingly dumb.
And so Stan hope you
know Cheryl Otis Lady.
So her response was to create this women
against Doug stand hope page on fear of
on Facebook and yeah,
women is so it's also on Twitter.
I'm women versus Stan hope on
Twitter and women versus standard.
Why women Facebook exactly
the right to die. Exactly. No,
because cause he asked for assist.
Oh cause he said called her con and
she said he hopes she gets assist.
Can we anyone join? I think
the Fed it ovarian cyst. Yes.
Well that's the problem.
This is what I was gonna say.
The problem is the only people that join
women versus Stan Hall, both on Twitter,
me and on Facebook. Me To join. No,
it's me and all the fucking Stan hope
fans from the rogue and board and all
the people who heard about this.
So they all join.
Nobody's gonna fucking women versus
stint bitch. Get the fuck out of here.
There's a few crazy hookers that are
looking to get mad at any guy who says
anything bad to any of them. Just
hear a quote. Women against so much.
She's always,
sure I'll sign up for a course.
I read one where this one ladies
take on it, you know, massage Dennis,
like standing up like, what are you
fucking talking saying dummy. This is a,
you know, yeah, he made
a personal attack on her,
but that's not the important part.
The important part is,
this is nonsensical argument by a fucking
Dullard saying that really terminally
ill people who are in horrible straits
shouldn't be able to stop their time on
this life.
It's somehow or another what is,
there's some grand plan
that has to pay out.
Is there some pill that you
know about that we know?
Is there some new leaf
that we're going to find?
The Amazon that restores his 80 year old
guy who's paralyzed from the neck down.
Jesus fucking Christ. Bitch, you
don't know what you're talking about.
You're talking nonsense and you shouldn't
be allowed to be in a position where
you have an opinion that can be
expressed and then can influence people.
Fucking stupid for them.
She worked for, yeah,
she works for this fucking newspaper,
man.
This is why I tried to save her telegraph,
arguing with the bullet
and because I'm like,
I don't want this to be about
a female or male at all.
Like I just want you to
know that you're stupid.
So I try not to use gender specific words.
Yeah, this is, uh, it's just, you don't,
you don't have to gender
specific with this lady. I
haven't, I don't think I have,
but unless I called her a bitch.
But the way I say that,
I call them and say that's what
happens with Doug. He was my boss.
It's not his fault, but that's what they
latch onto. I use with my best friends.
I was like, bitch, you crazy. I mean,
I'm not saying she's a bitch as a woman,
but that's what I,
that's what they latch onto.
Why you hate for you to talking about?
Well, because they want to be able to say,
you hate women course I do
worst. The women, I don't hate them, but
as a whole, like they look down on them.
He definitely looked down on them is
I looked down on men too.
There's a lot of men out
there that are pictures.
I run into a lot of very unfortunate men
out there in this world that if I was a
woman, I would be sad if I was a woman and
I wanted to have a real man. Good luck.
Good luck finding one
of those fucking things.
There's like a specific type
of female drunk that I hate,
but there's also a specific type
of mail junk that I hear you, dude.
I would way rather be a guy.
Then B. I think there's way
more women that are cool.
Then there are men that are cool.
It's tuning me.
Douche bags out there that have some
weird chip on their shoulder. You know,
there's some weird need to prove
themselves and this is just too many
aggressively cunty men, you know, I
think there's a lot of country women,
but I think it's way more country men.
He's just fucking people.
There's a lot of guys that
are just going like this,
just their chest and trying to like and
like why, why, why are you fighting?
What are you doing? See never who wants
this to never train. If you just trained,
they would never do that.
You know,
you go to a bunch of guys who are like
Jujitsu guys go out there like the nicest,
most polite people ever. You know, it
can be easier. It's way easier. Stupid.
You know? I realized, you know that
sometimes I used to do this thing,
I don't do it anymore where it's like
you're at a yellow light and trying to
like pause far enough so the car behind
you misses the light and you get to go
through it.
But I'm like,
the amount of energy that takes to do
that would be equal to the amount of
energy to speed up and get the guy in
behind you. The game works either way,
you're trying to accomplish
something total can't move.
It's like you can be nice to still
have the fun of the, of the game. Yeah.
Yeah. I think it's, I think people just
get locked into a wave. It's absolutely,
people get locked into a way of
thing and we get also get locked into
frustration.
Some of the most aggressive people
I've met word the most unsuccessful,
the most frustrated.
The reason why they were just like
constantly involved in conflict.
It's because they were dealing with
a lot of internal conflict and no
confirmation of, of, of anything
good. No confirmation of goodness.
It's from their life.
You know,
there's no confirmation of
them being worth something.
They were always getting dumped
in relationships or you know,
in the middle of fighting with their
boss and just shit on either side. Yeah,
there was always conflict.
And when you're in that situation that
that constant state of that's your norm
of unease comes, you're like your, your
base plan. It's fucking, it's the worst.
It's worst to you around. Yeah.
It's the worst to be around,
but the reality is you and I have it
far easier than the average person.
There was a threat on
the underground give.
I think the average person isn't like
that. I think that's a lot of people,
but the average person. Cool.
You're absolutely right.
But I'm saying the average person is
under a lot more stress. It doesn't,
it seems like standup comics will be
under a lot of stress and we sort of are,
but we're also a different
stress. Yeah. There was,
there was a threat on the underground
talking about Sunday night,
and the guy's like, man,
fucking Sunday night, he just,
some dude just reached out.
He goes, Sunday nights
are depressing, you know?
Do you guys find Sunday depressing
and focking? Everybody's like, yes,
I hate Sunday nights.
I hate going back to work.
It makes me sick and I'm sitting
here, I'm just relaxing. I'm dreading.
I'm dreading that. I got to go to
work in the morning and I'm like, wow,
that's when you really realize how stupid,
lucky we are.
Just stupid.
Lucky to be stand up to me.
I've been stupid lucky across
the board and even fear factor.
I never woke up and was like really
mad that I had to go and make retarded
amounts of money to I.
I do that.
It wasn't my favorite thing to do but I
was never mad at it but the dude's like
stand up or anything like
that will work for the UFC.
It doesn't even feel like a job.
It's something that actually when I'm
like tired and I don't want to go to some
awesome Gig or get on the plane
to go some great place, I'm like,
I have a worse than Ethiopia.
Just like put it out how it
is like a relaxed though.
You're going to complain but keep up,
keep it.
Say it out loud and she put that on your
wall. I have it worse than Ethiopia.
It'll force you to just not be a bitch.
This ice cream is melting.
I have it worse than Ethiopia.
Yeah, there's, I'm like,
let me complain,
but obviously I'm going fine.
It's super easy to get
into a shit mindset.
But the bottom line is
that life is a struggle.
It's a constant struggle
and doing anything.
It's a struggle like we were talking
about and you know, writing new material.
We're both doing that right
now. We're both, you know,
you'd go up but sometimes it
just eats Dick. It's not working.
It's sometimes you don't know where you're
going with something cause it's a new
bed and you're trying,
you try to say it one way and now he
tried another way but then it sort of
diffuses the second part of it and then
you've got to listen to it and go over
it and maybe rewrite it. It's a
weird process. Sometimes you're like,
okay this section just needs work
and then the next time you're like,
it's telling me it's work and
the next time like dammit.
And it's something that is coming. Bits
just show up done. Oh yeah. You know,
sometimes like you get an idea and I
have gotten an idea on the way to a show
and then got to the show and then boom,
the bit was done and it was killer.
It kills like an old bit,
you know,
one of my bits from my Facebook thing
the first time you said it. Yeah.
Which Facebook thing? Wait
a minute, I don't, I'm not
trying, I don't want to run.
One of your drugs are special.
If, if, uh, the premise,
if they had Facebook and
like 1800 hundreds. Oh yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. Um, that one came
out like immediately, like, yeah,
that was that night. It was
theater. I forget what. Yeah. Yeah.
Sometimes that's really fun.
That's a tag though.
That was sort of easy because it was,
the big premise had already been set. Oh,
right. You were saying the whole thing.
Yeah. But um, it's, it's weird, man.
The, the process is so weird the way
the process of creating new stuff,
but it's so exciting too. It just
gets you like real stimulated. Like,
that's my favorite time because it's
the most unsteady time you're going out
there with all these like fucking weak
ass weapons. It's like you're playing,
it's like become a bad motherfucker.
Starcraft or world of Warcraft.
I'm going to Mike Tyson and punch
out and you're like, what the fuck?
It just knocks you out in two shots and
then you quit and then you start all
over again. Yeah. With the new account.
That's a better example. And you're like,
what? Yeah, you're a noob
with shit. We played,
we played the thing.
We have [inaudible] we got to play tiger
woods golf with tiger woods. Right,
right. And he drove it off the tee
wants and he like went into this creek.
He was like, I couldn't clear the
creek. It was like 140 yards. Like yeah,
welcome to regular PR, PR,
PR people. Golf Tiger. Yeah.
I'm just mumbling cause he was like,
that's a regular people do it.
I tried that, I got stuck in like a
right, right there. That's in a skiff.
Worst feeling. And you're on a stage
in the middle of a fucking perfect Joe.
And be like, come on body, stop it.
You're Bonnie. Just hiccups. I don't word.
Oh God damn.
I'm running this whole moment.
I almost did that this week and I paused
myself and it actually made the joke
better. Oh really? I almost fucked
up. I had an almost fuck up where uh,
where was I felt it come out, twist
it. Like why does my tongue this shape?
I paused and extra second that I paused
and extra section after the word after I
got it correct.
And it was like a better pause.
It was chance buy stuff on
accident. Right? Oh. Like I
realized, I was like, Oh yeah,
that gives you more time. This I am saying
something kind of crazy right there.
Maybe it's better to contemplate it
for a moment. Political for you here.
The second step is sometimes you know,
stand up is it's just technical. Yeah.
And you do it in front of
different people. You know,
you got an, that's the only
art form that I know of where
you literally need them to
practice it in front of.
I need, I don't know. I know some of
this stuff is, that's funny. You know,
when I write it, I know some of
the stuff that's going to kill,
but some of the stuff,
every now and then it's some shit that
you didn't even think it was funny.
He thought it was like
laughing and washes.
It could be like the biggest
throwaway to you and it just,
and that's like the
biggest laugh of the job.
Find a lot of times that I'll do certain
jokes that I really enjoy that may or
may not get us bigger laugh,
but I'll do the jokes that get a humongous
laughed and I'm like, yeah, I like it,
but it's not my favorite.
But you guys seem to like it,
so I'll keep that in there.
So you're listening to these
ones that I want to say?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's like a tool.
There's no substitute for fucking
doing it on stage in front of people.
There's no way around it.
So I used to hear about bill Cosby.
Bill Cosby would just write his whole
routine and then just like go on the
tonight show and just do it. Yeah,
he just did it. He would say,
he just knows what funny is it
certain people like us go differently.
I would like to see that dude, if he's in
town, you want to see him with me? Yeah,
I totally, I bet. I bet he
comes to town like once a year.
First Time I tried to leave the day before
he was there and I was really upset.
Yeah.
I like to see him because it's hard when
you hear a lot of the veteran comics
talk about him because he's reached his
deity status and if you can't take it
out on us,
because I remember the one time,
you know obviously George Carlin's one
of the all time greats is no doubt about
it. It's like one of the greatest
comedians at several lives.
But there was a time where he was coming
to the comedy store and he was working
on some new stuff and it was not good his
last or second or maybe third the last
special. But yeah, it was
like, no, it wasn't good. There
was one good bit in there,
their hour and we all kind of sat
around and non and no one wants to say
anything and you know, and maybe you and
I got together and we were like, yes.
It wasn't going private,
it wasn't good.
But meanwhile he's fucking one of
the greatest of all time. But yeah,
you have to say like, I'm
not taking anything away from
his overall achievements.
There's that moment and it really,
the reason was there's a reason for it.
It wasn't that he wasn't
a good comic anymore,
it's that he had an
incredible workload and he's,
he did the Louis C k thing where he's in,
but he was the originator of it.
He would come up with a completely new
act every do it like a dozen or two dozen
special, so credible in his sixties right.
And he was, or was, it was an older, yeah,
and he's writing a whole new
special and performing every year.
It gave me 20 bucks.
I went to,
I went to the deli form
[inaudible] form and I get,
you're getting a ton of books.
I was like, oh, it's on a
house. He goes, yeah, I know.
And I was like,
thank you so much.
You can get 20 bucks from George
Carlin's should a frame that shit.
And I think I needed it.
That's,
I mean that's so courageous
to that he would do that.
That he would go out there
at 20 bucks. No, whatever.
You try out all the new shit bomb
when he could just pull out, you know,
hours of classes. He said that
his workout, he would be like,
I'm not doing the old stuff. Don't, don't
ask for it. I'm not going to do it. Yeah,
here we go. Yeah. That's how he had to
do it. Amazing. It's amazing. Really.
It's hard to put yourself in that
position, but if you do it enough,
practice enough, probably just
the same thing as working out.
You get to a place with like happier
that you just rely on the old
material and you actually just
went through the new stuff. Yeah.
But there's also Gaffigan and I talked
about this and one of the things that he
said was that you gotta have
both. He goes, I, he goes, I'm,
it's really important to me to be
really good to have a good show.
These people are paying a lot of money.
I'm,
I can't just work out in front of
them. And I was like, you're right.
I feel the same way. Like I want
to, I sandwich new jokes in between.
Well that's already known and killers.
That's why I love workout sets at
the store in New York or anywhere.
It's just like, this is just, you
know, it's a fucking Tuesday night.
I want to hear to see anybody.
Don't you think that, you know,
you got to like get there.
The audience is sort of a respect
before you like start doing new shit.
I feel like here's what I'll do.
I know what you mean.
It's like you want to open her, it's
going to get up right away. Opener.
That works for sure.
And find a new one.
I'll find a new one for
this year by not having one.
That'll make me find a new one.
That's a good way to look at it.
But not having a closer that'll force
me to get a closer. But if I do my eh,
whatever and ending and then like,
let me hit you with some great bid,
I know works, then I don't
leave with that feeling of like,
I need something better there. Did
you, uh, get bummed out if people, uh,
send you like shitty messages about your
show on Twitter? No. Thought you sucked.
Because rarely is it super bad.
I'm trying my best with whatever that
new materialists and then it gets better
and better.
So the more and more of it goes,
well maybe then eventually all
you need is just that closer.
But the first 10 is great, you know,
and then it becomes like, so, so yeah,
we've got to do some things, man. Let's
go to Alaska or something like that.
We've got some shit. Your
manager, and I told him, I'd say,
he's going to forget again. So just
Lo, I'm telling you, just look into it.
The longest day of the year she'll press
is Jay as a July 21st to the 23rd. Oh,
can you get shrooms in Alaska?
Fuck.
Of course you can write this the
way he says that. Of course you can.
There's no way that can't be true.
This is the guy who got almost were
arrested at the mall of America. You,
what do you mean to say?
Is this the guy who got led off
by the cops have mall of America?
That's one way of playing
it. But you did get, I don't,
I can't remember the last time the cops
came at mall of America to talk to me.
Yeah,
I'm walking the line better.
Ooh. Did you ride the roller
coaster at the mall of America?
I didn't. It looks Janky and
old. It's like it's like done.
Everything's from like 22 on the side.
The inside rollercoaster.
They have a water ride
to the mall of America.
The biggest mall Edmonton Mall in America.
Edmonton Maltsberger in Canada.
Wow. Yeah. That's the biggest
wall in the world. I think so.
Have the by the top people though.
How does like Dubai,
how they tolerate the fact
that we have the biggest mall?
They must be going crazy.
It's a really,
people driving their cars and
in Dubai like have you seen,
have you seen those photos of just like
Mercedes driving by with a big like lion
arm hanging out?
I haven't seen it.
There's a new show called
the Shahs of sunset.
All Iranian sell the
Persia here? Yeah. Okay.
Can I just say this and you could
disagree with me if you want.
You can put this on the record. I've
got the worst of the whites. Wow.
Persons and our mediums. You
are the Julius Jew of all
types. The way you said it.
The worst. The worst of the whites of all
the ways by Paul said that though you,
you, you so like made a Jewy face. God,
I'm becoming an old man. Oh Man. Set
in his ways. I worry about that man.
I say something like, like someone
will say something. I'm like, why?
What are you saying? I'm like,
what am I god, I'm an old
Guinea. Yeah. Listen to me.
I'm some fucking some old Guinea me.
What?
I was supposed to become the
worst of the worst of the light.
I'll tell you, dad.
Dot. Wurster the whites.
They were fine. They were
having a good time. I mean,
they seem like they were
enthusiastic people. Oh, this
you got think about. Yeah,
there's the show.
They're starting,
their dad's daddy lacks in the fucking
functional working so store that was
handed down to them.
I am listening.
I am all for anybody coming
from somewhere that sucks.
Like I ran and coming to America and
guess what? They're going to have some,
some fucking growing pains. They're
going to have to, I mean, it's not okay.
It's a completely suppress culture.
It's the ones that act overly that both
people are falling for the first time
ever. And like, you know, six generations.
You know what I mean? Think about that.
They come to America over
the last, I mean, look, the,
the whole hostage crisis shit happened
in the Carter administration and then
they stopped calling themselves Iranians,
cause I ain't a Iranian
girlfriend when I was,
she was Iranian then she was Iranian and
then they changed the person and they
change it to Persian.
Why?
Because it got a bad rep fucking nobody
wanted anything to do with Iran. Man.
You don't, you don't know what it was
like at that point. Like when I was,
when she was my girlfriend, this is
what, like my first girlfriend ever.
I was like 11 years old and she was this
girl across the street and I'm fucking
mother. The mother was Iranian, she
was half Iranian and half American.
And the mother tried to stab the
father with a knife while I was there.
The cops got there. It was
like, it's really crazy.
It was a crazy little situation.
She was a really nice girl.
But like they were in like deep turmoil.
Like her,
her family was in detail and
trying to get out. No, no.
I mean like the mother tried to kill the
fucking father with a knife. What? Yeah,
yeah. They got arrested while we were
there. It was really crazy. But, um, the,
um, my point was like, I got to see like,
you know what it's like in
their eyes to have escaped.
I ran and I ran was, you
know, it's, it's, it's,
it's a fucking Dick dictatorship. I
don't give a shit what anybody says. The,
all those voting's and
it's nonsense over there.
There's a reason why everybody erupted
and went fucking crazy after the last
election. There's no real democracy
going on. And I ran. That's great.
Hunting anytime soon, but oh no,
there's not. It's a scary place.
Excuse your behavior when you come
into a comedy club late at night.
I don't know why this place.
Yeah, you know what it is, man.
They're just like the guineas of the
fucking 1930s it's the same thing.
It's so those are the stuck. Most of
the word. Listen, that's my people.
I'm a Jersey Guinea. I was born in
Newark, New Jersey. Man. You know, that's,
that's the, that's the
environment. They're escaping
something that's sucks bad,
you know,
and so it takes him awhile to assimilate
to the greatest culture the world's
ever known. Hello. Welcome to
cafe. It was one time before you,
there's like 5% guys came
into the store late at night.
I would sit in the back row there and
run as AC is working the cover booth.
He was smoking a cigarette in the back
row. It was like one 30 in the morning,
but the Jim Painter,
the door guy was on stage and these
guys come in and smoking a cigarette and
we're like, hey guys, you can't, uh,
Steve said, guys, it's $20 cover.
And they're like, oh, okay. And they
sat there for him and he goes, guys,
it's $20 cover and you can't smoke
in here. You're going to go out.
And they kind of get this look of like,
alright.
And they walked towards the steps,
waited there for like two minutes and
I just go get the fuck out you filthy
Persians. Oh. And they
just started rushing at me.
Steve is holding back their kicks.
They were trying to spit at me a kick.
I'm trying to be cool and just sit there
and their kicks. We're just missing me.
Oh my God, I'm so mad at them. I was
like, get the fuck you're so rich.
You've done nothing. You're all
19. Get the fuck out of here.
So where are they getting their money
from? Others. What does, what does Dan do?
That worked hard because he overcame
that shit you were talking about. Ah,
all they did was inherit them.
This is a problem with a really rich kids.
You know like parents like you little bro.
A lot of parents are rich kids are
not taking care of those kids. Yeah.
Well don't children were black.
I'm working a lot too.
They'll let them wear black on black.
It's like you're a Douche.
Stop looking at your sweater.
Oh yeah. No, this is cool.
You have the gay flag sweater. Yeah.
He sitting on some picture pages.
How could you possibly ask me to
tell them what they're the worst?
They'll worst. What colors
to wear though? What?
It's were black on black now
with three buttons on done.
They're really nice people
and they were black on black.
They would never act like that.
I won't have
you waited for your wife to
yell at you in the back of it.
You're shy in.
My Dad would never tolerate though.
You're going off.
Oh my God, you're so hilarious.
It comes out of him. He said,
I just visited my parents. Maybe that's
all. Maybe if you were a Persian,
you could get away with
saying that. No. Why?
That's going to have
some person's mad at you.
They're going to come to the
show and be less Persian. He,
it's only the ones, you know
what I'm talking about. I
do because, because again,
in your defense, I am McGinney. I'm a Tom,
mostly Italian and I don't like most
Italians. There's a lot on say like, oh,
you're Italian. Oh, you're
a person. You're fine. Yeah.
It was a lot of my life,
but there's just this giant club. I
wouldn't even say it's most, I don't like,
I would say it's 30% Renault, like the
Milton Palestinians, 30% Douche bags.
So they ruin it for everyone.
That's all you think of. Exactly.
And all these goddamn mob movies,
which just pumped those fuck heads up.
It was really dumbed. Fuck titles
them. Do you know who I am?
I'll come back there. I know people
kill yourself. I know people. Oh,
that's horrible.
We stop
it. Get rid of the loan. Let's do this.
Yeah. I wonder how much, um, you know,
they say that the big mob in this country
is the Soviet mob and that they know
how to keep their mouth
shut. Cause the Terry, yeah,
they don't walk around with fucking
giant diamond rings on and they were like
very sophisticated and there
are forms of organized crime.
They're the most dangerous because
they're like the computer dude's Oh yeah.
And the ruthless like, you know, that's
how that's a cold world man. You know?
Then those people went through a lot of
shit that we can't even begin to fathom.
These guys are like, yeah, I pinky off. I
won't even blink. When we were in Japan,
I didn't see any pinkies cut off to
gym now. And everyone wore a black,
a lot of wearing black. Would you yell
at the Japanese? No. Black on black.
On black on black pants and a black
guy.
Black pants and a black shirt. NFC. See
what is wrong with that? First of all,
if you're worn out. Yeah. It's a
little douchey. Black on black,
you know my friend Bud, that's
all he wears. Black on black.
His whole fucking wardrobe is black,
black button down. He has black jeans,
probably a black tee shirt and
black jeans, black sneakers.
This motherfucker has black.
Everything is black car. He's his.
His whole thing is that he only wears
black. I want you to tell about something.
If he does that, because I know what
he's going forward. This is all right.
If he splashes a little bit of
color in there, it would really pop.
Maybe some colorful shoes or some
socks. A, you would never get your car.
Get my car murdered.
What do you mean they got all blacked out?
That's murdered is the matte black
matte. Oh yeah, call it that. Cool.
Matt. He has Matt Gray. Really
bad ass. I was like, damn,
maybe we should do my car on my gt three.
Get it man.
That paint your house that way.
Like Madam Merrill's house. Damn.
You rolling dirty over there?
What are you talking about
it? What does that mean? Oh,
that's what they'd would say about your
house. You'd be like, yeah, we're rolling.
Go. Do you think you think
we're not rolling dirty?
It's weird though, like not shiny is like
in now. People got tired of training.
He's crows. That's why I don't
wash my car. Really? I like shiny.
I like shiny.
You know there's certain cars that look
like space ships to me when they're
shiny. I mean like I saw a
Ferrari yesterday. It was
one of these new four, five,
eight Italians.
They look like,
like it's like something from Battlestar
Galactica. He's got these crazy,
I lights down the sides like
$300,000 that's about the time.
It's a house. It's transportation, but
it's not do it. It's not. It is not.
It's a Goddamn ride.
Everywhere you go.
It's a wild screaming ride that
men makes the most marvelous noise.
It was Italian since they have this
fucking giant engine. It's been amazing.
It's the good part of
Italians and it's like, yeah,
but I'm sure it breaks down like crazy.
My people are not to be trusted
like meticulous. Some things,
they're not good at that.
They're good to the passion.
Did they go to the crazy thing and
impulsive stuff, but it has this noise.
It's kind of drove by and was like,
Whoa,
it's like this wild animal noise,
man. It's just such a beautiful,
like passionate noise, but $300,000
and it looks like a spaceship.
You know, like the cars they're coming
out with today, they, they're, they're,
they're slowly starting to look like what
we thought cars would look like in the
future, you know, for a while
they'd be like, you know,
at Ford Festiva what the fuck is
this? This is not space. This is not,
this is not interesting.
And this is just some shit shitty looking
box that you've created. You know,
the older, older cars and
older, uh, Toyota's and share
bad as mustangs for awhile.
A lot of terrible shapes,
man.
But now they're finally
figuring out a way to like,
make cars look everything except like,
you should look into hybrids.
Yeah. There's still look like
shit. Except those Fiskars.
Have you seen the fiscal Fiskars a die
believe it's a Dutch company and they've
created the first a,
I think they're electrically,
I think one of them may be a hybrid
and one of them is all fully electric,
but they're really cool shapes.
They're really wild looking one,
they have like a sports car version of
it and have like a big like bad ass a Dan
version.
It looks like a almost like a Maserati
or just wait until they get it to about
300 or 400 miles per hour rate.
Miles branch once I get that. Yeah,
they're not quite there yet,
but the real issue with DME is with these
electric cars, it's conflict minerals.
The real issue is there's
only a limited amount. Well,
lithium ion is what you need
to make those batteries.
There's not a lot of that shit around
and you've got to get it in from places
where people work for
slavery. Really? Yeah.
Most of it's coming from the Congo and
isn't that what's in batteries and like
regular batteries? Lithium
Ion, yeah, laptops, everything.
The conflict minerals or
one of the biggest crisis
conflict chargeable. No, the,
the, the idea is they come
from Afghanistan, they come
from Congo places. Yeah,
exactly. Like blood diamonds. Yeah. Well
what, what, what people don't realize,
you know, when you think about,
like you think about a laptop,
there's a gene of things that has to
happen and be put in place in order to
create this laptop and had the very
end of the chain is going to be crazy.
It's going to be harder for
you to wrap your head around.
But the very end of the chain,
the very end is a kid in Africa
sticking a metal rod into the ground and
chipping away rocks. Like
literally they're mining. Really?
That's what they're doing.
Yeah. They're the little kids.
[inaudible] that's some of it's
cold tran for cell phones. Oh,
that's so sad to think about. Are we all
just say we'll put up with that? Well, no,
on our stuff, people are trying
to uh, do things about that.
But first of all to go into the
Congo is very fucking dangerous.
Nobody wants to do that. And you
know, you want to go into Afghanistan,
Jesus Christ.
That's fucking dangerous too.
So it's like you only have
so many different ways of
dealing with the situation
and obviously someone's in control
over these minerals. I don't know.
I don't know what companies
they are specifically,
but I know those companies must be
making ungodly amount of money. I mean,
there's something,
there's,
they estimated that there's more than
$1 trillion in unfound minerals in
Afghanistan. They have discovered
over a trillion in the mountains.
So they've known about this chip away
at the mountains. I don't know. It's,
we'll do, you know, once
they start extracting it,
then it becomes a big issue of
like who's getting this money?
Who's in control of the situation? Who's
in control of this, this piece of land?
It's, it's a, it's a huge,
well, not really. No.
I mean it's a huge factor and the reason
why we're over there and are in, uh,
Afghanistan, the first place
economically, that place is worth,
if the future is in technology and we're,
we're pretty sure it is.
It's not like technology is going to stop.
It's not like we're going to stop evolving
it and we're going to need minerals.
We're going to need these
conflict minerals that are
that. Yeah, it's a big issue.
What do you think of that guy? Shot up?
Pick one reason is doing well, that guy,
I read a whole story about him. If you
don't know who he is, he killed, uh,
I think it was 14 people and be 16, nine,
nine, nine. Nine of them were children.
Their homes. Yeah. Went
into their homes, just gun.
He was a soldier and he was a soldier
that quit his job in 2001 and signed up
for the army after September 11th.
Really? And they felt, Catherine, what,
you don't want to go on this last exactly.
Did it for all the right reasons,
you know,
did it because he wanted to protect
his country and defend his country and
thought, you know, this is my time to
step up and a and contribute to America.
And by all accounts, for the longest
time, it was like the greatest guy.
He was the life of the party. But he
started after his first couple of tours,
we went to Iraq, had been shot
in Iraq. Um, and then, uh,
he did not want to go to Afghanistan,
thought he was going to get a promotion
and he started thought it was going to
get a better job back home
and be able to come back home.
And he was denied that and he knew that
his family is back home. He has
two kids and his, um, his house,
apparently they had to put it up for
sale and the people that went to look at
his house, it was in complete disarray. He
was becoming an alcoholic. He was, yeah.
But look to man that the fucking pressure
of what these guys go through to ask
anyone to do it ever is crazy.
To ask anyone to repeatedly do it over
and over again when they don't want to do
it anymore. It was nuts. I mean this guy
was up until a certain point in time,
a hero and then he became a monster.
Yeah.
The weird thing is people are
sort of like sick sickness.
Like what are we doing with these guys?
And it almost seems as if
we're like apologizing for
his behavior and it's like,
no, what he did was
completely wrong and horrible.
But let's also examine what puts
a guy in this position. Yeah,
it's like a little bit, you're,
you're totally right. It's so complex.
I don't remember. The kid's like, you
fucking piece of shit. You should die.
And he became a piece of shit and he
should die. But how did he become,
we trained at a Taco.
It's horrible that that guy became a piece
of shit and it's horrible that he was
forced into this terrible,
terrible, unspeakable,
unthinkable situation where I've seen
people die. He watched a good friend,
got his leg blown off that day.
Yeah.
He,
he had watched the guy get his leg blown
off that day and then went trunk and
went on a rampage. That's when he lost
his shit. He, you know, the guy was,
he was in trouble,
you know.
And what they're saying is
how they not recognize this,
I think because everybody said trouble
over there. They're all in war.
Suicides are up there though.
Like 80%. It's crazy. More.
Some more soldiers have died.
It at one point in time,
I don't know if it's still the case,
but more soldiers had died from suicide
than had died from combat over there.
Yeah, no, it was in one point in time.
It was suicides and Co. Let me, let me,
it was at least in Afghanistan
at was, so that can't be true. I,
it sounds like it wouldn't be right.
Yeah. I better not have made that up.
So how do I put phrases,
suicides,
suicides, conflict, go for meadow, garden
casualties. I will like that.
That would shock me. Yeah.
It's a way to find out.
Suicide claims more US military
lives than Afghan war. Yup.
Like claims or they've killed more,
more soldiers.
American military personnel are
continuing to take their own lives in
unprecedented numbers as the war in
Afghanistan and that rack drag on by his
late November,
at least 334 members of the armed forces
had committed suicide in 2009 and more
than 319 who were also killed
in Afghanistan or more,
more than the 319 who were killed in
Afghanistan or the 150 who died in Iraq.
Wow. Yeah, but it doesn't
matter. That was at what point?
This is 2000 warheads more had died.
Morehead died by suicide or had no one
had done more soldiers killed themselves
then were killed in combat.
Yes. Wow. Two years in a row.
But that includes like American soldiers
and stuff like still still over here.
It's all American soldiers. Not I'm saying
still people over here or is that Oh,
people over there that were committing
suicide. You know what I mean? Yeah.
Cause it soldiers all Hawaii's period.
It just says American military
personnel that might be a little longer,
but there's still a the over there,
man. I think a lot of them have the,
they have the same styles when they come
back here and go somewhere or if done
post. Yeah, the traumatic stress
on many. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I was,
I was hoping, I didn't
know. That's crazy. Wow.
We listened to this before.
2001 the army rarely suffered.
10 suicides per 100,000 soldiers.
Now the army suicide
rate is 20 per 100,000.
It's higher than the registered
among males. Eight 19 and
29 gender, age bracket.
The highest rate amongst the
general population. Wow. So
look man, it's obviously,
it's fucking terrible over there. And
why? Why is it terrible over there? Oh,
there you go, man. Talking
about, shoot, you don't know.
We'll lose full gum trees.
The birds country and the world.
I don't know. I don't know. I don't
know. I'm asking you. I know what
I read. So what's the problem?
What I read is someone's
doing something really bad.
Why did you see the video
of the first person shooter?
A helmet cam firefight.
Pull that up. It's crazy.
Hell yeah.
Helmet Cam firefight.
They have a video of a dude in
Afghanistan. Oh. And by the way,
I got a message from a guy
on Twitter saying that, uh,
that him and his boys who are over there
in the military in Afghanistan listen
to show all the time. So I want
to say if you're over there, man,
stay safe and get them out of there.
Don't kill yourself.
Get the fuck out of there as quickly
as you can and, uh, you know, Godspeed.
And if you do get home and you
got some shit fucking with you,
apparently they've been doing a lot of
studies on post traumatic stress disorder,
an MDM ey.
So look into that.
Look into if you have post
traumatic stress disorder,
there's a lot of studies now
they're suggesting that you can,
you can get over it much
more effectively with Mtma,
which is ecstasy, ecstasy, or
the street name for it. Yeah.
There's a lot of people that are,
um,
taking ecstasy and they were
administering it to, uh,
soldiers coming back from it. They're
upbeat. Yeah. Wow. Well, you know,
it gives you such a loving feeling that
you can abandon all these terrible,
definitely like if you're
having those feelings,
go seek a therapist because your mind is
sort of messed up a little three and I
pick up those thoughts you got up.
Like let me just do this. Yeah.
And you gotta be real careful about uh,
traumatic brain injuries. You know what,
what a lot of this was another
thing that happened to this guy.
He had a traumatic brain injury,
a truck, a truck accident.
The truck flipped and uh, he had a um, uh,
a significant enough injury that they
called it a traumatic brain injury.
I don't know the extent of it, but I do
know from dealing with fighters, suicide,
no, this is the guy that killed everybody.
Oh, okay. It fucks with your judgment,
unquestionably.
It fucks with your judgment and your
ability can be in as little as a couple
like hard concussions
you just in your life.
A couple can really deteriorate the
suicide that think that concussions can,
can lead you to like unquestionably
brain failures if you don't put the relax
after the well,
especially these guys who have concussions
and then jump right back in the game
and get multiple concussions and the
same day that happens after you shouldn't
even listen to loud music or anything
that you shouldn't watch crazy TV.
You just sit there and read
a book, do nothing. Yeah,
you have to heal up your fucking
brain man. And there's not,
there's not a whole lot of different
things that they can do to help you other
than time. And nootropics too. It's
one of the things they do. They give,
they give them a lot of
different nutrients. Like, um,
Bill Roman [inaudible] has a whole outline
based on that. It's called neuro one.
And this was one of the first
new tropics I ever got into. Um,
no name told us about it. Remember when
we were up in San Francisco? And Alison,
Sarah, no name on the,
uh, Alice morning show,
great radio show that it doesn't exist
anymore. They were awesome together.
Or John, they split. But last time we did
no names when we, when I make
him drink his purse. Yeah.
Um, but my, my point was that he was
working out with this Roman Ascii guy.
Roman house gets suffered a ton of
concussions. He's had many multiple,
multiple concussions and he started,
uh,
looking into a different nutrients
that can within he'd his, uh, his,
his brethren, his recovery, and he
created his own line called neuro one. Oh,
that's cool. I used to take it all
the time before I played video games.
I should take, yeah, I
take it all the time.
That's one of the things that
may have said about Alpha brain.
That's what may hand Miller said. Well,
that's why I knew Alpha brain is legit.
Dude. He goes, I took it and
he goes, I was on fire when
I was playing video games.
I was fucking people up, you know.
But, uh, I take it before I play pool,
I would take Roman Asca Shit. We're going
to ask you stuff. It tastes good too.
It's um, and when we got caught taking
pictures with a BB John With who?
We be Jones, who's BB Jones
Horn store. Really like,
oh that was Grand Koski sorry. Chron.
Koski yeah, I thought there were about,
I don't know what you're talking about.
Bill Romanowski is a different guy. Yeah,
he's a,
he's a famous football player.
I think you said you got Kyle Clark
House cause I just got mixed up. Yeah,
I see what you're saying.
Yeah.
Gronkowski Romanowski I hear you don't
like white people. It's like, yeah,
you gotta have got the worst of the white
stallion. Tend not to do that anymore.
Just tell them not to tell them not
to do black on black. On Black Bud.
Yeah. No Bud never wears anything but
black and he won't listen to you. He's,
he's a dangerous man. You don't
understand. He's the man in black.
You don't get to cast it as a
black American Express card.
I Shit you not because
he loves it that much.
It drives a black Cadillac,
blacked out windows or has it gone?
He's I'm Douche bag either. He's
a nice guy, believe it or not.
And why did you have to do that?
He knows people who are in black ops.
So what I told your life over it.
I Dunno.
It's just a thing man. I Dunno.
Yeah, it's odd. He's an odd dude.
He just decided at one point in time to
wear all black and they never switched
because some people don't like looking
silly man. They don't like looking silly.
Too easy. Yeah. What is it that does
a specific type of black and white?
It's come to you easy. I can't do it
all black all the time. That would be,
it shows come too easy.
What are you just coming
all over yourself?
You know you come a little [inaudible]
it will definitely get on your pants or,
that's a good point man.
I see what you're saying.
Where a lot of white trying
to like hide come essentially.
Have you ever, yeah, you've done it.
You think you're a bit about it. What?
Come on myself where you look down and
you're like, dude, this shirt Scott.
So much come on it a bit about how it
would just wear that shirt outside the
house to door guys. It
happens a lot. Yeah.
If anybody would say what's on your shirt?
I don't even fuck do
you think it is bitch?
It's white and it's crusty and it's
right near my shop. It happens more.
You like
more than like,
I think most people are.
I mean did you feel like it happens more
with you? Like I, I feel like I have.
How often do you jerk it off? I'm out
and I see it more than that. I was like,
you had sex in like a shirt and everybody.
Do you have sex with your clothes on?
No. No, but I definitely
once you take you to,
you should definitely like it's at night.
I'm just like,
oh I gotta wipe this off and I grabbed a
shirt and then forget and then like two
weeks later I pick what you pick up
teachers off the floor. Where though? No,
they float in the air.
Why would you put shoes on
the floor where? I don't know.
See, I think she's one of them. I
think shirts have an hour life kind of.
I think somebody else talked about this
to me once and I totally agree with him
for an hour throw right Jarvis right
jars. Oh, so like if I have a shirt,
like I wear the shirt right now.
If I take it off like in an hour or so
and put it on the floor or whatever,
I think I could still wear it again.
They've only one or two hours.
I wore the same shirt Friday and Saturday
night. T shirt? Yes, but not really.
It was a tee shirt over a flannel or
over a thermal morale though. Yeah.
The reason I did it was because Saturday
night was Fitzsimmons Irish show and
I'm like, I got to wear
green. The green shirt,
you're changed none of the tee shirt I,
I kept on looking at more the thermal
underneath. So the t shirt. Oh no,
that's okay. I just did it. [inaudible]
though. I only had one in a plus.
It's a dope shirt.
Which one?
It's a Brazilian Jujitsu with Gracie
academy and kind of be a degree. You have,
you seen it like in Portuguese and with
that green sign on if the Brazil yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. It's like real
faded. It's this roots of fight line.
They have a whole line of like
you seen Eddie with that, um,
the Bruce Lee Kung Fu
tshirt? I think so. Yeah.
I always loved it because it was like
the name of Bruce Lee's first Kung Fu
school that he had when he
came to America. Oh really?
Yeah, it's really bad ass.
And, and so, uh, I uh,
I went to their website and they
had a bunch of fucking cool shit.
And so I bought this,
uh,
this old school Gracie academy one
and then I got this one on right now.
All the one I'm wearing right now.
So this was a Hixon versus uh,
Kimora or excuse me,
not Hixon Helio Hickson Hickson at the
main guy that the originator, excuse me,
helio a versus a Kimora from 1951.
That's cool.
Gear Gracie, close zero, zero. Yeah.
You had some tap out shit you used to.
Every now and then. And then I, when I,
when I saw a homeless guy wearing a tap
out shirt might be too mainstream now.
I saw a homeless guy in the
Ed hardy shirt. Yeah. Yeah.
Some old guy today cheer me on.
I went through a red light.
They just did this great space coaster.
No,
I thought it was going to look like I'm
taking them out to another dimension I
was going to go through. It's like
yellow. I'm like, Nah, I'll just run this.
When you wearing that sweater that
was wearing this way and he like,
he starts doing this pump
and as I go through he goes,
gets hit the fingers and I was
like, yeah man, here's your text.
It makes you think that
they saw a homeless guys
probably could have been kind
of cool in any other era. Maybe they
might not have been homeless, you know,
maybe if they grew up in
the 60s they would have
skated through and actually
doing that are okay.
It'd be a hundred percent homeless.
There's a lot of people becoming homeless
now though. Man, this is a tricky time.
Is it? There's more homeless
people now. I bet. Yeah.
Well there's actually people that I know
that our homeless like comics and it
kind of creeps me out. I don't want
to say like couch surfing. Yeah.
That's not really homeless.
Not having a house is a little and it
sucks when you have one of those guys that
lives in your house, you'd never going
to get them out. It makes me sad,
especially since a couple of them are
girls and was like, Oh you poor girls.
[inaudible]
oh Brian getting dark on it.
You put that up there on purpose
to hopefully go track cause that's,
that's scary.
That's scary because this couch surfers,
they must have stinky ass pussy.
It's don't you think because they probably
don't want to use the shower as much
cause they don't want to like get
him people's hair and there's,
you know what I mean? They wake up
early and probably go out for the day.
You girls, you're talking.
Yeah. Yeah. People that couch.
I've never had a couch surfer.
I would just imagine that they would want
to leave and get out of your hair and
not really buggy. Okay. So
someone was only crashing couch.
They don't have a bedroom in your house.
You know,
like I've only had people stay at my
house. Well I kind of had my friend John,
he stayed on my couch for a
little bit back in New York.
But the most of the people that
have stayed with me, they had,
they stayed in that extra room.
I was there for a week. Yeah.
Dunkin and Tate lived here. Tate
lived here for months. But it's great.
It's great to,
you know,
if you have a friend who stayed with
you and it's only for a short period of
time, it's cool. You know? Like I loved
having both those guys here. It was fun.
It was cool. You know, just
have a buddy, you come home,
your buddies watching TV at your house.
Well you have a good house for it.
It's nice. It's segmented those
with me when it comes to town. Yeah.
He's a great guy. Smart. Like excited
about it. Yeah, it's fun. Yeah,
it'd be quite a little bit. Bert and Tom
Segura except they have frame release.
You're fucked.
I know.
Like they'd be the Mommy and the
mom and dad and you'd stay out.
So mean, just live with them.
Live with them roommate,
if you could bring to a marriage, it's
up to make it happen. Get to go on.
I have to do is break them up. They're
happily married and shit, but whatever.
They don't even know what's best for them.
I did a podcast with Christina because
it's going to, I thought I lost,
I thought deleted it by accident
before he marked up. Oh,
she's funny as fuck man. That's
Thompson girl, his wife for the, uh,
did you guys kiss? We got an apartment. We
did not kiss. Did you ask her? Smell it.
I did ask her to smell it.
So don't want to talk real
quick. No, no. My finger. Good.
If you do, do you still do that
bit about the doctor, but uh,
getting you checked out. Never made
it. It never made it, you know,
that's why I need to record an album. I
forgot about that. I forgot about that.
Are you, can I tell you, yeah, go for
our, we had this bit where he would, uh,
did you have, was she an attractive
woman? Doctor was an Asian doctor.
Attractive woman.
Doctor was looking at his dick because
he had like some sort of lesion on it.
Something, yeah, something going on.
And he just thought for a second about
grabbing the back of her head while she
was down on our knees looking at us and
he, and then he goes like, oh, you like,
she would be like, oh,
finally a real man. I like,
but I was like, I don't want to
cause you're going to be mad.
But like what if she'd be into it?
We got the opportunity. The problem.
That's what kept Clinton alive during
those fucking leg. The lower house. Yeah.
Just whipping it out. Yeah. How many of
the presidents you think would like that?
You know, there's a, Oh, there's a
book coming out that says Nixon's gay.
Not only is it gay, really did,
they'd name the guy he was gay with.
He had a longterm relationship
with this one man. And he,
he took it with this guy
with him everywhere. There's
a really cute Latino guy.
He took the guy with them everywhere.
That's possible. I totally see that.
She playing him.
I barely remember when Liberace sort of
like it was like he's got aids or no, no,
no, not Liberace. That other guy rock
Hudson. Yeah, and people are like, what?
That's how I remember it.
Was he super good beforehand?
If he's just real handsome. It was a real
handsome movie star, like the, you know,
the early days and I think
people just never believe no.
So there must be God's like that,
like an office to of course.
Just so you just don't want to think
about it because of the times. It's like,
yeah,
they're pretty short nursing.
This guy's pretty sure he's going
on a limb on this Nixon thing,
but George Washington got a lot of
photos of George Washington's leave that
spread it,
spread it
can shared a bed with a
man was common back then.
The rusty trombone common,
now it's called homosexuality.
They were cold as fuck in the Lincoln
was living in a fucking house made out of
sticks. No, that's right.
Built his own fucking house.
Does that much with weather
proofing. Yeah. Well,
if you had a lot to sleep at one
president, who would it be? Clinton.
I bet he knows how to slide deck.
That's good.
He might be willing to bring some girls
in the equation, you know? Listen man,
you could fuck me, but can
we get some girls too? Shit.
I was always attracted
growing up to Andrew Jackson
just because of his hair and
yeah, on the $20 bill, it was kind of
cool. Well, Washington, Tony White teeth,
like these crazy fake teeth.
What do they call it?
Black and we'll have them cops. No, he
had dentures. Oh really? Yeah, they were,
you know, like one of the first early
dentures he had, you know, they,
they didn't take care of their mouths
back then and the people's mouths,
their teeth would run out of their fucking
head. They didn't know anything then.
No, ain't no shit. If
you had appendicitis, you
would just die in bed dead.
No one else in the list.
It comes on within a week.
You're dead. You're not. They,
you know, was witchcraft. Oh,
all these people are allergic to peanuts
and all that, but with, you know,
they just die off. Oh, to our, our art,
our technologies overcome nature's way
of getting rid of those people. I mean,
look, do the meek shall inherit the
earth. I mean that as a quote is,
it sounds silly. It sounds biblical, it
sounds like, oh yeah, sure they will,
but what do you mean physically meek,
but mentally strong,
physically weak,
but able to manifest all sorts of
incredible things out of technology.
That's really what's going
on and in manifesting all
these incredible things out
of technology, they've, the
body has less, less requirements
physically.
So they become meek,
they become meek and their computers
and technology becomes strong and they
inherit the there.
It's that simple.
But that's really what's happening
and it's what's going to happen.
And along the way,
they're going to figure it out.
Cures to every fucking disease
as people are alive or,
or the strong people would just start
bashing the fuck out of the smart people.
That's possible too.
But then eventually they
would breed smart people.
We're going to have a middle state right
now because I wouldn't say it's the
smartest people controlling
the world right now.
It's just the comments as far as people
that ever been the smartest cunts.
Oh yeah. But they're cuts the really
smart people like Bill Gates and you know,
they're not really controlling the world.
I mean,
they have a massive business
and everything like that,
but they're not directing,
you know, overseas campaigns to
get these minerals and fuck off
curing malaria. Yeah. Fucking
great things. Great things.
Just donating billions of dollars.
It's an amazing how it,
like Steve Jobs always got the
reputation as being like the cool guy.
He was like green and great for the
world. Meanwhile, Bill Gates was,
he got out there donating money for
schools and don't feel like he was crazy
humanitarian shit. Malaria research
institute or whatever it's called.
Go like we're done without him. As
soon as he stopped giving, we're out.
It's amazing. Have you seen his house?
Oh No. The battle. What's it like?
Ooh. Oh my God. What's it like?
There's a desire for it online.
It's fucking incredible.
It's built. First of all,
he has a submarine.
That's what I said.
He's got a door underneath his fucking
house where he can like open up and bring
the fucking submarine.
Sure.
It's just not crazy like it opens,
he can bring it in a bucket and
those old Nazi lab shows or whatever.
When they came in, hope I didn't make
the site. It's crazy. Yeah. I got a door.
It's incredible.
State of the garage
for submarine. Yeah. It's on
like a sad, it's not a sound,
it's all like the ocean or something
like that and it's this amazing fucking
house,
like the top of the lung technology
in every room you walk in,
you wear a pendant and
the Pender gives your,
your particular id out to
all these different sensors.
So as you enter a room,
your particular lighting comes on,
10 was to your temperature, your
mood, your music starts playing.
So wow, that's pretty cool.
That's what I'm saying.
So you leave one romantic
tailgates, his house. Oh
yeah,
you are such a case.
I was thinking about which President
Bill Gates is like that we were talking
about. I know, but I was
talking, I was thinking,
I was still thinking about which
president did that happen. The Pot.
Sometimes if I'm talking to somebody
and they'll be yapping in my mind we'll
just go elsewhere and I'll be like,
hey, can you back up a second?
I didn't hear any of it. I see.
I was thinking like JFK because,
but I don't know if it was just like the
Instagram colored look of all the film
that you see JFK and it's kind of cool.
But I think I would see Lincoln
just for that cause that's
of course meet with Lincoln.
JFK would probably the most likely to fuck
you. Who was living in Korea you time.
We're allowed to fuck any of them.
They want to care.
Apparently it was like the
biggest freak of all time.
I already had a couple thoughts down.
Physically fuck them. Fuck them. Fuck you.
I thought, Oh, you got to fuck them.
Fuck them. Oh. Then Grover Cleveland,
one of those fat guys. I'm going to
fuck my Nigga Nixon, Nixon, Nixon.
Well I tried to get the
secrets. Fuck them. Now.
Which one would you want to make love with
a Lincoln freed the slaves and he probably
had already had experience with men.
Right? Ra, what about you?
I mean like we're trying to
last as long as we can. Right.
What you made when you want to fuck you
and everyone will enjoy this moment.
Going condom or no condom. We find
spread out. This is love, Bro.
Love plus there were barely any ears
back then. There were letters, diseases,
but get a scrape yourself free if
you have something, what did you do?
I don't know. You'd to reach up there
with the guides isn't it? Didn't uh,
Al Capone, didn't he die?
Syphilis? Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Syphilis would kill people.
If you ever seen like pictures of people
who have like really like a longterm,
like advanced syphilis.
Horrible. Disgusting. Yeah.
It's an evil disease. It's crazy. We
give each other diseases by fucking,
it really is. It's like it just
attacks that area. Like a lot of them.
That's the only way to get it. You don't
get herpes by shaking hands, you know?
But you can get it flew by shaking
hands, shook a hand. You've product code.
You should [inaudible].
You actually touched a herpes
dick or her pedic peanuts.
You be fine if you had a cut on your
finger. No, you don't hand herpes. Yeah,
you're right. There's no hand
herb. You sure you can? No,
you wouldn't get it in your hand.
Lipson Dick Lipson deck. It's weird.
It has to be like an open, why would that
cause those areas, the genital herpes,
that's all over the place sometimes,
right? No, just in your genitals. Really.
Just general like in your legs too and
there's actually in your eyeball. Yeah,
there's, there's a type of it and
got a forehead to shingles too,
which is like another, like an advance of
herpes. Yeah. It's different kinds of her
thinking is shingles cordon
off. Yeah. They cook those.
But then you have that
juice inside you forever.
You had fucking bomb bomb that Obama, I
think I just see Ra being wanting it. Oh,
[inaudible] off my back so much.
Did you see the video of the guy who
claimed that he was Obama's lover and that
they had shared oral sex and no
real, is he in Chicago? Yeah.
You ever heard this guy?
Pull it up, pull it up.
I could see Obama's gay
lover just pull up, uh,
confessions. Obama's gay
or Gay Obama lover. Yeah.
The guy was so ridiculous and
he's got a nice house. Does he?
Confession of the Obamas
k lover? He was, uh,
they were interviewing him about it and
he, uh, it's just so ridiculous. He's,
yeah,
that's the guy is Larry Sinclair.
You can have, first of all,
you got to see Obama instead.
This is a giant Apatow movie.
Springs Colorado to
Chicago on November 2nd,
1999 arriving in our hair early
in the morning of November 3rd,
I went to the Chicago area to
attend the graduation. Of My Godson,
my best friends,
and from basic training from the
Great Lakes naval training facility.
I made reservations at the
Comfort Inn and suites in Gurnee,
Illinois based solely on the
location to the training center.
On November 5th, 1999 I hired the
services of Fivestar limousine,
Wiener, and guides me a lot of
details and this guy still hired,
hired them both for
November 5th or November 6th
and November 6th,
1999 I asked the limo driver whose name
I now really have for the first time,
Jack Pepper, me who? Connie.
Anyone who would like to
socialize and show me Chicago.
Most of them are totally understood
that I was looking for someone who knew
Chicago and would enjoy socializing.
Tiny said he knew someone
who was a friend of his
on November six 1999 after picking
me up at the hotel and Gurney,
and this is significant,
Mr he used his cell phone to make a call.
That call was me to then Illinois
state Senator Barack Obama.
Go set up an introduction
between myself and Senator Obama.
So on a sailing at the bar and setting
the limits in it or is he claiming
and I was just,
can you just hit the space bar? It
doesn't work. Yeah. Um, well hold on.
Yeah,
which has happened.
The guy saying that he fucked up Obama
and so we gave all those details in order
to do like an idiot be
corroborative or like say like,
well you can give all those details
cause he's a moron. But yeah,
it was such a long, it's part
of the storage. Hell Buddy.
Well I'm also doing a press conference.
You have 20 minutes to kill you think so.
This guy called this, he
got his limo driver to call.
Hey, show me some good. Okay,
good. Dick and Obama was like, man, you,
you let me know when someone's looking
for Dick. Oh you tried to limo.
And I'm a senator and I'm
thinking about being a president,
but if you see some of this, I don't
abandon all that shit. It just takes
the guy's nuts.
[inaudible] the guy he reeks of being
foolish and he's not just like we had a
relationship in college. It's like,
these are crazy. He's a random like,
call me up and I'll just fuck
somebody that's maybe, yeah. I mean,
the story is so preposterous.
What if it was around,
do you think he took a Abe Lincoln?
Was the vampire sounding lessons from the
Republican convention like us act like
us? That's what everyone, Obama,
I don't believe that it's real,
but I wouldn't be surprised
if it was real. Yeah,
because look at what
happened with Clinton,
who would have ever believed that there
was a president and he was, you know,
in his 50s and he was,
you know,
in the White House and he was
having a 20 year old girl, blonde.
They shooting loads on her dress and want
to believe that nobody poppers starts
talking a cigar in and out of her.
I'm going to believe that he would have
thought she would've kept her mouth shut.
I mean,
come on,
dude. It was the other one dragged her
in, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah. Wow. Yeah.
There'll be front.
Think about that position that he was at.
The president of the United States is
literally at the top of the food chain of
human beings on the planet as far as the
most prestigious position in the world,
in the world,
period.
I mean it just is how much you love
being from Ireland or England or wherever
you're from. Top 10 that
guy, the president of,
even if you don't respect president,
put pub capture orders and the president
of bombs, president, president,
and in control the military.
This is no, no comparison.
Pope's a joke compared to some religious
nuts though. It gets those chicks,
they could them with bombs. Oh yeah.
If there was a war between though,
it's more between the president of
public president wins every time.
He just sends all those pictures saved
up for years of all those guys getting
their dick sucked by little boys.
They just release those all over the
Internet and there's a massive campaign
against the Vatican would immediately,
if there was ever a position where
the United States went to war with the
Vatican,
we wouldn't use bombs who'd use pictures
of them blowing his horn and more of
those. Over the five year period.
They didn't have to be real man.
You mean how many fucking Photoshop
artists are there that worked for the
military? Luckily there's plenty
that they can find that are real,
that was her constantly doing.
I'm sure all you have to do a sit and
hidden cameras up or fall, these fox,
wherever they go, and you've got to
find a certain percentage of a, really,
all you have to do is give them all flip
phones and I'm sure someone will just
record themselves. Well, you know, I've
heard it argued on the online especially,
and it's really a fucking potent argument,
that worry argument that the entire
Catholic religion at its highest levels
exists for all these gay guys.
I believe that coming
up at the highest level,
not just covered it up and sent the guy
in the way covered up and sent him to,
to write more kids and it's, yeah,
it's a culture that's from the vedic.
A lot of them accepted a lot of
the boys except the position.
So a lot of the boys like it and
so they think that it's good.
They think that they're
doing a good thing they did.
There's literally things
that Ratzinger saw Ratzinger.
Who is the guy who was the pope right now?
Pope Benedict is real.
You might hit the Hitler youth.
No big deal,
but there's,
there's letters by this fucking guy that
this guy had under his review where um,
these cardinals or bishops or
what are the fuck they were,
we're actually specifically targeting
boys that had come from broken families.
He was, they were asking for boys from
broken cars and wanting people to,
couldn't fight back as much,
anywhere to go.
They didn't have a family that they
can call him from beat your ass.
Those are the people choosing how
you act in your religion. Lent,
how long that lasts and what
you have to do this year,
whether or not condoms are legal,
those are the people chosen.
You can't be Catholic
anymore. Dirty, silly bitches.
You just can't, you're not a
Christian. It's so dumb. It's all dumb.
But Catholicism is one of the worst.
That's,
it's a cult of people who are
dressed up like fucking Jeanie's.
They're dressed up like these crazy
wizard outfits with giant fish head hats
and,
and they're waving golden warns.
It's 2012 and these assholes are dressed
up like they're like a fucking Harry
Potter character. I mean,
it's preposterous. The idea
that that still exists,
then we still take that seriously.
My God, that's incredible.
I mean it's, it's really
incredible. And you know, people
go, oh, you're so ignorant.
You know, you hate religion, you hate I,
I hate everything that stinks like shit.
And that
shit up. It goes against
them. If he's a guy,
you want to have to give people fucking
birth control. If we're Christian,
it's like, Oh, if I'm Jewish,
I don't have to let people get
Bacon with the money I give them.
What are you arguing about?
What all the fucking Christians
don't let anyone do anything.
They think they run. Everything can get
birth control to art, to, to, to girls.
Because there's a lot of Catholics don't
want to have to offer that to people.
Well, Catholics think did birth control
is actually bad. So then don't take it.
The pope tells you that you're
not supposed to be using condoms,
you're not supposed to
be using birth control.
You're supposed to be having
sex for procreation only. Yeah,
so that's why they should do.
And he said nothing to do
with what your employees need.
That's why boys have a boy pussy.
If you're a Christian scientist,
you can't deny all healthcare to your,
to your workers because you don't
believe in healthcare. Yeah,
well there's just don't do it himself.
There's certainly that.
That's certainly a problem
if you're an employer,
but I think overall the real problem
is that it's an ideology and it's an
ideology that's based on just
some shit that's written down.
And the idea that there's a
god is not a preposterous idea.
If you look at the underlying
code of the universe,
it's really the whole Fibonacci sequence.
That's it.
Reoccurs in nature over and over again.
This,
this constant drive
towards going to flexing.
It may be very well be
complete coincidence or it
may be that there's some sort
of an impossible to decipher grand plan
to it all and it might not be a deity
and it's in it as far as
how we look at it, like, uh,
being a person, we, you know,
we, we anthropomorphize size.
That's what it was to be doing.
We didn't have an animal and you put it
in a human context. I mean, whatever,
however you would describe that. Putting
a God a deity into a human context,
I think that's ridiculous.
I think the idea of it even being remotely
like our consciousness is ridiculous,
but it's not ridiculous that there's
some sort of a higher order. It doesn't,
it doesn't seem to me,
but what's ridiculous is all these stupid
old stories that everybody's based in
their life on circumcise and kids
and not, and pork. And you know,
what are you talking about?
No water during the day crews for this.
You can do it if you want,
but don't fucking tell anyone else to oh,
cares what anyone else does. They don't
have to do your shit. Yeah, it's stupid.
That's what it is. It's dumped.
But the problem is the EU.
There's a lot of people out there that
really have a hard time thinking for
themselves and they are happier when
someone comes along and they offer them a
predetermined pattern they can follow.
That's why religion works for a lot of
people. All right, so do it yourself.
Don't force on it.
Anybody else. It's stupid.
But do it yourself if you want to do it.
And then I think the problem with data
is that when someone's doing something,
they want other people to do it too.
It's like when dudes go vegan
and they get douchey with you,
how many times a year for that APP,
but they're happy that you're not vegan.
Sometimes they're happy that
they can look down on you.
And some where I've had guys like, come
on, man, you really need to try this.
You really need to come on, man. I'm like,
so you didn't need to get
the fuck away from me. Well,
if I don't eat these animals,
so they're going to live forever,
so I'm going to happen. They're going
to cure cancer. You stupid. Fuck.
What are you saying? You're not
going to kill animals. What if,
what if plants would scream when you
cut them down, would you still eat them?
What if they made like a,
as you cut the lettuce off the out of the
ground, what if it every freaking, yeah,
would you be upset?
What if they loved it?
But there's a something when
someone becomes something,
when they become a Republican,
when they become a windows user,
when they switched over to sprint,
they want you to do it to everybody is
a lot of people that are weak like that
man, they feel better when everybody else
is doing the same shit they're doing.
If they're dressing like Johnny Cash,
they want everybody else
address like Johnny Cash to it.
You could tell them like,
like literally this is the only
car that fits into my car port,
but you need to buy American Bro.
Why you or they're like,
it's a cohort over Chevy Ford guy,
Bro.
That was for a lot of side to side when
you were saying earlier, I'm a Ford Guy.
Brow always bail for guide till I die.
You know it's funny, as Ford escorts,
remember how gross that car he
used to be and it was a whole,
it's like the grossest car ever scored.
That was before escorts were escorts
back then. They were prostitutes.
They called after it. They were
still escorts. They look done.
Have you ever attempted to natural know
things like that? Temple, the Tabernacle,
a tempo it and ask what,
did you ever have an escort?
I don't know.
I never got,
I never got an escort
Taurus's and sell a car.
You for Ford is the only company that
didn't take money from the government and
his bail outs and then
they're still doing great.
Who paid them back or when something
already just pay them fully back. No,
it's not true. No, we did try to
say that they paid them back fully,
but there's apparently,
there's a lot of funky malarkey
that I don't understand it.
I'm not a financial guy, but the way
it's been explained to me, it's like, no,
they're clearly taken away the idea that
we have any say in it. So it's like,
all right,
let's,
let's actually find out so that we
don't misinform people auto bail out,
bail out payback, right?
What your mouth is agape,
it's done and you're about to murmur.
I liked it.
[inaudible] you know what the hell is
Tom is a house like that and I can't hear
it. Here's why. Here's the issue.
But while we're still on the subject,
because I did know that there
was something wrong about this.
In the Washington examiner,
they have an argue.
They have an article rather the truth
behind Chrysler's fake auto bailout
payback.
And apparently there's a lot of
fucking funny accounting of how they,
yeah.
American taxpayers have already spent
more than 13 billion bailing out Chrysler.
The Obama administration already forgave
more than 4 billion of that debt.
When the company
filed for bankruptcy. Tax payers are
never going to get that money back,
but how is Christ are going to pay
off the rest of the 7.6 billion?
They own the Treasury Department.
The answer is the Obama administration's
bailout agreement with Fiat gave the
Italian car company in
tremendous incremental call
option that allows it to buy
up to 16% of Chrysler
stock at a reduced rate.
But in order to exercise that option first
it had a payback at least 3.5 billion
of the loan to the Treasury
Department. So fee it's, it's,
it's all like that is renting
them. Exactly. It's not,
it's not like Chrysler became ballers
and paid all the money back and I'm like,
thanks. It worked. There's a,
there's a lot of other shit
going on behind the scenes.
People are buying things and
selling things. You should be,
are we should fear. I would, I would love
it if America made all the best shit.
You know?
I mean,
I would think it would be amazing if
we could pull out of this and all of a
sudden make fucking bad ass cars and
shit. I would like to support that. I,
you know, when we buy, if you buy a
German car, you know that those people,
they're not slave labors, you
know. But if you, if you buy a car,
like if they started selling cars that
are made in China like Foxconn and starts
making cars,
that's a tricky situation of being.
I would re rather pay more if
I could afford it. Of course.
Obviously we rather pay more if I knew
that the people who made my car got a
good wage,
wouldn't you?
I, I've always bought Fords. I like
for zoning. Got Ford Mustang next.
I think that or a charger. I, I've, I've
always bought Fords except Ford boy.
Yeah, I know. It's a Chrysler. I
known it's Chrysler is full of Shit.
Did you hear what I just, it looks
nice. They look dope. The charges
best shapes out there.
They nailed it. They, they,
they made a modern version of
the 1970s in 1960s muscle car.
They did it.
They fucking nailed it.
They nailed it with the Camaro
to the new Camaro. Nailed it.
I saw crazy looking red
one with black stripes.
It's a yellow one the other day. It
with driving one. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
They're great shit. I wouldn't buy yellow
car though. I wouldn't buy that car.
Yeah, there's something about
a yellow car and it just, man,
it's hard to prove you're not a douche
bag orange man. I've got Nacho orange,
at least all the Mexicans love me,
but it's like creepy orange all
the best at what you call it.
The orange is what Ari cause it.
Fiesta all is. It feels like a fiesta.
It's like going getting a Doritos.
It's like, I'm trying to think.
Did they just had like an extra
gallon of that paint? I think so.
That's why it got it so cheap because
it was that color, but now I want to,
I want to murder that car. That car
was great. Brian, you have a great car.
American car also. That's
amazing. It's nice.
It's about as nice as it gets
except for the new Cadillacs.
The new Cadillacs are just about the
best American cars that have ever been
built.
Yeah,
there's some new Cadillac CTSV and CTSV
coop it you're you're in blade runner.
The Romeos. None of those is
nine of them, I'm sure. Okay.
So this boyfriend through catalogs from,
you're trying to relate to the
euro's auto workers. Oh really?
Did he really say that? It goes,
in fact, I own an cars at my wife
drives a Cadillac. In fact, she drives
two Cadillac's and you see all his,
if I was going, God damn it,
you stupid fast. What can
you say one you'd dumb cunt.
He also said this at the same thing.
He goes, he goes, I love auto racing.
I've always loved,
obviously we've been a big fan.
A lot of my friends are owners of
why you're killing us. Hey, do you
want to go racing? If you ever, uh,
kind of two race cars, go around a track.
Remember that? What's it called? Place?
Did you go in that? What a called place?
Oh, Atlanta and Atlanta to uh, yeah,
argues with me when we did a, yeah, I
went around the track. We, um, I uh,
did some sort of a hosting thing for a
mini Cooper versus Porsche challenge as a
race that they had in
a really close circuit.
So like the big engine of the Porsche
didn't allow it to overtake the mini
Cooper, which was speed. It was all just
about agility and real usable speed.
It's pretty fucking impressive that a
mini Cooper was only like a couple of
seconds behind a Porsche in this,
this race around these cones.
I love those guys too. They're like, yeah,
they're like, are you guys going to win?
And they're like, we'll
see. And then they didn't,
they didn't think they were going to win.
They're like probably not.
They didn't even, they just made
a little party for their owners.
Well they didn't even get the
sport version mini Cooper, but not,
they had a wagon wagon one that's
actually really have a regular version
apparently.
Like they had like all the people from
like the mini Cooper clubs and all that
shit come down. And there's people
that get fanatic about those cars,
just like clubs and Shit there apparently
the most fun to drive and had a
barbecue.
They invited any mini Cooper owner to
come out and you just get free barbecue.
I got a chance to drive it a little bit,
but it was only around this,
you know the small course, but it's there.
They're like real agile, a little cars.
They're like, it's like a go
cart. It's like you're so,
it's so small and so light,
you know? It's like there's something fun
in that man. So what's this? I just got,
I remember got just got so high, I was
like, you were like, I got to work.
So you do whatever you want it to.
It just get obliterated in Atlanta.
We got obliterated as fuck that day.
Remember how hot it was?
Sweltering Royce. The Atlanta
gets that crazy funky. Huh? Wait,
so when are you going to racing? I
don't know. I have a friend who uh,
I mean they're not,
I don't want to like have a
competition or anything like that.
Just go around quick check that box.
You put chicken line too in Burbank.
They have adult go kart,
indoor adult go kart track.
And I was thinking like that'd be pretty
cool. Great. They can, you're doing that.
I guess it got really fast. The owner of
the, how fast do they go? I don't know.
Whenever the ice house does
it. Okay, let's do that. Yeah.
You know there's a laser
tag place up here too.
They still have laser tag 12 year old
kids. Look at what point we should do.
All those things don't card. You
should do all those bags. Shoot guns.
I ain't fault. I have, I love
shooting in Israel, which to do that.
Let's go shoot guns.
I shoot fish in a barrel,
put fish up and then try to shoot fish
like dead fish. Why don't you do that?
So I used to be taught things at target.
You did pick a gross,
the American oh Derek Carr. Guns
into the air. Guns in the air.
Just shoot him like pull and just throw
a official like put them like on like a
target. And then she tried
to blow up with fish. Oh,
throw him in the air and then
try to shoot him out of the sky.
No shooting with Sean Miller
in Indianapolis. Yeah,
it was so much fun. Yeah, it was great
fun pull. And you just bought it.
And when you see it explodes.
Ah, yeah. It's like,
I mean even when you play pool
and you make it, you know,
he makes fine ball and everyone
hangs out that they have it.
Like they like a pro like area, you
know, everyone hangs out just like,
just like in pool people would hang out
or any place where he'll just chill a
golf room. I have a buddy
Justin, these uh, they,
they have like competitions where you'd
go through a maze. Like things come up,
like when you blast them and you get like
a score and then you go like after you
sold the area. Well this is bullets.
Yeah, that was, that was the cop.
What was the cop cop
movies. Oh yeah. You killed,
you killed a civilian again. Yeah. Gibson,
there's a lethal weapon. The funny ones.
But Berg attorney hitch with
City, Gothenburg, Gutenberg.
There were five police police academies.
Yeah.
They had to go through those courses.
Steve couldn't burn Tackleberry who died.
There was this thing about Halloween that
ate what you would pay money and they
had like a hundred people dressed up as
zombies anywhere on top of the building
and now they all just start coming towards
you and it's paint ball and you just
shoot them charged. Oh
yeah. So they just like,
it's like you're not just false warmed
by trends. It was in Santa Monica.
They wanted us to come down and cause
we were gonna have him on the pot.
It's like what do they do when they
get ahold of you? You just shoot them.
They're slowly climbing
up, you know, and you just,
and then they have to fall when they
get shot. I don't know. I didn't do it.
So they're slowly coming
in on you like yeah,
they're hoarding you. It was
like call of duty zombies.
They're eventually going to have a
game like the world's most deadly game.
Remember that movie? The
deadliest game? Whenever it was,
I think there was what they redid it with
Gary Busey also.
It was hunting them ice tea was
the one being hunted. Oh yeah.
That's when I see him like
crazy dreadlocks. Yeah.
But there was an old version of it.
It's like the deadliest games really old.
It was like a Russian military guy who
was like crazy and Dupre talked to every
thought. These people, there's
island then when hunt them down.
And the reason why I,
um,
well I remember this because I've been
watching this show called naked city.
Have you seen the show and not that one?
Oh, hidden city, sorry. Not Negativity.
Hidden city, hidden cities. All this
Marcus Shacki guy, he's a um, uh,
crime novelist and he goes to all these
different towns and finds out like the
really fucked up stories in this town.
Like all the crazy murderers and shit
that hasn't, that haven't been solved.
And one of them was a dude who would pick
up hookers and he would take them in a
plane and Alaska picked him up,
put him in us, handcuffed him,
put him in his plane and then fly
them to an island and let them loose.
And then he would go and hunt them.
Really?
He brought it would bring a rifle and
he would let them loose and just go,
you better run. You better run
around. I'm coming after you bitch.
And then he would go after, I
mean hunting, we track them down.
They'd be like in the snow. So
it'd be like tracking them. Yeah.
But it was like the thrill of actually
tracking them. Fucking blow him away.
And then he would keep their,
um, their licenses and shit.
And that's how they caught him.
What do we want it to his attic attic.
He had driver's licenses of all these
different women that he killed because
they had searched his place once.
They couldn't find anything and they
had a search place again. And uh,
when they searched this place again,
they found it in the attic.
I shouldn't keep mentos
they can't help themselves.
They tell us people want to be competent.
I think that's what it is.
I think they just like
keeping them or mentos well,
they look back at those momentos and they,
they have, they get excited trophies.
Yeah. I don't think it's like,
I'm looking to get caught though.
You think you're looking not
to and keep these things,
you get more complacent than
what you do it. I blamed my mom.
She always had like that book when you're
a kid and I had like little lock of
your hair and stuff like that and I always
was attracted like law locks of hairs,
you know, with the girls that I date.
What would you ever, would you ever,
if it was on the menu, would you try
human meat? No. No, you would never do it.
It's supposed to taste just like pork.
Really? Yeah. And you can always eat pork.
So why would I try human meat? I don't
want to know what that tastes like.
Apparently though, obviously would,
it must be distinguishable because uh,
well you can go to Liberia and you
can get some crazy anymore. The worst.
I know the war's done, so they're
not serving any more human meet.
Charlie Charles Taylor was in the Hague.
Charles Taylor's, the guy was the, the,
the horrible war criminal
crazy fucking name.
Charles Taylor. Yeah. Sounds like
the guy who had created peanuts,
they destroy their own
infrastructure there.
Would they need to like stuff
to tie people up with slate?
Just he was like telephone wire.
They would cut it down and just use that.
She sort of like, oh now we have
no telephone lines. Jesus Christ,
if that's their rockets out.
So they're like,
let me just show you how much I can blow
this thing up and then you show me how
much that rock can blow his damn. They
blow up. Blow up down. They're so stupid.
The whole, the the
Liberia. So frightening.
And the fact that it used to be
a u s slave colony. Really? Yeah.
That's how it started. It's all
better now. Slaves came from Liberia.
Yeah. Wow. It's better now. In what way?
Charles tells gone or trying to
like redo everything. Mass Man.
They had the vice guide to Liberia. It
was pretty recent. They were over there.
It's still crazy. Yeah. This
is parts of the world where,
how the fuck do you fix Africa?
Look at all the different like
look at you gone to look at it.
I mean that's a long, long, long
project. They wanted to give juice.
You're going to get them Jewish.
They wanted to give the Jews Uganda
instead of Israel. So listen,
figure this place as a lot of talk about
that. When was this? 60 no, no, no, no.
Wait before that, I guess the
forties and thirties the war Israel,
after the war they were like,
we need to give him some place to go.
Clearly we've shown enough times,
we just explain to me how the whole Israel
thing worked because at one point in
time Palestinians live there,
but no Jews live there already.
Like a bunch of different migrations.
Well Jews live there and Arabs live
there a long time ago and then one of the
Roman kings came and like dispersed.
The Jews killed him. Yeah, well no,
just like say extinguished
something like go to Europe,
go to Africa.
Just go pick them all out here.
What you've, what year was this?
This we're talking about like um,
this is way after Jesus I think.
I think because Jews were around when
Jesus was there way after Jesus and after
one temple was destroyed,
then the Jews wouldn't go back until they
rebuilt the second temple. Then I did.
Then they came back when that
was a story and they kicked out,
like they slowly started
coming back here or there.
So like in 1910 it was a big migration.
1912 big migration of,
of European Jews to Israel.
What temple was it where the Romans got
all the way up to the top and the Jews
Massada what? There wasn't a temple. It
was, it was it last enclave of defense.
They were resisting. So when did
they do, what was the store? They uh,
went up there.
It was one of those things that one
of the Roman kings built for like the
getaway, a sweet, sweet getaway. Um, it's
really awesome actually. They have these,
these um,
hot baths and they would like empty out
like the part of mountain underneath.
It's like a heat it,
up until then we come up with the ceilings
were curved down because they knew
that if they were flat, the water
drops put like hit and just like form.
And that hit you. That was really
unpleasantly minimal curved.
So the water would run down the
curved ceilings not drip onto you?
Um, yeah, just really great
design things. But anyway,
as the Jews are being pushed out,
send, convert or leave or die,
I guess some of them,
the last defenses like push back to there
and they realized they could just like,
there's only one way up.
So they just,
they can just shoot down
arrows at people at the Romans.
They couldn't get up there,
um,
until they started using Jewish
slaves as human shields, uh,
and then started marching up.
But also they are,
they had enough food and water
to last them for like so long.
So they will wait you out.
We'll just wait you out for years.
And they just had him surrounded like
that, that much, that much supplies.
And then eventually when I think the
human slaves, right then they were like,
all right, but we're not going to kill
our own. So what are we going to do?
And I think they are just,
they all kill each other. Well,
we're not going to kill her own,
so we'll kill our own will just help
commit suicide. We're dead anyway.
So did they commit suicide when they
use these swords? Right? So words.
Is that what it was? A lot of it wasn't
it? Where were they? Get poisoned.
It wouldn't be poison. Poison. Yeah.
I don't know that it was when it
was done in a very primal way.
It could be sourced. It could have been
swords. And I know like the last guy,
I had to do it to himself and then chose
who was going to be that last guy. Wow.
Go.
That's what it is.
They didn't want to commit suicide
cause you're not going to heaven.
So you would kill another person. So you
didn't have to kill yourself. Sit alone.
I had to commit suicide or he just
didn't look at all these juicy Ron at the
Romans
by cops or go,
oh you guys come up this way.
I came up back over there.
This Jews are all day and that's
probably why I choose my clothes.
And then, and then, uh, and
then times Roman outfits.
Wow. What a fucking crazy
time to be alive. That must,
you had to give them to religion or die.
Oh,
should be easy.
It just shows you that people have always
had that weird desire to have everyone
else think exactly the way they thought.
It makes them feel more secure.
Christians more crystallized.
It's more Christians did Jews actually
never proselytized. That's amazing,
isn't it? Yeah. Why is that?
Because of your religion? It's just,
it's silly as anybody else's based on the
same things. Yeah, it was the question.
So how come they figured out to like
keep to themselves and it said like,
you don't have to do this. There's no
reason you should if you want to, you can,
but we're not going to try to push
her. I was like, do whatever you want.
The time of David, they outlawed
it. Outlawed conversion.
Wow. It was too popular.
Too popular. But he wanted
to be a judge. You just,
because it was like they were the
ruling party. Really? Yeah. Damn.
So they outlawed it. So they said no
conversion during this time, John,
for how long? Oh No, please.
I'm fine. Yeah, I don't know.
Now you have to do that.
You have to ask a bunch of times.
I'm just hanging out.
I don't like these people do that. Now.
You have to do that. Most of the whites,
I don't want to be that ever. You
pretty much have to do that. The rabbit,
I'll tell you like, don't, don't do this.
You don't want to do it really any
big macs or can't just trust me.
You don't want to do this. He Cuny
big MACs. Yeah. If you're a Jew,
you can't eat big MACs, religious Jew,
you know you're supposed to eat hamburger.
Is that what it is? It's not kosher
meat and it's cheese on there too. Oh,
so just that in general.
But you could have kosher beef burgers.
You can have a kosher beef burger
with, with soy cheese. Oh, the cheese.
What is it you can't combine and
milk and meat. Is that what it is?
What's that all about? Uh, it's,
it's pretty much a stupidity,
just like all the religions.
But uh,
it's based on a passage that says you
shall not mix the meat of the mother or
the milk of the milk of the mother with
the meat of the calf. Huh? Yeah. Yeah.
Wasn't about sex horn. Instead
or anything else? Some sex.
Take that just to be that it's, it's
that actual mother and calf. Yeah,
but that's the case.
Why can't you get the milk from the mother
and then kill the mother and he heard
some milk of the mother and the meat
of the mother. That's all right.
I don't run it. I'm really good at,
it's just they just no meat and milk.
You have to wait. If you eat pizza, you
have to wait 30 minutes for you meet.
What are the odds though,
if I have a fucking piece of meat that
the milk is gonna come from the same? No,
it's not.
They said that means they said that
passage means don't mix it two at all.
Fuck you. Linen and cotton. You can't
mix, but yeah, but you can't. If you're,
if you have a, if you have like a, a
woolen the linen, that's what it is.
If you have a wool jacket,
you can't have linen things tying in the
buttons cause that's evil and you'll go
to hell when backing up and go to hell
for now. My favorite one, chocolate.
My favorite one that you told me to this
day was that you were told that when
you masturbate for that,
people don't really know.
Ari grew up extremely religious
to the point where he lived.
You lived on lives in Israel and
your show for two years. Yeah,
I mean that's the Torah all day long.
9:00 PM 10 9:00 AM to 10:00 PM I mean,
dad is,
that's some pretty intense shit and they
told you when you masturbated that you
were impregnating a demon and the, let's
just say you're on your back lying down.
They didn't really do positions
back then in our shower anyway,
but when you're doing it, some demon
comes and like, she's like round you,
fucking you as you're fucking your hand
and then you make like demon babies and
they have some writer uses the phage.
There was some like maybe it's in coons,
everything coons,
she use it in a movie or some
deep know in a book. There's some,
some demon was like riding
them and had anyway,
but then you get her pregnant and she
has babies. Every time you do that,
every time you're 100% as babies.
Never going to be one on earth,
only live in this demon world.
Milt have formed and gross. Why?
I forgot about this. And then when
you get to go to heaven, when you die,
you have to meet those demons.
Oh my God. And they got, Why dad?
Why couldn't we barn on the regular
planet? Wow. Why aren't you like this?
That so did you mastered with this anyway,
even knowing all this,
and what did you think was,
was this going on?
Why you were living in this like
really religious environment?
You were asking me and you never saw him
masturbating. You never stop. I mean,
I slowed down. I thought it
was evil for doing it. Well,
like, so you're doing this,
you're there 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM did you
think, well that part's bullshit. You,
you're studying like this
intense religious, well, there's,
I think there's two types of sense.
Literally this is how it is.
There's 2000 since there's, since you
plan out and say fuck it. I don't,
I don't agree with that. And this types
like gossip where it just happens.
You're not thinking about it like,
fuck, I shouldn't have done that. Right.
Talking about about
somebody's masturbation is
one that just overcomes you,
but it's one,
I guess it's one that you do
plan out because you could
just not do it this time.
Oh, you accidentally touched it.
Women I don't think have the same.
It's not theirs. They don't have
that backup. Women want to have sex.
They get itchy.
They want do they want it to be touched?
They want affection to get horny.
But we have like a backup of sperm
where like your Dick is like, come on,
let's go. It's like you got to get
rid of this shit. Jesus Christ.
We can't even think you'd sour
milk everywhere here. Come on.
What did you, when you beat off, did you
like go fuck. What about those babies?
Did you believe that part?
That part was more like fables
is wasn't like the written Torah.
So it was like this is what's, this is
what like the extra curricular stuff,
the ghosts and shit like that.
So when would they bring that up?
How'd you they barely brought that up.
Did they bring it up in class ever? Yeah,
we'll come up.
We're in discussions with
rabbis who studied all that
stuff that the uh, the um,
the Zahar Zahar which just
like the mystical book,
but you're not supposed to say that
until you're married in 35. What is it?
Second Mystical Book said you can't set
handle it until you're married and 35 at
least set up. It's got all this stuff
about ghosts and weird shit. Ghosts.
The Olin's is go Siemens and crossing
dude Judaism sounds like fun.
Sounds like fun. Literate. You
don't get to read it very much.
I never read the translation to was
and so hard. Maybe I should read it.
Can you get it online? Can you bobbing
by now he's talking about comicon.
It's probably all written
down somewhere actually,
but a lot of it would
be the exact language.
You wouldn't get that from transition,
but you look at clothes. Yeah.
There was this piece, there was
this one piece and a in the Talmud,
which is like a respect of like
you're supposed to study apart.
And they said this rock,
this rabbi went to his students who were
living in like a dormitory altogether
because there was a s a snake or a dragon
that was attacking them every night
and killing his students.
So he had to sleep and only the rabbi
was the one who gets to feed it.
So he had to sleep under one
of their beds, um, so that
he could kill this dragon.
It was a dragon. And I asked
my rabid about that. I'm like,
what the fuck is this all about?
Uh, it's my way. What's going on?
There's no seconds. Dragons, this is
all under this bed to suck your cock.
And that's how I killed the Dragon.
Yeah, he said there was a rash.
It was a rash of jerk offs going on and
the only way that he did so they can't
really write that out in the Talmud.
So they had a metaphor.
It was a rash of jerk offs.
And the only way I could stop it.
It's a rabbi hiding under their bed
saying, I call you. You're masturbating.
Wow.
So the dragon that was killing us it
the children was just damn masturbating,
desire to masturbate. Oh my
God. Their spiritual selves.
Holy Shit. That's hilarious.
Yet. But it's not written.
That metaphor is not explained.
It's just, it's just assumed.
And you have to ask someone who
understands the tax or Rashi would.
It looked quite stuff about,
if you can understand that,
that's so crazy, man. Well,
how would that in the future, people
would just think it's just craziness.
This was an oral tradition too,
so it wasn't written down.
Someone just had to tell you that story.
Wow.
That's so they wrote down when they
thought they were going to lose it all.
That's amazing. Wow. That
is a great fucking story.
You think I'd be making that up, but
I'm really not. It's hilarious. Yeah,
there's were so crazy.
And people, you know,
whenever we have these conversations
about religion and so really interesting
because I get so many angry
tweets [inaudible] get, they
get so mad and an idiot.
There's literally zero proof for it.
There's zero proof ever and there's
nothing else in your life that you will
entertain a conversation over
when there's zero proof, nothing.
That's the only thing. If someone tried
to invent any of those religions today,
you would laugh at them? Yes.
You'd say this is a call,
but somehow we can't because everyone's
involved in it and I just like,
it's ridiculous what you're
doing. Completely ridiculous.
And I say that it's the,
it's the enemy of progress
because you're not,
you don't does that's
not on the table anymore.
Everything is on the table as far as I
mean not is as far as like what is the
possibility for the culture?
Clothing. I'll real loud.
What is subatomic particles?
What is, what is, you know
what, what are in black holes?
Everything is really on the table and
and up to discovery until it comes to
religion. And what religion
that's not on a table, if you,
if anything is off the table like that,
like stem,
stem cell research or things along
those lines of religion. Yeah,
because of religion, especially when you
can get stem cells from skin. I mean,
they're at a point now where you don't,
you don't need to have embryos.
You don't need to encourage people to
have abortions like they thought the worst
case scenario,
whatever it be,
that people would be a courage to kill
their babies because stem cells from the
aborted fetus can be very valuable. That's
not even necessary anymore. They've,
they've passed that,
but we're still human.
It's still there because of our
belief in a god. Yeah. Yeah.
Some of those methods so long ago,
it doesn't apply to you anymore.
Even if it was invented for a reason,
It's just the ridiculous thing
is that if this God did exist,
that he wouldn't tell you while you're
fucking up left and right and surely
setting yourself to house, we're just
assigned asshole. Wait there and go.
Listen when you get up here,
I know this is life has been confusing
and everybody's full of Shit and they
been telling you these crazy stories,
but if you don't listen to
them once you get up here,
the infinite wisdom is gonna
fucking cookie. I got mad at God.
I started thinking about this
stuff. It was like, what the fuck?
So you're telling me that everyone goes
to heaven or doesn't or it gets rewarded
on the next plane or doesn't based on,
you've never been explicit. Just said,
I want you to do this and
you're supposed to guess it.
My Protestant friends where like if you
don't accept Jesus, you're going to hell.
And I'm like, what's your
parents were, were Christian,
so you're better chance of
accepting Jesus and mine.
So just because randomly
and my parents were Jewish,
I'm going to burn in hell for eternity.
It's ridiculous. It's ridiculous.
Like God wouldn't just intervene and say,
listen parents,
you're teaching your children wrong. This
is what I like. I like, I liked him too.
If you're a native American a
hundred years after Jesus came,
you've never heard of him. But if you
don't accept that you're going to hell,
you had no chance. Yeah. You
go to hell, just go to hell.
Burn forever for your sin.
You know where they say, well,
some people will believe that
Jesus is actually went to America.
And so we'd like told them
like one time and the left.
And so that was enough of generations.
They were Protestant friends tells you,
this is the only song so stupid about
Jesus and America was the Mormon,
the Mormons. They believed that
he fucking, he, he was the, uh,
that's where the, uh, the American
Indians came from. They were lost juice.
This, this is it. It's an India.
That's how ridiculous. I used to
have a joke about it, but I said,
but never really formed it.
But this is what it was.
There's other parts of that same
book that say what the Mormons do.
I've told you this, right? Yeah. When they
said he went to the moon, but with, yeah,
with more,
with more Hebrew people and start a
little race of people called the lunar
Syrians. No. Where they still
live to this day. No. Yes.
Or at least they were saying that until
we went to the moon and then we're like,
what's up? Like it's the linear. He said,
and here's my thing. This is what they,
and they didn't answer.
They just stopped teaching it,
but this is what they said was
like, oh, well when we made that up,
we didn't think anybody would actually
go to the fucking moon. Call us on it.
It was like 200 years
ago. We're like, oh yeah,
we'll take a golden light of
the moon and call me on my lie.
It's so funny. It's so probably the
people, what are they doing up there?
What do you think? There's no atmosphere.
You know? We didn't know any of that.
We didn't know shit. Yeah,
more templates. Yeah.
Joseph Smith was 14 he founded,
understood it.
When he said he found that the lost
tablets and they say it only he could read
because he had a seer stone. He had
a magic stone and he was looking at,
that's who's going to be the next
republican president for county.
I believe in all that.
Mitt Romney did.
You seen the trailer for
promethium speaking of
ridiculous science fiction movie
to move new Ridley Scott movie,
the Prequel to alien. Oh no,
really don't watch the trailer. They
give away just too much going on in the,
there's a few spoilers,
but God damn does it look good.
Ooh,
it looks good right now.
So she's an innocent man.
Charlise the Ron [inaudible].
It's a prequel.
Couldn't Charlise that all is the new
bad ass chick do it is it looks fucking
Trump. I won't watch it then
drill it. It looks so good.
It's coming out June.
My Dick is hard until June.
We were talking about with Doug Benson
that one time, but trailers, it ruins the,
for you. It's the scene. It says
you thought it was dead, didn't you?
He's not dead. Yeah, they try. They
try so hard to get you into the movie.
It really pisses off a lot of
get solid. Yeah. You fuck heads.
You give away huge plot points.
There's some movies that it's
almost useless to go see them.
Like you know what's going to end the
first 20 minutes when it's setting up.
You're like, I know you're going
to become poor. I know how to move.
He goes get to it already.
I love going to a movie that's supposed
to be really good and you don't see any
previous four. It's rare that that
happens, but man, when it hit,
when it does happen,
it's great.
It happens a lot from you now cause I
just download everything so it's like
there's no commercials so I can
miss commercials for things.
Does fucking from atheists like certainly
I'd love a good science fiction movie
written by, you know when you, when
you have Ridley Scott's good at home,
it's like come on, this is going to be
tremendous. You know, he's really good at,
there's not enough of those. They need
like avatars every couple of months.
You know, something along those lines.
Like something that had bad ass,
like Taylor, one's terrible ones. Can
we for adventures. I thought, I thought,
I thought that maybe I was getting cynical
because I was like movies aren't good
anymore,
but I'm like maybe just me getting older.
I mean my parents had the same thing.
They looked at rotten tomatoes,
which is just an amalgamation of all the,
you know what it is just,
and it was like the last nine box
office was like got shitty review.
It's kind of under 60% and I'm like, that
means nobody likes anything that's out.
It's not just me. Terrible
movies, man. I know it's hard,
especially hard when you've got a
bunch of different people involved.
Think about how much money it costs
to make a movie. Like the Avengers.
There's fucking millions and millions
dollars on the line as far as like they
have to spend and then the potential
profit is millions and millions more.
So there's so many people with so
much saying, trying to say like,
don't some male naval gets done.
You imagine just this podcast or
the way these conversations go.
What if we had so many in our ear and
every time we started bringing up a
certain conversation you'd
like cheese it with the,
they're the best of the white stuff.
I'm stopping started with that.
Ari guided the way back up on that.
That's what it happens.
You know, like, look,
I've been doing the UFC for you
know how long fucking who knows.
Weird to have them. Nine and seven is
very rare. Does anybody say anything?
But once we started going
on Fox, yeah, the, the,
the producer who actually
had to tell me in my ear,
the Fox executives like tell me to
take it down a notch. Come take it out.
Like when I get excited about something,
the way I get excited about it and then,
then it's, it's natural and
I'm pumping it up and I'm,
but I'm people like I'm actually fight.
Of course they like it,
but these fucking dummy
executives, they, the elevator.
While you're not saying the Fox ones,
I'm saying pretty much a huge group
of the huge percentage of the group of
people that is in the producer
position. A lot of them think
that their creative self did it.
Guess what everyone's going to be exactly.
The most people are going
to be fewer turnover. How to
deliver the way I deliver.
I'm delivery. I've been doing it
forever. The like it or they don't.
Most people like it. If
you don't, tough shit,
if it doesn't sound like you're fucking
baseball guys, your basketball guys,
it's not supposed to. You know,
it's not. It's not supposed to.
It's a different fucking sport
and this is just the way I do it.
If I was doing football, I'd
probably look you up. Disperse. Yeah.
You're lucky on on Chris. Well, I'm lucky
I got the job. Really. I'm lucky too,
but the whole idea behind
going in and like saying, oh,
we're going to fix all this and fix all
that. Like that's what happens in movies.
That's what happens on TV shows.
That's what happened.
It would happen to this podcast
are good at hiring a lighting guy.
If we brought in production
people and we said,
we're going to move the
podcasts or studio and butter,
he likes you to produce this,
just sort of take,
take some of the strain away from me.
You know, if you're having the same,
just talking my ear man. He says, hey
man, I'm thinking better. Take digits.
Change that subject. This is a
bad subject. Could you imagine?
You imagine how fucking crazy
we would go if you know, if, if,
if someone like that there was no
Brian moment and someone go, hey man,
you guys gotta stop that.
You get your papers.
I commercial breaks my podcasts. I do
commercial breaks. That's so stupid.
It's like I'd rather just
have a conversation, you know,
and now we'll be right back. Well no one's
doing it well these commercials. Okay.
Cause you're just talking it out.
And we do get them out of the way.
Bill Birtles that he went on a rant for
when he did flowers.com or something.
He just wanted to rant of how it,
cause it was Valentine's,
they come and I was like,
Oh,
you gotta buy it girlfriend flowers
to go to [inaudible] dot com I'll get
whatever presented goes. Well that's why
the fuck is that still a thing? Oh look,
they don't get any enjoyment out of it
either. The sex, we have to buy them.
That's still, he just goes on
this tangent back like, anyway,
so I go to flowers.com oh that's perfect.
Yeah.
That's Sorta sorta how we would do it.
We never really a way better way to do it.
I'm glad he's doing it because it
gives he as a comic, he's the same.
The way I feel.
It's like you don't want to have to say
the same thing over and over again. Well,
you doing commercials now too.
How are you doing your commercials at
the beginning of the beginning I'll say
what the episode's about.
I'll say this stuff into it,
my stand up and then the sponsors.
But do you do elaborate
on the sponsors at all?
Like how are you dealing with it until
it's like Amazon dealer came Florida and
you and you're doing it like a,
do you do it like the way we're doing it?
Like you just start talking, whatever
you feel about that. I'm just like,
this is the deal.
He bothering people.
So I use to express that like I have to
hate bothering people, but like anyway,
this'll get me money. You know,
people have complained about it,
but that's just a certain percentage of
the people are going to complain about
anything.
I feel like they used to radio though.
And when radio there's tons of
commercial all the time. Right?
I know we're not the same thing
as we know it looks similar,
but it is the same thing.
It's a conversation.
I mean most of these people
are listening this thing,
they could easily be listening
to the radio. It's very simple.
Iphones or iPods in their cars is a
huge percentage of the people that are
listening to this show because
everybody has their little hookup. Now.
It's so easy to have a USB port every,
you know,
most new cars like some like forwards.
I know your car picks it up Bluetooth so
you can out of course you can stream it
from your phone. So you, by
the way, if you don't have
that in your car,
there's something that I
recently purchased and it's
like this thing that you
put in your car and it's got three
speakers and you'd just goes right on your
visor and it automatically
connects Bluetooth Connect
to Bluetooth that once and
uh, it can either stream music to it
and also you can take calls on it.
So if you don't have it in your car,
I got this for I think $129.
I'll put it on my website.
But it's, it's good.
We'll have that like a lot from like from
like a phone to the car if they have,
if it's a music phone. Right.
And in California it's the law.
Like I know in Ohio you're still fucking
driving around and making phone calls,
but like a lot of places you can't do
that anymore. Yeah. You get tickets.
So people looking for people,
well on phones, every day, text
when you shouldn't got damaged.
Drives me crazy when I see someone looking
down their phone while they're giant
metal machines hurling 60 miles an hour.
I'm like, you know, 60 miles an hour,
you can cover a lot of God damn
distance and a couple of seconds.
And if you know anything about accidents,
that's how shit happens.
It happens like on a side. Boom.
I was, I was, uh, I was, yeah,
last accident I heard I was drunk.
I was texting trying to get to the
commerce where before last call without my
glasses launch without your glass
at some some,
some cab stopped and you don't expect
stop no reason. But they're hard.
You hit him.
I saw it last second stuffed into off,
it's still smashed him and then so
when a cop pulled over and was like,
and I was trying to get him to
wave off like no, we're good,
we got this covered right.
But it was like completely
because I looked away from
the road to cop waved off,
I waved off the cop like he was flown
down to like, do you guys need any help?
But like you know, I give him a sign up.
Like we're handling this like adults,
we're just exchanging insurance,
hammered, panicking, sweating, heart,
beating your chest. Also wondering,
am I get back to the store,
am I going to call it a breathalyzer
sound and be able to get my set.
That's what happens when you drink a drug,
but texting and driving, super similar.
You just look away from the road. I real.
I done it a few times here and there,
but I do it all the time.
You learned your lesson and you've never
done it since this accident, right?
Drink and drive. Yes. I
love to stay in hope show.
I don't know if it was before
or after and that was that one.
I think that might've been the last one
because nothing happened to that one.
I was beyond lit up.
I couldn't stay to the end real
needed to get Eric's rove home.
I drove home and I kept telling
myself that if I get to the store,
I only live a few blocks away
from the store. If I get there,
I'll just pull over there and I'm like,
what are you talking about?
Does it make any sense? Yeah,
you're blocked. It's 95%
that's 99% of the way there.
Dude. Why did you drive that? I was drunk
and I could not make the right decision.
I made the wrong decision and
luckily nothing happened. Ooh. Well,
how hard was it to stay in the lanes?
I think a concentrated hard,
I managed to do it but I shouldn't. I, it
wasn't like I'm jumping, jumping forward.
Like I think I can handle this,
but like almost everybody has,
but this was not one of those times.
That's scary dude. I hate hearing that.
Everybody out there learn from Ari. Don't
do that shit. That's a terrible thing.
Yeah. Scary. It was control your body man.
You'll have less control and you want
to feel like you have control but you
don't and you drive in a giant death
machine. Giant. That's what it is.
Everyone does it. Everyone drives a
little drunk. But it's like, you know,
you put that everyone
does it, man. I saw a lot
of it, but it's um, it's,
it's certainly a fucking problem.
I remember in high school though,
I used to have like a note,
like one drink and I'm done rule.
I don't know if you guys had that with
that one right way. No, I have had those,
especially if I'm driving, if I'm doing a
show that really can have a beer, maybe,
maybe two beers on stage,
but if I know I got to drive afterwards,
it's the worst feeling in the
world and you've got to sober up.
But Sam Kinison said it the best.
Well, you can't leave your car there.
How are you gonna get your car home like
that? Something like that. Toad. Yeah.
That's not realistic for most people know.
Most people.
It's not Vancouver [inaudible]
of all Canada. Vancouver,
at least they have super strict laws
so people just don't do it. Yeah.
I think that's one of the great things
about living in New York city that
everybody's just hiring cabs,
captain, subway, cab, subway.
You don't have to be responsible
for being hammered. Yeah.
But then you have to
live in New York City,
which I don't think I'm willing to do.
We've got to be there.
We're going to be a in New York
in May. Right. When is it Brian?
[inaudible] fourth. May 4th. Yeah.
Um, but the big the most, oh,
this weekend where the comedy magic
club too. Are you going to do it?
Maybe it just do Friday. Okay. What
night you want to do Friday night? Yeah.
Which show bull shows look, that's how
quick we roll. There's a gentleman,
that's what we make decisions. And
Saturday a little Esther doesn't know yet,
but I'm gonna ask her to do
it with a me and a docket.
So you're going to do just Friday?
Yeah. A little Lester in Dunkin fry.
So Ari and and,
and Dunkin on Friday and little
Esther if she wants to do it.
And Dunkin on Saturday this weekend.
Comedy Magic Club.
But the big one had saw for 20 in Atlanta.
That's my fucking special.
I'm taping it. This is the best
shit I've ever had. This is,
I could have taped a special a year ago.
You were ready a long time ago.
I'm fucked. I've never been
this black. I've got like,
I did an hour and 40 minutes the other
night and it was just all material really
just all look. Yeah, I
got a lot of shit. I went,
I went through all of it
and I don't think I still,
I still don't think I did everything.
I still have some other
stuff that I have to,
that I've written down that I liked
sort of abandoned along the way.
And I have to figure out where to put
certain things I want to try to get to.
It's like if he didn't get back to
it, it's like, okay, I didn't, I'll,
maybe I'll just start from here. From,
you know, for the next tier. Yeah. Yeah.
Like this never got good.
Yeah. There's some bits. Well,
there's some bits I can't keep doing. It
was just done with, I'm sick of it, right?
Yeah. I got to get rid of him. Even if I
don't, they don't make it to the special.
I'm getting rid of them,
but just holding you back creatively
after a certain amount of time there.
So April 20th at the Tabernacle.
Say It,
Brian Tabernac bowl habitat.
I have to tell [inaudible] how about,
how about angle in Atlanta? So,
uh, she moved up three dates,
Vancouver 29th through the
31st the comedy mix. Ooh,
one of the best clubs in the world.
Yeah. It has a big show. When was that?
April one no,
March 29th 30 31st March 29th through
the 31st comedy mixed in Vancouver.
Ari Shaffir who you
working with? Um, I dunno.
They're going to give me someone there.
They've got a good local scene. Yeah,
I think so. Yeah. There's a lot of
good comics. We were up there, um,
me and Gloria did sets there
last time we were there
and they had a great local scene,
which a lot of funny comics like
facility anywhere. West Coast. Yeah.
The Vancouver is awesome. It's one of the
greatest cities in the world. The wins,
like greatest city in the world all the
time. It's like friendly and worldly.
It's beautiful. It's west coast
that all chill back and laid back.
Food's incredible. Some of the
best restaurants. Jesus Christ.
We've had some incredible stakes at that
place. Yeah, I eman is amazing. That's,
that's how, that's one of my
favorite places to go ever.
So you're there March 29th 31st
31st and that comedy mix is the,
the downstairs of a hotel. Yeah. That's
the old Yaki. Yeah, we did once a long,
long time. Yeah. It's a great spot.
It's a perfect size to like the area
of downtown, wherever it goes out.
It's like two blocks away to a perfect
sized club. A place is amazing.
Yeah.
And then I think I'm doing an album.
I think I got to try this
again to take that thing.
So the first one didn't work out? No,
they just didn't get there in time.
They just fucked up the recording too
much. I didn't want to do it wrong.
What'd they do? They missed the first
three days. Why? They just didn't come.
Why not? They weren't, they
weren't organized. So they
were supposed to be there.
They never got there.
Yeah. Well who is this?
I don't know if I should say or not
say, but it was just delicious. No,
they were like, you wanna
do it again. I'm like,
I think I'm going to go and do it on my
own. I don't want to try this again. What?
That was really frustrating. They weren't
there Wednesday weren't the Thursday.
Oh, and you're killing. Yeah.
And Thursday was a super like
conservative crowd and Edmonton. But they,
they laughed super hard. It all the
cleaner jokes. Right. And I was like,
that's the best reaction. That was
clean jokes I've ever gotten. Right.
Like I would have liked
to have had that down.
And then Friday they sent somebody down,
but he's the system.
And then Saturday there was all
this feedback from the soda machine.
Oh No, they just couldn't
use two full bits. And I was
like, I want the hum. Yeah.
That shit's annoying. It's hard to
fucking get, get a, a special down.
There's a lot of pressure to just have
that moment be just like a real show.
Yeah. So that's why I'm doing a
lot of shows between now and then.
If you see me like adding shows,
that's exactly what's going on.
That's trying to get ready. Yeah. That's
why I'm doing, that's why I'm dealing, uh,
Hollywood of doing the Improv.
April 13th, 14th and 15th,
the Hollywood Calif, not California
rather, um, Hollywood, Lauren, Laura,
Florida. The uh, the one at the hard
rock. So that's a April 13th, 14th,
and then the 20th Atlantic. Oh,
in Louisiana we're doing, um,
the Improv in,
uh,
in Louisiana and Louisiana Improv in
Louisville, Kentucky. Say Louisiana.
Jesus Christ who don't have the living
talk tab or an ten one ml 33 30,
uh, March 30th through April 1st
we're at the Louisville, Louisville,
Kentucky Improv, Ken and get like right
and groove. I'm just trying to get,
I'm just, I'm getting up like crazy.
I'm just going to get up every weekend,
all week, everywhere. There's kind of
just banging out and listening to sets,
doing a lot of writing too. And I'm,
I'm also preparing for the next stuff,
so I'm sandwiching in new bits and I
find that when I do that I make my older
bits better anyway.
I'm just,
it makes my whole set better
when I'm new shit and had
a friend ask him about this. It goes
sometimes like store. He was like,
sometimes I feel like if I do this whole
bits I make them longer and like add
stuff to them. Yeah. But my, my theory
with that is you would that new stuff,
that new creative stuff that you put into
that you would put into the other new
bit. Yeah. Can you just make
your other bits better? It
is both. I think did a bit,
can cook for a certain amount of time.
Then after a while it's done. It's done.
Sometimes it's not done and you'll like
a year into this bit, you know, like you,
but then in the next year you'll come
up with all this great new shit to go
along with it and now it becomes like
a real piece that you're proud of it.
Then you can let it go. It's all, I'm
like knowing when to let it go. You know?
It's hard. Yeah. Friday
I'll be at the ice house,
but Joey Diaz and Doug Benson for
the ice house chronicles. Yeah.
Bridges in the icehouse
chronicles by the way,
are available only on iTunes
under the desk squad label. Um,
it's all free and everything.
And it's desk squad. Dot. tv.tv.
And that last one we did with Greg
Fitzsimmons and Jodie is Brody Stevens,
little Esther. We just put it up
so that's great. So that's it.
This weekend I'm at the comedy Magic
Club and her muscle beach on Friday night
with Ari shift fear and Duncan Trussell
and on Saturday night Dunkin and little
Esther come on down.
You dirty bitches.
And then of course all the other
information is available on Joe rogan.net.
The big one though is the
Tabernacle in Atlanta, April 20th.
It's going down two shows.
The first show is essentially sold out
this way to be there for a taping like
that. Just so you were there.
This is my best one. This is my,
I'm coming out guns blazing.
This is my best shit ever
and I'm going to release it.
Louis C K style on the Internet,
five bucks gingerly my last day.
But I gotta say is Dallas Improv.
What is that second week of April?
That's a huge spot for
you, man. That's awesome.
I'm glad prov letting me in and saying
like, let's see how well you do. Well,
we're going to have you on that. We
crushed that. What is it again? Uh,
Addison Improv when April,
let's say 11th to the 14th,
and they can calcification 12th through
the 15th, April, Addison Improv,
and they can give this information
to [inaudible] dot com.
It's all right there and
follow [inaudible] on Twitter.
Ari Shaffir, s h, a, f.
F. I. R. You fucking savages. All
right. Thank you everybody. Thank you,
Ari. It's always fun. Thank you
everybody tuning in and thank you. Uh,
all the powerful people. I want you to
tweet over there at your show at the show,
like four 20 Rogan or
something at a hackathon.
Hashtag [inaudible] for 20
Rogan or sounding Rogan.
Why not first said Brooklyn for 20?
Yeah, yeah, before 20 Roeger. Yeah,
for 20 Rogan.
Okay,
so that's the new Hashtag for Tony Robbins
leading up to the special April 20th.
So yeah. Beautiful. Well, I'm fucking
writing everyday for this thing.
I'm geared up,
I'm ready to rock and roll.
I've never been more prepared to do a
special or more excited to do a special,
I'm just excited about comedy right now.
You know,
part of it has been doing a lot of these
sets at the Ice House and doing the
icehouse chronicles and doing
these podcasts. I'm just
excited about everything,
man. I'm, I could, I've never
been happier. I'm in the
groove bitches. All right.
All right. Um, thank you to the
fleshlight. Please go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for the fleshlight.
Enter in the code name Rogan.
You will save 15% off and today,
this is the last day.
Today is Monday, March 19th
at midnight. This will expire.
But until then, if you go to [inaudible]
dot com and enter in the code name,
try it. You will save 35%
off single 30 count bottles.
Um, otherwise if you use the word
Rogan, you will save 10% off all orders.
That's the deal. Bitches. Please support
our sponsors. Please keep listening.
Please keep coming to our shows cause
the people that's way more into it.
That's where the group, I know there's
people listening. Yeah, man, we've got,
there's a movement going on here.
There's some crazy shit going down,
Ari Shaffir don't you feel it?
Feel it.
Headlining all over the
country now over the world,
you're international and they
sort of feel like fulfilled.
This is awesome as an artist, I'm sure.
Afraid to be on the road all the time.
Like, no, I professionally, I love it.
Are you selling out pitches? Get
in there. Go get some. That's it.
We will see you guys on Wednesday with a,
we don't even fucking know yet.
We don't even know who the guest is.
Sasquatch.
It's several hours getting Sasquatch
trying. I've been trying for years,
so you guys, thank you. Love you. Bye.