That's cool. Five, four, three,
two,
one a and [inaudible].
Brendan Schaub. What's up dog? Did
you buy those shoes yourself? Yeah,
I bought these. This one looks too much
flair for you. It's summer. Confident.
Confident move. I'll get the
tight pants around the ankles.
Just riding high enough to see the
Gucci shoes. Gucci Denim, Bro. Get it.
What's up, bro? You can pull it off.
You're making fun of medical like
Saudi.
Say like, yeah, I bet your girls like
Dez. I get girls also like Dick Dale.
That good flight. The chip
points then. It's true.
It's true. Dude. How about
these fights? Let's go. My God,
how about these fights?
How about I almost didn't see them.
Can I text you during the broadcast? The
ESPN plus thing was a nightmare, man.
Yeah, they had some hiccups. Yeah.
That'd be an understatement that
that has happened before. Right?
Well digital stuff,
they didn't stay 2019 though.
Especially with ESPN though.
That's where I was just shocked
and me being like a super fan.
I had to figure it out.
But you know how,
how I had to figure it out cause
it didn't work on any platform. So,
and it's a hiccup where you
can order it off the APP.
So you had to close the APP or it from a
desktop then shut down something and go
to your TV. It was a nightmare. But that
didn't work for me. And then I was like,
all right. And then I slowly was
missing the first fight. I'm like, man,
I got to figure stuff out.
And I tweeted out as having problems and
2000 savages sent me links to illegal
streams,
legal or illegal.
But of course you didn't watch
those illegal street didn't Joe?
And I'm glad you pointed out I did not,
but if I were going to,
would it be awesome? It was awesome.
It was HD and had zero problems.
I was going to glad you didn't
because they could track you that face
recognition software. They could,
they could definitely attract me.
It's a huge problem.
Well it was definitely a huge problem
for the first event. I don't know. Uh,
I don't know how many people
downloaded it and did it,
but I bet they probably
didn't see the number coming.
It was a big fight and those two
fights were huge. I mean, first of all,
something happened.
Um,
I think within the last year or so
for Max Holloway were like when Max
Holloway's face goes up on the screen,
people let people go nuts because
they know he throws down. Yeah,
I think it was the Ortega fine.
I really think that Ortega fight
made him a superstar. I really did.
The Aldo ones definitely helped us.
Tabak Aldo ass weapons.
And then the Ortega,
one thing that was different,
those Ortega had a big following.
Ortega was the young beautiful lion lion
with fantastic Jujitsu's handsome guy.
Cool, smooth talker. Looks like
a champion, fucking everybody up.
So he had a lot of fans coming
in there and they went to war.
They went to war and Max came out on top.
And I think Max,
a lot of those pm because they were
so cool with each other during,
before and after,
people loved it to Max is he loses
better than anyone on the fucking planet.
We'll loses or wins. He just goes, Hey,
I'm, I'm, I'm just going to get better.
He doesn't lose a lot. He doesn't
know. I mean, he lost a Connor.
He lost consciousness. He on his very
first fight ever, you know, 20 years old.
But I also think Max,
is it because we've always said,
I think both of us had been an agreement
where if a guy is cutting a ton of
weight and killed himself, go to the
next weight class. I've always said that,
whether it was a Darren till,
whether you know, uh, Chris Weidman,
Luke Rockhold, Jon Jones, like
Duke Golf, the way class dominate.
And then this is kind of the first time
we've seen a guy where it's like, hmm,
it's not that easy because
Mac Taller we went up.
But you could see the power wasn't
there. Like he might, he and he did,
he landed more than a dozen portray.
But when Dustin landed it,
you could see that it fucking counted.
Dustin is big dude. He's big Mary.
He smiled at 45. He used to fight at
45 and it really struggled there. Um,
but at 55,
he's found a spot and you look at him,
he almost looks like a welterweight.
I mean he's bit,
it looks like Tyron Woodley size and
he cuts a shitload of weight and Max
Hallway in that fight just looked like
they didn't look like the same. No,
just purely like fucking meetings.
And you gotta give credit to Poirier too
because if you look at the two of them,
like after the fight there was a big
difference between the amount of damage,
the poor.
It landed a big difference.
He was hitting him with big shots
and it wasn't just big shots,
it was shots period.
He was hitting him with really clean,
well time shots with great head movement,
great movement about that knee dude.
Everything split open his head at
everything. He did everything great.
I mean he really,
that was a coming out party for Dustin
Poria and a lot of ways or the common fan?
Well yeah, well the people
that knew him from the gauge,
you fight noon from the Eddie
Alvarez fight, they knew that man,
he beat these two really good guys.
But Max Holloway might be one of the best
pound for pound fighters in the world.
And I think is, I think is to Max
always the greatest one 45 or wild time.
I think he's a damn good 50 fiver but,
but 55 could be tough for Max.
Well this is a great example of what
we've always said about the differences
between the size of people. And
this is it. It's, it's first of all,
I mean all credit to uh, Dustin Poirier
cause he put on a phenomenal performance.
He got, you know, he got tested in that
fight. He came through. Let me see.
We talked about in the post
fight interview that he got
hurt in the third round.
He came through and just super impressive.
Think about as [inaudible] Anthony Pettis,
Anthony Pettis,
world champion [inaudible] world
champion. Eddie Alvarez, world champion.
Max Holloway, World Champ pedes
one though. Wasn't that an injury?
I feel like pedis got injured
and they stopped the fight.
Like did he break his hand?
Is that what happened? No.
Feel like the pedes one was an injury.
He had the issues with Eddie Alvarez.
Right. Which was a no
contest. Yeah. I think,
well there was one fight
where Dustin Poirier and
no. Yeah, I think, I think that was it.
There was remembered with pedes were
pedes broke his hand and Duke Roufus
stopped the fight. Remember that? Tony
Ferguson, was it 21st Tony Ferguson.
You're right. You're right. But
I think that was a great round.
Maybe it was an injury. I was a rib
member. Oh that's right. That's right.
Dustin got on top of him
and hurt his wrist. Right.
But still look at port A's when Smith.
Yeah. Well that's a weird one too. Right?
It's cause like what was that rib injury
from it pouring a body shot. Yeah.
What was that from? Was it
from the takedown? Like what
was it? Something happened.
I don't remember. That's right. But
either the portal or like a Tko. Yeah.
You look at portrays his list, man, the
guy, so who's fighting, who's lost too.
It's so impressive and portrays the guy.
Same thing with when Michael Bisbing one,
I always root for those guys,
those guys who've been around forever
and they fight the best of the best.
They might lose one or two here,
but they've been around for so long.
You just hope there's a title at
the end of their career. Yeah.
You just hope and it sometimes doesn't
look like it's going to happen.
Then when it does happen, I
just, I'm just so happy for them.
Such a good guy to Dustin Poirier,
great guy. He's a great guy.
He's smart and he's ambitious.
Seal Vons, favorite fighter.
Works hard to those lyricists that
seeing those two guys together,
that was hilarious. Calling them the
right both with the same whole school.
How about Theo was yelling instructions.
I'm going to,
I seem them on King of saying I'm
going to roast the shit out of him.
Did you take them down and went,
what? What is happening right now?
Why does this happen?
Yeah.
Shouting and strategically the
UFC provides me with a headphones.
I was hoping you'd shoot a
turnaround like, dude, what
are you doing? I'd love to,
you know, he's the best. Yeah,
just character, unique kid.
He was so happy. He was so
happy. I mean, him bet. Well,
I just bet because I'll see him and you
thought that I thought I'm not going to
be a great fight. I thought Max at 55
if everything was in care with them,
I thought Max would probably get it done
by noon, was going to be a good fight.
I was just betting feel because Theo is
boys with Dustin friend from the same
area, so it's just a friendly bet. I
would never bet against us and boy,
look at these fulls.
Hilarious. That's amazing.
How about,
how about a few?
He feels never been to a fight before
and he texted me halfway through goes,
dude,
I can't believe you did this shit.
I go maybe a little respect now
around king the staying, right.
You're your little fucking respect row.
Yeah.
He was looking at it as a
complete outsider who has
no idea. I told him, I said,
it's super intense and you're seeing
for the best fighters on planet earth,
you're seeing the very,
very best shootouts man,
the Kelvin gas to lump style
bender fight was it shoot out.
Best title fight from me
I've ever launched ever.
It's one of the best fights of
all time has to be. It has to be.
And when you see style under to get
rocked in the first one dropped.
You like Ho Lee Shit. I think he's
best thing that happened to them.
It's a good thing. I think it's a good
thing for career wise and going forward.
It's a good thing you
face a little adversity.
We see that he's not going to get
hit and crumble and you got one,
you got a special dude in style and how
good is Kelvin God damn. He's tired.
How fast? Our fucking hands. He's so
fucking tough. And even after all that,
I mean style bender was t and off on
human that fifth round and Calvin is
finding a way to survive.
Great incredible style.
Benders face looked like he was
allergic to shellfish and she sees
how quick the fourth round
he was helping the band.
He was in a war Kelvin hidden with
some bombs, man bombs. And it's also,
I think it's good. We saw, we saw a
sign, you get hit and get knocked down.
You saw him get taken down.
We saw it happens when he's off his back.
Look pretty fucking do it. He's
triangle. He's transitions locked up.
Who knows what the fuck would happen
if that was early in the fight,
they were dry. So I think that that fight
for [inaudible] checked all the boxes,
but also what's great about this is
Kelvin stock doesn't go down. No.
If anything, I'd watch that guy fight
whenever, whenever, and let's be honest,
he's really a welterweight.
Correct.
He's super small for Deron
till can make 170 pounds.
So soaking Calvin, it's
a discipline thing. Yes.
I just think there should be more
weight classes. I don't even think it's,
I don't think he's to your boy,
Dana Man as well as 65 you
could text mean no one can.
No one listens to me and I don't
want them to really? Yeah, I do.
I'd rather just stay out here and talk
about it. Yeah. I want it to evolve.
But what happens if I pushed it? I've
said, I think there should be a way class.
Every time I get out outta here,
we could like dangle the carrot like Yo,
we'll do a fight campaign every time a
one 65 or fights and just dangle that kit.
He's surprised it wouldn't do it.
Probably still wouldn't do it. It's um,
it's one of those things where like,
I think they'd like it the way it is.
If it ain't broke,
don't fix it,
but it doesn't make sense because if
you're going to do all these interim belts
went up to 65, I think they
belts on belts, on belts.
You think they would think
that it's watered down.
They have too many weight classes that
people would just be jumping back and
forth from weight class, which they would
be talking about chaos, which I love.
But you would also have people that
find a way class where they could be at
their best versus either have to bulk
up or have to drop too much weight and
compromise yourself. But you're happy
medium for a lot of guys that are not,
they're not hitting that
happy medium right now.
We were not getting their best
performance, but here's the thing about,
so if Kelvin's should be one seven year
style benders, a small lady, Fiverr,
he weighed in at one 83 up.
He weighed under the weight limit.
So look at how big some of these guys are.
Oh my God.
Brandon Davis to get the spicy 35 it was
one 60 dude that was branded neighbors,
right? Was it? Who said that? Well,
some of those 80 fibers like you
look at Jack Gray, get Yoel Romero,
Joe or mouth check. You antique dig
it looks like. We'll see what I mean,
it's going to happen. Think about Yoel
Romero stop it. Like you'll rebuild Jack.
Dude,
it's a big fight style or could probably
make one 70 easier then fucking 85 85
is a a big way club. That's why you have
you seen the talk? It makes no sense.
Style Benner and Jon Jones.
That's crazy. What are we doing?
Who the fuck's picking up on it?
It's just cause they're talking shit.
I can't find it. Just the last
card. Just A, I see it right here.
It just says, yeah, he ballooned
back up to hundred 60 pounds,
but it was Brandon Davis right
from 35 he's really talented.
It's crazy when I'm standing next to him
and this guy waiting at 35 because I'm
looking at him, he looked to all
of 165 pounds. I was like this.
He looked so bees five 10 he looks so
big for that one 35 pound weight class.
So like this is crazy.
Well Max at 45 so fucking huge.
The UFC performance institute gave
him the green light to do that. Wow.
So they must have known
what they were tilling.
Since David's site with Costa was a
first and the bandwidth division said he
needed to make serious
sacrifices to get there.
He said he cut out drinking alcohol's
Shit and ran 20 miles per day to line in
order to make the weight. By the
time he stepped in the octagon to 36,
he had ballooned back to this dude.
He's really big man.
He must be huge for the thing
is at the, the, he was also,
he was not just like tall, but
he's like, he's thick like you can,
it's weird how you can lose that much
weight, but why not just find a 45?
Why Kill Yourself? Like why fight at
45 he floods a beat and his last fight.
Well yeah. Has a beat. Macramed
Sharapov um, it's a beat.
Got Him in that crazy arm bar from the
back or leg. Leg Lock for the back. Yeah.
Which is so nasty from filthy back
mount fills nasty. There's two night.
I know. It's crazy. That's
a crazy move, right? I,
but I think when I think of one 85 hours,
think of Luke Rockhold. He shoot, man.
Yeah, it's a big ass. He's huge.
But then Whitaker's not like,
I think freakishly big. I think Luke's
done with 85 and he's at two oh five now.
He has a fight lined up already,
but I mean is he going to stay there
as he's just doing it for one fight?
Pretty sure he's staying there.
Probably a good idea.
But then you look at Whitaker
who's 85 such huge. He's stocky,
but he's not like huge.
He's like the perfect size Whitaker
cause he's still can knock out anybody.
But he's got awesome cardio and too,
he's strong and he's not
as strong as Yoel Romero,
but he's strong enough to hold them off.
No one is who is, you got to get that,
that Cuban gene pool to get that because
you know what I'm saying? Like there's,
there's certain gene pools like that
fucking mountain from game of Thrones.
There's some gene pools
out there, man. Yeah.
And then we throw in steroids in that.
Oh, you do you see as unable to it.
Of course he did. Of course he did. Yeah.
Yeah. She was like, yeah, no shit. Yeah.
And then when they kept asking him about
it, they go, he currently taking us.
Listen, I don't really want to talk about
this. It's like, yeah, no, of course I am.
Why are they asking questions like that?
Yeah, it's the strongest man contest,
but think about, come on. Yeah. Look Dude.
Who's going to win? Who gives a fuck?
How about a style bender,
verse Whitaker the all oceanic fight.
Are you really going to fly to Australia
for that? Are you thinking about it? Two,
three, two dudes on this planet
and get me to fly to Australia too.
There's not it. No Dude's on
this planet alive though. Here.
Rather be here. You're
crazy. I love Australia.
But now if
Rihanna was like, Yo Dude, get to
Australia, I'm like, I'm on my way.
Say No more fam, but not two
dudes. Yeah, but that fight, dude.
I want to see that fight in the
flesh. Live. You're going to do it.
I think I might.
I want to see how that goes down.
I want to see fight Whitaker
is a fucking animal man.
Just thinking about how much pain that
guy had to be in to an almost fight with
a hernia and a ruptured, he
had a ruptured rectum, right?
Was it ruptured rectum, I thought was
just a hernia. No, it's fine. No, no.
I think he had two major injuries.
No,
I know his intestines were
popping through. Yeah, but
I think it was another one,
Dan,
his rectum was fucked up too,
isn't that it didn't have a
tear because I called a Jamie.
You'll find a hemorrhoid. No, no, no.
Like a tear in his ass. Well, you don't.
You think about the firehouse
drain from sparring.
Just think about getting taken down
while you're trying to throw a kick.
You land fucked up on your hip.
Never ripped my asshole.
You can rip your ass hole.
I'm just saying I never check.
You'd catch a kick in the ass
hole easily. For sure. Sure.
People whose eyes about
someone misses spinning back,
kick low and it just catches your tank,
man.
Just the heel hits your taint,
rips your talent away from the bone.
That shit happens.
I wonder what,
I don't know what the odds would be out.
Assume Whitaker is a slight favored
in that fight. I would say so, yeah.
I would say based off one to Elvin did
well based off with Calvin did based off
Whitaker's uh, two fights with EOL.
He's been the only guy to hold EOL off,
although some have said that. I did
think that you all won the second fight.
Interesting. I thought you, Oh, I think I
could go either way. It's scoring Yo. Wow.
Had them rocked and
hurt by the new scoring.
I felt like it should have been worth
more. He thought she'd been a 10. Eight.
Yeah. I mean he had him almost out
hurt. He had them. He staggered.
We didn't see him do that to Yo al,
but,
but he did one more round and survived.
He survived. He wanted more rounds.
It's like how much are those the draw,
if you're watching a fight,
if a fight is a fight, if it was, I
mean, I not understand it. It's a sport,
but it's the sport of fighting.
If you're watching a fight and one guy
is really fucking a guy up and the other
guy never does that, who do you think
won that fight? Do you see that?
You're right. You can't. Yeah,
but do you think the guy that just moves
around and touches him with the Jab,
and I'm not saying this what Whitaker
did, but just, just as a, what if,
if a guy's just moving around for
four rounds and he's touching you,
the jab and lake kicking you and shut,
and you were like fighting in the street,
but then in the fifth round
you knock him down four times.
You beat the fuck out of him. He's running
away from you. His nose gets bloodied,
you end the fight with your hand
raised without a mark on your face.
You know the guy's face is pizza.
Maybe I'd look at my boys back, Dan,
for that first 20 that boy was moving.
Right, right, right. It's a quick,
it's a good question.
It's cause like what,
how much is that round as a sport
though? Yeah. That's what it is.
Because as a sport, yeah, to judge it.
If you're going to judge it
on a scorecard, you have to,
it has to be accumulative.
The question is like how much is it worth
for a guy to really take it to a guy
and almost stop him? See, I don't
think there should be more draws.
I don't have a problem with the drawl.
I don't have it.
Promise to drink with that fight. If it
was drama. That makes sense. Redo it.
Let's get it clear.
Club winner.
I think when a person gets really rocked
like that, it's worth more than a point.
I think it's worth more than two points.
I think it's worth a lot.
You think she'd be like ten seven? I think
it's a big deal. Got Done. You fuck you.
Fuck you are fucking real life
because of the rough. Well No,
cause you're kind of fucked,
right?
Like the idea that you
could go through a round,
you don't know who won right around where.
It's like a lot of feeling out,
a lot of touching, you know, this and
that and you know. Okay, perfect example.
First Round Anderson
Silva versus style vendor.
You could give it to style
bender for sure, but it was,
it was a round where they
were feeling each other out.
There was not one big moment where,
Oh my God, style benders taken over.
This fight is almost done.
So that's ten nine but yet another fight
where a guy beats the shit out of a guy
and doesn't drop him and
they have exchanges but the
guy gets rocked and hurt.
That is that ten nine to, I know it's
weird. What if he head takes them a drop?
Some of the guy barely survives.
You Hammer fists and attended the bell.
Is it ten nine in the old system it is,
but what is it in the new system?
Is it ten eight but if it's,
even if it's ten eight I think it should
be more than ten eight like that kind
of went out,
but the only thing is your fuck.
Let's say do a ten six or ten seven then
you get dropped. It's going to be tough.
You got to get away to his g
argument against what I'm saying.
Here's the argument against it.
Frankie Edgar versus gray Maynard
especially the first one, right?
Gray Maynard drops him as him
badly hurt in the first round.
Frankie manages to survive and come back
and win enough rounds and win the fight.
It's exception though,
but it is the exception.
It's kind of like if you gave him
like five points for that round.
Well it's kind of like with a Roundtree
and Eric Anders to how the fuck did
where people scoring those rounds?
Ten nine. Yeah. That's ridiculous.
The fuck are you doing a perfect exam?
What are you doing?
That's a promise that a ten nine
that was in a competitive fight.
How good is Roundtree look how good
you said something on the Brown.
He said that he likes and everyone's,
someone's booking a trip with cow shit.
Where the fuck was he at? They're
making fucking plane trips to Pooh cat.
My only thing is with that is once
the grappling like out there, hey man,
I don't know man, but get somebody to
help them get somebody that motherfucker,
he throws some of the nastiest inside
leg kicks and so fast and he was total
Thai style.
I wish I could lift my arms up shoulder.
You can tell you it and just style.
But he was a lady's leg dude.
His timing, his speed was off
the charts. He fucked his leg up.
I hope they are ganders posted a picture
today about it. But um, how tough.
First of all, how fucking tough as
Eric is. Coaches. What are you doing?
This is not a title fight.
There's nothing really on the line here.
It's just not his day. Couldn't ask
him to plan for financing to quit.
They just wouldn't ask him to quit.
He's so fucking coaches. Half the,
he's so tough. Crimson tide alumni
monster did geo Jon Anik said,
what'd he say?
He said it.
He goes and he loves winning
fights because then Bruce
buffer as to say your boy.
Oh really? Oh boy. Oh boy.
That's hilarious. He's a bad motherfucker.
Boy, he's a bad motherfucker.
Cause that guy does not
have a long history of mixed
martial arts like a lot of
these guys, man, way more athletic
than, than a lot of them. But look,
Kahleel athletic, it's fucked too, man.
You know, he speaks down to 20 pounds.
He was huge. And if
you met him, great guy.
He seems like a great guy to train
with them. Monster. I'm just,
well I was impressed when he knocked
out coconuts hockey and then um,
I know he lost a Johnnie
Walker who's just a beast.
I don't know what to make of Johnny
Walker. Ooh, he's care. I'm on the train,
but I'm kind of like, come
on. Where are we at? Me Too.
I'm pulling. I'm on the back.
Johnny. He's a bad motherfucker,
dude. He's something
special. He's just something,
I'm not hope he didn't hurt it's
fucking shoulder when he fell,
did that worm thing.
I hope.
I hope he didn't really hurt himself
because if we really hurt himself and they
can't fix that,
that would be a damn shame.
If the way he got injured is falling down,
playing around after
a spectacular victory.
I thought he came out and said he
was fine though. His man of Shit.
He's fun would say that.
I would say that too.
You got to tell everybody you're fine.
We'll fix this.
We'll fix it does look like a fruit.
He's a freak dude. He has crazy power.
Carets he power.
He's scary.
And he got Kahlil with a an elbow with
close up when those elbows where your
hands up high in the clench. But
it was beautiful. Flatline them.
Who was the way he did it though?
Like the tech look,
anybody gets flatlined with that
fucking elbow and knee buddy.
That guy hits hard.
And how about that's the site.
That was the reason why Cleo went to
Thailand. This noise, it's beautiful.
And now he's all in. He's
like, he's moving there.
It's going to move his family there. He's
going to do all his camps. So intense.
It's so intense. But when you have
results like that, like I love it.
I love a story like that.
I love a story like that till a
grappa comes around goes, that's cool.
Thailand riding elephants and shit. Check
this out. That's what I'm worried about.
Who kept top team and a lot of those
places out there in Aka Aka Mike's quicks
place. They must have wrestling, I'm sure.
Right. Came out of Ak and that's true.
I see academy. But Mike Swick
wasn't exactly wrestling. Well he,
but he knows this deal always with
wrestlers though. You're right.
I mean he knew how to wrestle Swick do
everything. Yes, it's true. And he's been,
the gay was, I'm sure they got a mother,
but is that where he's at? Ak k out there.
He's got his place out then I'll say. Is
that we're clear? Is that, I do not know.
I think he's at straight kicking on him.
I think he's doing the really
hard style drinking coconuts.
He actually yelled lady
boys, go to his, um,
see if can go to Clio Roundtree juniors
Instagram page because he posted thanks
after the fight. Was a lot
of people doing it. Well,
a lot of people are going to Thailand.
I think there's something to it, man.
Learning in the motherland
with those dudes, you know,
watching those guys work out and
train just to be in that environment.
It's like good for the soul.
Nobody would be like, he's the
nicest guy. Joe, the nicest guy.
That's caleel's Instagram.
That's me. And Him and his crew,
he used to work at like a MMA warehouse
and sell shirts when he's 300 pounds.
It was like, dude, I want to fight. That's
crazy. See if, um, there's a thank go,
go to the back to the, um, oh,
that's it right there. I'm sorry.
Go back to that one to see her there it
says teddy bear peachy indeed boxing.
See that? Click that. Click
on that. That's the dude
I'm thinking. Does the gym,
so he's with or that's one of
his friends came and pitched him.
He's training with them right there.
That's the gym there. Yeah. Oh,
that's not what I'm saying. Let's see.
I want it. Damn. That dude is in shape.
I want to say, listen, you want a
little Roundtree junior kicking you?
You're probably better off in that shit.
Fucking yeah.
You gotta be shaped like a test.
That dude was probably his pads
guy that helped him with his pants.
He's doing work, man. Damn. Look at
the legs on that fucking tattoos. Oh,
he's on that western diet son.
He's like,
pass on the Pad Thai and get me the
Donald Trump pad. Thai. Fuck that noise.
There's something too.
I think it's good for the soul.
Might be so being over there you mean?
Yeah. There's something about Kahleel man.
Oh, this is a t I Tammy's doing
this just to make us laugh.
Thank you son of a bitch.
Shut up to that guy.
There's something about being in a
place where something was invented.
It must give you like some extra
juice ever done Jujitsu in Brazil.
No Man shall place. I mean they hate
white people put special place. No, no,
they hated,
but yeah,
especially when you're fighting Nogueira
doing jujitsu fight. No. Yeah, it was fun.
And your Jujitsu guy. Yeah. Yeah. You
came from Jujitsu. So for you to fight,
knowing that was a thing like, right,
like if you fought a Jujitsu guy,
and remember the early days,
if a Jujitsu guy fought Jujitsu guy,
I'd be a real issue.
And that you're just a community.
Like why don't you fight somebody else?
Remember with the Anderson,
he didn't want to fight other Brazilians.
That's where we fought. Like towels,
ladies and Damien Maia. Yeah. It
was like the worst fights ever.
That's Ryan strange, weird.
The talus latest fight.
It's like almost like you just kind of
let them survive because it was Brazilian.
That's crazy. Like p one fuck each
other. No, I think it's like a,
do you think it's a nationalistic thing?
They think they made like they
take care of each other. Yeah.
Tail slate. This was good. He
wouldn't take any chances, right?
I think it's too much a respect
thing. Yeah, I think so.
So you think it was a Brazil thing?
Although with feet doorbell for silicon,
cool story flick to the face.
But,
but the thing with Damien Maia
was they had like a real problem.
There was some sort of like real uh,
animosity between them.
Cause Remember Damien Maia? I think the
mask. Yeah. No, no. That was a detour.
You're right. But he was yelling at
Damien Maia. I'll try it. And Damon,
this is disrespectful
percent some act this way.
There's something going on there.
When Ashton,
when he's fighting other Brazilians,
it sucked. And then he blew himself out
going after Damien Maia and then coasted
for the last few rounds. Remember? Yes.
That was a big deal.
Matt.
It was in Dubai and Chris Weidman
fought on the same card and Bj Penn.
That's when Frankie Edgar beat Bj Penn.
Right? That's a new one. The title,
I heard the, I heard Khabib. Next fight
might be in Dubai in September. Whoa dude.
Khabib is pack your bags custody
versus Dustin. Whoo. That is,
that is going to be wild. That's
going to be wild. That's yeah.
That's how fucking dust man
Ken crack does and crack.
He can crack. I mean he's
a, he's an interesting cat.
It's like how good is he going to
be able to fend off that grappling?
How good can anyone fended off?
It's going to be hard. No one can.
It's going to be hard. I'll tell you
what, the fight is not. I had them on.
My show is just engaging and he was like,
do I love to fight Khabib? He's like,
what's he gonna do to me? I was like, take
you down to, I can wrestle my ass off.
And I scramble. That's where he
gets guys in the scramble. He goes,
and that's what I specialize in.
He's a wild man.
You know one thing I believe that
isn't all that believe. Well,
I believe you would want to fight.
I don't mean wild like
he's not calculating,
but I mean wild and that he takes risks.
Correct.
He calculates his ability to perform
in those risks, but he forces action.
He wants to carry the reason why he
forces action. It's definitely technical,
but he's, he's a risk
taker. He's not laying back.
Like if we just talked about Anderson
Silva versus Talus latest, that was a,
that was not a risk taking fireball.
Fuck that motherfucker.
Never had fights like
that. Never. Just to gauge,
you know why he says he gets your soul?
He says he fights that way
because he doesn't have the car.
He goes out of the way. I fight. I
don't have the cardio to go fight.
Like my style isn't conservative.
I have to get it in two phases.
We'll with Khabib that those are issues.
Men. Yeah. Fucker. We'll go all five.
All five. And I don't know who's
going to beat Khabib. He's big too.
[inaudible] numbers can be,
can be struggled for 55 he struggled
can be scary until he got like his
nutrition on track member.
He'd had some issues.
He's a fucking phenomenal grapple.
I don't know who's going to beat him.
He's so good. His grappling soagain we
tied up Connor's legs in that first round.
I was like, Christ, this is early
on. I think maybe Tony Ferguson.
Tony Ferguson has a real good chance of
making it interesting because of his own
wrestling and it's scramble ability.
Tony's a wild screening for this 21st
seen gate. They're both available.
Everyone else's matched up.
It's pure chaos.
But I bet Tony is pissed and wants a
shot at the title, which um, you know,
he was on his way to that when his knee
ripped apart at a fucking promotionally
tonight thing. So crazy tripping.
All the desires of freak incident.
Talk about a guy who
deserves the title shot. Yes.
And a guy who people have kind of like
forgotten in the mix of all these killers.
There's so many 55 pounders that are
just straight up killers, masters,
you know what I mean? It's
what a, what a wild do vision.
You look at 55 70 85 that's,
there's never been a better time to be
UFC fans in his murderers fucking row.
It really is. You look at it, go, oh
Mike, I really like, I was looking up,
the matchups are stop. And I'm
like, what the fuck? He's a showy.
I look at one seven areas.
If you had to think of style,
bender is Joel Ramiro to scaries
fight. Pretty scary fight, right?
Scary for everybody. He's scary
for everybody. Still 40 years old.
Jesus Christ, every bit of it to
enjoy every bit of monster monster.
And so explosive and
the fucking wrestling,
his wrestling as on it's from another
planet and they get an explosive in
striking. Yeah, he'll fuck you
up. He'll spinning back fist. You,
you always got to worry about him
exploding nightmare because you've got to
worry about him exploding. If you try
to catch a break, if you like you,
you know you're standing on the outside
and your bolt breathing and you're
moving, you're like, maybe this
is a time I'm gonna catch a break.
And then all of a sudden he flying knees,
you in the face.
He didn't see a comment. And
whether you're Whitaker, uh,
style Ben or whoever wins that fight in
Australia, you're, you got Yoel Romero it,
yeah, he's number one. I'm
sure he's going to fight him,
but how much longer can he do that when
father time go y'all, you're special.
But yeah, let's go. Yeah, when is it,
you know, but Whitaker also might,
might,
the thing with Whitaker's,
he gets seriously injured after
every fight and has to have surgery.
When's that going to catch up
with him? Well, let's style
benders. Healthiest. Fuck,
that's true.
But is it the shellfish but healthy is
when you're that good and you go that
hard.
I mean to train as hard as he must trained
to be as good as Robert Whittaker is
the human body. Like look, Cain Velasquez
is the great example of that, right,
for that explosive like those guys.
But he has unbelievable work ethic.
Correct. That's part of what it
is. Mad. Correct. It's just the,
the ability to push through pain,
the ability to just keep
working and working and
working and we're in crying and
attack and that way when
you're in those fights,
like a guy like Cain would put it on
people to the point where they couldn't
believe it was real. They were
like, this doesn't even make sense.
Like how was he coming after me?
Still like how is he not tired?
What the fuck is going on here?
But you know who can do that and dish
decides whether or not he's going to do as
Jon Jones,
Jon Jones and do this,
what we're not suffering from those
kind of enacting. And John does.
What style do you do? You're a grinder.
Let me show you how to grind. Yeah. Oh,
you're a striking or you're a striking
the expert. Let me shed a strike. Yeah,
he's so fucking good man
style bender and Jon Jones.
Why are they talking shit to each other?
I didn't know what started it. Uh, yeah.
Um, John did a it, it originally,
it started, it did start with John.
He came out in the interview and goes,
you know, style benders looking good.
He's fine. 85 only a matter of time before
I think we cross paths, which is silly.
And then style bender, I think
TMZ asked him, he's like,
guy or already beat one goat.
I need another one. You know,
I'm just getting started. But if you're
John, why are you even engaging in this?
Why are you pressing it down,
John? Because Sanchez, well,
it's great for John because he
wants to let everybody know, hey,
I'm the best motherfucker on the planet,
this guy.
But he wants to let everybody know,
like when he's,
when there's a car that's about
someone. I mean, he's active now, right?
Jon Jones got momentum.
Now think about where he's at right now.
He's in his thirties right.
Long Ass fucking career as
champion as the best every second.
He's on a run right now.
That's what I think.
I think they took it away from him for
all those months when he tested positive,
that long suspension,
all that time off,
all money that he should have made all
the legacy that he could have laid down.
And I now,
I think,
I think he's just fucking chasing it and
the best about it all about it. However,
talking to 80 183 pounders,
kind of silly. Yeah,
but what if you say that in an interview?
I don't think that's that disrespect.
I don't either. By the way. He said it
is at one day maybe we're going to fight.
Yeah.
But then style bender,
you know TMZ ass and they don't
know shit about finding like, oh,
this guy's baked, this guy's big.
They're both black. Let's fight.
They have no idea. You know, that's
what they think. Right. So then,
then it gets picked up. But then also
I think Jon Jones is the hot, you know,
senior in high school and style benders,
the new freshman who saw it and it's
like mean girls like fuck that dude.
It's also a wonder how much of this is
like they all agree is good for business.
It's entertainment. It was looking
at cotton is anytime there's a fight,
blast something out.
Well not just blast something out.
I mean Connor is real good about that,
but like the way he's
able to turn these shit,
talking back and forth into
publicity for fights. They are,
there is real shit talking is
psychological warfare, but it also hypes,
people love to know and like the Khabib
fight all the craziness that led to the,
obviously that backfired when could be
tried to fucking attack him after it was
over and was,
it was an email.
The other people punched him in
the head and all that craziness.
The Biebs never been bigger.
Look Khabib's never been bigger.
Connor's never been bigger. And yeah, I
mean he needs to fight. He needs to fight.
He's a fight. He needs to fight. You
guys know this. I ride Connor's nuts.
I read compete nuts. Stomp enters
nuts. But with Connor, I'm like, God,
how hopefully something gets lined up,
but what I'm trying to say is like that
shit talking keeps you relevant. It was,
yeah, it's worth something. It's worth
something green. Both of them agree.
Like if style bender and Jon
Jones did decide to fight one day,
that shit's worth something to
both of them. Agree. Yeah. Agree.
Does a big gap between 85 and two oh
five though, man. John's a giant tool.
Fiverr,
John,
John could beat up any heavyweight
in the world with these could beat up
probably six of them in a night.
So to fight a one 83 or is weird.
Yeah. Well obviously he wouldn't be one
83 if style bender was going to do it,
I'm sure he'd want to put some,
some weight on. Imagine that just,
that's such a nightmare,
but it's the best.
What makes style Ben or special cause
those guys same as mashed hollering.
He goes, I'll fight anyone.
Yeah, sure. That's, that's
what it's all about. Also like,
and this is not a knock on Santos or
you know, the level of competition,
but at two oh five there's really
nothing there he get excited about.
There's just not, you look at the other
divisions. Santos can be a fun fight.
He's going to be a plus 700
plus 800 underdog. So, you know,
but I liked that John's active. I like
watching John beat everyone's ass. Yeah.
It's, it's one of those things now
where you've got to find contenders
for John, right? Because there's
no one is really standing out.
Rockhold would be cool at
two oh five so heavyweights,
the Dominique gray has just beat. Who did
he beat? Did he fight on Rosedin Mirror?
No. Yeah, he did. And I didn't think
he beat him. And I'm a race fan,
but you can be dosed a minute. I thought
he'd lost. Yeah, that's what I was.
How's it weird decision
that, so that one is, look,
Vulcans are very good fighter,
no doubt about it.
But you saw with Daniel Cormier
did to him. Neither one of them.
I ready for John not ready for John.
And I have in the same realm. Right. So,
but we were looking at Dominic when
we're like that kids really talented,
super pro, he's got massive potential
and I still think he does bell. Yeah.
You know, so he's just going to get
better from this Johnny Walker. Right.
But that guy might have blown shoulder.
Let's say he doesn't though.
If he doesn't, he's still thinking
we're fights away from John Jay.
He might be four fights away.
Here's the thing,
he might knock for people into another
dimension on the way to John Jones.
Like guy's something special.
That's what I'm saying. Yeah.
You got to knock those four guys out
so we can sell this. You do. He does.
I mean he's, he's put away to top
level guys a pretty spectacularly.
And um,
I mean you look at the way he fights too.
He's loose and weird and then boom, she
jumps on you and it's so special, Howard.
Dude. Fucking crazy power.
But I think with John, his
team smart, they're gone. No,
we know heavyweights there.
We're going to clean out to a five.
Ain't nobody been this room clear,
clean out.
So we're considered the
greatest of all time.
Then we go to heavyweight and get paid.
While you know they wanted this fight,
they thought it would be a good fight
with Tiago and I think one of the,
one of the things that it's a good fight.
One of the reasons why it's a good fight
is Tiago can shut anyone's lights out.
He knows he can shut anyone's lights out.
That mother fucker throws for the
bleach and used to fight at 70 no 85 85
[inaudible] 85 struggled to make 85 look,
he's big. He's big. He's big. A big dude.
It's fucked up fucking power that that
guy has and I hit the Manoa fight and he
just swings, man. He swings wild.
Now John is not going to fight him the
way man and will fall. I can't touch him.
You know John is going to keep money
outside of those kicks quench him.
He'll clinch them, wrestle them, take
them down. John's ground and pound.
His horrific is top games off the chart.
Missions are great submissions,
everything better.
Elbows are from hell,
from the top by sound gets
on top of you the best.
You're getting elbow to
oblivion and they're coming.
Well after the other FTI they
have to the other, but the,
in the wild exchange where he asked
to be careful is that that Tiago,
dude, Tiago Santos, we'll
swing with everything. Johnson,
he will throw it all in there.
John's me. They engage in that.
You're not going to see the opportunity.
I mean, that's what makes him so special.
Those guys that go, that's where your
one places to win. Watch this. Yeah,
he just canceled it out.
I don't think that he would
willingly wade into a firefight,
but I could happened, but it could
have. That's high cell fight, sir.
It could happen. See what John
is going to do if I had a gas,
it's try to further cement his legacy.
He's going to fight the best way he can.
He's got great coaches. They know
what the fuck they're doing. He's
going to go in there.
He's gonna kick that dude.
If he decides to clinch with them,
he's going to have a giant
advantage in the wrestling.
But he's got to be careful on the
way in, man, that dude will swing.
We'll try to kill you. He,
he swings in a different way.
He swings like this ain't making it to
the fifth round. There's no fifth round.
He's not even looking to get,
he's that guy is just every shot.
He's trying to take the lights out. No,
I'm out. I'm definitely in a watch it.
He's a wild motherfucker man.
I think this is an interesting fight.
Jon Jones should be the strong favorite.
Should be a giant favor but it doesn't
mean it's not going to be interesting
because this dude's style
cause he's so fucking wild.
The question's going to be how's
he performed? How is he performing?
When that octagon door
shuts and you look over,
you see it's Jon Jones and
title fight the tunnel fight.
But I think one of the reasons why John
Talking Shit to style Benner is one of
the pros is we're talking about him,
right?
Because we probably want to talk about
him verse Santos on this show. Right.
If it wasn't happening, it keeps
them relevant. It's, you know,
he is probably the biggest name
in the sport now outside Connor,
the guy who's the most active him and
could be proud of the biggest names and
talking shit to stop Benner. I actually
think it helps style Benner too. Right?
Cause now he's associated
with the greatest of all time.
He wants to be the greatest of all time.
But when he just,
and it's going to get there and I
can't fucking wait when he goes,
I'm ready for heavyweight
him verse Francis.
What are we going to do?
Himber Steve Bay cane.
Well they're probably Brock
Lesnar deal doesn't get done.
The talk is Steve Bay versus DC cause
the Brock Lesnar deal is not done now in
that whole process cause brought
lost. No, that's not real.
What WWE fuck he didn't know. I
thought it was real. I'm sorry.
Do you see game of Thrones?
I'll give you some more spoiled dude.
I did bet your sweet ass. I don't
talk about it. People get angry. No,
we will shut up. There are
dragons, DVR and dragons are real.
Um, they think that, you know, see
Steve Bay to rock might not fight.
They don't know.
Like my Brock has to decide this is
something he definitely wants to do.
Quit fucking given us blue balls and get
the fuck in there. I get the fuck out.
You know, he's got to make the
commitment and I know he's been training,
he's been training a lot training
and he's trained with some high level
wrestlers. I hope Michigan
to DC July. What's up?
Yeah.
And then July stack,
you gotta be careful with Brock memory
tag Randy couture and dropped him and
hammer fists at him into a blue.
Randy was 48 years old, but I hear Ya.
I hear Ya.
I like you're selling me on the twilight.
Remember how he smashed Frank Mir? Yeah.
It was terrifying. That was remarried.
Him and freight Katie and each
other and each fucked frank up.
Well cause frock on him with that
knee bar and he didn't, he uh,
he tapped the referee didn't stop it.
Dana White's STP meal chick,
not buck Brock Lesnar next and
like, Ooh, when did this happen?
Preconference oh wow. Well,
that's just the headline. He goes,
we don't know what Brock's
going to do, but if it doesn't happen,
it's Steve Bay. Oh this is one of them.
They got us, they got you.
They got it. You know,
better Jaimee exam could it worked.
We could listen to whatever click baity
farmers, they got us. I love steep Ayp,
steep ADC. I'm like, alright, yeah,
yeah, I need something spicy, man.
I get what you're saying.
And I get the Brock Lesnar appeal.
I would rather see steepest steep,
you know like,
cause you're a purist and that's
why I like you but not me.
I'm like to Perez Hilton up
MMA, not me sir. Out of respect,
because I know he deserves it.
He Won.
He defended the title more than any
human being that's ever held it.
He's the number one guy in
the heavyweight division.
So you have to rate him the
greatest heavyweight of all time.
If you look about accomplishments,
he's the greatest UFC heavyweight of
all time because he's not in terms of
accomplishments, just because he's done
it four times. Okay. You know DC beat him.
Obviously DC is supposed to mean if
you, if you had to rank him, you know,
like right now,
like one through 10 [inaudible] Frank Gcs,
number one,
because he's the champion and he
knocked him out to say he's number two.
It'd be silly,
but to say like the all time greatest,
most accomplished heavyweight.
Your boy Damon CTCs. Okay.
The all time most accomplished
greatest heavyweight is DPA.
You gotta take an count.
Well,
Kane never defended as many times
a steep paid did. The question is,
did Cain beat the better guys?
Did he beat junior dos
Santos from junior was young.
He before he had been through
those wars with Kane, right?
Because by the time Steve Bay got him,
junior had been in some wars and jr has
like really good late. He looks amazing,
but you can never discount that damage.
I'm not saying that he's not as good now.
I think he's still phenomenal.
Now put the band back to the Vasa fight,
knocking out that toughest shit
man knocking that motherfucker out.
And the way he did it,
he looks good.
Matt Dude is jds a Francis of a ESPN card.
That's not a paper view. I think
that's fucking does ESPN? I think so.
Stew a fucking cause you do and you do it
him around and he fought Derrick Lewis,
right? Yeah. Stop Derrick
Lewis. Stop Derrick Lewis.
Look to junior dos Santos
still is an amazing fighter.
That's something July card.
Ah Fuck.
So I'm going to watch it when
Steve Pay beat. But you know what,
Steve Bay can knock anybody out
like that too. It's hard to say.
You know what the problem is with Steve
Bay, the Prom is, is DC's fought what?
Twice since their fight.
But he's just been chilling.
Well he's been wanting this rematch.
Wait guy. Got It. I get it. But,
but it's a risky thing when you're a
former heavyweight champion and you're
going to take a fight when you
rightfully deserve a rematch.
And what if you get hurt while you're
taking this fight? What if you get,
you know,
you have this fight and you get hurt
and then you have knee surgery and then
you're out for another year and
then DC loses it in DC retires.
He wants to fight him again. And the
way to find them again is to hold out,
to hold out this whole title. No.
Obviously the UFC wants to fight DC again.
That's the way it all now in
hindsight, cause lessons that happen in
John. John's not going to heavyweight,
but he's the third choice in all
this. Well, I fuck waiting for that.
I thought it was very interesting.
Herbs it John said that
to Steve Bay that John,
I don't think it's weird if we each
assigned thing the same thing we do with
style bender. He's just
fucking with everybody. He's
getting his name out there.
He's learning from Connor C
I think there's more to it.
I think UFC was fishing went, hey,
you down to fight steep and John went,
y'all fuck ups DPA and what?
Steep. But he'd done fight
Johnny. Y'All fuck up John.
I think there's more to it. You think so?
What makes you say that? I don't know.
No reason at all.
Maybe they did have some preliminary
discussions as to whether or not the two
would engage in fisticuffs. Maybe
they did. That's a great fight.
Great fight. He deserves it 100%
he deserves big fights, man. Look,
the guy doesn't deserve to be
forgotten. No, not at all. But again,
Francis and Ghana was one of the most
impressive heavyweight title defenses
because Francis was on fire.
He was so dangerous because they have
Francis ranked ahead of him now that just
be disrespectful.
But Francis has done world.
Steve Bay's gotta be the number
one contender. Know what?
B D C B as number one. Yeah.
Come after Barry. Have to be,
you never know with running path to
be have to be friends or your Francis.
Yeah. For Steve Bay be Francis. It's
that simple. Steve paid be tuner.
It's that simple. I mean, come on man.
I'm dude Francis dos
Santos. Oh my God. Dude.
I can't believe that's even happening.
Well,
he gets dicey done that
heavyweight after six.
It gets dicey. Look, Ben Frances,
really 15 heavyweights in the world,
Francis would take down defense Frances
with an understanding of what it's like
to fight five rounds and Francis a
little bit more experience and uh,
they'll Santos fucking luck. Steve
Bay booked a Jujitsu match. I saw.
Did he bring it to do the magic?
You blow your knee out had to match
and you can't fight for the title.
It was just two matches. It backfired.
It trust me. They're rough men.
And those big dudes want to fuck you up
to, he is going against right fights.
True to fight to win one 10 and Cleveland,
please don't say it's a leg lock.
I please don't tell you. Oh No.
Or cyborg. Cyborg will rip
your legs apart. Or Gordon.
Ryan Gordon, right. I can't really do
that right now. Right. We're Gary Tonin,
Garrett Gordon. Ryan just tours needless
or no info on his opponent. Oh, okay.
Cause he's probably booking a
flight. He's like, see Ya dude.
Your boy Ben Aspirin is fighting.
Yeah. Bill, the fucking not Mazda doll.
He's fighting Mazda at all. But I'd
say girls Ras. Isn't that crazy?
Crazy. And that's like make
six. I think. You know, if,
if Ben asking can really hang
with Jordan Burroughs still, dude,
I ain't saying cause everybody who
rolls with them. I've never, uh,
I never even clinched with them.
But everybody
who's done everything with him,
the closest I came to a clinches like
that hug you do when you go hug a dude
over under a little bit
just to feel it out.
But they say that it's like
he's got forearms, they say,
dude, it's ridiculous. Oh,
I've heard Jean Thomas was telling
me [inaudible] Thomas and St Dude,
it's ridiculous.
I feel like it doesn't even make sense.
Bali waps world champions. We all
know. Yeah, just ranked offs people.
That's how good his wrestling is.
I mean if you see that fight with
Robbie Lawler, they'll fucking bombs.
That guy took his fucked up in the fact
that he's still figuring out a way to
get ahold of Robbie Lawler's neck.
Did.
He still figured out a way to get him
into that head like once and Robbie knew
he wanted to clinch with him.
He couldn't keep him off.
I was sweating in that pike cause you
and I hyped him up so much as like,
oh please don't get
starts in the first round.
It's still super controversial ending to
me. What you had her bond. Would he say?
Well Herb said that first of all,
herb dean is the shit.
Nice guy. Couldn't be nicer. Great Guy.
But I love his perspective
so laid back and he,
his ego is so healthy,
like 20 talks about things like you,
you don't see any,
it's very reasoned thing but he's just
like chilled out and he's like very self
deprecating and chilled out about it. But
he had a very good point. He was like,
that's not just a
manipulation of the neck.
Like in terms of like cutting off
the carotid artery because this is a
manipulation of the spine. It's
like a, a bit of a neck crank.
And he was thinking about that.
He was talking about like,
you look how he's got a hold of
the head and how is he goes real.
What I'm concerned with is if someone's
going unconscious for from some nerve
shit. Oh Wow. From a neck crank.
Like apparently he had seen a guy who
had gotten neck crank like that and then
afterwards the guy couldn't walk.
He like couldn't move. It came back,
but for moments,
but for moments he couldn't move his shit.
We don't even think about it.
I'm like, exactly. Yeah, exactly.
That's why he's herb dean. He's the
gold standard. He's the gold standard.
It's big. John McCarthy and him
and big John doesn't do it anymore.
So it's a herb seeds, numero uno. And um,
just that when you think about and
ask her and says what he says is that,
see that's nasty dude.
It looks terrible.
That's nasty with the way he's
holding onto the head like that and,
and cranking your neck. I like
that. They're not very bad position.
I liked the UFC went. Oh, all right.
We're good. Yeah, I dig that. I get it.
I want to see it again. I, I,
I disagree. I think that, um,
I, I agree with herb stoppage and uh,
I, I see the, the, the arm went limp,
but then the thumb came up, but then as
soon as he let go, Robbie jumped up. Ooh.
Had me convinced that
Robbie was never out,
but herb had me convinced that it was
too dangerous for him to allow it to
continue. Once the arm dropped in that
weird way. So do you side with her.
You have to side with her in that
situation you have to side with herb cause
he's right because that
is a special circumstance.
See I looked at it in terms of,
and I didn't even consider this when I
was talking to [inaudible] that I looked
at it in terms of it's just to choke
in her blue. No, it's a neck crank. Me
Too. So, but still I'd
love to see it again.
I'd like to see Max if they both win cause
asking Mazda Dall I know that doesn't
get your dick hard.
Oh and Mazda dolls wall and then it,
let's ask him when's that, which is
tough fight to win. That's a tough one.
That say a Woodley and Lawler,
a lot of wins that then they find it's
even bigger. Would loop versus law.
We're though that's a tall
order after order for both.
Both fights. It's a tough
for both fighters to fight
to call either way. Yeah.
I'm, I'm really interested to
see how a Woodley bounces back,
but he spent saying all the right things.
I love with Lee. I love Woodley too.
And one of the things
that I love that he said,
he said he didn't realize the value
of the title until it was gone.
And now to give you that understands it.
I mean,
I just think he really understands it
now that it's, it's not there anymore.
He's not the champ anymore and to get
beaten and it's not like a fight like s,
you know, you could make a rematch with
Calvin and style bender in six months.
True. You can back and forth. You can make
that rematch. Kelvin knocked him down.
Kaelin's fill that wasn't that kind
of fight. No. Who spend like so fight.
Who's smart and guy who smile looks
spectacular. Former champions,
Tyron Woodley and Robbie Lawler to meet
and UFC main event. Yeah. Oh yeah. Yeah.
It's booked. It's booked.
Yeah. Yeah. That's where talk
delivered Minneapolis, right?
Yeah. Yeah. No, I'm not going to be there
for that one fight. It's a fight night.
June 29th target center. That's
a hell of a fight. Imagine that.
That's a fight night.
Two former world champions and pro Robbie
Lawler physically and that looks so
good shredded. He said he had this
crazy strength and conditioning program.
Super motivated. You know, dude, we
haven't talked about this on air.
We talked a little bit at the
comedy store. How about your boy,
Tj Dillashaw both our boys. Yeah, that's
not good. She sees apology. Yeah, I did.
What'd you think?
Well,
I mean at least he's a just straight
up admit nothing I said you have to do
because then you're kind
of like, yeah, I fucked up.
Then people can't really come at you.
Yeah,
I mean he's being honest about it and um,
oh, I do have to correct something. He,
someone wrote an article that said that
Cody Garbrandt found out the TJ tested
positive for his fight too.
And Cody went crazy.
I think I got duped by a click baity
articles. Oh, we all got duped.
Everyone thought that and actually had
got us with a click baity articles and
everyone did. But I, I should have been
more responsible. So my apologies to Tj.
So they ha,
I don't think there's been another
one that they tested him on that he's
positive but they're looking into it.
Now here's the thing. Well we have to,
this is something that I know,
um, EPO is not always tested for.
Correct. And she, Dana, what'd
he say? Cause you sought as
expensive as fuck he was.
Hold on. You guys aren't, he
had, he didn't know. He goes,
you guys aren't tests for EPL every time
we paid this much money for you numb
nuts to show up guys at three in the
morning and test them and you're not
testing every time. And we paid this
much. He goes, I had no idea. Yeah.
Well time to cancel you side. Thanks boys.
Thanks boys. Thanks for playing. See Ya.
Everything has been looking good Jeff,
take it from here. Come back, be cool bro.
Yeah, next thing you know,
everybody's back looking thick,
thick and juicing now,
but they still, I see,
I guess what they're going to do is
they're going to go back and see if they
still have the samples for when he did
beat Cody and test those for EPO. Well,
this is what you and I were talking about
where we're at the store and when like
how far do we go back? Dude, I'm telling
you, Joe, you don't want to go down that.
I said, Oh, you're crazy tomorrow.
Let's find out what's real.
Why, why you want to do that?
You're crazy, dude. You can't do it.
You're gonna ruin the foundations is the
UFC. This is an intellectual exercise.
I don't really want you to test them
all. Yeah, but if I was going to argue,
I'd say test tomorrow. I think
lined it up. What's fine? What's up?
We've always wondered half. We'd
not be easy. I've never wondered.
Do you want to test Forrest Griffin and
Stephan Bonner? You'll see that the,
the fight that catapulted the freaking
task. You'll see this, but then again,
test all the football players test all
the base everyone's feelings for me.
You Watch screwball. Did you
want screwball? No, I have it.
Holy Shit is a good bill at the
Billy Corbin document. Yeah.
Do you know what they did? Yeah, they
had little kids play a right. It's crazy,
right? It's hilarious. The story.
The story's nuts cause it's in the people
who are actually there narrating it.
They're,
they're telling the story and they got
these little kids playing a rod and
playing the, it's fucking great. Crazy
story though. That's a crazy story.
I feel bad for Tj, man.
You know what, man,
when everybody makes an
agreement to not cheat,
they're testing you all the time to try
to make sure that you're not cheating.
Don't you think that the environment's
different now than it was before you saw
it? It was instinct was initiated and
don't you think that's a good thing?
I'm putting words in your mouth. No ties
to phrase that question. Yeah. I was like,
oh, come on. No, you're right.
Writing it is better overall for the
purity of the sport. I think it's better,
but I still assumed guys are gonna
figure out a way to cheat because,
because pds in sports is no different
than than a referee or a judge or gloves.
They go hand in hand.
People have always done pds or
enhancements when in every aspect,
whether it's football, basketball,
and music, surfing, sex.
It's just what humans do,
especially when the odds are so high that
this little thing can help you achieve.
Maybe it gets you a victory,
but you know,
and then also with with
Tj Dillashaw is thing.
Granted we know epls illegal,
but this is,
this one's a little different for tested
positive for like steroids or whatever,
like straight up steroids because if
you and I engage in a fight and we have
eight weeks of training and you go to
Mount Everest or where the fuck you want
it to get your red blood cells higher
and then fight me back at sea level,
but I just stay here and
Jack those red cells.
You know the difference that
if you operate at sea level
and you are taking EPO,
you will be able to work much harder and
get more rounds in and you will recover
much better if you are up at altitude.
The problem is living in
training really at high out to,
you can't put out as much output,
but the night of the fight we're
going to have the same. No.
Why Epo have more labor? Yeah. Not
even close. No, you're getting,
you could have a stroke from that stuff.
I mean it depends on how
much you're taking. Yeah,
that was one of the things Novitsky was
telling me about where young cyclists
thick. They were just having strokes.
We are, boy I think it was lance.
I'm shine that maybe just on your show,
but he would wake up middle night and I'd
have to ride a bike because I was sick.
That was my friend Salami. Do I
know Salami? No. No, I'll explain.
Okay. But you know what I'm saying?
Like it gets like bike racer.
You'd have the talent in
the middle of the night.
Lance did discuss how guys think.
That's what I got it. Yeah it's been,
we've talked about it.
Maybe Lance did.
Did Lance talking about having to get
up and where did you and I are talking
about getting up in the middle of night
riding a bike. No, I'm just kidding. No,
just kidding.
But anyway,
obviously look that with
the Lance Armstrong thing,
I feel like everyone was
doing it and you don't,
you think Tj is the only one?
No,
I think other people are taking EPO and
they're hoping they don't get caught.
That's what I think. I think it's still
cheating. Correct. And I think, um,
I don't think everybody's doing that.
I think there's a lot of guys who
were doing it honorably. I agree.
Most guys are doing it
honorably. You know, I think
you could get it in your mind,
but I don't,
this is just,
is what to take from Max Holloway. It
is what it is, right? It is what it is.
What it is. It's cheating. Right.
He would, TJ would admit that.
I'm sure he did a minute. Yeah,
he did. That's what it is. But
I mean, I don't even know if have a point.
I don't know if I do either, but it's,
but it's the guys trying to,
I was going to say the guy is
trying to provide for his family,
but so is everybody else. Cody
Garbrandt, Mardi gras ramps. So as Henry,
so Hutto so has everybody.
Everybody. He fights. But I,
I would like to sit down with Tj and
I reached out to him since he's been
suspended. I want to sit down with
them and she's like, why would you,
why did you do it?
Like what led you to this?
Because his card has been great since
he was a child with his rather this
wrestling background. At what point
along the way, was it six years ago,
six fights ago. Did you think you need
to do this in order to beat these guys?
Well, let's, we could look at one thing
that we know that he's been doing.
He has a rigorous strength
and conditioning program
that training one time at
that strength conditioning program
that he's doing it. You have,
I have an issue with that.
I understand your issue,
but that shit is off the
charts crazy difficult.
They're doing wild stuff and Madison
Ball work and plyometrics and all this
stuff and Tj looks like a
fucking beast when he's doing it.
Have you seen Brown Ortega's
workout with with is
with Mike. Yeah. They do crazy shit
too. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I mean,
I'm not justifying it,
but I'm saying is that in
order to do that kind of work,
like to put out that kind of pace,
your body's going to have to have some
time to recover in between workouts. Well,
if you take EPO,
that time of recovery is diminished
quite a bit according to Novitsky you're
saying it allows guys to put in more
work so it doesn't just give you more
cardio, it allows you to recover
faster so you could train harder.
And you know as well as anybody that
sometimes the difference between victory
and defeat is just having a
little more in your gas tank.
Just having special at that,
a little longer camp and
shot being injured or the
last couple of weeks we lost
some cardio. You know
those awful feelings. Well,
if you had the opposite of
those awful feelings of not,
instead of being compromised being his
hands, it's going to help you, thankfully.
Exactly what's going to help your head.
You're going to come in there like
a fucking champion to that. Uh,
what's that song? He always comes
into, uh, give it away. Give it away.
Now that what? He goes? No,
he comes in. He comes the red
hot chili peppers. Oh Damn.
Damn. Damn Dink. Dink, dink.
I always forget guys. Well,
the only guy who's walkout music,
I always remember two, two.
One was of course Matt Hughes cause
he'd come out to country board council.
That fucking song.
Who's the other Randy go tour when he came
out to strangle hold. Oh, interesting.
Not Anderson Silva. DMX.
Oh that's right. Shit was,
that was scary. Mickey galls got the
best one though. Where you think, oh,
Mickey gets a file. Like come on
man. Or Boy, he's got a good one.
The song, it's called Wonderboy. Oh is
it? It's pretty tough. Like wonder boy,
what is the secret of your powers?
It's pretty dope. It's awesome.
Who came out to the game
of Thrones song though?
Zone came at the game of Thrones. That's
pretty gangster. It's a little boring,
but you know, Shit's still,
it's something special.
You see Deleah that fucking
Dork with his shirt off.
Dude doing air violin to game of Thrones.
Fully committed,
fully like he's so silly.
He's so fucking silly.
He's those silly. Do you
think, uh, I've seen about Tj.
Do you think two years is good enough?
It's a good question.
I think it is two years without ancient.
But here's the question.
What are they going to do it?
What if they decide what of Cody demands
that they test his sample for EPO?
That's a good question.
So let's say they can't test that and
let's say this might have already happened
and we don't know.
You'll know before me.
So let's say that they go back and test
the two fighters. Cody, that'd beat him.
So let's say both test spots for
EPL. I don't think they, well,
but let's say they did. That's three
brother. That's the three strike rule.
You're out for life
man.
Can they go back that far and do it?
I mean this was being stressed.
This would be the best
argument for getting rid of
a Novitsky says Dillashaw was
testify EPO in both files against
Cody Garlia chefs come back,
never came back negative. Okay. So,
so he's good. Yeah. So He's good for
that. But they could go back to, you know,
but go ahead and go. Cause he, if he
didn't do it during Cody Garbrandt fights.
C'Mon dude.
Well,
but also training at the training lab was
the first Cody Garbrandt fight when he
was out of Denver,
was he?
He was switching time and then moved
here per permanently because the training
lab but also,
which was the first fight?
Was it the Cody garb and fight?
I'm pretty sure the first coding,
the first one but also
at one 25 it makes sense.
You do EPO cause he cut in that
way and 25 Henry snap more.
Yeah. No energy when he's trying to
train. Yeah. Yeah. Cause your wrecked.
So that was the test is hot for at
one time. Yeah. And he was like,
that was the only way. The
25 fuck, that's awful. Awful.
Still
two 17 the Madison Square Garden.
Okay. So that's it. Yeah. So that's when
he started, when he would do it. Right.
It makes sense because he's trying
to get down to an ungodly wait dude,
he looks so bad when he was walking
around that day. Credit City the day.
But no, no. It was more
than it was skeletor stuff.
That's why I'm talking
shredded like an Ethiopian kid.
If it was more like a like
somehow it was starving.
It was like his face was not so sucked in.
I was worried about don't this
like this just doesn't look good.
It looks so sick.
He looks like an ultra marathon runner.
Like one of those crazy dudes who's
just doing one every weekend. God,
I need to get like that. Um, what is
the one on the bottom? One 35 wow.
He looks so much bigger.
It's crazy.
The difference in the amount of muscle
he carries on like his body eight muscle.
What a nightmare.
What a bad decision.
Go to one 25 and also to do it where he
wasn't draining himself that much cause
he got down to like one 35 naturally
last 10 did that training lab.
How and they have to do with
safe face. I get it. They,
but Tj came on my show and he's talked
about in other interviews saying how they
did blood work every day
and testing everything.
You're telling me that when you insert
fucking EPO, no one had any idea.
You're doing it yourself.
And this is the other alarming thing.
EPL is not a gateway drug. It's not like
marijuana. The drug's not gateway PDS.
That's some black belt level shit is it?
Yeah. Talk to your boy lance about it.
You just don't start with EPO.
That's some high level shit man.
Cause think about your blood
thick. You got to read test, right?
You wouldn't want to start
with like some Anna bar. Yeah,
little psych winstrol what's up babe?
Look at the traps coming
in and so I'm always
like Epl, some serious shit man.
It is serious. That's a very know.
Maybe someone came to
him. I was like, dude,
better cardio at one 25 EPO is the
way to go and I know how to do this.
Let's go down this road. Who Do you
think's going to be the first dude come
along with gene editing.
Might be y'all. Remo
is just a Cuban experiment.
Just so fucking crazy science project.
God never gets old because
a Ninja turtle on a twitchy,
shy be looks exactly the same.
Why is happening here? Yeah.
He doesn't age like a normal person.
Probably be some Chinese dude, but yeah,
one day they're going to deal with that.
One day there's going to be a person
who shows up who is ridiculously jacked
that never gets tired and it fast as fuck.
It's fucked and everyone's fucked.
If they figured out a way,
I mean,
how much can they manipulate cardio
when your, when you have big muscles,
that's what we're going to find out.
You're going to find out if there's a
point where you can't like the physical
structure, one holding more muscle and
you can't get any more oxygen through it.
You only get, get to a diminishing
point of returns. You know,
what are you going to do then? China
would be the first one. China for sure,
for sure. She's Jack Chinese. Dude.
Russia doesn't need it. We're an hey.
They think they might have already
done something like that with Carolyn.
Did you ever see Karalyn and his,
uh, his parents know that the,
the crazy conspiracy theory
was always that Carolyn,
who was one of the most feared wrestlers,
if not the most feared wrestler ever,
who just would take 300 pound men and
hoist him through the air and they move
like a panther and he's a big giant guy.
Panther.
His parents were small little tiny phone.
Wait. Oh Dude. They called an experiment.
There was a picture of him and I
think it was sports illustrated,
one of those sports magazines where he's
got his hand on his mom and his dad if
the likes his children bro. He said, John,
I just be a freak though. Mike does that.
Like, I don't think shacks pants are
big dude. Holy Oh lets him with fader.
Oh my God dude.
I gigantic if go to that black and
white photo of him looking ferocious.
There's a look at a picture of him
right there with the shirt right there.
Click on that one.
Click on that one whole ah fuck bro.
Listen to his giant Tism we get
his chin dude. [inaudible] Rowe.
He's got more than that dude. He's got
more than that. He's got more than that.
How big is, he's not, he's fucking huge
man. Look at that picture with him.
That's him, right.
Fuck. Look at that brow.
He would pick dudes up and they
would go for a mother fucking ride.
Guys would try to flatten out and lay
their whole body on the ground in hopes
that he couldn't pick them up. He would
clench his hands underneath their belly,
hoist them up in the air like a fucking
pillow case and smashed him on the
ground. He's the guy or American beat.
Yes. The big fat guy who lost all the,
lost his toes in the winter.
Rulon Gardner. Yes. Yeah.
We'll have him on here. No,
I never happened. I would,
but brew Lawn Gardner beat him in the
twilight of his career and is not taking
anything away from la but only beat
him by a point cause he made Corel and
separate his hands as sumo
as a controversial new rule.
It was like a controversial
new changing in point system.
I can't believe I'm calling that correct.
Sure. I'm calling that correctly. A cow.
Rulon Gardner and that rush
and that's fucking right,
dude. He was so scary, dude.
He's Jack.
He was so scary and he had one,
I think he had a fixed fight in Japan.
It looked like a work, you know,
like they do those in Japan still do.
It looked like he tension and fucking
Floyd with faith. What you think is real.
100% oh Joe, you want to watch again?
We can. Why do you think it was fixed?
Come on. Do you watch it? Yeah, I just
think of some bullshit. No, it was a,
a guy who's legitimate hundred
55 pound man who is fighting,
crying and throwing around on the ground
due to fights at one 26 it doesn't make
any sense.
Never had a professional boxing match.
How crazy was fighting
against the greatest boxer?
Listen to what you're saying is so small
and tensions fixed and tensions there.
Fucking poster boy. Yeah, and they're
like, yeah, here's Floyd Mayweather. Dude.
I don't think they thought he was gonna
knock him out. Really tensions a beast,
man. I mean he's the scene,
but when it comes to I have,
but when it comes to boxing,
I understand that.
But they were really
thinking he could hit him.
This was the thought was that tension
is really a striking genius if you've
never seen him. So Conor Mcgregor,
well, but no, no, but it's different.
Tension is faster. It's
smaller. I mean he,
he moves like a lightning
bolt and in Japan,
the fact that this kid is
only like 18 or 19 years old,
crazy and been fucking people up,
including knocking out
world Moy Thai champions.
So they threw him to the
wolves real early on. Okay,
let's watch this and tell me,
tell me why you think this is fake.
I see a dude who is so
much smaller than Floyd.
Look how little he is way smaller.
He's way smaller.
Floyd is not even before messing around.
He's not remotely nervous.
This kid is a hug. I mean,
remember Floyd, last thing,
I remember he didn't do this to
Connor, right? But this cookbook,
of course Connor can knock him out.
This kid can't knock him out.
Supposed to be the next big thing too.
He's a great kick boxer,
but he is not kickboxing.
He's boxing.
You're not going to outbox
Floyd Mayweather when you've
never had a professional
boxing match.
At least I don't think he has.
He's had a lot of kickboxing though
and in kickboxing he's fucking amazing.
But he's also amazing against
guys that are 126 pounds.
So 18 to look how small he is compared
to Floyd Floyd. It's tiny. And Floyd,
look how easily Floyd blocks those
punches and he's not feeling any danger.
So he's just tides to put it on this kid.
He's walking him down.
He's walking him down looking for
an opening. This is the first round.
He waits. Boom. He cracks
him. Why would you whacks him?
That's he just got us crack. You don't
think back it up. Back it up. Back it up.
Let's watch it again, dude. He cracked
him. Watch this right there. Here we go.
Let it roll from here.
Get some of this corner.
But he hit him with a
left hook to the temple.
You don't see that left
hook to the temple. Watch.
Why aren't dark pink right there.
Thank you.
He fucking cracked a dude who's a legit
30 pounds lighter than him here and the
temple and dropped to how?
Just watched the crack.
You just watched it do doubt you a,
that is a flying bat. That is a
form on left talk. First of all,
there was a stumble in there as well,
but he hit him.
See The stumble after he got robbed.
That's a tough one. It's not tough at all.
The kid gets up, he got wobbled.
They give him a standing eight count.
He looks nervous as fuck.
He looks over smash your fucking crazy.
You think it's gone and now Floyd moves
in and the kids even trying to fire back.
He's just not good enough.
Man.
Floyd standard right in front of
him with his fucking hands up.
The kid's got no chance.
He's much smaller.
No experience against a guy as good as
Floyd and Floyd's walking him down with
his hand. This is real, man. This is
real. That kid's trying to hurt him.
He just can't do it. He's fighting
the best ever. And then boom Collins.
Don was that fuck up was not all of it's
read. The first one didn't look you.
As you should know.
We've all seen guys get hit with shit
that didn't look like much and they go
down.
We've all seen it.
We've all seen guys get touched on
the Chin and they fall down like,
you know Floyd,
look at this.
Do you remember Travis Luder versus
Marvin Eastman? You remember that?
A lot of people said that was
fixed. They were like, that's fake.
No one gets hit with a
punch like that. No, no.
Sometimes you come into a
fight compromised. Look,
this is 100% legit one,
two right in the fucking head,
and he falls down. Dude,
this is 100% a legit fight.
This kid got fucked up by the
best boxer of all chassis.
They might say 126 tiny. None of this made
any sense in the first place, but yeah,
no sense. But you got to admit that's
a real fight that looked pretty legit.
Like it's real. That's a real guy. That
first one, that first one is questionable.
The next to work. Right.
It was a questionable,
I'm just saying for the I in for my
first one, it look questionable to me.
If you watched the whole
thing play out in slow motion,
what happens is you see a left hook.
I was,
if you see a stumble and Floyd moves in
and their legs tangled up a little bit
and then Floyd hit some of the right
hand when he's on his way down. Floyd.
Fuck that dude up.
Did you see him all that handy pack
y'all sign with them now or is that just
took me out.
I was watching the video at [inaudible].
He probably didn't even want to wear
a mouthpiece. The fucking Mafia.
He fight in Japan.
This was a,
this was in a sanction fight dude
expedition. No mouthpiece. They, oh yeah,
there's no, you don't need a mouthpiece
sent to, they let dose Carlos.
Remember that dude? That
dude who wore the, um,
what was the guy's name that wore the
wrestling mask when he fought cro cop.
That was one of the best
cro cop Kaos of all time.
Like a scene from a movie dose.
Carol's, is that who it was?
I'm trying to remember
his name. But anyway, Cro,
cop hits this dude with the perfect
left high kick shin to the dome.
The guy goes down like he got shot and
blood starts leaking under the just fuck
was he thinking dose Carlos? That's it.
So why? But when he lands his kick, dude,
the end is so crazy.
It's like a scene in a movie.
Like I'll click a Quentin Tarantino
movie,
some dude who was a pro wrestler who
decides to fight one of the best cake
boxers of all time to treat
to MMA. Boom. Now watch this.
Watch when they focus in on home boy
or these down, just take a month off.
Let me say this, it doesn't it. Ah,
when he was during pride, when it
ended, the dude is sitting there,
you see blood trickling out
from underneath the mask.
He shinned him to have a cro. Cop
had to retire. What's happening?
I think of something in his, was it his
neck or his heart? It retire though.
What? What was it? He had
a health scare. Oh Geez.
You had like a small heart attack I think.
Does that right Jamie?
Some health concerns stroke
and to retire on a stroke.
And the thing with rob Whitaker too,
I was trying to bring it up,
but you guys were going too fast.
Dot.
He had an abscess on his not torn rectum
in the same area and then because he
was taking antibiotics for that,
he got chickenpox. God, Oh man.
Which ones to have that and his whole
team was like, you're not fighting.
She's still kind of want it to, but Jesus
Christ such, he had assistance rectum,
he had the hernia and then an abscess.
An APP in your rectum.
It's like around some muscle tear,
like pus pocket thing,
but probably from some sort of an injury.
Right.
You can get it from a lot of
different things. The [inaudible].
Have you ever had a hemorrhoid?
They're awful, nasty off. Well,
as preparation h works so
well. It doesn't work. Done.
If you have a serious one and don't
give a fuck. Oh Man, I've had no,
I didn't let it go. I did like
dead lifts or something. It went,
let's not do that and flared it up
the size of a small grape. Yeah,
they get gross. Oh my God. Are He
bleeds every time he shit's still. Yeah.
That can't be held gotta
be bad. Right? I mean,
have you had with Jamie once,
but I just depiction Ari's,
he'd like shows pictures of just like La.
Yeah.
Lots of them sends you those Lavaris
text or tweet about a game of Thrones.
Spoiler feels fuck you. I'm going to, I
want to talk about it. Yeah, stay offline.
That's what I say. It happens to the
offline. I love game of Thrones. Yeah.
It was pretty dope last night. How? I
mean you can't give away any spoilers,
but how good are those? God Damn special
effects. They're good fucking dragons,
man. There was a lot to get
this, so there was just,
they had to like tie everything
together so it's slow.
Yeah, it cut the shit they need. Like the
white walkers fighting. They also need,
let's be honest, you can't do
this hall in eight more episodes.
You're lying to us or go into though.
Fucking study was only five.
I thought it was only six
total could be way wrong,
but they were there longer to that.
Like the last two or 80 minutes.
I think this first one's the shortest
one, right? Yeah. I thought it was eight.
Isn't it crazy that the shows the most
popular show in the world and they're
going to stop it?
I wonder what they're just like good.
Like the whole thing you always want if
you're in show business is to have the
most popular show in the world,
but it's good to go out right at a lie.
But I mean,
you know how hard it is to get the most
popular fiction show and one of the
greatest fiction show,
if not the greatest ever,
and you're there in the peak of it.
How many people are watching it?
Like help me watch last night, do you
think? Do you know how crazy that is?
17.7 million people watch
something on Hbo. That's crazy.
You know,
there'll be like if it was fox,
if it was just thinking like
Roseanne was like 40 million,
it'd be off the charts because
everybody has regular channels,
but everybody doesn't have HBO.
Especially today with Netflix.
How many people would watch it
if it was on youtube? Oh my God.
But what you're watching on
your TV? On Youtube. Yeah.
Watch it all the time on my TV. On
Youtube. You do, you have an APP,
you use it and use it for Apple
TV. Well, no, I'm a, I have dish.
I can just go to channel
three 72 and it's youtube,
like click and watch all my shows. Three
72 on DIRECTV. Is Youtube a dish on dish?
There might be three 70 lens. Netflix.
It's amazing that there's only one, right?
Like there's Vimeo,
but like youtube in terms of
like how much content is on Zion,
they have a big competitor that
not a lot of people talk about.
What's that porn hub for real though?
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that I've had
to move and they put their content on
there, whether or not they're doing
like there's tits out or whatever too,
but a lot just uncensored and like there
are people actually making money on
there also. It's what the ads but
probably know what, oh I don't know.
I don't know how much they can visit
a ton. It was a lot of guys on there.
So pretty safe on the
book. Both websites. Those,
when is VR porn going to really start
taking off when those headsets don't
become so cumbersome to where
you can't check off of the back.
Let's to a wall with a cord.
You just won't be able to relax.
You know,
you won't be able to relax.
That brain tracking thing though would
be an interesting while you're beating
off. Want to find out
what's happening. Meanwhile,
Jamie's just thinking
about like animal attacks.
No, it's Jamie price. Do we know how
many, uh, he can't even say users really.
But how many users does youtube? Half
compared to everyone cycling. Hello?
So like you don't even have to
have an account to go watch it. No,
you don't have to log in or nothing. It's
really a crazy business model. Right.
They figured out some wild thing,
let people to stream shit.
And the thing about it is that
there's no one else like it.
Like where the fuck are the next ones?
There's nothing even close.
I'll say this too. Like I've
never just go back to the fights.
I swear,
swear on my life.
I've never done a legal stream ever
because I was thinking I was taking away
from the fighters,
don't want to fuck them over.
And when I couldn't figure it out and
I thought I might have to do that.
I got probably 2000 dms of links and not,
and I'm just thinking of my cof this
out. People watch the fights. No,
it's a real problem.
Like I was in a shop before I came here
and the guys were fight fans and listen
to my shows and they go, man, I want you
to think of the fights. I'm like, yeah,
yeah, good. How'd you guys watch it?
And it's for young guys and they go,
come on man, we're not paying 80 bucks.
You just delete your streaming. You know,
tons of people are doing that, but I
think it's actually good for the fighters.
I think it's good. It's good
for their popularity. Correct.
And that's all they care about because
the UFC is going to pay him a finite
number no matter what.
Yeah.
And it's probably also good
for the sport that way too,
because more people see it more
people see how awesome it is.
The more people that saw that last fight,
the more people are gonna recognize
how at the very best level,
how fucking exciting this.
Because think about ESPN plus and
when you have to buy the paper view,
you're limiting how many people can
see that by pine, these pay walls.
So with these illegal strings, at
least for the fighter sake, everyone,
we can see these great matchups. Yeah, I
knew. I know what you're saying. You know,
like, but I'm always torn because
I don't want to go see a shutdown.
I love the UFC. Loved the fucking UFC. I
don't. I want, I don't want it to do bad.
I hope these numbers do great,
but when I see what I have to go through
as a diehard fan, like my dad was like,
oh, I'm out. Nope, I'm not doing it. I'm
like, come on man. It's like no. Too much.
So I'm wondering how many people did
that. I'm sure quite a few, but that's,
you know, it is what it is. There's
nothing to cite. Max Holloway. Again,
there's nothing you can do. Those
strains are ga is over. Yeah,
the streams are going to exist.
Nothing they can do really.
I got to make it easy for
people to just get it,
make it easier and once they make
it easier, once everybody's set up,
I think the numbers would go up.
I think most people don't want to go
through the hassle of going through a
stream,
putting it on their television.
Most people just want to be
able to tune in. Correct.
And if you can get that ESPN
plus on everything, that's
the other problem, right?
If you have like direct TV and
that's the only way your TV set up,
your TV is not set up for the Internet.
Correct. So then what do you do?
You know what, if your Internet
is not strong enough to stream it,
even with all that, but then yeah,
if you, if you're not, that's fine.
That's for everything. Yeah.
But, but that's for a fight.
But now if you're 18 to 36
$80 and let's say you just,
you're struggling to get
by $80 a lot of money.
It's $80 for the whole year though.
The whole year of ESPN plus and the fight.
So hold up. Yeah. It's not $80
for all the paper views. No, no,
no sir. No, no, no. For Espn plus
a membership for a year. Correct.
But it's going to see the paper views.
Right. Then it's going to pay 80 bucks.
Yeah,
but which she much would a year
cost of ESPN plus 60 60 bucks.
So for $79 you get the fight and
a year of ESPN plus not paper,
he's not pay reviews. And
there's Tennessee, all the
fights. All the fight nights,
every fight that you know
that it has happened.
I wonder if you get to ESPN fights
as well as the SPM plus fights.
Yes. Yeah. Yes, but the papers of course
they would do that. Why wouldn't it? Yeah,
so if there's 10 paper use and
they're $80 that'd be another did the,
the 80 bucks is just for
the one deal.
Just for the one they can do it again
and they might have other deals.
You might get to buy two for one
of the teacher who knows what.
They can do a lot of
content on there now too,
because they put the paper views up there.
They've put a bunch of
paper views up there,
like the older fights like fight Passy
fight passed on his BN plus. Yeah,
you can get them a deal. Yeah. Yeah.
You could watch some old fighter
UFC fight pass just over then.
I don't know what you can do with it.
There's other stuff on the five past.
It's not that you can't get on ESPN plus
flux and make sure I'm right about that.
Did you just see stuff? That
kind of thing. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Five passes a lot of great shit,
but they have glory to
make sure that's true though.
That um, fight that uh,
ESPN plus has older paper
view. I'm pretty sure it does.
Really? Yeah. I'm pretty sure that in
the lead up to one of these fights,
well then you can click on it,
but you can't go back and like say watch
UFC one 83 he can't. I don't think so.
I don't know. No, no. I
think they might only have,
that would be kind of cannibalizing fight
pass Cypass Dave aired maybe like they
only have the stuff that was there
at three ESPN, like from now on,
they'll have all that stuff. Like they're
building their library from this point.
It must've been a pain in the ass,
but I know fight pass.
Like what?
He's two 29 that could be,
it could be buck on or you
can watch on here. Oh yeah.
So that does have only certain ones.
Yeah,
there's only certain one 97 is on here
also and I don't see anything. Okay.
So it's not all of them, but
there's some, so your record,
there's some bus pass we can go
through and see what you can see.
Everything you see,
every
pride fight and I'll see
if I passed for me is like,
I like throwing up some shit
that I've never watched before.
Like some Moyie Thai like were, you know,
just some dudes I've never seen before.
Yeah, I love doing that. I liked doing
that when I work out for whatever reason.
I'll, well ESPN now though,
but like on ESPN two,
those throw up like classic fights at
Max all the way Brian or take was on
Connor. Nate Diaz too was like, I'll
watch the hose when I'm working out.
But again,
with all this ESPN and buying this and
7,989 I've never been a dark web guy.
And when I clicked on us, I'm like, dude,
this is a problem because it's so good.
It's so good. And then when I talked to
the young, like fans around, they're like,
yeah man, why would we pay $80?
I'm like, I can't tell you.
Cause I used to always think you'd
be fucking over the fighters.
Do you understand the
tech knowledge behind it?
Do you know how they would stop it? How
do you stop a stream? I have no clue.
As from from our, I've watched,
they've never, they've,
they can fight them but
you can't stop them when,
but when they were suing people.
Yeah, my buddy got soon. Really? Yeah.
He put on his gym.
Put a paper you on as Jim
[inaudible] play or a pill? No, no,
you just had it on for free. He paid
though. Whatever the WHO ratted him out.
I don't know. They are, they can track
the Ip address and we're like, hold up.
This is a gym.
Well you owe us this much cause you,
and they looked at the capacity or
this how much it is if to do that.
So he paid just this whatever, six,
nine, 900 at the time and would hold up.
You're doing it from a public gym. It
fits 300 yours, whatever. 15 grand. Oh.
So he made the paper view.
So he paid for it like on a slab.
Individual streams going on a big
thing they don't fuck around, man.
This is also for us only. So for people
that are outside of the United States,
the ESPN plus thing doesn't want,
it's not for them.
They still watched through fight
password. Okay. They cannot,
they also get it on the regular networks,
pts or whatever.
They don't have all that.
Yeah.
Like English fans were making fun
of me when I was having problems.
Like you fucking
Americans. I'm like, yeah.
So in England they could watch it for
free. A lot of it. Yeah. Yeah. In Brazil,
they don't have a paper view thing. In
England, the way we have it here, they do,
but it's cheaper. Like when Joshua
fights like 1999 oh really? Yeah. Huh?
Why are we soccer's like, what's
going on? Is that what it is Jamie?
We're willing to pay for it. Yeah.
Yeah, man. If someone's fighting it,
it's a crazy fight and you've
got to pay 70 bucks for them.
It makes people bought Floyd
Mayweather Pacquiao for 100 bucks.
Is that what it costs? Yup.
Nine 99 never gotten cheaper.
From what I remember my
whole life it's always been,
it's always been expensive bucks.
Yeah. It seems like it's always, yeah,
it's always in the like (599) 096-0990
nine something like never like cheap.
No, it's not cheap. There
are wild encounters.
I panicked though when I couldn't
figure it out and I knew for my favorite
fighters, I panicked. Yeah, dude,
listen, I love working for the UFC,
but I used to fucking love watching and
I still love watching a good paper view.
I love the paper view,
comfort of my own home.
Nothing better to sit and down kicking
back the watch it all play out.
Listen, if I did watch it on the dark
web, I'm saying I did, but if I did,
I did buy a style benders shirt to
give back to you. See? That's good.
So you still get somebody how much to
stop Mendix 7 cents I've seen not just DM
and him $80 just start selling
his own church. I think you can.
I wonder if you can. You can't. I don't
think so. Right? You have to sell a deal.
It has to be through Reebok that
happy cetera. If that's the truth.
I'm sure it is. Don't you think
like, do you think fighters are they,
they must have some sort of a,
a garment in apparel deal cause they
all have like style bender tee shirts.
Like everybody has a, uh, you go
buy a t shirt with Yoel Romero,
but you,
I bet you can still sell your own shirt.
He thinks [inaudible] like a unknown
fighter would be prevented from doing that
would be a little strange to
stop from trying to be fucked up.
But if you're stopping to think
Conor has Conor Mcgregor August shit,
what does that he his own line of
clothing. Yeah, but that's like a,
that's not athletic. Yes. Yeah. And that's
not athletically or that's David August.
That's, he's like, he makes suits. He
makes the suits that I wear for the UFC.
You're right bro. So can he, as a fighter,
you cannot have your own shirt and slang
it. I don't think you can. I don't know.
I'm not a businessman.
I'm not sure.
But I would think they have an apparel
deal that they would have Reebok. Yeah,
like I know that I low you
that [inaudible] Ramiro shirt,
which I almost wore today. I forgot
to wear it. Which she did dope shirt.
Great Buck three buck shirts. Do you
see the style band Reebok shirt? No,
fucking dope. It looks like the
Matrix. He's all different colors.
She was sick.
That fight was sick man.
He showed who the fuck he is and that
fifth round he showed who the fuck fucking
is. Great fight. That was a great fight.
In that fifth round he
went out there like them.
They both won the fucking chapters.
Both dead.
They did both go out that way to style.
Bender eventually got to him that lab,
that fifth and final
round. Woo. And you know,
and that's what he said when I interviewed
him that he just felt like he was
ready to just throw it all
out. He's talking to himself
with to that fifth round,
he's seen something like this. Saint,
something to that. Yeah, that's it.
I mean he decided to go out
there and be a champion.
You to think about if,
let's say Francis becomes world
champion was definitely possibilities.
Number two, you've got three
African champion. Boom, boom. Yeah.
Well when if Daniel Cormier,
he decides to retire and
Frances keeps getting better.
I mean Francis only been doing mixed
martial arts for what, five years?
Four months.
He's,
he's so powerful man. He's just what
I told him, I told him wait it out,
let DC do his thing and
you just go do your thing.
Cause he was kept saying I want
whatever it gets me entitlement.
I don't know what you're talking about.
That's not fight DC.
Let him go out and do his thing.
Then you go,
what that dude needs is a best friend
who's a super heavyweight wrestler.
Correct. That's a tattooed needs.
Just a best friend who was like, Bro,
I'm not going to hurt
you. And he you, yeah
that guy is like 55 I'm
saying a guy like that,
you should watch a wrestling match
with them cause it was so preposterous.
The way would hoist guys up in the air
see if Google Carell and slams toothfish.
No, no, I've heard of him.
Yeah. When I saw him it,
I recognized, I had a picture of him on
my Instagram, said that I looked at it.
I used to have it in my
favorites on my iPhone.
I pulled up every now and then just to
remind me of what a pussy I am. Dude.
That's the one. Him with him
grabbing the guy and all the fucking,
the teeth and the muscles,
he's such off. It's crazy.
Like our American beat him rule on
gonna beat him. He's all chunky. This,
look at this. Watch how he had hoist guys
up in the air. You guys, you'd be like,
who please don't serve. That's
embarrassing. Watch this.
What the fuck? Oh, he hit you.
He's just using the ground,
but look how devastating it is to you.
Boom. He's driving you with
all his fucking weight,
all that momentum and power and
he's knocking you the fuck out, man.
Holy Fuck. Powerful Reebok
sweatshirt. Yeah, look at that.
Reebok back in the day was
sponsoring Karalyn dude,
he's so ridiculously the little boy's
wrestling, that's all. Yeah. Has.
Who fucks are going to find
another seven foot three guy?
It'd be nice to get into
either Reebok shoes.
Look at fucking monster man.
How tall was a Carolyn?
I think it was like six
nine or something like that,
but just Denise was the undefeated
for like ever for years.
Six three it says, he says the
only six. Three. That seems weird.
That doesn't see it. He was undefeated
for forever. Oh Man. He was at when?
When he was fighting,
I think it was 300 plus pounds.
Was it say there to 85 okay.
He's 51 now.
God Damn, that guy was a
girl. How do what he does now?
I think he works here with
wrestlers. Holy Fuck. I mean,
I think you know that whole Russian
program they, they probably have a very,
very prestigious position.
Yeah. Was He undefeated forever
to rule on beaten? Yeah,
but again,
the way he beat him,
if you could please Google that because
I think Rulon Gardner beat him and this
does count, but by getting him to separate
his hands, looking that up, the reserve,
they had to do a video review.
Even if something that happened and then
rule on was awarded the point and then
I made a Corolla and be extra aggressive,
kind of 84 inch chassis said that was
really hard for him to get his hands
around in the first place. Yeah, that's
right. Rule owns a big fella thick.
Remember when rule on fought MMA?
Yes. Last and people that Jab,
this was like getting hit
with a bottom of a dumpster.
Then he lost his dad cause you could still
pick anyone on a hike and got lost in
Colorado. Must his toes and
fingers. No, I think he was um,
a snowboard on board. Yeah. I think
he's known will be snowmobiling.
He was snowmobiling and it broke
down and he got frostbite. Hostos.
He lost at least one toe and
I think he kept fighting men.
I think he fought even,
I think he fought in Japan.
I think they let them wear
shooters. Oh, that's right.
They let it let you were wrestling
shoes. What's he doing now? I don't know.
He was on the biggest
loser. All that. True.
Then he had eaten a lot after
he retired from fighting, bro.
He was so big country fed son for
the size of that motherfucker.
That was when he was on the biggest loser.
He was morselate got some tits high.
But look at him in pride.
Go to go to Rulon Gardner and pride.
When you see him in shape as a a,
an MMA fighter,
you realize what a dangerous guy he was.
He was in an enormous man.
Everyone should be thinking their lucky
stars that Russia freaked into side
looking at him right there. Look
at them in the far left, far left.
That picture dude. Um, that was uh,
who did he fight there? He
ain't skinny. That's Ah,
that's God dammit.
That's the, the judo guy.
Fuck God dammit. I can't believe
I can't remember his name.
That guy was witnessing, weren't they
two Olympic medals and say that is done.
I see. They're both Olympic
gold medalist. Right. Just go.
Go to rule on gardeners. Um, MMA.
Wikipedia. Did he go Yoshida. Oh,
Yoshida. That's right. Exactly.
Yoshida started out.
Um,
he was a gold medalist in judo and
was fighting with the Guiana. Yeah.
Cause I remember that fight because
either that's what medalist,
I forgot about Yoshida,
how another great fighter that was
fighting during the pride days.
But here's the point. Rulon Gardner
was so much bigger than him. Dude,
pull to go back up and you see that
photo of the two of them standing there
right there, Jamie? The
one. Yeah, that picture.
That's how you get to just an,
an understanding of the difference in
size one didn't have that many fights
though, dude. He was so big.
He was smashing that dude with a jab to
like he was beating him with a jab like
Yo, she was getting stunned
by this giant heavyweight jab
and Rulon Gardner. Yeah. I think,
I don't know if he really, if that
was his first love though, you know,
I think you'd be really loved wrestling.
He said he's burnt out of wrestling too
though. Yeah, I remember seeing that.
And then you went to MMA. That's tough,
man. After all the years of wrestling,
especially at that international level,
how many of those guys
do you think at the,
in the top echelon of amateur wrestling?
If they just decided, you know what, fuck
this, I'm going right into MMA right now.
Like how many of those guys would
be a giant nightmare for everybody?
All of the above. All of the above.
I'll think about Jordan Burroughs.
You kidding me?
Kidding me is athleticism dude and world
class experience and work ethic and
just the knowledge and like,
oh the mental fortitude it takes to become
Jordan Burroughs city aspirin and him
are going to go out.
It will ask her and is in the middle
of embarking on a career African. Well,
if he takes him down, that would be
insane because that's possible. Is it?
I don't know.
Wrestling that well to the point
where I just aspirin stand a chance.
We're going to get lit up
on the Internet for this,
but does he even stand a chance? I
was that crazy. No, I think he does.
I don't think you'd take it if he did it.
I don't think he would take
it if he didn't either. He's
just smart. Yeah. I mean,
I want to say I'm, I'm very
curious. I just so hard,
dude, you got go ahead. Good.
Yeah. Good odds for it. If there's odds,
why would imagine Jordan
Burroughs gotta be the favorite?
Because I got to see how big
it was or something. Yeah.
Because aspirin has been fighting MMA
for so many years now with one and then
before that with Bella tore the ballot
tore one is such a weird situation
because he was clearly dominant and
clearly their champion and they just let
them go, you know? And uh,
I'm really excited about him and Mazda
at all because if there's anybody that's
going to be able to give him a really
hard time by being sneaky and creative
and,
and using slick counter punches
and having good wrestling,
takedown defense and good,
good defense and,
and he wrestles with a lot of big guys,
big powerful guys.
He's a slick customer.
That's a real interesting fight because
he has such a giant advantage on the
feet, especially coming off of
the, uh, the Darren till fight,
him being able to knock out Darren till
like that. That's a giant statement.
I mean, Darren till is a
legit experts. Stryker,
I mean he's a lightening
fast knockout puncher,
knockout kicker,
nasty moitai skills.
And to see Mazda doll crack
him like that and drop him.
So it's like this, this is,
there's never been a better time.
Like Sean and I were saying to like,
like fights. There's never been been,
no one's ever,
there's never been a better group
of champions and contenders either.
It's like everyone is
at the top of the chain.
So what were you pulling up right there?
Uh, trying to find that. If there is
odds on the fighter with what's going on,
it's like a charity event apparently.
So I don't know that they're also fire
fighting, but they're weighing in.
It's 74 kilograms, which is one
63 puts that up so I can see it.
It's a little,
it's one 63. Oh Wow. So, so
Ben's got to lose some weight.
Um, he could do that easy though. I'm
sure. Say too much more about it. Really.
It's that one 63 apparently the
Jordan Burroughs, Ben Aspirin match.
Brendan shot back from PN. How much? Boy,
that's the best feeling in the world
and you have to Piss for a long time.
Ah
hmm.
Very interesting. Very interesting.
I'm looking forward to the W.
Where can you watch it is? I don't think
it's a paper. If you think right online,
is that what it is? It doesn't
say. I'll definitely pay for that
wrestling doc. I'm on the dark
side. Don't, don't go. No,
I'm not going to take four.
Definitely pay $80. She got
sued. Magic. They went after you.
This is allegedly allegedly
allegedly, right? I, I'm so happy.
I'm ESPN plus cardholder. Oh,
there you go. And I can treat well,
you should be able to illegally stream
and no one should say shit. Why?
If you're a cardholder? Oh No, no,
because it doesn't get for the paper view.
I tried giving my money.
To me that's a bold move on the UFC is
part to go with ESPN plus for all their
paper views.
That's a bold move.
I mean that's like when apple
got rid of the CD tray. What?
It's a little shocking, but I'm sure
the figure it out. Yeah, yeah. Dude,
your ESPN employee now it
looks like congrats. Well,
I'm a independent contractor. That's
what the fighters say too. I am,
I'm an, I'm an independent contractor.
But to watch you have to have ESPN.
Yes, I paid for it. I love you Stan.
So I grew up with ESPN. Listen man,
I think it's good for the sport.
I think what is going to be
these huge gaps aren't great,
but the future is in streaming
the pictures in something
on the Internet. 100%.
It's a as
long as everyone.
And see right now there's a lot of people
out there that got fucked because they
had,
they might have a nice TV,
but it's not set up for the Internet
and they couldn't set it up in time.
So it's going to take a little bit of
an adjustment period, you know? And,
and eventually, you know,
some people don't want to go.
I have to go out and fucking buy
something that's Internet ready,
like a TV that's internet ready,
like to watch it on your TV.
If you got a TV at home,
you'll see you've got satellite and you
don't know how to fucking set up your TV
for the interviews.
He's not painting on those people,
the bank on the people who figure
this shit out and the future.
But what I'm saying is it's going to be
a bit of a learning curve for a lot of
people. For the absolutely.
No, this is how to do it. Yeah.
So that's why it's a bold move.
But you have to do it,
whether it's now or in six years,
you have to do it.
You don't want to do it in six years
because then everybody would already have
done it. Dude, I support the movement.
Yeah. You gotta be there in six years.
So six years down the line,
everybody knows paperview tonight on
ESPN plus that's what they're gonna say.
They're gonna say, dude,
paper view tonight on ESPN,
ESPN plus Erbitux in six years.
Just ESPN.
There won't be any plus I bet everything's
digital interest. Yeah, which is the,
it's,
it's a good move.
It's funny because the only reason to
have regular TV for a lot of people's live
sports, regular people, like
a lot of people like look,
you can get a whole fucking
year of whatever TV show
you want to watch on iTunes
or you can watch Netflix and
now Youtube has sports. Right,
but you remember how much it
used to cost to get like cable,
like how much Kaylee used to cost,
how much direct TV used to cross,
how much did it cost while I,
while yeah,
I did have a dish sponsor for like
less eight years. Then they were like,
hey buddy,
no more so I have to pay for it now it's
like hundred something dollars a month
now. Now think of that in
terms of what Netflix costs.
What's Netflix like 10 bucks,
nine bucks or something like that.
They just raised to like 15 and then
you need an internet connection and then
that's it. That's it.
APPLETV tube. Apple. Yeah.
Or a Amazon cause that was on Hbo,
but I have HBO now so I can watch prime
is even more interesting because if you
have Amazon prime for shopping,
you get Amazon prime for free.
Like the TV. He watched the TV shows.
So you get to watch Mrs Maizel.
You get to, what do you ever watch
the guys from top gear went? Oh,
I love those guys. They went over to, uh,
the, the grand tour. They went over there,
they fired him and the other two guys
went, fuck it. We're going with them. Yes.
Type move. Well, Jimmy Clark's
and got drunk and punch some dude.
And so they fired him. I guess he
was different on social, whatever.
Guys off the bass,
these hilarious,
the best funny dude can't do a
show without them. And so, uh,
apparently like they just ended that
show and he was crying like he cried.
Like that's how he teared
up. Oh, it's over. It means
to him. Yeah. Oh Damn. Yeah.
I think, um, they,
they committed to do like a couple of
seasons and paint them so much money.
I'm sure. Look, it's a good
move on please. So that
Bayzos dude's burning money.
You can do whatever the fuck he wants.
Yes.
So much money.
Although his girl has half now she's
third on the list of richest Chaka Chaka
Chuck. Yeah. He has that diamond
piece with them now though.
Hulu has gotten that game too for
live stuff. So there's not that same,
everyone is playing the game
pretty soon it's going to be over.
Imagine if you're trying to
do a shoot a sitcom right now.
Could you imagine if a guy got divorced
from a woman who's like a duchess or
some shit and made out in the
deal as good as Jeff Bezos,
his wife was gonna make out to be sick,
is she?
And then she had like $1
billion or something like that.
She had way more inability
to get bill young son.
They said as soon as they divorced she's
and be like top 10 richest in the world.
Yeah,
he came for like 25% of its stock
or some crazy shit he get. Yeah,
like, but they did start together
like his room. Yes. Listen men, yeah,
she deserves it, but it's
hilarious. It's so much money.
Like damn.
She banked on it correctly.
She's hanging out with that dude when he
was like 24 going this fucking psycho.
Have you seen him around the
world? Have you seen that? Yes.
That picture yes is amazing.
I want that.
Send me that picture.
I know you get a picture.
Do me a favor and send that to my phone.
I need to see that. Isn't that great? Oh,
I'm going to, I'm going
to put that as my, uh,
I'm going to replace the American flag
with that in that. Great. I'm serious.
Any like any,
he's like shaved his head,
TRT tandem on stylus bawling.
Just look at that banner on the wall.
I look at the,
just a little desperation
banner. Look at him there, dude.
And have you seen his new
girl? What's up? Holla? Sure.
That caught you about $40 billion,
but you gotta be happy. Yeah.
He looks like he's enjoying us.
When you have 80 billion, what's 40?
Who gives a fuck? How much can you
spend? And by the way, spend it.
Do you think he's going to, he's,
here's a problem with that dude.
He might be making so much money.
They think about it like when did
Amazon even start? Was it 15 years ago?
A second ago?
It wasn't that long ago.
What's going to be like 15 years from
now when he's on fucking gene doping and
they got 'em
back dated to a 24 year old bayzos.
His Chin looks thicker,
the shoulder caps Ron, and she's
going to be 85 years old running shit.
Look in 30 how much money do you
need? He'll have that guy. Billion,
billion dollars. Like how
much money? This is my point,
like if if he stays healthy
and is enthusiastic and
still has like this drive to
succeed,
how much is going to be worth when you
start getting that kind of momentum?
That's why companies like, that's why
you get people like Elizabeth Warren,
but I don't know too
much about her politics,
but one of the things that I do know
about her is she wants to shut down or
break up some of these big
companies. You know there's a, yeah,
I forgot what big companies
she was talking about, but
that would be an example.
Like you have too much power,
so much power. She'd probably
want to break them up.
It's interesting because it's
like you see like what is,
when you see capitalism play out, right?
You see someone, they start a business,
they want to kick ass,
they want to make a lot of money and then
they do and then they keep calling and
then they get to this point where
they can make more money more easily,
more often,
and they just keep going and keep going
and then they get to this point where if
you hit the right river
at the perfect time,
but the most ambitious
person ever at the helm,
and you got this fucking boat running,
running down this river,
I just pass and everybody, that's
where you got Amazon with Jeff Bezos.
It was the perfect guy at the perfect
time with the perfect adjusting to the
role of scrooge McDuck he's,
he's making, he's like,
Elon wants to make a rocket shop.
Gimme a rocket ship. Correct each.
It's an ego thing.
These spaces too though.
You have nothing to do.
Like what challenges does he have?
That one click is the shit. If you need
something, it's the shit. Amazon. Yeah,
it's amazing. Shit. The
only thing, anything,
just just go fucking find it. Bang, boom.
You don't have to think about anymore.
That to me, that means a lot
to me. Not anything time.
I can save time and hassle. I don't
have to leave my house. Thank you.
She's actually the only third
richest in the world. Richest woman.
They made a deal last month or this
month actually to give her 35 billion.
That's it. Ooh, good for her.
And she keeps a 4% stake. Oh,
I thought it was more than that. Damn.
4% cheese is balling. She's balling.
She's still just 4% stake in Amazon.
My Sane.
And where's it going? Where's it going?
What's going to be 10 years from now?
What's going to be 15
years from now chooses?
And she's got 35 billion Jews on us.
35 billion. I bet she
went. All right. You know,
I bet she's so used to $35 billion.
So you're not going to spend it that,
okay. Okay. I mean,
do you need 35 but also I think Jeff
Bezos had a weird agreement with his new
hot girl where they like,
they're not having sex until the divorce
is final or some shit like that. Oh,
sure. Yeah. Yeah. He was like
some weird thing to justice.
Nuts. They're staying away from each
other until they do. What did he doing?
Chat forced and married or
something like that. Well, oh yeah,
she's getting divorced too.
If you want to live like a movie,
you got to write a script.
Like a movie script.
Dude's already live in like he's in a
movie. Let's, yeah, you're right. Oh yeah.
And then when you get married,
make everybody dress up like a priest or
some shit. Do whatever you want to do.
I can everybody dress up like a,
like a Kanye service,
like one of those do whatever you want.
God, what he do, man, not to control.
What'd he do? What'd he do
well, what would you do?
Just do whatever the fuck he can do.
Whatever the fuck he wants to do.
You're supposed to do whatever
the fuck you want to do.
There's only one Jeff Bezos.
I know, but why posts?
He just stopped Kinda you fucking key.
I keep going.
The foot on the gas.
If you're the Rock, do you need
to do 19 movies? And He's 22 ways.
Can we do a story? Last year did 19
movies this year, 20 to 22 movies.
Engevity 22 boobs getting bigger.
Matter of fact,
he'll be 3000 pounds. Yeah. Like how many?
He's a gorilla man that did so
jacked right now. He's so huge too.
When you meet them in real life, you're
like, oh my goodness, he's so Jackie.
So jacked. He's so inspirational
to man. You know, he's,
but if you know how it is being busy,
like how often is he home?
Did he so inspirational? Oh, that's true.
Yeah. Yeah. It's hard, man. It ain't easy.
Well, I know my schedule.
Yeah, and I look at halftime.
That's a silver back to his under
Armour shoes. So his workout,
we're going to choose their dope.
I love this fucking guy, man.
I love the five of them too.
I can go to his Instagram at anytime
and he's always super positive and he's
always super motivated and motivational
and he's always getting after it.
I love it.
He's always getting after it,
but I wonder what it is in him that you
have to do this many movies when he was
young man, he was young. He fell upon hard
times and he never forgot. And that's a,
that's who he is now.
He's just any,
he also knows that he inspires
people with that work ethic.
Part of what who he is is not just
the things that he accomplishes,
but how he makes people feel like that
guy. He's an inspirational person.
I think the same thing you could say
about Kevin Hart and a lot of ways, man,
it's for selfish reasons too though,
cause you check those boxes.
I'm not saying it's a bad guy,
but there's also this, this ego.
Everyone has an ego that he has to fill.
Oh Dude.
She gets from the red carpets and he talks
about it. He talks about kicking ass.
He talks about how everything's
going great. You know,
he talks about that whole lot getting
after it. That whole aspect of it. Sure.
Yeah. But there's a kidnapper selfish
for sure. For sure. You have to be,
they have to be for anybody who
does anything really good like that.
Like you gotta be doing some of
it for yourself. But he's also,
what he's getting out of it is his,
what he gets out of it,
but what he gives out of it,
it's not just entertaining with that guy.
What's interesting is he's, he's
also super motivational. Right?
Like if he leads by example,
I always really positive.
Now w before social media,
when you had an action star,
you just had the guy that you went
to see in the movie and you saw like,
you know Sylvester Terminator,
they would do interviews
or relate to them. Yeah. It
would be kind of interesting,
but it wasn't this kind of thing.
The Rock is the rock and he's
also the rock on social media.
And he makes very good use of social
media because he just talks right to the
fucking camera and you could tell
he knows what he wants to say.
But he's speaking from the heart.
She's tall.
So he's interacting with people you
know who's done even better than this,
which the rocks might be the best.
But on the other side of this will Smith,
he's fantastic. He'll
Smith my hold up. Okay. So
the movie's doing are right, but
Instagram is the new shit. Right?
Let me focus on this and it's,
I mean ridiculous how good he is
on the wall on Youtube as well.
I remember when he did that fucking
dance on the roof of that bridge.
It's climbed up.
What are you don't fall down.
Don't fall down while you're
dancing. Kevin Hart's get
a social media too though.
Now he's phenomenal at it.
He's um,
he's one of the most inspirational
guys I've ever talked to. Kevin. Yeah.
Cause I liked his message. So
positive, super positive, genuine,
genuinely not a bullshit positive,
not a fake show business.
Positive and motivational show.
Business positive.
He's got a healthy outlook. He
does so many things though. I got,
I got tired just listening to him talk
about how much energy he was talking
about all his businesses. I was getting
exhausted. I was like, how'd you do that?
How do you have the time? It's
incredible. I mean he must sleep.
He and he said he only
sleeps a few hours a night,
but I mean he must be just from the
moment he gets up just fucking foot on the
gas. I wish I was one of those guys.
I wish I was one of these guys.
You only need four hours and
just do function at a high level.
If I don't get aid, I'm fucked
man. Do you? I don't think,
but I mean do you really wish you were
that guy though that like always hit the
gas all day long? Whoa, whoa. No,
I'm saying I could get Monday or Sunday
and then before my son gets up at five
I'm up at three and get my workouts in.
I can do all my research for my shows
and then I'm off and running. Yeah.
I need a man. Like if I do, let's say if
I do a set tomorrow at the comedy store,
I get home at midnight no matter what.
I'm up at five,
five 30 with my son and I go to work.
It's a beast of a day
when there's certain guys that
should need four hours. Yeah.
Those people are freaks. You're not
that guy now. And I need five to feel.
Okay. Six to feel good. Six. I can
work out normal. I could do anything.
Seven makes me feel happy.
Seven is nice. Kevin. I'm seven.
I'm a seven guy. Yeah. Yeah. Seven's good.
Seven's a solid number.
If you could get that,
you probably got most of
your bases covered, but damn,
if you get eight or nine,
that's when the real,
if you could really sleep for
eight or nine like engineered.
So my problem is I drink too much
water at night. I get a pee. Yeah.
It's so annoying.
So stupid.
And Like I had a z Vo last night while I
was watching game of Thrones. I'm like,
I should know what she does and I have
to pee. I have a pro. I have a problem.
I have to,
it's so weird.
I have to have beverages packages.
Oh, late in life. Yeah.
You just want to be able to sit back
and slurp that z via and then at five
o'clock in the morning, God damn, I got a,
do you ever sip on a whiskey or
earthy at night with the wifey,
watching game of Thrones? No. I'll
drink a little wine with dinner,
but I don't drink whiskey
at home very often.
I drink whiskey when I'm looking to get
fucked up or before weighty up. Yeah.
I'll have
a shot. Yeah. Here's a prompt. So if
I become an alcoholic in three years,
it all stem on blaming you because
when we are doing that said,
I think at the Improv you're like,
you want a shot of whiskey? I'm like,
I don't drink before
shows, man. You're like,
I'm telling you it helps you with
your nerve. So I was like, all right,
this guy's been doing it forever.
Let me try it. Did the shot,
one of the best sets I've ever had.
I don't know how long ago it was.
Two months ago.
Three months go.
Every time I do comedy now I have
a shot of whiskey. Well, make sure,
make sure you don't do that.
Make sure why not.
Cause you don't want to become an
alcoholic. Which one shot. Hey,
come on lunch. I am. I was going
to get it. Whistle show the day.
Yeah, you could do it. Yeah. I feel good.
As long as I work out the next morning.
Hydrate. One shot is not
that bad for your body. No,
it's not the best thing in the world.
But it's not live in though.
But it's a good amount to give you like
a little, just a little. Fuck it juice.
Loosey Goosey. So uptight.
It's a fucking man. Fun.
Yeah. That's what whiskeys for. You know?
That's why it's been around so long.
You know,
like that buffalo trace shit that we drank
when we were doing the podcast. Shit,
man. Stuffs from the 17
hundreds fucking night. It is.
That fucking company was started in the
17 hundreds. How ridiculous that is.
I have seen about orange some from my
house cause I like that with so much.
Like I don't need that in my life. Yeah.
Because I'll just start drinking, become,
you know, I'm not like out
with me. I'm on alcoholic man.
It's good during fight companions.
I'm going to save it for that. Yeah.
I don't keep like whiskey at home.
I don't find myself interested cause I,
if I want to get like a little tipsy,
I want to be with my boys and fuck around.
Like I don't, I like it at a bar. I
like it. Uh, I like it at a comedy club.
I like it here. I love it during
five companions or favorite.
But it'd be like if I had like a man cave
or guys came over and we played poker,
we drink some whiskey. That'd
be fun. Yeah. But again,
you're with your boys. Yeah,
but I'm just chilling at home by myself.
Yeah.
Might get trunk and say
something inappropriate. Yeah.
Get cancelled at my own house. Again,
it's a different kind of drunk too.
Like whiskey trunk is like Jesus
Christ like you, you, you know,
you get belligerent.
I don't need that
until he started having fun.
You start playing Hank William to juniors
songs real loud. Outlandish. Yeah.
Yeah. Dude, there's some fucking,
you go into that deep country music.
What were you just telling me about
country music that some giant country rap?
What is the a song it's called Old Town
road. Old Town road. Old Town road.
One of the biggest songs out.
It's number one on the regular church
in the country. T charts, right.
Put it together. Little nausea x, is
that right? Everyone's little legs.
Little Nas had a little nausea,
but so he was on the country charts.
They took them off because
like this isn't country man,
but then he linked up with
Miley Cyrus, his dad. What's
his name? Billy Ray. Cyrus.
Billy Ray Cyrus. How dare
you, I think also had
to do with this. Is he used at whether
he did it or not? I don't know.
But he used the video game,
red dead redemption and some of the
cool graphics and then made a rap song,
country rap song, it's called called
country trap is what they're calling it.
That's why it's a different
thing. But it's got, it's got,
it's catchy and it's based around this
kind of stuff. It got, it got hot,
it caught, they're
caught. The wave country,
like the djs on all the stations were
like just ripping it off of youtube and
playing it. That's why it made it on
the billboard. And then they'll put,
it was like, hey, this isn't
a country song. Take it off.
And then because that almost, it's
like Streisand effect. It got bigger.
So they, um, they who,
who took it off billboard did, why did
they take it off? Because it doesn't,
and there third description was that it
doesn't meet the qualifications country
to meet country with Billy Ray.
Cyrus jumped onboard and then there's
video of him and Billy Ray Cyrus studies
studio. It's so interesting when
you're looking at the footage of it,
how cool that fucking game, this is just a
game. This is, that's a huge game, right?
Red Redemption. Yup, too. But
what a great idea to wrap over.
Read the smart demolition.
That's a genius idea.
I think I'll take that game is
played it in here. Jamie and I,
we pay you guys beat the Shit on me.
Whatever game we played last night.
That was quick as fuck.
I don't want to fuck with that game.
We're just talk a little about Tom.
Papa walked in.
Jeff and I were battling to death.
Tom Papa don't play. You know,
he was just watching us going,
what the fuck are you doing? Yeah.
What are you doing? What are you
doing Tom? Papa. So funny man.
He just wants everything to be old school.
He's so wants to go to the,
to the paper vendor and get a newspaper
and bake his own bread. I take that.
What does this Manson, what
was that like with Billy Ray?
He's like a real video now.
They made a real video. Oh Wow.
I'm not feeling a real video.
Do I like the way he two dancers with
a cowboy hat on? No. But he's like,
he's become a star because of this.
It's getting played all the festivals,
all the last couple of weeks.
The crowds are loving it.
Why didn't he open up at Coachella? It
was already booked. It's more along.
This happened so quick.
You could sneak him in.
Billy Ray Cyrus let bit your mind ready
to get his whistle wet at Coachella
played it,
I'm sure.
But like I saw that little like the
Yodel kid was singing this song,
like he's even Toronto
and all kinds of shit.
Do you know who Billy Ray Cyrus
says? No. He knows big hit. Oh yeah.
Don't keep breaking my heart.
His daughter's way bigger.
Um, he was really huge for a
brief moment in time. But yeah,
he was never like what she is,
she gets,
she gets she fucking sound to fuck.
And she was on that crazy.
Disney hit forever. Hannah Montana,
Montana forever, which made no sense.
I put a wig on and nobody notices
because it is strange. So ridiculous.
Like Batman, there is glorious locks.
God looks like. Yeah, he goes, brother.
Yeah. So everybody was doing the Achy
breaky heart back then. [inaudible]
93 million. I bet that must have
fucking freaked him out, man.
Take he's famous. He was back then
for that brief moment in time,
dude gets weirder now to be famous.
Like back then you could get away
things and now it's a nightmare. Yeah,
that's true.
Do you remember the Bill Hicks bit?
Bill Hicks had a joke about Billy Ray
Cyrus. What? He said it was terrible.
He was so mean. He was saying
that, uh, this is my last show.
I'm not doing standup anymore.
Uh,
because I got a TV show and he goes,
thank you ladies and gentlemen. I mean,
I worked hard forever and uh, now we're
going to do a new television show.
It's called let's hunt
and kill Billy Ray Cyrus
chase him down.
I forget what he,
but he said like grab him by his
faggy ponytail. And she was like,
wow, it's intense. It was ruthless.
It was ruthless because Billy Ray,
you only had that one hit, right?
He didn't have multiple kits.
Maybe have like shit one or two other
songs that were kind of popular,
but that song was gigantic. It's
interesting that his daughter show big.
She's so talented. Man. That Song
Malibu. She so good. So good.
Yeah. Can't tell people like
it though. They get mad at you.
Like get mad at you when
you're wearing those shoes.
And I don't give a fuck dude wrecking
ball for Miley Cyrus Acoustics sucked this
beast.
I'll listen to that and wear these shoes.
The best thing she ever did to me,
like when I, well, the most impactful.
So the first time I realized she could
really sing was that song Jolene. Oh my.
I've heard of,
to Jolene Christ Monster.
God Damn fucking pop. Do you
watch American idol? It'll do.
I look like a girl. You don't watch
any American idol talking about man,
Malibu,
Bro.
We were broken out over music
kid watching American idol.
There's always some stuff
from it. This like, dude,
they did at the grammys this year, but
the American, I sang it together. Yeah,
that kid is awesome. Yeah.
You watch American idol.
You're fucking line. They do.
What do you have the time?
Sunday nights you have the time for
Sunday night's my night off, bro.
He be playing quake with us in the
quick hello. I have a little land party.
They're real.
You only still real people seeing your
balls and in game of Thrones through
dragons thrill.
I love it as well too.
I'm just saying at least American idol
or people pursuing their dreams so sweet
and they can sing. Yeah. Oh,
I don't hate on the show. I'm
happy it exists. I just uh,
it's only so many hours in
a day, son. That's all I'm
saying. I hear you. You know,
but at night when you're chilling,
not me. I like to chill to fiction.
That's what my favorite shit
is. Like what? Give me example,
game of Thrones type shit
or like a Mrs Maizel or uh,
any show that I'm Ozark and
he's a stranger things and
show that I'm really into,
that's why I like to chill with, I like
to follow like a storyline for years.
I like, it's weird. I, I'm
with you when I get soup,
like I'm super into game Thrones.
Like I watched all
the old seasons leading up to
this. Yeah, that's dope dude.
That's just,
it's just like a fun little escape where
he just locked into that and to me,
as you know, Paul Mooney said to
me once a long time ago, he goes,
if you really want to write, he goes,
go get entertained first. And I said,
you like, how would you like what'd he do?
He goes, whenever you go see some music,
he goes, go to the movies. It goes,
go be entertained, you're entertained,
and then you're going to
want to write. Oh Wow. Yeah.
That was great advice that I never heard
anybody say before, but it made sense.
It's like go get it or tained and get
like it'll fire you up and then is take,
take that fire and then just start
creating, inspires you. It's a,
it's a great piece of advice for,
for young people because I know there's
been many times where I've seen someone
like murder at the store where I
couldn't wait to get home and write.
I just couldn't wait to,
you know,
I just wanted to run home and bust
out that fucking laptop and come on.
What do we got in here?
What are we got in that brain
come on or something in there.
Do you listen to music when you drive?
Sometimes.
Depends on if I'm on my way to the Gig.
If I'm on my way to the Gig,
almost always try to listen to last
night set or whatever new shit that I'm
working on to go over it. Just not done.
Not just to go over but to examine it,
see if there's any way that I want to
stop and rewind to maybe slow it down or
speed it up or do it different.
If I don't take those extra,
like say if I do four sets a week,
but I listened to three sets a week,
that's seven sets instead of four sets.
I think that's,
that's a difference like a rep thing,
but it's uncomfortable.
Like you don't want to do it.
It's annoying,
but I think it counts almost
as much as doing a set.
It's not as much cause doing a set.
What happens is you get that
spontaneity and you get the flow.
When you get the instinct,
the feeling when it hit the
punchline in the car's a mental rope,
it's a mental rapid,
but it's also like a third party examiner.
Like it's almost like you could
watch it from the outside.
You could watch it as someone,
well,
I still be second party is you'd watch
it as someone watching you and you'd go,
Ha, I don't like, this is clunky,
white sand. It's like this.
If you could just do that and say it
like yourself and say like yourself,
but then listen, like you would listen
to it too. As a fan of most t get.
Yeah. Listen, as a person who
is also, you know, you do it,
you practice it so you
know where the or the,
but sometimes you get caught up in doing
something a certain way and it's hard
to break out of the pattern of doing that
bit to try to find a better way. Yes.
Like you're comfortable with like, Oh
God, I've got to get into this bit.
How do I get into it?
And then you'll stumble into this one
way and then you keep doing it that way
when really the right way to do it is to
kind of break it down and rebuild. Yeah.
Like you know where the funny
parts are breaking it down.
And I've done that a few times in broken
bits where they never worked again.
Sometimes it just, they don't
bounce back, you know? Yeah.
You fricking a at the ice house,
man.
You get it. You mean you fucking, you did
that cause you getting ready for your,
your four 20 show. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Is
that the biggest crowd you've ever done?
Yeah. No. Uh,
Air Canada center was bigger Air Qantas
like that's the Scotia Bank arena.
Flock in Toronto. Canada is, is that
where a, that's what the UFC is.
That's right. Yeah. It's
the Scotia Bank arena now.
It used to be they're kind of the center.
And how many was that joint?
That's like 13,000. Were you on a
stage I Kevin Hart stage? No, no, no.
It was on like a regular stage. Is a San
Diego circular? Yeah. San Diego Sorkin.
I find it awkward men watching it.
I find it awkward.
I mean obviously we can kill it, but
I find it awkward. Yeah. I'm excited.
I think Joe does doing for 20 in Milwaukee
as the past.
Can't get enough of that dude.
So happy he's around. He's one of the
most, you know what he's doing right now,
right? I don't think I can say it on
there. Don't say it then. Oh yeah,
I do. No, I don't think you can say it.
No, I don't think he's announced it.
It's amazing. Yeah. Yeah.
Can't say that. Can't say that.
But you know. Yeah. So cool.
He's the one of the most important
figures in the standup world today,
in my opinion,
who's one of the most free guys?
Like in terms of like if, if you
look at, if there was a style of, um,
say is a style of Jujitsu,
right?
Where one guy is just always
catching triangles on people,
super aggressive and always
catching, trying. It was like,
how is this guy always kid?
And it sort of changes your perception
of how often someone can catch someone in
a triangle.
Joey so fucking loose.
He changes your perception
of what's loose. Like he, he,
he moves the needle. Yeah.
Is Rare. That's rare.
I think bill bird does that two
moves the needle too with bill and I,
and maybe it's because I'm around Brian
and Brian's always like, you know,
you gotta be careful
if you say this stuff,
especially in the culture side right now.
Yeah. Be careful with this. And I'm like,
yeah,
maybe.
So I've started like almost reserved
and then per went up at the last fact.
Don't have that. Oh Shit. You can do that.
Yeah. He's on fire right now. He just
filmed, um, he just filmed some, uh,
special. Did he really? Yeah, yeah.
Yeah. He's kind of come out with, oh,
I should say anything a while ago though.
Right?
Because the stuff he did in
the house all knew it. Well,
I don't know if I'm supposed to be
saying this. Did I give something away?
I Dunno. I don't know if that's been
announced. So I'm going to shut my mouth,
by the way. Either way. Murderer murder.
No fucks get bit all the time.
No fucks. Given at all. Yeah.
Yeah. He's um, he's uniquely free.
Like he was making the
comics in the back like,
and we're just watching like
what, it makes hilarious
points too. They're so bold,
but that's what she's so bold.
That's how he started. Yeah. He's
just sticking with his guns. That's
what he is. That's who he is, who he is.
I think I'd see a lot of guys navigate
away from that because they're afraid of
offending people and then he gets
up and he's like, shut the fuck up.
What people are taking comedy as much
more of a statement than like if you wrote
a movie where some
fucked up things happen.
Like if you were older and
that's probably coming to,
if they let people take comedy,
they'll probably go after
that next w which would,
it's kind of falls in line with what,
what could be next.
But if you decide that someone saying
something that they actually mean that
they shouldn't be able to say that even
though it's funny and it made people
laugh. The guy's clearly joking,
which is that it has been,
especially when you try to use it
in print, it's a slippery slope.
It's a slippery slope.
Greased Hill because then why or why is
Quintin Tarantino allow to write a movie
where a bunch of people get killed?
Why is he allowed to write a
movie that might incite violence?
Why is he allowed to write a movie
where people use racial slurs and shoot
people over? Nothing. Why is you're
allowed to ride to write that movie? Oh,
it's all Quintin Tarantino.
So he's responsible for
this whole movie. Fuck that.
We got to boycott him and that that kind
of nonsense is an episode of fucking
South Park that's coming, went on
in this world. I don't think it's,
I think it's swinging back the other way.
It could sway back the other way,
but you got to realize we could take a
little break and then have it come back
hard again.
May Be,
or those guys or the guys like Louis C
K who selling out everywhere and doing
great comedy like he can't, he could
sell out fucking staple center right now.
Multiple Times in a row. What's crazy
is he doesn't want to, doesn't want to,
it's just too in comedy
clubs just working. Yeah.
He could easily come back like
tiger woods easily right now.
He said something so fucked up too because
they asked me why I did it. He goes,
I like to jerk off and I
don't want to be alone.
I like to jerk off and I don't like to
be alone. Like, oh, and then you know
he's great man. Yeah. I mean he asked, he
did some creepy shit. He definitely did.
Did some creepy shit. I don't approve
of it, but he didn't molest anyone.
I don't think we know exactly what
happened either. I don't know.
But I do know is he could
sell out staple center. Yeah,
because I think most guys in fans go,
all right man. But the other thing that,
and he's really good at
comedy. Yeah. That's the other,
the other thing that we always have
to think about whenever we talk about
anything is that where dude's,
and so when we're talking about
someone jerking off in front of you,
just imagine a woman
jerking off in front of us.
Now you can't because that's not the
same cause it would the only reason why a
girl could jerk off in front of you.
And it's hilarious.
It's cause she can't rape. You. See if
a guy is jerking off in front of you,
most guys are bigger and
stronger than most women.
Obviously there's some variables there,
but most guys are bigger and
stronger and men make all the rape.
The women aren't out there raping
dudes, right? It's all men.
So if a guy has his dick out
and he's jerking off scary shit,
that's why it's scary.
It's creepy if a girl,
if you go over a girl's house
and for whatever reason she goes,
I want you to watch it sit down.
You fucking, you know, fucking fuck.
She starts fingering herself. Fucking
whoa. Yeah, but you wouldn't laugh.
You would laugh and you
would come back to here.
And we would talk about it cause I know
I can get out of time. Yeah, right.
We'd be crying laughing, but it
wouldn't be like you were in danger.
But if a guy is with safety,
you have a daughter and your daughter
weighs 110 pounds and she's with a guy and
the guy wants to jerk off in front of her.
Yeah.
And he asked to do it and she
says yes cause she scared. Fuck.
Then it's like what,
what would actually happen?
And see he hasn't really said anything
other than the stories are true.
And you know this is come from a
guy that sounds like, you know,
cause you have two daughters. Yeah. Well
it's so you have to think like that.
Well you have to think like that
as a human being, right? Yeah.
But I'm saying to you,
it's probably the first thing you think
of cause you have two daughters. Right.
But I don't think that's what he did.
I think from,
I can't say too much cause I don't know.
But I think he did some regrettable
things and I think he would admit that.
But I don't think he did what a lot of
people are claiming he did in terms of,
that's what I've heard,
how often he did it or who he did
or what the circumstances were,
but it was either way.
There's no defending when it
was bad. No, it's not good.
There's no difference.
It's a terrible thing to do.
But what's the punishment for that?
You know how much I punish her?
Do you not pay for it? You're lost
all his jobs, lost all his TV deals,
$35 million in a year of work and people
still were saying no, but he's still,
he's fine. I've heard that
argument that he's fine. Like what?
These are also, these are also things
that he did like more than a decade ago.
Right. What, when do you
offer someone compassion?
Like when do you, when do you let
some explain themselves? When do you,
when is it enough is enough or
should he have to do something?
Like what would people like someone to
do? Well, I think they're coming because,
because there's only a year and then
he's back and killing it because he's so
good at comedy because like with Tiger
Woods, right? People hated tiger.
Well there was that,
but there was also the material
that got leaked when he came back.
So people were upset at the jokes.
The parkland joke. Yeah. Not the best.
It's that shit falls in line with
how he's always done jokes though.
I told he's always,
whether he did this or not,
he says the fucked up thing to say.
It's part of what makes him really funny.
And he does that in real life too.
It's not, it's a style of comedy man.
I mean it's just like a Quentin
Tarantino has a style of making movies.
His style of comedy is
to say fucked up thing.
So that compounded the fact that people
were upset at them that a year ago,
you know, he said he was going to take
some time off and it's, um, I don't,
you know,
I think it's really important to know
that I don't know what happened and,
and you know,
he knows and they know and it's,
it's never good when someone's upset
that you jerked off in front of them.
That miss I get time,
which is never good for anybody,
but also him losing $35 million
in only being out a year.
I think people are upset that have
such a quick turnaround. Like Tj,
is that a quick turnaround,
man? I mean, not as a comic,
but for, to the, to the, uh,
normal person like a year. That
ain't shit dude. But as a comic,
not to be able to do, let's imagine that
he's going to live another 50 years,
right? A year, a year out of 50.
It's like a 2% right. Yeah. It's a lot.
It's a lot and a lot of money. Yeah.
Now now, oh, now compare this
to Tj Dillashaw two years,
two years of he's 31.
Yeah.
One 35 or not a lot of fights left now.
Two years is almost a death
sentence. It might be, is that fair?
That's a good question.
I mean the real question is,
would he have even been able
to pursue that weight class?
Like with what you were saying in terms
of like having the advantage of the EPO?
Yeah. Wonder if he would have
been able to pursue training,
but at the same way in hindsight,
what a terrible idea.
You know, I don't know what the thought
process was, but it's definitely,
definitely not good. And um, it,
it doesn't take away from how talented
and skillful he is as a fighter.
And if that's the only time he did it,
it's kind of understandable.
That's what I'm [inaudible] yeah.
If that's the only time,
but I think honestly, all bullshit
aside, I think you are right.
As far as don't test anybody else. Don't,
don't go back and test everybody. No.
Unless you want to spend a lot of money.
The one of the things they were saying
that like to test everyone for EPO,
it costs an additional two and
a half million dollars a year.
Something ridiculous like that. I might've
made some numbers, stopped doing that,
divide that money amongst the fighters.
Ooh, I can watch them go off any test.
Don't care to give the fetish more money.
What style been and Kelvin did
and Max Holloway and Dustin Poray,
they should be set for quite some time.
But here's the thing,
if we look over the history and really
are only testing pool would be Connor
McGregor who Deborah has to fight again.
Nate Diaz,
I guess you get thrown to that. Who?
They make life changing money, right?
They don't find a lot,
do they? No. And here,
here's the question because if you give,
I'm sorry, I don't mean to interrupt you,
but let's say, you know, if
he have certain fighters,
$20 million like you want me to do
what now? And they don't fight, right?
So if you're Dana, you're like, listen,
look at Conor [inaudible], Nate Diaz,
when they get this boatload of money,
we can't give them to fight.
They have the sports too
hard. They won't do it. Hmm.
That's interesting. I know. So
to keep, to keep 'em hungry,
we got to pay him this hit with
that. It's so fucked up. So if,
I'm not saying it's the right thing to do,
but I'm saying if you're Dana,
from his standpoint, you're like,
do you think they get really,
they don't fight way they really think
that way. I don't think that's the case.
You don't think it's a side effect
of making boat loads of money,
but I think they tried to make boatloads
of money cause it doesn't happen very
often. It only happens with a Rhonda
Rousey or Conor McGregor or some gigantic,
huge star like a Nate Diaz did. You
have to be a gigantic, huge state. Yeah,
but that's, that's rare. There's so few
of those guys. There's so few of those.
The idea that you would try to pay
people less because you want to keep them
hungry. Because if they'd become giant
superstars and they're not hungry,
then they stopped fighting,
then we're not paying more.
So what you're saying is pretend
you're not there, not giant superstars.
Even when they are know the
giant superstars still get paid,
but they also have crazy demands.
They want to fight who they want to fight,
they want to do it when
they want to do it.
And there's all sorts of jockeying
going on back and forth. I mean,
I don't know what happened with
Nate Diaz and Dustin Poray,
but they were supposed to fight
first fight and Dustin got injured.
But so Nate was scheduled for a fight
and he's never pulled out of a fight that
has been scheduled for as far
as I can remember him. No.
He was going to fight that fight and then
went to happen. That made other offers.
You just like, I'm good. Right?
But let's imagine that if Dustin poray
did not pull out of that fight, would,
if he did fight Nate Diaz,
and what if Nate Diaz beat him?
The Nate Diaz could very well have
fought Max Holloway maybe Saturday night.
Yeah. Maybe. Maybe if you
paid them enough, it may
be. I'm sure he would. They,
they might've decided to make that shit
happen, you know? And you know what?
I bet it would have been. Yeah, that
was it. That was the face to face off.
I bet that would have been a very
entertaining fight to God. Oh my God.
Acts and 80th Bolkestein sane cardiac.
Yes.
Insane volume striking. That would
be an incredible fight, man. Fuck.
That would be a great fighter. You
fight. That'd be a great fight. Yeah.
Max and Nick would be,
would have been insane,
but Max was going to fight Dustin Poirier
and you know, he could be looked at,
would be a big fight.
Dustin Poria if he doesn't fight Khabib,
if for whatever reason they decide to
go with Nate over could be, they're not,
they're going to do, could
be next. Yeah, in September.
Well maybe can be fights the winner
or uh, the winter rather fights. Nate.
That could be possible too. If he really
still weren't Tony. Tony Ferguson.
Yeah. God Damn. And Kate. She's
still in the mix. I mean, Katie,
he's deep in the mix. That superheat
Boza he's so excited before.
Now he's right there. How
can you deny that? I mean,
what a fucking division man.
Amazing. What a fucking division.
It's crazy. How about that dude in
one fc that knocked out Alvarez.
I know. Nasty. UCAN. What a crazy name
too. How about mighty mouse though?
Getting the wind? Yeah. I'm still waiting
for sage Northcutt to fight. Um, yeah, no,
she's a tough fight to fight. And cosmo
Alexander his tough fight. Dude. Cosmos.
No punk. That dude's a nasty
Moyie Thai fighter. I got to beat
John Wayne Park. He's really, really
good. Yeah, he's built like an Adonis too.
That's going to be a best
bod contest between those
two. Yeah, that's first team.
First team. Both of them.
Dangerous fight for, um,
sage Northcutt while they're standing.
If he can't take it to the ground.
You mean stage is a very good
striker and he's very fast,
but cosmos worldclass he's something
special. He's something special. Nasty,
nasty. Moy Timon. Monster.
Yeah. Big Guy too. You know,
he's jacked. His thick sage is
such a nice kid. Could be nicer.
Couldn't be nicer. It's
almost fake. Did you,
were you surprised that the
UFC let them go? Uh, no.
I'm not surprised by anything you'll see.
Does not surprise.
They don't need anyone. I thought
they were grooming him. Me Too.
And put a lot of marketing behind
him. They're like, fuck it.
We're going to go on
ESPN. We're good. Well,
so what do you think the
future is going to be like?
Do you think there's going to be that
this is going to be how it is for most
sports.
They're going to be watched on apps.
You think they'll ever have that for like
the NFL? Oh, hundred percent. They just,
the future. The UFC is
just, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Pick the last two years at a
Thursday night games have been on a,
at least last year was on Amazon prime.
They were,
they were on Twitter on to
twitch for a little while.
They're on Twitter last year, so they're,
they're doing all sorts of stuff.
The NBA has talked about moving
towards, uh, being maybe on twitch.
They've even talked about shortening
our season or doing different stuff that
they just had a big conference about that
because he made the smart move. Yeah.
It's a smart move. It's, there's a smart,
because they're getting out way ahead.
That's what it is.
I feel like once everyone's TV's hooked
up to the Internet cause right now it's
not everyone. No. You know.
Yeah. It's a lot of people,
but it's not everybody. It's going
to be everybody. For sure. Dude.
I got a role they get to my
kid on 6:00 PM I know, man.
Brandon motherfucking shop. Thank you
for coming out. I love you too, brother.
That was fun. Hey, we're doing a show
together when we were doing that show.
Sold out. Both. Ha. I'm in Arizona
though next week. Friday sending you out.
Stand up live dog. Phoenix, Arizona.
Beautiful. Phoenix, Arizona.
Standup live tampa.com.
[inaudible] dot com all right brother.
Can I see you say everybody?
Yeah,
yeah.