Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Well,
I'll start.
Hello,
ladies and gentlemen.
Hello.
Dr. McGee.
That sounds not me pitching.
If you're hearing that,
you're like,
what is this?
Is this a podcast and a bathroom?
No,
that's coffee.
How are you buddy?
Good.
Thank you for having me.
Thanks for being here.
For folks who have heard me a rant and
rave about the fantastic results that
I've had,
I'm getting treatment on my shoulder
where I was that close to getting
surgery.
It's this gentleman,
Dr Mcphee,
who has a fixed me up out of Las Vegas,
Nevada.
And uh,
now we're here to talk about it.
Yeah,
no,
I appreciate the chance to be here.
What do you have,
man?
A very short words today.
He was very talkative before the podcast
folks.
That's how it goes.
But now I'm hearing myself and that was
it.
Weird you out?
Yeah,
you take them off.
We can take them off as too weird.
He'd never done a podcast like this for
you.
Did John Dudley's.
Yeah.
Is Excellent.
We can take it off.
I might have to.
Okay,
let's take it off.
I don't want to freak you out.
Yeah.
Is that better?
This is a little more like a normal
conversation.
I don't want to freak you out.
To me it's better cause like I can hear
like if it's things are wrong,
what's a,
what's the notes Daddy?
Oh,
what do you got there?
Uh,
just a couple of things I jotted down.
Just make sure a gift you all the
information you want to hear.
Well,
I just want to tell you that I feel
super fortunate to have met you and to
have been treated by you and to be able
to have these conversations with you and
your office,
which is why I wanted to have you here
to talk to you because I mean,
I was having some really significant
shoulder issues before.
Um,
you treated it and it's,
it's amazing the results and what,
what,
you know,
I mean,
what,
what I've avoided,
avoided in shoulder surgery.
Yeah.
I mean you've had a tremendous result.
So,
uh,
obviously we're very thankful that
you're able to get that benefit.
And I think we're in my community of
Orthopedic Surgery and sports medicine.
You know,
we're very excited about the possibility
and eager to continue to learn about it
and see what it can be and how it can
help and what it does best for.
What now?
Where's all this stuff coming from?
Like winter?
Where is this science coming from and
how has it evolved over the last few
years?
Well,
um,
a lot of the stuff that we're using is
not new in terms of,
uh,
the tissue or a,
that type of thing.
But it's actually that the application
for Orthopedic Sports Medicine,
so you could go back decades to when
it's been used in plastic surgery,
uh,
for corneal ulcers is one of the
original applications of placental
tissue.
So the idea of it isn't necessarily new,
it's just that as we've gained more
understanding in our community of
orthopedic surgery,
now we're starting to see what the
applications can be.
Now,
when you say plastic surgery,
like what have they done with it?
With plastic surgery,
mostly helping with wounds,
complication,
wound healing,
and the potential
for there to be wound healing without
scarring.
So that's one of the things that we'll
get into.
How do they do that?
Um,
it's part of the mechanism of how the
cell helps the process of the healing.
So,
but we'll talk about that for sure.
Now when they extract the placental
tissue,
like how are they,
they're,
they're doing it on young women who have
had [inaudible] sections,
crusher.
So bypasses a lot of the ethical
concerns that a lot of people had during
the Bush administration,
which kept them.
Okay.
So let's,
you said a couple of different important
things,
so let's start breaking that down a
little bit.
So the first thing is,
um,
you know,
where does it come from?
It comes from a young,
healthy mother.
In this case,
what we're talking about,
um,
this particular category of biologic
treatment or cellular tissue,
uh,
this comes from a young healthy mother
that's having elective c section and
prior to the delivery has agreed to make
a charitable donation.
And then they have been screened and
there's a process that must be followed
by the American Association of Tissue
Banks.
And they have a series of blood tests
that they have to go through.
And so you're checking to be sure that
there's no communicable disease,
you know,
for example,
hepatitis or HIV,
uh,
things of that nature.
And so once that has been cleared and
they're an acceptable donor,
then they go through the delivery,
the tissues collected.
And as you said,
this is stuff that typically would go in
the garbage.
So,
um,
essentially the,
you know,
the ethical and the moral dilemma
shouldn't exist for that portion of it
because otherwise it's just garbage.
Now that's taken by the company that has
harvested and they have their processing
center,
which also has to be,
uh,
evaluated and approved by this aatp
American Association of Tissue Banks,
uh,
to be a facility that is up to their
standards.
So they have a sterilization process.
The tissue's not contaminated.
Their packaging is appropriate that are,
you know,
their shipping's not causing problems
with the tissue.
So you have to meet all these standards
is very stringent.
And so if you have that,
if a company has that,
uh,
approval,
then you know,
they,
they meet the standards allowed so that
that stuff can then go either to an
office or to a hospital.
So now the,
the next thing of what you said,
um,
let's talk a little bit about,
uh,
President Bush and that whole
discussion.
So first of all,
that is about embryonic stem cells.
Okay.
An embryonic stem cell,
and that's,
you know,
that doesn't have anything to do with
what we're doing.
Um,
an embryonic stem cell is when the sperm
and the egg join and begin to form the
beginning sells a life and there's
initially two cells and then it divides
into four,
eight,
et cetera.
In the f the first five days of life,
that's called a blastocyst.
And those cells can be harvested,
um,
and they are what we call toady potent.
That means they can become anything.
They have the ability to transform into
any line of tissue or Oregon,
or in the case of that first five days
of life,
those individual cells can actually
become a complete organism.
So that's,
that's where we have,
you know,
the cloning of the sheep.
So that's what happens.
So they,
they took the cells in that first couple
of days and then they divide process to
allow it to continue to grow.
And,
and so you had two different,
from a single sperm and egg,
you had two organisms,
complete mammals,
you know,
created.
So when you say this blastocyst,
is that how you say it?
That's just the term for the initial,
you know,
the ball of cells that's formed.
And how many cells is in a blastocyst?
Well,
they're dividing over the number of days
in doubling each time.
So then thousands,
not by that time.
No.
Hundreds.
You're 16,
you know,
32.
So if you have 32,
how many different organisms can you
make off of those 32 cells?
Technically,
if you have a toadie potent cell,
every individual cell has the ability to
become a complete organism.
Whoa.
So that could be one.
Blastocyst could be 32 different people,
I guess.
Potentially.
Wow.
I don't know if that experiment's been
carried out,
but theoretically at least.
Wow.
So,
um,
now when they have like frozen embryos,
when people do things like that,
when they decide they want to have kids
later in life and they freeze their
embryos,
how the hell are they doing that?
What's,
what's that about?
And I'm not like a reproduction
specialists so we might be getting,
you know Adam,
but it's frozen embryos.
A lot of times they don't get used.
Right.
I don't know.
I don't know how that works.
Um,
cause I know there's been battles,
like people have had battles with their
wives and stuff.
That's very much the,
my understanding of it would be that if
you're,
you know,
you're freezing it with the intention of
maintaining the cell viability and so
somebody has demonstrated that you could
then thaw that sal and it still has the
opportunity to divide,
produce and you know,
become a living thing.
Wow.
I was thinking like for the non-viable
ones or the ones that don't get turned
into people,
they could probably use those as well.
Right.
Well that,
that's a big,
that was the thing,
right?
That was the big George Bush thing.
Well.
Okay,
so let's back up on that because I think
there's a lot of misconception about
that.
And I hear like very strange comments
made about it all the time in the media.
So the thing that George Bush signed in
2001 stated that the federal government
was not going to supply money for
embryonic stem cell research.
That's it.
It was not a ban on the APP,
on nation,
on stem cell research.
So for all of that time,
I mean private equity companies in any
private investor could have and probably
been spending the money
to continue to research that and develop
it and find it.
So I always find it interesting when I
hear on TV,
oh,
like the,
our country has been set back a decade
because they signed to this,
you know,
Bill.
I'm like,
so you feel that's wrong?
Yeah,
that's so,
um,
but all he said was,
we're not going to dedicate federal
money to it.
Right.
That's different than a ban on any
study.
But how much research does rely on
federal funding?
And I don't know.
I mean there's,
there's private funding for all kinds of
things.
So is it more common now than it is
before or is it always been the case
where there's a lot of private funding?
So President Obama in 2009 lifted the
ban on the federal funding.
So federal fundings been going on for it
since,
since then.
Interesting.
Yeah.
So what is the difference in terms of
the viability of placental stem cells
that you would get from a woman in
necessary and section versus something
that you would get from a blastocyst?
Well,
so a couple of things about that.
Um,
one there's,
um,
it's actually to our benefit in
orthopedics not to be using that line of
cells because those cells starting from
that time point have the ability to have
teratogenic potential.
So what that means is they can
potentially form tumors.
So that makes it obviously a big
disadvantage because now we're,
we're adding our risk to what we're
doing once they've gotten to the point
where it's a part of the,
the whole,
you know,
we call this like a human placental stem
cells or Mesenchymal stem cell.
And that includes the placenta,
the umbilical cord,
the Wharton's Jelly is a mucus type
substance.
It's around the arteries of the
umbilical cord,
the amnion or the amniotic sac,
which is the inner layer around the the
baby.
And then the outer layer is called the
cory on.
Now all of that has cells in it that we
would put in the category of Ms Inca,
most stem cells or Mesenchymal stem
cell.
And what that means is they have a
specific line of tissues that they can
become.
So now back to when I was explaining the
formation of the blastocyst becomes a
Morella becomes,
uh,
an embryo eventually.
So in that process,
uh,
you have this ball of tissue and then it
starts to kind of fold in on itself.
And then it starts to layer out into
these three layers.
You have endoderm,
ectoderm,
mesoderm,
the,
um,
each of those kinds of is directed
towards a certain line of cells and
tissues.
The misa Durham,
and what these,
uh,
the Mesenchymal stem cells can become,
are all of the things that we care about
in orthopedics.
So cartilage,
bone,
muscle,
ligament,
tendon.
So we have that whole line of cells,
um,
that this particular sale has the
potential to become.
So when we talk about a stem cell,
the by definition,
what it means is one,
it can divide and become another stem
cell so it can,
it can duplicate itself so that now you
have another cell that can divide and
become another cell or it can divide and
differentiate into a cell that then has
the characteristics of the things that
you're hoping it will become.
Now that's a,
uh,
directed in ordered approach in
embryology.
And in the case of,
uh,
treating an injury,
what we're hoping is that that can
differentiate into the injured tissue.
And how long have they been doing that
while studies on that have been going on
for at least 10 years.
So I want to say maybe back as early as
2007.
Um,
now we've been,
if you go in a way back to the early
days of a arthroscopy,
and now it'd be like the late seventies
and early 1980s,
uh,
and I don't know exactly what year,
you know,
he would have started doing this,
but,
um,
doctor steadman at,
uh,
in Vail,
Colorado and he was in Reno and Lake
Tahoe area before that.
They would,
um,
this,
he's the one that developed the
microfracture procedure.
I don't know if you're familiar with
that.
You've had a couple of knee surgery,
so I don't know if you've heard that
term,
but I have,
but I don't really recall exactly what
it is.
Sure.
So basically if a patient had a small
cartilage defect,
he took a small,
uh,
an all or like what looked like a tiny
little pick and made a puncture into the
bone.
And what that did is it releases marrow
elements along with blood.
And they were able to see with time,
and you know,
there were occasions when they got to
have second look arthroscopy that that
cartilage could fill in.
Now they also found that that didn't
become the native cartilage.
It becomes something called fibro
cartilage.
So when you look at it under a
microscope,
it looks different compared to our
normal cartilage.
Hmm.
Appearance like physically looks the
same,
but under the microscope looks
different.
What is the difference?
Uh,
well,
the main difference in,
in what's applicable is that,
um,
it's doesn't have the same structural
properties.
So it was more easily able to kind of
come off with a sheer force.
So just picture like you were bending.
Yeah.
You could kind of flake off or,
or in some cases just didn't form as
well as you know,
you would want.
Hmm.
So,
so that experience,
um,
and I,
you know,
having conversations with the guy that I
trained with,
his name's Larry Lemak in Birmingham.
He noted just over his career that he
always felt like patients that had worse
arthritis,
but they would do this microfracture
procedure on in knee arthroscopy
actually would do better than patients
with less arthritis,
but that they didn't do the procedure.
And so it had always been in his mind
that,
that somehow that marrow stimulation
was,
was providing something that was helping
with either healing or pain relief.
Um,
and,
and it's only now that we start to
understand,
you know,
because the bone marrow has some of
these mesenchymal stem cells available
also.
And we'll kind of talk about the
differences and stuff like that.
So it was essentially like a crude
version of some stem cell transplants,
like,
yeah,
I think that's a good way to put it.
Yeah.
I mean,
our hope is that we're,
we're using cells that can again,
change into other things that we want.
And when did they start applying this on
people?
Like in terms of not just tests and
studies,
but actually in practice,
like what you do?
Uh,
well,
in Orthopedic Sports Medicine,
I don't think I started to hear about it
until around 2012.
So that was the first year that I was in
practice and I attended a conference in
Las Vegas and it was called the emerging
techniques in orthopedics.
So they were kind of talking about
what's the,
the newest and uh,
you know,
most forward thinking ideas that are
coming through.
So a company presented and one of the
physicians presented information showing
that they had harvested fat tissue from
patients abdomens and injected into
their knee,
um,
for patients that had knee arthritis and
they were showing new growth of
cartilage and,
and actually improvement in some of the
x rays.
So when you look at an x ray,
there's some characteristics that we
look at that,
you know,
define what arthritises.
So if the patient has narrowing of the
joint space or they have bone spurs,
things like that,
um,
they were actually seeing more space
between the bones and some of these
serial x rays.
So,
you know,
I saw that and that was just like so
incredible and something that I'd never
heard about,
read about or you know,
had encountered before.
And that's really what kind of sparked
my interest.
And what are they doing with the fat?
Cause I've,
I've heard that they do stem cells,
the virtual,
like a,
like a mini liposuction,
right.
And then they're,
you know,
they either spin it in a centrifuge or
there's a,
there,
you know,
these syringes that you can pass it
through a filter and then you reinject
it.
And,
and what you're trying to do is,
is again,
take advantage of the fact that there's
these mesenchymal stem cells in the
tissue and like what can they just,
are they just taking the fat,
like when they spin it in a centrifuge,
like what does that accomplish?
Uh,
just separates out the,
the cells.
So then you can inject the portion that
you want.
And we do that.
Usually I've had it with PRP.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So just I've,
I've had with Regina King,
which is like a form,
right?
PRP,
correct.
Yeah.
With a heated up and becomes like a
yellow serum.
Right?
So when their platelet layer of the
blood and you're looking at,
okay.
Yeah.
And so the,
the red cells separate out and you can,
you can easily see that in the tube.
And what is the difference in the
results from someone who does that?
Because I know quite a few people who've
done it that way.
They've had injuries treated where they
suck the fat out.
There isn't any,
uh,
any research to differentiate like one
of these treatments versus another yet
it's just not available.
So it's all anecdotal in terms of like
talking to patients.
It's happening.
I mean,
people are collecting the data,
but it's just not,
you know,
it's not at the mature stage where,
um,
you know,
where it's available and we have
published stuff to look at and
personally know of anybody who's had
really good results using the fat
method.
Um,
yes,
actually,
uh,
a physician friend of mine in Memphis,
Tennessee,
her name's doctor Laura Lenderman.
Um,
she has utilized that quite a bit and
she's been very happy with the patients
that she's treated in.
Naturally.
Some people do better than others,
but you know,
the,
the real,
the rigorous study of this though is
still yet to come.
It's really fascinating.
Like d have you considered trying that
or you just definitely,
yeah.
But you don't so far you just do the
stem cells haven't had anybody
specifically request it and,
uh,
maybe somebody wants to lose a little
fat and fix her knees.
Yeah,
I mean that's,
that's probably taking things in a
direction I don't want to be going.
But by plastic surgery are,
we know there are a number of different
options in terms of where these sources
of the cells can come from.
Um,
bone marrow is certainly had a lot of
use and Daniel Qca had that done.
That's what he told me.
Yeah.
He had a pulled out of his hip and he
said it was brutally painful then he was
walking with a limp for like two weeks.
It's a,
obviously it's a procedure.
Um,
there's pain and there's,
you know,
morbidity.
There's a consequence to,
you know,
putting a sharp object into the bone and
drying them.
Yeah.
So that means,
uh,
a bad thing.
I don't like that word now.
It's,
we don't like it either.
In medicine,
more bid is a bad word.
We have conferences called Morbidity and
mortality and that's where you basically
own up to things that you've done a
terrible job with or explain,
you know,
why somebody has died as a result of
your care.
And it's a awful thing to go through and
it's critically important to be able to
evaluate yourself and understand what
things happen when they don't go the way
that we want them to.
So it's an important exercise that
physicians go through to review cases.
So I can only imagine.
Yeah,
I mean,
especially if you're dealing with people
that are broken apart.
I mean,
essentially as an orthopedic surgeon,
you're dealing with,
people's bodies have failed,
right?
Your limbs have failed,
ligaments have torn off the bone,
and these have exploded.
I mean,
you've
told me some gnarly stuff in terms of
the kind of injuries that you've had to
treat,
and I could only imagine some of bad
things.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And so your time doing this with
placental stem cells,
how long have you been doing that?
Uh,
it's been a couple of years.
So essentially you did mine,
I think.
How long ago was it?
I think it was July of 2015 yeah.
So I kind of came in pretty,
pretty early because Jeff Davidson to
doctor from the UFC,
he was the one who told me about it
because he had shoulder surgery and um,
he was very stiff and had real problems
after the shoulder surgery and was,
I'm just very unhappy with his range of
motion and the pain that is
experiencing.
And then he got some stem cell
treatments and it just all went away.
Then he trains a lot.
Yeah.
Trains really hard and he's very fit,
pretty impressed with,
uh,
you know what he told me about how he
was,
what he was able to get back to you
after,
you know,
he had been treated with,
uh,
that type of injection.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So he told me and then I was like on the
fence.
I mean,
I'd seen an orthopedic surgeon and the
only thing that was keeping me from
getting surgery is,
you know,
he put me through all these,
um,
stress tests where he pushed down on my
arm and all this time and I resisted all
of them.
And he's like,
this is,
it's kind of odd,
but your injuries this bad,
but you have so much strength in your
joints still.
Yeah.
Like maybe you should hold off a little
bit before you get the surgery.
He's like,
cause I thought that when I examined you
two because I really couldn't reproduce
your pain.
Yeah.
So and that,
and that's,
that's another reason and then I
probably would have been in the same
boat as the first guy in terms of uh,
you know,
trying to make a decision about surgery.
Um,
because you know,
if your physical exam doesn't,
you know,
show that somebody has some significant
deficits,
it's,
it's hard to make the jump to take
somebody to surgery.
Well,
during normal,
everyday life there'd be like zero pain.
Right.
Problem is what I put my body through.
His has nothing that resembles normal
everyday life,
Jujitsu and kickboxing and kettle bells
and archery and yeah,
there's just so much explosive movements
and so much weight bearing movements and
doing really high demand stuff.
Yeah.
So in that,
in that case,
that was one of the reasons why I was
thinking,
cause like I don't want to walk around
with a compromised body.
I'm like,
if I have to just get surgery and then
take six months of Rehab or whatever it
was like,
what is the,
for a type of shoulder injury that I
had,
what is the rehabilitation time?
Um,
you know,
for sure probably three months.
I mean,
it,
it can be longer than that.
It depends on the patient.
Um,
somebody like you that in one of the
things that we,
uh,
have trouble with,
with some patients,
they've never even lifted weights for
example.
Oh yeah.
So for them,
the Rehab,
recovery and rehab,
we're introducing things to them that
they've never seen or done.
Right.
And they don't understand the
difference,
you know,
being sore and in pain.
That's,
that they should be conscious about.
Um,
it's challenging,
it's hard work and it's uncomfortable.
And so some patients,
you know,
they struggle to get through that part
of it,
um,
in a naturally will take longer to
improve.
So it's harder for them to get their
motion.
It's longer,
much longer for them to return their
strength.
Now you already have like a significant
baseline level of strength,
so much easier in your case to bounce
back.
And then also the things that you would
do in rehab there are so rudimentary,
you know,
you would move through that very
quickly.
And then,
uh,
once you're at the point where you have
had enough tissue healing and it's safe
to progress,
you,
um,
you know,
through higher level exercises,
then you could really push it and you
would,
I mean,
you would be committed to it.
Dedicated,
diligent.
I mean we'd almost have to hold you
back.
Yeah,
that was another
question that I had.
How often do you have people where that
is the,
the issue?
Like I know you,
you've treated a bunch of fighters and
when you treat mma fighters,
is that an issue where you're trying to
like slow them down?
Go
all the time.
You got to let people know,
like,
and one of my,
uh,
you know,
one of the lines that I'd say to all my
patients,
um,
regularly is you got to respect biology.
Like you have to allow the healing to
happen.
I know you feel good.
I know you're moving good and you're
ready to go.
You want to be back on the court,
on the field,
things like that.
But if we don't take the proper
progression,
you know,
we risk having you reinjure and then
you're right back in that same boat.
We don't,
we only want to have you miss the most
limited block of time that you can.
So I never want to,
I don't want people to miss one more
practice game,
you know,
match workout or whatever.
Then they have to,
uh,
but same time we don't want to put them
in a situation that's unsafe.
So it's always a,
it's a balancing act.
So in your time of doing this,
have you had people that didn't respond
to this particular topic?
Definitely,
yeah.
Definitely.
Yeah.
And were they the people that we talked
about before that don't exercise and
Arnie each shape or is it across the
board?
You know,
I would have to go back and look and,
and kind of critically evaluate each
case.
Um,
certainly,
you know,
we worry about the patient that has
lower like baseline fitness,
like their overall health is poorer,
you know,
and what their response might be.
But I think that's information that is
still to come.
But definitely,
I mean,
some of the people that have responded
the most dramatically,
like for example,
you and John Dudley,
I mean,
you guys are fanatical about your
nutrition.
You're working out regularly,
you're doing all kinds of things to
optimize your chance to not,
you know,
in this case he'll,
but in other instances perform.
Uh,
and I have to believe that that has,
you know,
that's a huge factor.
Yeah.
I would wonder what,
how much of a factor it is if your body
is conditioned in a way to constantly
generate muscle tissue
and breaking down and rebuilding and she
was always constantly under stress.
Definitely has to be a part of it.
Mm.
You know,
I think it's,
um,
it's not the typical realm of my
specialty to be looking at all those
other factors.
But I think with all of the information
that's becoming available,
one of the cool things for me has been,
it's forcing me to have to learn about
it.
It's forcing me to have to take look at
it,
you know,
how can we do better?
What are we ignoring?
And I think if you're not looking at
every aspect of that wheel,
then you're missing a chance to do as
good as you can for,
for each patient.
Um,
and it might be things that we have to
do before somebody even has treatment.
We may have to bring them up to some
baseline level with a number of
different things,
you know.
Um,
and so,
and the other side of it too is we're,
we're in a,
we're in a system now where there's so
much information,
you know,
one person can't be your source for
everything,
so you really have to have a good team
all around you.
Um,
I think that's really important.
I find myself more and more seeking
help,
help and just saying,
hey,
I just don't,
I don't know enough about this.
Like,
can you,
can you help me with this?
Or explain it better or you know,
can I have the patient talk with you
and,
and maybe get some more information.
And I think that may give them even
better a chance to do well just because
the options and the possibilities are so
comprehensive and time.
So,
you know,
in,
in a typical orthopedic practice,
you don't have a ton of time to go
through all of this with every patient.
Um,
and so you just have to make sure that
you're providing resources and,
and getting them as good information is
available.
One of the things I thought was
interesting,
you were telling me that there's been
really good results with people going
into a sauna directly after treatment.
Well,
I don't know that there's been good
results.
I think it's,
it's interesting.
And the things that you've talked about
for other applications in terms of heat
shock proteins,
you know,
there's some belief that that may either
assist the cells and pro proliferation
or their ability to,
you know,
have as robust a,
um,
a response as possible.
You know,
that's not proven.
That's,
that's hypothesis.
But I think it's interesting and again,
it's,
it's falls into the category of a lot of
these things that we're talking about
where the science,
the basic science is,
they're like,
we understand how it happens in the
embryo,
in the developing child.
We know what it does in a lab.
Like we can add these things to a petri
dish and watch it,
watch these changes happen.
But nobody has demonstrated this in a
human,
in a clinical trial where we're treating
an injury.
So we have to be very careful about
that.
And that in fact that the FDA is very
clear that,
you know,
we cannot be making those claims.
Companies can't be making those claims
about their products and physicians
cannot be making claims and marketing
their practice to drive people to them
stating that these things were.
Now
when you talk about heat shock proteins,
um,
I dunno if you can answer this question,
but is there a difference between the
heat shock proteins that you receive
from,
say like a steam shower,
like a steam room versus a sauna versus
even a hot bath?
I've heard of people saying that you'd
get heat shock proteins from a very hot
bath and I think you would have to,
there would have to be some kind of
biopsy or blood test and you know,
sample like have people go through each
of those things and control for all
those factors.
Right.
But the whole idea is just being
involved in an environment that's
extremely hot,
where your body is like,
what is this guy doing?
And then it produces the heat shock
proteins to try to compensate.
Yeah.
As a protective mechanism.
So that the,
just the,
the knowledge of this,
I mean this is really interesting
because people have been using saunas
forever and it was all sort of
anecdotal,
oh to sauna makes me feel great.
And I would look at them like,
well what are these assholes doing?
They're going to go in there and sweat.
I always thought it was people that were
just like lazy and they didn't want to
lose weight.
And so they went to the sauna and they
thought they lost weight.
Yeah.
I really did think they're just dropping
water.
But I'm talking to Doctor Rhonda Patrick
and she was explaining the um,
the benefits of a sauna where there was
one study where mortality decreased 40%
from all causes.
Turning the guy literally using the
sauna.
Yeah.
All cause mortality was less.
40%.
Here it is right now using the sauna
four to seven times per week associated
with a 40% lower all cause mortality.
Might be heat shock,
protein science,
daily.com.
Fascinating stuff.
Um,
yeah,
I can click on it.
Click on it.
Young Jamie,
here we go.
So get a little larger than the Journal
of American Medical Association.
So serious stuff,
right?
I mean that it's a peer reviewed
journal.
Yeah.
I assume that there may be some validity
of the information.
Amazing.
Um,
yeah,
I mean if that's correct,
if the,
if,
if all I have to do is get in a sauna
and I,
you know,
can decrease my chance of death from all
you had all diseases by 40% like cancer,
heart attack,
leukemia.
Amazing.
Here's what a suitable replacement,
hot bath won't be as robust but can
increase blood flow of eight Harvard and
cleat increase heat shock proteins.
So she saying it just won't be as
robust.
Say she's never taken one of my baths.
So it's,
you know,
a simple thing to find out or like what
you could do yourself is check your
heart rate,
blood pressure,
temperature,
you know,
just like,
just take those as like a baseline right
on after each of those sessions and see
if there's difference.
How much is your body temperature
elevate during those things and how much
of it is a surface here is can you can,
you can't elevate your core temperature
too much or you're going to have,
that's what I'm saying,
enzymatic breakdown.
Like these bad things are gonna happen.
Yeah.
I wonder like what the line is the point
of diminishing returns where the sauna
becomes detrimental versus beneficial.
Yeah.
And I wonder like how a cryotherapy
comes into play with that as well
because cold shock proteins also show
some great benefit in reducing
inflammation and yeah.
So it was just an amazing time for all
the different,
definitely the options that are
available to people.
I think at the same time,
uh,
one of the things that we have to be
conscious of is,
you know,
being responsible about how we use this
information and what we're telling
patients.
And you know,
I think there's a lot of misinformation
and a lot of people taking advantage of
that.
And so,
um,
you know,
when we want to try to avoid that,
I want to try to give people good
information so that they can ask the
right questions and they can evaluate
places where they're going to see if
they're comfortable with what they're
being told and what's being offered.
So I think there's something like 200
plus regenerative medicine clinics that
have popped up in the last couple of
years.
Hmm.
And that means at least 40 of them are
bullshit.
My math,
I mean,
maybe,
maybe 80,
maybe more than that.
And they always 90.
Well,
I just think people have to be cautious
and careful about,
you know,
what,
what am I eating,
what they're saying.
And some of these places have received
direct letters from the FDA saying,
hey,
you can't say that he can't be making
claims,
um,
go over some stuff that's definitely
beneficial.
Like platelet rich plasma,
PRP injections.
People have had real benefit from that.
Right?
Sure.
So,
um,
that has some validated outcome studies.
Um,
there is a comparison study with prp,
uh,
on tennis elbow or lateral epicondylitis
comparing that to corticosteroid
injections,
which is a common treatment for attempt
to give pain relief.
Um,
in the particular study that I'm
thinking of,
they had 73% of the patients that
receive prp had relief of their pain
compared to about 50% of patients with a
steroid injection.
So that's a head to head study comparing
treatment and you know,
the advantage seem to be to prp.
Now.
What is the difference between the
results?
I don't know if you've even know that
it's between the results of PRP and
Regena keen.
I don't know much about that product
actually.
I mean,
I know what it is.
I know that it was,
you know,
going on in Germany.
I know a lot of people traveled.
Tate ranting,
Koby Bryant,
all those guys flew Alex Rodriguez or
thing Dana White did to the president of
the UFC.
He went in there for tonight,
us,
you know,
and uh,
found through intramuscular injections.
There's a deep relief of tinnitus.
Mm hmm.
You know,
so that,
I mean,
that's great.
And again,
there may be great applications for all
of the different things that fall into
this category of biologic treatment.
Time is going to tell us what things pan
out clinically to be best.
I mean,
you can look at all kinds of factors and
we can draw conclusions from that.
But ultimately,
you know,
the proof is going to be when we have,
robust clinical studies that compare
treatment.
Um,
and you know,
we have follow up physical exams and we
have follow up imaging to see exactly
what's happening.
So we know what we are hoping for.
We know what we want to see.
We want to see that.
Yeah.
We have this cell that has a potential
to differentiate into other tissue and
actually causes healing.
Um,
but nobody has demonstrated that yet.
There are some studies,
I mean there's,
there's 35 studies,
a 29 or animal,
there's six,
six or seven that are a human trial.
I,
I just saw this a review paper and I
don't,
I didn't know if the review paper had
been written before.
One of the more recent,
um,
clinical trials was published.
Um,
there's,
so the one was on a knee arthritis and
the others were on mostly foot and ankle
stuff.
Um,
the most recent,
uh,
as from USC and a in combination with,
a doctor that's in Indiana and they
looked at patients that had a knee
arthroscopy and they resected part of
the meniscus.
So we call it a meniscectomy.
And part of it was essentially cut out.
So there was a tear.
They cut out the bad tissue,
they left the remaining healthy tissue
and they did an Mri and they measured on
the Mri,
the volume of meniscal tissue and they
injected the patient with a bone marrow
aspirate.
So in this case was the,
you know,
be Mac or bone marrow aspirate,
um,
which is stem cells extracted from bone
marrow.
Like the way Daniel Cormier they had
done.
Correct.
Okay.
So they injected that into the knee and
then I think,
I want to say it was four or eight
months later,
I think it was eight months,
they re imaged the knee and they found
that there was a 15% increase in the
municipal volume.
So the patients had apparently grown
meniscal tissue.
I had a meniscus scope on my left knee,
um,
from,
uh,
an acl injury that I had,
I had an acl surgery,
but there was still some meniscus
damage.
And then,
uh,
they,
um,
at the time of the acl injury they tried
to stitch up the meniscus and okay.
They just tried to,
tried to repair it,
cut it out.
And it was a problem for me for several
years.
And then finally a tour became a bucket
handle tear where it locks,
you know,
so it locked my knee.
I was brutally painful in the middle of
the Jujutsu class.
It was really bad.
So,
uh,
I had to get it scoped and then once I
got at scoped,
it was oak.
It was functional but it would provide
me with maybe every couple of weeks.
It would be painful.
There would be something going on
[inaudible] it would be a problem.
You shot some stem cells in there a year
ago.
I've zero problems with it since zero.
Nothing.
It's like,
like I don't even acknowledge that I
have a knee that's weaker than the other
knee anymore.
It doesn't even feel like that anymore.
My left knee feels exactly like my right
knee now.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
I mean for a decade plus I had pain in
that knee,
one,
one injection a year later,
nothing and it was almost within two
months.
Within two months after the injection.
I felt like a significant difference.
I was like waiting for those days
because those days when I pushed it
hard,
particularly after kickboxing.
Okay.
There's something about those like hard
pad work,
like kicking the pads on the MTA.
Any particular things that you were
doing that made it feel the worst?
That was the big one is just such a
striking cause.
Striking is just jarring and there's
just so much,
and I just think there's just,
there was laxity in the knee.
Said a word to sound wrong.
No,
I know it's word.
I say that it sounds,
it sounds wrong.
Laxity sounds wrong.
It sounds like a laxative,
but sounds like I'm making up a word.
You know,
I was laxity from my laxative.
Um,
but that kicking motion would always,
you know,
and it would just hurt and I would put
ice on it.
You know,
it'd be just go about my day.
I'm like,
wow,
it's fine.
It's not swelling up to now.
It's something you don't think about.
Dude,
it's zero.
I ran a trail yesterday and the
mountains like brutal steep trail for
two miles.
I have zero pain in it today.
So this is
it kind of thing that I think gets a lot
of us excited about what the potential
is.
You know,
you know,
you've got a patient here that you had
him meniscal tear then you,
so you had attempted to repair.
We know that about 15 to 22% of those
fail the meniscal repairs.
You know,
it's a disappointing number.
we like things to be much higher than
that.
But that's what the,
the facts are.
That's what the,
you know,
larger scale studies have told us.
And to anybody that has a meniscal
injury,
that's a risk worth taking because if
you know what it feels like to have a
bucket handle tear and someone says,
Hey,
you have an 80% chance of success,
you're like,
I'm in man.
Yeah,
take it.
We'll also for the,
this is what we know,
this is why we will take the risk.
So for a young person that has the tear,
you know,
we want to preserve that meniscal tissue
and for as long as their life as we can.
So certainly you are willing to risk and
even you sometimes might attempt to
repair something that you think even has
a lower chance just because they're
young and you want to preserve that.
Why you want to preserve it as we know
that if you even resect a small amount
of the meniscal tissue,
like Sapta 25%,
um,
it will change the contact pressure in
the knee.
So they do these,
you know,
color pressure studies where it,
it shows you the amount of,
of force and its distribution.
And with a normal meniscus,
it's evenly distributed into the,
you know,
on the medial femoral condyles the end
of the femur and the tibial plateau is
the top part of the Shin Bone.
So when those come together with a
normal meniscus in there,
the pressure's,
even if you resect part of that,
now you see this point loading.
So you see these hot spots where it's,
there's a much greater amount of pr of
pressure.
Sort of like when you go to a restaurant
and you're sitting at a table and it's
wobbly and you have to stick a napkin
under one of the legs.
What about analogy?
Maybe?
Probably bad analogy.
Not following you,
but you don't,
I'm talking about,
I've done that.
Eating is dump then.
Yeah.
And then the guy comes on,
you kind of test the one leg a little
higher.
Yeah.
A piece of a wedge under there.
And I know what you're saying.
Yeah.
I don't know that it's not the best,
if that makes sense for you.
It doesn't,
that's fine.
I tried,
I swung and I missed.
Let's continue.
That's all right.
But the point of this story is that we
know if we cut part of that out,
your cartilage is going to have some
wear and tear over time.
Now,
whether or not you develop symptoms from
that is hard to,
it's hard to predict.
Well,
I'm pretty sure that that's what was
going on with my knee because it,
because it was uneven and the jarring
action of kicking a heavy bag or kicking
pads.
So I think that what I was trying to get
to,
and I was taking the long path to get
there was that,
you know,
in the past what we might've said is,
Eh,
you know,
you had an acl tear,
he had meniscus tear,
you know,
your niece crappy,
sorry.
Like you're going to have some pain,
but in what are you trying to,
what do you kickbox and for eight year
age anyway,
I've heard that this is,
this would be the attitude,
right?
Um,
and really what that means is I'm
uncomfortable because I don't have an
easy solution for you.
So I'm going to blame you for,
there's also people wanting you to adopt
their lifestyle or them to think that
your lifestyle is foolhardy.
There's definitely that.
I just trying to find an easy solution
so that you don't come back into the
office and complain about something that
we don't have an easy solution for.
Also,
I think they're trying to talk sense
into you.
That might be true to their mind.
You know,
like if you don't do martial arts and
you see some knuckleheads out there,
risk of having to come to my office,
that's true.
It's also you see someone who's doing
this and hurting themselves and you tell
them,
hey look,
you've got to stop doing that.
You know,
cause you think you're doing the right
thing by telling them that.
Right.
But you know,
you're,
you're essentially telling someone that
all that stuff that makes you feel
amazing,
alleviates stress,
builds confidence.
It makes you,
it's part of your soul.
Yeah.
It's a big part.
So how am I supposed to rip that away
from me?
For some people it becomes a real,
I mean,
obviously with certain injuries.
Yeah.
But,
um,
some people we have to have the hard
discussion.
It's like,
yeah,
I know you want to keep doing this.
I know you think you're heading that
direction,
but this is over.
Well when they do replacements now
because uh,
I know a guy who's got a knee
replacement and one of the things he was
saying actually I know quite a few
people,
one of them was on the podcast,
his name is Dan Pena and he was saying
that,
uh,
the problem is with his knees is they
only been this way.
Now they don't move side to side.
There's no lateral movement and the
knee,
like there's no wiggle room.
He can't go side to side.
Like the knee is just goes straight up
and back like this artificial ne.
Does that make sense?
No,
you're,
you got skeptical hippo face.
It depends on a lot of factors.
Um,
maybe for him,
um,
there may be other patients that don't
have quite as much stiffness in their
knee,
but no one who gets a hip replacement is
doing triathlons.
They shouldn't be,
or a knee replacement rather,
they shouldn't be.
Yeah.
So it's limited with 100% certainty that
implant will loosen and fall apart.
Huh?
Why can't they make a knee of fake knee
that's as good as a real knee?
Hmm.
That's a long question.
Are they lazy?
I wouldn't think so.
Certainly.
Uh,
certainly lots of motivation and uh,
you know,
an now,
oh my God,
if they could fix a Ni and turn a knee
into a superior need to the need that
you have now.
So the,
I mean,
it's like an overall question,
right?
Why can you not a replace something
better than you can repair it will
wouldn't,
wouldn't we want to be going more
towards repair and renewal regeneration.
We're hoping that we can figure
something out for that.
But that's what factors did.
The knee replacement,
you have a metal component that you're
either,
you know,
cementing to the bone or you're,
applying it to the bone and having bony
in growth into the implant.
So there,
there's an interface between that
implant and the body and to come up with
something that would never allow that to
separate.
I mean that's,
you know,
how would you do that?
Yeah,
I know a guy who had bone cancer.
It's a really kind of a terrible story,
but he lived near a golf course and the
golf course used these horrible
pesticides and it leaked into the ground
water and all the people in his
neighborhood got cancer,
like a huge epidemic of cancer in his
neighborhood and he got bone cancer and
they replaced one of his femurs with a
metal rod and uh,
it causes him significant discomfort in
some of those,
in my training.
It's pretty gnarly.
Swore.
What's that about?
Talk to me.
Total femur.
Yeah.
It cut someone open like a fish and
stick a new leg in there.
Uh,
you literally do,
it's an incision about bat long.
Whoa.
He's making his arms about what the
spreads your arm about four feet.
Three feet.
It's the entire length of however long
your thighs she wow.
Wow.
Yeah.
Okay.
Snarly yeah,
they all get infected.
They do.
It seems like it.
Wow.
Now Post op like right away or you mean
in time time and just because your body
is rejecting it,
it doesn't know what to do with action.
It's just you got this big hunk of metal
and the up,
um,
bacteria forms,
you know,
this sort of slime layer that can't be,
um,
even with antibiotics,
you know,
blood can't get to the metal.
So you formed this layer and then it's
just once it's contaminated,
you can't control it.
Whoa.
So the metal on the leg,
the fake leg just get slimy.
Uh,
not so much that it gets slimy.
It's just the,
the stuff that's produced by the
bacteria adheres to the metal.
Oh.
So,
and it's just so much metal in the body.
There's so much opportunity.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
So what do you do when it gets infected?
You gotta open them up again,
clean it up.
You do.
You try by the end of the line is a
invitation.
The limb has to go,
Whoa,
Daddy.
Jamie is Jamie almost threw up.
Got An image.
Pull it up.
Hold it up.
You don't come.
You're a doctor.
How dare you.
How dare you say,
don't pull it up.
You're,
this is what you do,
man.
That's what I'm feeling bad.
And it's was right.
I don't know where you're going to get
the total femur.
What?
Yeah.
That's go large with that sir.
I want to see that.
I don't even,
holy Jesus.
Whoa my God.
First of all,
what am I looking at there?
So that's the f the Femur,
that's a metal femur.
And the
just google replaced Femur and look at
the flags opened up there and you have
to make measurements.
And so it's basically a,
a total knee and a total hip.
And then all of the bone in between has
been replaced with that metal.
And then your foot's just attached to
your regular Shin below it.
Correct.
And what does this normally used for?
Like how often?
What does this,
uh,
so that would be in the case of a
infection and you know,
there's the cases that we had were
usually multiple fractures below a hip
replacement and then,
and then below a longer stem hip
replacements.
Finally,
you've got just no bone.
Uh,
the other reason would be infected bone
that you had to resect and then still
another reason would be in the case of
tumor where you have to,
you're doing limb salvage.
Yeah.
That was this gentleman's now that one
above Jamie where it's got like they're
spreading it apart afar.
Yeah.
Are there,
what's going on there and what's all
that stuff on the outside,
that orange stuff.
Oh,
so,
uh,
that's called io band and it's a thin
film that we cover over where we're
making an incision in surgery is to help
prevent infection.
So we naturally have,
you know,
staff and other bacteria on the surface
of the skin and you put this sticker
cover on top of the skin and then
anything that's around the wound is,
is contained.
It says play video.
I think you should listen to him.
Click on that.
Let's see what that is.
Yeah,
let's see who this is.
Oh,
it's just a picture of that that says
that I could visit page,
click play video and here we go.
Ooh,
I'm scared.
I get nervous.
Oh Daddy.
Whoa boy.
Ooh.
Now that seems valley view surgery
through incisions,
like better about this big,
yeah,
a little tiny incisions.
Now that seems odd because that seems
like a very old person.
Like I'm looking at the lack of muscle
tissue,
either very old or very unathletic.
Uh,
yeah.
And um,
this is like good evaluation.
That's incredibly traumatic then.
I mean,
that's
how does someone recover from that?
It's slow
now.
Is there a potential use of stem cells
in the case of like,
is it,
is it possible to regenerate a bone?
I know they've built a woman,
a artificial bladder through
sympathetically bone is one of the
tissues that is a part of that line of
the Mesenchymal stem cells.
Right.
That's what I'm saying is from the Misa
Durham.
So you think that could be something
down the line that they could be able to
accomplish there?
I mean,
replacing that femur and it's cartilage
covering at the knee and the hip.
I mean,
I think that's at this point,
um,
uh,
fantasy.
Yeah,
but isn't that one,
but I said when,
when if someone came up to the person
that had the telegraph and said,
Hey,
do you think one day I'll be able to
send Dick Pics from this thing?
They're like,
well right now that's the fantasy,
right?
Don't you think?
Probably most likely,
you know they would look at you like
you're crazy person.
Well when I was a,
this is an embarrassing story to admit,
but when I was about 13 I went next door
to my neighbor's house and he was kind
of a computer nerd at the time.
But you know computer nerds at the time
or playing with like commodore 64 right?
And he's like,
dude look at this.
I can hook my computer up to the phone
and I can type on the screen in my
friend down the street.
We'll see what I wrote.
And I was like,
that's the dumbest thing I've ever
heard.
Dude,
can we like go play football?
He talking about,
so apparently not very forward thinking
guy.
Cause obviously we're doing that quite a
bit now.
I had a showtime special in 2005 and
Netflix special actually that eventually
wound up on showtime.
But I had a joke in there about cell
phones,
um,
about people sending you a text message
and the part of the joke was like,
it takes you four presses to get an S.
Right?
Like why don't you just call me?
Because like it was before anybody had
figured out.
Right.
We'll keyboard and I'm like,
why are you making me read like this is
so stupid.
I thought it was just like a dumb trend
that was going to go away.
And now if someone calls me I will fuck
you.
Call me for,
yeah.
It's very strange what's happened in
just 12 years.
Yeah.
It's a chill little shift in how we
communicate with people.
Right.
A massive one.
I mean how uh,
how disruptive to your life is it to
have to like send emails now?
I mean to sit down and like type and eat
like email,
respond back.
Some emails you like,
people email me with like a bunch of
questions.
It's a big chore.
It's like homework,
I got to sit down and it takes a lot of
time.
Whereas,
you know,
a text is like a quick response like,
hey,
why don't I just,
I'm so used email,
I send
a lot of emails.
I have so much email.
I mean,
well I do all the booking for this show
too.
I mean,
while I have a guy,
Matt stags who contacts people,
but I reached out to a lot of people as
well.
So like a lot of the booking and the
different things that I do,
I contact people and you know,
the best way to do it is through an
email.
It's like,
Hey,
you know,
I would really love to talk to you about
this or that.
I have a question about that brief
emails.
I would bet sometimes,
yeah,
but I've gone,
I've,
I've had some,
yeah,
that's the problem is the volume,
the sheer volume I get is just
unmanageable to the point where people
think I'm ignoring them.
I'm like,
man,
I'm not ignoring you.
I didn't even see it.
It just got lost in the tsunami of
emails that came in.
Like,
if I go on vacation,
I hardly communicate.
I barely do anything.
Maybe I'll put up a social media post
and you know,
just just to like,
cause it's kind of a part of the job.
Right.
But I don't pay attention to the emails.
I just leave him alone and then I get
home and I'll go,
oh my God,
there's 2000 emails.
I'll have 2000 emails in a few days.
I don't know.
I'm not exaggerating.
Do you go through all this?
I do my best.
Try to.
I look for my friends.
Yeah.
You know,
I look for people that are important and
uh,
look for,
acquaintances that I like and you know,
work related stuff.
Yeah.
But it's a mess.
I have several email accounts to which
helps,
like people that are important to me get
the big one.
You know,
you don't get,
you don't get the patent on it.
Don't worry about it.
I like you.
I don't think,
I don't want to,
don't.
If you do,
I'll give you the real one.
I just want to let you know,
you won't tell anybody.
People don't like to be on the outside.
You tell him about that and they're
like,
which one way up,
bro?
Yeah.
Alright.
Why worry about it man?
What list of mine?
Why worry about it,
man?
Yeah.
But if you have to ask the question,
yeah,
it's not good.
I wonder when it's going to pass what
we're doing.
I mean,
when it's not going to be this,
it's not going to be typing like what's
the next thing is,
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's definitely not going to be videos
where you force people to watch.
The beautiful thing about an emails,
I can kind of scan it through.
What's this guy saying not interested.
Next,
have you messed around with a like
dragon dictation?
Yes.
It's amazing for notes when you're in a
car or when I'm,
if I have an idea in my head and there's
no way I could type it on my phone that
quickly.
Have you ever seen how good it works?
It's,
no,
it's very good.
Yeah.
No,
we'll just,
what comes back?
The most recent,
uh,
versions of it?
Yeah.
Like this right here.
Check this out,
doctor.
Rati Mcgee is an amazing human being.
He has fresh breath and his hair is
wonderful.
Oh,
look at that.
Perfect.
Yeah,
100%.
That's incredible.
That's pretty good.
I mean it is,
it really is incredible.
And you can do that in your car if you
have an idea.
So you're not some asshole is texting
because sometimes like neal,
Neal Brennan had the best analogy for
it.
You know,
Neal Brennan is standup comedian,
Co creator of the Chappelle show.
He had the best analogy.
He goes,
my notebook is essentially like a net
for catching ideas.
Yeah.
And you've got to catch those ideas as
quick as you can.
I'm sure that's a good way of looking at
it.
So like if you're,
if I'm in a car and I have an idea,
I'm like,
oh my God,
I got to get this out before I forget.
So I start repeating it to myself.
And then if I'm at a red light or
something on press that record button,
very responsible of you.
Um,
I'm very responsible when it comes to
texting and driving.
That's good.
Um,
I just,
I think that is one of the most
infuriating things.
That's fucking terrible.
Yeah.
It's like you're going 60 plus whatever
miles an hour.
The amount of distance that you cover in
a glance where you are not looking at
the road and things can happen at any
moment.
Just to me it's super disturbing.
Yeah.
Anyway,
back to the back to the grind.
Um,
what did,
what do you got there that you would
like to?
Sure.
Well,
um,
so you know,
okay,
so we touched a little bit about,
about,
you know,
all of the,
all of the elements of the care of the
person,
right?
So it's,
it has to be more than just giving you a
shot and send you on your way,
right?
If you truly have an injury and we're
trying to recover you,
then what also comes along with that is
the appropriate rehab protocol.
And none of those are defined yet for,
for what some of these things that we've
done.
Um,
but we're trying to develop that and
dial it in and hone it down.
For me,
for me right now,
the easiest thing is to try to adapt it
from a surgical rehab.
Um,
and I'm not a physical therapist
obviously,
so I tried to collaborate with those
guys and girls that are smarter than me
in that,
uh,
avenue.
But the principles are the same,
right?
So you have,
you have an injury that you're trying to
heal.
Now,
in some cases it's,
you know,
we've created the injury or we've done
the thing that the patient has to
recover from.
In the case of an injection,
you have an injury.
If you've done the injection and now we
need the effect to happen,
whatever it is that we're hoping that
we'll be.
So,
but then you can't ignore the fact that
if somebody has a bad shoulder,
we'll,
maybe we may decrease the pain,
but if they,
if they're,
if their motion is poor,
if their strength is poor,
if it's not functioning correctly,
then how can we be achieving the best
result if we're not also attending to
that?
Right?
So it's a multi step,
no doubt.
And then in the more that we're learning
about all these other factors,
I mean,
like again for you,
you're paying attention to your sleep,
you're paying attention to your
nutrition,
you're on,
uh,
you know,
a variety of supplements that are meant
to help a lot of these processes.
And I think we're going to get better
and better at it.
And that has got to be pretty critical
as well.
Right?
It's got to be hugely important,
especially like staying away from
inflammation.
Enhancing foods are inflammatory foods.
Yeah,
no doubt.
So,
um,
yeah,
I think it's gotta be critically
important and we try to share that
information with people.
There's,
um,
for athletes,
uh,
like a website that you could pull up
and we can share as the college and
Professional Athlete,
a dietetics association,
I think it is college in professional
college and professional athlete.
I was like,
what college and professional athletes,
and I don't even know what that means.
We all have Collagen,
right?
College hand.
Yeah.
So these guys have some great
information and good infographics that,
um,
that we utilize.
You know,
since I'm not a,
that looks good.
I'm not a dietician,
so I have to rely again on people that
have good information.
I think these guys have a good,
reliable,
they're good reliable source and uh,
they've got great infographics if you go
to,
mmm.
Uh
hmm.
Educational Resources.
There you go.
Yeah.
So this will pull up some,
some different things,
balancing extra exercise,
induced inflammation.
Now here's a good question.
Um,
because uh,
it's pretty much universally agreed that
rest,
ice,
compression,
elevation,
all those different things that people
have said in the past,
there is benefit to a particular icing
things.
But yeah,
there's,
there's a lot of debate,
right?
There's some debate now.
Certainly there's like a definite,
uh,
anti ice community.
Yeah.
What is that out there?
Do you think it's legit?
Well,
there can't,
there's not a downside to it.
I mean,
to ice.
I don't think so.
I mean,
we've used it regularly and so I don't
know.
There's,
there's definitely a group that,
um,
and I don't know all of their arguments
against,
but may should take the former UFC
bantamweight champion.
She had had a podcast with this guy who
was the anti ice guy.
Yeah.
I got this whole thing.
See a flat earth guy to no,
but he doesn't believe in dinosaurs I
made is not,
no,
I made that up.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean,
so you,
I believe he's a doctor,
but he,
you know,
he might be a fucking veterinary works
on no cat infections or something.
I don't know.
But I don't think there's a downscaling
about that too.
So in my opinion,
you know,
I've definitely had athletic injuries.
Um,
I was a pitcher previously.
We routinely ice our shoulder and elbow
after pitching.
Um,
I did it as a matter of routine and may,
it felt good.
It felt better when I did it and I
didn't.
But here's the question.
It felt good at the time,
but it is that feeling good in any way.
Slowing the healing process.
Hmm.
Hard to know.
I mean,
that's where it gets weird,
right?
Yeah.
I don't know.
To be frank.
God Damn it.
I like it.
No,
you're the,
you're the fucking genius,
Dr. Guy
of you don't know we're doomed.
They get back to me.
So,
uh,
what,
I'll get you some good information.
It thank you.
Appreciate
it.
What else you got here?
Um,
so I think one of the interesting things
about this whole topic,
um,
and the possibility of healing from
utilizing this type of treatment,
um,
is how it allows you to go through the
process of healing without this fibro
vascular response.
So the typical healing cascade has an
inflammatory phase,
proliferative phase and the maturation
phase.
So in the inflammatory phase,
you have neutrophils and white blood
cells and these enzymes that are present
that are trying to start the process.
Then in the proliferative phase,
you're having what's called angiogenesis
and that means the development of new
blood vessels and vasculature to the
area.
Um,
and your body's producing fiber blasts
and you're laying down tissue in this
sort of haphazard manner.
So it's just kind of piling on in there.
Um,
and then the maturation phase is when
you have remodeling.
So those,
that scar tissue is changing over time
and,
and developing into a tissue that's more
like,
or is the native tissue.
So that occurs over a period of time.
And then a lot of times during that
process,
before you're fully matured in the
healing,
you're backed activities.
Um,
the best.
So let's just take an example.
Like when you sprain your ankle and then
you,
you know,
you start feeling better and maybe you
go back to basketball within a couple of
weeks.
At that point,
if you've actually torn one of the ankle
ligaments,
you don't have native ligament tissue.
That's the same structural properties.
It's not as strong.
I mean,
you might be developing the strength
around it,
but it's not like the native tissue.
Now the hope is that we can demonstrate
now we know that this is the science.
This is what it's supposed to do.
This is what it does in the developing
fetus.
We see it in kids.
You know how,
you know when your,
your daughter was real young,
she scratched her face,
the healing it will ring.
It was like gone like the next day.
Um,
so healing without scar is you know,
has to do with not forming this,
these fiber,
this fiber blast or fiber vascular
response and in fiber optic phase.
Now what the cool potential of this to
me is if we can skip that and we can
have more complete healing and quicker
resolution to the native tissue,
then you're going to have those,
the same properties,
you're going to be stronger,
you're going to be better,
you know,
technically and hopefully you know,
clinically this pans out that you would
be more resistant and lower risk for
repeat injury because that's really our
goal is in treating patients is get them
back to their activity and decrease the
chance that they have to miss more time.
How do you know how much to inject into,
nobody knows,
oh Jesus.
Nobody knows that.
This is one of the big questions that
that will be discovered with again,
you know,
rigorous studies where we can look at,
what should the dosing be,
what should the frequency of the
treatment be and what should these,
the protocols before and after be a,
it's not defined in anybody.
That's telling a patient that they have
exactly what it should be.
I mean,
be wary of that because that has not
been discovered yet.
So trying to,
we're trying to take,
you know,
we're taking the information from our
experience and applying it that way.
It's,
it's not the,
it's not the best way to go about this
and it,
it's one of the things that prp suffered
from is that all of the things everybody
was using it for so many different
things and,
and just kind of hoping that it was the
magic bullet that it was going to treat
all the things that we had difficulty
treating.
Um,
and even all of the studies that were
coming out,
you know,
people were using different centrifuges
and applying it for different reasons,
different protocols was just a mishmash
of information.
It wasn't valuable.
How d how does platelet rich plasma will
work?
So it has growth factors and cytokines
and the,
um,
the,
the platelets release proteins and
things and those things help mediate
that inflammatory response and help the
healing process.
I mean,
that's kind of the basics.
Do you think that they could work in a
symbiotic fashion with like this
information that adding prp to,
uh,
some cellular treatment like bone marrow
fat or the placental tissue,
uh,
and that line of treatment can help
expand the cells.
Ooh.
So that gets us to an important point,
which is,
uh,
expanding the cells has been done and is
not currently legal in the United
States.
So there was a place,
and they do it in other countries,
but here if you,
if you more than men,
this is a mouthful.
If you more than minimally manipulate
the tissue,
then that is not under the guidelines of
the FDA for use of human cellular tissue
products.
So they were taking,
for example,
bone marrow and plating it and growing
more sales,
bringing the patients back two weeks
later and injecting them with this,
you know,
super production of cells,
which probably is great,
but we don't know.
We don't know if that's safe.
And,
and that has to be,
you know,
that has to be taken through the
appropriate process.
So,
so you can't necessarily recommend
someone taking prp while they're taking
some sort of a stem cell injections.
So here's the difference of that.
A manufacturer can't say that we have a
product that is a combined prp stem cell
injection.
Right?
And it does this right.
That's illegal.
But if you're a patient we can't put on
my website,
I have the magic potion.
It's PRP and amniotic fluid and tissue.
I just inject it and it can heal
anything.
I admire how responsible you are and how
you keep cutting me off whenever I was
suggesting some ridiculous thing.
But is would there be a benefit for a
patient potential benefit who's getting
stem cell injections and also gets prp
at the same time?
Or is it just theoretical?
Its theoretical right now.
Yeah.
But potentially,
definitely.
Uh,
there's potential and it's encouraging
to,
you know,
that the possibility is there.
It appears to be safe there.
You know,
we don't have adverse reactions to it.
Um,
and so,
and the point that I wanted to make is
that a physician can prescribe something
and use it off label.
Right?
So the FDA doesn't regulate the practice
of medicine.
I can do that in my office,
but I can't make claims about it and I
can't put it on social media and on my
website and say,
if I'm going to do this and I'm going to
fix your shoulder,
like come here if you have a meniscus
tear,
cause we do this injection and it's
gonna make you better.
That's illegal.
That's,
I understand.
So,
but I,
if somebody comes to my office,
you know,
I can elect to do that because both
things are available.
Um,
they have,
we have permission,
you know,
to use them,
but we're using it off label and I
understand.
So,
um,
when you say maximize cells,
that's the term used maybe.
What does the term used about prp in,
in conjunction think that it can
increase.
The proliferation of them is income.
Stem cell.
Oh,
how much of a time period would it have
to be between the injection and the PRP?
That's undefined again.
So what would you assume?
The way that,
the way that we're doing is we would do
the injection at the same time.
Uh,
so yeah,
putting it in there together.
So you really only have a narrow window
from when we take those frozen cells and
then we thaw them,
you know,
we have a short window when we can then
inject them and then there's,
you know,
maybe between seven and 21 days that
those cells are viable in your shoulder
or your knee or wherever we inject it.
So if someone gets an injection that
does PRP,
they would have to essentially get that
done within those seven to 21 days to
have some sort of a benefit of what
you're saying theoretically radicals
that yeah,
that,
that's uh,
that's how I would do it currently.
Uh,
based on that information.
It's fascinating stuff.
Yeah.
What else you got there?
Well,
so,
um,
we just,
I thought it was important to talk about
the,
it's called section three 61 of the
Public Health Service Act.
And this is the definition from the FDA
on the use of human cell tissue and
cellular tissue products.
So it has to match these criteria.
So you have to have minimal
manipulation.
That means you can't add things to it.
You can't combine it with other stuff,
you can't.
Um,
like I was saying,
you can't,
you know,
put it in the lab and grow it and add
things to it and then come bring the
patient back and treat them how this
isn't part of the,
um,
part of it,
but we,
you can't treat patients on a,
on a different day.
It has to be at the same time whenever
you're harvesting the cells or utilizing
whatever it is you're using,
um,
it has to be something called homologous
use.
And what that means is whatever tissue
you're taking has to have the intention
of the purpose of that tissue for when
you put it into somebody's body.
So for example,
uh,
if I have,
if you have a fracture that's not
healing and I take a bone graft product,
so cadaver bone,
and we're going to use that to help heal
your fracture,
that hasn't healed.
That is,
that's homologous use we have,
we're taking bone,
we're using it to become bone or to be
the scaffold for bone to heal and grow.
So,
um,
it can't be combined with something else
and it can't have,
it can't be intended to have a systemic
effect.
So now all of these things that I'm
explaining,
these are rules for manufacturers and
what they can,
what the rules are for them to be able
to market their product.
So for example,
you can't take amniotic fluid and say
this is a product meant for IV infusion
for treatment of whatever diabetes.
Right?
And that is something that people do in
other countries,
right?
They're doing in other countries,
you can do that in,
you technically can't do that.
You can't manufacture a product and put
that on the labeling that that's what
it's intended for.
But do they do that in America?
I,
ve stem cells,
I've been told by patients that they've
gone to places that have suggested to
them that that was going to be the
treatment.
Right.
And what is,
what is going on there?
I'm not aware of it.
What,
how does that even work?
Do you know?
It's not your wheelhouse.
No,
but,
and nobody knows if it does.
So it was just experimental.
It is.
I mean all of this,
you know,
boss ruin is former UFC champion.
Do you ever treat him?
I have no law to say that.
Um,
uh,
something I can say talk about any
patient that unless they tell me,
okay,
set it or they're sitting in front of me
talking about it and okay,
I'll give you permission.
It's that it's hipaa violation.
Just want a nation state for the record.
I give you permission.
Um,
bas and went to,
where did he said he'd go to Peru or
something like that.
Went to the jungle,
some dude kill the chicken and then
showed some stem cells into him,
but a blood vein.
He was saying it was fucking amazing if
you,
you know,
you were to wait boss talks.
He's like,
it's like the energy was coming out of
my body.
Like Ah,
he said that.
He literally felt like,
like
some guy of Kung Fu and we'll be where
energy was like shooting off his
fingertips.
He said it was amazing.
Like the emperor,
he's not the only guy that said that.
You know Dan Bilzerian,
do you know Dan Bilzerian is the
instagram guy with the boobs and the
butts?
Uh,
he told me the same thing.
He said that when he got it done,
he said it's amazing.
He goes to Mexico to get it done.
Not recommended,
but he can't talk about it off air.
He'll be a little chatter box.
Just you wait maybe,
well,
what I'm interested in,
in what I was thinking for you threw me
off there.
Um,
is,
is he going to with a specific intent of
treating something or is he just like
looking for the Fountain of Youth?
Um,
I think he fucks so much.
He doesn't have any sperm in his body
and he's trying to kicks,
I dunno.
Yeah,
that guy's an animal.
But uh,
I think he's got a series of injuries.
I know that because he's had regena keen
for his neck.
He put it up on a,
on instagram,
like with instagram stories.
He was videoing himself while I was
getting injections in his neck,
which I've had a Regena keen
interjections.
Yes.
It cured my cervical disc bulge.
Yeah.
That and disco decompression,
a spinal decompression,
you know with like a harness where
they're pulling on your neck that I had
a bulging disc in my neck that was
pushing on my unresolved.
Yeah,
completely resolved.
Like on an MRI.
It doesn't exist anymore where I was
getting numb hands cause the Ulnar nerve
was being pressed upon.
Yeah.
Huh.
Yeah it works.
Some massive anti inflammation
properties.
I just don't think that it has the same
healing potential.
It seems like it reduces inflammation in
a giant way.
What's going on with,
um,
by the way,
I had regena keen shot in my knee too.
It didn't really show me.
So they didn't really have the same
effect.
This is a little bit,
so patients like yourself that have had
a number of injuries and a number of
treatments.
And one of the things that's got me
enthusiastic about the potential of all
of this is when somebody tells me,
look,
I've had this,
this,
this and this.
And then I had this,
what we're talking about and that it was
just completely different game changing,
just a hundred percent captured and
different.
Look.
Mine right shoulder is not 100% but it
might be 90%.
You know,
and it's strong as fuck.
Like I could do a lot of shit with it.
Like it doesn't do some insane stuff.
Yeah.
And it's,
it doesn't bog things that I probably
wouldn't recommend,
but no pain.
Let go.
I can,
why could do,
um,
I take these 90 pound kettle bells and I
do windmills with them.
Where you,
you know,
you're pressing overhead,
you know what a windmill is dropping
down.
Like that's what your shoulders
rotating.
I don't do that with 90 pounds,
but I know what it is.
But the,
um,
the fact that I can do that with a
shoulder that was on the way probably to
getting on it was just amazing.
My bow tie,
the most impressive thing was that push
up with the wheel thing.
What's that thing called?
Oh,
the AB wheel.
Now it's like a little roller that you
had your hand.
Yeah.
Those things when you go for,
what's that called?
The comfort of all havoc creates it.
There's sliders,
havoc.
Sliders.
Okay.
Uh,
amy,
that was like,
why k sliders?
There's a video of it on seat.
There's a video on my instagram,
Jamie,
um,
from quite a while ago,
but it was posts post,
excuse me,
uh,
injection.
Um,
it's from way back.
I want to say at least a year ago I was
doing that.
But um,
yeah,
there's my range of motion's 100%.
I mean,
at the most it's uncomfortable in
certain things,
but for a big one for me was archery
because um,
you know,
I really enjoy it.
I do it all the time and it's very
meditative to me and I,
I just,
I love archery.
So for me,
like the idea of not being able to pull
my bow back,
I was,
it was really disturbing.
I was like,
Gosh,
I'm going to have to get the surgery
done.
Yeah,
you've been pretty committed to it for a
while.
Now I,
I'll shoot a hundred plus hours a day
and I'm pulling back 84 pounds to 84
pound compound bow and I'm shooting it a
hundred times a day and there's no pain.
I did it yesterday.
All I'll look for hours.
Me and my friend Cam Haynes who,
you know,
you met who came to talk to you as well.
Um,
you kind of indirectly got me,
uh,
into it.
I don't know if I went to archery
through John.
John Dudley.
Yeah.
I know you're shooting all the time now,
right?
Yeah.
So John got me this unbelievable,
you know,
horror,
Hawaii,
uh,
carbon spider bow.
It's like a,
if you want it,
if you want to see,
uh,
any of my friends,
like make the greatest faces you've ever
seen.
I just,
I pull this thing out and it's like,
you know,
some space,
age weapon,
it looks like a bow.
The Batman would have,
yeah,
yeah.
She bug out.
Yeah.
Something like that.
I would say Batman,
but yeah.
But yeah,
it's um,
those bows or they're amazing.
It's incredible.
And it's uh,
yeah,
I've only been able to go a couple of
times,
but I'm definitely hooked.
It's the most amazing meditation.
I love it.
It's cause it's you,
when you're focusing on that shot,
you literally have no room for anything
else.
It's,
it requires so much concentration.
You're concentrating on the front hand
position,
front shoulder position,
where,
where the string touches the tip of your
nose,
the corner of your mouth.
And John is just an amazing coach.
So,
you know,
totally unfair.
I get,
that's the bow.
Then the first bow that I get to shoot
with,
and then John gives me the first lesson
that I've ever pulled a back.
He's standing there right with me.
He's an Olympic coach by the way.
He used to coach to the Olympic team and
he's amazing.
Yeah.
I mean he really,
he's a great guy too.
And he can take years off of people's
learning.
I mean he's,
he's absolutely taking years off my
learning curve.
Yeah.
I'm going to sneeze.
I hate when you say you're going to
sneeze and they put a lot of pressure on
yourself and you're like,
man,
I'm,
I might not,
it might just look like a Weirdo for a
few minutes.
Did you find that video?
No,
it's in there.
I swear to God.
So here's another,
uh,
kind of crazy thing about the,
the placental derived treatments
is it they actually have a antimicrobial
properties.
Whoa.
So this is crazy.
I mean we kind of know this,
um,
you know,
one of the functions of the amniotic
membrane is to protect the,
the developing baby.
Right?
But,
um,
in,
in one of the things it does protect it
from infection,
boy,
they were able to demonstrate was that,
um,
when they,
they've actually introduced bacteria,
like literally injected bacteria onto
these membranes and then they come back
and,
and check and it,
it,
it has destroyed the bacteria so.
Huh.
So ability to,
um,
resist scar formation,
move through the,
the fibrotic phase of healing and then
also the antimicrobial profit.
So amazing.
That would be super beneficial.
Postsurgery right.
Cause that's a giant issue.
Staph infections and the like.
It's one of the things that you know,
frightens us most about,
you know,
doing our procedures is,
can we prevent infection?
Yeah.
Giant issue where people,
I mean I know because of the nature of a
martial arts,
it just,
everybody I know is that surgery.
Yeah,
that's pretty much.
And the big issue is post in post
surgery infections.
Yeah.
Oh those guys are,
they're getting abrasions and everything
like that on the mat.
And then so then they're colonized with,
you know,
Mrse out of whatever funk is in that
gym.
I tell everybody,
if you are a grappler,
this is super important.
I want you to look up defense soap.
Defense soap is a soap company that was
created by my friend Guy Sacco.
And what is it?
It is all natural soap that promotes
healthy bacteria.
It doesn't destroy the healthy bacteria.
Hmm.
But it's all tea tree oil,
eucalyptus oil.
This shit is amazing.
And I used to get,
I've gotten staff at least twice.
I used to get ringworm all the time.
Well,
not all the time,
but I got a couple of times and until I
was like super diligent about wool
washing myself,
like immediately afterwards.
But once I started using two things,
probiotics,
which is huge.
Um,
acidophilus.
Yeah.
Eating yogurt and a drinking Kombucha.
And then the next one in fact soap
probably not,
but it's a little bit of something and
it's a little bit of something.
I think it's good to have.
It's good to have.
Um,
probiotics.
I like Kimchi.
I tried to take my probiotic probiotics
and multiple forms.
Um,
this stuff that I was drinking when he
got here.
Kombucha.
I love this stuff.
I drink all the time.
Or that you like or did he met mixing
you gotta be careful because I'm a low
sugar guy,
so like the grapes,
there's some of them that are delicious,
but they have a lot of sugar.
Sure.
This,
this multigrains does not have a lot of
sugar.
I don't want to see what it's got.
I think it's something like 10 grams per
serving or something like that.
It's really,
that sounds high.
I think I've seen them lower.
Oh two.
Yeah.
Two grams.
So yeah,
that's what you want the grapes high
grape is,
but the taste wonderful and write
essays.
Yummy.
That's a problem.
This does not taste so good.
But you know you're getting something
good in it.
And this is the fight your way through
it.
The important stuff is that you get the
strong Kombucha.
This is the brand that I really liked.
I don't work for them.
They're not a sponsor.
GTS,
Kombucha,
gt gts.
Um,
this stuff is awesome but you have to be
over 21 because it has more than one
half of 1% alcohol by volume because the
fermentation process,
cause it's so strong.
I see.
So they make you get,
you show your Id.
Interesting.
They actually pulled it from whole
foods.
I don't know if you know this.
I thought,
see,
I thought I saw,
that's where I've seen it.
Yeah,
they have it back.
But they pulled it from whole foods
until whole foods had to like put some
regulations in place to keep,
you would literally,
if you were eight years old do,
you could drink one and not get drunk.
I mean,
it's not like,
it's not like you're going to get drunk
off of it,
but just due to regulations,
you have to listen to the law.
Exactly.
What else?
You got
got a lot of papers there,
buddy.
Got Drawings and shit.
Charts and graphs.
Have to think about probably a bunch of
stuff you say.
Don't let joe talk about this.
Um,
what other questions have you come up
with along the way?
Or One big question I wanted to talk to
you about was something that I had a
discussion with Dr. Davidson about
recently.
Um,
and Jeff was telling me that the most
recent procedure with stem cells is
injecting them directly into the discs
for people that have degenerative disc
disease.
And that there's some really promising
results.
I've heard anecdotally of a number of,
uh,
very positive outcomes,
with treatment like that.
Hmm.
But that's amazing.
Again,
we,
you know,
it's still too early,
so a lot is surely enough conservative
about this are really,
really,
really do appreciate that.
Although I'm giving you a hard time,
I feel you when you hustled.
I've really wrestled with it because,
uh,
you know,
again,
our whole training is based on,
you know,
we need to do things that have an
evidence base for our patients.
I mean,
this is kind of the,
the foundation of what we do.
And so,
but we're in a unique situation,
so we have patients that,
um,
one week this stuff is available and
it's legal to do and it's there and
people know about it now.
So they,
they're seeking the information,
they come to us.
And even,
you know,
even before we started talking about it,
it started to be like here and there and
then all of a sudden it's like two,
three patients a day.
Now even more are saying,
well,
what about,
what about stem cells should,
can I have stem cell?
And,
uh,
like,
okay,
well I'm going to have to back up and
like have the whole discussion.
Like,
okay,
well let's talk about what that is and
what may be it can do.
And,
um,
so people are seeking the treatment.
It's available.
Um,
but we don't know and we don't have a
lot of information.
So we just have to be forthcoming and
say,
look,
this is experimental.
We've had encouraging early results.
I can tell you anecdotal stuff.
We've even seen images where somebody
had,
you know,
full thickness rotator cuff tear eight
months later,
what looked like a healed rotator cuff
on an MRI.
Now,
did that happen on its own?
Well,
we know that that happens at a lower
percentage,
but it is possible to heal.
It's just a lower percentage.
Um,
did it happen because of the treatment,
you know,
that hasn't been established.
So I have to really explain all that.
And the other category to that,
uh,
patients will come in and they'll
explain an injury and,
and I've had to turn away a lot of
people that were,
they were fully ready to come in and
have treatment and,
and they were fine with paying out of
pocket because of course,
it's not covered by insurance because
it's experimental because there's,
you know,
no data yet.
And that's not true.
There's not no data,
but there's,
there's not enough data to support
treatment for certain,
uh,
conditions.
Um,
but you know,
I've had to tell people I don't think
this is appropriate even even to try
even if you want this.
Um,
and usually the category is,
excuse me if it's something mechanical.
So I think this makes intuitive sense to
people.
So for example,
had you come to me and you said,
hey,
uh,
you know,
I dislocated my shoulder seven times and
uh,
can you just put an injection in their
will?
The,
the problem with that is that the,
in that case,
in this example,
the ligaments of the shoulder had been
stretched and disrupted.
And in the case of a dislocation,
there's oftentimes a labral tear that
comes with that.
Now,
I don't believe in,
I could be proven wrong over time,
but I just don't believe that that an
injection on its own would magically
decreased the volume of the capsule.
You know,
tightened the static structures in the
shoulder and resolve the pain for that
patient now.
But those right there was in my head.
Sure.
I believe there was something that came
up a few years ago where they were doing
something where they're heating up the
insulation or capsule and shrink the
normal capsulorrhaphy.
What does that was very popular for you
was,
yeah,
now it's close to malpractice.
Oh,
Jesus.
Yeah.
So it's interesting though,
the way these things go.
So there was a huge wave of,
um,
interest in this.
And essentially what guys would do is
they're looking inside the shoulder.
You have a radio frequency wand and
you're using that to heat the tissue and
you can watch it literally shrink in
front of you.
And then Richard Hawkins is a very
accomplished orthopedic surgeon,
kind of iconic guy that's done tons of
research.
He was also went in Vail,
Colorado,
now in Carolina,
and he published a paper that,
that showed a very high rate of failure
from these procedures.
And so as a result of that,
um,
it's fallen out of favor.
So yeah.
But it was done very frequently on lots
and lots of shoulders,
a high rate of failure.
It was like 40%.
Okay.
But here's the question,
is that because you're,
you're talking about already compromised
joints,
right?
Which is a very complicated joint.
The shoulder is very complicated.
So there's certainly a number of reasons
why that could have failed.
But,
uh,
there was a lot of problems with,
basically damage to the tissue from the
radio frequency.
Oh,
so it was weakening things?
Yeah,
I say yeah.
So that,
that what was the benefit of it?
Well,
you could watch it and you were seeing
the decrease in the volume of the
capsule.
So you are where structures had become
loose.
You were seeing it become tight in at
the time zero period.
What about doing that in conjunction
with some sort of a stem cell therapy?
Um,
does that make sense?
Yeah.
It must be a doctor.
Right?
You're very close.
You know,
you're only a 10 years in school.
The only 14 years away.
14.
Yeah,
that's all 14 for regular people.
Give me 20.
Um,
so,
so why did they think that it would work
in the first place?
Like what,
what was the,
uh,
the idea behind there?
There's,
there's early published papers that were
saying that the outcomes were better if
you used it.
Wow.
So it's,
it's murky.
I mean there's things that over time we
discover that what we thought we were
looking at,
you know,
we didn't fully understand.
And how long did it take before it
became malpractice or that problem and
exaggerated term problematic?
Um,
I,
I don't know the exact year that his
paper was published,
but it was,
um,
it was before my residency training.
I started,
I graduated medical school in 2006 so it
was before that that people weren't
doing that anymore.
Okay.
So I'll bring it back around.
So when someone has had,
like if you talk to some due to play
football or something,
had multiple shoulder dislocations,
like what would you do to,
when you would encourage surgery?
Um,
so the,
you know,
the typical
course for recurrent instability of the
shoulder would be a stabilization
procedure.
Now a lot of that's based on the exam
and what you see on imaging.
Some people can do well with a simple
shoulder arthroscopy and then you pass a
couple stitches,
you repair the labor from,
you can tighten the capsule at the same
time.
And young patients progressed really
well through that.
Um,
when there is,
you know,
more complicated problems such as the,
there's bone loss on the front of the
socket.
So when you have a dislocation,
the head goes forward.
It,
it goes out the front.
That's the typical and anterior shoulder
dislocation is the usual one.
And then as it tries to come back into
place,
the head bangs into the glenoid or the
socket.
So you can,
you'll tear the front of the Labor.
I'm,
you'll stretch the front of the capsule,
but then you can also get a dent in the
back of the humeral head.
So the correct procedure,
um,
I,
I keep throwing you off track,
but when someone does have a shoulder
dislocation,
what are you supposed to do?
He supposed to pull on it and just take
him to the hospital.
Um,
there's probably no harm in doing that.
There's,
there's a great technique called the
Zahiri technique.
Spell it.
Z,
a,
H I,
R I and it's just the name of the guy
that wrote the paper.
Um,
but it's essentially,
it would be a really easy thing for you
learn cause it's kind of a leverage
thing.
Yeah.
So it's a way to,
um,
leverage the,
the arm so that you can get the muscles
to relax.
It's easy on the person and you can
actually do it awake and like at the
field.
So I actually did it on a,
uh,
professional steer wrestler,
um,
at the Rodeo.
How hilarious is it that you can be a
professional steer wrestler like the
Seattle Sandwich
for a few years,
but yeah,
no,
there,
there's,
they're pretty serious about stuff.
Super serious.
You were talking about you're a bucket
handle meniscus.
The first Rodeo cowboy that I took care
of had a flipped bucket handle meniscus
tear,
and he came in the,
the day that the national finals Rodeo
was starting and he was also a steer
wrestler by the way.
And had been a previous,
I think he was a champ or he,
he won a bunch,
that's for sure.
Um,
so they basically,
they taped his knee.
You got to come closer.
They taped his knee,
you know,
in about 30 degrees of flection and he
competed the whole nine days.
Whoa.
Just roped up knee.
Just taped it up,
got on his horse and was jumping off and
throwing 600 pounds steers on the
ground.
Forest.
Yeah.
Those guys are crazy.
I want to see stuff on TV.
I've never even been to one live because
I'm terrified.
You need to come to,
I don't,
we did an episode of fear factor.
We may people ride bulls made him write
it.
That's,
that's you can die.
I mean that's not,
it's dying no matter what.
You're dealing with a goddamn steer.
That's what I'm saying.
You can die.
Getting on top of the stairs is not a
yielded.
Right.
We had bowls steer wrestling is
different.
Right.
Steer wrestling is the,
they grab him.
They take off.
Yeah.
You wrote here and the guy and the horse
take off at the same time.
You jump off,
you grab it,
you grab it by the horns and turn its
neck and throw it in the ground and then
they wrapped it.
Yeah.
See with steer is a bull that doesn't
have any balls,
right?
Yeah,
that polls.
But the same animal,
they're younger than the ones that they
cop.
They chopped their balls off before they
get a chance to mature.
That's why when they,
they rules are terrifying.
So,
and write down next to the bucking chute
and it's like frightening actually had a
clot of dirt.
Get one of them kicked it up and it hit
me in the head like a baseball.
I mean,
yeah.
See they're a little babies and they
have no balls.
So this guy jumps off.
What?
Uh,
and you tell him that is so whack.
What a stupid fucking thing to be
excited about these ideas.
I'm going to ask what of that thing I
was trying to get away.
I grab him by his natural handles and
I'd tuck them down.
Look how quick,
look at their move.
It's like a darce choke and the cows
like,
what in the fuck man,
why is this even happening?
Look,
the cows like what is going on?
I got to get out here and look how they
always do it the same way too.
They do.
It's it's,
it's similar to like a a chokehold.
Yeah.
Oh,
what a dumb fucking thing to be excited
about the neck and flip them on their
backs.
Not It's outside of your world,
but I'll tell you outside of the world,
these are some of the nicest guys I've
ever met in my life,
honestly,
and there are some of the toughest
athletes.
Oh yeah.
I would imagine those guys are tough as
hell.
You have to be,
they got to do it on fearful pete
through every injury.
There is no injury that they don't,
that they won't compete.
You're always broken up.
I mean,
you have to.
We have to do it on food.
Also.
They've had nine don't make money if
they're not competing,
so right.
We have to do it on fear factor was a
steer champion or a Rodeo champion
rather.
He had nine shoulder surgeries,
his shoulder was just like sliced all
open and he,
I don't know how long off it has a
dislocated,
he goes,
get me anytime I could open up a car
door,
it will pop out of socket.
I'm like,
yikes.
Yeah,
it's bad.
Yeah.
Um,
so back around to where we're at.
What,
um,
what do you do?
How does this xy here technique?
Can you describe it?
That I say right is that hearing Tahirih
Erie techniques.
So that one of the guys that we trained
with a in are my sports medicine program
and Alabama showed us this and um,
it was like one of the first things that
we reviewed at the beginning of the
year.
And uh,
so basically you have the person lying
flat on their back and I would hold your
wrist and then I loop my arm under your
arm and then grab onto mine for
leverage.
And then I literally just sort of lean
back and I'm using the muscles in my
back so I'm not pulling with my arms.
So a small person can do this on a very
big athlete and you're fine because
you're,
you're using all of the strongest
muscles in your body,
right?
So you literally just
lean back and you hold traction in that
position.
So you've got the arm is positioned like
this.
Yeah.
You got to describe to people that are
listening.
Uh,
the arm is in front of the person,
uh,
while they're laying,
laying on their back.
And again,
I have my right hand on your right
wrist.
If it's a right shoulder dislocation,
well,
let's just see a video.
You got to,
you got a video of it.
It's really hard to find him,
but I'm going to hopefully guests that
this is maybe it,
hopefully.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let me explain to people at home what
this is like as if you were trying to
give someone an armbar.
You,
it's,
you get a hook on the left side and so
the hook is a,
your left,
if you're trying to arm bar someone on
the right,
the right arm,
and you were inside control,
you would hook it with your left arm and
then you would trap it in place.
And what a person does when they don't
want to get arm barred,
their defense is this,
they grabbed their hands together and so
you loop your arm in that and pull it
back like that.
So that'd be real similar what you're
doing,
you're using the left arm,
you're kind of connecting it like this
and then you're,
you're actually just using traction.
Yeah.
So the,
the treater in this case on the right
side,
he just going to lean back and hold and
you just wait and in about 10 seconds
pops in place,
the deltoid and the pack and the biceps
relax and it just slides in.
Oh,
that's interesting.
And you can actually do that.
And I mean the kinder way to do this as
you know,
with some anesthesia,
but a lot of times you can do that and
they're perfectly comfortable in there.
Immediately better on the shoulders back
in,
while they're not completely better,
but the pain is relieved from the
initial event.
Now you told me when you looked at my
Mri that you think that my shoulder was
dislocated at some point in time.
I don't remember it exactly your Mri,
but if you had a tear of the front of
the Labor Room,
if you had,
and you had that,
any evidence of that little dent in the
back of the humeral head and then that
would be consistent with that.
I just do not remember ever having a
dislocated shoulder,
but I've had,
I've been Kamora you've had a bunch of
times that you've had it slip maybe a
little bit.
Well,
when just the nature of your shoulder
locked,
you know,
there's been a many American as in my
past and Maura's and all these different
like hardcore,
you know,
the thing is we're on the receiving end.
Yeah,
yeah.
Before this injury,
I never,
Americana you could definitely have at
least a subluxation of the shoulder for
sure.
I'm sure.
And you fight it off too because you
don't want it to happen.
So you're resisting.
And um,
before this injury,
I didn't do any shoulder exercises.
I just worked out,
but I didn't do any specific exercises
just to strengthen my shoulders.
And I think that was a big mistake.
And I kind of emphasize that with people
like doing a external and internal
rotation,
um,
exercises doing like,
I'm a big fan now of a inverted
kettlebell presses and yeah,
that's what had been one of my,
a giant right.
My favorite lately.
It's definitely a challenge.
You don't need much weight and uh,
yeah,
this little 40 pound iron man
Kettlebell,
I use this one.
It's amazing.
That exercise.
That's pretty good.
Well,
it's just a,
they say you should be able to do 50% of
your Max weight or is that 50% or 90% I
forget what they say.
I forget me.
Don't listen to me.
Well,
it,
it depends on,
I think I said 90.
Yeah.
Obviously in the,
in the injured patient or the person
that's recovering,
we're going to be starting with much
lower,
much lower,
but focus is on your motion,
your,
your posture,
engaging your core,
keeping your ribs down in,
in having the full motion.
The strong first protocol.
I think what they're trying to say is in
order to have really powerful shoulders,
you should be able to do 90% of your Max
Kettlebell press.
Like say if you can Max Kettle press 90
pounds.
Now that's with the,
with the handle down,
build down.
Right.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
With Max,
that would be your Max.
Like what you go with one rep Max.
Yes.
Or you know what,
you would pretty much be,
you,
maybe you could do two or three if you
really had to,
but you know,
you're talking about a lot of weight.
Um,
the,
you know what you would normally like
Max out at like there's,
um,
there's a protocol that this guy,
Pavel Tatsu lean follows.
That's really kind of interesting in,
you know,
Pavel,
right?
Well,
he's the Kettle Bell Guy,
right?
He's the guy that brought him,
they call him the godfather of
kettlebells and America.
But um,
the guy that I trained with talks about
that all the time.
Yeah.
The,
the idea behind it is,
um,
don't do your,
like if you could do 10 reps,
you do five and you wait a long time and
then you do another five and you wait a
long time,
then you do another five and he never
worked a failure.
And that working to failure is actually
not healthy.
It's not smart and you don't really get
stronger that way would be my
recommendation is that for,
and,
and this is coming from not,
this isn't from the orthopedic surgery
world.
This is what I've read from strength and
conditioning people.
The thing you want to avoid in doing
something to failure is with load in a
skill activity.
So for example,
like a clean or a snatch or something.
Things that involve coordination.
Yeah.
And where you have to time it requires,
you know,
sound mechanics,
right.
And you're doing it with load.
It's bad to do that to failure because
what happens as you fatigue is your
mechanics are going to break down,
right?
That's where you're gonna get hurt.
Well,
what Pavel talks about is that strength
as a skill and that all these different
things,
think of them as a skill and then don't
do things to failure.
And if you're looking for,
you know,
endurance or something along those
lines,
you want to do light weights and you do
want to do multiple repetitions is not
what you're doing when you're trying to
get stronger.
No.
Yeah.
So it's,
there's a,
but there's,
you know,
a lot of different arguments one way or
another.
I mean,
talk to power lifters and they're like,
that guy's a pleasure.
You got to do it to failure.
Yeah.
I Dunno.
Talk to crossfit people.
They want to do 100 reps,
you know,
no.
There,
there are activities that you can train
to failure and there's no risk.
So for example,
like,
like pull ups,
I mean,
when you fail,
you just,
you just can't get up.
Right?
Right.
Like you just going to come off the bar,
right.
The battle ropes,
you just going to fatigue out like there
is,
you're not going to hurt yourself,
right.
Do they even believed that when you're
doing chin ups,
like if you're doing pull ups or Chin
ups,
um,
that when you're doing it,
you shouldn't go to failure.
You should just stop,
like close to it or halfway there and
then take a long time off and then do
another five reps.
Like say if your,
your Max is 10 reps,
get to five,
stop,
take a break,
do another five stop,
take another five,
10 minutes,
do another five,
keep going and just you're,
you're working on form and your muscles
are performing these actions in a very
clean,
smooth delivery and that this is the
best way to recover or to build strength
and that you just do it more often.
Don't do it to failure once a week and
then be a wreck for like three or four
days afterwards.
Because you know that feeling when you,
when you lift weights and you lift
weights for a week or you lift weights
and you lift weights to failure rather,
and you're sore for so long,
you can't get anything done.
This idea is you do more frequent
workouts and you don't go to failure but
don't go over five Reps.
I think one of the biggest mistakes that
we see in reasons that people show up in
my office,
it is because of overload and you know,
no time for recovery,
right.
From the training that you're doing.
So you don't see people period ising and
incorporating the times when they're
just allowing rest.
I mean,
you can't be working at Max capacity all
the time.
Right.
Exactly.
So that's a big thing with fighters.
Huge.
Yeah.
Keeping them for working hard is so hard
to do.
Yeah.
So I always,
I try to emphasize with [inaudible] and
we have to really talk about this with
our acl rehab.
Um,
because that's a group that,
you know,
they're so eager to get back,
if they're a competitive athlete that,
you know,
you got to remind them that,
look,
we have steps to go through.
And I always say,
you got to work smart.
Not Hard.
Like,
you know,
we have a plan and there's a reason why
this week may not be a whole lot of work
and your body needs rest and recovery in
order to put stress on it again so that
we can continue to make your progress.
Otherwise,
at some point you're either going to
plateau,
you're not going to be making changes,
you're gonna get frustrated or you're
just going to get hurt.
Right.
All right,
we got to bring this home.
So anything else we need to,
uh,
cover on this?
I think so.
I think we got,
we got to talk about quite a bit.
Yeah,
we really did.
Thank you very much for doing this.
I really appreciate it because this is,
we've always had these really cool
conversations when a visit you in your
office.
And I'm really glad we got a chance to
do this.
Now,
if people want to get ahold of you and
they want to seek treatment,
please give them a necessary
information.
Oh,
sure.
So our website is
www.totalsportsmedicine.com.
I like how people still say www,
like,
yeah.
Like I still get there,
right?
Yeah,
you can just total sports medicine.com.
Yeah.
Um,
and then,
uh,
we have information on there in terms of
how to contact us and,
uh,
you know,
we'd be happy to get additional
information to patients if they have
questions.
Awesome.
Well,
again,
thanks for everything you've done for
me.
It's been a lifesaver and,
uh,
I've been at umass benefit.
Allow me to come down.
My pleasure,
brother.
Thank you doctor Rati Mcgee,
ladies,
gentlemen,
and that's it for this week.
We'll see you next week.
Bye Bye.
Mm.