Guys need to cut it out.
Try Casting.
Did you ever organize parents podcast
brought to you by the flashlight?
What is the fleshlight?
Fleshlight is a vagina made out of rubber.
That's an a thing that looks
like a flashlight and John half.
Ron The brilliant
comedian John had fallen,
had a very funny point and he said
they really should make a fleshlight.
That's a flashlight because you
never know what your flashlight is,
but you always know where your
fleshlight is. You laughed.
You can't help but laugh
because it's funny. Hi.
If you go to Joe rogan.net and click on
the link to the flashlight and enter in
the code named Rogan, you will get 15%
off the number one sex toy for men.
Shazamm bitches,
Duncan trussell's in the house.
We ready to get off free con.
Hi.
Hi
Dunkin. Hi. We got everything going on
here folks. We took Alpha brain pills,
Alpha brain by on it,
o n n I t.com.
We've been selling these here on the
podcast telling people about them.
They sold out completely quickly and
you know, there's always going to be,
some people don't, don't like
certain things, but the response,
a positive response from these things,
it's been fucking tremendous. And a,
even Tim Ferriss loved it and he thought
the, you know, he read the ingredients,
he said they were great, said
it's a perfect combination. It's,
which is really nice to hear because
he was fucking brilliant man.
What an interesting guy. But reading
his book, the four hour work,
while the four hour body is
the one I've been reading,
it's so fucking informative.
There's so much in there man,
about so many different things and his
own personal detailed examinations and
experience. He's done with his
own body, like gaining 30 pounds,
like getting over a course of like six
weeks and did all this bodybuilding stuff
and all these different things where
he combined foods and nutrients in
different times of the day and he detailed
everything and it's fucking really
interesting. And one of the
things that he detailed his,
that his balls were getting cooked by
his cell phone and it was killing his
sperm count. Like he's totally healthy.
It just gained all this muscle, right?
He's lifting weights, doing all
this kettle bells and shit figures.
He's healthy as a horse. Good gets his.
Is is berm checked just for whatever.
I mean I'm, no, it's gonna to
come back. Awesome. You know,
it's was one of those things,
my loads are going to be awesome.
I'm going to be glowing.
Well he goes and he's,
his sperm is like down significantly,
so the only thing he does to
change it is he adds some,
I believe Brazil nuts to
his diet because Brazil,
Brazil nuts contain certain minerals,
minerals or something like that.
It's supposed to be good for your sperm
count and took his cell phone out of his
pocket,
did no longer had a cell phone on him.
Apparently the studies online that show
a significant correlation between having
your cell phone in your pocket
and low count. Can I ask
you why it was important to
him to have a good sperm count?
Well, we wanted to know what was going
on with his body because his whole,
his whole thing is about him experimenting
with his body and trying different
things that people try to get
optimum performance out of your body.
His sperm count, the number of sperm
that are live and healthy living.
It's not the loads,
the size of the loads could be the same.
But inside those loads is just how
many words a dead fucking does it.
He goes ship,
he'll look good,
arrives like, you know, you're calm,
smart boy. He's the fucking boat.
Hits the beach at Normandy and
every living soldiers just dead.
They're just slumped over and
it's terrifying. So you're so,
so my loads could be filled with
dad wore a good friend of mine,
had a really hard time getting
his girlfriend pregnant,
his wife pregnant. And um,
they went to a doctor and he's not even
40 and he found out that he had a really
low sperm count and he's kind of freaked
out about it. You know, it was like,
what the fuck? And He's thinking
about all these different things,
but one of those things could
easily be your cell phone.
Your cell phone is cooking your balls.
Your laptop does that too. Yeah.
Well that's heat though. Differences, what
you're talking about heat or radiation?
No, it's the signal. It's the megahertz.
It's a spectrum. The radio spectrum,
but cell phone during her.
That's a good question.
I apparently having the receiver right
next to your balls is like really bad for
your balls. Your balls are just
battling this radiation. Now this for,
I just want to say I've done no research
other than read what he said so I
haven't rehearsed researches online.
The, it's like the brain cancer.
It's switches left and right every time.
You know, every time they say, oh no,
cell phones give you high brain cancer,
but that they say is true one day and
then just treat onfi. I don't think,
first of all, I don't think it has to give
you brain damage to be fucking you up.
It could be fucking you up in subtle
ways. It's very possible. It doesn't,
it doesn't necessarily
have to give you tumors,
but if it's the potential for giving you
tumors is there, what does that mean?
That he'd either kills you
or it does nothing to you.
So either it turns your fucking head
into a grapefruit and pineapple start
growing off the side of your head,
your brain, or it does nothing.
That's ridiculous to me. To me that,
that seems like we're being silly.
That's a silly way of looking
at health that like you, you,
it has no effect on you other
than maybe kills your brain,
this
thing.
And in Virginia there's a part of
Virginia that is a cell phone free zone
because there's some kind of
radio telescopes out there
and they don't want it.
They want to have the purest signal
and they don't want any disruptions.
So there's a name for these zones.
And there are these people who
have been moving to this town.
I can't remember the name of it. Green
something. West Virginia. It's Tom. I,
it's my last tweet. But they've
been moving to this town, uh,
because they think that they're sensitive
to cell phone frequencies and they
break out in rashes.
And this article,
it said that like the has
acknowledged that this does exist,
this health problem does
exist, but there's no proof
that it's from cell phones.
But there are people who get really sick
when they're in cell phone areas and
you know, there, I'm sure a lot of them
are kooks you know, but uh, so you know,
who knows.
Well that's a good guess because a
lot of everybody with when whenever
outrageous claims come up,
you've got to think a certain
percentage of them are Kooks.
But I don't think we've
completely assessed the
effects of all these wireless.
Yes,
no.
Think of that shit man.
Think about the fucking megabytes of
information pouring through the air at any
second. It's, it's like, if all like the,
the information that can create the
beautiful world of Warcraft is like flying
around me at every second.
That can't be good for you.
That's so much information just
blasting out of your modem at all times.
How is that not going to
affect you in some way?
Yeah. Even if you can't process
the information rationally
is your brain's still
tuning into it, like all these
wireless signals that are in our,
I mean we never think about that because
really it that wireless like real full
wireless like we have now with
like Internet and you know,
and radio signals where you're cordless
phones are on certain frequency and then
of course cell phones. This is
really kind of recent, right?
How many years has it been
slowly since the 80s right?
Yeah, but even in this started, I don't
know when Ra wireless routers started.
I mean like in niche more recently.
Yeah. So yeah, there were cell phones,
but I bet the information that
was coming through is less.
It had to have been because
fewer people had cell phones.
I remember the first, first time I got a
computer that was a wireless, I was like,
this is the craziest fucking
thing I've ever seen in my life.
I'm no where near a wire and I'm on line.
That's when you really start to think
how crazy the fucking internet is that
this thing that I can't see can fly
through the air at like ridiculous speeds
and sits on my laptop and I get all the
answers to anything. It's basically,
this is a magic box that lets me have
every answer to everything that's ever
been asked that Cuban pings of answered,
but what, what's coming through
the air? Isn't it just that is it?
Is it like a sound that's telling
your computer? It's a signal.
It's like ones and Zeros
basically certain frequency.
It's like the old dial tone sound that
used to dial in using a 50 60 modem but
quiet.
I thought believed that wireless Internet
was invented by Nikola Tesla too.
I believe the concept of it came
from his work. Is that true?
You did that drunk Tesla drunken moment
and if you haven't seen is folks,
it is one.
I retweeted it just the other day.
One of my funny and one of my favorite
videos and I think it's the one of the
funniest videos ever because it's
first of all, it's so informative.
It's really interesting. A lot of people
don't even know who Nikola Tesla is.
He was just amazing genius.
And one of my personal
best examples of that,
I have a lot of other,
I have a lot of theories about brilliant
people and a lot of the brilliant
people that I've have been crazy. You
know, there's, there's something there.
They might not be a hundred percent crazy,
you know,
maybe it's only 10% grazie maybe
they're hanging on with 20 or 30% crazy.
But to,
I almost believed to be super,
super brilliant at something like Tesla
was like at that level so far beyond
everybody else can almost like you have
to be quirks tuned out. You can't be,
can't be balanced.
There's no way.
Well remember when you were
a kid and you would play,
make believe with your friends and
whatever that was that you did. Like,
I don't know, cowboys and Indians, I
play with my daughter all the time.
So when you,
so now imagine this,
imagine that you had to play that
game for the rest of your life,
even though you knew you were playing
with kids and you knew it was just this
big kids' game. Maybe when people
get super, super, super smart,
they recognize that they're
sort of trapped in this
dimension where everybody's
deeply engrossed in what
amounts to a baby's game,
that they all things very important.
They all think it's really serious,
but you recognize,
oh no,
this isn't even a a 1% of
what exists in the world.
This isn't even 1% these,
these idiots are playing the game of
like presidents and country and army and
police officer, a married
person, but it's just the game.
Maybe when you get really,
really smart,
you see that and all of a
sudden you don't. Not If,
if you're not really smart
or if you're just one of us,
you just normally play the game. You
don't even think about it. You wake up,
go to work.
He was playing the game.
But imagine if you knew this
was a make believe games.
So every day you woke up and you're like,
well,
got to go play with play this absurd
silly game and you just knew it.
Then you'd start doing weird shit
cause it'd be hard for you to just
instinctually do all the different
things that everyone does.
You start doing weird shit and people
would be like, why? And he's kind of off,
isn't he? He's a little
off. He doesn't shake hands.
I wonder why then shaking hands.
What's shaking hands is stupid.
Fuck, I don't want to slap
technicals. I'm sorry.
I don't feel like rubbing tentacle.
Yeah,
those with you today.
You don't want to touch people.
You don't want to offer up your
sword and I feel disrespected.
You know that's what it was. You would
offer up your sword hand. That's right.
You couldn't, you couldn't
kill each other at that moment.
I'm not going to stab yet.
That's not wine England.
He's still driving the left hand side
and then we drive on the right hand side.
They drive it the left because that was
how you wrote a horse and had your sword
in your right hand.
So some Douche bags coming in the other
direction and you want to get them on
your right side so he can sort
his ass. Jesus Christ, they still,
that's why they drive on
that side of the street.
I mean it makes sense because look,
realistically,
it was just a couple of hundred years
ago and people were riding horses
everywhere. I'm, these were
tough. That's how it works.
That's not that long ago man.
That's,
it's amazing when you stop
and think about the end,
Nikola Tesla is really one of the
reasons why we're so fucking advanced.
If you look back at the inventions this
guy was responsible for and all the
patents at this guy was responsible for,
it's a brilliant thing.
And I don't remember at feet here in a
fucking peep about him in high school. I,
I, somebody told about him, uh, when
I was in college and some, some,
it wasn't even in a class.
Some dude was a reading something about
the guy and he looked interesting on the
cover and I think that's how I learned
about Nikola Tesla. But I mean,
I obviously, I didn't take
any science shirts, but I, I,
I never hear about you
hear about Thomas Edison.
You hear about Benjamin Franklin,
the people that invented a May. Oh,
you've had electricity. He wouldn't
have told you who the fucking keys. No,
Nikola Tesla was talking to
aliens, bitch. All right.
That guy was inventing everything and
wound up dying like completely crazy at
the end.
Yeah.
Yeah. He, well, he, yeah, he
was a, I mean, I feel like
I'm quoting the drunk history,
but he is essentially,
it was in love with a white pigeon and
he was wandering around New York and,
you know, and you know, New York
was lit up with his technology, um,
and he was just broke and it was all
there because it came out of his mind.
You know what,
I'll give you a weird little trivia
money from him. Was it Edison? Okay.
Uh, I, well, no, it
was how many die broke?
He died broke because he
had some bad luck. Uh, his,
um,
one of his main laboratories burnt down.
He had basically figured out in his mind,
a way to generate, I, I guess you'd
consider it wireless electricity,
like he had this idea that you could
there rather than having to have like a,
an engine,
a generating the electricity that
the, I don't know, reality
itself for every, you know,
bit of reality had compressed within it,
enough energy to supply anything.
There's like energy all around us.
That was his idea.
We're just surrounded by energy
and there's a way to tap into it.
And so he was way to broadcast electricity
later. Radio. Well, yeah, yeah, exactly.
I mean, I guess you could
if, assuming that you didn't
have to have like, you know,
a hydroelectric dam or oil
or whatever it, it to, uh,
create energy,
assuming that in every inch of the
universe there was infinite energy,
then you would just,
every house would become a power plant.
It wouldn't all be based on wherever
the main energy is coming from,
the nuclear power plant or whatever.
It would be some sort of device
that you could put in your house.
They could channel the,
the energy, you know,
channel. But what, what are they
calling that energy? Like what is it?
Just something we haven't
figured out and discovered yet?
Something we haven't figured out.
And so instead of this the crude method
of pulling oil out of the ground and
light it on fire,
that there's another step.
Well, yeah, or you know, I mean it's
obvious. I mean, look at fucking, uh,
the solar panels, right? I
mean, there's a, there's,
there's enough energy from the sun that
to keep every organic form make that the
law. Why don't they just
make that roofs? You know,
in California you have to
have solar panels on it.
Well, it's no fuck laws, man.
You don't need to make more laws.
The last thing we need is more people
telling people what they have to spend
their fucking money.
It's also expensive to make them an
n n the a amount of time it takes you
forever to recoup the amount it
costs to install and make them right.
Right now it's financially a good deal,
but they can be done.
They give you a tag backs or whatever
they're called. Uh, I don't know.
They give you money back. I would think
about doing it just to get off the grid.
That's fine. Sand when I
lived in Colorado, I wanted to
do that. Tom. Um, what Chia
Saunas [inaudible] yeah.
Fuck. I can't forget his name.
A friend of mine. Anyway, he uh,
he had a windmill set up at
his house. That's cool. Yeah,
those are awesome man. I love passing
those fields and when males, it's so cool.
Yeah. He, um, he had a windmill
set up at his house and he, uh,
he was giving money back.
Like they would give him money rather
than me giving energy back to the grid,
which is crazy.
He was making numbers on energy.
You know what, man, the thing,
the thing I've been thinking
lately is that, uh, it's,
we live in such a funny time because I
guess people just don't like if you start
saying things like, no, you know what?
I have the feeling there's actually
another energy source out there that we
haven't even stumbled upon yet that has
like all a million times more energy
than you could ever need.
If you say that now people really will,
you seem kind of like a fruit or a
flake or an 88 or they are like here,
well bays it in science.
You don't know what that is or you
don't know what you're talking about.
But there was a time when if you
were just talking about electricity,
you would've seen like an absolute
lunatic. Like if you went around in the,
I dunno, 12 hundreds and
started telling people, listen,
there's this fucking energy
called electricity that's
more powerful than fire.
You can use it to, you can, you can run
it through wires and if you touch it,
you'll get electrocuted. They go like,
get this fucking, which on the stake?
What are you talking about? War Lock. We
are going to harness lightening. Yeah.
Yeah. What are you talking Frankenstein?
What are you talking about?
But so in the same way, man,
I think that there's probably,
I've been thinking about, it's
such a, I have this weird idea.
Do you remember when Frankenstein,
when he made that fucking chick, when?
When were you made when they made
Frankenstein and they actually had to get
lightning to make him a lot of,
they had a good idea how to
hit the tower with lightning.
Wait, you mean they really did that?
Are you saying that one of the movies,
the movie back to the future?
Hmm.
One of the Frankenstein movies.
Remember when they did them? I know,
I know Frankenstein was fucking,
I know that like Frankenstein what I've
like had to have like a hit of whitening
to bring the person to life. That's
right. I'm sorry I interrupted you.
So go back to what you're saying. Well No,
what I was thinking is it's like, okay,
so like what if like you look at like,
I know this is something I so wish that
you can do and you'll never be able to
do it,
but it would be so amazing to look at
from the beginning of time to right now
and like a 22nd fast forward to see what
that blur of happening look like or the,
you know, the good, the evolution.
It'd be so fun to be able to see in a
real way what evolution look like from,
you know, the evolution of
a fucking, I don't know,
the evolution of a chicken and do
a or a dinosaur and do a chicken.
It'd be amazing to watch. That thing
happened really fast to be really cool.
But so like,
okay,
so this is gonna sound crazy and I'm
sorry if it seems rambling and weird cause
I haven't quite figured
out how to articulate this
idea. But like if you have,
okay, you have fire, fire leaves
a trace, you know, where there's,
where there's been a fire, there's
suit, there's ashes, black suit,
whatever from the carbon's being released
in the fire, right. The carbon rather.
So in the same way I was thinking,
what if there's another form of energy
that's raging through time and this form
of energy instead of leaving ashes
leaves evolved things. It's like the,
the biproduct of the energy is that it
causes things to evolve and advance and
grow and become more sophisticated.
You know,
and like maybe that energy
that there's literally an,
an energy associated with evolution.
There's an energy that you can tap into.
And so when you see like,
which is why you know computers are so
amazing is because they can really tap
into that energy right away in the form
of like open source software and stuff
like that.
And you see things that go open source
or things that allow the most people to
have the most input to the
most intelligent people.
Having the input create the advance
in whatever the thing is. You know,
the classic example of it
as a silly example of it,
it's like reddit where someone will
write something and then the top comment
inevitably will be so fucking
funny because hundreds and
hundreds of people have
like voted it up to the top.
So it creates this evolved way of getting
information to float up to the surface.
So in the same way it's like, that's
brilliant. It's fucking, it's, yeah,
it's brilliant. Awesome. It's the
way our government should work.
If someone Youtube Cummins do that
too. Yeah, yeah. It goes up to the top.
So like that's a form of
like tuning into this energy,
this like evolutionary force
as it's manifesting, you know,
and the form of the most, uh,
the, the comment that his mo,
the strongest comment or the comment
that works best in that particular
zeitgeists their paradigm goes to the top.
That comment is the fucking animal
that survives that comments.
The animal that in its environment does
the best. And it's getting there through,
um, you know, people voting.
But what I'm saying is technology
like harnessed the evolutionary, uh,
flow in that situation. So I'm thinking,
okay, maybe evolution itself is an energy.
What if you could fucking harness
that shit? Remember in Star Trek,
what was it called?
The genesis beam or whatever.
They blast the planet with the thing that
makes the life grow out of it all of a
sudden. Wow. I don't remember that at all.
Which was that the new star trek reverse
spoiler alert. No, no, it's an old one.
I think it would have to incur the
wrath of Khan. Oh, the wrath of Khan.
Don't you remember the RAF
and Ricardo [inaudible] bonds?
Fuck yeah, with the ear.
I was like,
how the fuck are you going to have the
dude from fantasy island be the bad guy
in a fucking star trek movie? I think
you did great out of here, bitch. Yeah,
he was great. He was great. I mean
he's a great actor, don't get me wrong.
But when at the time she was like,
this is the dumbest Shit I've ever heard
of in my life. And they're like, no.
Ricardo Montalban he's a
very respected actor. Yeah,
he was handsome bastard man kind of pussy.
He got off of fantasy
island. Your fantasies can
through with die. Did he die?
I bet he overdosed from Posey.
I bet they'll the line of chicks.
They wanted to fuck him in the 70s it's
probably still outside of his house.
They just get into them right now cause
I have no time for all of you girls.
Welcome to fantasy island.
He had his own midget,
he was the first guy on
TV to have his own midget.
Yeah. And, and you know, have you ever
seen the pilot? No. It's Kinda creepy man.
It's like diabolic like that character
Rourke, that was his name, right?
Rourke was, uh, in the pilot it was
almost like he was Satan or something.
Like he was like some dark being
really. Yeah. Cause you know, in,
in history, uh, in a cult history,
which is always have amps are familiars
that a common way to know that you're
around. Like that's why, you know,
like David Lynch and twin peaks,
that spooky little fucking
backwards talking midget,
you know the guy that table
is for Micah. Right? Um,
so like that's an a cult symbol I like,
which is what always have
around them and lower,
they would always have like a cat,
you know, some kind of creature.
And sometimes they'd have a little
emp Earl or creature with them.
So Monto bond.
Rourke's tattoo was his name.
It seemed like in the pilot they were
thinking, let's make this like heat.
Let's make him a feisty in character
where he's like, when he's not,
you know, he's maybe not giving
people exactly what they want.
Cause remember some people would
want something and it fuck them up.
Didn't they redo fantasy island for a
little while? I don't know. Did they,
didn't they or was it the love boat? No,
it was fantasy island. That's Jerry Redd.
Wilson. Yeah. That's how he died.
There's this comic named Jerry Redd
Wilson and he supposed to go and film
fantasy island and he apparently had
meningitis and he did know he just had a
headache.
Yeah.
Like knew something was wrong and he went
to the doctor and I guess the line was
ridiculous and he wound up just couldn't
take it anymore and he left the doctor
and you want to die. Oh Shit. Yeah.
Get yourself checked out people.
It's just not, not as, not a bad
thing to do. Smart. But um, point is,
I'm pretty sure he was
going to do fantasy island.
It was a fucking great show back in
the day, dude. What a great idea.
People have fantasies,
they fly in,
they get welcomed by this magic man and
it's magical island is going to make
your dreams come true and teach
you a little lesson. Bitch.
They always taught you a nice little
lesson and g and quiet. And then let you,
you leave the island and
you kind of get it now.
Wait, did everyone, did everyone who
came in on that plane leave on the plane?
Didn't some people not make it out? I, I,
I don't know.
You can't have people die on your island,
Ben Fucking,
you see what happens with Aruba
is said fucking 19 year old chick
from Arizona or something like that.
It's just on a vacation. And you know, a
rube was like where they turn up missing,
right? That's right. Scary was the
one with the boat. Gilligan's island.
But the other one with the boat love boat,
the lowest got love boat
in that show mixed up. Oh,
did people die on the left
though? No fucking way. No.
No shows ever. I don't know.
I probably was like,
they should
the love boat ship wrecks on fantasy
that didn't like go for from the love boat
become a politician. He did, I believe.
Yeah. Yeah. I need to research that.
But I uh, I'm pretty sure he did.
I'm pretty sure he became like a senator.
So politicians are, they are this,
I cannot wait until the day
and this day will never come.
But that day when we have zoos,
where politicians are placed in zoos,
like antiquated things like
kids can come and look at them.
Behold Fred Grandy,
that's his name.
He's a politician. He was a congressman.
He used to be, go for Weirdos,
man on our kind of crazy shit they did
back in those days because that then when
they did shit, they could totally
get away with everything. You know,
they just were complete freaks.
Like,
remember that movie about the guy from
Hogan's heroes at the fuck's his name?
The, the, the main dude wound
up killing himself. And um,
you don't know the movie I'm talking
about? No, it's a great movie. Um, here,
let me look it up real quick because
it's, it's really important. It was the,
the guy from talk soup.
John Hanson. No, no
grey patch. Uh, uh,
the dude from love letter movies,
love letter movies. What is his name?
Kissy face movies. Fuck, I can't auto
focus. That's the movie. Greg Kinnear.
You got it. Yeah. Pam, it's
a great fucking movie. Um,
they don't got a 6.6 on the IMD B.
How dare you get an excellent movie.
I know.
I didn't want to bring the
legacy of this movie auto focus.
If you haven't seen it, you must,
you must see it. It's about this guy,
whatever the fuck his name was,
Bob Crane,
he was a sex fiend,
like a complete the charts sex fiend.
And he started out on the
show have married guy. And uh,
somehow or another he got so many girls
from being on Hogan's heroes that he
just completely became out of control,
didn't take care of his career,
taking care of his family,
just with just banging chicks and
filming and all and like their stack.
Any eventually wound up getting murdered.
And it was a very sorted thing cause
they believed that the guy who played the
Willem defoe character was the one
who killed them. And they even,
I think they have that in the
movie as well. But either way,
it's our great grateful.
They fucking hated each other there,
boning together and shit. It
probably got jealous that, uh,
Bob Crane was getting all the Punana,
you know,
he used to sit in front of a television
at a bar when he knew that the show
would be on so that they could see him.
They'll show was like long since canceled.
It would be on in reruns and he would be
doing like local theater like at these
towns and he would just bang all
the local broads and filming.
They were freaks back then.
They didn't have any Twitter,
they didn't have any TMZ.
You could just go off.
You didn't have to worry about it.
If something was on a VHS tape,
I mean he's was,
the VHS was like 18 millimeter,
eight millimeter or 16
millimeter over the hell it is.
You know those little reels,
you had to play it on a projection thing
and he was like one of the first dudes
to be on top of that shit,
that technology of filming things.
And you see those naked pictures of
that girl that, that were released,
that actress check what actress chuck.
I,
and she has to be in a new movie soon
because there's no way that that that's
just happens to be released. You know,
that's the big talk on the Internet too.
Let me see.
What's her name?
I don't know who that is, man. I've no
idea. No, she's like super famous. Yeah,
that girl. Super Fun. Yeah, she's a me.
I picked up the cover of one of those
us weekly things, whatever it is,
one of those inside something or other
and I didn't know who any of the people
on it where I literally knew who
none of the celebrity don't know any
celebrities aren't like your Hansen and
I fee. I was like, I think I've won.
I think I won. Yeah. It's good to not
know celebrity names like in this,
this one battle with gossip.
I got free cause I had no attachment to
any of them and it occurred to me when I
looked at the magazine and I didn't have
any attachment. I'll be like, God damn.
And if there was a fucking some Jennifer
Aniston broken heart because Gerard
Butler, you know, fucking did her wrong.
I'd be like, Oh, why would that guy do?
I'd have to go read it.
I would have to go read it.
I'm invested in that storyline,
but there's like,
there was some guy on from
the Bachelorette and some
girl on from fucking orange
county wives or something like that. I
didn't know who anybody was. I was like,
this is great. And they had a couple
like little teeny boppers, you know,
and you know Joe, he breaks up with
Demi wants her back. I'm like, Oh,
who the fuck they are either.
And it occurred to me,
while I didn't have any idea who any of
these people were, how freeing that was.
It is like a little God damn drug.
If there's some fucking crazy story about
someone who, you know their storyline,
like tiger woods,
you know tiger woods,
you know a man resurfaces,
you know tiger woods apparently was
bisexual and they did that and that was on
the cover of us weekly. That would
be like a God damn tractor beam.
You wouldn't be able to avoid it.
If I sent you a link and it was
photos of tiger woods kissing a man,
you are so God damn connected to
that storyline, you would, you would,
it would be impossible to get you
to not click that link. If you had,
if you had the photograph,
you'd be a millionaire.
If you ever had that photograph
and you put that online,
I guarantee you it would
be like 100% click through.
Like if you send people it and they know
they have this link and they click this
link and they see tiger woods
kicking that dude click,
it'd be like 100% like no one's gonna go,
who cares? No one's going to say that.
They're going to see people are invested
in that storyline because it's such a
charged one. Such a big
scandal, very unattractive guy,
beautiful wife Guy, super,
super fucking successful,
like ridiculous. Really Rich,
the greatest golfer perhaps ever,
and just fucks everyone.
Just fucks everyone.
So it's so highly charged
that if something else
happened to it and it's like,
well, I'm already invested
in this tiger woods story.
I can't believe he's kissing guys. You
know you would, I would be drawn to it,
but all these people, like one of them
was, you know, I don't know any of them.
I don't know,
age people.
One was like a on America's got talent
or something and I don't know the fuck
any of them were. I was like, this
is awesome. I could walk away.
I don't have to read it.
I don't have to open this up.
Great. It's gravity man. It's like that
Shit's got gravity. It's got attention.
Gravity.
Like some stuff in the world act does
the same thing to your attention that the
planet does.
Dale like satellites.
It'll grab your attention and suddenly
you're circling this weird like a
temporary vortex in the subjective
reality, the planet with your attention.
And it's so stupid. I mean, there's
so many things that have that example.
Football, fucking uh, any sports is
the exact same attention. Gravity,
video games, attention, gravity,
girls' attention, gravity, mu,
it's all like different,
quite gravitational fields that will,
depending on what person you're like,
you're going to get your attention
sucked into this certain thing.
And once it gets sucked in deep enough,
you're not thinking about anything else.
No. That's true thing when everything
shuts down except for whatever this silly
thing is that when you're locked
in a video game, yes, that's it.
You will negate yourself if you get
stuck deep enough into a video game.
Complete introversion.
Yeah.
Do you think that it's like a hijacking
of our natural ward system by this new
creation by it is what it
is, right? Because you know,
I've always said that we're sort of set
up to imitate successful behavior. Right.
But I don't think we can
differentiate 100%. You know,
how we can't differentiate
between a placebo and, um,
and an actual drug in certain situations.
Even if the person knows that something
is a placebo, they showed marked effects,
you know,
if they're concentrating on this
actually having some sort of an effect,
it shows sort of some sort of effects.
Oh yeah, totally. I read that placebo, I
know it's, I don't understand that, but I,
I get it.
If the police CBO affects amazing.
That's why people have different
rituals. They do. What was my point?
I had a point where you get
the same effect though from me.
What do we were just talking about?
We're talking about attention, tension.
Vampires were talking about the forces
of nature that grab your attention and
you were saying, is that based
on a reward system? Is that like,
is it hijacking the reward system?
Right. Okay. That's what I meant.
What I meant by that is that we've
created something with like w like big
events. Anything that you see in
your life that's memorable, the,
they're very shocking and engaging because
you need to learn from this situation.
If you could come over a hill and you
stumble upon a bunch of barbarians
slaughtering a village with axes,
this is supposed to shock
the fucking shit out of,
you're supposed to be aware that this is
all possible. This is like, oh my God,
you could be dying right now.
You need to learn from this,
but when we recreate that in some
sort of a crazy imaginary flacked,
one dimensional or two dimensional image
with sound that comes from all around
you,
I don't know if your brain 100% can
differentiate that from reality any more
than a placebo has an effect on
a person. I wonder. I wonder.
You know what it is, dude,
I'm sorry to cut you off.
When you take your cat and you have one
of those like, I don't know any cat toy,
watch what it does to your cats attention.
Your cat goes from like,
if your cat gets into it enough,
it stops being a toy and now the cats
obviously thinks it's the a bird.
It's intuit, it's in nature again and
it's stalking it's and it's attention.
It's totally sucked into that cat toy.
That's what video games are for.
The human nervous system. They were
like, he, they're like human cat toys.
You're playing this fucking cat toy.
Your attention sucked into it in like,
you know people when they party,
when they portray aliens coming down,
they're going to use laser
guns to subdue us. Fuck that.
They're just going to like some super
advanced being which is analyze our
nervous system and just like hypnotize us.
That's what it would do.
Well,
Laura,
assuming that life is going to be hard
or assuming that life isn't going to be
like a fucking Wifi frequency,
right?
Just because we are physical and we are
hard and we touch things and move them
and manipulate matter, it doesn't
mean all life has to do that. Do we?
We know that bacteria doesn't do that.
We can't even fucking see it.
We know what we need.
Some crazy lens that magnifies our normal
reality down to the point where it's
supposed to be completely invisible to us.
Like we're not supposed to be able
to see it. Right, right. Yeah.
We can find it and we can find
that there's some life there.
There's something there.
Intelligent life might be ideas.
Intelligent life might be creativity.
What creativity might be is when you
just relax the fuck enough to listen to
this intelligent life
that's all around you.
This training get you to move your
monkey body in a certain way where you're
going to manipulate matter to the point
where you punch a fucking hole through
space and time. And the idea of
tangible objects no longer exists.
Right? Like that's the
destiny. That's what,
that's your reason for your curiosity
as a reason why you've created music and
motivation and cocaine.
You're supposed to be pushing towards
this inevitable goal of creating some sort
of a fucking opening where this
thing changes into the next thing.
You know what that made me just
think of like, imagine, you know,
like when those miners got
stuck in the mind. Yeah.
Imagine if like when they got stuck in
the mine, so I'm kind of fume came out,
they gave them complete Amnesia and so
they completely lost their identities and
couldn't even speak any
language anymore. And so, uh,
they thought that that's where
they were born as this stupid mind.
And imagine the people outside the mine
would first have to teach them English,
teach them a language,
teach them who they were,
give them all this information first
before they could get trapped out of,
you know, escape from the
mind. So in the same way,
maybe this whole dimension is some kind
of Cavan and on the other side of it,
there's like super advanced beings that
are trying to teach us like, hey, wake up,
you know, try this, try this, try this.
You'll have to get smarter before they,
cause like if you can't tell someone
in the 18 hundreds about electricity,
you sure as fuck can't
tell them about the most
diverse. This is going to
sound totally crazy. All right.
But what if people are to ideas what
reconditioned laptops are two people.
And that when you get
a recondition laptop,
you've got a laptop
that's all his hard drive,
all the space and the operating system
and then you swipe all the data at and
just give it to someone to add their
own stuff to completely clean. Yeah.
Like, but has this past, you know? Yeah.
And that is what it like a human is.
You come into this life,
you press the reset button,
press or re, what is that?
It's kind of like Carlos when see it.
I don't get it.
I was talking about that tweet. I have
nowhere what? Tweet? Chris Hardwick.
Sweet.
Oh
God damn dude, you lost me. Totally.
Yeah, of course. Hardworking.
Brian and I had a
conversation about stitcher.
I think are co other people see
podcasting differently than we do though.
You know,
there's a lot of people that are trying
to monetize their podcasts and um,
you know,
when you're in the top five or top 10,
all right,
he was breaking down 3000 listeners.
Uh,
an episode on stitcher.
3000 is how many would he,
how many people listen on stitcher and
your keys in the top four of comedy,
iTunes rankings, right. I know the numbers
just because we did, we did this show,
I'm not gonna say the numbers,
but I'm just going to say 3000 is not
going to affect anything in the top five.
Well, it's a, it really
depends on what you're doing.
Some people are actually selling their
iTunes podcasts and the there building up
towards the point where they're gonna sell
them. And then some people they, they,
there's not though.
Okay.
But some people have advertising that's
based on their iTunes ranking. You know,
it could be based on how
many hits you get on iTunes.
And in that sense he's absolutely right.
Cause in that sense,
if he doesn't want to shit on stitcher
and they, I believe they pulled it off,
he's absolutely right because
he gets paid by iTunes.
What he should be able to do is go to the
company that's sponsoring them and say,
well, here's, there's another application
called stitcher. It's very easy to track.
Why can't we work that into it? Say
let's say, you know, I get x amount per,
you know, thousand downloads on iTunes
and then, you know, a percentage,
uh, of the downloads on stitcher. It
seems to me that it's, if it's trackable,
you should still be able to run the ads
on it. As far as I know, they don't, uh,
they don't do any editing of your show.
They don't do any of that. The only
thing it is, it's a banner on the APP,
which is about one 12th of the
APP. Right. And it's like, uh,
from Hardwick's numbers that
he did it in a blog post,
I can't remember the exact number.
I want to say it was uh,
800 every 800 views of that
teeny banner on that APP.
He gets a dollar,
which sucks.
But knowing what Google adsense pays
for like views of ad, it's not far off.
Well, I, I, you know some man,
he's got his own thing. He,
he likes doing it a certain way
and he should be able to, it's his,
it's his product. I'm, I'm agreeing
with Chris Hardwick a hundred percent.
But for us, we have a totally
different take on stitcher because I,
the podcast is, first of all, we started
off with, it wasn't supposed to be a job,
it was a goof.
It was just me and Brian having fun and
why I wanted to do it too is just to do
something. I thought it would be fun to
just do it and do it on a regular basis.
And people like things that are free.
It's good.
It's good to give people free shit.
I think it's in the spirit of things,
you know? It shows that the entertainment
that you're trying to provide,
you're really trying to provide it
for the sake of it. If you don't,
you know what I'm saying? Like you know
how he don't have any ulterior motives.
You're just doing it for the sake
you're trying to make it good.
You're trying to make it fun.
People will respond to that and
they like it and they'll do,
they'll support you in other ways.
They'll come see your comedy show. They'll
no what, man, whatever. That's where we
did. I just say I disagree with that.
I think it's awesome to give free content,
but I also think it's fine to charge for,
no, no, no. You're missing turban me.
I do not think there's anything wrong
with charging it. I just don't need to,
so since I don't need to, I make
it free. Right. It's that simple.
If I needed to look like in your case,
I know that you charged
occasionally for podcasts,
we do an extra episode a week
and charge a buck. Right.
And this has been like a a source of
controversy and some fucking dummy on my
message board wrote some whole thing
about how he's upset at you because you
charge for a podcast and all that.
I fucking pay, you know, listen,
no one is telling you you will have to
pay and in fact Dunkin is actually giving
you something for free still.
He does an extra one a week and then
the extra one he wants to see if he can
make some money. We know what's
particularly to me, what's gross man,
people are gross.
But I think it's a, it's,
it's, it's, I know it's, I,
that's what I thought originally, but then
when I started thinking about it more,
I realized that it uncovers this certain
layer of conditioning that exists in
people because like when you go to the
ATM and the ATM asks you for two Bucks or
whatever to get cash out because you're
not at your bank, you're just like, ah,
fuck it.
Do it when you're at the gas station
and it's like 35 cents convenience fee.
I don't even know what that fucking means,
but I'll pay it.
But the moment artists
start saying, hey, I,
I like to make money for this
stuff I'm making. People are like,
what the fuck you're gonna charge
for that Shit. They, but if
I see you're getting it for free, you
mean? Well, they're getting it for free.
If you start charging from the beginning,
people have no problem with continued
to pay for things. Yeah, yeah. It's,
once they start getting it for free,
that's all. We added an extra episode
and experiment totally worked.
And it made me think, you
know, this is a model.
Maybe this is a new model
that other people can use.
It's like instead of pulling the rug
out from people's feet and saying,
you're paying now I'm
charging for everything.
You always offer some free thing for
people to enjoy and then you add one extra
thing to. It's if people are really
into it and don't mind paying.
Most people send us emails saying they
like supporting the show. They like it.
Well,
most people do.
The reason why people get upset
is the reason why people there.
There's people that find something
anywhere to get angry at and it's because
they're looking for it. They're
looking for something to piss them off.
And if you're angry at some guy whose
podcast you like because he would like a
dollar for an hour and a half's
worth of, uh, him talking,
I understand what you don't. If
you don't have a buck, like, look,
I've been there before,
man.
I've been to points in my life where I
rolled pennies so I'd have something to
eat for dinner. I understand poverty.
I've, I've been there for a long time.
I totally get that.
You don't have to buy it,
but you have to be fucking mad that
he's selling it. And by the blessing,
when someone's giving you something
for free, and also, by the way, how about
you email me and ask for the fucking MP3?
There's like a 99% chance.
I probably wouldn't
just send it to you.
Just fucked up and said on the Internet
was the one time I would have done unto
email. Never do it again.
Okay, well, whatever.
Trolled by a hot chick,
right? It's really a dude. Ah,
that will be tearing at whatever height
you fucked up. You open up the gates,
you challenged.
There's all this time he challenged the
hackers in the world right there to what?
To a duel. I do not just mentoring.
I know you said you were,
you said you were respond to email.
You saying you respond to emails is
like opening up the gates to hell sure.
That someone's going to go,
okay, how do I get this one?
The fuck could it looks stupid.
Oh No. Next game. Now I'm paranoid.
Now we got to exist in like a Philip k
Dick Universe with like being terrified
of people who email me. I do.
You know what, by the way,
people already know I respond to shit
cause I talked to people on Facebook and
you do on occasion get some emails from
people that it really seems like these
are cops. You know what I mean? For sure.
I got an email from somebody who's like,
hi me and my buds.
We're thinking of taking some magic
mushrooms and we're wondering if you could
tell us where to get them or
could send us some in the mail.
But it was like the slang they
were using was like, like sides.
But yeah it was weird.
Obviously worse. First of all,
you hippie ever. Even if it was serious
like I'm going to be like, oh sure
his mail you an illegal substance is
really hilarious. Yeah, it's very,
it's very spooky. I had a guy wanted
to get DMT from me and Cleveland.
I knew he was a cop cause the first of
all, who the fuck is asking me for DMT,
Cleveland and Cleveland. I mean
Cleveland and this guy is a crew cut.
He's looking at me and I'm like, this
guy isn't this rock. He's not high.
And you know, you know, I'm assessing a
dude, I'm looking at this guy. I'm like,
this guy seems like he's had some
self defense training. Right?
It seems like he's a confident man. It
seems like he's in a, he's acting what?
He's got some weird like um,
feeling of authority about him.
I was like, he's almost
like, he expects authority.
He expects you to like this guy
was like such an obvious cause.
Ridiculous because a bad cop or
at least a dumb cop, they get a,
a feeling of entitlement around
people. You know, a dumb one.
I've seen it a bunch of times and I'm a
big supporter of cops and I always say
that the 99% of cops are
just trying to do a good job.
It's the 1% of cons that fuck it
up for everybody else. You know,
they run a pretty fucking tight
ship and most police for sure,
but this guy just eat of cop. I was
like, what are you talking about man?
And he goes, he goes, he
goes, come on man, DMT.
He's like looking at me and I'm looking
at him, we're making eye contact.
I'm like, motherfucker, the last thing you
want is DMT. You're not looking for DMT.
You fucking Weirdo.
Yeah. You know and I,
and I was like, I said
weirdest stare off man.
It was so strange.
I think associate cause cause
he was totally full of Shit.
There was no way this guy was looking
at trip. He wasn't looking at Trevor,
he was looking to fucking arrest me.
You're not know that marijuana thing
that John Have Ron gave you? Yeah.
Ever since that show,
every day this guy rob writes to me
and he adds an extra hundred dollars.
He goes a hundred dollar donation. If you
send me one of those marijuana sticks,
$200 donation, he's done it every
day. I think I'm up to $500 a month.
That's just to tell him to suck your
cock on video. Do An internet search.
Why Tracy didn't tell him about Google.
Yeah. Well, you can't get that shit on.
You can't get a vapor I oh really? Yeah.
Yeah. Those, these are California. Oh. Oh,
I see. I didn't, or maybe
probably Colorado's rockets.
They're thinking about closing
the post office. Yeah, man.
I'm tired of getting mail. Yes, me too.
Me Too. I never get good. How about,
how about we make it so that,
just like our answers,
Sasha, we get to the point where
nothing we have is traceable.
Once the big bang happens,
right.
Fucking rock hits the planet
and all our fucking, yeah.
Yeah. All our hardware corrodes. We
have nothing solid written anywhere.
How about no post office and only
quarters do you mean only quarters doll or
money? Dollar bills and stuff
like that. Paper money, but
only quarters. No pennies.
Nickels and dimes. Everything
really. Recording. Stopped
doing the, no, I mean, what,
what? Did that make sense? I mean,
that'd be a good idea. Oh Jesus. Dude.
Everything in quarters. Yeah. I mean,
how many knowing it seems like it would
be a nice excuse for them to raise taxes
so that everything runs off
to a quarter. Yeah. Yeah.
No matter what it rounds off to.
The next quarter always raises high
and all that goes to the government.
That's not a good move. What are
you doing? What of those fuck heads?
More money had been watching
these republican debates. Yeah.
Did you see the one where
they were talking about the
guy dying cause he didn't
have any money and didn't
have any insurance.
She die and the audience was cheering.
Yeah.
Tell me about that.
What is,
well I'll tell you what it is.
The tea party is hilarious because the
moment you climb out of the pussy it's
open game. But when you're in
there and no one can touch you,
they're all anti abortion.
But the moment you're born there like
let him die and I'd like you could have a
baby that pops out and doesn't
have insurance inside the fetus.
If the woman wanted to get inside the
womb, if the woman wanted an abortion,
the tea party be like, no, it's
evil. The moment that baby comes out,
if it doesn't have insurance,
tea parties
let it die. It's Mama didn't
have insurance, let it die.
I don't think they feel
that way about babies,
what they feel like grown ups on it. But
growing up, growing up, you're on your
gramma grownups,
which is mutated babies.
Well, their babies that grew up there,
but I don't think they're anti baby.
I think they're just,
when you get to a certain point,
you're supposed to take
personal responsibility.
I think the way they're going
about it is pretty silly. I mean,
the idea should be that you should have
a sense of community that is earned
where everyone contributes. So
everyone wants to help everyone. Sure.
Our real problem is that there's too
many fucking people and that you cannot
have communities of 20 million people,
right?
Because you're going to get a
diffusion of responsibility.
You're going to get a situation where
there's too many fucking people and
they're not going to care about one life
here or one live there and one person
here, one person there.
They don't have to.
But if you lived in a
village of 50 people,
everyone want to have to care about
everyone and that's how we're supposed to
live. We're supposed to live like in the
movie Little Red Riding Hood where the,
there's a girl with a bug eyes.
It's really hot. What's that chick?
She's blonde flogger who cares?
I don't care what it is very hot.
She's in a lot of movies and um,
she was in Little Red Riding Hood and
they played this little village where
there was a werewolf that
came was fucking everybody up.
I have to see all werewolf mode across
even a little red riding hood. But uh,
she lives in this little village and as
well as watching all these people sort
of prepare their town and
you know, and, and you know,
stockpile everything and prepare
for this werewolf. I was like,
this is how people really
are supposed to live there.
Some supposed to live in small communities
that are worried about outsiders.
That's how they're supposed to live.
He supposed to be.
Everybody that you know in this
little area is your friend.
You're all cool, you're cool together,
you work together, you eat together,
you hunt together, you cook together.
Everyone is in this little group.
The people that you don't
know that come over the hill,
those are the ones you
have to worry about.
I don't think people are supposed
to live in any particular way.
I think that there's bears, you know,
that's what adaptations all about. Sure.
So I think that the,
you know,
now that the real problem isn't that, you
know, people are sucking the system dry.
The right,
the real problem is really quite clear.
It just seems like it's right
in front of everyone. Diabetes,
it's that 2% of the people on
the planet have all the wealth.
And that's,
that's the problem.
That is,
that is part of the problem.
But the other part of the problem
is that the biological evolution,
the evolution of the animal to human
animal itself to adapt to this system of
this community being intensely like
incredibly larger than it used to be.
That our DNA and our,
the way we think and behave and it's
based on communities and when all of a
sudden the community is some abstract
number that you can't even wrap your head
around a community of 300 million
people. Well, that's the only
reason why we can except states. And you
know, if we just had one giant state,
it would be so completely
ridiculous. You know, it would be,
it would seem so strange.
World. The order or like a global, yes.
No,
I mean the idea of a giant community of
bunch of people you don't even fucking
know of a, not in a number that's so
large. You can't wrap your head around.
We don't know what 300 million means.
300 million is just some
numbers on a piece of paper.
No one's brain registers
with 300 million people is,
but that's the community that we're
involved in. Somehow or another,
the world has grown to the point where
300 million people plus the whole rest of
the world is constantly
communicating at the exact same time,
which is something the biological body
of today, it's absolutely not ready for.
So all of our checks and balances and
natural reward systems are completely
fucking hijacked. Just like
they're hijacked with movies
that fucking trick us.
Just like their hijack with placebos,
just like the whole system is hijacked
and we have just have not caught up to
how much life has changed,
not catching up and and a
big reason it is not right
catching it is,
but slowly it's the,
it takes longer than the thing.
Well that's because the people who are
in control of the system are the 2% who
have all the money.
That's the fucking problem.
But isn't that why the system has gotten
this big this fast and the first place?
It's almost like you need greed tents.
You need a greed and intense ambition
and all these things in some form
ultimately lead to monarchies
ultimately lead to bad things.
It's like they get so intense that a
person is so competitive about money that
they get to the point where they have
way more money than they can use and
they're fucking over
the rest of the world,
but they can't even help themselves
because it's like an ethic,
always an explanation for tyranny.
There's always an explanation like that.
You can almost always tell there's an x.
There's like there's the
current explanation is these
people the not what you're
saying because what you're saying is
is is is smart, but the, the, the,
the base version is these 2% of the
wealthy have earned their money and they
deserve to keep it in everyone else.
They're lazy fucks.
That's the idea.
They're just not lucky.
They just didn't put their
shoulders to the grind stone.
They didn't push hard enough and
so that's the, that's the idea.
Now I think the real truth of the
matter is that many of these people have
inherited their money.
Many of these people,
they didn't necessarily earn their money
and even if they did earn the fucking
money,
the fact that there are people
in the world with big fat,
bloated fucking bellies cause they're
starving to death in Somali and we can't
get the resources there because some
of fundamentalists fucking Islamic
organization what the Shit through
so that fucking babies can eat.
The fact that we're
totally cool with that,
while simultaneously every bomb we
drop costs $100,000 on top of Libya.
The fact that we're totally cool with
that is an indication to me not have a
nervous system not catching up,
but a state of people not being
educated appropriately and ethics.
It seems like a simple thing.
We need to fucking t school teachers
need to start getting paid that doctors
wage school teachers need to start getting
paid the same amount of celebrities
get paid so that it becomes a competitive
industry and only the super smart are
the ones who start giving our
children like the basic information.
You're absolutely right and on that
platform you should run for president.
But my,
my point is not a attached to the
human animal as one of its own.
My point is looking at it objectively.
When I look at it objectively,
when I look at the,
the way human beings are so intensely
focused on wealth and so intensely focused
on privilege and of uh, on, on,
conquering and taking over things,
I really think that it's like a queen
bee or like any sort of a natural,
you know,
a large leader of an ant colony
or whatever the fuck it is there.
There's some crazy thing that people
need in order to accomplish what we are
abstract, abstractly, aware
of trying to accomplish.
And it goes back to this technology thing.
You, when you, when you have ambition,
any kind of ambition, you're going to have
competition. When you have competition,
you're always going to have people
that take it to the next level.
And some people,
you know,
take it to the next level like Michael
Jordan does on the basketball court.
Or you know,
you've got guys like William Randolph
Hearst who takes it to that next level
when he was running newspapers. He's
just a fucking dominator. Fuck you.
I don't give a shit. How about I make
up stories and put them on my newspaper?
You fuck head.
And then I'm going to kill you and I'm
going to make up a story and put it in my
paper that says you were in the
Kiddie porn. You fuckhead I mean,
William Randolph Hearst got
to some insane point of power,
but I almost wonder if instead of looking
at these individual circumstances are
individual,
uh,
people that create horrible things and
greed and an obscenely wealthy people
while other people are starving.
Instead of looking at that,
I always look at the mechanism itself.
Look at the movement itself.
Which way is the wave going and
why, why, why is it going in the,
the most supposedly progressive of
all the countries being America,
the most hyper aggressive about
controlling natural resources and about
innovation and have about weapons,
about weapons and about science.
And today NASA announced that
we're going to try to go to Mars,
so going to have manned missions to
Mars, a giant fucking thing, like,
like the Saturn five rocket on steroids.
They're going to send astronauts to
Mars. And you know, this keeps American.
This is one of the big
points of their point.
The keeps America in the
leader in this space race.
People are worried that we're losing the
space race because we can no longer put
people in the, the, the space station.
We have to rely on the Soviets.
And the Soviets just crashed one
of their shuttles the other day.
So now we're like, um, you guys, did
you change the oil? What are you doing?
We don't even know what they
did were hopping on their plane.
You know, that we still have space racist.
That's like the last Olympics. You know,
this is like the dumbest
thing that were in these,
the Olympics with other countries that
we got to go farther, faster first.
Yeah. But no, because it pushes innovation
and it pushes people to really, I mean,
whether or not you believe
people will end up on the moon.
I know it sounds retarded. I was 12
questions. Um, and people go, well put,
I got answers.
You know,
there's like this recent photographs
of the moon landing and everybody sends
them to me and they're like, what do
you think, man? What do you think?
And I think if I was guilty of something.
Okay,
and I sent you a picture that showed
that I wasn't guilty or something and it
was really fucking blurry and it looks
like it was taken from a million miles
away and black and white.
Would you believe me? No. Oh,
I'm sure that this is a satellite photo.
It's very likely that it is.
I leave open the possibility that it's
not and people say that's crazy and I
probably is.
Is that possibility 1% or how?
How big it?
I have no idea. Then I would know because
they look, this is what I would say.
I would say if it's 99% if there's 1%
why was that 1% therefore what the fuck
did therefore it's 99% means I really
believe it. I just see leave it open.
I don't have a percentage labeled on it.
I think the people in the 60s
and the 70s were full of shit.
I think the government was
intensely full of Shit.
I think the Nixon Nixon had
wrenched administration was
deceptive as a practice,
generally across the board,
completely full of Shit and without
accountability until they got busted in
Watergate and the shit that
went on in the Vietnam War.
How they got into the Vietnam War
from the Gulf of Tonkin incident,
which was a big fat fuck
can lie. Do you think the government
would have learned by now like, Hey,
we're getting into some harder age. Hold
on. We're not going to lie. I don't know.
I don't know
cause they still do shit that's fucked up.
Who get the Pamela smart
or not Pamela smart case.
The girl who got the girl who got rescued
in Iraq. What the fuck is her name?
The Fun on polling
anybody's names out today,
but the point was this girl with
Jessica Lynch, she was in the hospital.
They said there was a gun fight.
She was kidnapped,
they had a rescue or they're brought it
back. She was an American hero. Well,
it turns out she was not in a gun fight
at all. She was in a fucking hospital.
There was no guns fire.
They went in and got her and
they made up a god damn story.
The Pat Tillman story. Pat Tillman
died because of fucking friendly fire.
Someone made a mistake and he died, you
know? But when they put that story out,
they did not say that.
When they put that story out,
they said he died in defense of our
country. Meanwhile, Pat Tillman,
when he was over there,
was a huge,
he went from being a huge supporter of
the war to going over there and openly
criticizing and saying was a gigantic
cluster fuck of epic proportions.
And his brother's still maintains that
to this day. So they lie about shit.
They make shit up.
But I don't know whether or not
they've made up landing on the moon.
I don't know whether or not they killed
Kennedy. I don't know. I leave those open.
I leave those open because I think it's
very possible. It's, there's nothing,
there's etched in stone shit to me.
Here's something etched
in stone edged in stone.
There was a man named Kennedy shot and
cats. Right? That's actually the stone.
I don't know what the fuck
happened to him. I don't know.
It's fascinating to me the whole idea
of this bullet magically showing up on
governor Connolly's Gurney, they bring
them in. Oh, I think we found the bullet.
This bullet didn't look like he gets
shot through anything. It's ridiculous.
There's more fragments of metal supposedly
in their bodies that are missing from
this bullet. You know,
attribute that to what you will,
but the idea that you could shoot a
bullet through fucking bone and no one's
ever been able to recreate that.
They tried that in one of those fucking
shows and the only way their ability to
make it look anything
even close to that bullet,
they had to shoot it through like gelatin
that it's treated through like fake
skin that's supposed to replicate gelatin.
But as soon as you hit a
bone that's a rap song.
That bullet was warped and fucked up.
That's what happens to bill. It's man,
it's supposed to be like that.
They fragment inside your body and they
create more damage. They shatter things.
They're led with a shield
on them of of another metal,
like brass or something like that.
And when they,
depending on what you have and they
hit things, they fuck up, they bend up.
That Kennedy bullet
didn't go through shit.
They shot that thing into a fucking
fish tank. The thing we like,
it never had anything like
it hit a million pillows,
didn't look like in fucking hitting
anything hard like a bone and shattered
someone's wrist. I don't buy that for a
God damn second. And if you do buy that,
you're looking for that to be the answer.
You know?
And the only reason why they
ever even said, you know,
people dispute the positioning of the
magic bullet, the positioning look.
But you know,
Anthony Bordain had a really good point
when you talked about people that get
shot when he was on our podcast.
Talk about some people get shot and the
bullet ricochets inside their head and
exits out the back and doesn't even
do any damage. It was totally true.
Crazy things can happen when
you're shooting bullets for people.
People have been shot through the
head and nothing happens to them.
Literally shot through the fucking head.
They have a hole straight through their
head and they live and they don't have
any functioning, you know, they're,
they're allowed to walk around there.
They're fine. They can rehab.
It's amazing. Some people know,
but every time you shoot
a bullet into something,
that bullet gets fucked up every time,
every time.
And that bull,
if you look at that bullet,
it's so clear that bullet didn't hit
anything. There's no fucking way.
It went through two different people.
There's no way.
And the only reason why they even had
to say it went through to people is
because we had to attribute three bullets
to one person because they found a guy
who was under the underpass who was
hit with a ricochet. When that guy,
when it hit the curb, the ricochet
of the granite came up, hit this guy,
fucked him up. He had to go to
the hospital. What happened?
I got hit with a ricochet. They've found
the spot on the concrete or the, uh, the,
the granite,
the whatever.
There's the curbs don't where
it had been hit by the bullet.
So they knew he was telling the truth
though. Here's a bullet hole, okay?
This is where the guy got hit. So they
had to that. Now they have three wounds.
Now they have all these shots and they
don't, or two, I guess two wounds.
And they had to attribute one of them,
two to one in two different
people's bodies to the same bullet.
It's completely unscientific.
Instead of saying, what are the,
what is the possibility that even though
we caught Lee Harvey Oswald would,
if there was a guy on the roof above him,
what if there was a, is that possible?
And No, no, no, no, no. Impossible.
Is it pos? No. Nothing possible.
Let's talk to this guy and find,
oh,
this fucking mob collected guy or mob
connected guy ran up to him and shot him
in broad daylight, in the stomach, in
front of everybody and police officers.
What, what happened? What kind of
fucking charade are you running here? Oh,
the guy who killed Kennedy
is dead. Oh, well that's
convenient. There you go. Well,
let's go back to work in Vietnam and uh,
Lyndon Johnson's going to take care
of everybody. He loves you. He's a,
he's a good old boy and it's
terrible to happen that boy Kennedy.
But you know what? Sometimes those
younguns it's fucking Massachusetts boys.
They don't know how to shut the fuck up.
Yeah.
They clink whiskey glasses and they
proceed to fuck headless tie whores,
you know, come on man, those guys are
animals. Those guys are all savages.
Let me think. Brian said about
how, um, maybe now they've,
they're not doing that anymore.
I think that, oh, it's nonsense.
But I think that idea is like a prevalent
idea and it's a hilarious idea because
if you look back at every age and history,
things accelerate,
you will find that in every age there
was an idea people had about something
that was okay,
that a later age found to be
completely an absolutely rock.
Most recently segregation.
There was a time when,
I guess our grandparents,
they would really like go to use
the bathroom and they'd be like, oh,
there's the white person's bathroom.
And then they would say to
whoever was working for them,
like if they happen to take their
a black made on a shopping trip,
they'd be like, oh, there's the
colored restroom. You can go use that.
And that was normal. They didn't do
that with some sense of like, ah,
I don't know if I should
do this or not do them.
That was a normal state of existence.
If you go back a little bit before that,
there was slavery.
You would go over to your friend's house
and your friend would have a fucking
dude that he had bought.
Did I had to do everything he said
because it was as new beat it. Yeah,
he beat it. He beat a human fucking
being. That was totally normal.
And then if you go back
a little bit before that,
you would wake up in the morning and your
cow's milk would be sour and you would
go and say to your wife, I think there's
a witch nearby. And she'd be like, well,
who?
Who Do you think it is?
And you minute and you find a woman and
you'd fucking incinerator on a Goddamn
pyre that was just before slavery.
Now somehow people think that right now
we've got all figured out and there's
not something equally insane that we all
considered to be a total normal facet
of reality like all of a sudden know all
of society's totally got it figured out.
No,
we don't have it figured out.
The truth of the matter
is there is a hive mind.
People are leaders in their people who
have under who understand that in primate
neurology,
there is a way to tune in to that fucking
frequency of attention and convince
people that you're the president,
the leader, the king and the Queen,
whatever the fuck it
is you want to call it.
You can convince primates if you like,
spend the fucking spiral in
front of them in the right way.
You can convince them that you're their
leader and they'll just believe it.
Oh yeah, that's a leader. He is our
president. How? He's my president now.
Somebody saw that them. Then
I said, noodle fight. He's
my president. Fight you.
You got to respect the president.
He's our president who's our president.
Don't talk about our president that way.
Now,
this is a clearly a form of conditioning
and a form of hypnosis and what I think
that that, that's like the
final thing for us to overcome.
We got over fucking slavery,
but it's a weird thing when you're
not supposed to discuss that. No Way.
You're not supposed to.
It's got to be current guitar.
You're an intelligent person.
If you're an intelligent person,
he respected person.
You go on television and say their
president should be respected no more than
any other men.
Ooh.
You Know Matt people, people, if
you want to see the conditioning,
when you watch somebody burner,
watch someone burn a flag in
front of the wrong person. Yeah,
people will freak out.
You want to see the conditioning fucking
burn a hundred dollar bill in front of
people. No, not the patient.
There was a story,
a new story about a dude who was in front
of a Mexican restaurant and he was a
Vietnam vet and he was angry because the
Mexican restaurant was flying a Mexican
flag above and American flag,
whatever.
Apparently this dude said
that that was not legal.
So he goes there with a fucking knife,
opens up this giant knife and saws the
rope on this guy's flag in front of this
man's Mexican restaurant.
Good man,
holds the flags down
and cuts old glory free,
folds it up properly and takes
it with them. And he's like,
you will not disrespect this flag. And
he's like, he clearly states somewhere,
I don't know where it is.
Some old asshole who's dead as fuck
wrote down on some piece of paper
or the old glory. Most be on top.
This is the appropriate late of food.
America can never be, you know,
[inaudible] never be humble.
You can't be like the third flag.
Yeah. You know, really cool to bat.
You want to be on top, be on top
Tibet. Who wants to be honest?
But in the middle of Ireland,
you wanna be in the middle. Okay,
we'll just be on the bottom.
It's cool who
we are. America, that's what
I'm talking about there Jo.
I'm talking about this make this game of
make believe that we're being forced to
play.
And it seems like the tea party represents
the people who most want to hold on
to this silly game of make believe.
And it's like, you know, I, I,
I love this country and the sense that
I love the geography of the place I'm
living in.
I love the cultures here and the people
I've met and I really love like a lot of
the ways in our culture that um,
free dialogue can spring up
and all the amazing things.
But why are you forcing
me to then take that,
that love or a sense of like belonging
here and put it on a God damn symbol?
Why are you making me put
that on a fucking flag or
on whatever the silly thing
is that you're turning into an idol?
I don't want to do that any more and
more as we get smarter. I think as a,
as a species, that kind of stuff is
becoming less and less palatable.
And, and, uh, because now when
we're engaged in these ceremonies,
most of us are thinking like,
you know,
the pledge of allegiance or
whatever at a baseball game.
I don't even know they do that. A baseball
game, I think, I'm not saying everyone,
but I think there is a
percentage of people in the
audience who are doing it out
of just a sense of like, oh, it's kind of
quaint. I'm going to do it. This is weird,
but you want me to put my
hand on my chest? You so okay.
It was just one of those same reasons
why a lot of people want to be Christians
and tell you they're Christians because
it automatically carries with it a
certain amount of respect. And you know,
if you say to me, you know, you know,
where do you stand with politics?
You know how you feel I'm
fucking patriot Patriot Bro.
I fucking believe in this country.
I'm a patriot.
And all of sudden like Dang
guy is not to be questioned.
You know what I'm saying? Right?
You mean like that guy has a,
there's a certain amount
of respect for you,
you're going to get from
me for being a patriot.
Well,
no,
because I believe in the system and this
president was elected and because this
president was elected than everything,
and I just have to go with
what's happening and this
I trust my government now.
This is a,
this is the silliest fucking place
to have tea for your mind to get to.
When you really look back at the fact
that this very same government with the
same government that enforced segregation,
it was the same government that illegal.
You went to war in Vietnam.
It was the same government that told
us that there was weapons of mass
destruction in Iraq when there were
no weapons of mass destruction.
This very same government that you've
pledged your allegiance to again and again
and again and again and again and again
and again and again throughout history
has shown that it does
not do the right thing.
He consistently does shitty things.
Slavery,
segregation, now it war, war now, bombs.
Now it will repair
itself from time to time.
And what's really beautiful
is the promise of democracy,
the promise of democracy or are a truly,
I guess what a representative government,
a truly representative government
is fucking beautiful. Jesus Christ.
That's like pure evolution. Okay. A purely
representative government
have an educated population,
a truly educated, not just educated
with books and number or you know,
numbers and words but educated as far as
behavior educated as far as character.
There's too many of us to get that done.
There's not enough insight.
I know that that the,
that we are right now,
the idea is that there's too many of
us and I think that's what this whole,
I'm a patriot. I'm a Christian. This
is a reason. No, no, no, no, no, no.
There's a million good things Brian up
anti just what I'm saying. The, the, the,
the idea is that being a Christian
saying you're a patriots hearing you are,
you are trying to hold some higher ideal
that you would really like other people
to do as well.
And if they do do it,
you know you're going to treat them
better and everyone's going to have more
energy together. So this is
like, you know, they're trying,
it's like when people say like, I'm, I'm
a Christian. I'm a, I'm a Christian too.
Even though a lot of them don't
do anything Christian, you know,
the first thing they want to do
is fucking shoot the enemy. Yeah.
Jesus has turned the other cheek.
The last thing you want to do is go
and fucking say, I'm a Christian.
I'm here to fuck people up. Yeah. You
can't say that, man. It's like they're,
they're, they're saying it because
there is this urge to do it.
Yeah. It's fun to imagine Jesus
flying the Enola Gay. Like imagine
fucking beard.
He's got his toe gone or whatever the
thing is he's wearing and he's flying that
fucking Enola gay did drop a nuclear
weapon on a population of children and
women and boyfriends and girlfriends
and artists that Jesus is like,
I must do this from my father.
Of course not.
Well, I had to get that out,
but what did you mean Brian?
Like what were you saying?
No, I mean it's just like you're
saying about how bad the government is,
how many bad things they've
done, you know, in the past.
But everyone never looks at the good shit,
you know?
And no one's ever looking at
all the good shit they do.
I don't think that's going
to tell him the bad stuff.
I don't think that's necessarily
the Grand Canyon. It's bad ass.
Did you ever read watership
down? Government didn't
make the grand canyon, Bro.
He's a fucking buster bubble. Hey, will
you do me a favor of, no, we're not
plus to play music,
but there's a song that we have to play.
We have to play because I really liked
the song and it's a super appropriate and
we'll just talk over it.
Okay. We're not like selling,
it's Aaron Lewis country boy. You
know the dude from stained. Okay,
well he's reinvented himself as a
country music singer and yes, yes,
yes. I want you to you because it's
important. It's really important.
It's really important for two reasons.
One, because I honestly like the song.
I liked the song a lot. I really
do. It's a fucking good song.
Guys got a great voice. I loved him and
that, that band stained and he, yeah,
I think he's a bad motherfucker. He's,
he's got a great voice and a apparel.
It's just so fascinating because
it's super, super patriotic song.
Cause here it and it's, it's,
it's, it's so patriotic.
It's like almost like a parody tone
from the beginning. From the beginning.
Hit it from the beginning. Here we go.
Ready? It's about being a country boy
that's here. We never play
songs anymore, but fuck it man.
I love this song.
No dirt around it.
How do you know? Do the
listen, how good his voice.
It was probably 1500 bucks back in nine.
Man. I don't like sounding
like a home. I'll put down,
motherfuckers got a bad ass voice.
He could talk to me to bed at night
with that voice. You're alone.
Listen to this
change of a man.
I don't know what is changing.
Vh One gray. This is a
great fucking song. Dude.
Rarely drink from the bottle,
but I'll smoke Gulen
concept. He's onsite, man. He has
don't tread on me. Tattooed on his neck
tense. That's a tense right across
his neck. It says, don't tread on me,
and this song is talking about how he
never leaves his house without his nine or
is 45 it's like of gangster rap.
It's tried to know the words
that come out. La Concha,
he sold his soul to the devil in La.
This is talking about women's
in that other band winger. Yeah.
It's the saying, the devil hooked him
up in La with a, like a regular guy.
You ever see spinal tap?
He's like,
what he's doing is he's making up for
his time as a Rockstar, a spinal tap.
When they sit like there's a great thing
where it shows all the pictures of the
band and they tried every demographic.
They kept changing demographics according
to what was popular and to like.
He's just swapped demographics
like, yeah, you've got race entries.
Publicist was like, hey listen. I
think, I think the country markets,
he's trying to be legit, just like a
gangster rappers trying to be legitimate.
In the video. There's a picture
of him like get to holding a gun.
He's two and he's got a gun in his hand.
I am not bullshitting.
He says me age too.
He's holding a gun and there's another
picture where he's got a large mouth bass.
See I used a fish, you know, so
it's like all these pictures of him,
but all that shit is like so manipulative
and silly and that whole thing, man,
it gets way better.
I grew up on a country place.
You never know the last few seconds of it.
I'll tell you Brian,
exactly where to go because it's so
ridiculous. It was one of my, it's, it's,
it's just really interesting cause
you know there's a miss hands. No,
and it's way worst and Mr. Quota,
four minutes and 14 seconds.
Go do at a four minutes and 14 seconds.
We'll just end this because
it's fascinating. By the way,
I'm not dissing this guy at all and
I fucking love this music and I love,
I love his song and I love that kind of
music. I like a lot of Toby Keith Song.
I don't have anything wrong.
A patriotic songs
at the end of it.
Listen to sky does this little speech,
and this is like this old old dude.
It's like, I love my country. I
love my guns, I love my family.
I love the way it is now.
And anybody that tried to change
it has to come through me.
I should be on our head.
Jeez, it's, this is America and
a country boy was good enough.
Okay,
play that back again because that
might be a terrorist message. Okay.
That re retarded. Fucking
speech. Back it up, right?
Listen, listen, this
is that. A bag. Listen, I love
my country. I love my guns.
I love my family.
I love the way it is now.
And anybody that tried to change
it has to come through me.
That's a music or attitude that
should be all of our answers.
This is America and a cargo
is good enough for me.
Country boy is good enough for me.
Like we are as evolved as I need.
Let's stop right here.
And he sadly,
if you can listen to a cancer cell,
just so fucking stupid.
It's like a Loma guns. Oh,
that's you. Oh, I love my
country. I love my guns. Oh,
do just hurry up and die
when you fucking hurry up,
you got he fucking modeled t human being.
You dip shit.
Just die. A family a more
guns. Brow trash picked those.
They'll come to me. Okay, look, I'm not
saying I want to take your guns, dude.
I don't want to. I like guns too.
I love my family too. All right.
Settle the fuck down. Every time it
hits price. Every time in history,
no one's coming through you bro.
But every period in history,
he's got those human anchors desperately
trying to dig their claws into that
fucking into the earth and keep
evolution from happening. Desperately.
Fight. They'll kill for it. They'll kill
for it. What do you mean? Wait a minute.
You can't be serious. Do you? Everyone
gathered around. Did you hear Galileo?
Did you hear what Galileo just said?
Father,
he said that heard he speak not being,
I love my earth in the
center of the universe.
Earth sticks and bows and arrows.
I love, I love Burt's ears.
Muscling.
I love my slave Vernon,
which is trying to take my catapult
away. I'll come to me. I love my scroll.
I love my car. I love carving
and rock. I'll love walking.
I don't need to run any horses. I need
domesticated animals. That's complicated.
But who wants to domesticate
horse has got to come through me.
I love being a hunter gatherer.
I love having a lifespan
in a single cell organism.
We're all having a good time down here
at the bottom of the ocean floor and
anybody who wants to change,
that's got to come through me.
I love being a carbon molecule.
I love exists in the pre
big bang conditions. Hello,
11 protons.
Anybody wants change that
as I opened up the second bottle of wine,
it's always,
yeah, I have a question about it.
When you're a beautiful song, man,
the guy's just sing his fucking ass
off. I'm sorry, I'm not denying it.
I'm buying that shit on iTunes
right now cause I made funny bro.
I love that song. No bullshit. I
love and he's a Massachusetts boards.
Just like me. When you first, when you
first talked about the horse pumping,
how many dirt roads or in
Massachusetts you called it Mr Hand.
Just because you saw the file name Mr
has done mpeg. Now was that his name?
His name. The guy who got
fucked to death was Mr hands.
If you don't know what the
story we're talking about,
we're talking about a real true story
about a gentleman in Seattle, I believe.
I believe he was an engineer,
but he was a professional and he had this
crazy fetish for sex with animals and
wind up getting killed. And there's a
video of him getting fucked by a horse.
And the video's Mr [inaudible]. Dot.
Amp Peg and you can get it at two guys,
one horse.com and then if you're new
to the internet or you don't have any
fucked up friends like me, you probably,
you might not have ever even seen this.
It don't. You're right, John, do it.
It's not worth it. So we do that to you.
So crazy.
Watch a guy get fucked by a horse.
They were talking about Mr Hands Today.
I worked on this horror movie,
there's low budget horror movie and
they're all talking about Mr hand.
They're all calling it,
you know,
like you know that and Mr
hands died mpeg or whatever.
And then they were saying that there's a
Mrs hands and really Oh yeah mrs his is
even worse.
Cause he described it where it was the
woman's face is off the side of the thing
and the horse,
it was just fucking come and say it pulls
out and just floppy Dick and calm and
everything. And the girl at one point is
Glenn. Oh yeah. You know like it changes.
That's old. That's not actually
misses hands. They just called it.
It's a marketing. Yeah. There was
a dude named Billy Billy Connolly.
I fucking wash it over his house while
someone's stood guard over the front door.
We were in the basement and what one of
us had to stand guard by the front door
that were in the basement that would
go up the stairs and stand by the door.
And if you hear my fucking
mom better say something.
This is Billy saying cause it's apparently
maybe his mom either caught him with
it or didn't know he had it.
But there was some issue cause it was,
it was called barnyard better. Yes. Vhs.
And then you could barely see
what the fuck was going on.
It was really shitty quality.
But that's one of the scenes.
The horse shoots a load all over her and
she makes these moans like Oh yeah and
it's so disturbing.
It was like almost like I got
molested that day because the, the,
the day is literally like broken up
in my memory with these jolting one,
the standout memories.
Like you know how you scroll through your
icons if you're a a Mac and you scroll
through and then they get larger
when your cursor goes over the thing.
Like that's what those memories are.
And it's like,
like the whole day is like a normal day.
No memory of the day at all.
So growing up fuck by a horse
and Billy Connolly's basement,
I gotta tell you something,
man,
I don't think there is a comparison
between a girl getting hoarse, calm,
blasted all over.
And a guy getting impaled to
death on the penis of a horse.
Those are two different things.
We didn't have died from getting fucked
by horses. Many people have got it. Sam,
this woman who was a some,
God damn. Who the hell was
queen there? My memory sucks. I've
worked all day today in the son.
Tell him doing something that I goddamn
wish I could tell you folks about.
I can't tell you. I can't tell
you a damn word, but oh my God,
I can't wait to talk about this once.
It actually happens.
You can tell you what
happened. I did today. This,
this a standard insurance
going to be just as awesome.
There's this girl named
standard divas and the baby me,
she played like this monster,
like a carry monster.
That's a real name or real name is Sandra.
Yeah,
that's like a famous name or Larson
in Greece and don't actors slash act.
Oh, she's waiting on their real
name, but she's a bigger one.
She's an adult and it was 100,000 wait,
her friends over 100,000 to fund the
bigger one. Let me check her out.
And she has a British accent.
Fucking hot as balls.
What is her Twitter Standard d back?
Just Sandra Dee with a d or d.
E. E. So anyways,
this maybe she kills me in it spoiler,
but uh,
she's like sitting right over me like
at one point and I die from her period
blood. First of all, you just fucked up
some poor girl named Sandra Dee. Hello.
I only have 17 followers
for Sandra.
Dee said it's sitting in front of her
ATS living in northern Michigan is going
to get bombed on by the savages that
listen to this podcast. What is it?
It's Sandra are some regular girl and
I'm Sandy Butler. Hi Sandy. Sorry.
Sorry to bother you.
I felt like,
I feel like we accidentally called you
and how your acid, I feel like he got,
please be nice to her folks.
Please.
She seems like a nice
girl with a love of Atvs.
There's a photo of her with the ATV
here and she's smiling like, really?
You want me to take a picture right here
randomly getting attacked by killer bees.
It's somebody does walk her Twitter
just got mobbed or Twitter just got
assaulted by savages.
Do you know how fucking trippy it's going
to be for her to open up her Twitter
tomorrow morning and look at 5,000
responses out of nowhere. Like what?
Huh? Yeah. Sorry.
Sophie D as You o.
P. H. E. D. E.
I posted a bunch of photos of me
today and I feel so bad on my Twitter.
If someone's,
I'm going to follow you sandy.
If someone's mean to correct
everything I'm following, you know,
Sandy's so anyways, she, there's
one point where she's like,
she's had one foot on each side of me.
Completely naked. Princeton bloods,
Sophie D as You're in a movie with
this check. Yeah. Sop Is Hie d.
He has this like one of those,
it's like evil dead movie,
like really low budget horror
movie. Ridiculous. Oh really low.
Like really cool blood
like crazy blood effects.
But uh, yeah, it's just a
fun little what happened?
You're hanging out with this, this dirty
hot check. This girl looks so dirty too.
Oh my Lord.
Pictures of her and bikinis.
Shay's us file decry anxious tense
I've ever can trust with Don Duncan.
Trussell look at this picture.
I don't need to.
We'll do this podcast and we can't
you folks at home can't see this,
but we're kind of drunk right now.
It's ridiculous to imagine the incredible
puller heals those tits look real.
They real. I thought they
looked real though, I think
are, they're huge. And Look,
look, if you look at them now, they
can't be real. You know what I think?
I think she's one of those crazy bitches
that Hedwig real tits and then got a
bigger look at that. They're naked on my
Twitter. Look at backslash red band. Oh,
I see what you did.
You Fuck?
That's [inaudible] Twitter. You
don't even do you. Yeah, I do.
I hope the hackers,
the hackers on everyone.
I see no pictures of this pitch, Bro.
Like I keep looking. Keep looking. Yeah,
you fucking asshole. He just fucking
tricked me man. Kind of photos on it.
It wears. Speaking of photos,
I heard I heard or heard
the little Hobo game.
Yeah, little hobos back, but he's smaller.
I ordered the wrong God damn size.
I think it's funnier.
Could he tell the story? Dude? How
big is it? How big is a little Hobo?
I don't know. He's like this big and
that's even better. It might be better.
First of all,
it's easy to carry him and second of all
it's even creepier than a tiny little
dog is going to kill you if you
want to do it in New Orleans,
but I don't think it'll work on fuck it.
It's not going to work. You must do it.
It's too small. It's like
a tiny little dog. Oh,
that's the picture of what's
going to the head. It's pretty
funny and the whole time I'm
laying there while she's up at me,
I'm just looking up her pussy.
How I'm sure fucking made.
Her eyes are like look like scary
monster liquor. Just still blue.
They're the most beautiful geysers
keep talking.
I'm saying you notify,
but she's married to a black
wasn't as long as what?
A black, white and that's K and she's
married to another porn star. Oh,
how's that work there? They allowed the
only bank people on camera. This is,
we had Dana DRM on. Don
wants, it was very cool check,
but she was talking about her
relationship relationship.
She was in ones where she had a,
a relationship with a porn star,
but they were only allowed to bank other
people in movies and she caught him bag
at other people outside of the
movies and she was mad. How dare you,
we do a bench. I'm Morgan. I'd
be working all day. That was,
that was like a total loophole in
marriages. Every man would be a porn star.
We'd all be like, I got to, I'm like, I'm
still, I said, how many times are tough?
Okay, it's a bad economy. I'm going
to pick up a little money on the side.
Fucking checks on film.
Yeah, man. It's still embarrassed.
I mean that's one of the other things
about being human. It's like, you know,
you're just trapped in these fucking
awful primate monogamy patterns and it's
just like embarrassing.
You get jealous or weird and
all that shit's embarrassing.
It's like the whole situation,
like we're still stuck in this really
primitive way of living and we can't get
out of it.
That's what it is,
is we're becoming aware that it's silly.
Whereas for the majority of existence,
it was just accepted and
it wasn't what it was.
And it was what made you feel good?
What makes you feel good to conquer
your enemy? You know, it's like Conan,
what does best in life? What is
that, uh, to crush your enemies,
to see them driven before you and they
hear the laminations of the women. I know.
And he had this, uh, you know, and I
mean, but that's what it was, man, man,
fucking ancient Sumeria or some area,
whatever the fuck you was from.
That's what it was about. Right. You know,
and that's, that's whatever supposedly,
you know, it's a fake world, but we're,
we're thinking he lived 6,000 years ago,
7,000 years ago that some people did.
And then there was,
it wasn't a lot going on. I like the
first two, but the third, it's like,
I don't want to hear it. All the commands.
I don't want to hear the limitations.
I don't mind like crushing
when you hear them go
laminations screaming because you're
fucking getting raped by his limitations
cause he, you know, he
says it wasn't like he,
it's a word that I've never
used ever. Yeah. It's moaning,
screaming cause you use this word
by the way, you're a douchebag.
Mentations use that word.
That word.
You should hear my wife laminating now.
Is it limitating oh,
there's some weird thing about
the Jewish Prophet Jeremiah.
Are you sure this is the same
thing? Pretty sure. What definition?
Isn't it like a nurse or
I went to with a Bible.
Hmm. The act of laminating and that's
the worst definition. Pressure. Sorrow.
A cry of sorrow or grief and lemon.
Asians as the women are crying until,
until you start because they're getting
raped. No, no. The men are getting killed.
The Cross.
Do you see them?
The Mongols and the Mongols would
fucking ride in and it was just,
you would sack a village and
then you would rape the women.
Are you saying that Conan was
based on the Mongols? I think so.
I think they drew a lot from it. Cause
this was day bro. It's Robert, he Howard,
he didn't know about her book and I know
he committed suicide and I used to have
the fucking poem he wrote when he got
suicide. He's to have it memorized.
I can't remember it now.
Yeah.
Did you ever read any of the old
Conan's fuck yeah dude. Fuck yes.
Things got me through a depressing
high school. Yeah, I love,
I'm so bummed that apparently the new
movie sucks cause I was like really
looking forward to, I really wanted
to see it. I love those dudes.
Well I met the guard too. He came
to the UFC once and he was, uh,
I was Kinda glad that I didn't get a half
to interview him cause he was kind of
going crazy and I don't know
how I would've reacted to it.
It was not going crazy in the bathroom.
It was all psych because Chris leaving
wall and he's all pumped up and
everything. The Goldberg is like, you
know, Mister professional well all.
Tell us about this movie Conan.
You know, Goldberg is like,
he's like a super professional
play by play broadcaster guys,
so he can interview somebody
if he knew nothing about them.
When I interview somebody, if I know
nothing about them, I feel weird. Right?
But this guy is the perfect Conan.
You know people are giving him shit
because they don't like the fact that he's
pretty,
they don't like people don't like fucking
six foot four beautiful man sculpted
bodies and game of Thrones, right? Yeah.
He's great and fucking game of
Thrones and he have been good.
This movie is a piece of shit. He's a
good culture and he, there's, there's,
there's scenes where he's fighting as
Conan that are bad fucking ass. There was,
he's fighting with these things that
are made out of sand and he's like sand
monsters and the way he moves
around, I'm like this, you nailed it.
That's Robert Howard's Kona. That's
it. This guy just needs like he needs,
first of all, you need a singular vision.
You need a guy who's a brilliant writer,
who's a Robert Howard fan. Go
for it. Create the whole thing.
But there's scenes where it's just like
so preposterous. They were so dumb.
This the final scene with him and his
antagonist is like one of the dumbest
scenes in any action movie ever.
It's almost like they slapped it together
in 10 minutes and filmed it with an
iPhone.
It's so why do they do that?
Because there's a bunch of people that
want to get their fucking greedy little
pause on things.
There's a bunch of different producers,
a bunch of different executives,
a bunch of different people,
and they all have their own vision
of how it should work. This guy,
Jason Momoa is an unknown actor,
fairly unknown.
At least carry such a gigantic franchise.
It's a $90 million fund
vestments for the studio and all these
assholes want to stick their dirty
fingers in it and I've seen it, man. I
watched in a fucking movie contagion.
There was a movie I did
called Frank mccloskey.
CII and I have talked about it once
before that I did this movie and I watched
this kid who was a really funny
kid. Frank, I should say his name.
It's Dave something. Frank McCluskey. See,
let me look it up just
to give this kid props.
He was a fucking really funny
comedian man. He's like,
I was watching them,
Dave Sheridan,
I was watching him like his adlibs. I
was watching his, the way he performs,
he was like really over the
top almost Jim Carrey in uh,
ace Ventura ash.
Right.
And there was a guy who was on the
set who was an executive and um,
I don't know what production
company film that.
I was barely paying attention
to any of that shit back then.
But this guy had the Rolex on and a
super expensive suit with suspenders and
cufflinks. I mean this is a
fucking, this was a baller.
This was some guy who
had made a bunch of big,
big movies already and made a ton of money
and was dressing on this movie set in
a way that I'd really never seen
anybody addressing the movie.
Said it was to me it was ridiculous.
And he's wearing this ridiculous,
it was so obvious.
He had a ton of money and he was
giving this kid line readings.
This kid was doing his scene and the
kid would do the scene and he would go,
okay, okay, okay. Instead
of that, how about this?
But you walk in,
you step one foot on the floor,
your throw your legs up in the,
he, he, he made it himself.
He did his own little interpretation of
what he thought would be awesome and the
scene. And I was like, God
damn here is ego one, a mock,
some completely uncreative
fuck head wearing.
Cufflinks is telling this
really funny kid. What,
what to do. And I was watching
it a road right before my eyes.
I was watching what was like a really
funny script and it really zany kind of
silly actor. I was like,
oh, it's kind of fun.
And I watched them poison it or watched
them like stick their dirty fingers.
And that's what Conan's smelled like.
Conan smelled like one guy thought we
could do it right and we could recreate
robbery, Howard's version of
Conan and we could have, you know,
fucking monsters and sorcery and all
kinds of crazy shit that he fights again.
We could do this. This could be fucking
wild and studio is like, we're in.
We got chasing Mamoa from the game of
Thrones. Look at him. He's six foot five.
He's a fucking male model. He's built like
Hercules. This guy's Conan. He is Kona.
I want you to meet him. I am Kona. He's
fucking Conan. They get all fired up.
They do lines and then they
start rewriting the script.
The executive say they like,
these guys don't fucking movies
like I know fucking movies.
I produced 25 fucking movies and they
start getting their dirty little stinky,
TJ's covered paws all over that script
and they start fucking drop and rocks out
of the fucking
nose on key words that they blow it.
But that's when,
when people,
or not to get back to the idea where
it's totally different scenarios.
This is just for entertainment
purposes folks. Please also mean
I enjoyed the thing we were talking
about at the beginning about, you know,
when people are used to free
entertainment, you know,
they want it to stay free.
And you know,
a lot of people when they watch NBC
or ABC or CBS or any of these shows,
they think they're getting
free entertainment,
but they're not getting free
entertainment. They're getting,
they're paying with their attention on
the advertisements, but more than that,
they're paying in the form of
getting diluted entertainment.
They're getting shit. It's got, it's
that thing that you just described.
Every show on a network has had almost
every show has had that exact same thing
applied to it and so many different ways
because the executives want to sell and
a depressants or they want to sell
Chevrolets or whatever the fuck they're
advertising on the show.
So you,
have you ever had this experience
personally where shit got diluted.
My one experience with a show that
didn't get picked up by comedy central,
weirdly, because I was prepared for
this. I was like, they're going,
they're going to comedy central.
Ruined my vision and not the first round.
And notes that came back was awesome.
It was great notes. Really smart.
It was like, it made the,
the, the notes made sense.
There wasn't any kind of weird
like, Oh yes, wait, no, no,
no. I did have it happen.
I did have it happen when I made some
stuff for fuel TV for this show called
stupid face. And uh, uh, that,
that's where we made our
galaxy cabin log cabin.
And Jodie is living in someone's,
yeah,
please explain how ridiculous it is.
What it was Julie Diaz doing well,
this lead of fishermen.
Well, the story was about,
I played at mountain man and my friend
Brian Jarvis played a space captain and
something had happened where he'd gotten
sucked into a black hole and a flood.
It sucked my cabin to a
black hole at the same time.
And now we fly through space in
this cabin and we're just idiots.
And like it is the stupidest, I wish
we'd had a bigger budget though magazine.
It's such a funny idea. So stupid.
I wish to give us more money.
I know cause we had no budget for the
thing. We had like a green screen.
So Joey Diaz is episode was
we're like in the cabin and um,
my grandfather comes like knocks on the
door of the cabin and space and I'm like,
granddaddy, I thought you
were dead. And he's like,
Bree wants might the space
commanders ring. He's like,
let me see your friends ring there.
And my friends like,
I'm not sure this is your grandfather red.
And then basically it was
an alien living in the neck,
my dead grandfather and alien living in
the neck and that was showing him and he
was called the fishermen and he was in
a rain slicker and it was small bodies
floating on a canoe.
Joey Diaz nailed is,
have you ever had children and you and
your wife were getting divorced? She would
bring that fucking
video to add to a court,
say this is the kind of
shit I got to deal with.
If you know, that's another thing
to fight for the kids. No, you win.
You get the kids,
you can keep them.
Oh well you don't want him.
And once you become attached to the kids,
if your wife is crazy,
he comes a real issue with people.
Or if you feel like your wife is going
to lie and turn your kids on you,
that's what a lot of men think.
A lot of men are worried.
I wonder why they think
that. Well, listen man,
when someone fucking hates you and
they talk shit about you all day,
that's a terrible thing. If you
go over as a nurse, you know your,
your mom's house,
your mom is just constantly talking Shit
about your dad and you go to your Dad's
house, your dad's constantly talking shit
about your mom. It's like Jesus Christ.
How the fuck am I ever going to have
a normal relationship at five you dumb
cunts.
Yeah.
Fuck heads don't even know how to get
along civilly outside of your fuck time.
You know you stop fucking and now
you hate each other. You have kids,
you don't want to be together.
Get, get, grow bro. The fuck
up. You got a kid dummy.
Yeah. Well, you know, man,
the the problem, the thing
about that Shit, man, is that,
well, the thing I'm realizing is there
as a fucking shitty network executive in
everyone's life are most people's lives.
It's like that shit doesn't
just stop at the network.
Nah, dude. Most people have
bosses. These are way, way, way,
way worse and shitty network executives
because if even if you've got a shitty
network executive, you're on fucking TV
too. All right. You got a television show.
You're doing something wild and crazy
that very few people ever get to do. Yeah.
I've dealt with network executives when
we did the man show, we got fucked.
Doug and I both get fucked.
It was a disaster and I watched
other people get fucked.
When I was doing news radio,
I watched the influence I've seen.
I've seen things that could
have been really good,
get fucked with combat or when people
don't believe in things because the
ratings are not good. All of a
sudden they want to bring in people.
They want to bring in man and bring in
women and hot chicks and we're going to
mix this up in a network,
has all their nutty fucking ideas.
How to tune things up and make
them more exciting. It's gross.
It's annoying as fuck,
man.
What they're supposed to do is promote
the shit out of the show and if it's not
good, if it doesn't get good ratings,
just cancel that piece of shit. Sell it,
don't smell it.
Don't.
What you don't want to do is get a bunch
of network executives who are generally
or uncreative people influencing creative
piece. Sure. W the creative people,
either they do it or they don't do it.
Either it works or it doesn't work.
That's what I take.
But wouldn't do an executive start
digging in.
Very few know what they're doing.
It's very few. Very few
know creatively. Yeah, it's,
it's like like the time when we are
doing stupid face that the guy we,
oh, here's the weird thing
that executive are like,
there are two guys here are
these skateboarders named
Ted and Laban or the main
producers and they're awesome. Just
crazy. Awesome, brilliant guys.
Then above them was this guy did,
they had to pass everything through and
he would give the most random shitty
notes about stuff that you would do.
And I was like notes that were impossible
to do it to address, you know, like
not specific notes like I'm
trying to think of like, so
we know like to on notes,
like, you know, this was good,
but it would be better if we
could make it more laughy. Whoa.
You know what I mean? Like kind of
ambiguous notes were like, well what?
How do I make something black coffee
or more like, you know what I mean?
There's like, do you mean fun z? What,
what are your specific problems with it?
But that was the one experience
I had with that. But,
but I have obviously heard shitloads
of people having these problems.
It's kind of like remembering, you
weren't when you were in reading class,
when you're learning to read as a kid
and you'd sit in a circle and you'd read.
Yeah. And there was always that kid
who slowed the whole thing down.
It would get to that one kid
who's like there is right.
You know, and you knew how to read. You
are, you know, you can read pretty fast,
but the whole fucking thing,
lunch was being fucking push back.
Cause this one thing when the same way
those people insert themselves into power
positions,
right.
And they'll put themselves into like
creative power positions or they're
everywhere. They're in fee even affected
everything. But now they have power.
Imagine if the kid got his,
let me tell you something that's an,
that's an unrealistic characterization
because it's very fucking difficult to
become a neck network
executive. Right? Most of them.
No, I don't mean that kitty. We
know. I don't mean they can't read.
I mean there are like that for creativity.
I'm saying their skill
level for creativity.
The same as the kid who
can't read or write.
But I thought you were talking
about those people. No, no.
Hopefully those people learn to read
z Z.
I think it's an ego thing entirely.
I think they become successful and
successful people think they're good at
everything.
That's why people who were successful
at one thing don't like learning other
things.
You know,
one of the biggest problems in mixed
martial arts fighters is people who have a
specialty and don't want to learn
another specialty. You become, yeah,
they become very,
very one dimensional.
There's a lot of fighters like that
where they're really good kickboxers and
they never learned how to wrestle or do
Jiu Jitsu. Good. Yeah, no, it's terrible.
It's terrible for them. And the problem
is they're not willing to be a novice.
There's so good at that one thing that
that's the thing they want to train all
the time because they're so good.
Yeah.
But whenever you see how he's just someone
just showing me this website for this
actress and it's her resume
and it's like director, actor,
producer,
writer.
There was like seven things that
she said she was and it was like,
Oh God could give me a fucking break.
And then like that she had quotes,
you know,
like referenced to it of Healer.
That shit. Yeah. It's like, you know,
when you in spiritual guy and some
people do it, some people do it,
some people like we'll have like nine
things going at once. But I always,
there's something I respect and people
who are just focused on this one thing,
like just start, there are
a writer. That's what they
do, right? They just, right.
I think that's cool. Well, it'd
be in a comic, you know, I
mean, I do a lot of other
shit besides comedy. Like, uh,
I do the UFC and,
and do other things.
So what I've managed to do is be
professional, a professional. Me, I'm,
I'm me professionally.
So that's, that's what,
and so I put me in certain situations,
I put me in a situation where there's
some fights going on and have to explain
what's on in a way
that people are gonna think it's
entertaining and ingest that.
And then there's other me where I'm
going on a stage in front of a bunch of
people and I,
I,
I'm going to say things in a certain
way that's gonna make them laugh.
Or I'm me and I'm talking on the Internet.
And the podcast, you know, or um,
me and getting people to do
something fucked up on fear factor.
I just, I'm a professional
meet. What's that?
Talk about that thing. Oh yeah. I wish
I could too, but I cannot sir. Yes.
Photos or something you can't talk about
on his phone will be able to talk about
it eventually. It's, it's insane.
Oh, it's terrible. It's terrible.
It's amazing.
The difference between 2002 fear factor
in 2011 fear factor. It's just like,
Oh yes. That's exactly what
happened. The Internet,
no question about it has changed our,
our line in the sand.
It reminds me of when rap turned in to
gangster rap. Remember that transition?
This is way crazier than that dude.
I mean hip hop,
but to the hippity hip hop too,
like some Nwa or something like
that's terrible. Yeah, exactly.
It's terrible. It is. By the way,
when I was, when you were taught,
just talking about it is always
drinking the coconut water. I gagged.
I'm immune. I was right there.
And not only was I right there,
I was right there while there
was people vomiting and nothing.
I'm immune to vomit.
It's crazy man.
My little baby threw up in the bed the
other night and uh, you know, it's sad.
You know,
she was okay.
She just sometimes kids that cough while
they have food in their mouth and he'd
just throw out all the fuck.
Yeah.
But cats are gross to throw up so much
because they lift their hair, man,
the lick,
their own hair.
That's one reason they either
they have to throw up those,
those hairballs and
sometimes they get food.
She throws up every three times a week,
three, four times a week. My female,
my mail doesn't throw up.
And you know what else I've done.
I started bringing them to the groomer,
which is great for them cause it's
hot as fuck out here in California.
And so I don't let him out. I do let
him out in the courtyard sometimes,
but outdoor cats,
I believe that cats should be free.
And I've had outdoor cats in my life and
I believe that's the best way for cats,
but I'm terrified of that fucking toxo
plasma shit. You know? You can say that.
That's ridiculous, but if you, if you
read about it, I might have it to him.
You got to talk to me. A microphone,
homeboy. You got to talk.
Anybody 100% serious
that I will take a test.
We should all take a to put your
headphones on. You think you have it? No,
I don't think I have it, but I think
we definitely need to take a text.
I think we should do it on the show.
Yeah, you're right. I think Joey Diaz,
how's it by the way? You can. You
can have it and be a healthy version.
It just affects your judgment
apparently or has a effect. Look,
if you're slightly cranky, that also
affects your judgment. You know,
there's a lot of things that affect your
judgment if you haven't gotten enough
sleep. If you're in a bad relationship,
there's things that affect your judge.
I know I've got it. I fucking change so
many bags of cat litter. When I was like,
breathing in that shit is probably
not to worry because it's not. I worry
because I've had feral cats. I had,
wow. I did too. I captured six kittens,
brought him back to my apartment. Oh,
we both have feral kittens.
I'm festering.
Came around by their neck on by
your mouth. I caught him in a box.
I caught him in a box and a construction
site and they were assholes. Man.
I wish I'd never done it.
Well, they're scared of people, but
they will bond to one person and really,
really be attached to my account
was super attached to me,
but terrified of everybody else.
Ma'Am
have cats. What? Why?
Because I was an idiot. You've got to
have a lot of responsibility. Yeah.
Pet cats are like, hey, it's
easier than a fucking Hams.
People don't understand
more responsibility than a
plant. Yes. And, and also,
and also depending on your conditioning,
some people,
some people raise other people to think
that cats are like one step above like a
steak. Like people don't, a lot of people
don't, they don't have animal empathy,
so they're really shitty
with their animals.
Like when you drive by someone's
porch and they've got a dog.
I'm like a tiny little chain
and I think that's normal.
People think that's normal or people
only like walk their dogs for or do dogs
who don't have a backyard.
People only walk.
Their dogs are like five minutes a day.
Like you can't do that. You'd have to,
you got a dog,
you have to walk your dog like 45 minutes.
What ever you should aids walking.
What do you mean you should if you don't
have a big yard or are you just should
no matter what.
Well, I mean for what it's worth,
that's what the doc whisperer sad.
He said dogs need like a 45 minute.
I remember different
breeds on these Pekinese.
My dog loves it. That's the point.
My dog loves a good long walk.
It's clearly like he wants to be
cooped up in a fucking house all day.
My dog. That's totally true. I hope
I have a one solution when my dogs,
I have a giant yard that I
have a yard for my dogs only.
That's a full acre wooded
saw pine trees all day.
They're just fucking chasing squirrels
and having a party up there. Fine. Yeah.
But I,
I bought this place specifically because
it had this big lock right next to it
and I knew that I'd keep my
dogs then. Yeah. You know,
I feel like if you have dogs,
man,
you have a responsibility to give those
dogs like a fun environment. Totally.
You know, like my dogs are happy
as fuck you come to your mind dogs,
they're wagging their tail and shit.
They're never like freaking out.
They're stuck in this yard, their yard.
She huge, you know, it's a full acre.
Yeah. Yeah. I think I've basically
transformed my dog and down monkey.
My dogs turned into something more
than a dog because I treat you,
I treat my dog like a person and I
feel like my dog understands that.
I think that dogs can become like these
amazing creatures if you give them
enough love.
Sure that people are dumb and they don't
get that and so they like give him some
dry food and water and
let them lay on the couch.
I'll fucking day it says it doesn't
want to do that. They want walks, man.
If your dog doesn't want attention,
they want attention and he
wants to simulation and they
want to be outside. Yes,
they need the outside. They need the
air, they need this. The squirrels.
Oh guys really loved it when we lived in
Colorado because we lived in Colorado,
they were just roam free.
You know,
I was on 148 acres in the
mountains so I didn't have a fence.
I just let them outside at night.
What I did was we were there every day
for weeks and we let them know this is
where everybody lives. Okay,
this is where we live now.
And they figured it out really quick
and I just did it totally natural style.
I just, you know, walked him with me
and I took them with me on walks. We,
we know we scattered up perimeter.
They got ahead of me sometimes,
but when they got ahead of me,
they always went right back
to the house if we lost them.
It was pretty interesting until the dog
got emailed the mountain mine of course.
Cheers.
Frankie Harris and drinking game.
You have to just bring
up the traumatic story.
It's my little buddy.
It's a sad story.
Did you hear about this fucking shit
about lifelike cells made of metal that
they've,
they've figured out a way and then
they're theorizing now that there might be
living things out there in the
university evolve from metal. Yeah.
Like fucking terminator type
Shit. Yeah, of course. Yeah. That,
I mean,
what the fuck man?
That's the same thing like people thinking
that let light it has to be water and
times that's the,
isn't that the same thing as thinking
that the earth is in the center of the
fucking universe? It's the
same silly idea. Right?
The scientists said,
listen to this statement,
I am 100% positive that we can get
evolution to work outside organic biology.
How funky boy fucking scary is that.
Yeah,
totally.
That's what the article says.
It's probably like that monkey boy from
the old son TV or the national enquirer.
The screaming monkey boy,
monkey boy says Mr. Sign.
Just fellow. He's from,
his name was Lee Cronin.
So what do you have to
be to be a scientist?
Can do you have to go to school work
and you just like three times things and
call yourself a sign. That's
an interesting point. I think.
You think you have to have some sort
of a degree to be taken seriously?
You can your mom right you the degree
and say from her knowledge and her
backyard,
you
silly goose.
This guy's from the University of Glasgow.
He's from Scotland and his building
blocks are largely, oh Jesus.
Say this word. Poly Ox. So, but tell a
ox Pauline [inaudible]. Oh, you
mean poly ox and metallic? Oh yes.
I mean poly oxo met towel.
Yes.
That's,
it may have a range of metal atoms.
Mostly tungsten linked to
oxygen and phosphorous.
By simply mixing them in a solution,
he can get them to self
assemble into cell likes. Fears.
Whoa.
That's called.
Could you imagine if we fucking
showed up on some planet somewhere?
And they really were like maximum crime.
They were like the transformers.
What about transformers were
real, man, this, this, they
should have released this.
If they released this just six
months or six weeks rather before the
transformers movie came out and they can
have this information along with their
teasers. It can be a more exciting
movie for me because I'd be like,
maybe it's not so preposterous.
And these big stupid cars,
com people saving robots, I think give
a fucking flying shit about people,
Dude. I, what about the sun? I mean,
maybe the son's alive. That's it.
That to me it's like why God,
why think about other planets.
You have this source of
all life on this planet,
the main energy source for all life on
this planet outside of things that are
getting it from like a steam vents
that they brought him in the sea. Uh,
things that are living in thermal
ducks or whatever. I'll do,
I'll go you one further please. We're
made out of stars. We're literally,
every fucking is single piece
of your body is stardust.
Yeah.
I mean that that is what happened to human
biology is a direct result of fucking
son's blowing up.
That's right.
That's the only way you get
the information to make human
beings or the, the, the,
the materials. It's so incredible
that it, yeah, it sounds ridiculous.
Stuff like a kitty Roger's song.
We're like retarded.
No, not just kidding. Dot. Katie Rogers,
he log book, but Kenny Loggins. No,
it sounds like the, the fucking, the
highway men. That was a highway man. Yeah.
Costa goes calls.
Where does it match and pistol grandmas.
God, I love that song. It's a great song,
man.
When Johnny Cash comes on,
I ride a star ship cross
the also university of eyes
and when I reached here,
if you haven't seen, it's a,
it's a song. The highway men.
It's about real good up Brian.
We're, we already violated.
Our music is great and this is what
happens when we get drunk. That's one.
He opened herself up to get sued.
Aaron Lewis,
please don't sue me or you think you're
fucking music's awesome. I love it too,
son. I'm officially hammer. I've got blood
is to drink it too much. We're
stones. We're drinking wine. I'm on.
Ion is fucked up.
I ate so much fake,
but today I think I might shit
out and living in that water.
What's it made out of? I don't
know. But they said not to drink it,
but they were squirting it in
my face. Right. I drank it. Wow.
They said not to drink it,
but you're dragging your
swipe. Clever. Cheers. Cheers.
My little retard buddy. Yeah.
You're not a retard retired.
Your only play one on the podcast.
It's awesome.
So I understand going on,
Ari Shaffir I was going to branch
out on his own and have iTunes.
He just wanted to, to frank was
frequently. And when you're doing it well,
he also wants you to do it. He's he, you
know, it's hard to do. Uh, you know, your,
your podcast is getting super popular.
You've got so many people that
are doing it. If you don't know,
Brian has a whole network of
podcasts on iTunes called desk squad,
and it's with a bunch of great comics.
There's Sam Tripoli,
he's got a podcast and now John Reap
and John Heffron, our buddies are, are,
are doing a podcast and Tom Segura
and his wife are doing a podcast.
Sam Tripoli's doing a podcast.
Did I miss anybody? Uh,
low Esther once in a while
does wine Brody does when he's,
when he's feeling good. And I love how
you phrase that. Know they just had Steve
O on and they've had a bunch of really
good ones the day before that Mike Tyson
and him ran into each other at their face.
And then you didn't hear what happened
at the roads and Charlie Sheen roast.
Now I don't,
this is just,
I heard from word of word of
word internet or know of people.
I heard that. Is it on the
Internet? Did you search?
They just recorded it Saturday
supposedly a Steevo as Mike Tyson.
If he could run into his fist with
his face. And when he, when he did it,
he broke his nose and
he has a picture on his,
on Steve O's on Twitter with
two black eyes. By the way,
Steven wants to come on this podcast.
So those are how much he loves you.
So are you talking about,
we've got to do Judah Friedlander is
gonna come on to my buddy Judah contact.
He's hilarious. And I'm Max Kellerman
who is the, uh, HBO boxing analysts.
My personal favorite boxing analyst.
I'm next to Jim Lampley who's also those
two guys together on my two favorite
boxing analysts.
You know,
a lot of people think that because I do
the commentary for the UFC that I don't
like boxing. I'm a, I am
a gigantic boxing fan.
I've been my whole life ever since I was
a little kid and remain, and by the way,
so is Dana White, the president of
the NFC. He's a fucking huge, huge,
huge boxing fan. He bets ridiculous
amounts of money on pack, you know,
fights on Floyd Mayweather fights. He's
a fucking huge fan. But Max Kellerman is,
we're both fans of Max and he's cool
as fuck. He's a really interesting guy.
And he used to be a rapper, so it's going
to be, he's a white guy too. And he used,
he used to be a rapper and
he's really coolest fucking,
he's going to be on the podcast too.
But Judah Friedlander and Graham Hancock,
we're going to work out Graham Hancock
and the way this is going to work,
Brian's,
we're going to have to do it probably
most likely in Irvine because he's doing
some seminars down there and he only has
like one day off and I felt bad that it
was to drive all the way the fucking
bad ass spot at the Irvine. Yeah,
we're going to do as well.
I want to,
what I want to do is we're going
to have to talk after the show.
We're going to have to figure out a way
to make the ship mobile cause there's
some people that might need to come see
for the lavender hour has just innovated
a mobile podcast kit and I'm
sure he'd help you guys out
and it's got a laptop. But no, it
would be what? I want it to equipment.
He's like this kid's a sound engineer.
He went to college. Well listen,
this guy's a sound engineer.
We should listen to him.
The fuck burn anyway,
so we'll, we'll do that,
but the bottom line is that we're going
to go to Irvine and we're going to talk
to Graham and see if we can
make sure that this happens.
But Graham Hancock emailed
me out of the blue.
It was one of the fucking
coolest things in my life.
If you don't want the coolest thing so
far of this whole thing, this whole,
how about this?
The coolest thing of my entire show Biz
experience right up there with my spike
TV special, which is my favorite special
is Anthony Bordain doing the podcast.
That was pretty crazy. That was pretty
the room. That was cool as fuck.
I would definitely get star struck,
but the next coolest thing and may
be even cooler if it's possible,
is this Graham Hancock
interview. Because if you don't
know who Graham Hancock is,
I want you to go and research fingerprints
of the gods if you're so inclined,
if you're interested in this,
but what a fascinating guy who's basically
dedicated his whole life to the very
controversial and unpopular idea that
human beings have been around perhaps far
longer in this advanced state of
civilization that we currently enjoy.
Then we give credit to and then the fact
there's been some huge ups and downs
throughout history and it's not simply
one straight path from caveman to Wifi
and that along the way there's been some
disasters and that this can be clearly
it.
I wouldn't say that it can be proven,
but what I can say is enough evidence
can be brought forth that makes you
completely questioned the current ideas
of the timelines of human history and
this guy, Graham Hancock is
responsible from his book,
fingerprints of the Gods
completely changing the way
I look at at civilization.
Do you,
did you send me where you,
the one who sent me the fucking
video of that Mayan Pyramids,
they just found in Guatemala the single
largest pyramid by volume on earth.
And it was covered in jungle.
They didn't even know it existed.
Not only that, but it has
a, you know, when, when the,
when the Spanish came and when the, uh,
the Mayans were conquered, you know,
and you know, in different
parts of, uh, you know, uh,
South America, you know, diff,
obviously there were different
things happened, but, um,
the one of the things was a big issue
was the, the mind creation story was a,
was changed and altered and
fucked up and broken up. And it's,
it's very hard to find, uh, an
unedited mine creation story.
The pub view it's called, but
they found this and it's an, it's,
it's [inaudible] unedited and
it's amazing. And they're,
they're going to work on,
on, on, on translate again.
Now anyone in it before, like,
does it look like people who know? Not
only that, not only they're not in it.
It was completely covered.
I mean,
I'm sure some local people were aware of
its existence because you know when you,
you know, you stand, you walk around on
there and all of a sudden you're like,
what is this? We'll dig a little, oh,
it's a giant fucking perfectly hewn rock.
There's four feet wide and two feet tall.
Well obviously this didn't just happen.
You know, somebody made
this, who made this,
they just didn't know that this
mountain, you know, there's, there's,
they say that there's thousands of
these that they haven't discovered,
which is so mind boggling until you look
at the geography of South America or if
you take into a comp. Yeah, Google maps.
But if you take into account the
size of North America, South America,
look at Mexico. Look at like how, how,
how much land you're talking about
and how much of it is jungle. No,
they've found there was a documentary
that I was watching on Egypt where they
were, or excuse me, on the Amazon,
rather whether we're talking about all
these different structures that they're
finding in the jungles of civilization,
that they have no idea how
this civilization got there.
Don't know who they were dumped on,
what their origins were. Origins were,
but they're looking at aqua docs,
they're looking at roads,
they're looking at all this shit
that's just run over by the jungle.
And the reality is,
man,
if you have a fucking house and you put
this giant stone house in the middle of
the Amazon a hundred years from now,
that mother fucker is going
to be covered with [inaudible]
tree. Yeah, man, there's a
documentary. I know, we claim it.
There's a document or a
Netflix you can watch now.
I can't remember the name of it, but I'm
taking these fucking Alpha brain pills.
You take it on backwards. I Google
it, but I mean, what is it about,
so what it's about is this side.
Yeah,
it's an explorer who was
searching for this a theme,
the last city that existed
in the middle of the Amazon.
It might be that pyramid that they found.
He was looking for it based on like some
old scrolls in this like library that
he found and he was like a
theosophist cause the theosophists.
We're really into this idea
that there's still existed,
advanced civilizations on this planet
that had closed themselves off to the rest
of human society.
And he thought you would find a place
where people were still living there,
but he went down into the Amazon
and just basically vanished.
Save the secrets of the dead last Amazon.
Yeah.
Be a PBS documentary that's on Netflix
called the secrets of the dead set out to
find the fabled lost city of
z. That's it. Yeah. Yeah. And,
and the Amazon in 1925.
Yeah.
It led to a mysterious disappearance was
actually a movie. It's a, it's a, it's an,
it's a drama. There's a documentary too.
Oh wait, no, it is a document. I'm sorry,
the late Liev Schreiber is apparently
the, um, I looked at that author, I mean,
or that actor, I assumed that he was an
actor. He's actually the narrator of it.
Yeah.
But there,
it was like a big news story because
he was a famous explorer that vanished.
And it was weird that you would
have watched that shit tonight.
It's really fucking cool, man. But they,
you know, he thought that they would,
there would actually be
people living there who were,
who would give him like it
was a mystical quest for him.
Like he really thought that there was
going to be this advanced civilization is
still in existence. There was somehow
going to transmit this information to him,
which some people still believe, you know,
there's like the hollow earth theory,
the idea that like the
Shambala exists in the Arctic.
If you ever seen that shit no. That
you've never seen like in the North Pole,
the ideas
hold on a second. This secrets of the
dead. Apparently it's a whole series.
Oh Shit. Bunch of them. And they're
available online secrets of the dead.
China's terracotta warrior. You,
me, and you know what that is? Yeah.
Well they found these fucking,
this army of terracotta soldiers like
buried for thousands of years or however
long it was, secrets of
dead. Her kilania uncovered.
I don't know what that is.
Secrets of the dead silver pharaoh,
secrets of dead world's biggest bomb
secrets or the dead, the Dead Sea Scrolls.
One Star on Amazon dog. It can't be
too good sequence. You get one star.
No,
no.
Churchill's deadly decision is got four
stars maybe that maybe has the same sort
of lost in the Amazon only has
two stars. I wasn't the, well you
know what man, who knows?
One customer review.
Maybe you got one current who reviewed
it and didn't like it. But um,
anyway, the point is that these, uh,
this, this discovery in Guatemala,
I believe they discovered it in 2009.
Um,
and it's just sort of being publicized
today and it made its way through Twitter.
But somebody said to me on Twitter when
I retweeted it or wherever the hell
happened, he said, this is from 2009. I'm
like, you know, he's like, just old shit.
The Guy said this old shed. I'm like,
oh my God, there's 24 months ago.
We're talking about some shit that's
been buried without human beings ever
finding it for fucking thousands of years.
No one knew it was there. You know, the,
the unedited Mayan creation story.
Do they still have, she stole my voice
on Netflix not to change the subject.
And what is that? It's a documentary about
lesbian rape. I recommend Grand Canyon.
It's like lesbians raping each
other. They, oh, no way. Yeah.
They like lesbians rape each other.
Will they just fucking forced scissors
on each other? Yeah. The idea is you,
it's that you mount someone's face
and face. This is not on Facebook.
Fuck them bro. They took it off.
Did you find it? No, it's a,
it's not on the IMD beating. She stole
my voice on Netflix. I was talking to
don't get in the car on the way here.
I watched, uh, Grand Canyon recently.
Do you remember Grand Canyon?
Yeah, we talked about this. Yeah.
It's weird how time has passed
since that movie came out.
Uh, and how we don't, we don't
buy it anymore. We're, we're,
we're way more intelligent than 1993
or whenever that movie came out because
that movie and the first hour,
15 things happen in one day
almost to all these same people.
Like what is it fucking
well worth the unconnected though.
There were a bunch of different things
to happen in two people didn't even know
kind of, but yet there was also like,
all right, the husband, you almost got,
you know,
mugged in his car,
got stolen and then the next morning his
wife is walking and found a baby in a
Bush and then like, you know, then his
secretary or they connected though.
Or are they just like, it's all like
crazy shit happened in like one day.
Like it's so ridiculous now you kind
of watching her like this seems pretty
extreme, you know, for one day.
Yeah. This lesbian and Rafe movie gets
terrible reviews. Oh, it's terrible.
Horrible documentary.
Or should have known there were views
of this movie before I purchased it.
No,
it's really so funny.
It's the worst documentary you'll ever
see because really all it is is like a
porn that somebody wanted to call
it documentary cause it's real.
It's like reenactments of
what girls like, yeah. Yeah.
It's like just all these reenactments
of lesbian sitting, it's just niches.
Reenactments of like some bloods being
like sitting on another woman's face.
He was like, no, no, I can't get you off
exactly that. Lesbians rape each other.
Well I guess so man.
Brilliant. Yeah, he's dead on. It's weird.
It's freaky that you know
how to do it so well,
wait a minute.
Do you know
just a real high, he doesn't,
Brian knows about that.
What do you think happens?
What do you think
it happens? More ready? Lesbian
rape or Chinese Nascar drivers.
I shouldn't be in a fucking Chinese dude.
He just really loves cars and you get
into Nascar and you have to hang out with
those assholes. Well can
you, hey man, you want to,
we'll blows up some Chinese
food before the next lab.
Oh you know who wants to come on the
podcast? I totally forgot about this kid.
Dr Ken. Doctor Ken [inaudible].
He's great. Really? Some zookeeper.
And he was talking, he hang over. Yeah,
he saw Joey d is the other day and he
wants to come on and he's hilarious.
Norton's in town right now and we should
be my call. Yeah. Well I'm, we're all,
Duncan and I are only in town for a couple
of days cause we gotta get ourselves
over the knowledge.
We're going to do the house of Blues.
It's fucking Friday night and that
solve that bitches crazy.
Ooh,
I can't wait.
But we're also right,
they're going to be at the
UFC Ellenberger versus um, uh,
Jake shields this side,
this
interesting.
I know last time portraying Jay,
well,
you know,
people who don't know Jake Shields Dad
died and he died just a couple of weeks
ago and it's, you know what, I'm
in Jake, his dad was his manager.
His Dad is like super duper
close to him and you know,
they grew up whereas dad home schooled
him in the mountains. So I mean this is,
I mean, I mean everybody's relationship
to their father except mine.
Cause I don't know that Douche,
everybody's relationship
is close, you know,
and not everybody's for a lot of people's,
Jake shields was particularly close to
his dad. So, you know, it's for him to,
uh, to fight just a couple of weeks
after his dad died. It's devastating.
And it's down. I was like pretty healthy.
His Dad, his dad died in his sleep.
His Dad was a vegetarian. I mean he
grew up with, Jake is a vegetarian.
Jay Jay grew up vegetarian. He only gets
his animal protein from eggs, you know,
he just believes that,
uh,
that factory farming is fucked up
and he would actually eat food,
animal food as long as it
was hunted, you know, like,
ah, did food is like, like, like,
like a Kevin Smith was saying the other
day how like just like that everything
can fucking change. You know, you
could wake up and then I have a stroke.
I never walk again.
We have to, we have to somehow or another
balance, the idea of ambition and,
and, and, and, and planning for the
future with enjoying the present.
And that's the grand dance that everybody
has to go through this so difficult to
master. And I've, I still
don't have it down. No one, no,
I don't think anyone ever has it down,
but I'm way better at it now than
I ever was when I was younger.
I'm way better at it and I can offer
some insight and here's the number one
piece of inside that I can offer that he
be reckless. I'm reckless. I'm a little,
I'm a little bit reckless,
but I'm also really nice.
I tried to write as nice as
I can, you know, and I'm not,
you know, people say, Oh,
I'm a Joe Rogan, who's a dick.
A guarantee. You're me first
for sure.
You know,
and you might've been a deck because
you were nervous or you might've been in
debt because you were drunk, but if you're
nice to me, I can't be not nice to you.
It is impossible. I am.
I grew up, I, I've, I've,
I've been a nice person as long as I've
been capable of being a nice person to
know. Don't wear a condom.
What are you saying?
I'm just saying do everything exactly
opposite of what you're told him to do.
Well, I don't know if that's the
truth. I don't know if that's the case.
It's like you have to, because when
you start talking about sex, okay.
And you say don't work on them, you
know, sex to me is just like doing drugs.
Natural. It's fine. Yes is
natural. It's fun. But you can,
you can get caught up in it
and you can get fucking crazy.
Yeah. And it can, it is,
it has just as much of a poll as,
as,
as any other kind of crazy
psychological addiction,
whether it's gambling or anything like,
but Brian, you don't really mean don't
wear a condom. Yeah, I do. It feels good.
It feels way better now I'm on them
for the first month or two and then you
figure out the girl enough.
No side.
If you want to or need an abortion and
your life to appreciate the little things
can go wrong. It makes you good
together. Closer. A little horror story.
I'll tell you a little horror
story. I would love to hear it. Um,
there's someone that I know,
there is someone that I know who got a,
who got a waitress pregnant and we
just, what did she work? She worked.
She just girl, why did you have
to make her a waitress? Yeah,
because he was a bartender or something.
I don't know.
Cause they both like they worked at
the same place, so it's like, okay,
so they worked together at this place.
So I'm just going reverse sexism on.
Yeah.
I don't know why I said I don't mean
to leave a people. I'm so sorry.
Stop Lesbian rape. They, they uh,
so they um, they, they ended up,
uh,
he ended up putting his pee pee inside
of her and the guess what happened?
She got pregnant. You should have kept
the cell phone in his pocket. Yeah.
But yeah, he should have. And guess what?
She doesn't want to fucking abortion. No,
this is like awesome.
This is,
this is a one night stand
now he's a daddy. Awesome.
But it's with someone that he just
fucked one night and, and like,
yeah, it's like now he's legally bound
for the rest of his life to this,
to this, to his kid. He
didn't wait the two month ago.
You got to wear a fucking condom.
You're crazy if you don't work on
them for two months. Yeah. But you
also got to fuck people that you like.
Yeah. Don't, yeah. No, it's hard.
It's hard to say because you want to fuck
anybody want to give up the pussy at a
certain point in time, pussy is like
water and you're living in a desert. Okay,
so you weren't going to get him.
You know, it's only until you,
you live by a fucking stream.
They could drink water every day.
Can you see the forest for the trees?
Because otherwise your entire waking life
is dedicated to getting this resource
that is fucking water or pussy.
Either one.
They're interchangeable and
when there are plentiful,
then you could see them for what they
truly are. You know, and you know,
it doesn't necessarily mean that you
have to get spoiled does necessarily mean
that you have to get that.
You know, you, you don't it,
you should totally appreciate every
single one of the biological pleasures of
existence.
One of the reasons why I'm a huge fan
of Anthony Bourdain is cause he calls
himself an enthusiast, but he
is a chef and he enjoys, he,
he like really shows how much joy you
can get in eating great food during the
whole fact that the feeling of taste and
the feeling of pleasure and the feeling
of friendship. I like drinking wine.
I like smoking weed. I like going to,
I like seeing fun movies.
I like listening to great music.
You know, I like being, I like being
inundated by great feeling shit. You know,
I think that's, it's important
to wrap our heads around that.
Well, I mean, if you can like accept it,
it's just like the, there's uh, you know,
me and my friend were just
talking about this, uh, uh,
sorry, the one of the excess,
this French existentialist philosopher
and like how they have the existential is
basically I have this idea where it's
like, yeah, you can fucking, you know,
enjoy reality and get caught up and
being an enthusiast or whatever.
But the depths of it, it's just pure
absurdity. There's no meaning behind it.
There's no meaning to life. It's like
just this empty meaning was vortex.
So like, you know, for example, like when
you see your dog dry hump, another dog,
you know, you see the dog dry hump
and you're, you kind of watch it.
It's kind of funny, but it's like
you're, you're watching a, uh,
an instinctual trigger,
you know,
go through the thing and it
just acts this thing out.
And then when you find yourself humping
somebody that you just met and you
realize you're going yeah,
to the same extent, instinctual
trigger and you're like, ah, fuck,
same thing. No meaning to this.
No meaning, this is just a,
I've triggered a series of responses
in my primate brain that is wanting to
reproduce once, once I come, I'm going
to go right back into this state.
And that's absurdity. That's a
form of absurdity. I got an answer.
A question for you Brian, because I,
it's so funny you just said that cause
I just thought it's something that the
other day, like you ever scratch
a cats but, and they do that dude,
that dude I think where they're just like,
yeah,
ever fucked a girl and seen her do
the exact same thing. It's creepy.
It's almost exactly the same. Yeah,
it's cause they turned to me and Shane,
you know,
fucking them hard enough.
You've got to fuck them to the
point where they're nervous. No body
circuiting. I think that's what it
is. I need to buy I fuck up dude.
I fuck 'em they get nervous
for an audition or is, what?
Are they nervous for them? And
that's a lot of pressure, son.
As 185 pounds of Alpha and
loads in your body making grunt.
No, listen, stop. Like
I'll make anybody nervous.
Imagine a girl on top of you that's way
bigger than you. And while she's talking,
you should just start fucking hitting you.
Yeah.
Fucking bitch.
You can fuck me.
Could you imagine being a situation
where you girl can kick your ass?
Have you ever been there like
Bourdain's? I don't think so. Well,
I don't think board wife can kick
his ass. I'm still, he's still a man
and she's still anybody
on enough adrenaline. Eh,
Anthony Bourdain been around the world.
I guarantee you he probably
has no endurance, but he's,
he knows how to throw a straight right
dirty boxing match. If you have a hammer,
if you have a hammer in your house
and you sleep next to somebody,
they can kick your ass no matter who
they are, what they can slam it. Yeah.
They can slam the hammer on your
fucking face while you're sleeping.
If they catch you off guard. Yeah,
they can catch you off guard. Right?
So do you want to get
gay? It's like, yeah.
This videos online of girls
sucker punching guys and
knocking them unconscious.
There's a bunch of them. I mean, it's
hilarious. The sucker punch a guy.
You know what? A sucker punches. Yeah,
I know what a sucker punches
a lot of videos of girls,
sucker punching guys online.
It's a great fetish. Listen man,
it's a fucking wide world out there.
A lot of fucking things happen.
A lot of cross streets,
a lot of one thing intersects with
this thing when it wasn't prepared.
And next thing you know,
fucking coked up girl punches a drunk
guy in the John knocks him unconscious.
It happens all over the
[inaudible].
It's like MMA spanking.
There was a girl that used to work
for a buddy of mine. She was, uh,
my friend's assistant and she could
punch so fucking hard. She was nice.
I mean she wouldn't have ever
punched anybody, but she was like,
I could punch hard. And I was like,
all right, whatever. You know,
I'm fucking do commentary for the UFC.
You could punch hard. There's some people,
man, there's some people that
for whatever fucking reason,
they got this crazy Tommy Hearns punch.
It's a weird thing man. Cause I've,
I've experienced this since I was a
child since I first started doing martial
arts. Every now and then you'll
come across some guy who can just,
he gets so fucking hard. You're like,
where is that coming from? Does he make?
He's 160 pounds. Does it make
sense? But when he hits the bag,
the bag just moves more than anybody else.
There was this fucking check
and she was a regular girl.
She was like 23 years old. She was my
friend's assistant and she was like,
I can pass. I can punch. Okay. She's
like, put your hand up. I put my hand up.
She goes,
she hit me and I thought about my face.
She hit my hand and my hand was stinging.
Fuck.
And she turned her shoulder into it and
through her fucking weight into it and
she went to knuckles for,
I go, who the fuck taught?
You had a punch like that and don't like
her dad taught her how to punch people
and Shit, but I was like, man, if
that check punches you in the face,
she will knock you the fuck out. Right?
Here's a, if you're not ready for it,
it only takes a certain amount of
pressure to hit your jaw at a certain way.
Your legs just go. I've seen
it. I seen him in person.
I've seen it in fights. I've seen it
in bars, I've seen it all my life.
It's a weird phenomenon. If you
don't get the job, why the job?
What is in that cluster of,
it's a design flaw, design flaw,
complete design power off
button. Well, this is what it is.
Your brain is this fucking
central core of information,
of movement, of
everything. All the design,
all the direction comes from this spot.
Well,
what you are your body is
is like a fucking a house
that has a bunch of ethernet cables in it.
You know,
and you want to get Internet to your toes.
We've got to run wines.
You got to run nerves through
your whole situation. Well,
you also have this thing where you have,
you have to chew food, supply the body.
So we'll, how do we do this? Well, we're
going to have something that moves.
We're going to have something that moves
and it's going to be hard and boney and
it's going to be right in front of
all the chords. We have no choice.
That's the design and we just got to hope
that the human doesn't get hit on the
job bone and it doesn't compress all
those nerves that send the signals down to
all the limbs because if
it does, everything shuts
off. It's right here, right?
That's that. They call that John? No,
no, no. It's the actual jaw itself.
Is that what they call the button?
Yes. What I call the button.
It's the movement of the jaw. I got
the apple shop presses into the cord.
Well, I don't listen. When I say
precedent, the court will have,
what the fuck do I know is inside my neck?
It could be all elves,
gummy bears
could be all sparkly fairy dust that
comes out and you cut my throat.
I'm just guessing.
But the idea that I have,
I've had explained to
me is that the nerves,
when you punch a person on the jaw that
their job on slams into the cluster of
nerves behind them and it just causes
this big electrical short circuit
depending on a bunch of different things
to printing on your determination,
depending on your anger,
your adrenaline level had your focus,
whether or not you saw this coming,
whether or not you've been punched before,
you know how to react to it or
how to stay calm under pressure.
And depending on the physiological,
the physiological design of your actual
frame, different body structures have to,
can take a different load of impact.
You know,
like large jaws and big
David to luck looking faces.
There was a guy named David too. I was
still is a very dangerous heavyweight.
Boxers is a Samoan dude. Tanga Dude,
whatever the fuck he is, he's anyways,
whatever he is, I think believe
is smaller. The bad ass boxer.
And one of the things about him, it says
this mother fucker can take a punch man,
you can hit David [inaudible] with a bomb.
He fought Lennox Lewis and Lennox Lewis
connected with straight right hands.
It just would have put normal
men on the moon and just boom,
hits him and he can take it. He
just doesn't go out. He's had,
he's got an incredible job on top of
big, big punching power. So there's that.
There's the, the shape of your
frame, the shape of your body,
the thickness of your tendons
and chords. And then, you know,
then there's just the fucking design flaw.
The jaw goes to the,
the cluster of nerves and
depending on your sensitivity,
some people just shut right off.
There's some dudes that they just have a
glass jaw man and all you have to do is
get to their jaw and it's fun
and doesn't have, you know,
there's nothing I can do to strengthen.
I mean,
they get toughen it up a little bit.
Who's exercises dude's do,
where they fucking lift weights with their
jaws. They pull cords with their jaws.
They suck a lot of caulk. They,
they tried to suck Bryan Cocke.
They just hold them down. There's, um,
there's things that I've seen guys do.
Gerry Cooney who was doing it once in
this video I watched the first time I ever
saw, we had like, oh,
it's almost like a bungee cord and all
those tape inside his jaw and he was
biting it.
It's change a fucking pulling jaw,
trying to strengthen this whole set up
so he doesn't get knocked unconscious.
So embarrassing. Why is that
embarrassing? It's fascinating.
It's fucking embarrassing his man.
Why is it embarrassing? You know?
That's embarrassing because you never
beat the fuck out of a dude in a cage.
No, I don't mean no. Look, no.
Look, look, take that shot.
Come back with a counter drops.
The crowd goes dusk. Hell,
it's amazing. I think. I
think that's really cool to
watch and I fucking love it,
right?
But I just think that when you get into
a situation where you have a bungee cord
hanging out of your mouth and you're
lifting weights with your jaw,
it's embarrassing. It's like that moment
in time. If I was doing that, if I'm like,
gotta get my fucking dry stronger.
Why don't you fucking
pick up a history book?
It's time to look at a globe job,
right? And you're not at the
same time. And here's why.
You're right. You're right.
Because you see where this is all going.
You see the falling away of the archaic
models and the ridiculous nature of
clinging to our monkey genetics.
But we aren't.
We are trapped in this age and we have
about 80 years to have a good fucking
time and one of the things that have a
good time, you know you got that right,
is one of my favorite songs ever.
Leonard Karen Song.
I like to drink and dance all night.
There's nothing wrong with that.
It's nothing wrong with liking
a drink and dance all night.
Now there's nothing wrong with
like glad going to fights.
These guys agreed to do this.
Let them do it.
They're going to do what they
want to do it. I used to do it,
they've got to do it. They're going to do
it. Nothing wrong with that. It's go on.
Go enjoy it. Yeah. Oh man,
I feel really bad about porn and
porn exploits women. Well guess what?
There's 100 million gigabytes it have on.
Yeah, not me. It's you.
You're not going to go back in time and
keep those girls from being fingered by
their uncle. You're not going
to do it. What you know,
and I've tried and if you can jerk off to
that, you will feel better. No, enjoy it.
By the way,
if like you see like if you see a kid
playing with dolls and you go after to the
kid and you're like,
you know,
those dogs aren't real and what
you're doing is totally meaningless.
You're kind of an asshole. You the kids.
Lucky. It's getting to play with dogs.
The kids fucking lucky that the
kid can get fixated on doors,
that he can wear a fucking great towel
around his neck and pretend he's a
superhero and wander around his
backyard with a cardboard sword. Lucky.
He's lucky. Lucky. But
I, so in the same way,
when adults are doing the identical thing
and taking on these silly identities
is drinking their draws and
they're absorbed in their
attention is focused on to
whatever the fucking thing is,
whether it's Leonard Skinner drunk at
night of line dancing or somebody punching
his fist through a fucking wall or
someone climbing a mountain or whatever.
If that's grabbing your attention,
lucky you, don't stop it,
go for it. You're being distracted. The
void for a little while, congratulations.
Fuck you.
But once that shit stops distracting you,
if you continue on that path and pretend
that it still is like it distracting
her from the void,
that's like where shit gets weird.
Maybe maybe you get to a
certain point where you're,
where you realize what difference does
it make? What difference does it make?
What my understanding of the situation is,
what differences that make my acceptance
of the void if I am but a temporary
creature and should I not
just enjoy this time. Yeah.
And spread as much positive energy as
possible and contribute my part in a true
and clear understanding that that I cannot
fix all the things you ever see those
videos,
but that is my,
my obligation to enjoy this moment and
to have as much positive feeling as
possible the most spread as much
positive feeling as possible.
That is my instinct.
That is my dry.
When I'm in the isolation tank and
I'm alone and I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm,
when I'm at my most happiest
when I'm thinking about things.
You know what I think?
I think I have a rare opportunity to
spread as much positive energy as possible
and I think that is what
is most important. That is,
that is my instinctual pull.
That's what's pulling me. What's pulling
me is I feel like I've got this weird,
crazy opportunity. We have this
weird, crazy opportunity right now.
There's at least a half a million people
listening to this and will over the
course of iTunes and stitcher and
Mario Stream. It's more than that.
It's going to be easy.
It's going to be even more than that
over the course of a couple of years
because this shit is going to
spread and spread and spread.
And some of these ideas are going to
resonate with people because you are ahead
of a lot of other people in
this weird game of thinking.
There's people out there the right now
or listening to this podcast and they are
19 years old and they've never considered
any of the ideas that Duncan Trussell
is presenting to them.
And the idea that you know that that
is human civilization and ideas and all
these things could be literally alien
lifeforms trying to manifest themselves in
a conscious way on this plane.
And that's how they interact with people.
There is a lot of people right now,
17 1615 sitting with their friends,
getting their fucking mind blown by you,
dude.
And you don't think about it
because you're just being a new,
but that impact is serious and legitimate.
Yeah, that's a court. And that
impacts, we love it. Well, of course.
And also why it's fun to,
uh,
it's what you're saying is
exactly the thing that I'm
obsessed with is, is, uh, is,
is whatever that is
transmitting like as a,
anytime you can like help someone
be happier, connect with something.
It's awesome. Hey, do you think
the Dalai Lama on Twitter's real?
I don't know if he is.
He's fucking
positive shit he ever, he writes
positive shit every day. He does.
He just writes a bunch of fucking
passive isn't it? Is Shit.
Why is people serve others? Putting
the needs of others above their own.
The ultimate result would be that
you find more happiness. Hmm.
He's got sounds like a song written
by a dude who's trying to fuck a girl.
Amazing.
He's got someone's waiting.
It's not verified yet.
Of course Twitter doesn't verify anymore.
I don't know if you guys know
that Twitter style verify.
Oh well son of a collector,
father bitches know you have a collector's
edition Twitter that you can sell
before it to my spacious
cell right now. Yeah, man.
But to get back to that idea
that we were just talking about.
When you find yourself successfully
getting fixated on shit,
like successfully getting into something,
the last thing you should do is stop it.
It's really up.
It's kind of sad when you see people who
really enjoy something and out of some
sense of guilt. They're trying to stop
themselves from doing it, but like,
like addicts, they keep doing stuff even
though they're clearly aware of that.
It's not satiating them anymore.
They're just doing out of heavy. Well,
you've been addicted to things. Fuck
yeah. Yeah. I've been in, I have,
I have an addictive personality,
so I know exactly what it's like to
have the focus in my mind sucked away by
something and for me to consciously think,
I don't want to do this anyway.
This is a direct, this,
this, this conversation.
This idea is directly connected to what
we were talking about earlier about
hijacking the reward system
about something that is
artificial and artificial in
its power and its potency.
The idea of what can fucking fucking the
Oxycontin pill, that shit is artificial.
This is not, suppose somebody,
something's not supposed to impact you.
That strong a fucking Avatar Avatar in
three d if you were a caveman, your,
your GNA is basically the same DNA as
people that live 10,000 years ago drawing
fucking stupid buffaloes and
the caves. Well, you know,
on the cave walls while we're
living by the light of a fire,
I mean w w th th th th it's,
it's impossible to wrap your fucking
head around the kind of impact that's
having on the organism.
Yeah, well that, that,
that it's all a magnification
of the four basic drives,
eating, sleeping, mating and defending.
Those are the things that drive all ma
or of a prime most organic forms of life.
I don't know about Amoebas and shit,
but, and love and law and look, look,
you know, it sounds gay as fuck,
but we could say it because we're drunk.
The reason why this podcast works,
the reason why,
you know,
we all can do this over and over and
over again is because we love each other.
We're all passing notes underneath the
table to each other. We're playing footsie
about data.
Everyone would be if we all are even,
how about if we only did this podcast
holding hands and with our sweaty feet
touching each other [inaudible]
with each other afterwards.
Like we all like that.
But you know the reason why we can have
this conversation and be so fucking
crazy with our ideas that is, you
know, I'm not going to judge you.
You know the judgment between you
and me is already done. It's over.
We met each other, we know each
other literally inside and out.
I know that your weirdest fucking thing.
You lived with me. We lived together.
Yeah.
You know,
you know and Brian and I have known each
other for almost a decade. What are,
we've known each,
we know each other inside and out.
Brian and I have cried together.
Its gaze
that sounds, yeah, we, we've cried
together. You know, he's, he's my friend.
We've known each other forever.
So because that,
because we know each other so well
and we know we're both looking out.
We're all three looking
out for each other.
Rather we can say anything
and then we can say anything.
But what we're doing is we're saying
anything and somehow or another way more
people than we're ever going to meet ever
in our fucking life are listening all
at once. Yeah, it's crazy.
That's where things get squirrely
and that's where things get,
you know when we sit and be calm to play,
like you know, what is consciousness?
What is reality? What are ideas? What
does imagination, where does it go?
Why is it going? Why is it going
through you? Why is it going through me?
Why do you,
why are we so looking forward to going
to New Orleans where this weekend you and
I are going to go to the house of Blues,
a sold out show and we're going to perform
for that. We don't know those people.
I'll probably know 10 people
in the audience will be a
bunch of people from the
UFC that we'll ask for tickets,
I'll hook them up, you know,
they'd be 2030 people and it's you and
me and we can have the greatest fucking
time and right. It's going
to be incredible big. Why?
Because you've been putting
that thing out your whole life.
And I've been putting that
thing out of my whole life.
You would cry if you, if he found
out it was a guy also, what guy? The,
when we create it again,
fucking podcasts over Brian.
Brian gets the line of the night.
If you want to get in touch with Dunkin
and you can follow him on Twitter and
now he's obligated to respond to all of
your messages because he told you that
all you had to do was
call him about the flux.
I didn't say podcasts,
searches video with Tim and Eric.
I don't think we've ever talked about it
on this podcast that we talked about it
and he has the surfing video,
the body surf, Adi Boys,
legend, Legend or the pipe.
One of the best videos. I laughed
my ass off. Yeah, it's pretty great.
So it's something I did with Tim
and Eric for a HBO is funny or die.
Is that it? It's, you know, it's
something I did for Tim and Eric for Hbs,
funny or die and it's like,
basically I take off on the
skateboarding videos, but it's about,
we play these 80,
it's like idiots who learned to body surf.
But mainly it's just about us all. Fucking
this one dude on the team. It's really,
it's one of the best things. You
fucked a dude on a beach. Each horse,
each horse thought of it.
You kissed another guy.
What was it like to kiss another guy?
It was amazing.
You kissed.
You guys are real. Well, I mean, I,
I believe it was on the cheek. No,
I don't remember it though. It was on
the Dick. You know. I love you bro.
I'm just kidding. All right.
It's a very funny video.
What are the dates, man? Uh,
what's still available this weekend is
totally sold out tomorrow, by the way.
Nowhere out of nowhere show we're
doing it. The Ice House. Oh, here's,
here's what you should talk about
this real quick. We are all of us. Uh,
last weekend we did the
comedy. Um, there's,
there's two rooms at the
Ice House in Pasadena,
which is one of my favorite
clubs in the country.
It's been around for about 30
plus years, I think. 35 years.
It's not just a comedy club,
it's Goddamn museum you bought.
It's like the comedy and Magic Club
and her Masa. It's one of those clubs.
It's been forever and
it's got all this like a really amazing
history and the walls and it's a really
cool fucking club. And there's a, there's
two rooms. There's the big showroom.
I say big, you know, in quotes,
it's 185 seats. It's very
small. It's very intimate.
But then this other room it's
like 85 seats. And uh, you know,
Brian and I w you know, an all company.
You've, uh, you've talked about it,
we've talked about it before about like,
what's the perfect size of the comedy
club? I don't know. I mean, we're,
this weekend we're going to do somewhere
around 700 people at the House of Blues,
which is, you know, like a medium.
And then there's like the really small
places where it's like the ice house,
which is like 85 people.
And then this October 7th
at in Houston with uh, uh,
Brendan Walsh and me and Joey Diaz,
we're going to do that
horizon wireless theater,
just like thousands of fucking people.
So it's all different sizes,
but there's something magical about
those little fucking rooms, man.
And we did that little, we did that
little 85 seat room at the ice house this,
this past weekend.
And Brian and I and,
and Ari and manager Madrigal
and Brendan Walsh, all of us,
we got together and we talked about, I
was like, this place is fucking great.
And then someone came up the idea,
I don't know,
it was,
I was like,
imagine just renting out that room right
there and doing a podcast. And I showed,
okay, that's fine. Yeah.
Well it also, Brendan said, I
know it was Brendan Walsh said,
why don't I just do it right here,
right in front of the door,
which I don't know if that
word, but it might work sometimes. Can
you imagine fans trying to do a podcast?
Well,
this is what I was thinking.
If we hired some Tait Fletcher looking
dudes to fucking keep people away from
you and fucking keep the peace and then
just the energy of all those people.
As long as they didn't
interfere the energy of all
those people hanging out sec.
When we did the live show with Jim Norton,
there was definitely a different feeling.
When you are trying to feel like you're
entertaining people watching you,
it's cool to hear. We're
hanging out. Podcast has great.
I did a live podcast at the laughing
skull on stage. It was fucking awesome.
That's a small club.
Norton is small too.
We did it at Kevin Smith's placement
only like 60 people I think,
but my point is that you can,
you can.
We're going to do our
idea for a podcast with,
we kind of assimilate it all our ideas
together and the best idea seems to be
wherever we put it,
it's the comics that are right about to
go on stage or just got off stage and
we're fucking smoking when we're
talking shit. Just like this,
just like the show and we do it. You Know
Brendan Walsh, Jon Heffron, John Reese,
who the fuck? Who the fuck is
in town? You know anybody who,
Joe Judah Friedlander texted me and
said he wants to come on the show.
How would you to frailer
Freelander you know,
calls us on a Wednesday night and says,
Hey,
I want to come to your fucking crazy
podcast thing at the ice house. Boom.
It comes down to the ice house and we
have this wild ass show with 85 people in
that little room.
We do a free
podcasts. We all have a good time. The
idea with Hollywood bullshit. Exactly.
Not deal with traffic and black wizards,
black wizards and parking and nonsense.
Listen,
you fucking Goddamn fucking
show is over. Wait, can I tell
people this show I'm doing
testing
September 23rd uh, Joe Diaz
Brennan. Oh No. Joe Diaz,
Ari Shaffir and I are at the
paramount theater in Denver.
Colorado tickets are still
available. They're going
quick. There's not much left.
If you're interested in brain pills,
go to [inaudible] dot com o n n I t.com
if you want to see one of the best,
most interesting and fascinating
standup comics in the country.
And one of my best friends,
go see Duncan Trussell at the laughing
skull in Georgia and Atlanta, Georgia.
And when is that? That's at the end
of this month, and I'll be in Seattle.
What was it? What was the dates? It's the
last stuff weekend this in this month.
That'll be on my website.
I don't have even put it just
Duncan trussell.com t r u s s e l l.
Call the laughing's gone away.
And I know if it's the last weekend,
it is either the 23rd of the 24th
or the 30th and the 1st of October.
Dunkin doesn't know it's the 20 it's
gotta be the 20th the last weekend of this
month, so, okay. Whatever that
Friday is the 30th oh yeah,
that's it. Okay. Fridays,
right? Yeah, that's it. Call them that.
So you're basically doing the
weekend and Saturday night you'll be,
it'll be October 1st yeah,
that's it. Yeah, sure.
Duncan trussell.com t r u s s e l.
L.
Holla at your boy. Thank you to the
fleshlight. Go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for the flashlight
and enter in the code name,
Rogan and you will get 15% off of this.
Number one did your, did your girlfriend
still hide yours or throw them away or,
I need a new one. Yeah. Anyone.
I've got a box of them. Great.
Approximately who loves
Ya. Next week we will, uh,
we were going to get as
many people as you want.
I know that a Jim Norton is in town.
Jim contacted me.
We're going to try to get Jim
in here and uh, we're going to,
when I would try to do Judah
Freelander like I said,
we're going to do max cries and you're
to Eliza slash for sure she has a new
show and um,
uh,
for sure Graham Hancock and that
will most likely be the 23rd.
Not sure if we're going to do a Ustream
with that because it all depends on how
good the a wireless system is in
the hotel. We go to in Irvine,
they usually suck ass. It does. It
sucks ass. They suck hard. Yeah.
Maybe we can record. Oh, did you use
during lets me record to the computer.
So we're good. We just have
to, I can't do it live.
Maybe so we can upload the video
on Vimeo. We can't do it. What's,
what do you mean we can't do it live?
But no,
I mean like if we're at a
hotel that the internet sucks.
The new Ustream lets you record to your
computer and then go back and upload it
later. What's, yeah. For
Real. Yeah. For Real.
So we can do private shows whenever we
went to, you know, is this some new shit?
Yeah. And you should, when did
this happen? Uh, about a month ago.
And what does this Vimeo thing,
you've got some shit up on vein.
It's like youtube.
Yeah. Son. Brad hunts the bowl.
Nice a lot buddy. He's the,
I'm the fucking big Maha over at, um, uh,
the president and founder of Ustream
and he puts our shit online and uh,
he and I haven't been going through, he's
very good guy. He was like your podcast.
Yeah. Good people use streaming. I like
stitcher. Oh, I'm going to go on, um, the,
the Nerdist podcast too, for sure.
I'm going to do that as well. Uh,
Chris Hardwick's a buddy and I ran into
him at the airport recently and people
say like,
you guys got in the best Twitter argument
ever because you like solved it like
so like civil lead. Everybody was so cool.
It wasn't really an argument, you know?
I mean he doesn't like the stitcher thing
and I understand his point and I like
it and he
whatever.
And anything else? Anything
else? We all look, oh, I'm sorry.
The lavender hour you
can get the lavender Tau,
which is Dunkin and is a lovely better
half Natasha Lucero's also on tonight.
Also a fabulous show
for as well right now.
Prime Time TV show. Watch it
on NBC, Mr Premiere to be,
and I'll be in Seattle next
Thursday to in Seattle. All right.
Duncan Trussell on Twitter again.
It's d u n c a n t R U s s e l l two s's.
Two L's in case you were worried.
I can't stop talking.
I got verbal diarrhea is
fucking shows over by, you know,
we love you. It's just shut the fuck
up. Stop your negative bullshit.
You know? I love you. All right, bye.
Right?
[inaudible].