I get,
I get heavy,
you know,
I'm going to talk about life and death.
You talking about life
around.
That is what we're doing.
We're living in.
Some people were dying.
That's life and death.
We're all.
What's really interesting is that we're
all going to die.
Yes.
And,
and that everybody pushes away and I
guess that's normal to push away,
you know,
thoughts of your death,
but the real enlightened,
like the Buddhist Buddhism,
eastern eastern and stuff,
they say the way to get enlightened is
to die if you can check this out,
is to die before you die.
Meaning lately kind of go into the fear
and they claim that the fear is
releasing ego,
which what they mean by ego is like,
like you have this beautiful studio and
you have a career and a wife and a kid.
Kids I guess.
And,
and it's like,
it's like you can't be attached to it.
You have to die to that.
Like in other words,
you don't own your wife,
you don't own
anything really,
because we're just,
we're.
The bottom line of it is,
is we are temporary,
yes and impermanent.
And it doesn't mean you can't enjoy,
you know,
like you're in the prime of your life.
Right?
So why think about your fucking death,
you know what I mean?
But I think for guys like me,
I'm a little older and like for some
reason we're on,
right?
Yeah.
For some reason I experienced panic
attacks,
um,
and I had a full blown one coming up
here while you're driving.
Wow.
I was driving.
I now will feel like,
okay,
this is what it feels like is,
um,
I'm feeling kind of tired.
I've been doing a lot.
And that's not to brag.
I,
I've been,
I've been
in show business.
What?
You're in show business.
I'm in show business.
You're doing a lot of work.
I'm in show business,
I'm married,
I have two dogs,
I have three cats.
It's a,
it's like to manage the dogs are,
are,
are intense,
you know,
because you,
I love your dog.
I've talked to have three.
You have three?
Yeah.
Okay.
But for me,
uh,
and this is,
I think one of my,
one of the,
uh,
you know why I'm a panic attack,
suffer occasionally.
His Dad,
I get into these dogs like I,
I think I'm a sign of someone who has
panic attacks,
is someone who cares too much about care
of things instead of trusting that
everything's gonna be alright.
Like I to get up,
I'm going to feed the dogs.
The dogs will be okay.
I'm always like doing stuff like,
hey,
my dog's name is Charlotte and Basil
Charlotte.
Does she have something in the Charlotte
or something in a right?
And I blow it up a little,
you know what I mean?
Instead of chilling and going,
oh,
she'll be okay.
Let me just,
let me just,
you know,
wipe the.
I'll see her like scratching at the
aisle and it can set me off into this
worry and I think that's kind of um,
the symptom of panic attacks.
Like I'm coming up here,
so I get on the one on one.
People who don't know the one on one.
Well you should just kill yourself
because the one on one is a main artery
and you should know about it or what if
they don't drive cars,
thing.
Other things to worry about.
I think they're brilliant if they don't
drive a.
But anyway,
it,
it was packed.
It was,
you know,
the Google maps was like accidents up
ahead and I started to feel this kind of
feeling trapped.
Have you ever felt trapped on the
highway where,
uh,
and,
and for some reason I think because I'm
overtired and I wanted to get here,
this is first time I've done your
podcast,
I just started feeling an anxiety about,
oh fuck,
I'm going to be.
And this is what happened.
I mean,
I'm doing it physically feeling I'm
going to be late,
I'm going to have the walls are closing
in.
Yes man,
right?
Yes.
The real scary thing is the breath.
Like,
oh man.
It's like I'm this,
I'm doing it in the car.
And by the way,
the one thing I hate about La,
I don't know about you,
but like here we are in December 28th
and it's hot.
Yeah,
it's pretty warm.
It's like 75 degrees.
80.
Is it 80 to 80 and the sun is blaring
in,
through by side window.
And I'm feeling a little fuck.
There's nowhere.
I just don't,
where I can't get off,
I can't,
you know what I mean?
It's,
it's,
um,
so it's a buildup of anxiety instead of
just going,
you know,
what,
like your shirt,
let that shit go.
Let that shit go.
I,
I couldn't,
I couldn't let it go.
Like when I get entangled in it,
when it reaches a tipping point.
Right.
You know,
when,
when the anxiety reaches a tipping point
where,
you know,
I,
I am like,
Oh God,
like,
like here's the voice in my head that I
have to always battle.
It's like,
Oh God,
this isn't going to work out instead of,
hey,
you know,
for some reason I have the.
Oh God,
okay.
But you intellectualize it,
right?
Like,
like now like we're talking about,
but now now it's after it's over,
you realize like,
ah,
I should just say,
hey,
let that shit go like you without any
stake in the game.
Right.
You removed.
If you were
giving yourself advice in that car,
he'd be like to come on.
I really think it's great.
You're living in America.
Here is few extra people on the road.
Some of them bumped into each other.
Let's just get through this.
You know,
you texted me.
It's no problem.
Come a little later.
It's no big deal.
Start a little later.
It's casual.
There's no,
no reason to get anxious about that.
Where I don't smoke pot too.
Did I would understand more because
people that eat edibles and then get on
the one on one and get stuck in traffic
and then what happens?
Here's your whole world starts closing
in on you.
You started without the adipose.
Yeah.
It's the same kind of thing.
It's A.
I think one of the things that I've
noticed a lot is a lot of people that
have anxiety and a lot of people that
they're generally,
they're intelligent people and the
problem is with intelligent people is
that you're overwhelmed with
possibilities.
You're thinking about all the actual
variables that are in play.
Whereas dumb people just fucking stumble
into walls where they're talking on
their phone and you know,
they're like texting and walking out
into traffic.
They're not thinking,
you know,
somehow they get things work out for
them.
It doesn't snow illusion.
You're not living in their skin.
If you were inside the nine volt battery
brain,
you'd be like,
Oh God,
this is fucking nothing to think about
here.
Like was it Jamie?
Will you with me or is it with Tony when
we're at the airport and there's this
girl.
I sat next to her just to listen to our
conversation.
I think it was Tony and she was just
talking about amazing race and I wanted
this team to win and I can't wait until
this happens and when I get paid on
Friday I'm going to buy this phone and
then there's this is this food I really
want to eat and it was just this
droning.
I'm like,
this might.
You might as well be a robot that just
sent here to consume.
There's no like there was no.
There was no curiosity or creativity.
It was just consumption.
It was just food and buy this and watch
that and and drone on and on and on,
and who knows if it's genetics,
if it's nature or nurture or whatever it
is.
There's a lot of really dull folks out
there and we're not supposed to do just
a lot of really told folks,
but the culture is also geared to
consumption.
I mean a lot of it is sure,
isn't it?
It's like it's like you turn on the
fucking TV and that is the message
center that our culture,
that is our culture.
It's a part of our culture,
but our culture is pretty vast now.
I would say that one,
much more of our culture,
the Internet much more than than
mainstream media now and that's one of
the reasons why they're grasping at
straws,
trying to stay relevant.
What the mainstream media like
television shows there.
They're down record numbers like news is
down record number to be about that.
Yeah,
I mean I think it the idea that these.
It's great if someone is like,
you know,
New York Times,
Time magazine,
respected journalism,
someone who you can go to when you
really want to.
What the fuck
is happening in Syria?
I need to know,
oh,
I need to know from someone who's going
to give me an objective informed
opinion.
That's,
that's huge.
And it's very critical,
but once you get past that you're
dealing a lot of the shows you're
dealing with,
whether it's CNN or Fox News,
you're dealing with opinions and your
opinion is just as valid as Shepard
Smith's.
Like why?
Why is Shepard Smith?
Because he has makeup on and he's
wearing a tie and they have ready,
set,
go and they press the green light and
what you're talking about is really
interesting.
How,
how?
Because it's just on TV because it's
sanction sanction to sanction by the
powers that be like,
like it's really about ownership.
Like,
like I don't even know who owned CNN
anymore.
So was it Ted Turner?
He probably still owns it.
He's Hashtag Ball.
He was right?
I think so.
I mean he's like one of the biggest land
owners in the United States.
He has millions of acres.
Yes,
he owns buffalo.
Got Restaurants were served buffalo.
Unbelievable.
Hashtag ball.
Is that Montana?
Think it's called Montana.
Yeah,
it's in Montana,
right?
You have them in Colorado.
They might've been Montana as well.
I think it's actually a chain.
I don't know where they are,
but it's supposed to be very good
restaurant,
but what my point was is that the
structure at CNN says,
well,
we're going to talk about this,
we're going to talk about that.
We're going to talk about that.
We're going to put it on TV and people
watch the fuck.
You know,
you have to break it down to the
essential is like there is a screen,
it's being transmitted into your,
into your home.
It's been and it's,
it's very much,
it's very much with people not realizing
it a complete fucking mind control thing
or it really influences you and it takes
a lot to kind of disconnect and,
and for instance,
I have said to myself,
I am going to disconnect from the grid
for a while.
You ever tried to do that?
Like,
I'm not going to go online.
I'm not going to watch TV.
Like,
you know what I mean,
but it's,
it's really kind of very difficult.
Might go somewhere.
I go hunting.
That's what I do.
I go to the woods for like a week and I
have no choice.
Can't get cell phone signal.
Can just,
no Internet connection.
Do you feel rejuvenated?
Well,
yeah,
it feels good.
It feels good to take breaks.
You know,
I,
I enjoyed the Internet.
I enjoy the information,
but it's overwhelming and one of the
reasons why it's overwhelming is we're
not,
we're not really accustomed to this
experience.
This is a very new experience for human
beings.
Like over the last,
you know,
20 years we've options to a little bit
more.
Twenty four,
I think 94 ish really came up.
Ninety four is when I got online.
Don't you sink and I really want to
relate to this again,
just like cut to the panic attack.
I drove it up here.
It's because this is,
it's another form of,
of the anxiety
that it's information overload.
Overload.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
Because my brain,
my brain,
I think your brain is the same way.
It's like my brain,
I feel my brain just digging into shit
like,
oh,
you know,
like I'll read a paragraph on,
I don't fucking know.
Hunting and then you know,
it'll mention something about guns and
then I go to guns and then I go to gun
control.
Like go,
I go and then I go to the scumbags who
don't want gun control and then I go to
a school shooting,
like one thing leads to another on the
internet,
rabbit holes,
rabbit holes to go down that rabbit
hole.
I was,
I want to do more of this on stage,
but like talking to an audience about,
Hey,
I've only done it once and it went over
care.
Okay.
But it was like,
hey,
you ever get a,
you ever go on facebook and you just
start reading a fee.
You just start reading your feed and you
just get drawn into like people's random
thoughts.
You start connecting into their brains
and you're like,
oh,
I get that.
And then where you go wrong is there's
262 comments wound.
You read the comments and you their
feeds,
you know,
but after you fucking let's say 30
comments in.
Yeah,
something happens to your fucking
center.
Like your brain just Kinda is free
forming it about.
I forget what,
what,
what?
Um,
what I was.
Oh,
I was reading this was a,
this was some threads.
Somebody started this guy said,
improv comedy.
Improv is bullshit.
It's halfassed.
It's um,
it's,
you know,
amateurish.
It's like they're presenting a product
that hasn't been chiseled and worked
out.
Whereas standup,
he was,
he was a proponent of Stanford and he
said,
stand up,
you know,
it's,
it's chiseled and what people want is a
finished product.
And I,
you know,
I,
I kinda,
I disagreed.
I mean,
I love different things at different
things.
So it's like some people enjoy jazz.
Yes.
That's what I love.
Yeah.
They,
some people enjoy symphonies,
some people like to go to see an
orchestra.
They want to say everything that's been
perfectly tuned and,
and just gotten to this point of
perfection where they were great.
Great too.
It's all.
Look,
it's great to watch someone's finished
set.
Yeah.
I loved watching your thing about how
America is now a whore and we're driving
with trump like you,
you did that thing with up.
But I do my bit and
no,
but,
but here's the thing is that you get
sucked in because the way the guy on the
Internet,
and this is what
happens on the Internet a lot,
the way they guy who said Improv socks,
that's how we framed it.
This sucks,
this is good.
And then it's a thing that then your,
then your ego gets involved.
Like I think I even know I didn't engage
in that one,
which is really good.
Here's the thing,
he's right to him.
For him.
He's right.
It's just,
he phrased it wrong.
If you said the what I like is standup
because I'm like a polished product.
I don't like Improv because it feels
amateurish to me and people could say I
disagree.
I love Improv because it's wild.
I like that feeling of being in the
audience where someone yells out,
you know,
genre,
World War Two films and you know,
that they're,
they're scrambling and they fucking try
to pretend they're into the,
in the,
what's that called?
The tunnels for trenches trenches.
I,
yeah,
I build trenches and I have mustard gas
at home.
It's grey.
Poupon mustard gas,
grey poupon,
mustard gas.
I think that,
uh,
there's nothing wrong with having
opinions on things,
but people don't like that.
Your opinions are different than theirs
and they get mad at you.
Like some people get mad at you if you
like a certain kind of music.
It's crazy.
But they'll get mad.
Like,
your tastes sucks.
You're tasting music sucks.
But here's the thing.
What we're talking about is that that's
what's going on a lot on the internet.
Yeah,
you suck,
you're wrong,
you're wrong.
Definitely wrong.
And,
and I think it's really reached a fuck
in a heightened state because of the
politics in the country.
Like another words,
it,
it filters down to where the president
stands up with the president insults
people constantly.
That's all he does.
That's what he's a divisive.
You know what I mean?
This is not new,
but that's how he,
he operates.
He's very manipulative in the fact that
he usually,
he's very praising of some people,
you know,
like doing an amazing job.
Beautiful job.
The other day he was talking about these
firefighters and he had all these
firefighters behind him and he was
talking about what a great job they're
doing as firefighters and it's just like
this weird speech and now going to go
see each other on tv and like,
you know,
I don't think they get enough credit and
so he'll,
he'll like bestow.
It's very interesting method course is
going to bestow preys on the
firefighters.
You would say that right.
But only if it's convenient for him.
Like about John Mccain who was a fucking
war hero.
He was like,
I like people that don't get captured
like Jesus Christ.
Like he had like six deferments.
Like,
Yo,
I had a hangnail,
like I can't go to war.
He had a gang of deferments and
meanwhile he's saying something about
John fucking mccain who a legitimate war
hero who was captured and tortured by
the Viet Cong and he had the balls to
say,
I like people that have been.
I mean that's effecting the military at
all.
Didn't.
No,
but here's the question.
Has He get away with that?
Shit just does because this just who he
is.
It's like if you look,
if you know someone's a scumbag,
like then the scumbag behavior is like,
wow,
that's fucking,
that's Mike.
That's what he does.
Right?
But if Mike is a priest and it turns out
and what Mike really likes doing is
smoking crack and below and guys,
you know,
you find out,
you're like,
oh Jesus,
Mike,
I thought you were this other thing,
but if Mike is Andy Dick and you found
out how many dicks out there smoking
crack and blowing guys like,
oh andy,
it's trump is Andy Dick.
He's
who he is.
He,
that's his thing is you come after him,
he comes after you.
And we just sort of assumed that once he
became president he would stop doing
that and he would act hashtag
presidential.
He's not at all.
No,
he can't help himself making it all
about himself.
And it's interesting.
Back to the Internet Shit.
And what is going on?
Uh,
you know,
just for instance,
taking that example of Improv,
stand up is the best,
right?
It is.
The guy who wrote Improv sucks.
The Guy,
you know,
the guy who started the thread,
it's like,
it's like what they're doing and what
trump is doing.
It's like
shit is all about what I think and I
know you're gonna come at me,
but that's what I want.
I want,
you know,
the attention.
I mean,
I really think it comes down to I want
to fight.
I wanna fight,
you know,
I want an ego fight.
I wanna fight and I want the attention.
There's certainly a little bit of that,
but I also think she wants repercussions
for challenging him.
He wants people to feel he wants to
punish him.
He wants people to feel very
uncomfortable if they challenge him,
I think that's a big part of his game.
You know?
And he wants everyone to know that he's
going to come after you,
like as the president,
he's going to come after you.
And if he does,
all the trumpkins are gonna come after
you too.
Because if he comes after you,
then all of these,
these puppets,
these people that follow him that
literally are on there all day long,
like you really have to realize that
some of the people that are online that
are tweeting for trump or treating about
certain things,
whether it's on there all day,
by the way,
I'll follow people just to see how crazy
they are just to get it in my head like,
oh,
okay.
I see what you do.
You do this all day.
You,
you,
you start tweeting at 7:30 in the
morning with your first cup of coffee.
You're hurling insults and you do it til
1:00 in the morning and then you start
all over again in the morning.
How did they do that?
Because their credit go insane.
I find,
I don't know about you,
but if I spend an hour on that kind of
rabbit hole with twitter or facebook at
my limit,
I think is about an hour before I.
it.
It just something says to me,
I need to,
I need to get out.
I need to walk,
I need to do,
do something.
I need to get away,
you know what I think is happening in
this,
I've been thinking about this a lot over
the last week.
I think humanity is in the process of an
overwhelming transformation that
something like giving birth.
I agree and I think that like if you
ever watched someone give birth,
like the crazy thing is how much,
how much pain the women are in.
Like when I watched my daughter come out
of my wife,
I was like,
Whoa,
that's a lot of work.
Like it's fucking painful and it's crazy
and they're talking about
blood in.
It's just,
it's not even the president at birth,
it's like this.
It's like,
ah,
but then boom.
Did you film it most unbelievable love
comes out of it.
Yes I did.
But the most unbelievable love comes out
of it.
And then it's like,
oh my God,
and the way you feel is incredible.
And it's like,
I think there's a,
you got to go through hell to figure out
how to,
how to handle this better.
And I think culturally we're going
through a weird kind of hell in this
kind of health.
Avoidable look,
you could just put that phone down and
you can just go hiking,
go with a good friend,
bring your dog,
go have a nice day.
Sit Up there,
you know,
crack open a cold glass of water and
look over at the landscape and go,
man,
it's fucking beautiful and it does
something to you when you look at
beautiful things,
right?
You can do that,
but you might want to just check your
twitter real quick.
See if anybody respond to that real
witty posts that you left there.
Oh,
they get any likes?
Oh fuck you.
I didn't say that.
That's not what I meant.
And then he and then he start the wheels
start turning.
Exactly.
You know,
they did a study.
I don't know if you're heard about this
one,
that just turning off the phone.
Like if you have the phone in the room
with you and you turn it off,
you think,
okay,
the phone's turned off.
I'm cool.
What the scientists said it was a study.
I'm not sure where the study was,
but they said,
no,
no.
You have to put the fucking phone out of
into another room.
They said something about someone's call
you.
What if you get a text or if someone
sends you off,
but what if there's a cool instagram
posts that you'd miss?
Absolutely.
Like
everybody's worried about,
I think does all the chaos that's going
on the world now.
A really thing that we're in this
unbelievably tumultuous time in human
history at.
We're not designed to have access to
information 24 slash seven like we do.
It's all about information.
It's connection and information.
Those two things,
those two things are critical.
It's all about information,
but I think even more like insidious is
the way the information is given.
Like here you got our president just
basically like a prick the way he
fucking hates this year,
but he takes pride in it,
right?
That's part of who he is.
Said say it's regular guy.
See what if you're a regular guy and
you're a media figure,
like a some fucking.
Who's the guy from American idol was
that guy's that mean Guy Simon,
that guy like he's a dick.
You know,
everybody knows he's a Dick.
Like that's the brand that was trump's
brande.
You're fired.
That was his brand.
So it's reinforced with public
acceptance.
It was reinforced with the tension.
It was reinforced with like,
he knew that that is what got him the
credit,
that he is so gravely desired.
And so then that allowed him to run for
president.
Right.
He runs for president.
Yeah.
Coming off of a reality show,
they canceled his fucking reality show
while he was running for president.
Remember I taught Schwartzenegger took
it over?
No,
they canceled it because he was the pr
because he was running for president.
He was saying things about Mexicans.
Then Swartz,
nigger took it over,
but his.
They fired him,
I should say and can't say,
but they fired him.
NBC fired him from the show because the
things that he was saying about Mexicans
and that's really where it all came
from.
So he was a fucking literally an on TV
reality star on a,
on a shitty game show.
And then from there it goes on to be
president.
So that style of car,
he's not going to like have this moment
of reflection.
At seven years old we realized this has
all been a terrible.
Like I have this amazing responsibility.
Now I'm in charge of the greatest
nuclear.
Yeah,
you think you would,
but why would he?
Because he's just a person.
I think we have these narratives in our
head that these people become heroes.
That a president is something different
than a person.
Yeah.
Well I would just think to that if that.
Yeah,
I get who he is,
but it's like God damn it.
Don't you get also influenced and formed
by that,
by that way of the job.
Like yes,
you do have,
and this is the scary point.
You do have a nuclear arsenal at your
disposal.
Edit his fucking dangerous because you
know you're dealing with another fucking
lunatic.
You know what I mean?
Crazy.
Yeah.
I mean they found each other.
You know what I mean?
I mean,
it's kind of a love story.
Yeah.
Well,
in a way there's an argument and this is
the argument that a guy like trump is
actually good in this situation because
a guy who is too diplomatic and it would
allow this guy to develop real long
range nuclear capabilities that it'd be
extremely dangerous and that with a guy
who was harassing him and fucking with
him like the way trump does,
and then you allow the military to do
something to stop this guy from
developing these long range nuclear
capabilities that this would be better
than having some very wishy washy
president who,
uh,
put,
put severe restrictions in the military
and didn't allow them to stop this guy.
We would all like to think that the
world is like we are here.
We are here in the United States for the
most part.
Pretty safe.
Not a bad place to be.
You know,
most neighborhoods,
even in bad neighborhoods,
most of the time it's not that bad.
Occasionally bad shit happens regularly.
Bad Shit happens,
but not like it happens in the Congo,
you know,
not like it happens in Syria right now.
Not like Aleppo,
not like all these other other parts of
the world that are in constant turmoil.
Libya,
go to Libya right now.
It's fucking Kate.
It's a failed state.
It's an isis hotbed,
right?
There's parts of the world that are just
fucked and if you're not the kind of
person that is willing to do something
to protect the rest of the people from
getting involved in the kind of chaos.
It's in those parts of the world.
That stuff can leak over.
Bad people can come in to your neck of
the woods and start treating where you
live.
Exactly how they treat Syria.
Exactly how they treat the Congo.
It's totally possible.
Absolutely.
But I'm a believer that if this bad
stuff,
and it is what you're talking about,
what you you mentioned is horrific
stuff.
Like if you go in,
I mean Aleppo,
if you've seen pictures of it,
it's.
It literally is a wasteland and now it
has been a lot of palm doubt.
Yeah.
You know,
and the suffering that those people have
endured and the amount of refugees in
the world has gone up and up and up to
me.
I don't think you can isolate that.
I really don't.
I,
I think that has to come back to roost
in some ways and it does.
I mean,
it's kind of random incidents of
terrorism.
In other words,
what I'm saying is that we have to have
more of a,
like unified worldview light,
like seriously have a compassion for
him.
I know this guy but,
but for everybody,
like,
oh no,
fuck,
Syria,
Libya,
Iraq,
you know,
they're bad.
No,
because if the world is kind of a small
place,
especially with technology these days,
you know,
and if,
if there are thousands and thousands of
refugees because of bombings,
you know,
people,
they seek revenge.
They,
they,
they grow up and hate,
they grow up of course.
But what are you saying?
I'm saying that I'm saying that that
does affect us.
Like you originally said,
well we live in a nice place where it is
kind of basically.
Okay.
And I say that I don't know how long
that can exist without
all of the turmoil.
What I'm saying is if you're living in
the United States and you're living in a
fairly peaceful place,
you have to take into consideration that
there are people out there like Kim Jong
Aoun who do regularly killed their,
who regularly kills people who are
insubordinate,
who regularly kills anyone who thinks,
who would challenge him in any way,
and then he has nuclear powers and he is
going to do something and it's entirely
possible that he could launch a missile.
It's entire.
He's so fucking crazy.
It's entirely possible that he could do
it in some sort of a suicide mission and
then he could launch a nuclear strike on
the United States in a suicide mission.
If he gets the capabilities.
Some people,
it really depends entirely on how that's
managed,
but there are people that would manage
that incorrectly and he could get to the
point where he has those nuclear
capabilities and he could launch and he
could do something that has to be taken
into consideration.
We've done it.
We did it to Hiroshima,
we did it to Nagasaki.
We lose.
We literally dropped indiscriminant
bombs on entire cities,
so that's unbelievable.
Crazy and it just happened.
Just happened on 100 years ago.
Not even right.
Isn't it interesting how,
how most people don't have a sense of
time and history.
Eighty fucking years is nothing.
It's nothing,
nothing that's nothing,
but the modern day person is like,
you know what,
a long time is 45 minutes ago on my
twitter feed.
Like that's 45 minutes ago that someone
gives you a,
an article,
they send you an article but growth from
2013 just like,
whoa,
that's four years ago is nothing.
I get caught up in that shit.
Like,
like,
you know what I love watching
documentaries is because it reminds me,
holy fuck.
Yes.
A lot of the same shit went down in
1960.
You know what I mean?
Sure.
Like demonstrations,
you know,
Nixon was in power.
We had Vietnam going on.
You know what I mean?
I think there's always been a problem
with people feeling like they're
represented and communication.
Those,
those two problems have always existed.
It just exists today in a different way
almost.
We almost have too much communication.
Well,
that's what I mean,
too much information.
A little bit.
Yeah,
for sure.
And I think you're definitely right that
we have to think of the whole world as
being a like one thing instead of
walling things off and.
But the problem is when you pull over,
right?
Yes.
But you get a little scared.
I mean sometimes fuck,
but you have someone who's a military
dictator like Kim John Loon.
That's a totally different situation.
Like he won't let the people live.
He shoots them when they try to leave
like this is.
This is a very,
very bad thing to be seeing in 2017.
That's entirely different than someone
who is a Syrian refugee who those people
are fleeing for their lives and
obviously they're in incredibly hostile
environments and situations,
but there are substantial parts of the
world that welcome those people and want
those people to have an opportunity to
get away from what they're experiencing.
You know,
there's a lot of people in this country
that argue for bringing them over here
and helping those people.
So I think our compassion is still
there,
but people don't want to be unsafe
themselves.
You know,
I think we,
I think we will eventually these
boundaries will become more and more
preposterous.
These lines in the ground that we've
drawn where we've decide like this is,
you know,
we are Canada and we are against you
America and you're connected to us by
the same dirt like we were tribes and
the tribes that were tribe earth.
Okay.
You know,
and I think once we realized that will
be a lot better off,
but then we're going to have to really
understand the allocation of resources.
Yes.
Are you talking about also distribution
of wealth,
which is kind of another way to put
allocation of resources?
Well,
I'm talking about fixing places where
there's no hope.
You know,
I mean it's,
you could say that it's allocation of
wealth.
Like one of the things you think about,
like when like Halliburton got these no
bid deals to go into Iraq and build
these things and why can't someone get
the same sort of contracts to go in and
established established places
like in the United States?
Like established community centers in
impoverished neighborhoods do the same
thing to Guadalajara,
go into Tiawana and try to like set it.
Here's the answer.
I think.
I mean this is my trip,
not trip,
but like my bent is like,
um,
there is just like what you're talking
about,
community building,
you know,
going into places,
setting up education centers,
it,
it doesn't seem to be a priority when it
was not profitable.
Yes.
Right.
But war war is a huge profitable.
Rebuilding is profitable.
That's what I'm saying.
Halliburton is rebuilding and rebuilding
his problem.
And what do you need to rebuild?
You need to fucking knock it down first.
Right?
And that,
that's weird,
right?
Because things are already knocked down,
but rebuilding them is now profitable.
What do you mean?
Oh,
parts of the world are already fucked.
But going in them and in rebuilding,
you know,
going to impoverished parts of Ecuador
and rebuilding that and try to,
you know,
make it so that these people have
opportunities to advance their lives and
take care of their families and there's
no money in that.
Why isn't their money of that?
I don't know.
What's weird that we know that
everything is about where there's money,
you know,
and that like,
look at how much the,
that's the problem.
Look at China,
right?
Look at how much their,
um,
their,
their way of life has improved since
capitalism sort of been installed.
Like the amount of people that are in
poverty in China.
I was just reading this like the,
the staggering change since what's close
to capitalism capitalism,
but they have a lot more restrictions on
what they're allowed to do and not do.
You know,
in China they still can't research
tenement,
square research it.
What happened?
Yeah.
You can't find out about it.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
That's crazy.
And I feel like when you do that to
people,
if you say to people,
look,
you can't,
you can't look into that.
Isn't there immediately like,
I don't trust you.
Like you,
like it's immediate.
It's a dictatorship.
You know?
And that's,
that's what,
that's the crazy thing about Kim Jong
wound.
That's the crazy thing about China.
Anytime you're in a situation where you
have a dictatorship,
you have a group or a person who's
controlling the inflammation that gets
distributed to the people and then the
people who are under the thumb of this
person,
and then when this person says
something,
that thing is the law.
That is one of the scariest things about
trump is that what essentially trump is
doing is treating his word as law and
saying that everyone else is fake news
and they're all liars and everyone who
poses him,
they cannot have a reasonable opposition
of him.
Any,
any opposition must be chastised.
If he wasn't within our system,
he'd be a fucking Dick.
I mean,
he is that personality.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
he's in this,
this thing with the FBI,
you know about this,
right?
Where they're investigating
the unnatural where it's at.
He's talking about fire read fucking
Miller.
Yeah.
As he's talking about,
I'm still not sure.
I think he knows and the people around
him know that,
dude,
you cannot do that because I think that
will.
I think you're going to fuck with the
wrong people.
They're like,
you still could fuck with the world.
People within this country already
fucked with the wrong people is fuck
with the intelligence community.
It means fuck with the CIA and the FBI
and they're all like,
Jesus Christ,
this guy.
But here's the thing.
At the FDA for him,
it's certainly not as dangerous.
It wasn't the sixties.
It's harder to kill a president today,
but the FBI,
it's just stopped a terrorist attack in
San Francisco.
This.
Yes,
you don't hear about it because the
president hasn't talked about it in the
news that talked about it a little more
to happen.
There was a planned isis terror attack
at one of the peers in San Francisco and
this guy who was a former soldier was
planning it and reached out to isis and
was trying to do in the US soldiers.
You're a soldier.
Look at that.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
you get crazy on all sides,
but that's what I mean about,
you know,
when there is bad conditions all over
the world,
it filters and that's one way,
you know?
Yeah.
But this is a guy who was an American
citizen that wants to attack random
American civilians.
You know,
this is a crazy person who was the
person who have blown a fuse and was
just going to do this for Isis and was
doing it publicly on facebook was it was
reaching out to these people.
So he was.
He had a blown fuse for sure.
He didn't understand what he was doing
or understand that obviously people are
going to be paying attention to these
fucking isis pages.
Isn't it wild that people publicly put
this shit out on facebook?
It's wild,
but it's not wild.
I mean,
there's a lot of doll mines out there.
But anyway,
the point is that the FBI thwarted this
attack.
President hasn't said a Goddamn word
about it.
He's praising these firefighters doing
an amazing job mazing job.
But he's not saying anything.
I wonder if,
because I wonder if it's because wants
everybody
to think,
hey look,
there's no.
There's no terrorists or activity going
on and just want to praise the FBI.
Well that's.
That's fucked up.
I think that's exactly what it is.
I think he's against getting groceries.
Getting investigated.
Yeah,
because he has a vendetta against the
FBI.
He's at war with the FBI.
It's crazy.
This is a crazy situation where someone
have this mindset is running the country
and some people love it.
They love it mag.
Uh,
we're going to get things done.
Look at the job list.
Snus rate is down,
unemployment is down.
There's all this good stuff is
happening.
The stock market is hitting record high.
It's hilarious about when they talk
about the stock market.
I'm hitting record highs first of all.
I think it's a fact that 50 percent of
America is in poverty.
Five.
Oh,
you agree with that stat?
I don't know.
Is that real?
Yeah.
I mean you could look it up,
but it's poverty.
It's a certain level of income and I've
forgotten what it means.
What is the number?
Is it like I'm not $20,000 or.
Yeah,
it's around 30,000.
it's around there and I find out.
I think also it.
I think it also talks about benefits and
that was just an article man at the
Washington Post,
dude.
About how people in their seventies are
having to take full time jobs because
their pensions have been taking away.
I'm in corporate America is taking away
shit.
Well Jamie was just talking about this
yesterday about how uh,
like companies are selling you the same
product but now it has like a half an
ounce less than it used to before and
the boxes are slightly smaller and I
just bought two boxes of cereal
yesterday and they both say they're 12
ounces,
one's 12 ounces and one's 12 point one
but the boxes are not even close to the
same size,
same cereal to rights checks.
So it's the same shape.
Cereal and everything.
You told her that they're lying or do
you think that they've figured out a way
to get 12 ounces in a smaller box
because you know how you would open up
cereal and then there would be like a
little air space and then you'd get to
the package and then there's a little
air that package.
Cereal might be a bad example,
but gatorade for example was a 20.
It's 28 ounces now,
used to be a 32 ounces for three years
ago.
A perfect example of like taking you pay
more and get less.
Well,
they just this.
It's just a fact.
Infinite growth.
That paradigm that corporations operate
under where you constantly have to
improve every quarter you have to make
more money.
You have an obligation to the same.
It's crazy.
It's like,
how come you can't make.
Listen if you make $100,000,000 in your
corporation this year,
why can't you make $100 million next
year?
And everybody's happy.
Like,
yeah.
I mean isn't that the isn't?
Yeah.
Isn't that the textbook definition of
greed?
See this three different size cups
appear to hold the same amount of soda,
might be a sponge and the bottom of one
of them you can't really tell,
but it just,
like I said,
this guy did this four or five times to
sort of prove that there wasn't.
This is a small medium and like super
large sized cup and they all hold the
same amount of liquid.
Huh?
Super Strange.
This was explained to you yesterday that
Bra,
Huh?
See this a daily mail's super sketchy,
but that's just where they sat in
England.
Yeah,
the Daily Mail.
Like they,
they,
they're super sketchy with staff.
They're super sketchy.
Yeah,
I mean,
yeah,
there's definitely a problem with that.
We have with the system that's in place
in terms of like how corporations get
treated as individuals,
right?
They're allowed to donate enormous sums
of money now,
and this is a fairly recent within the
last decade,
the way that the structure has changed
and then there's also the diffusion of
responsibility inside the corporation.
If you work for a big evil corporation,
but you're a good guy,
you're ready pepitone,
you're a good guy.
You waived your neighbor,
you know,
you give money to charity,
but meanwhile you're making toxic sludge
that's killing people in the Philippines
or wherever the fuck it is.
You know,
you know how it goes.
Yeah,
it is how it goes,
and that's how it goes.
Also to justify this infinite growth
idea.
This corporation keeps growing and keeps
growing,
keeps growing.
That's why trump is opening up these
national monuments for drilling wells.
That's really fucked.
I knew an outdoors guy.
Scary,
scary shit.
It's really scary shit.
But Natalie is scary.
It's,
it's,
it's an affront.
It's like,
no,
I don't take away our fucking land
because to me I get talking about,
you know,
circling back to the panic,
I feel like,
wow,
these motherfuckers,
these core corporate greed,
let's call it.
Right?
And that's where patients and it's,
it's endless.
They're taking away our places where we
get some serenity.
Where were we fucking connect to nature,
you know,
like the,
the lifeblood of it.
You know what I mean?
They want to me and I,
to me,
they're taking,
they want everything fucked up about it.
It's,
it's,
it is Americans land,
right?
Is the public's land.
And so if they're going to go to these
areas and extract resources,
why should they have those resources?
Why?
Why are we allowing them to take the oil
out of these spots?
Why are we allowing them to take the
minerals out of these spots like these?
These are,
these are not there for your disposal.
This is American land,
this is the public's land.
These corporations that want to come in
and start drilling and mining in these
areas,
it's sanctioned,
stealing and then,
and then to like jump to an issue one
step further.
What the fuck?
We're the only country who pulled out
of the climate accord right now.
Are you with me that it isn't climate
change is climate breakdown that's going
on and,
and,
and anybody you've had scientists on if
they talked,
have you had an environmentalist on
talking about this shit?
Um,
I mean just here in La this past summer.
You live in the valley too?
Yeah.
I never experienced like d,
it was 115 for 10 days and not 110 for
like three days in a row.
And then I was starting 2016 year one
day.
I remember telling my wife,
hey honey,
it's only one on one.
They were beating me down to like,
sweetie,
it's kind of Nice.
It's only 103 today.
You know what I mean?
But,
but my point is,
is that they're taking land to do more
oil drilling,
to do fucking fracking,
do that kind of stuff.
Where the fuck is that?
Why aren't we going completely toward
solar wind phase II?
That shit out,
especially in California,
if you fly over California,
you see very few clouds and all the
rooftops like these rooftops should all
be solar panels.
If they were,
we would have almost no need for
external power.
It's sunny 24 slash seven here and and
if it's not today,
within five years or 10 years,
as the technology improves,
there would be a way to extract all of
our needs from solar power.
That's,
that's what I'm saying we should do
instead of fucking opening up laminate
problem is like there's so much money in
that oil and we still rely on it so
heavily right now and they're not.
They're not thinking about the future.
They're thinking about right now.
Right now we can get that the thing.
Here's the thing,
they're not thinking about the future
dude not be a future.
And I know that's really like,
like I don't want to be like,
you know,
but scientists really well known
scientists are saying,
you know,
these hurricanes are the beginning,
the massive ones we had that buried use.
Then you know that Barry,
there were a couple that really fucked
up and they're going to be the norm and
also the constant heat out here in la.
I mean,
you know what really freaked me out for
wildfires in December.
Yeah.
The big one that's still going on right
now.
They haven't even put it out in Ventura.
Yeah.
Jamie was saying yesterday,
it's not totally contained,
right?
It's still 90 percent.
It's like that fucking crazy.
It's been going on for weeks at Thomas
Fire.
Gigantic fire.
It's,
I mean it's an enormous fire.
Hundreds of thousands of acres and a
terrifying.
By the way,
the firefighters out here,
I cannot believe what they do animals,
but you know,
apparently they have a lot of prisoners
that they make fight the fires for like
a dollar an hour.
Yeah.
It's like part of the Gig that's fucked
up.
Yeah.
You got to fake your own.
You've got to just run into
that fire,
get three.
But I think a lot of them,
like you have chicken shit,
it's fucked up,
but it's fucked up.
My car can get a fucking dollar an hour
for work.
Like why is it okay to like that slavery
is slavery.
Like if their work,
like I used to think that about license
plates,
like that was always the big thing.
Like in,
in Massachusetts that was always a joke
that like every two years a new comedian
would come up with the same show because
it was so obvious is that a new
Hampshire,
the license plates say live free or die.
And I'm like,
uh,
those plates are made by prisoners.
And that was what was crazy.
It was like,
that was always the thing that was
always the thing about license plates.
They were made by prisoners,
right.
That was always the reference that we
would talk about how you're going to go
sent upstate and you gotta make license
plates.
It was,
that was what people did.
But when you make those license plates,
you're making like thirty cents a day or
whatever the fuck you're making.
Well again,
that gets back to corporate greed.
Like I was reading about that stuff like
verizon,
I don't know,
there's so many big corporations using
prison labor to make stuff for them and
prisoners also get charged.
They get charged,
I don't know where the fuck they come up
with the money,
but they get charged all these shit.
Like if you want to make calls,
if you have to buy your own fucking
uniforms,
it's like,
yeah,
well they're being punished.
I get,
I get the idea behind it,
but it isn't punishment.
You have to be fucking confined space,
you know?
I guess now you have to work.
Well the idea is that someone's
profiting from it.
That's where it gets super squirrely.
It's like,
wait a minute,
okay,
I get the fact they're being punished,
but who's making the money?
Is the money going to the victims of
these crimes?
No.
Okay.
So there's one thing if you made a guy
like say if a guy robbed your house,
right?
And then he goes to jail and then he
makes a thirty cents an hour.
The,
the state should pay him.
Like what a normal working wage would be
like 25 bucks an hour,
whatever it is for this job this guy is
doing.
And then you get all the rest.
Absolutely dickheads working for you
while he's in the pokey and he's making
thirty cents an hour because he broke in
your house.
No,
no.
He's working for verizon.
Yeah,
that's what's weird.
He's working for some company that's
willing to pay for those services at an
exorbitantly discounted rate.
Yeah.
Now it's not.
It's all not good man.
And here's the thing.
You can't keep an eye on all of it.
He can't keep an eye on what's
happening.
And then the private prison structure
and then we know what happened with
Bernie Sanders.
His wife is involved in what the college
went under because of how is he legit?
How many vacation homes is he happy.
And then you look at Hillary Clinton.
Wait a minute.
Wait,
hold on.
Hold on.
What's this?
Clinton Foundation?
How much money.
She didn't know what she was opposed to
gay marriage until 2030 years.
You'll be overwhelmed.
You'll be overwhelmed with all the
different people and all the different
scandals and all the different
possibilities and you're in your car and
you're on the one on one and you're
freaking the fuck out.
Eddie pepitone.
That's what it is,
why you have to go into nature,
you know,
you have to go into nature,
kind of disconnect a magnet.
The native American Indians knew how to
do that.
Yeah.
They knew how to do it,
but that's all they had.
They didn't have cell phones.
It's not like they made a choice,
you know,
it was interesting how you taking that
shit away from them by saying that,
no,
I had sebastian younger,
uh,
on the podcast.
He's an author,
a brilliant guy,
and one of the things that he was saying
was that,
um,
during the revolutionary war,
or I'm sorry,
during the time of colonization where
the Europeans are moving across America,
some of them were kidnapped by these
native American tribes.
And then when they were rescued by the
soldiers,
they resisted.
A lot of them wanted to stay the native
Americans and some of them moved in with
the tribes.
Like some people,
like voluntarily moved into tribe.
What does that tell you?
Well,
this is what he said.
No one did it the other way.
The native Americans did not join the
Western civilization.
They,
they didn't like the only force.
Did they join the cities and move into
these towns?
They wanted to be with native Americans.
Well,
they wanted to live the natural way,
the way they've been living forever.
Their system is attuned to.
Yeah.
Do you feel it?
Because I originally started,
started this off with talking about
anxiety and and as we've been talking,
I think the one of the biggest causes of
anxiety is disconnection.
Disconnection from mother earth
disconnection,
disconnection from the heart of life,
like disconnection.
I don't know man,
but,
but on,
on top of that than what's fueling that
disconnection is this incredible
technology where you're bombarded with
information about everything and you're
trying to make some fucking sense of it
and your brain overloads and then.
And then the bigger picture almost is
that there are people in power and there
are people in power.
I don't know if it's a conspiracy,
but these people own everything they
fucking own just about everything.
Owning more where we're talking about a
bunch of different issues here.
Then if you put in all these things
together,
trying to put them together,
that what you're saying about people
being disconnected and being overwhelmed
by that,
all that stuff to think about that's
real because you're supposed to be
thinking about your immediate area and
what the threats are and your immediate
environment and where your friends are.
Where's the community?
Where's their communities?
I mean they.
They talk about this community is
breaking down like,
like we have a comedy community.
Don't you think that's a big thing like
our community,
like especially the comedy store.
There's one of the cool things about the
comedy store is we all go there and we
see other and it's like very,
very friendly and supportive.
I think it's huge.
Huge,
so rare.
I mean I,
I,
I realized that dad is what we're
talking about.
Like you need you,
you ever have a fucking thing where
you're like flipping out about something
and then you make one phone call or see
one friend and the problem goes away.
Yeah.
Especially if you,
maybe you and a friend are in some sort
of a disagreement and you thought that
they thought this thing and they thought
that you thought that thing and you get
to talk and especially if you meet each
other and your friends like,
no,
I thought this and you're like,
ah,
I thought you thought that.
And they're like,
ah,
and then everybody's happy.
So you were stressed out and freaked out
and nervous and feeling weird about
talking to that person.
But then once you talk to them,
everything's smoothed away.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's,
I don't know if people.
I think when you're doing that online
thing and you're spending your day
online or even texting,
like I have to text friends and that's,
you know,
but I see them.
Those are weird.
I have a few of those,
a lot of east coast buddies still.
I just texted them every couple of
months we text back and forth.
Isn't to say it's like there's something
missing.
No,
but if they call I won't answer the
call.
I look at that time for a conversation
right now.
Send me a text.
I mean,
texts,
I'll get back to you,
but I'm in the middle of doing my ads
here and I've got to fucking write this
bit and I wrote a fucking go somewhere
and I got to work out an hour and.
But um,
yeah,
but I,
I think,
you know,
and,
and we're all busy.
I get that too.
But it's like we,
we,
we have to find time for the kids
community.
I mean,
I'm find time for being a human,
an actual human and are a huge part of
being human is interacting with other
humans.
We need each other.
The worst thing they can do to you in
prison has put you in solitary.
I think of that.
The worst thing they can do,
you're,
you're locked up in a cement cage filled
with murderers and rapists and criminals
in the worst they can,
they can do is to leave you alone.
Yeah.
Isn't,
that is the big punishment is not like
letting you go out and hang out with all
the guys in the cafeteria.
No.
Yeah.
Punishment is putting you in a room,
taking away your clothes.
So.
So just getting back to the technology,
I think voyeurism is fucking killing
people.
We've become like this nation of
lawyers,
like just like what I was.
I went to a little birthday party
yesterday and a bar and it's not to brag
and silver lake like bragging about
silver lake,
I don't like silver lake anyway.
You don't.
I don't think I do.
I'm also,
I'm also the guy who likes who makes
immediate judgments places without
really knowing them.
I think that's a comic thing to do for
sure.
Absolute bullshit.
Oranges suck or
fuck
what's wrong with overlay?
No,
but I do.
I just want to talk about voyeurism and
technology.
So.
So I was trying to do the thing.
We were talking about fucking hanging
with people around us in this bar.
We're five fucking television screens
and,
and I'm the type of guy and again,
it's my anxiety,
like my tension in me.
I wanted to go and go,
can you please.
And this is how I would say it too,
which is why I never get anything done.
I go,
would you please turn off the fucking
televisions?
By the way?
They didn't even have a fight on,
they didn't even have a good game on it
because the games were over something
and it was just showing random dumb
shit.
Like,
I don't know,
one was a reality show where people
doing weird things,
you know what I mean?
And it's so loud and my vision was drawn
to this shit constantly and it was like,
no man,
this is the problem.
This is.
It was right there instead.
But if you own a bar and you want people
to come in and spend a lot of money,
you gotta give them something to stare
at
the problem.
You can have acute community bar,
like when them little pubs in England,
you know,
it's been around for a thousand.
They don't have the TV's right.
I doubt it.
I don't know.
I've never been to one,
but I would assume if they're a thousand
years old,
they don't fucking stick giant flat
screens everywhere.
Right.
But what about if we give it a shot
where if I owned a bar in silver lake
fucking someone said it would be funny
if I just had one black and white and
I'm just showing old Joe Louis fights on
it.
Like really small.
Absolutely.
Cool.
Joe Louis versus.
Who is the guy that he had these great
fights with?
Was it Max?
Max Schmeling,
yeah.
Yeah.
Maximum.
Ellen was unfairly thought of as a Nazi.
He was really just a German.
You just a German guy who was a boxer
who really didn't want to represent
Hitler apparently,
from what I've read.
Yeah.
It was a big rival of Louis where they
had these incredible.
He stopped Lewis and the first fight and
then Louis destroyed him in the second
fight.
And the big thing about him beating
Louis was that he beat Louis and Louis
was that he stopped Louis.
Hmm.
Uh,
I think he.
Did he think he did an in Louis?
Hardly ever.
I mean,
did he lose one?
Two fights was at he lose.
He lost quite a few when he got older
and his career lost to rocky Marciano by
brutal knockout and um,
but that was,
he was quite a bit older.
I think he was in his forties at the
time,
but I think um,
when he had the rematch,
I think he,
I think Max schmeling might have killed
him.
And then when he had the rematch he
destroyed Max schmeling.
Here it is a loss by K.
Oh yeah.
Does it say what round 12 out of 36.
Yeah.
And then he came back.
There was another guy,
he came back and he was a giant hero
when he knocked out smelling in the
first round.
Scroll up all the way.
How many years later was that?
Eight 38?
Yeah.
So you remembered first round?
Oh,
he smashed him.
Yeah.
I mean that was when Joe Lewis was Joe
Lewis.
I mean that was when he had really come
into his own.
And then he went on this incredible
tear.
They used to call it the bottom of the
month club because he was just locked,
knocking out anybody who's willing to
get in there with him.
Yeah,
he,
he thought some legit guys and billy
conn found them a couple of times who
was actually a light heavyweight buddy
bear.
Was that Max Baer's?
It says disqualified.
You see that 49 and one.
I don't know what happened there.
I wonder if that's a relation to Max
Baer.
Probably the 19 thirties.
Must have been.
He imagined going back to the thirties
and forties.
So look at this.
He was the champ all the way up to
Ezzard Charles in 1950.
Think of that.
And he started in [inaudible] 36.
So the fight with the first fight with
Max Baer was 36 with Max schmeling
rather was a 30.
Hold on right there.
He.
Yeah.
So he rematched them in 38.
The first fight was in 36 and then he
was all the way the fuck scroll all the
way up to the top.
By the time he lost he lost the Jersey.
Joe Walcott a unanimous decision in
1950.
That's incredible.
That's 14 years later.
Wow.
Fucking crazy.
No,
his first loss was to Ezra.
Charles,
sorry.
Yeah,
he Kao Jersey.
Joe Walcott,
by the way,
that you know,
Yankee stadium was the venue for less
Chicago Stadium and these were huge
events.
He won a bunch of fights after that.
He lost the unanimous decision,
scroll all the way up and then lost
again to rocky Marciano.
So you really only lost three times.
It looks like a believable three big
ones in the later stages of his career.
Unless he lost earlier.
What's his overall record?
It was 66 and three according to that.
So three losses.
So one max mayor,
the brutal one to rocky Marciano,
which ended his career.
Did you see that Charles?
The brutal one?
Yeah.
You want to watch it?
I,
I love,
I love.
I grew up watching boxing.
Did Ya?
Yeah.
And it wasn't paperview it was ABC 59.
Yeah,
it was like,
it was like network back then.
There was something,
it wasn't paper view and they were free
tv and I really got into the sport like
I was like,
I would be like so psyched to see this
shit.
I'd be like,
I would watch you remember a guy named
Oscar Bona.
Bona point of view.
He was like a bro.
He was just like this kind of wild
brawler,
but it was a big guy and he'd fight guys
like,
uh,
I don't know if he changed his name yet.
Cassius clay.
Oh,
what's this?
This is jersey.
This is a,
as a Charles,
right?
Is that as a charles the loss,
but that's not the one we want to see.
Want to see the rocky Marciano one.
This was the one where as a Charles the
first guy to beat him and he beat him by
unanimous decision,
but we look,
first of all,
look how much smaller were back then,
like rocky Marciano when he won,
the heavyweight title was 15 pounds
lighter than me.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Think of that.
And I think he was only five,
10 and that might've been bullshit.
You know,
like people were a little sketchy about
how tall they were back then.
You know,
try to find that rocky Marciano one
this.
Um,
yeah.
I mean he,
I believe at the time,
I think when he was the champ,
he was 185 pounds,
maybe one 90 and Seattle was known like,
like Marcy Ghana was known for like just
having unbelievable strength and his
punches.
Like she fucking is this.
Yeah,
that's what he was.
He was like,
this is this hitting.
Yeah.
This would think of an immigrant brock
town brawl.
Like he was from Massachusetts,
Brockton mass.
He looked small.
Yeah.
He's 15 pounds lighter than me.
Man.
Louis Louis isn't even that big.
Louis is probably 200 pounds back then.
That was a heavyweight back then.
It's just a different world.
People didn't have that kind of food.
They didn't have enough to eat.
They didn't have the nutrition
knowledge.
They didn't have steroids.
They didn't have weight lifting.
I mean they had weightlifting,
but boxers really didn't engage in that
is very rare.
They thought it stiffened you up.
They didn't understand that the
stiffening you up is just as your,
you know,
getting sore and that you have to
recover from that and that's how you get
bigger and stronger.
Like boxers today,
if you look at like Anthony Joshua,
who's the heavyweight champion,
the world now as you look at him.
Yeah,
he's an English fellow.
He's a tank.
I mean he's a busy man.
You look at Anthony,
Joshua,
he looks like like a superhero.
Do they,
do those guys have as much stamina as
these guys do?
They do,
yeah,
because this conditioning methods that
they have today are just so superior.
They understand rest and recovery and
they monitor your heart rate and you
know they're,
they're monitoring lactic acid build up
and creatine in your blood and so the
science is really,
it's such a scientific.
If they engage in that at,
you know,
some,
some people still take it old school,
but I just think they know more about
what gets you in condition and high
intensity conditioning drills.
High Rocky Marciano had something that
you can't teach people,
which is just brutal,
brutal power.
He just had the ability to land these
bone crushing shots and he also was
insanely tough.
You're dealing with a just a different
time.
Like I was having this conversation with
my wife this morning.
We were talking about old school.
Keep that going on and see the end.
It's brutal.
We were talking about old school
cartoons and about Pinocchio and they
were so mean.
There were so mean and even old school
cartoons about Santa and Christmas
elves.
The ells are all shitty to each other.
Like,
what the fuck I fuck you guys work for
pc thou they totally pct out.
But back then in the 19 forties and
fifties and these cartoons were
originally made,
the world was a hard place mat.
It was hard from World War Two was World
War II just over or.
Yeah,
well here's something that I didn't
realize until recently.
My friend Steve Rinella was actually
talking about this on a podcast when we
talk about factory farming and large
scale agriculture when it comes to
stuff.
By the way,
when we talk about that,
the reason why that all got instituted,
the reason why we have those programs
set in place in America was because of
famine because people were worried about
what happened to the Europeans during
World War Two,
during World War One and World War Two.
It's estimated that millions of people
starve to death in the world and in the
United States.
After the war.
They wanted to do something to make sure
that that didn't happen over here and
one of the things they did was they
started instituting subsidies for
farmers to make sure,
look,
you're not making enough money,
but we're going to give you money just
so that we have all this food on reserve
so that everyone thinks about it as,
oh,
this is evil thing that the government
has done to keep us fat and stupid,
and no,
it was originally put in place to
prepare for the worst case scenario,
but we're at war again and we're short
on food.
I get it.
I get the genesis of it,
but,
but now,
now it sucks.
It's horrible.
Fucking horrible.
The worst part is the animals.
See,
that's,
that's my thing.
I watch a fucking.
I mean,
um,
I,
I have gone to veganism and I grew up
Italian and we ate everything.
I mean,
I love sauce and I mean,
I just couldn't admit it.
It's amazing that I have gone this way
and I did it because my wife got me into
it,
a big animal rights activists and just
watching some fucking slaughterhouse
videos and seeing the fear.
I mean to me animals and the most
powerless because they don't have any
choice in this shit,
you know,
human beings who have fucking horrible
life since at least some fucking element
of choice and freewill fucking animals
are just,
it's just like,
especially factory farmed animals.
Right?
Dude,
I mean they're just trapped.
So
yeah,
I have been for,
I would say it took a while to like,
not like slip I would say pretty solidly
for three years,
four years.
Um,
and how's,
do you get your health monitor?
Do you get your blood levels checked?
My sugars are a little high because what
happens for me and,
and this could just be fucking
willpower.
I,
I don't know,
but.
Oh,
he just knocked down.
left hook dropped.
And this is,
you know,
an older Joe.
Louis.
How old was Joe Lewis at the time of
this young Jamie to say,
and rock and Marsianno.
How old was Marsianno?
He was in his prime,
I think Marciano was 30 or something
like he is a lot smaller than um.
Does it say no?
No.
He was older.
Yeah.
Nineteen.
Fifty one.
He got knocked out by Marsianno.
That's crazy.
God,
I love Bradick.
I loved that Cinderella Story.
You that Russell Crowe is fucking great,
you know.
But anyway,
so you eat too much carbs.
Yes I do.
I do carbs and terrible for you,
man.
That'll do 10 more than anything.
What about eggs?
Fuck Dude.
Vegan?
Yeah.
But why go vegan when eggs don't harm
anything.
If you get like,
I have chickens if free range chicken.
Yeah man,
they,
they just run around.
You feed them,
have a good old time,
and then you eat their eggs like no one
gets hurt.
The eggs are not viable because there's
no rooster.
Right?
So you're not taking away a life.
This is just something that the,
the chicken's almost like,
you
know,
they're just ags now.
They're only an embryo if it's on,
if it's pregnant.
So it has to get fucked by a rooster.
If there's no rooster,
they just lay eggs.
Oh
No.
Funny that most people didn't know that.
I didn't know that.
I didn't know that until I got chickens.
I,
I kind of intellectualized it,
but then I was,
oh yeah,
yeah.
There's no rooster.
How could they?
Of course,
it's not like the chickens can lay eggs
and those eggs can become new chickens.
No,
that only happens if a rooster gets in
the hen house.
So I guess I guess the answer to that,
I guess the answer to that would be the
way they housed the fucking chickens to
make.
We don't have to get them that way.
You can get free range.
I mean,
there's,
there's places that you can get
legitimate gentlemen free.
You might actually even visit the farms,
you know,
there's a guy that we had on the
podcast.
What does that gentleman's name that
runs polyface farms?
Joel Salatin,
Joel Saltz.
Oh,
I've heard of that name.
He's a real.
You main?
Yes.
And He,
you've heard of him.
I think it was in a movie called forks
over knives.
Maybe.
I Dunno.
Maybe that movie is very deceptive that
that movie is filled with a lot of
bullshit that works overnight.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
That's it.
Vegan propaganda movie.
And they're the same guys that did the
most recent one,
which is,
uh,
what the health widely torn apart by
actual scientists to understand human
nutrition.
Oh yeah,
yes.
Yeah.
Real problems like meat does not cause
diabetes.
There's zero evidence that does when
diabetes is caused by sugar and by
complex carbohydrates,
or excuse me,
by refined carbohydrates,
this not processed all diabetes,
right.
Obviously there's genetic diet.
What about the connection between meat
and heart disease use?
Here's a connection.
When you say people who eat meat are
more likely to have heart attacks,
right?
You're not saying what they eat the meat
with.
Are they eating a piece of grass fed
steak or the eating of Shitty
cheeseburger that's on a bond that's
filled with sugar,
with fries and that they have a syrupy
soda with it.
Just talk about this.
I've had Dr Rhonda Patrick was on this
recently and what she said,
the zero is a direct correlation between
consumption of saturated fats along with
refined sugar.
When you have refined sugar and
saturated fats,
it produces a lot of bad cholesterol and
this is one of the things that's been
proven clinically to lead to heart
attacks clinically to lead to strokes
and hardening of the arteries and yeah,
it's the big thing is sugar.
The big thing is sugar and
carbohydrates.
Those are the big things.
And carbs turn into sugar.
Yes,
but
I,
I very little carbs.
Very little.
They'll crave them,
huh?
No.
Once you get out of it,
see,
a lot of is your gut health.
A lot of it is what's going on inside
your stomach.
Like what?
What your stomach is used to eating.
If you feed your stomach sugar and
processed,
refined carbohydrates all the time,
that's what you've got in your gut.
I mean,
that's the kind of gut flora your.
You're cultivating and it's gonna.
That's what leaks.
Delete leads to leaky gut,
leads to inflammation,
you know?
I mean,
I want to pick on you,
but you're a little overweight.
No,
no,
no.
And this is a lot of innovative problem
with carbs.
Yeah.
And my trip has been.
My trip has been that,
um,
about the animal rights.
You know what I mean?
Like,
like I don't,
I fucking hate the way they are.
That's fine,
but end,
it's good.
But you can do better for yourself.
I mean,
you can live,
you can live an ethical,
humane life with no animal products
other than like free range eggs and be
okay and just cut all the dairy out,
cut all the things that you are.
But I'm just what I'm saying to anybody
even listening to this.
You can,
you can have eggs and you can get plenty
of it from A.
There's a,
there's a lot of plant based protein
that's like very rich and powerful for
you and excellent for you.
Hemp based protein is really good.
Spirulina is fantastic for you.
There's a lot of really good sources of
nutrients,
but you got to really pay attention to
what you're putting in your body.
If you just eat vegan pizza and vegan
cookies all the time,
you're going to get.
Well,
I know it's going to fight it out.
Right?
You're right.
And I do find myself craving like,
and maybe that's because I put it in,
you know the fucking.
Oh yeah,
it's gonna be before I came here I had a
fucking,
you know,
blueberry Bagel.
Whoa,
that's great.
Right.
You feel good when they're going in.
They really do.
You what?
I don't think that's what gave you the
panic attack.
No,
no,
not specifically,
but I.
But I think,
you know,
if you're feeling kind of shitty and
general,
you're more susceptible to think you're
right.
For sure.
Yeah.
If you could just cut out carbs.
It's harder on a Vegan diet,
but it's positive.
Right?
But you got to get a good book on it.
You got to find out like there's,
there's really good vegan health books
that can show you how to eat in the
right way to go that way at all.
Or you reject it.
Well,
it's not that I reject it for me.
Um,
I,
I eat wild game almost exclusively.
The wild animals that I hunt.
Yeah.
So I hunt the wild animals and if I an
elk,
I get hundreds of pounds of meat and I
eat that all year.
I have commercial freezers in the back.
I'll show you after the show.
I keep meat here.
I have meat at home.
I give me to my friends.
And so my meat that I get is a wild
animal that was going to get eaten by a
wolf.
Like if I,
if I didn't get it,
I mean this isn't a factory farmed
prisoner that gets to slaughter.
Um,
this year I got an elk in Utah,
a shot in Utah,
and I also shot one in California in a
place called to hone ranch is this
270,000 acre ranch in the middle of the
country or middle of the state rather.
Right.
But I'm getting it that way.
To me it feels.
When I,
before I started hunting,
I had decided I was either going to be a
Vegan or I was going to be a hunter.
I'm like,
I'm going to figure it out.
What I'm going to do.
I didn't want to eat.
You don't want to take part in that.
When you,
when you killed the elk,
right?
When you shoot it,
do you have like,
like what's the feeling there?
That must be intense.
It's very intense.
There's a moment,
there's definitely a moment of loss.
Will you feel like,
you know,
this animal is,
is gone now,
you know,
and,
but there's also a moment of reverence
and awe,
but you got to do it sustainably.
Like when I do it,
I'm doing it in places that have
extremely healthy populations.
You get an animal that's past its
breeding prime,
right?
You get an animal that's seven,
eight,
nine years old where they really don't
have much time left you.
That's what you target.
Like people think when you target a
trophy animal,
you again barry,
you're very specific about you know,
what you're doing very specific and I'm
also specific about making a difficult,
which is why I do it with a bow and
arrow.
I don't,
you know,
I mean I've hunted animals with rifles
and I don't think there's anything wrong
with it,
but for me I feel like if I really want
to make this a more even arrangement and
make it more difficult and make it more
ethical,
I use a bow and arrow.
Yeah.
But there is that high.
Like you know,
you,
you've killed it and then you feel a
sense of loss.
There is a sense of loss.
It's c,
that's what we've run across a bunch of.
This is one of the things that once you
get into the natural world and really
started understanding what's going on
out there,
you realize like this is this.
No one gets out of this ride alive with
this.
This like the ALC that I killed hae had
holes all over his body,
all over his body when we were taking
them apart.
Holes everywhere from other elk stabbing
him.
Oh,
that's what you look up there.
All that shit,
those,
those elk antlers,
those real,
that's real.
That's the one that I shot in September,
that those things are designed to kill
other elk.
They slash each other.
They clash and smash those horns
together and it's all to fight over
breeding.
And the most powerful ones with the
biggest antlers are the ones that get to
breed.
And one of the best ways to ensure the
health of this,
this,
uh,
this group of animals is once this
animal has reached its breeding prime,
that's the one you take out.
You take out the herd bull.
It allows the younger bowls to have an
opportunity to breed.
You can spray genetic wisdom to see the
big dog.
Yeah.
You see the herd,
they call him the herd.
Bull had you learned that?
I got obsessed about five and a half
years ago and got crazy with it.
Food and.
Yeah.
Yeah,
well I got obsessed before actually one
hunting,
but I went hunting in 2012 was the first
time I went and then once I did,
once I did that and I was like,
okay,
this is what I'm doing now.
Like this makes sense.
This is.
And it's difficult.
So it's a pursuit.
So my food now isn't just food that I
got.
Now.
There's this like this intense
connection with that food.
Nobody's got a fucking connection with
their food.
People don't.
But the weird thing is everyone did
until about 100 years ago.
That's what really crazy.
This is so new.
So new.
Yeah.
You got a 19,
17.
Everybody had probably seen an animal
get killed on a farm on farms.
I mean everybody was.
You were around it.
It was a normal thing.
You go with 18 slash 17,
you couldn't avoid it.
You go to a marketplace,
you'd go to a farmer,
you go to.
I mean everybody and then also there was
no pesticides.
The genetic manipulation of the food was
nonexistent.
It was,
it was everything was as it is in a
natural state or in a,
in a cultivated state where you know
you're splicing things and doing normal
things that people do gone like,
like my favorite target topic,
haven't we got just the wrong way?
Well,
we've definitely gone away,
you know,
but that way that we've gone in in the
negative ways is terrible.
But in the positive ways of things like
golden rice,
that's allowed thousands if not millions
of people to not starve to death because
it's rice that was infused with protein.
There's a bunch of different things that
we've done to ensure the shelf life of
foods.
So get the food to the hungry people
because these foods can last longer.
Like tomatoes,
they look kind of fucked up now because
they're hard and you know that these
also can stay on the shelves for a lot
longer.
Like,
and this goes back to what we're talking
about,
like post World War II,
people were terrified of scarcity.
There were terrified of famine and they
were terrified of the idea of going back
to war again and not having a stockpile
of food and resources.
So this is it all.
It's all bad now.
It's all bad when you go down the food
aisle and most of this shit has sugar in
it and simple refined carbohydrates and
it's killing people and giving people
just organic markets are mostly.
Yeah.
I try to get organic farmers markets to
farmers.
I liked the feeling I got was growing
the tomatoes.
Yeah.
You walk it fucking supermarkets and the
bright lights all the fucking.
It feels like you've walked into that
corporate death,
you know,
and they call sugar white death,
right?
Yeah,
it is.
I mean,
it's,
you're not supposed to have a sweet
tooth too.
I have a lot of things to work on.
It's so fun.
You know,
I get overwhelmed by that shit.
I get like,
God
damn it.
You know,
and,
and check this out.
I've,
I've been working out with a trainer for
the last year and a half,
three times a week with like this guy a
lot.
Yeah.
But you know,
I'm such an idiot that I work with them
and I'm like,
well,
I'm okay,
I'm good.
Now I can have this shit.
You know what I mean?
It's insane what I do like my little
reward.
I've,
I've liked that child.
I'm a child who is lights when the
lights are so funny.
I got to fucking change that other part
of you.
And you know,
it's so funny because we're having this
conversation and what happens to me is
I'll be driving ongoing.
Well,
that's fucking it.
This is my state of state of mind.
I'll go,
that's fucking it.
You know,
this is.
Yeah,
a fucking Rogan.
You know,
he just hammered home.
What I already know about,
you know,
it's,
it's got it.
The sugar's got to go.
The process.
CARBS got to go.
Then you said cupcake.
The fucking rationalizations and
justifications of really style.
It's fucking new year.
Yeah.
It's almost Christmas.
It's almost thanksgiving.
Thanksgiving is another 360 days.
Yeah.
It's normal that I'm on a shoot in,
in June,
in January.
Uh,
and I'm like,
ah,
they don't have any good food here.
I gotta have something,
you know what I mean?
It is.
I'll have a cookie.
Yeah,
it's a bitch.
You gotta write it down.
Write down what you want to do.
Write down what you're allowed to eat.
Someone else.
So a couple of the people told me the
write down thing helps writing down,
writing down things helps with
everything I wrote down on that because
you now you have to,
you have an obligation.
It's like one of the things that uh,
uh,
Thompson,
Bert Kreischer and Arusha fear and I did
sober October.
Oh yeah.
You went through all that.
No booze,
no pod.
You liked that?
It was educational.
I think it's important to do.
I think it's good to do.
I think I liked pot.
I'm a big fan and I like the occasional
drink.
I like a glass of wine with dinner.
I like that.
But it's also good to abstain.
Just having an addictive personality.
I do,
but I don't.
but I don't let it.
I,
you will it?
Yeah.
I keep that bitch in check,
but I can let it go crazy if I wanted to
quit pot because I felt interesting,
like I just would love to smoke all the
time and I'd be like,
well,
this movie,
I'd be like,
this movie's going to be great on it.
Fucking Joe.
Yeah,
it's.
Hi Tanya.
Tonya.
It's kind of like,
like to me what pot did it was like this
got to make like cvs and I'm going to
cvs and if I smoke it's going to be a
fun fucking trip because Weirdos at CV,
especially in silver lake,
but you know what I mean.
So,
so.
But what happened was that I felt like I
wasn't
doing my creative work.
Like what happened was the weed was
taking me totally.
Again,
I'm a child like taking me totally into
this.
I just want to pleasure myself the whole
day and I couldn't buckle down and do
work with.
That's a real problem with comics that a
lot of us struggle with.
Having the kind of discipline that's
required to get work done.
You know?
It's like you're really funny,
but you don't produce any new stuff
because you're impulsive because you're
kind of silly.
I think writing things down helps a lot.
Having rules that was going to say about
this sober October thing.
I knew that I couldn't do any of this
thing and I knew that I had to do 15,
90 minute yoga sessions in this month.
We had a rule and we were also
accountable to each other,
so we all knew that we had to get this
done.
Community.
Yeah.
Community and,
and you know,
talking shit to each other on text
messages all the time,
you know,
like we were constantly fucking with
each other and having a good time.
I mean,
it was really fun.
It was really fun,
but it was also very educational.
But knowing that I have these
requirements,
so I give myself requirements.
I write down things every day,
every month,
every week,
every week or every.
Occasionally it's daily.
If,
uh,
this is like a big list of Shit I have
to do,
but like I have to write five days a
week.
I have to write for one hour,
five days a week.
You have to.
That's where the stuff comes from and if
I write more hours,
great.
That's great.
But at least five hours a week.
What if I miss a day?
If something happens the next day I
require two hours.
Okay.
So you know around to a plan.
You have two other ones.
Do that with food and you do it with.
Yeah.
See that's what I do also for food.
I do intermittent fasting.
This is my rule where I only eat for 10
hours a day.
So for 14 hours a day I don't eat at
all.
So whatever that cutoff is.
So say if I eat my last meal,
my last bite,
I don't eat until 10:00 in the morning
the next day period.
So if I get up at seven,
that means for three hours I'm not
eating shit.
I'll work out.
I'll maybe have some coffee.
Yeah,
I do a lot of workouts with no food.
That's cool to do.
I always think,
oh,
I'm going to get low blood sugar in
paths out.
No,
that's bullshit,
Huh?
Yeah,
you'd be fine.
It'll be fine.
It's just harder.
It's just you don't feel good while
you're doing it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But if you're used to doing it,
you can't have coffee.
Yeah.
Coffee.
Yes.
That helps suppress your appetite and it
gives you a little,
a little pick me up.
Yeah.
It's a psychological boost,
you know,
like,
have a nice cup of coffee,
then I'll go hit the gym.
Yeah.
But I definitely feel better if I have
something to eat first.
You know,
it's amazing how I resist structure.
Of course.
You're a funny man.
Uh,
this is,
this is a reoccurring theme with so many
funny friends.
It is crazy impulsive,
funny,
but you're also the guy where if there's
a group of people sitting around and
they're all a bunch of fucking suits and
they're all boring people,
I'm going to gravitate immediately to
you because you and I are going to talk
real.
We're going to be silly and you're going
to say some fucked up shit that I'm
going to laugh at and we're going to be
slapping each other on the back and how
that's what you do.
Men.
But you have to,
you gotta manage
this Portland with me.
I swear to God,
you know,
I'm so anti corporate.
Um,
um,
so kind of an anti anti government.
I don't know what this anti
authoritarian streak,
you know,
it might've been from my dad who was the
Sicilian motherfucker,
right.
I any kind of course construction.
Right.
But stop and think about this.
You're talking in a microphone that was
made by a corporation you got here,
I texted you on your phone,
which was made by slave labor in China.
You got here and your car,
which was probably constructed overseas,
right?
Yeah.
Honda.
See,
this is we need corporations because you
and I are not going to build fucking
planes.
Okay.
Boeing is required to make sure those
planes get done correctly.
I just want them to do it in a way
that's a gala tyrion and not fucking
over people and you know,
but it's just like,
it's really convenient to put that Che
Guevara tee shirt on and fuck that guy
guy.
Fuck Society Man.
I mean it's,
it's so tempting.
And in your inclinations are all
correct.
Your heart is in the right place,
you're your instincts are all good.
He's like you.
You don't want people to get fucked over
and you rightly realized that a lot of
this materialism and this fucking
corporate bullshit is pointless.
If,
like you said at the beginning of this
podcast,
we're all going to die and we need to
face that and stopped just collecting
shit and instead work on having a great
experience in the moment because this
moment that you have right now,
this is all you'll ever have,
is the moment you can plan to make that
moment better in the future with more
discipline and more structure and more
happiness and and even more like
scheduling community events and
scheduling things.
You think you know military.
It's hilarious that I don't know any
military.
I know a lot.
Yeah,
no law.
Is the discipline good for the gigantic.
Huge.
My friend Jocko,
he wrote Jocko Willink,
wrote a book called discipline equals
freedom.
See,
that's what I need to fucking go toward.
Do you need to follow Jocko?
Every morning at 4:30 in the morning,
he posts a picture of his watch as he
gets up to work out,
which is named Jocko willink.
I'll,
uh,
I'll send you his instagram,
send to this,
but he's a,
he's a,
like a bonafide savage navy seal and the
guys God damn animal and every morning
at 4:30 he works out and then he goes
and watches the sun,
come up on the beach and that is his
reward.
That's his reward.
So he gives himself that.
It's all this stuff done that he has to
do during the day.
See the aftermath.
Like he'll post pictures of like his go
to is actual page and see all the photos
of his watch for 30 2:00 AM there is up
and you know,
his heart in the right place to,
oh,
he's a good guy,
great guy,
great guy.
And he spends a lot of his time right
now I'm doing these corporate seminars
and uh,
you know,
like explaining to people the importance
of leadership and discipline and that,
you know,
is this how you get things done is say
you feel better.
This is how you relieve yourself of your
demons,
your tension and his concept of
discipline equals freedom really
resonates because if you have the
discipline to get things done,
then you feel like I don't feel good
unless I've accomplished this shit I
need to do,
but when I have accomplished should I
then I like to kick back on the couch
and watch a boxing match or a television
show that I enjoy.
I can enjoy it where I don't have
anxiety,
I have fucking anxiety if I don't get
things done.
I think that's,
you know,
it's funny because I started the podcast
talking about anxiety ed and I'm
thinking it's all about community and
disconnection and for me it may be this
just a more kind kinda days I have
instead of fucking going,
okay,
I'm going to do this,
this and this to give me a little
structure that would probably alleviate
a bunch of a bunch of it.
But community is important too.
We fucking need each other.
You know,
it's one of the,
like we were talking about the comedy
store and I wish everybody had something
like the comedy store,
you know,
I used to have a pool hall lot I used to
go to that was like that where I would
be everywhere I would be.
I'd be like,
ah,
I can't wait to get back to executive
billiards and hang out with all my
friends.
And it was like this freak show where it
was all these Weirdos was ambler,
white plains,
New York.
Oh,
okay.
And all these Weirdos and gamblers and
strange little outcasts of society and
lifelong bachelors who were in their
seventies and we'd all get together and
laugh and hang out until fucking 4:00 in
the morning and then go get something to
eat and a comic.
But this was like a home base and I
think the comedy store and a lot of
ways.
Delis.
Hey,
let's wrap this bitch up.
It's 2:00 already.
Okay.
How quick was that?
Just went by.
It was great.
Eddie.
I had a good time,
man.
Often I had a great time and and I think
I'm going to change my life.
Change Eddie pepitone,
goddammit,
and follow Eddie on twitter and on
instagram as well.
Eddie pepitone on both of those.
Eddie pep on instagram.
Eddie pepitone having twitter,
Eddie Papeles and gentlemen,
but boom.