Hello Freak bitches.
When we chipping away at this thing,
like we know that politicians are doing
an act.
We know that there when,
you know,
I've always mocked the way they
communicate,
like the way that give speeches with
long pauses and this very distinct
pattern of behavior that's completely
alien to anything other than a political
speech.
Like the only way this country survives,
you know,
like that kind of the strange thing that
they do.
But when,
when we're always like chipping away at
that were always trying to like,
get to like be real key,
get look,
we gotta get,
we gotta find out what's real and then
we get this guy who realer than anyone's
ever been.
Yeah.
And we're like,
well,
fuck this.
This is crazy.
And it scares us.
That's the point of that documentary.
We like to be lied to.
Wwe.
It makes us all feel calm and
comfortable to be given a stable live
than to be showing the real truth of how
fucked up and unstable everything.
Yeah.
I mean,
the trailer has this tech stover over
just like stock footage.
It's just,
and it's so scary.
It's,
uh,
the,
the words are,
uh,
politicians lie to us.
We know,
they lie,
they know,
we know,
they lie,
they just don't care.
And I always like sent chills down my
spine because it's so true and everybody
knows it.
And yet we're all engaged in this
willful suspension of disbelief.
Like,
no,
everything's good.
No,
no.
Both Americans,
both the greatest country on earth and
it needs to be made great again.
It's like we're all in this weird,
like we're unclear on what were even
arguing for that is guys like do crazy,
insane cardio.
Bisping's got insane.
Cardio and the Diaz Brothers Cardio.
Yeah.
Nick has swam back from Alcatraz five
times.
Me.
Whoa.
Five Times.
I said twice once.
And he corrected me online.
He said five now,
but they,
they can fit race every year.
They compete in triathlons all the time.
Yeah.
Oh My,
you know,
my,
my dad,
uh,
actually,
he was in a plane crash in his early
twenties and it was off San Francisco
and need to swim a couple of miles and
that water real survive and Holy Shit,
he crashed into the water.
Yeah.
Most people don't know that it's,
it's,
it's pretty crazy.
He and,
and I'm going to,
I'm going to butcher the details,
but,
uh,
just,
you know,
from growing up,
this is
exactly,
um,
but what happened was he was in the army
and uh,
it was right around the time the Korean
War was starting and he was,
they were flying,
they're doing a routine flight or
something and they had to crash land in
the ocean and it was getting night.
And I,
I believed,
I believed the pilot died and I could be
wrong on that.
The pilot died.
But his other guy,
he was with survived.
So him and him and,
uh,
this other guy,
they were there was swimming to shore
and they got split up cause it was
getting dark at night.
Whoa.
And so then now they're swimming alone.
And anyone who knows,
you know San Francisco is cold room.
Yeah,
definitely.
Jazz water dump.
Dump,
dump,
dump.
That's where they breed.
Yeah.
Early.
Great.
Whites breed in northern California.
There's like a nesting ground up there.
Yeah.
Fuck on now.
Or you want to crash a plane?
They're not where you want to swim from
Alcatraz five times either in your
underwear.
I know.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I didn't know.
I guess I've heard of that race.
They know,
but that's crazy.
You've done that.
Yeah.
Wow.
So your dad had a swim two miles.
Yes.
I'm like that made more.
I could have been more,
he'd fuck,
but it was a long,
I'm going for a couple hundred yards.
I started looking for a log to hang
onto.
And what is the difference in the
results from someone who does that?
Because I know quite a few people who've
done it that way.
They've had injuries treated where they
suck the fat out are
there isn't any,
uh,
any research to differentiate like one
of these treatments versus another yet
it's just not available.
So it's all anecdotal.
It's terms of like talking to patients.
It's happening.
I mean people are collecting the data
but it's just not,
you know,
it's not at the mature stage where,
um,
you know,
where it's available and we have,
published stuff to look at and,
and personally know of anybody who's had
really good results using the fat
method.
Um,
yes,
actually,
uh,
a physician friend of mine in Memphis,
Tennessee,
her name's doctor Laura Lenderman.
Um,
she has utilized that quite a bit and
she's been very happy with the patients
that she's treated in.
Naturally.
Some people do better than others,
but you know,
the,
the real,
the rigorous study of this though is
still yet to come.
That's really fascinating.
Do you,
have you considered trying that or you
just definitely,
yeah.
But you don't so far you just do,
the stem cells haven't had anybody
specifically request it and uh,
everybody wants to lose a little fat and
fix her knees.
Yeah,
I mean that's,
that's probably taking things in a
direction I don't want to be going.
But by plastic surgery there are,
we know there are a number of different
options in terms of where these sources
of the cells can come from.
Um,
bone marrow is certainly,
um,
had a lot of use and Daniel Needs da had
that done.
That's what he told me.
Yeah.
He had a pulled out of his hip and he
said it was brutally painful then he was
walking with a limp for like two weeks.
It's a,
obviously it's a procedure.
Um,
there's pain and there's,
you know,
morbidity.
There's a consequence to,
you know,
putting a sharp object into the bone and
drawing that bone marrow.
So it means,
uh,
a bad thing.
I don't like that word now.
It's,
we don't like it either.
In medicine,
more bid is,
we have our word,
we have conferences called morbidity and
mortality.
And that's where he basically own up to
things that you've done a terrible job
with or explain,
you know,
why somebody has died as a result of
your care.
And it's a awful thing to go through.
And it's critically important to be able
to evaluate yourself and understand what
things happen when they don't go the way
that we want them to.
So it's an important exercise that
physicians go through to,
you know,
review cases.
So I can only imagine.
Yeah,
no,
I mean,
especially if you're dealing with people
that are broken apart.
I mean,
essentially as an orthopedic surgeon,
you're dealing with people's bodies a
failed,
right?
Your limbs have failed,
ligaments have torn off.
The bone and knees have exploded.
I mean,
you've told me some gnarly stuff in
terms of the kind of injuries that you
had to treat,
and I could only imagine some of bad
things.
Yeah.
Okay.