Three,
two,
one.
Jamie was giving us the,
the almost double of gun finger.
Not Yes.
One Papa Sam's glasses.
You got a new look right now,
buddy just said fuck it.
While they're their uh,
their uh,
reading glasses dirty.
They're dirty.
They're progressive's.
What's that mean?
That means that the top.
Oh,
look,
yes.
Three levels.
Oh,
far.
Medium reading.
Fuck Dude.
What are they going to fix?
That?
It's pretty good.
I fixed what your eyes?
Yeah.
I only have,
um,
I have reading glasses that I've worn
over the last few years,
like two or three years.
I think I hit like 46 and that's when it
just started going eee.
Like I'd look at my phone like,
hey,
why does that look like shit?
It really is bad.
And then Adam Carolla did my podcast and
he left some glasses over who loved
reading glasses and I picked up his
reading glasses and I put them on.
I went,
fuck,
I can see,
I can fucking see clear now.
I know it's really frustrating
and uh,
I can't wear contacts because I have a
scar on this eyeball.
Low from A.
I don't know what from the only thing I
can think of is he said it was something
as a child,
there was a pillow fight I had with my
friend Keith in like third grade and I
remember him hitting me in an open eye
and just being down for awhile.
But just as kids,
you know,
you're like,
oh,
that hurt.
Right.
But you only thing I could.
Totally,
yeah,
there's a scar on the outer layer of my
eyeball.
Can they do something about that?
And they like,
no,
I mean you can start messing with it
with this guy is a really good eye
doctor.
And he's like,
don't mess with it if you don't have to.
But if I look through that,
I,
it's a little cloudy always even with
the glasses.
So this one,
uh,
because of the little bumpy scar I can't
put a contact on so they'll go with the
glasses.
But uh,
you say it's a new look when I don't
have glasses on,
I just had these glasses for like two
years.
But everyone I've
get used to people wearing glasses,
like greg fitzsimmons wears glasses and
sometimes he doesn't wear glasses and
I'm like,
Oh man,
what do you like better?
What's Tom Papa to you?
I just like you buddy.
Oh,
I don't really care if you wear glasses.
The glasses or the odd thing that makes
girls sexy.
There's something about a girl wearing
glasses.
It's kind of sexy.
Yeah.
Worked in every eighties movie.
What's always like girls pulled up with
their hair,
pulled up tight blouse,
a skirt,
dropping off papers.
Why is that?
I don't know.
A smart girl is sexy.
Yeah.
And then at the end of the movie takes
it off and gets all slutty and lets her
hair down.
Yeah.
Is it like an alternative thing?
Is that like what it is?
Like you see the girl with the glasses
and you like,
oh,
she's different.
She's out reading and
she's focused.
Yeah.
She's got her act together.
Shit,
what shouldn't be?
She'll be able to see my flaws.
Maybe she can help me.
She'll know if I really read those
books.
I don't know if you think it's the same
for kids now though,
because there's so many weird looking
kids now.
Like when we were young it was like the
glasses girl or like the blind girl,
that cheerleader girl.
Now everything's so much together.
You mean like what is attractive?
Just like the classifications of people.
We had like teams that you were a part
of the job or the nerd or the burn out?
I was a jock and a class clown.
Oh you were a class clown.
But like,
but like I had a lot of friends because
I was the class clown so it wasn't a,
it wasn't a douchey.
You just liked sports?
Yeah,
it was A.
I played football from kindergarten till
I graduated and then uh,
I was the captain.
I was all league.
No shifts.
Spoil you.
Tom.
Papa.
I was a fullback.
How many a head collisions did you have?
Tons.
How's your head?
Fine.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean it all depends who you're playing
against.
You know what I mean?
Like we were a white suburban school
running into other suburban kids that
were going like this.
We played,
we played in a scrimmage.
PASSAIC,
passaic,
New Jersey is like one of the big
cities,
you know,
and they had ironhead heyward.
Remember that guy?
He went pro,
big man's giant man size black man from
passaic and we scattered like deer.
Just we saw him coming after our all
white league and then not just a black
guy,
but like an ultimate job.
Oh my God,
look at this size of that guy.
He,
when you see them,
especially with football pads on the
shoulder pads,
you're like,
oh my God,
how big is that guy?
If they would just hand them the ball
and just tell them to run straight,
what are you going to do about that?
That's so not fair.
That's why I think fighting is so much
safer because there's weight classes.
Yeah.
Like a dude like me and a guy like that
should never be involved in an
altercation.
Not Fair.
How big is he?
Oh,
he's only five slash 11 slash 65.
Jesus Christ so thick.
He's a tank from his back to his front.
On the side was probably six feet thick.
You have to be to be five slash 11 slash
65.
That's what Mark Hunt is.
Mark Hunt the a kickboxer reference in
the UFC.
He's so sick.
He's like five,
10,
five,
11 to 65.
Just a massive,
massive Samoan though he's the Super
Samoan,
like samoans in general are really
powerful people.
It's just a thick people.
They are a durable,
powerful race of people.
It's amazing because you need to think
about it.
Those people,
the
and his island folk,
they were traveling in canoes back and
forth across the oceans.
They probably.
It probably required severe physical
strength.
Right?
But when you see Polynesians,
Hawaiians,
a lot of them,
they're fucking stout people.
Big Time Midi.
Well just like just solid built,
fucking powerful.
But there are big download too,
so when you're in a canoe,
you're just all upper body,
but they kind of carry those canoes to
men.
You've got to carry stuff.
You're probably packing out your camps
and running up hills and eating coconuts
with your feet.
Well,
how would you do that?
You hold the Samoans.
They were able to hold the canoes over
their head and then pick up coconuts
with their toes as they walked and bite
it.
Like an apple.
No,
that's not true.
Almost had me son of a bitch.
I was like,
wow.
I was going over my head.
I was doing it like I was.
I was mimicking it.
Why would they put the commute down?
I mean,
how,
what kind of a hurry are they in that he
can't pick up on?
Looking at the whole thing was so
confusing and then when you said bite it
like an APP on my.
He got me.
No,
but wow.
I was a kid playing football.
There was,
there was.
I kind of went between groups,
but there were the jocks and the
burnouts where the kids get into high in
the back and then there were the band
kids.
My kids are in school now.
They don't.
Those classifications don't really exist
anymore.
Yeah.
They're like Bros,
jocks and skaters and yet we're so old.
We shouldn't be talking about these
kids.
They're going to be mad like you don't
even know what the fuck you're talking
about.
Old Man.
Well,
I literally.
Yeah,
because yeah,
I don't go to.
I'm not in seventh grade.
I got to ask questions and they don't.
A smart girls get high.
Wow.
A bookworm docs are in choir.
It's more acceptable to be yourself.
They grew up in a time when you could be
anything and do anything.
No one and no one shit on you for trying
things that real.
It's real.
That's amazing.
If that's true.
It's totally true.
They have a whole different way of
looking at the world.
They don't.
They look at the way we were raised as
animals,
just saying the mean shit to other
people and people just shitting on you
for trying anything that we look at that
like it's cavemen times feel like you
would call someone fat what you would
call someone retarded or gay or.
I mean all that stuff is,
you know,
it's a lot of word speak conversation,
but it's manifested itself into the way
these kids were raised and they're
sweeter and kinder.
Wow.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
That's so fascinating.
I know you got to see like real cultural
evolution because if you go back to the
beginning of the 20th century and those
poor people that were surviving through
the depression and you ever read any
books on the depression,
Grapes of Wrath,
there was a
book,
I think it was called mcgurty.
It was,
um,
by a guy named Bob Burns who's a famous,
a billiards historian and he wrote this
book about a Pool Hustler during the
depression that traveled literally by
train car,
like a Hobo from town to town and found
people to gamble with these bars and
they would hustle and pretend they
didn't play very well and lose a little
bit of money.
And then when money,
you know,
that kind of it already.
Yeah.
But it was a really depressing book,
man.
Yeah.
Just people are suffering,
people are suffering.
And there was this one story where he
was literally a knocking on this guy's
house begging for food and the guy
brought him out some sausage and you
know,
and they had like a soup together and he
was just describing the food that this
guy had given him.
And like how,
how wonderful it was and how amazing it
was in that moment.
Like he was literally dying.
Like his body was giving out from hunger
in America,
in America in 1920 9:30
is that when the depression was official
in the stock market crash was 29.
It's so scary that the stock market is a
real thing.
Like I was.
I was trying to explain this to someone
like what my frustration with it is
because I was like,
okay.
He just looked at it this way.
Right?
I know if you're,
if you're a financial person,
you're like,
oh my God,
you're so,
let's do.
But I really think it works that way,
but this is what I'm saying.
If you look at the world and you look at
all the people,
the number of people's tastes constant,
the resources stay constant.
Like there's kind of the same amount of
metal as the same amount of silicon.
This is the same amount of all the
different materials we use to make
things.
The same countries are in place.
The monies to say what the fuck
happened?
That all the sudden everything's
terrible.
Like you had this state where like you
have prosperity,
everything's wonderful,
people are doing great,
then the stock market crashes
and when the stock market crashes,
all these people lose their jobs and
mortgage rates go get fucked up.
Everybody's fucked and this just like
this terrible period of,
of,
of fear.
Right?
But meanwhile the earth is the same.
It's almost like we create these
disasters,
we create these,
these systematic dislike in there like
inside the system that we've created
well as disaster and it's the.
It's the system that we've built to
survive and be able to trade goods and
food and homeless and the structure we
built to live and be safe from the
outside elements on this planet.
Right?
So weird when that thing.
But that thing has to run and it runs by
money and money circulates.
All that stuff all around,
all the time.
There's still money when all that stuff
happens,
but it's up here clogged with these with
very select places and then the rest of
the flow just stopped.
There's no more water coming to these
tributaries anymore that everybody goes
tanking.
Such a goofy system.
You know what that feels like that like
someone
took windows 95 and just kept upgrading
it.
Right now we are in 2017 and we don't
get a new operating system.
We get a new operating system for a
fucking computer,
which is not really that God damn
important.
All in all,
if you could choose between a good
operating system for life,
have a much better,
more,
more updated operating system for,
for civilization or whether or not you
could get online.
You Got Online and 95 you your shit
would work.
Yeah.
You know,
what do you do when you're writing
emails?
You checking your twitter,
how much time do you take online would
work fine.
It would work size a web.
Browsers didn't crash.
You can go to the websites.
It's way more important to have a new
operating system for life.
We don't even touch that stupid thing.
You can't.
It's too massive.
And what really bothers me,
and it's really been on my mind lately,
is that you can't escape the herd.
You can't,
can't right now,
like the.
Everything was really crashing in 2008.
I mean that scenario that you're talking
about where everything just stopped like
all the top people were like,
the economy is grinding to a halt this
afternoon,
that calamity right took everybody's
savings and messed it up and all this
stuff so now and everybody had to go
through it.
Now things have kind of come back and
they're coming back and there's this
trump bump on the stock market.
Things are really going really high and
then some people think it's a bubble and
this is just a false thing and it's
going to crash,
and some people even say it's going to
crash worse than 2008 if things go
really haywire.
My question is,
if we know that,
how do I get out of the way of the
tsunami?
Why do I have to go with everybody else?
Can?
What can I do with my money where I can
be safe from this,
these tides that take everybody?
That's a really good question,
but I think the question that
overwhelmed that question is,
why the fuck are we still doing it like
this?
That seems to be a better question
because this seems crazy.
How are you going to reboot it?
What are you going to do?
Just
are you.
You're right.
I don't know.
I don't have any.
I'm not fucking zero education and
economics.
I know almost nothing about how all that
stuff
stuff works.
I did a show two weekends ago for these
financial people.
Really Fun show,
you know?
It's like their private event.
I'm talking to them after after the show
at the bar we meet and greet kind of
thing and some of these guys who are our
age who are just economic guys,
they're in finance.
They start these conversations about
buying and selling properties and
shifting stocks and bonds and all this
and where did the bond market doing?
It's like they're speaking Chinese
and I felt like a 10 year old kid.
I'm like,
this is what the rich people talk about.
I wish I understood.
Some of you know
what I mean.
You know what it's like to me it's like
when someone starts bringing up like
chess moves when we're talking about
specific chess games,
like Kasparov playing some dude.
Yeah.
And then they start,
you know,
rook to king two or whatever the numbers
are on.
I'm like,
what,
what is he doing?
Like,
what's happening in him?
I knew a guy and he went to prison and
uh,
when he came out of prison he had
learned to play chess in his head.
Oh my God.
So he could sit there and him and this
kid,
there was this kid who is this.
It was a really,
really interesting guy.
It was really tiny kid that used to come
to this pool,
so super smart.
But he was like this little,
like,
like almost like a fucking honeybadger
probably funny kid pool where you can
like pick fights with people.
And he was a tiny little guy,
was so little that people will be like,
why is this guy doing?
But anyway,
he was super fucking smart soup.
I guess he just felt,
yeah,
I felt like,
I guess he felt like he had establishes
his place in the social pecking order
because you're so little.
It was a pool hall and he was a really
smart guy.
So I think it's tragic to yell at
people.
Like one time he yelled at me,
Oh really?
Oh Man.
He was probably like 15 or 16 and I was,
you know,
25.
I was like,
man,
like what are you crazy?
Like what are you doing?
I had to have a conversation with that
dude.
I'm not your,
I'm not your enemy.
We're arguing over a pool game.
You know what's going on?
Yeah.
Don't say you're a take me outside and
go listen to that.
How old are you?
And he goes,
like,
15th.
I go,
dude,
I'm not just listened.
I'm not,
I'm not your enemy.
We're trying to figure out who's right
on a foul foul as foul is whether or not
like maybe a foot off while you're
playing pool and maybe your,
your tip touch the ball before it was
supposed to and you try to ignore it and
then someone calls you on or the hit is
bad.
Like you don't hit the number ball.
You're supposed to have your play nine
ball.
The other guy's supposed to get ball in
hand,
right?
If it's a competitive thing that a
tournament,
those,
those conversations get,
they get pretty emotional.
People got really upset.
Like I definitely did not fall because
all of a sudden he was like trying to
start a fight and how little we have
tall was not big at all.
Okay.
And this was like right after I just
said I just maybe had my last fight and
there's a couple of years before that,
so I was still kickbox and I was still
training all the time and I was like,
this is the craziest conversation I
can't believe I'm having with this
little kid.
And so I pulled them outside.
I go,
we just had,
you know,
just kind of a down to earth,
you gotTa,
you know,
you got to get respect from these
fucking people.
I go,
yeah,
not like someone's going to hit you.
Oh really?
Yeah,
you got to be.
So it was a planned thing because this
fucking kid,
it was cool afterwards because I had
this kind of conversation.
He knew that if we ever did have a
conversation before,
I was never going to go to a bad place.
I was just going to talk to them.
Right.
So it made it a nice thing because he
was a wizard.
He's a really smart kid and,
and for pool is that I like,
is that like chess?
Like.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Vantage.
Yeah,
because you're also smart in the
execution of your shot.
Like one of the things about pool is the
execution of your shots should be almost
effortless.
You rely on your structure,
you rely on your stance,
you rely on your technique and it's
supposed to be like incredibly gentle
and smart people can figure that out
better than dumb people how to get.
Instead of slamming the ball,
instead of using your muscles,
instead they'd stroke the ball where the
weight of the queue is kind of doing all
the work.
The point is,
this kid was so fucking smart that him
and that prison guy would get together
and play chess in their head cheese and
I would sit there like a stupid a pool.
They,
I sat there and I just pulled up a stool
and I just watched them playing chess in
there.
They went through a full game in their
head.
I was like,
this is so crazy.
They know where all the pieces are.
So crazy.
That's what it was like with these
financial guys.
It was like,
you know what?
They're just smarter because even though
I was never that great in math,
I,
I could not have.
My head isn't built for talking about
that stuff.
They're smarter in that area.
That is what it's like when you hear
them talking.
It's like night to rook six.
Like what,
where,
where is that?
What's happening?
Where's the grid?
I don't understand the grit,
but it's even more complex.
So they're talking about dividends,
bonds and fucking I know and they can
make a lot of money because they just
have that knowledge.
Sure.
And some of them start doing coke,
then they get crazy and leave their
families.
Oh Man.
That's like a.
that's what business where people go off
the rails,
but like what can you do to protect
yourself?
Say trump goes off the rails and the
stock market goes down again.
What?
There's nothing you can do right now to
prepare yourself for that.
Well,
you can put your money in cash,
but then it's not growing.
I think the amount of pressure that guys
under is probably unmanageable.
I think very few people can manage that
pressure.
I think that job's insane.
I don't think it should be real.
I don't think it should be a job.
It should be five people.
It shouldn't be a ton of people.
Yeah.
I mean,
I think five people's enough.
I said I don't even know,
man.
I just.
I feel like it almost should be all of
us.
Yeah.
Well,
it just.
It seems like if you wanted to give your
reason,
you,
Tom,
papa wanted to give you a reasons why we
shouldn't be engaging in some sort of a
military action against North Korea or
whatever's next.
You would have to do it.
You have to write it out or you'd have
to record it,
right.
You'd have to give a coherent reason why
you feel and that that,
that,
that would be considered.
So you'd be like one person,
imagine if there's 350 million of us or
whatever the hell it is.
Right now.
Everyone having single opinion,
a new wants to complex comprehensive
opinion on any sort of an action that
any thing in the government is doing
that represents us.
That's what the government is.
I mean there's these people.
It's boiled down to a few people that
are supposed to successfully represent
us and all of our ideas,
but there's no way they could know what
our ideas are.
No,
but you can come close being like,
okay,
this my town,
if you go to Congress and be like,
my state really thinks weed should be
legal.
You know,
the consensus sort of.
Yeah.
Sort of.
I don't know how accurate or inaccurate
and in certain ways.
Right.
It's just,
it seems to me it is.
It is strange though.
I mean to be that president to be one
guy and it really is a thing about,
you know,
there are huge guy,
there is one guy on the top of virgin or
tesla or but they know it's their job to
run things in.
Have people doing stuff for them?
It's almost a job that's more about
poise and intelligence and patients than
it is like taking everybody's thing on.
That's what's so unsettling about the
time right now.
You want someone,
you want dad to be at the steering wheel
and you feel good and safe in the back
seat.
Well,
that's why a lot of people are really
excited about trump because he's
confident and if you're a confident
older man who's successful people like
there's a natural instinct like an Alpha
chimpanzees now it's an Alpha factor,
right?
It's a total.
There's a total instinct to try to
acquiesce and also an instinct.
The challenge is to be a big instinct to
challenge him because of who he is too,
and he sees weaknesses and see we can
swipe out his ankle and it shouldn't
exist.
Folks.
This is this,
this is highlighting what's wrong.
And everybody's like,
yeah,
you don't know anything about politics
and you're right.
I don't.
I know so little about politics.
There's a lot I don't know a lot about.
A lot of things does.
Nobody does,
but I know one thing I know that I can
see patterns and trends.
I see them,
I'm pretty good at it and I see a
pattern and trend in our communication,
in our expression of ideas.
It's like what you were talking about
with kids today.
I'm not surprised by that at all and I'm
excited by it because I think that I
think that people are more openminded
today.
They're,
they're,
they're way smarter than I was when I
was their age.
If you talk to like an average 10 year
old or 11 year old,
they know so much more about how the
world works and I did when I was asking.
The amount of work they have to do in
school is 10 times what we had,
but they're still all being trapped by
the same system,
which they still have the same
educational system,
which I think is fucking bananas.
You make kids go to school all day and
then at the end of that you give them
homework.
How about fuck you?
How many hours in a day is there?
You're preparing people for suck,
but it's what you're doing.
Yeah.
My kids,
they were up til 11:00
at night doing work,
not hanging out,
not screw it around like fuck man.
Working.
That takes away your life life.
It's really important,
especially especially when it's a.
it's a curriculum in the public schools
that is geared towards a manufacturing
middleclass.
Now there's learning in that
way.
Learning like robots,
if you want these kids to,
they could work so much smarter about
more uptodate teaching methods and
things that are going to apply to get
jobs going out.
Then it's like,
all right,
spend a little time on that door.
Also training people to put their energy
into things that don't bring them joy.
They're training a certain kind of
discipline of certain kind of morose,
like dark gray cloud disciplined.
You're totally right to the factory with
a hammer.
Bang,
stay alive.
In order to stay alive,
we have to work.
Bang,
row those fucking boats across the ocean
in your kid like,
but wait,
I just want to board man.
Tony Hawk makes way more than you do,
dad.
I'm so much happier there.
Yeah,
you mean it's so many people that want
to do so many things and they could.
They could,
they could,
but as a parent,
oh fuck,
all that.
I mean,
I'm go for it.
I have,
I got,
I've got two and one is not into school
is not into it.
Pull them out and I got home.
She seems like a comedian.
Like she is.
This sheet she dropped.
She seems the same.
She's funny.
She doesn't care about authority.
She's clever.
Just not into school.
She's probably smart.
She is dad.
She is,
but she's.
But she sees her dad.
He's like,
this guy doesn't do nothing.
Sits around talking shit about bread.
That's right.
That's exactly it.
He's baking bread.
He's always smiling.
Baking bread or going to a show.
Billy's dad just had a heart attack.
Billy's Dad freaking out and he works
for a financial institution.
You don't go to work.
You don't go to the stuff and put as a
parent,
I can't be like,
yeah,
just hang out.
No,
you can't be just hanging out,
but you can be like,
find your groove,
find a thing,
and then get into it.
You know,
I think introducing kids to things that
they can get into,
super important,
but what about the school thing?
Can you,
if your kid,
if your kid brings home sees,
do you get on her or do you say you got
to step it up.
There's a real.
Stepping it up is making her that drone
both.
There's a real problem and it's that
kind of learning is boring.
Like all of a sudden I was not in the
science at school.
I can't get enough science as an adult,
as an adult.
I constantly read scientific American
watch all those science shows on tv
about fucking space in astrology.
They make it look strong.
You rather.
It's fascinating.
The cosmos.
You ever seen the Neil degrasse Tyson
series the best.
I couldn't wait for that thing to come
on every week we celebrated when that
came on.
Look,
science is fascinating.
They find these seven new exoplanets
that they think have it life.
You're like,
Jesus,
I know.
They're like earth.
Amazing.
When I was a kid,
I could not have given less of a fuck.
I didn't care about any of it.
I was like,
why boring teachers?
Math teachers,
hundred percent if Neil degrasse tyson
was my astronomy teacher in school or
taught astrophysics
or whatever and taught it the way he
teaches things.
Like when he talks about stuff he gets
you so excited about the ideas that he's
talking about.
Any cause he's able,
he's intelligent and can explain it in a
way that you'll understand it.
I think his passion for it's real,
like she was really excited by and when
you.
Here's the other thing,
it's almost like it's engineered to be
that way and I don't want to get all
fucking crazy tower seven on anybody,
but if you look at the idea of school
itself,
why the fuck are they paying those
teachers so little.
I mean teachers,
they have arguably the most important
job in developing your child.
Outside of you.
It's you,
the parent and then the teacher?
Yeah,
for sure.
And how many teachers are just kind of
barely getting by with a total ceiling
on how much money that can make your
right?
Because my,
my science teacher was,
he wasn't like being gay.
He was a stressed out chain smoking,
angry guy and bad shitty clothes because
he couldn't afford anything else.
This guys,
life pressures are so huge.
He can't be like jazzed about science.
He's worried about getting kicked out of
his apartment and whether he's get lung
cancer from smoking,
from chain smoking.
If you did pay this guy twice what he
was making,
he'd be relaxed.
He'd be motivated,
he'd be into it.
He could spend more time putting plated,
you know,
but if that's what you want to do,
like if you want to be a teacher,
they go,
well you know how much you are going to
get paid.
Yeah,
but why?
It's one of those things where you're
getting paid that much because people
have decided you're getting paid that
much.
They decided to only allocate a certain
amount of resources towards education,
but meanwhile think about how much more
money they spend on military.
Well,
I was just going to say that there's no
talk right now about increasing spending
for schools.
That's probably the most important thing
we could do is make less losers schools
better.
It's the most.
It is the most important thing,
but is there an advantage to keeping
some part of the population dumb man,
that's the big fight.
I don't think that's the big conspiracy
theory,
right,
but I don't think it's a conspiracy.
I think it is just a convenience.
I think once people are in a community
that's poor,
there is no incentive for the wealthy
people that are in government or running
government to say,
let's allocate a an inordinate amount of
resources to try to rebuild these areas.
They don't benefit from that or people
with money.
The only way you can get them to benefit
from that.
I saw that chance.
The rapper donated a million dollars to
Chicago public school system.
Congratulations to that guy.
That's a fucking awesome human being.
He is a class Berlin.
If you could donate a million,
how much did you make kid?
Hashtag balling.
Yeah,
man.
I just think that it's.
It's not necessarily a conspiracy as
much as it's just easy to ignore now.
The people who don't have political
influence and the people making the
decisions put their kids in school and
they don't have to worry.
Exactly.
You know,
if everybody had to go to their local
public school I,
but things
change.
Well,
it's worse because you're,
you're,
you're making things less safe because
you're creating more crime because you
creating more disenfranchised people and
you're creating more of a need to stay
in your wealthy communities.
Yeah.
He know how it is.
I mean,
it is what it is,
but it's um,
it's something that there's no incentive
to change.
It's not like there's a giant amount of
pressure to look at the same way we look
at.
We have to go to Afghanistan and make
sure it doesn't fall apart.
Maybe.
Are you fucking Chicago's falling apart,
man,
like we're talking about.
It's right there.
What?
You have to go to Afghanistan.
We haven't done shit about Detroit.
Detroit is completely full.
There's a lot of fucked up spots in this
country where there's dangerous.
Was Flint still doesn't have good water,
right?
Yeah.
Is that still going on in Flint,
Michigan?
Worse now because they're cutting out
the abolishing the clean water acts,
so it's gonna get worse.
What's going to happen?
Look,
we all are nervous about a lot of
different things.
My only focus is the environment and
what's going on with that because that I
care the most about and I don't like my
kids to be sick.
It's also something you can't pull back
everything in reversing every emission
cars.
They're going to come to California who
has the most advanced emissions controls
and it's working.
They're going to force California to
lessen the emissions restrictions the
way that the rest of the country is,
and they're going to go back like 20
years.
They're changing emissions there.
You know what they're doing.
They're not funding satellites that keep
track of global,
of a,
of climate change.
They're going to cut off the information
so you don't complain when you're.
When Miami's underwater,
they're putting a waste back in in the
waters.
They're taking all the regulations off
the head of the EPA is the guy who sued
the shit out of the EPA,
hates the EPA.
They're tearing it all down.
Can I ask you a question?
Tom?
Drilling for drilling for gas in
yellowstone,
you want to see that?
This is where they're opening the door
for all of this.
Just.
Yes.
You can ask me a question.
Are you a cook?
What?
Do you know what that means?
No.
People who are anti trump when you are
a.
that's a cop.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
my only focus is what's going to happen
with you.
It's also more like a demo.
What is the official definition?
Again?
It used to be cuckold based on cuckold,
which is who likes watching other men
fuck his wife because there's a whole
level of porn and then what's the
official definition?
Now?
It was confusing to us,
but sort of a political thing.
It's sort of like pretending you're
progressive when you're not new one.
Oh,
is a new one,
and insulted reveals sexual insecurity,
misogyny
and fear of those who use the term.
Oh,
that's so ridiculous.
So ridiculous.
Britain Gq magazine.
What does cook me?
Why are you being called one week
feckless?
Spineless,
and decidedly pathetic.
Specimen of manliness is a derivative of
the turn.
Okay,
so that makes sense.
Huckle anger.
Why people?
Why angry?
White people love calling people.
I agree with white men is Christ.
It's a fun word to call.
People prefer.
It was insulting when you said it really
felt like,
say it on the news,
you know,
you're just like fuck,
but it's with so it.
Well,
he's a cook.
That's the problem.
The newscasters be like,
we'll be right back with the weather.
They didn't even know what to say.
You just stay right there and you can
even say the word cuckold Coquille.
He loves cuckold Erotica.
You could probably say that on regular
TV and they would not.
They would not be able to do anything
about it.
Wow.
That'd be stuck and you've just painted
a ruthless image in their mind.
Some poor sobbing man.
Some fucking dude that looks like iron
head is laying pipe to the lady.
They take you off to the green room
book.
We know you can say,
can you just not.
Those people need to stop all those
people that tell you we know you can,
but you shouldn't.
Yeah.
Don't say that word.
Just junk you.
Fuck you.
And your magic words.
What do you have child?
There's certain words you can't say.
That is another thing that has to go and
it's being more and more highlighted by
the Internet.
It's why you're seeing in,
in television shows,
like if you watched the walking dead,
you'll see a lot of random use of
swears,
you know,
and you'll hear a random use of swears
on other shows on cable,
say shit during their TV sets.
Yes.
Shit is okay.
We've,
we've changed it,
but you can't,
you still can't say fuck if you,
if you watch walking dead,
they've,
I don't think they ever say fuck,
I'm pretty sure if they do know,
I'm pretty sure they just say shit and
asshole.
And they could say tits.
And My last Cole Bear,
which I did in December,
ish,
they said,
uh,
I couldn't say fly open one ball out.
Hmm.
I could say fly open one testicle out or
I could say fly open everything out.
But couldn't say one ball duct Stan hope
came up with an idea.
Um,
when we were doing our version of the
mantra that was a big fat failure.
But a doug came up with this idea to do.
I'm a game show where a dude had a box
over his private areas and a light would
go off whenever it was like,
like your direction.
So the light was red light.
We control the light obviously.
So it'd be like dwarves eating bananas.
Light goes off,
like guys
hairy as light goes off.
And they told us Doug's name for the
show was make me hard and they told us
we couldn't have it called make me hard.
We had to change it to make me stiff.
Right.
And we were like,
what?
Why?
And they're like hard just too,
it's just not the right word.
We think make me step.
And these,
these two ladies that were talking to
her that had nothing to do with comedy,
like literally nothing.
Like how is it stiff is actually more
offensive.
It's like,
it sounds like a really a dumb person.
He gets ready to take my fucking stiffy
and yet discussing.
So when we were,
uh,
when we're,
when we're doing this,
this light obviously we controlled.
So we played this game show so we
couldn't call it make me hard,
which,
how to change it to make me Steph.
We lost the argument.
It was the stupidest fucking argument.
And it was so indicative of how
frustrating those shows can be.
We have all these fucking chefs in the
kitchen.
I just think it'd be better if he was
wearing blue underwear better.
It would look better.
Um,
so he,
um,
the guy's lying there and we have this
woman come out and she's got these big
juicy tits and he's sucking on them and
she's climbing on him and everybody's
going,
Ooh.
And they put a whip cream on her tits
and he's sucking the whipped cream,
offer nipples and moves like heavy duty
stuff.
Then she pulls her pants down.
She's got a Dick,
right?
Not only does she have a Dick,
she has a dick that looks like it had
been poisoned,
you know,
because she's a transvestite transsexual
rather bubbly woman coming because like
the estrogen,
it was like kid killed the deck.
Oh No.
It's like dark.
And like it was like a crispy French
fries.
You get to Jerry's Deli like,
Whoa,
but that was okay.
That was okay.
Yeah,
I mean we had a blur the deck,
but that was okay.
You just can't use the word hard.
So weird.
So stupid.
Hard to bad word is hard to bad word.
Fuck off.
Testicle sounded worse than ball to me.
One testicle out it.
Testicle sounds.
Look,
what about that?
It's kind of fun.
Half sack half's heck out.
Says Negus said fuck a few times in that
scene where he was a bad scene.
I guess that was censored version where
he says like 23 times and uncensored
version.
I didn't see the real workers and so
that was the scene that made me stop
watching that show.
It was like,
that's it.
What am I watching?
I'm watching torture show.
This isn't a fun show anymore.
This isn't a show where people trying to
get away from zombies.
The zombies are inconsequential.
You can like push them aside now used to
eat horses,
raw terror horse apart and right now you
can just kind of trip them and push
them.
Devops,
it's so stupid.
Nobody gets killed by zombies.
Everybody gets killed by each other.
I was like,
it's just so stupid.
It's been on a long time.
That's enough.
Yeah.
I wasn't enough.
I think I watched one season.
Yeah,
I just can't.
If it
was like 28 days later,
zombies,
I think it'd be way better.
I think.
Yeah,
there's something about the fact these
zombies are so fucking slow and they
never seem to starve to death.
Like explain to me how they're still
going.
They brains,
but there's no one to eat.
They're all zombies.
The known each other,
which is bizarre.
It's fuck.
What do you have like Zombie rules
cannibalize each other.
How come you fucks are running around
looking for people that are moving and
you're moving and you don't need each
other.
You have cloudy eyes.
You could barely see.
All people have to do is cover
themselves with guts and blood and they
pass as a Zombie and they walk around
you.
That's all I gotta do.
Fuck out of here.
Yeah,
it makes me mad.
It makes me mad.
That's ridiculous.
Making up their own Zombie ass rules.
Yeah.
Fuck you.
And your Zombie rule.
Stick with the plan.
See those 28 days later.
Zombies.
Those are the fast ones.
The ones I liked.
The ones that look like they're on
rabies.
Yeah.
Just chase you.
Those,
those.
Uh,
I saw those in thousand oaks.
You saw Zombie like that?
Yeah.
Like a whole.
Her real one.
Yeah.
I think it was going on.
I was just a.
what's that?
Was there a sale?
There was black Friday sale.
It was black Friday.
Is that the worst thing that we do as.
As a culture?
It's A.
Yeah.
Trample over each other on the way
through Walmart.
Yeah.
Who Does?
Who does that?
Yeah.
I don't do it.
Do you do it?
I don't do it,
but a lot of people do it.
What?
People are good.
I don't know.
People on TV.
My kids want to do it.
My kids don't let them do it.
People not disgusting.
Well,
it's just ridiculous.
Yeah,
but you'd line up outside of a store and
you save $10 or whatever the fuck you
say.
Crap.
Yeah.
How much you save?
Who Cares?
Why don't you make a nice little card
instead of going to.
You know what though?
There's things that become things like
somehow or another they just become
events like I'm used to be devil's night
in Detroit,
which was the day before Halloween.
Was Lighthouses on fire Devil's night.
Yeah.
It was arson night,
wasn't it?
Is that what it's called?
Devil's night.
See?
See if you literally light people's
homes with them in it.
Well,
I don't know.
We had cabinets.
Shirts happened.
You'd throw eggs at the cops and a
habit.
It was called cabbage night the night
before when I was a cabbage old Timey,
New Jersey.
One time.
There was cabbage in the fields.
Angel's night.
Um,
it's an event designed to mitigate
criminal acts associated with Devil's
night in Detroit after brutal is Devil's
night in 1994.
Then new mayor Dennis.
Archer.
Promise city residents are.
Will not be tolerated.
Yeah,
Devil's night is a scroll down to see
this a.
It didn't catch on though.
Yeah.
Well,
the devil's night thing apparently was
going on a lot.
We would hear about it in high school.
She really look at the flaming bags of
canine feces in front of portraits.
Always fun canine feces like shit.
You can't even say who says feces you
put talking to.
It's A.
Well,
if you said Shit,
I would have never known what you were
saying.
So thank you for saying fishies.
Is there something nice to using feces
once in a while rather than shit?
Yes.
If a scientist doing talking to a
scientist and he's like,
well it's really important that we get
feces samples of these animals to make
sure that you don't want your.
Or saying your doctor saying go shit in
this cup.
Amount of your collecting animal shit.
Make sure we got a lot of them guys.
I was.
I was watching this show on the science
channel last night and the science
channel by the way is it's not all
science thing.
There's a lot of marketing.
Get goofy,
start selling you foes and they started
to do these shows.
Man,
where they have a.
there's a certain amount of experts,
like there's a guy I really want to get
him on.
He's like the preeminent,
like legitimately intelligent Ufo
expert's name,
Stanton Freedman,
and he's like,
I think he's a nuclear physicist.
Actually a real guy.
See if he could find his wikipedia.
I is named,
I believe his name is Stanton Friedman
and he is a,
and he was on one of those last time,
but he's one of those guys where you see
them on willow shows.
You Go,
oh,
I know I'm watching a show about
bullshit because he's a guy,
not that he's full of shit.
He's like,
you actually make some real sense as far
as like what kind of physics would be
required in order to make a craft that
can travel between worlds.
Um,
is that.
No,
that's not the same guy.
Civilian investigator.
The Roswell incident.
Maybe it is.
Yeah.
Where's this?
Where's this picture?
Those picture looks weird.
Oh,
it's just a weird angle of him.
Yeah,
that's him.
That's him.
Um,
yeah.
Stanton Freedman.
Yeah.
He's um,
yeah,
he was on the show last night.
I was watching.
I was like,
Oh,
you son of a bitch next to this big
foot.
Yeah,
exactly.
He's coming.
Psychics are coming.
But before that it was,
um,
there was a show about this explorer
that something,
I forget his name,
tweeted it yesterday to somebody in
response to somebody.
I tweeted the whole incident and then I
tweeted this guy's name,
but he was an explorer in 19,
25.
They went into the Amazon and he was
looking for El Dorado,
which is like this purported city of
gold.
There was a legendary story in the,
in the Amazon.
Yeah.
But there was something about him that I
had tweeted earlier in a great car.
The Eldorado.
Well,
anyway,
this guy,
um,
in 1925 went to the Amazon and saw these
mounds,
these mounds in the day,
you don't know,
this is almost 100 years ago.
And uh,
he was,
uh,
he wanted to investigate these mounds
because you've got on top of one of
them.
And he looked out and he saw another
mound there is named Percy Fawcett.
You saw another mound out in the
distance.
And then he realized that they were on a
grid and he realized that there's a city
here.
This is a city.
It's like,
oh my God,
I'm looking,
these aren't dirt mountains.
These are city.
Yeah,
these are stone structures that the
earth has sort of covered up because the
Amazon,
it's just so tense.
It just covers everything massive.
So super recently,
like within the last decade,
they've got these satellite images of
that area and they found these pictures
like what Jamie just pulled up that last
article that see those images,
that's all stuff that they found out
from the ceiling or from a satellite's
rather from the ceiling.
It looks like a snowman.
They were saying that they did these,
um,
well they're just,
you know,
it's just paths and structures is a
bunch of them though.
There's a ton of.
When,
when was this discovered really
recently,
really recently.
Um,
but um,
so one of the,
on the show,
they were saying that the carbon tested
some of these mounds and they were over
6,000
years old,
so thousand years old.
This is the speculation.
This,
this show might have been wrong what
they were asserting.
And it could totally be true because
definitely some culture 6,000
years ago,
they're just finding out about that
6,000
years ago,
somehow or another,
these people had created irrigation.
They had created these,
these pathways,
you know,
they,
they had made a grid,
like a system against what looked like a
city,
but it didn't look like a settled,
like group of tents or something.
Like how long have human beings on the
planet and enormous area to have.
It's bigger,
bigger than Georgia.
What does it say that it could have
maintained a population of 60,000
people,
more people than in many medieval
European cities.
Wow.
The structures were created by a network
of trenches about 36 feet,
nearly 11 meters wide and several feet
deep line by banks up to three feet
high,
somewhere ringed by low mounds
containing ceramics,
charcoal and stone tools.
It's thought that they were used for
fortifications,
homes and ceremonies,
and could have maintained populations of
$60,000.
That's saying they sound fun.
Yeah.
Great people,
they were cannibals.
Oh yeah.
But that other than the ones that he
found.
But other than that,
they're fine.
So he had these guides and the guides,
we're taking them to this mount.
Obviously this is again,
a Wonky TV show.
Might've been bullshit,
you know,
they,
they go fast and loose with the facts or
tomato show seemed more fun and they got
me.
They were saying that he was told by his
guidance to stay back.
They wouldn't go any further because
there's cannibals and he was never seen
from again the last contact with him.
He ran into some other tribes.
I was like,
yeah,
somebody probably jacked him.
They probably knew even back then the
white people coming over from England,
like what can they just want it as north
face.
He didn't have to throw everything back
then was probably super nice.
How long were crap though?
People,
people in this forum and this forum,
I think it's been 150,000
years.
One hundred 50 I think.
And what's the oldest town that we found
like that?
I think the oldest structures that they
know of right now are somewhere around
14,000
plus years ago.
14th as far as like stone structures.
Like when they went to like one of the
very first
cities,
which was in Beirut.
Ooh,
it was this,
I forget the name of it,
but it was like one of the original
cities,
like where they actually started to grid
out and stuff.
And uh,
but I don't know how long ago that was.
Well,
let's find out what is the oldest known
evidence of civilization and what do
they do determine a civilization like
functioning?
Like,
you know,
we were hunters gatherers first,
right?
But he,
I guess,
where do you draw the line?
I guess when did you have girlfriends
and like have fun on a Saturday night.
What did you guys have a drive through?
That's when it all started.
So when I was at a food festival the
other day and the band pretty good.
Van,
like these young guys were playing Elton
John Saturday night and were like
Saturday,
Saturday.
And I was thinking,
is that as important to kids as it was
when we were like,
yeah,
because school Saturday it important.
Is that still the way it is?
Yeah.
School makes it important.
Earliest evidence of modern human
culture found 20,000
years.
Oh Wow.
Forty 4,000
years ago,
over 20,000
years before other findings.
Modern modern human behavior.
So this is the earliest unambiguous
evidence for modern human behavior has
been discovered in an international team
of researchers in a South African cave.
Now,
here's what's crazy that is saying that
the first evidence of civilization of
modern human behavior was all 44,000
years ago.
That's so crazy recent.
That's so recent.
And then the earliest stone structures I
think is that the stuff they found in
Turkey,
the really big stone structures in
Turkey at,
um,
go becky,
go Beckley,
Tepi.
I think that's the oldest right now as
far as like really complex because that
before then they weren't really,
they weren't really convinced that
people could do that kind of stuff back
then.
So that means in 30,000
years they figured out how to make that.
There's gotta be some older structures
that they just haven't found that are
way down or could see.
Yeah.
I think they're guessing you definitely,
they're guessing with a lot of evidence.
That's a good.
I'm guessing with a complete supply of
evidence that be found,
this whole other culture,
will they find stuff aliens in it where
they find stuff is in the oceans because
the water levels prison since then,
so they find like entire cities like
underwater that that I think there's
probably some amazing evidence.
They've never even discovered,
right.
Ancient cities.
So there's got to be.
But you got to think also that what was
the city made out of?
Because unless it was made out of solid
stone,
the oceans just going to destroy the
ocean crept over.
Malibu.
Do you think you would find anything in
3000 years?
Right.
What would you find?
Gary Busey is this thing on marina.
She'll still be at the back.
What do I find a good time?
Is this thing on the pills?
Come on.
We're in Malibu,
which is vanished.
Totally vanished.
Salt Water,
metal,
and even if it was anything made of
metal would give out after a thousand
years.
What about like any jobs and stuff that
are down under the ocean?
Not that old.
There's some hundreds.
There's nothing that's like.
Yeah,
I mean there's.
There's probably some the remanence of
it of like the Roman times,
but think of that.
What's that?
A thousand years?
Yeah,
right.
Two thousand years.
Three hundred years.
What about 7,000?
What about eight?
Nothing you're not going to find.
So we're talking about more than 14,000
years old.
If it was a city like this,
you ain't gonna find shit,
but what if just hear me out.
What if it was covered with lava and you
couldn't.
And then get solidified it like Pompei
crack that bitch open and we're ranch
where divers discuss,
discover ancient Roman treasure trove
and shipwreck.
Sixteen hundred year old shipwreck.
Whoa.
There's still some stuff,
but like the ship's gone and look at the
anchor dude.
They found the anchor.
A.
You go back to that anchor again.
Find a little coins.
Look at that.
Is that the anchor?
Yeah,
that's a long walk.
That's so cool.
That is cool.
Imagine that they would throw a giant
hunk of metal overboard yet it to snag
them over and then they would hope that
they'd be able to pick it up within that
role and look at the rare bronze statue.
Holy Shit.
That's incredible.
You've been to Rome,
right?
Yeah.
Just once.
Just last summer.
Two summers ago.
Last summer.
And pretty mind blowing,
isn't it?
Fuck man.
Life changing.
The images are insane.
Look at all this stuff.
They're finding down there that.
Wait a minute.
That was the statue of Liberty.
The Statue of Liberty.
And get back to the souvenir shop on
third street.
Someone's fucking with us,
man.
Goddamn liberty.
Holy Cow.
Stole.
It's about as close to the statue of
Liberty as you can get it.
Really?
She's.
She's just the same pose.
Just not holding the torch.
We'll look at the bottom of it.
It's like a horn.
Yeah.
What is it?
Is it like you drink out of that or
something?
I think it's poseidon.
What?
Oh,
what is it?
Yeah.
What is it at the bottom though?
It seems like it's got it.
Doesn't Jamie like a horn?
Like a buffalo?
Some kind,
yeah,
like maybe you drank out of that,
right?
That's probably a new handle.
I mean if you flip it upside down like
the [inaudible] could be to and.
But it's the wrong way.
It looks like you would want to see her
if it was on a handle on her face facing
the door.
It's a hood ornament.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
Because on the front of the car.
Oh yeah.
When our old buicks big as a house kids
that lived across the street from me
where like,
uh,
like maybe five years older and that was
the thing to do on Saturday nights.
There were parties in the neighborhood
with adults and stuff.
They would go rip off everybody's hood
ornaments.
Oh,
the household.
They had a whole box of like the big
ornaments from the front and then like
the names on them from the side there.
Just take a screwdriver and ornaments.
Such dick's has.
They're such dicks.
And when you give kids freedom,
you let him go outside,
like anywhere,
what's ring that doorbell and go go,
go a little fucking gremlins in your
windows,
throwing eggs at your house where people
give them homework,
her homework because you just let it be
free.
These gonna go nuts.
But it was a pipe.
Could be.
Yeah,
it fine.
I was like looking for more pipe.
Big Pipe.
Holy Shit.
To Roman pipe right here.
I to party.
So I just be an ancient Roman.
I might've made it in the style of
ancient Roman.
Um,
I don't know about all that plastic
mouth.
Plastic or is it carved out of be
spencer gifts?
You get more than $100 at forever.
Twenty one bubbles come out of it.
They're trying to encourage pipe smoking
now that trump's in office trying to be
pretentious.
I smoked a pipe recently on the podcast
a couple of weeks ago.
That's good over there.
I was going to bring a cigar,
but I didn't know if you could smoke a
cigar in here.
Yeah,
we could.
Sure.
Yeah.
Just turn on that filter thing and we
could smoke.
I think we smoked cigars in here,
right?
Yeah.
Wow.
Let's do that next time.
I have a big thing of Cuban cigars.
Do you juggle or illegal?
Big shots.
Illegal through a guy.
I know in Vegas.
It's not a big deal.
I know people a little to get them.
Thanks for great.
It was good.
Yeah,
it was fun.
The fight was weird though.
The main event,
there was a lot of controversy.
People thought it was a boring fight.
Oh really?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
It was just not a lot of action
happened.
It was very tactical fight for most of
the five rounds.
Then the fifth round,
tyron woodley cracked them and almost
had them out cold but was losing most of
the round in a lot of people's eyes
before then.
So the scoring was really oddly,
uh,
it was,
it was really odd because a lot of
people disagree with the score.
The score was,
it was for the champion,
but the first fight they had was a draw.
And then people,
a lot of people like,
well,
if that first part was to draw this
fight was a draw to including the guy
who was commentating with dominick Cruz,
a former,
a bantamweight champion.
So it was um,
a lot of people felt disappointed when
you're in that situation and you're
broadcasting it,
do you speak your mind like sometimes
you think it's weird sometimes,
but I don't want to.
I didn't think in that case it was that
weird.
Okay.
I felt like I don't.
I think the scoring system sucks.
Oh yeah.
Do you know anything about scoring
system for MMA?
We essentially took the boxing scoring
system and adapted it to mma.
Oh.
So it's a 10 point must system and it's
very difficult to get around to be
scored 10,
eight.
The with that is,
I don't think it leaves enough room for
a accurately judging all the events that
take place in a five minute period of
combat sports because there's so many
different interactions.
I think those interactions should
probably be judged on their own merit.
Like almost like,
um,
it should be like there should be a way
to quantify how much damage was done,
whether or not it was the right thing to
do and it should be like probably a
hundred point score system or something
like that.
A lot more factors,
a lot more factors like the difference
between a 10,
nine and in one round at 10,
nine and another round.
Totally different fight.
Like one guy's getting dominated and
he's clearly losing.
And the other one it's a toss up and
it's still there both to 10,
nine rounds.
It doesn't make sense.
A does it work for boxing because it's
longer and it's just one thing.
Just one thing.
It's three minutes instead of five
minutes you more rounds.
So there's more variables because
there's 10,
nine rounds boxing.
The 10 point must system works.
People like it.
I mean maybe it can be improved upon.
I'm not saying it couldn't be,
but for MMA is woefully inadequate.
So they've created an updated system,
but Nevada hasn't adapted.
Adopted it yet.
Okay.
But when you go to vegas and you're
gigging gigging,
Daddy,
you and you're gigging,
do you,
uh,
do you eat whatever you want today or
this weekend?
I had to it this weekend.
A Spaghetti I had like linguine with
clams.
Nice.
I fucked up.
So you need a Cuban sandwich?
Grand Sunday night?
Yeah.
I shitty food.
So I felt it today.
So that's like,
people are so tired of hearing people
complain about what they eating bad food
and what it does to your body.
I think people have.
I've worn my welcome out with that stuff
because I've talked about it too much on
my own.
I definitely,
uh,
definitely indulge.
I had pizza on Sunday.
I had a lot of shitty food.
Yeah.
No because it's hard when you're on the
road.
It's difficult to,
uh,
to not do it.
And once you break the seal when you're
on the road you're like,
oh,
I'll just clean it up when I get home.
Exactly.
Yeah.
But,
but I've been pretty consistent.
It's like diet and pretty consistent
with working out.
I was going to bring some bread today
because I,
I,
uh,
I was experimenting with something and
tried to make something different and it
was kind of a fail,
not a total fail.
It's still tastes good,
but it didn't look that great.
And it was like I was going to bring it
by and then I was like,
Eh,
I don't think they're going to want to
eat bread.
I think they're,
I think they're dialed in right now.
I'm trying to be dialed in right now.
I just think,
uh,
I'm going to get myself one day a week,
one day a week to fuck off.
We're not always going to take it.
I'm not always going to take that day.
And that was my,
I don't need it and don't go batshit
crazy.
Well,
here's the thing.
In Aubrey Marcus,
my good buddies described this the best
way.
He's like,
well,
you're doing is you're just for a few
moments of mouth pleasure.
You're totally hijacking your body for
the next day.
Yeah.
Like if you're eating like an ice cream
Sundae
and you know,
you drink a coca cola with that and you
have a cheeseburger and fries,
right?
You are high jacking your digestive
system.
Yeah.
He just said,
listen,
I don't give a fuck what did for me.
We're going to throw some groovy
poisoned down there and I'm going to get
the shortest.
I mean like a few minutes of good
feeling.
That doesn't come close to a lot of
stuff.
That's legal.
It doesn't even come close.
Yeah.
But something's Kinda last.
Like when you've been thinking about
fried chicken for for a month or so,
and then you get that fried chicken,
it'll stick with you for a bit.
Do you think you should earn it?
Yeah,
I think it should be special.
I think it's gotta be like,
you know.
Yeah.
I think it's.
You're one of my all time favorite cheat
foods is,
is Popeye's fried chicken with hot
sauce.
Hot.
Damn.
I take some fucking l you could take a
Habanero sauce when it's cold.
I like it the next day even more than I
liked it better.
Yeah.
And then dip it in the Habanero sauce
and just fucking gluten be damned.
Ah,
you got to put a nice potato with that
fuck potatoes on the side of that.
Just going hard with fried chicken.
Fried chicken is two food groups.
Okay.
It's bread and it's chicken,
right?
Because all that crust on the outside of
oil.
Yeah.
Plenty of oil.
Got Fried Chicken at this food festival
the other day.
I was like,
oh,
I haven't had that in a long time.
And it wasn't that great.
That's the worst.
You know what the best chicken isn't?
California Roscoe's.
Oh really?
Roscoe's chicken and waffles.
The just my eyes.
Maybe it's just the combination
combination of the chicken,
chicken and waffles and Syrup and
Collard Greens or something about
Collard Greens.
On the side column,
there's a place in a studio city called
a uncle Andres and it's barbecue place.
Tiny little place one do just in the
back making this stuff forever.
It looks like they took him out of
Alabama and the woods and he's just kick
ass makes them credible.
His Collard Greens are insane because
somebody's gotta learn how to cook
because when someone does it really
well,
I got a really good barbecue place and
it's like dripping when you pull it out
of the box a little.
Yeah,
a little liquid.
It's good stuff.
It's a delicious vegetable and it's not
like a well used one.
No,
it's good for you.
Fuck it.
Why anything green?
Essentially.
It's good for you,
right?
It's,
you know,
they say that Bok Choy is something that
people are really getting into now for
the health benefits.
Bok Choy I'm going to do with that.
I'm a Kale Freak,
man.
I love it.
Makes me feel good.
Kale does make you feel good.
Love it.
It's really good.
I had a.
there's this place called a blossom in
New York and it had this total Kale dish
and a.
It was a lot of it and you just ate the
whole thing and then you walk out.
You feel better than when you walked in
the restaurant and you shit like a
lumber
accident.
Our river ship hit a rock.
You want to take pictures and send it to
you?
I'm proud of you little buddy.
What was that scene?
Was it in dumb and dumber where he's
holding on while he's taking a shit was
getting launched into the air.
Literally.
Sometimes you just want to take a
picture and share it with your friends.
There's something about shit jokes,
man.
Ari Shaffir had to get rid of his agent
or a manager,
one of the to realize they told him to
stop.
Oh,
there it is right there on found the
scene.
Said so funny and such a child.
It's a primal thing,
but already had this great joke about
and it actually was a real thing that
happened when he and I worked together,
he had to go over this bridge and it was
a long ass bridge in Sydney,
Australia,
and as he was halfway over the bridge,
he had shit himself.
It takes forever to get to the other
side.
Just he stuck.
His manager was like,
you shouldn't do that.
It's a shit joke.
And I mean this joke.
Oh,
he had it in his act was a joke kit.
Eld killed.
He was closing with it,
you know,
and his manager was telling him he
shouldn't do it because it's a shit
show.
And he was like,
yeah,
we're not going to be working.
We can't,
we can't do this.
We can't do this.
While I was just laughing at it.
I was like,
I came to tell him I,
I do the joke.
It's so funny.
It's so funny that you tell that story
and it's fucking hilarious.
And he goes,
yeah,
I just had a fire my manager.
And he was,
yeah,
he told me to stop doing.
I go get the fuck out of here.
There's no way.
He's like a.
because it wasn't,
it was a joke about a guy who had to
take a shit,
but it wasn't just,
it was a,
it was just funny.
It was a real story.
And that concept is a real part of life.
It's not just theirs,
but there's people that think like
there's toilet humor and there was a
thing that like in the 19 sixties and
seventies,
you know,
someone like Lenny Bruce came along,
Oh,
he's doing it.
Toilet humor,
right.
If it's coming out of somebody and all
they have is that,
and there's nothing if it's coming from
ru,
like he's a funny comedian,
you know,
and it's just a subject,
you're just a real subject.
But I was talking about how it's hard to
be a human being and I had this like run
and I said,
uh,
you ever Fart so loud and your sleep,
you wake yourself up.
And I was like,
wow,
this is so base.
Like I know normally have talked like
that in my act and it's just so fun to
talk about and the girls just get
hysterical in the audience because they
do.
It's just too much fun to talk about.
Oh,
why?
Why else are we here to enjoy ourselves?
You know what I mean?
I can't be like,
no,
I mean I'm not going to do it on Cole
Bear,
but you know,
it's fun to do at Ice House.
I mean,
it is a thing they put.
It's a thing that
you should certainly use it sparingly,
right?
If you're going to describe it and talk
about it,
like what is this guy obsessed with
shit,
right?
Because vic is your computer.
Jesus,
look at his bookmarks.
Oh God,
I accidentally so many fucking retweeted
a scat page.
There's a scale twitter page.
Somebody retweeted it and I was like,
why is this on my feet?
It was some dude with these giant hairy
fat overweight ass hunched over this
woman's face and hitting in her mouth
while people were like pulling the shit
out of his ass and run it face.
And I was like,
this is on twitter,
but Milo's not your guys' band,
Milo Yiannopoulos and this is like,
whoa.
Oh that's terrible.
I'm like,
what in the fuck am I looking at?
How was that?
And also there's a lot of porn on
twitter.
Not really.
Yeah,
like fight a hardcore.
I don't read the twitter feed anymore.
I don't.
I'll read like mentioned like with fans
that want to talk about stuff,
but I,
I've known through everybody else.
No,
it's just,
well,
yes,
it just got too much.
It's just,
it was overwhelming.
I'd rather just talk to people about
bread recipes and.
Well there's too much information and
for sure we're definitely suffering from
an overload of information.
I just feel better because it's just too
much to go through.
It's just instagram is good.
You see a couple of pictures of your
friends.
I feel like if something really crazy is
happening,
someone will text me.
Yeah.
Something really crazy.
Like Erin Foster,
the guy who's coming tomorrow who thinks
he can kill a wolf with his hands.
He's going to be on a podcast tomorrow.
Oh yeah.
Former NFL player.
Has he done it?
No,
he never has killed a man by the way.
No one's killed wolf with their hands
up.
Giant super athlete.
And he's like,
I'll get.
He said if he gets a hold of its neck,
it'll be done.
So that's what he said.
I'm like,
I'm not entirely sure he understands how
big that NEC is.
Well,
I don't think he understands how fast
those things move.
How vicious they are.
They have a bite that's five times
harder than a pit bulls.
Oh No.
Yeah,
I was uh,
I was,
I joined the wolf movement when I was in
college was around the time it was like
saving the wolves because the numbers of
guns so low.
So what year was this?
This was a like a 89,
88.
So that was before the yellowstone
reintroduction?
Yes.
It was all part of that.
Oh.
And uh,
everyone's just pouring money and effort
into,
you know,
talking about it and stuff.
And uh,
we were,
me and my friends were so into wolves
were just like we'd watch wolf videos,
wolf packs.
We loved like the packs and the healthy
would hunt and like go around different
things.
And then now the wolf is a dominant
again.
It's kind of exploded a little bit of a
problem,
right?
In some areas.
But most in most areas they think it's
like it's healthy.
It is good.
Yeah.
Like they think it's healthy in
yellowstone.
Like people are upset that live on the
outside of it because they weren't given
a say
and they,
there's a lot of wolves.
Now there's a real,
it's a real thing.
And as long as the elk populations are
high and they manage the wolf
populations,
that's where it gets squirrely.
Some,
some people don't want anyone to kill
wolves.
Like you say,
well why would you kill a wolf?
Man?
The problem is if you get the,
they get over populated,
you have a real problem,
like I agree and beautiful and I think
they're amazing.
They'll probably like,
if I had like one animal that I would be
like most psyched to see in the wild,
it would be a wolf.
I think they're incredible for sure.
I'm fascinated by them,
but I'm also really aware of what the
consequences are.
If there's too many of them,
they'll eat people.
They definitely eat people they've eaten
at many times in the past eight dogs.
There's some pictures that someone sent
me.
Um,
his buddies and Kazic Stan had three
dogs killed the night by wolves and they
ate the dogs and they have pictures of
the remains of these dogs were,
they're bitten in half,
like the lower abdomen.
Like you could see everything from the
shoulders up,
like the dog's head,
the dogs arms,
and then everything back there is gone.
They cut it in half.
She's there.
The amount of power they generate in
their jaws,
he's insane and they don't look at dogs
like their buddies.
They look at dogs like pray and they'll
look at people like prayed.
Yeah,
if there's.
If they don't think that you're
dangerous,
they'll get you.
They'll get you.
There's coyote is all around us and
we'll get you to.
If everything gets.
If it gets real bad.
Yeah.
We know someone who would.
The coyote went in the house and got the
dog.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Little dog winning got it off.
Oh,
they're scary.
Yeah.
They're scary.
Who has a stronger bite?
A Wolf or a bear?
Grizzly bear.
A grizzly bear.
Yeah.
Not even close.
No.
A real like if you're talking like a
Kodiak Island grizzly bear,
that's the biggest they get.
They're not really grizzly grizzlies.
There's two bears,
right?
There's a brown bear and a grizzly bear
and the grizzly bears,
the interior bear.
That's the bear that you find in the
rocky mountain.
That's a grizzly bear,
right?
The,
the burial.
Find a Montana,
but the coastal bears are even bigger
and that's what they had to kill in
California.
You know,
our state flag has a brown bear on it
and that brown bear that's different.
Gene Brown and Grizzly st animal,
but one of them lives interior and it's
much more aggressive.
By the way,
the Grizzly is much scarier than the
coastal bear because the coastal bear
gets plenty of food.
That's why they're so big and the other
one's hungry.
Yeah,
so coastal bears are enormous.
I mean enormous.
And the biggest ones on the planet that
are brown bears,
the biggest bears in the planet right
now are polar bears.
Polar bears,
but the brown bears on Kodiak Island,
I think they get too close to 2000
pounds.
Like find out what's the brown bear ever
shot on Kodiak Island?
They,
I think it might be close to 12 feet
tall and I think it might be in the
neighborhood of 1800 to 2000 pounds.
She's,
I you,
that time when I was hiking
in Alaska and I was close to a bear who
accidentally.
Yeah,
yeah,
girl or a boy,
I don't know.
Black or brown.
It was a kind of Tan.
Tan.
Yeah,
probably it was in Alaska,
like probably a black bear.
They have the color phase.
Black bears there.
It was big.
It looked like the size of a minivan.
Oh Jesus.
So it was probably a grizzly though.
It was big.
Yeah.
So really big.
And it was coming through the weeds.
God,
that was with my.
We were in the back country.
We were out there like miles and miles
in like overnight for like a week.
Oh Jesus up.
And it was reads like as tall as me,
like a whole field of those reads and we
just saw the,
the,
the reeds just partying like 50 feet
away,
like oh my God.
And I'm with like five other people and
you're not supposed to run when they see
a bear,
you're supposed to freeze.
Everybody took off.
They just got so scared and me and my
one friend's froze and then saw them
running and we went to bat.
We were like,
kind of in between the instinct of what
to do.
The bear was like where the corner of
that room is and just was,
it was late September.
It was full.
Oh yeah.
It was going way down to get the last
berries,
like way down low.
And uh,
it was,
uh,
didn't care about us at all.
It just,
but you realize it
like in a split second if this guy
decides this is a whole different story,
you know what I mean?
They can move so fast,
so fast.
Okay.
The biggest brown bear,
the world record was bagged by Roy.
I like how they say bagged.
Just say killed Roy Lindsley in 1950
2:30
12 slash 16.
I don't know what that means.
A score.
Largest scoring.
Where's the size of it?
I don't know.
It doesn't say 30 feet long.
They're just scroll down,
scroll down.
No,
it's definitely not 30 feet long.
Twelve feet?
No,
I think.
they're,
they're actually measuring the skull.
I think eight cups.
I think there may have measuring the
skull and then 16.
Who knows what that is?
Maybe it's the length.
Yeah.
Just trying to find out what that meant
on here.
I didn't really see anything.
Just just look up how big or how much
does the biggest Kodiak bear way?
Just Google that says it weighed more
than half a ton.
Oh,
that's a big bag.
Says commonly way more than half a time.
Yeah.
I mean that's just a thousand pounds.
I hate this website.
This website blows,
Bro.
Ever.
I think that's one of them.
Hunter websites,
right?
Is it bears my favorite animal though?
Outdoor hub.com.
Yeah.
See that's like,
wow.
Oh my God.
That can't be real thing.
One thousand to 1200 pounds can weigh up
to 1500 pounds when conditions are
right.
That's not real.
Look at the size of that head.
Oh,
that's real.
That's real.
Yeah.
It's perspective though.
The guys behind it and he's like hiding
out like three feet behind.
The barely got killed her so big and I'm
is the.
That's
a heavy rock.
Adam.
Stick that dire wolf skull.
This is what a Dork I am.
I recognize that.
That's not a dinosaur.
Which one?
No,
it's as mammals.
What is that animal?
Is that a dire wolf?
A look at those teeth.
Sun.
Ooh.
It looks like my dog.
Good Lord.
Look at those fucking teeth.
What is that?
A visit page.
What the fuck animal is that?
It was a parakeet.
What does it say?
It says the hell pig.
Hell pig.
Oh hell.
Helping.
I just found out about this thing a week
ago.
I never heard of it.
A hell click on that motherfucker,
please.
I'm learning new things.
This was apparently like a super
predator giant pig,
mean fucking huge.
There was a um,
was an article like really recently,
like within the last couple of days on
it that I saw online were there were say
thank God the hell pig gets extinct or
something like that.
But it was a fucking huge.
It was a huge animal.
They haven't seen my family on
thanksgiving.
Hello Bob.
Hello pig.
Wow.
Facts about the giant killer pigs.
Look at the face on that fucking thing.
Look at its haunches.
It's like a bowl.
It's like a bull horse.
Facteau horse that fucked a wolf.
Yeah,
right?
Yeah.
Like a bull horse wolf thing.
Face.
It was like a tank of a face.
Oh God.
Let's imagine that thing running at your
family.
What do you do?
He's closer to Hippos and Wales.
You Push,
you push the smallest one into it and
run to devolution.
Scares the fuck out of me closest to
hippos and whale.
We're here.
Definitely a good time.
A hippo whale thing.
That was huge.
I mean they were a hippo size too.
And I think this was a thing,
correct me if I'm wrong,
we're this thing live.
He lived around people,
right?
Joe,
would you rather live in a world where
2000 pounds with all of nature is being
decimated and we're.
And we're drilling in national parks and
it's really bleak.
Like everything's concrete or would you
like to live in a time like this where
hell pigs are running around and you had
to fight for your life the whole time?
Depends on what you mean.
If I had to live back then with the
weapons they had back then because what
year is this that this was going down?
These were times when did this thing
exists?
Nineteen to $16.
Million years.
Okay.
So there's no people.
No,
let's put them in modern day.
So if there wasn't an animal back then
that was like us,
it's past the,
um,
the big impact that you could on impact.
So that's 65 million years ago,
so there's.
Those are probably like weird monkey
people.
Back then they didn't have.
They probably they were fucked.
Let's update it.
Let's let's say the EPA is granted all
of the things I wanted to be able to do
and the place is just crazy with
animals,
but we have held pigs,
pigs in your garbage.
See that's where got guards and stuff
like that.
People are going to be happy that
there's people that know how to hunt
because if there really are hell pigs
and they really do become a problem,
look,
the only thing that's keeping wolf
populations down as hunters and when
they don't have that,
you know what they do in Alaska,
they get an airplanes,
they fly over him and they shoot them
from the sky.
They find the packs,
they locate them and they swooped down
and shoot at them when they killed too
many Caribou or they killed too many
moose.
What would happen if they didn't do
that?
They would get overwhelmed.
They have massive populations of like
they have in Siberia.
Siberia.
A few years ago they were having these
super packs of wolves because it was a
particularly horrible winter and it
would have like 100 wolf could,
would get together so they could take
out horses,
so they would go into these barns and
then imagine you're hanging out in your
house and your barn is next door and
there's 100 wolves apart,
100 walls,
right?
So it's okay if we kill a couple of
things.
You have to.
It's survival well if you don't,
they're going to get.
They're going to get.
Or with the Russians in World War One,
the Russians and the Germans in World
War One.
So many of them were killed by wolves,
that they had a ceasefire and they
decided to kill wolves for real and they
went and they went back to killing each
other after they figured out how many.
They sorted it out and killed a ton of
walls
and this friend that's coming tomorrow
says he can kill him with his hands.
He believes he seems incorrect.
I think this thing people have this
thing in their head and a wolf is like a
dog to kill a dog.
If he's a giant dude and the,
you know,
the dog doesn't bite him in the right
spot and he can get ahold of it's neck.
He might be able to kill a dog.
Could kill a dog.
I'd bet you might be able to kill some
dogs.
My lab.
Yeah.
Which puppy do you have a knife with you
when this is going down in Sirhan's?
Choke it out.
Not Easy.
Not Easy to kill an animal with your
hands.
You suffocate it.
Choker hold very hard.
It was going to be very hard to do.
Yeah.
Very hard dog.
Yeah,
very hard.
Have you seen my hands?
You have giant hands,
like a massive,
massive football player,
man.
Um,
if you learn,
know Jujitsu and you get it back and you
can sync the choke in like a real proper
rear naked choke,
you might be able to kill it.
But I would think you would put it to
sleep and then stomp it's head,
right?
It'd be the move.
Yeah.
You got to wear boots if you're going
dog hunting.
Yeah.
Well it's,
it's like an animal that we've chosen.
Again,
you know,
this is an animal that.
This is our animal because they eat
them,
right?
Can't.
But if you go to China,
they have a whole festival.
You know,
you can eat dogs just like pigs.
Yeah,
man.
I mean they're supposed to be the
smartest pigs.
Yeah,
you're right.
My dog is definitely not as smart as a
pig.
Dogs and idiot.
I love her.
She's fun.
We just got her.
She's great,
but a not bright.
Do you remember when people were having
pigs for pets?
Yes.
It was like a thing.
Everyone had pop up.
Not everyone,
but a lot of people.
Pop belly pigs.
What happened?
All those pigs.
I bet they're not doing that great old
farting in the house.
It's a pig barely hanging on.
What
do they do with those pegs?
You're bring them outside and just let
them go.
What do you do with those pigs?
My dog got picked up from Bakersfield.
Yeah.
A lot of people dump dogs and
Bakersfield.
Because it's open and you can just pull
off the highway and throw a tennis ball
and keep going.
It's that terrible.
God.
People are assholes.
They the worst.
That's so fun.
I really so sad.
I could not imagine.
I mean sometimes I get mad at my dog,
but not to the point of driving it
somewhere.
You hear those stories about someone
checking a bag of puppies out their car
window and you're like,
wait,
what?
My dog was a puppy that might've
happened.
Oh yeah.
Just a whole bag of puppies.
You couldn't do something else that's
just dumb and lazy.
You couldn't walk into a shelter and be
like,
here's some puppies for you.
What's worse and dumb and lazy.
It's.
It's so fucking callous.
Yeah.
Like how do you not feel?
Get a puppy.
You don't get excited.
Like,
oh,
well that's how they know you're a
psychopath,
right?
When you're a kid.
It was always the kid that would torture
animals.
They were concerned about that kid.
There was a kid in my class who tied a
bird up once.
No,
a cat tight.
A cat like spread eagle and went to town
on it.
Yeah,
he went away for awhile that.
Well,
he was weird.
He was doing weird stuff all the time
and then they.
Then the cat story got around and
they're like,
all right,
someone's got to.
Someone's got to do something with.
This guy's getting weird because that's
a sign that you'll do.
You'll hurt human beings.
You don't.
You're missing an empathy that makes you
able to kill things.
I don't know if you were around back
then,
but there was some,
someone in life and men want to say like
the early two thousands maybe.
Maybe like even before that,
like maybe late nineties someone was
killing cats and Hollywood.
Oh really?
I don't know if they ever caught the guy
really.
And by the way,
no how I said guy,
because I'm sexist and I know that most
people that kill cats are fucking guys.
Yeah.
But this guy was killing cats and
cutting them open and like,
I'm like,
you know,
like gutting them and shit.
Like really?
Yay.
Yeah.
Like oh my God.
Almost like he was doing like science
projects on like spreading them open,
holding their guts out.
Yeah.
And people would come outside and they
would find their cat not just dead but
dead and surgically cut open and pulled
apart and oh my God.
Yeah.
It was scary.
That's a guy you want to feed into a
wolf.
Yeah.
Some people were speculating though that
they were wrong and that it was really.
Coyotes were getting these dogs.
Well,
you know,
what else does that guts cats and leaves
them a raccoons.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
My neighbor's cat was killed like a
raccoon that way and they don't eat it.
They just kill it and gutted it.
Will raccoons are predators.
Yeah.
Record was trying to get into my
chickens.
There was a raccoon on the other night
trying to get at my chicken.
Yeah.
He wouldn't even fucking leave,
man.
There was trying to scare him.
No,
I was trying to scare him.
I was like,
bitch,
you better get the fuck away from here.
And he just looked at me and I got
closer to him and he got closer to me
was like,
oh my God,
I will fucking get a bow and Arrow and I
will kill you if you kill my chickens.
You can't
because this chickens are like their
pets and their pets that live outside.
Just fucking guy was hanging around by
the cage looking right at the chickens
trying to figure out how to get at him.
And he'll figure it out to their smart.
Will he uh,
he'll come back.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
Probably take them out there.
Allowed to.
How's that work?
I would have to check what the laws are.
I think if it's on your property,
he allowed to kill raccoons.
I bet you're not just allowed to just
kill him.
He said,
well,
you got to call someone to have them
trapped them.
Well,
first of all,
I have to make sure he's in a place
where I can actually hit them with an
Arrow ethically,
like I have to be able to actually make
sure there's nothing behind him,
you know?
I don't want to miss and have an Arrow
go through my neighbor's window because
I'm playing Robin Hood,
my backyard with a fucking.
You know what you're doing now?
I do,
but.
But you want to make sure there's
nothing behind.
So he would have to be in an area of my
yard where I would shoot a target or
there's like a back wall,
you know,
so like I have to be somewhere where I
could.
Yeah.
But the arrows you used to go after elk,
would it go right through a raccoon?
Oh yeah.
Oh my God.
An Lte.
So big.
It would go right through.
The elks are a thousand pound animal
going to be like,
what was that?
Elk have these huge bones.
Man.
These arrows just plough right through
those bones.
Really?
Oh yeah.
The only thing they have a hard time
going through is the really thick,
big ones like shoulder bones scapula
sometimes give your.
Is Not that powerful like ribs.
They,
they all the time you get what's called
a pass through.
Where's the Arrow goes completely
through the animal before it even knows
what happened.
She says it happened so quick,
it's just like one second.
They don't have no,
they don't even know what hit him.
That's for would rip a raccoon and half
today,
or I'm developing some mechanical
advantage because the cams,
so they're there on the compound,
bows around these programs that roll
over and they can generate way more
forced than just the amount you're
pulling back.
So like,
um,
like if you had like an old school Robin
Hood recurve bow,
right,
those bose,
the more you pull them back,
the harder it is because it's like
you're,
you're stretching and pulling out would
then let it go in the Arrow it takes
off.
But with a compound bow there on these
cams.
So as you pull it back that's happening,
you have these thick carbon fiber or
fiberglass limbs that are pulling back
and holding tremendous amounts of
energy.
And then you have these cams that
rollover,
that impart and mechanical advantage on
the whole system.
And then as you pull it back,
the cameras allow it to be light at the
end.
So if my boat takes 84 pounds to pull
back at the end,
it's only like 10 or 20 percent of that.
Oh Wow.
So I'm holding it with like 20 percent
of the amount of energy that it takes to
pull it back so it's not hard to hold
onto.
And then when you let the Arrow go,
it's flying like 290 feet a second.
Holy Cow.
Yeah.
So let's go get raccoons and the ways of
the arrows.
Wait,
what's 500 grams?
How much is 500
grams in a pound?
How many grams in an ounce?
Five hundred grams,
or would that be [inaudible] you say 500
grams.
It doesn't seem to make sense.
Like what is.
That doesn't make sense to me.
I don't know what that is.
That's like a pound and a half pounds.
One point one pounds.
So the arrows a pound.
So one pound of Arrow is going 290 feet
second and it's got a razor blade at the
front of it.
Hopefully razorblades designed to
penetrate rib bones with a chisel tip to
it.
Now,
what if you just threw a hammer at the
raccoon?
You might kill it or you might just hurt
him.
Then that's probably even worse.
He wound him and he's walking around
with a broken leg or something.
You know,
you got to consider as you're sitting
there talking to that raccoon and he's
like pretending to come up on you.
There's probably two raccoons flanked on
either side.
The like wolves?
Yeah.
Really you think so?
I bet they feel confident.
They're crafty.
I was telling him,
hey man,
fuck off.
And he moved closer to me.
He's like,
don't you see my boys?
He's just looking at me.
I mean he's looking right at me and he
was,
he was circling like from my side and I
was like,
this is crazy.
He's getting closer to me.
Holy Cow.
Yeah.
Not afraid to.
He wasn't afraid of me at all.
Well,
you know what I mean.
Look,
I don't wanna I don't want anything bad
to happen to the raccoon.
I just don't want him to eat my chicken.
Mine.
We're rolling up the grass and eating
bugs underneath.
I come out my grass,
which just being rolled over,
rolled clever,
they have little hands,
they've got a little busy hands,
but if you raped me,
it's such a weird relationship that we
have with these things because if you
raise him from the time their pets,
apparently they make these amazing pets.
Really?
Yeah.
If you can catch a raccoon when you're
really.
When he's really young and domesticate
them,
domesticate them.
And you know,
the problem with animals becomes
survival.
Survival.
Once food is scarce and once they have
to struggle for it,
they,
they will adopt a wild feral mindset.
Those are dangerous animals.
Their cats or dogs or they're not the
same.
So our ideas about animals,
like for a lot of people that really
truly love animals.
You're talking about these domesticated
Weirdo animals that aren't even animal
like in any way to barely animal.
Like my friend who worked on a farm was
like grew up with pigs,
cows,
the whole thing.
It was just like she had no sympathy for
them.
It wasn't like we have to be kind to all
these animals because they're big and
dumb and smelly and like she just grew
up with them.
It was just like.
See,
I feel like that's kind of fucked up
too.
Right?
It seems like when you're not related to
it.
Yeah,
but the reality is that there's just.
There were held pigs just going crazy
and we had to survive so we had to pave
it and put in Jamba juice,
but I think you need those people that
are like the crazy diehard animal
activist.
Otherwise there would be nothing.
I just want to save the parks.
Just leave.
Just leave Yosemite alone.
Yeah.
They're going to leave it alone.
Title,
they're not doing anything to the one
guy.
Zinc,
what's his name?
Yeah,
he spoke.
He seems pretty decent.
Well,
he's also a big supporter of keeping
public lands public and not selling them
to the states.
Oh really?
Yeah.
The way it works,
it's been explained to me by Steve
Rinella and some other people,
but the way it works is that we have all
this land that's a federal land and you
can go on it.
You would hunt fish,
you could camp,
you could go.
It's literally our land,
but if you sell it to the state,
if the state has a financial burden,
they'll sell it off to private
corporations,
so that's the danger.
The danger is the state will come upon
dire times,
it will be forced to sell it off,
but the federal government,
they can't do that,
so as long as people don't vote to make
it the property of the state,
you're okay.
It stays in the federal trust.
If it's in the federal trust guy,
manage the way it's been managed since
Teddy Roosevelt was around,
so we figured out a way to do it.
Where as of right now they get leasing
rights for minerals and for cattle and
stuff like that.
The bundy ranch thing was about those
guys.
I've been Oregon,
Oregon.
Yeah,
but the.
But what Pruitt is his big push is to
make things give all the power back to
the states and that's a gateway that
gateway to privatization of and that's
A.
There's a hotly contested bill that was
in the house,
hr six slash 21 by this Guy Jason
Chaffetz and if you want to hear him
talking to my friend Cameron Hanes on
Cameron's a most recent podcast,
he flew to dc to talk to him.
The guy with drew her six slash 21,
which is turning over 3 million acres of
land to the state,
which state could then do with whatever
they want and the problem with that is a
slippery slope and it eventually leads
to privatization of a lot of those lands
and especially the people were scared of
that with Republicans in power,
especially when you see that they lessen
the EPA and all the different things
they're doing.
Like you were just talking about the
environmental satellites,
all that stuff scares the shit out of
people.
So then the next one would,
he's got her 6:22,
which people are also opposed to because
it would be about turning over the
policing of those lands and uh,
the law enforcement,
turning it over to state and taking out
a federal hands bureau of land
management and stuff like that part for
Park Rangers.
They wanted to do two local sheriffs
but,
and then they would allocate money
specifically for that,
but people think that's a slippery slope
too because they don't know what they're
doing and except it sets it up for,
hey,
these people don't know what they're
doing,
we need to go back and uh,
you know,
sell this land because if we do that
then we won't be responsible for
maintaining it.
And then real private group in this is,
this is what Rinella believes is going
on.
And the Guy Jason Chaffetz a,
uh,
he disagreed and he has his points of
view,
which I don't know if he's right or
wrong,
just leave them alone.
Just just,
just the parks.
Just that.
Can you just leave that alone?
Well,
it's a super rare thing we have and it's
really cool.
It's amazing.
It literally changed my life when I
started in college,
going back country with my buddies.
We would just get packs.
We didn't know what we're doing in the
beginning we did.
We literally were carrying gear like in
like army sacks and it was just go into
the back of Yosemite for a week and a
half and Denver in Montana and Wyoming
and those were life changing
experiences.
Just to sit behind the grand tetons in
this land.
It does something to you,
it changes you and to think that you're
gonna sit there and there's going to be
a back hoe digging something up to look
for some oil that might be under sulfur.
Well,
you know that when those oil things are
going to weird sounds,
it's a nightmare.
Sound like,
whoa.
It's a nightmare.
He had just leave that alone,
but it's,
it's so crazy that we operate on the
blood of the earth.
Yeah,
and that's really what oil is.
Oil is like the blood of the earth,
the word like these giant mosquitoes
that are using machines to suck the
blood out of the earth and then what we
do with that blood,
we take it and we pollute the air with
it.
That's what we do.
We burn it,
we light it on fire and we have these
engines that are essentially controlled
explosions contained in steel and inside
the of this.
This blood that's boiling and burning
and fire and explosions are going off
inside the steel box.
There's iron box and then we're driving
around,
spitting out our poison gas.
The worst thing.
Yeah,
totally weird thing and we don't need it
anymore.
Well,
when you go buy a factory like a New
Jersey factory and you see those fucking
plumes of smoke blown up theory,
how are you allowed to do that?
Yeah.
How are you allowed to do that?
Would you be allowed to blow that right
on a baby's betty?
I was driving down the New Jersey
turnpike in college.
I was working for like a fireplace
company.
We're on the turnpike in the summer,
like August.
No air conditioning in the truck sitting
there.
The whole area air was orange.
It was
orange.
Just coming out of those smokes.
I was like,
if I ever get cancer,
this is the day.
This is the day it happened.
Oh,
I remember these places you would go by
where it just stunk.
Here's the thing.
My parents,
and this is not just factories,
it's also farms.
They say like one of the biggest
producers of methane pollution and the
country is the,
the cattle industry.
And when I used to,
my parents used to live in Pennsylvania.
They used to live.
Where the fuck were they?
Outside of Wilksberry?
I forget the name of the town.
It was in nowhere.
Pennsylvania.
Right.
So you have to drive through what,
when you think of Pennsylvania,
think of Philadelphia or Pittsburgh,
but there's a lot between where you're
just going 30 miles an hour.
So you know,
slam into a deer.
Some method of deers darden onto the
highway and like what in the fuck kind
of places this,
it might be.
My parents had deer in the yard every
day.
They hated deer.
Deer like roses and like
get those county fucking animals.
Yeah.
And um,
anyway,
uh,
when you would drive down there,
you would go past these farms and the
smell was so bad you could not believe
that people could live there.
The smell,
because it was in the summer when I was
visiting them.
It would smell like shit all the time
I'm sure.
But it was hot too.
Yeah.
So it was hot,
funky shit smell.
And it was everywhere.
It was just the air you are breathing
was shit.
Particle air 100 percent.
I drove past a,
the Hormel factory in the summer ones.
Oh my God.
First of all,
there's a whole bunch of pigs and stuff.
You're behind these trucks on the way
there.
And then it was like,
where are they going?
And then you just see in the next giant
Hormel plant,
the smell in the summertime.
All.
But we have so many faces to feed.
Yeah,
there are so many mouths.
There's so many beings walking around
right now getting hungry.
Right?
They're all getting hungry and they've
all got to be fed.
So it's like,
what's the,
what's the solution to a good question.
They're all hungry,
they're going to get hungry and another
three hours going to crap it out,
and then they're going to eat again.
We are the zombies,
the zombies running around needing to
feed constantly and if you want to be
able to pull into that Wendy's,
drive through and get that double
cheeseburger at 1:00
in the morning,
someone's got to pay.
I mean you can go to the Wendy's drive
through at 1:00
AM and almost instantly get a
cheeseburger beef right away.
Yeah,
ground animal sandwich.
You don't have to feed in,
have to shoot him.
You don't have to cut it up,
you have to grind it,
you don't have to cook it,
you don't have to find a button right in
your face,
right in your face.
And it cost like what?
Four bucks or something.
It's nothing.
And then boom,
you're full and then you're on your
merry way.
So weird and it's millions.
Billions of people are doing that belief
and that's the only way you can have a
city.
You can't have a city where everybody's
growing things.
None of food.
No Way.
How could you feel like if if people
were eating meat in particular candidate
vegetables,
could you imagine if New York City had
to be self sustaining?
Oh,
please.
I was looking just for a,
a,
a farm to table steakhouse in New York.
They don't have,
they don't have that.
Nobody can provide the grass fed beef to
one rest in one New York restaurant is
going to go through so much meat in one
night.
You can't do it.
God Damn just one restaurant when you go
there.
Like I only go there once or twice a
year,
but every time I go there and go,
oh yeah,
I forgot.
Oh crazy.
This place is like,
this doesn't make any sense.
I was looking at the map yesterday.
It was looking at um,
lyme disease centers as lyme disease is
God damn scary.
And there's a lyme disease map.
And the lyme disease map is fascinating
because it's like a giant percentage of
it is like Massachusetts,
New York,
the east coast,
east coast,
just overwhelmed with wellmed.
I know so many people that got it.
Another thing was weird.
It's like shape of New York.
I was looking at it.
How is on
that up there?
New York and long island is this thing
like,
well,
how come you guys don't have more than
one state?
This is a bunch of different states.
You gotta yeah.
You put a lot of stuff together.
Like New York State is definitely not
New York.
Yeah.
New York state might as well be
Kentucky.
Absolutely.
Might as well.
Totally different.
It's like going in Alabama.
There's some spots like when you drive
into buffalo or something like that.
We like,
okay,
where the fuck am I?
Right.
Like Buffalo,
good luck.
You might as well be in West Virginia as
wellbeing.
Rural,
North Carolina.
Oh,
mile away from how people are in the
West village.
There's like you have your cities,
you know you have Albany,
Buffalo,
you have syracuse,
but you don't.
Those are so different.
Do you live in New York?
I lived in new Rochelle in new Rochelle,
like right outside the city.
It's like I know where it is.
Or the bronx rather.
Yeah.
I lived in New York for a long time.
It's um,
it's just a weird shape that it's all
that stuff up there as New York to Long
Island and Manhattan and Brooklyn and
New York state.
When I was a kid,
uh,
when I was coming up as a standup,
I would uh,
like the first Gig I ever got in New
York.
I was so nervous.
I couldn't believe I was doing a show in
New York and it was a New York state
room so I had to drive up through
western Massachusetts to get into New
York.
But I was like so proud of myself that I
did a show in New York.
Not even the city,
not even close just,
but it was like,
it made me feel like,
okay,
I can do comedy in New York.
Look at that big deal,
look at that.
Crazy.
So white plains,
he see that in the lower right hand
corner.
That's where I used to live.
Right outside of that because I used to
play pool in white plains.
I'd executive billiards if you go like
see where the Y is in New Jersey on
yonkers.
Yeah,
that why right there,
that's about,
that's about where I grew up.
Dude.
Look at that.
Fucking look at the size of that thing.
It's a beautiful state.
The adirondacks.
You ever gone through the adirondacks
goes all the way through to the top of
Vermont?
Yeah.
Well it's New York.
What do you want?
But isn't that insane?
Like what?
An enormous,
enormous state.
Yeah,
it takes Vermont,
Massachusetts,
Connecticut.
Wow.
Look at the catskill mountains were
custom motto used to train Mike Tyson.
That's right.
And there's Ithaca.
There's roam a Rome,
New York.
Because where it worked,
that's where I worked.
I worked in UTICA.
In utica.
Yep.
What'd you do there?
I did stand up there and I had to drive
from Massachusetts that Massachusetts
Ninety,
I think them 90 was the Massachusetts
turnpike and then it turned into New
York state.
Yeah.
Look at the,
uh,
I've done gigs in Rochester,
Buffalo,
Saratoga Springs.
There's a new club there.
I hear,
you know what I used to hear all the
time when I was a kid to the Capsi.
No,
I'm not the catskills,
but what was one that's in Pennsylvania?
The poconos.
Poconos.
The mount airy lodge.
Yeah.
You always heard about people going to
the poison that were dirty dancing took
place?
No,
that was cat skills.
Poconos is like the champagne tub for
the mount airy lodge.
They had that ad on TV and the catskills
was like where the comics would go.
Yeah.
That's where like those Roman type do.
That's right.
Wow.
Yeah.
She'll manage.
If you can go back in time and watch
some of that.
They used to play Buddy Hackett hotels,
little bungalows,
little trailer home like it was.
Everybody from New York dumped up there
for the weekends and then the
entertainers would come and they would
just.
You do it was like Manhattan to do a
whole bunch of gigs a night.
That is the Poconos.
This is an Arrow through a heart.
Also the mount airy lodge couples
resorts.
All couples resorts in the catskills.
Poconos,
Poconos.
A sexy.
That's where you go.
Well,
yeah.
That one hit that one up.
Yeah,
that was in the ad.
That was in the ad when I was a kid.
We didn't for a kiss.
He's got a girl floating in a pool.
You that.
Oh,
heart-shaped baths.
I with one of those weird roof's
destroyed.
You pretend like you're fucking.
Oh,
it's all destroyed.
The abandoned Poconos.
There was so much banging their.
Yeah.
That's the champagne one.
Look,
it's a champagne glass and you make love
to you lady.
How do you get in there?
You got to take an elevator.
You get them having sex with each other
to get the champagne glass.
Let's go through.
The broker knows and we'll go to Egypt
room.
Oh,
you serious?
Can you really get the Egypt?
There's a waiting list,
but I know a guy.
She's got her shoes off to take her from
behind.
He sneaking up behind her.
I got you a new coat from Lord and
Taylor and that's a.
that's a fuck position.
You only going to stay like that with
someone you're banging.
See?
Because if you were a that was a buddy
of yours and you were sitting in his lap
like that.
People walked in,
they'd be like,
Hey,
what the fuck's going on?
We're just watching the game.
It's just how we caught her.
Stay warm and preserved body.
Why your feet off a while you have your
shoes off.
My bare feet on.
Are you going to climb me up to that
glass or just look at it?
You have to throw her up there.
If you want to bang her way.
She lets you mount airy law.
You gotta thrower over your arm,
like throw over your shoulder and then
you have to climb stuff gently.
Layer down champaign.
Oh,
it's so terrible that there's another,
a couple of different couples in the
Egypt,
Rome.
So I'll let you know.
You are not the first people to fuck in
this room.
This,
this African American couples been
fucking in this room before you.
Oh yeah,
that's what.
What do you think happens there?
That's where people go to get there.
Fuck off.
Fucking basically naked pants on.
That's like playgirl 1975.
Gave
Handy and he said thanks.
And she just is really sensitive because
she's on her period and they got some
room service.
Look at this.
This guy's hanging from the edge that's
going to break.
It's going to be like when I'm rob,
dry deck videos with a champagne glass
going to come down,
crushed his skull.
She's going to fall.
She's going to be paralyzed from the
neck down.
He's going to be dead and it'll all be
on security camera that the Russians
have captured through wikileaks.
There's no part of looking at the two
people in the champagne glass.
That makes you think that would be a
good idea.
How about this old guy to get my fuck on
down here.
Who needs a lady?
I'm by myself.
I'm in the glass.
I had to make a decision.
I can only follow one pair of glasses.
So I went with the prescription
sunglasses.
I don't give a fuck.
I don't like to look at it.
The daytime to those some fluorescent
lights at bad for your brain.
Louis,
trust me that bad for your brain.
My guy's a good guy.
Nobody knew what was good for you,
buddy did it really did to go to school
to find out whether or not you should
eat cigarettes.
A toast to pride.
Gay dudes getting that bathtub.
Gay dudes have been banging.
Everyone bangs in that glass smell.
Bleach bleach.
Looking at her puts.
Why you have clothes on hooker?
I'm by myself in a full full one bottle
babies.
It's like more like a so depressing.
People are so bored.
Oh God.
Can't you stay home and read a book or
just take a nap.
Do you get your daughter was taking
dancing lessons for Patrick swayze.
He's got that fucking Silky mullet and
he's dancing and moving across the floor
and you know guy does that unless he
wants to.
Fuck.
Fucking guys are.
He's fucking your daughter.
That's why dance is so good.
Hips around wants to let you know.
This is how it fuck you.
Fuck you to the spinning around.
Also style type polyester pants.
Do you remember Saturday night fever?
You remember when it came out where
everybody wanted to go dancing?
Yeah,
I was a little kid,
but I remember all of a sudden everyone
was dressing like them.
What year did Saturday night fever?
[inaudible]?
Seventy seven.
Was it?
Yeah,
so it was 10 years ago and I remember
people just would go dancing all the
time.
It's true.
And they were wearing like old open
shirts.
My aunts were living with us at the
time.
I moved from New Jersey or Florida where
the fuck they were at the time.
I think they,
uh,
they,
they move with us around that same time.
When I was 10 I went dancing where they
finance.
Yeah,
they were nice looking at this.
Here it is,
yeah.
Oh Jesus.
Oh Yeah,
look at that shirt.
Open shirt hair because it never had
hair like that.
What a great album.
It's amazing.
The bgs,
the beaches were incredible.
Credible.
We should,
we could play some of it on the podcast
who can sing like that.
You had to cigarettes on cigarette
smoking.
They were playing records and it was all
about going out and everybody would go
dancing
and occasionally knife fights and that
girl accidentally got their product in.
She was cute,
but she wasn't as hot as the other girl
when she dropped the condoms and it was
like,
what were those?
Yeah,
I didn't know what happened and he's
looking at A.
I can't believe how good she is.
You want to give me lessons.
Next thing you know,
they're bang and she's not from his side
of the tracks.
She shouldn't be with them and you know,
he's kind of flawed,
but he's got this special something and
he could dance.
He could really dance.
Tony,
you can really.
You think so?
Yeah.
You could really dance time.
They just wanted to dance.
No one does that anymore.
I don't know,
just hadn't love songs.
There were so many love songs.
The Seventies.
Just life in general was different.
Yeah.
Came out of the Vietnam War and stuff.
He just want it to just chill out and
love a little bit.
Whereas we're getting overwhelmed with
data and information.
This becomes more and more ridiculous.
You look at like making a movie exactly
like this today and you could make one
of those like step on up dance movies,
but those movies are stupid.
La La land,
but I don't know what that is.
That's the one that almost won the
award.
It was a big hit this year and it was a
musical and there's a lot of dancing.
Well,
did you see it?
I did.
How dare you live with girls?
The theater queens.
We weren't in the theater.
We were watching it at home.
I've got the screener and my kids wanted
to see it.
I didn't really enjoy it.
Will you listen?
It's an anomaly.
I was fighting a raccoon and while they
were watching it I was fighting a
raccoon in the face.
Oh Wow.
That's a rough night.
But it was this,
but it was kind of this.
It was kind of dancing and la,
la,
la.
What I'm saying is this is a dumb movie
and if you want to make this dumb,
Louis today wouldn't be so interesting.
It will be silly.
You'd be like,
this is so silly,
but now the people we know more about
how people are,
you know,
it's just different and we've seen a lot
of stuff so things can't be so a shitty.
Yeah.
I was watching everything.
I saw someone had a thing for a speed
buggy.
Remember that cartoon speed buggy?
No,
I don't.
It was like a.
It was like a cartoon when we were in
the buggy speed button,
remember?
Yeah,
and it had the guy with the goggles and
they would do this little theme song and
who would go speed buggy,
look at this and they'd go speed buggy,
and then speed buggy goes,
that's me.
Wait a minute.
Does that have anything to do with
scooby doo or they just thieves.
Probably the same people.
Exactly like the Scooby Doo people.
Yeah.
That's that Scooby Doo.
Instead of the car is Scooby Doo.
Shaggy,
redheaded guy and those.
That's the other two people that really
hanging out with scooby Doo and the
cheerleader.
We're in the same clothes.
Yeah.
Look,
that's a fight crimes and they find out
who the bad guys are.
Oh,
the gorilla almost gets it.
Like see that guy in the back?
That's the jock and the girl in the
front.
Yep.
That's like Veronica.
It was so simple.
Like,
you wouldn't make this now because I'll
Gilligan's island speed buggy.
That's me.
Could you make Gilligan's island without
people banging a fuck with believe that
he's telling me the only one that's
banging his Thurston Howell and his
wife.
They're the only ones who are banging.
The only ones that are married,
lovey.
Nobody else has even kissing.
Nobody.
The sailor,
the fucking.
The skipper and Gilligan.
Don't.
They have bunk beds?
They have a bunk hammocks.
Is that the most obvious gay couple ever
get over here.
Little Buddy.
Look at this.
We'll get have to fucking smoking hot
girls and then there's the two camps.
Like which camp are you?
You kept ginger or you can't marry in
like a regular girl.
Look,
I could take fishing like the girl next
door.
Yeah,
she looks sexy.
Girl.
That looks good on the red carpet.
I'm more ginger type.
I'd rather live in penalty hills and the
professor was like the intelligent one
and he wasn't that smart.
We didn't get to bang either.
Nobody gets to bang.
Nobody.
Bang.
The professor wasn't intelligent.
Not really.
It was like 70 science.
Well,
what did they know back then?
Right now he's like,
look,
I found a bird.
You can tell by its wings.
He's not concerned that stupid and bold
it like birds or pray like they get
eaten constantly.
Does that burden have any instincts?
If you eat it,
it's probably poisoned.
This was a hit,
a hit.
He's runaway hit.
He's rehabbing this bird.
I think if I remember correctly,
Gilligan's island was on for far less
time than we think.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I believe that.
I don't think it did a few seasons.
How many seasons if you.
Yes,
I loved it when I was a child.
Where are we seeing it in reruns for
sure.
60 seven.
60 four slash 67.
See,
it's only a three year.
A show for years.
How many episodes?
30 episodes.
That's crazy.
I guess it's four years.
If they did a full season for each year.
That is pretty short.
That's crazy.
How many episodes was it?
Say I'm trying to find out.
Might have been 30 per season.
Really?
That's a lot.
It's a lot of storylines usual.
Usually.
Usually it's 22 because you would get
13.
That would be your big order and then
you would get the back nine.
This was the olden times.
Well,
this is real old and times where they
didn't get paid.
So Gilgamesh skipper and everybody,
they got fucked,
played these things.
They're playing them somewhere now,
so whoever owns them,
they own it forever and you don't get.
You don't get residuals.
Wow.
Poor Gilligan.
They paved the way though.
A lot of shitty shows,
but they're still make like goofy shows.
You know?
It's interesting like the other kids
shows that the kids get raised on like
these Disney shows and stuff there.
As
goofy as all this stuff in the
seventies.
Some of them are funny man.
Yeah,
Dude.
I watch dog with a blog with my kids.
It's called dog with a blog and I think
it's canceled.
It's canceled now and they're all bummed
out for new episodes to watch a funny
show.
Good writing.
Like it makes me laugh.
I've laughed.
It's silly.
You know,
there's,
there's something to that classic rhythm
of giving you jokes.
Yeah.
They're,
they're,
they're traditional sitcoms is what's it
comes worse.
Multi camera and just joke,
joke,
joke.
Yeah.
Which is good.
If their jokes are good.
Yeah,
it is good.
If the jokes are good.
Yeah.
I don't watch them anymore now.
Well they don't really.
The only ones are the ones on a cbs like
big bang and they're the only ones who
still do it.
Yeah.
They're the only ones that really
doesn't do it anymore.
Now they're all single.
Cam NBC like the Carmichael show.
Is that one?
How's that?
True.
How do they do,
do they do okay.
They're still on and it got renewed for
another season.
So I mean that's at least what they're
looking for.
Probably.
It's.
Well,
I'm sure some people still enjoy it if
we're talking about it right now,
you know they do work if they're funny.
And there's funny characters.
That's a pure.
It's more jokes than the single cameras.
A lot of work.
You have done one.
You did one right now.
I ended up.
Well you didn't have a sitcom.
You had six episodes.
Yeah.
What was it?
It's called come to papa,
come to papa.
And uh,
it was just like a little song.
NBC.
Yeah,
man,
they kill them.
It was really quick.
I'm glad I did it,
but I would never do it again.
You wouldn't know why work.
Yeah.
It's so much work.
It's a great thing to do if you want to
be an actor,
but if you want to do standup as well,
no way.
Not especially not in the beginning
because in the beginning it's ruthless.
It's like 12 hour days every day.
You're always tired and you're not even
writing on it.
You're just acting in.
But you.
The only good thing is sometimes you
have time during the day,
like you might have a couple hours break
during the day.
You might even be able to go to the gym.
You might be able to,
like,
if you know you're not in like four
scenes in a row,
they'll tell you like,
hey,
you know,
we don't need you until noon.
You can bust out of that.
Sometimes you can bust out.
Right.
But that's not often.
But you'd be able to write a little bit.
Maybe it's,
yeah.
You know,
and the guys who are in it and write on
it,
then forget it,
and then you're when all the actors go
home,
then you go start going to work in the
writer's room.
I never forget.
I had lunch with Ray Romano when ray
was,
when he was just starting to do.
Everybody loves Raymond and I was me and
him and Kevin James and we're at Jerry's
Deli and all Ray Romano.
He's obsessed with his show.
He's like,
well,
how about if I had the guy?
He comes in here,
he walks in the door and that's a.
that's how we set up the scene.
Like he just feels like the reason why
that show had become that monster hit,
that it was like he was a great comic
who is obsessed with every fiber of his
being making this a really good show.
Yeah.
That's probably a really,
really to this day,
underrated show.
Everybody loves Raymond.
A great family show.
Great show.
So funny.
He's a funny dude too.
He is funny.
I worked with him in Queens,
New York at Jimmy's comedy.
Allie,
do you ever know that place is?
Never heard of it?
I never,
never there.
It was an old bowling alley that they
converted to a comedy club.
Great spot.
Was it?
It was a great spot.
It was a great spot and I.
I was the Middle Act and he was the
headliner x Ray Romano and I remember
like sitting back after the show was
after I did my car wash and go,
God damn,
this guy's a good joke.
Right?
So smooth and it's timing.
And I ran into him at stand up New York,
same thing.
I thought I did well and then ray walked
in and went on and I was like,
oh boy.
So good.
He was freely so smooth.
He was talking theater.
He was talking about somebody actually
saw another guy steal his joke and I was
so upset.
I just joke about a movie theaters as
you go with your guy friends and there's
always the.
I'm not a homo seat going off about the
insecurity of men.
They don't want to sit next to each
other,
but everyone's a hard schedule though.
Well,
how long were you doing it?
That was five years.
Five years?
Yeah.
I did it for five seasons.
That's,
that's good.
That's a good run.
Uh,
yeah,
I guess.
Yeah.
I mean it was good.
It was an interesting thing to do.
We did 90,
I think 98 or 99 episodes.
It was weird,
man.
It's a lot of work.
Yeah.
But no,
it was an awesome thing to do.
Yeah.
But I think that today,
like as back then,
that's all there was.
There was no reality shows.
There was no anything else.
There was a few dramas like cop shows
and shit.
There were multiple nights of all
comedies.
Thursday night was like all sitcoms on
NBC.
That was like the big lineup.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
What do they have on Thursday night tv?
So I don't know.
I have no idea they have.
And uh,
I know is not watch any of that stuff as
law and order NBC.
Yes.
What the fuck is with people?
Why are we so obsessed with people
getting caught murdering people?
I don't know.
I know someone was saying that,
uh,
like there's another podcast that just
came out that's really probably all
about murders.
It's just people love murder.
I'm sure.
I know.
I don't get that.
They love mysteries.
Mystery.
What's going to happen?
Is it going to get caught?
Willie Mack,
you know,
there's a podcast.
It's out now specifically about the
mystery of where's Richard Simmons?
Oh,
that's my podcast.
It's called come to papa,
but it's really about Richard Simmons
and back to come to papa.
I'll be in Syracuse,
May 14th,
15th,
and now Richard Seguin of where I am.
Whereas Richard Simmons.
Is that a real thing?
Oh yeah.
It's a real pocket.
Like they can talk to multiple days
about that forever.
They can talk to the end of the time.
They're gay.
If you're gay and you're on adderall and
you talk about Richard Simmons,
you could probably keep going,
keep going,
keep going.
And he was amazing.
Pioneer.
Okay.
Give him some fucking respect to the
left.
He's a goddamn pioneer,
but do something about that here.
Sarah.
Sir.
That's why people love murder.
I was not,
I don't like murder.
I don't like hospital shows,
I don't like.
My wife was addicted to a autopsy shows
when she was pregnant,
what it kicked in and she couldn't stop
watching autopsy shows on Hbo Guy.
Yeah,
I think that was it.
Michael Baton would catch people in the
weirdest ways.
Yeah.
Ooh,
weird.
There was one guy who had.
He had a.
He was a doctor and you have this woman
and he kept her body in his house and
you bring in crates and crates a perfume
and you had douse her decaying body with
perfume and he had fast and some sort of
a hole near where her abdomen was.
When it rotted away,
he put something.
He put something there,
said he manufacturer where he could
stick his dick into it.
It put a put a mask on her and you know,
they.
They were trying to figure out where the
body had gone.
This guy had taken the body and brought
it to his house.
It was so intense.
I'm like,
ah,
because I remember thinking like,
wow,
this guy wanted this woman so bad that
once she died he couldn't help himself.
He had to like keep her body.
Now I have her,
now she's with me.
This is what I've always needed.
Let me just keep covering her up with
perfume and he would get rock hard and
climb on top of her rotting bag of bones
and meat and stick his dick anywhere.
She's just,
he's probably at like a surgical mask
on.
She's like stinking of rotten meat and
perfume.
I would much rather watch Bob's burgers.
Yeah.
I got a little graphic folks.
You got really into it and it was
disturbing.
Well,
I just see this is why these shows are
popular because it like,
you know,
man,
I don't even watch that anymore.
Me Describing that and putting that
visual image to everybody's mind is
nothing like watching and getting that
visual image.
It's so much more innocent and less
guilty.
It's worse because now you made us a
part of it because we had to picture
painted ourselves.
You've got to know those people were
real though.
You know,
you do have to know those nurse one's
always freaked me out.
Find some nurses,
killed 50 people.
You're like,
what?
Had just quietly quietly poisoning
people.
These people are doing so good.
Tom.
Papa.
I just have a tooth.
Big.
We're going to have to amputate.
What?
Wait.
Hold on.
This nurse crap.
I mean that power rush must get from
doing crazy shit like that.
There was an autopsy.
Shows are fucking weird.
Man was a weird compelling fascination
that had happened to her while she was
pregnant was like this weird,
like definitely like something physical
and mental was happening.
We start getting nervous about your
environment.
How safe are we?
What's cool,
what?
What are people capable of?
You want to know what everything is and
you see ice tea kicking in the door to
some house and it's a woman gagged
special victims unit.
I'm here.
Body check out.
My new album dropped Monday.
Bombbomb.
She'd never done it.
Bombbomb,
take them away.
They get them in the end always because
it's law and order.
Bomb bomb.
It's not law and hopefully we have
order.
We enforce the law with ice t bomp,
bomp and Richard Belzer Belzer what a
weird career battles or two calls ago,
and a rapper they just go from.
It's important comic of his time,
New York and then palm palm for them for
the last 30,
just reading stale lines.
Thirty years.
Like how many years was he on that show?
Yeah,
I think.
I think maybe you think that's where the
body is so weird.
Probably like.
I bet he was on that show for 15 years.
The Bom Bom.
That's crazy,
but I guess that paycheck is just want
to go to giggles and Saugus no guy.
I'm not going to have a weekend.
Some drunk asshole is going to heckle
you over there.
Pizza?
No,
I'm done with that.
You'd have the sunglasses on and just
that attitude.
Harris?
No.
Do you remember that?
Yeah.
When you live in New York and you work
in New York,
you can live in Paris.
That's like a far away.
It's five hours flight.
It's like it's coming here.
Yeah,
it isn't coming here.
Just kind of go through customs.
New York's in the middle and so like
Johnny Depp lived in Paris for awhile.
I wouldn't work.
I did it.
No is he started hammering people,
hammering them.
I don't know.
I go on vacations and I'm like,
go to like some foreign country and
you're like,
this is so great.
And it's like after a couple of days,
like I got to get back to the states.
Yeah.
I don't understand people like I'm
moving to Costa Rica.
Fuck it.
No,
you're doing what right?
no,
no.
You visit their vacation.
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Why would you move there?
I want to go live.
Their coastal work is amazing,
Bro.
It is amazing.
It's amazing.
When you visit,
what if you live there?
You would go,
oh,
you have to bribe the cops.
You've got,
oh,
this is a toll.
I wasn't.
I was in Costa Rica on vacation with my
fucking kids.
Dude.
I'm walking my kids on the beach and
this guy goes,
hey man,
do you want weed?
Do you want coke?
What do you want?
No girls.
I'm like,
Hey,
listen buddy.
Come on man.
I'm here,
I want all those things,
but I don't want to right now they don't
ever real police force fire forest
running waters.
Intermittent,
no Gimme convenience.
One time it was in Mexico and I was at
this resort and they had these like
electric golf carts.
You can take the carts out of the resort
to go to a like a the local town and so
we left the resort and went to the local
town and maybe a block outside of the
resort.
There was a full on military compound.
I mean full on with dudes standing there
fully armed in a jeep,
an armored jeep with a like a
bulletproof face to face.
They like ducked down while they're
driving so they don't get shot.
And I'm watching this and I'm like,
what in the hell on the street realized,
Oh,
this is to protect the resort.
Oh my God.
Oh course.
It changed my entire feeling of what I
was doing before.
I was like,
Hey,
we're relaxing on the beach or Jamaica.
We're going to have some Mai Tai's and
kick back and look sad and it's so
beautiful.
I love Mexico.
I don't want everybody thinks is
dangerous.
Then there's guys with machine guns and
if they're not there,
we're all dead.
Oh,
you're fucked.
You're fucked.
Because of the people from the town.
We'll just go,
why do they have so much?
And we don't.
There's so
they're so poor and then you're bringing
in all these people with a lot of money.
Yeah.
Scary.
Yeah,
it was,
it was in A.
I just went to Dominican Republic and
they're like,
uh.
I said,
where do you stay in Puntacana?
That's where I was doing the show and
they're like,
that's the only place to stay.
And I was like,
isn't that bad?
And as I'm landing I'm like,
just look up to make it.
Like someone was doing a live,
a facebook live thing,
like in a studio and some guy walked in
and just shot him in the middle of it.
That was like happening as I'm like
nervously trying to find my guide to
bring me to the resort.
It's always just on the outskirts of
these places.
Yeah.
Well that was going on.
Acapulco.
Remember our member during the drug war
when it was at its worst.
Oh yeah.
Mexican drug war was going on down there
and Aco Poco.
A bunch of people got shot like tourists
and shit.
She's now.
It's serious stuff.
My parents went to Mexico when I was a
boy and brought back a shirt that's was
a Mexican guy and his sombreros said Aco
Poco and his bow tie said gold.
Oh,
that was my cool shirt.
Tim.
Tom.
Papa knows where the good weed.
My.
Yeah.
They would grow weed and Aco Poco.
They're called Acapulco gold.
Acapulco gold.
That was the shit.
Yeah,
man.
Remember that?
I got the shirt.
I never had any of that stuff mean I
didn't smoke weed.
I bet it wasn't that great.
Now,
compared to this science we had no,
no way.
No Way.
God Damn Wizards.
Yeah.
I get uncomfortable in those places.
I uh,
I always wanted to be like the cool
photo journalists who kind of hangs out
with the people and there's doesn't
worry and just goes to their house and
has a meal.
But I'm totally on guard and nervous
when I'm in places like that,
especially with my family.
Well,
if you're in a real poor area and you,
you know,
you're a bunch of wealthy white people
that are fucking vacation.
Yeah.
It's weird because the area needs it
because it provides,
you know,
like your revenue comes in and it helps
them and it gives people that live their
jobs.
It's again,
like we were talking about going outside
of Albany,
you just drive two hours outside of
Albany,
like where the fuck am I?
It's the same thing.
Yeah.
But probably more extreme.
Right,
exactly.
Because there's not as many cops.
Yeah.
Right.
And being a cop is a different thing.
If everybody's corrupt right now.
Narcos.
Yeah.
Woo Hoo.
God down 10 sat down.
That's a good show.
Narcos is scared.
Pablo Escobar lived a fucking crazy
life.
Crazy late with his pot belly.
How did he do that?
It's amazing how far some people get
with insane behavior.
It really is amazing,
isn't it?
Whoa.
That guy was just completely like,
no,
I'm going to make this work.
This is how my head works,
man.
He was blown up government buildings and
airplanes.
Scary.
Built his own jail,
put himself in a jail and partying.
They're bringing them bitches and
playing pool and handing out cash to the
people.
He was a hero.
Then afterwards he's like,
you know what?
I'm tired of being this fucking place.
Murdered a guy in the jail.
Lead them to hit in the head with a bat.
Yeah,
and then he's like,
ah,
fuck this place it just getting out.
I'm believing was a little sneakers so
crazy running down the path,
but this is all real things.
It's insane when you think how far that
is from how you live your life.
You know what I mean so far away and it
just happened.
Yeah,
it's happening right now.
Some.
Some new guy's on his way working up the
ladder.
How about when Sean Penn went down and
met El Chapo?
Took that fucking picture with him.
Yeah,
it was like,
how crazy is Sean Penn?
Was there ever.
Was there ever an article about that?
Like was there ever like an interview
with him and he wrote it?
Sean Penn wrote it.
I never read it.
I read it.
I remember the.
I remember the thing going down,
but I'm just my weird.
It was weird.
It was like,
I don't understand like what he was
trying to do,
like why he decided to do that.
Look at that fucking picture.
That picture is insane.
Dude.
Why did he do it?
Because he's crazy.
So wild man.
Sean Penn is a wild man.
I mean he really is.
You have to be to do this.
I had one opinion of him before that I
had a different opinion of him after
this.
This guy,
he actually did that.
He actually went there into the woods.
Right?
Then they put a hood over him or a
blindfold and remember how it all
happened.
But there was some girl who was friends
with El Chapo.
El Chapo was probably Dick Dicker way
the same way.
Same Way.
Pablo Escobar quarter shorter.
So El Chapo was probably stuff in that
girl too and he's like,
I want you to give me Sean Penn.
Right?
You're exactly right.
That's exactly what happened.
I don't know.
I don't know if he'll do it.
He'll do it.
Give me jump back.
I went that boyfRiend colors get get
healed from fast times at ridgemont
high.
He'll understand the good part of drugs
and that's right.
He was in colors using colors.
Ama nightmare.
Walked in.
Psychopaths talking ice tea.
It goes full circle.
We're back to it again.
I did a show last night for a charity
show and a common was on the show.
The rapper turned.
Now he's a big time actor,
writer and poet.
What a ppo.
Yeah,
he's a poet.
Slow your roll son.
He's a is because you make shit,
ryan.
I'm published.
He's a.
He's a positive force.
That guy.
He is a.
He's a good one for sure.
That's nice.
Yeah,
it was really.
I was impressed.
The world needs more poets.
Tom.
Papa it.
Sure.
It does not really.
Let me count the ways.
Poetry.
Boy,
that's one thing.
You better be good.
You're right,
and even if you are half the people are
gonna hate it.
It's like a comic.
It's like,
oh yeah,
you're bad.
It's really bad.
Even if you're good,
have you going to hate it?
You're just going to be a certain amount
of people that hate you no matter what.
You can do your best shit ever and some
people could say like,
you'll get like four tweets in a row
about a special fucking amazing,
amazing,
very disappointed.
I was going to be people that hate
everything in your audience of people
who are coming to see who's coming to
see you.
There's going to be a couple of people
like and there's also people that you're
never going to make happy no matter
what.
No.
Is it just twats?
It's just they just suck.
It's such a fun word.
Great word.
God is a good one.
They let us say it on the tv.
You can say on tv,
right?
You could say twat.
I bet you think you could say if a girl
says it,
my mom's a twat or mom's a twat.
My swat swat.
If a girl said,
looking at twat,
you should really think about not doing
it.
I know one girl says,
look,
my twat,
you go,
whoa.
It's a twat your,
what do you call it?
Dang it.
I was banging.
This girl wants,
you know,
back in the design when I was 20 and she
was the first girl to ever call her
pussy cunt.
I want you to fuck me in my car.
I was like,
whoa.
Hello.
This girl is crazy.
She was one of those nether regions
girls.
She was like the wildings,
you know how the wild were in the game?
A game of thrones,
you know those people that lived out in
the land between the kingdoms,
right.
She lived in Connecticut,
which is my mat.
That's where the wild things live and
those weird New York and Massachusetts,
Connecticut or some shit like that.
Like,
what are you doing it?
She was just,
she really,
she was crazy.
She was so crazy.
I went to the bathroom once and she gave
my friend her phone number,
like immediately after I'd already been
having sex after I had sex with that day
and she gave my friend her phone.
She was crazy.
But you know,
women don't like any guy that would not
tell you that some girl gave,
you know,
the year you're dating gave him her
number.
that's like,
yeah,
a bad guy to have with.
Did he Tell you fuck you.
I did.
Oh,
that's good.
He goes,
dude,
he goes crazy bushes.
As soon as you went to pete gave me.
She gave me her number.
I go,
no way.
Showed me the piece of paper.
Oh,
that's cute.
He goes,
go show it to her.
I go,
okay.
did you leave this with my friend
started laughing.
When she say she was so stupid.
She was crazy.
She was more crazy than she was stupid.
And what did you see her often?
I saw when I would go to Connecticut,
right?
Like every,
you know,
five,
six months for like a year and a half.
Right.
And the last one was like,
I gotta stop.
I gotta stop hanging out with this girl.
She was way too crazy.
She came to one of my comedy shows and
she brought these people that might as
well been screaming baboons trapped in a
cage at the zoo.
Well,
people threw water balloons.
There was screaming.
They were heckling and screaming and
then I left her there.
I left her and her friends there.
I just bolted as soon as I got off stage
and just went outside,
got in my car and just drove.
And back then when you drove,
you were gone?
Nobody had a cell phone.
That's right.
You could escape.
You can literally get escape.
I actually had a cell phone before that
but I couldn't afford it anymore so I
didn't have a.
So I had a car phone for awhile in like
1989 nights.
This was like a year or two after that.
I was like 90 or 91,
so I don't even think anybody could get
ahold of me.
That's cool.
You could just get in the car and go.
Oh yeah.
No one could find you.
You just go.
So great.
well,
I used to have these,
like one of the things I really like
about these yellow legal pads is that
these yellow legal pads to me,
they have like this different feel to
them because that's what I would write
all the directions to places that I
would go to because there was no
internet back then.
So you would get lIke a gig from like
the comedy connection,
like Billy Downs would be booking a
room.
You call him up and he would give you
the directions,
you know.
Okay.
You got a pen?
Yeah,
hold on a second.
And it was always,
I would write it all on these legal,
legal,
a yellow legal pads and then I would
write down the address and directions
how to get there,
what to look for.
There's a third bar and that's the one
you want to turn and then you'll see the
fucking wings hot is that amazing?
So crazy.
But I would have them with me and I'd be
all excited because I look at that piece
of paper.
I'd be like,
I'm a hitman going out to do a job,
you know,
sort of felt like,
yeah,
I'm in the middle of,
as I'm driving out in the middle of
nowhere to disconnected lands.
So these places like,
is that shit?
Damn one nighters.
Just drive for mont,
do a sHow drive back same night.
Yeah.
I met this pretty girl once in Maine.
She was really pretty and she had a nose
rings should,
I think she had two nose rings.
Had a ring in each nostril and like
she's still pretty.
Yeah,
pretty that word.
But it was what it was and we were
hanging out and I was,
it was just too heavy.
I was like,
sHe was so trapped in this weird main
town.
Oh yeah.
And I was only,
you know,
21 and I was seeing like where her path
was,
where my path was and like I didn't even
want to have sex with her because of it.
It was so heavy because you knew that
she was trapped in this like weird land
and if you had sex with her,
you know,
some turnaround with her.
RigHt?
Or I would get her out,
I was just like,
the whole thing to me was like so
bonkers.
So like she was describing her life and
all the different winter or family that
were abusive and
all this craziness.
I was like,
oh my god,
this is so heavy.
And I realized if you just buy an
unfortunate roll,
the dice were literally shat out of your
mom's vagina in the forest and there's
some weird bar that everybody in this
forest town gravitates to.
And then some industrious person from
boston decides,
well,
we're going to book that bar and we
would drive up to those places,
meet these poor poor people that were
trapped there.
Some of them are cool as fuck.
Some of them are really cool.
Some of them have Great family.
Some of them love it up there.
Yeah,
but not this girl.
This girl was.
I'll never forget like her just.
Well,
especially at that age.
Imagine like being a girl in that
situation where it's just like these
animals,
one of these guys in this pack is going
to be the one or some new dude just came
out of town from out of town and tell
jokes at least now with social media,
you see that there's options out there,
like you see other people living lives
in different places so you can at least
you're aware that there's another.
There's somewhere I could go.
well also you are also aware that
there's other communities where you
could probably thrive and you can make
friends online and you can get really
find out where's a good place to live.
You can get a job online.
you could save up your money.
You can go somewhere and you can get out
of there.
This is what I was thinking.
Don't you remember that there were kids
like working places all the time when
you were growing up?
Oh yeah.
From the time I was like 14 kids were
working.
You would like you.
There'd be kids working at the diner.
They're big kids work at the pizza place
at the ice cream shop.
At the gas station,
you don't see kids working anymore.
It's true.
What happened is are the jobs just taken
by adults who need them?
God damn man,
come over here and steal our children's
jobs.
I used to be a good job for children.
Is that just where we grow up that
there's no kids working?
Like are they doing it?
You know,
we live in California is always white
people out here,
but I grew up in New Jersey and we were,
we weren't that far from the city.
See again,
we're old people talking about young
people.
These kids today,
we don't know what we're talking about
with high school.
Like they don't fucking know what
they're talking about.
We're not judging them.
It's in their forties.
Talking about high school,
we're trying to learn,
but there used to be kids working
everywhere.
We're speculating now.
We don't know.
People get upset if you're speculating
such that somebody did on twitter.
some comic dude got mad at me because I
was talking to gavin about gay people.
We weRe talking about,
um,
not,
not even gay.
People were talking about specific
incidences that have been in the news,
like milo yiannopoulos,
having that a thing fall out from under
him because he said like it's acceptable
for older man who was essentially saying
it's acceptable for older men to have
sex with her 13 year old boy,
and they were talking about george to
kai who talked about that as well.
It Happened to him at a summer camp,
like some older dude had sort of busted
moves on him and ran him off and shit
and it was pleasurable and he enjoyed it
and we were talking about like,
wow,
it's like a.
It's an intense,
intense subject.
Right.
Scott got upset that we were talking
about it.
Without a gay perspective.
You're not allowed to speak about it.
Figure it out.
I think it was attention whoring and
maybe he just saw the green light to be
upset and so he went for it.
It wasn't right.
Wasn't rash comic.
Yeah.
Guy branham's of his name,
whatever.
We worked it out online.
He was friendly afterwards and he
apologized and I apologized.
right,
right.
It was one of those things where it's
like people do get,
tend to feel like they're allowed to get
upset.
You're talking about something that you
don't have experienced death.
I know.
Even if it's something to discuss it,
it's ridiculous,
right?
You're not allowed to try and figure it
out.
Well,
that's what learning is.
That's what learning is coming from
something that you don't know anything
about and asking questions and having a
discussion about it.
THat's when you know something's
bullshit.
When you're not allowed to talk about
it,
you're not even allowed to talk about
it.
You can't discuss even politely,
respectfully talk about it.
Well then your thing is bullshit.
You know you have no argument.
You have no side.
Well,
there's always this thing,
right,
and it's.
This is a big thing in certain circles
when it comes to disenfranchise people
or you,
you hear it when it comes to gender and
sex.
You hear it like,
you know,
you should like one of the wonderful
things that male feminists love to say.
I'd love to say,
just shut up and listen to the women.
You need to shut up and listen to women.
Well,
that's crazy.
You never shut up because even if you're
being respectful,
someone says something and you would
like them to clarify or are you
confused?
Or maybe you have some information that
may they might not be aware of that
might change their thoughts on things
like being engaged in the conversation
with someone is not necessarily a
negative thing,
but everyone is assuming that if you're
not a girl,
you shouldn't talk about girl issues.
You shouldn't hAve any perspective.
Yeah.
If you're not a part of the world of
girl,
if you're not a guy,
if you're gay,
if you're not straight,
if you're not,
you shouldn't talk about it.
So what you're saying when you're asking
people not to talk about is you're
saying it.
It'd be better if this whole,
that whole,
your whole part of the population stays
ignorant of what's going on and we just
listened and we just stay where.
Listen,
I'll tell you.
Right.
You just listen.
I'll tell you.
That's crazy.
That's completely insaNe.
Well,
it's a power thing is what it is and
when certain things developed too much
social clout,
when subjects hit hit this critical mass
of social clout,
but like when the whole bruce jenner
thing was going on,
when you had to say that she was
beautiful and you had to say that you
accepted it,
you had to say it was amazing.
Wasn't she?
Just a fucking kardashians.
Just a little while ago is a ridiculous,
insane family.
Wasn't this guy like the dumbest one on
the show?
Like right?
What just happened?
Right?
He's got just push a lady into traffic
with his car because he wasn't paying
attention to kill her.
If we don't Pay attention to that,
but we pay attention to this whole
gender change.
It's going to give.
It's going to make you give a pass to
all that other behavior and it'll make
you seem like a really progressive and
open minded person if you say all the
right things.
Tom,
papa,
what's your opinion?
Well,
let me just say,
I think she's very brave and she's
beautiful and a hero,
but
the hero hero.
You know what I kept doing with my
daughters to a to drive them crazy.
They were living in 14.
We're watching the oscars.
Anyone that came on was a little chubby,
male or female.
I would just say,
oh my god,
look at him.
He's so brave.
Oh,
look at her.
She's.
She's so brave.
My $5.
That's just a new way to say to you,
your thinks she's fat.
No,
I think.
Look at that.
I mean,
she's wearing that dress on tv dad.
My five year old doesn't give a fuck.
My five year old,
she will.
She's six now,
but when she was five,
she was watching caitlyn jenner,
my youngest.
She just say she was watching caitlyn
jenner on tv and she goes,
daddy,
why does that?
Well,
dress and makeup like that.
She's like shaking her head.
She goes,
why is that man wear dress and makeup
like that?
I go,
I don't know.
That's how he or she identifies as a.
She now she turns from a man into a
woman and she just looked at me and she
just like leaned her head back and
raised her eyebrows.
She walked away,
I was like,
dead kid,
just she left the room.
She just left the road.
She's like,
bitch,
please,
without saying it.
She said,
bitch,
please.
She pulled her chin closer to our chest,
lifted her eyebrows up the fuck outta
here.
You just told me that that man turned
Into a woman.
I know.
It's a man.
I'm looking at her.
Daddy,
daddy,
why does a man have a dress on him?
He got and I was like,
well,
she used to be a man,
but she became a woman.
I liked her.
Walking out of the room is kind of
blaming you too.
like all you adults that are a mess.
You are retarded.
That can't even happen.
I'm six and I know it can't happen or
five time,
daddy.
I'm not stupid.
I'm stupid.
Okay.
Yeah.
This is some santa claus bullshit.
You're fucking running by me.
I'm supposed to think the tooth fairy
comes,
sneaks under money under my seat.
The Whole thing is.
This is so funny.
I mean that,
that is a big part of what the,
uh,
election was about.
Talking you making a say in things or
just letting things be real well,
it goes in cycles.
We go one way and we go the other way.
That's what it is.
It's just like we got tired of people
going so hard politically.
Correct,
but you see how there's progress now.
Like we were talking about school.
Yeah,
exactly.
I mean you can't.
I mean that's good.
People would walk into our schools,
kids will walk up to other kids that
were kind of slow.
What are you retarded like right to
their face.
Look at him.
He was a sped.
He's retarded.
That doesn't exist anymore and I think
it still exists.
It just exists less and not when your
kids go to school in comparison to where
you go to school,
I mean a bit of a unified and you're
hanging out in compton.
I bet you see some bad shit in school.
Probably.
This is probably some bad shit's still
going on in a lot of schools.
A lot of kids are getting bullied and
people understand the consequences of
that now.
like you're scared to go to class cause
someone's gonna hit you,
scared to go to class.
Someone's beat new.
But bullying was just part of life,
wasn't bullying,
it was just life back then,
but it wasn't bullying and it did ruin
people's lives did,
but nobody called it out.
No adult would you out with it?
No,
it's just the way it went.
You have to learn how to take care of
shit and everyone was being bullied by
somebody else.
It was a.
It was dog eat dog.
It was,
you know,
I don't know.
I think that you're right.
I mean the politically correct thing.
There's swings that way and you're left
with some good stuff and everybody
adjusted and then it goes too far and
you start to go after things that don't
affect a lot of people and then people
get fed up by.
well those.
The thing is those people that goes too
far that go too far with all that
politically correct stuff,
right?
They're almost always emotionally
unbalanced,
so given enough time they will reveal
themselves to be either crazy or power
hungry or like really like a big part of
that whole social justice warrior
movement is really about shaming people,
like expressing anger,
attacking people,
gaining power,
punching people that disagree with you,
like punch,
fascist punch,
punch nazis like being aggressive about
it and that somehow or another,
this is a good thing as if because
they're so delusional and so detached
from real physical violence that they
have this idea that you just going to go
out there and push these people and take
it back.
No,
They're gonna show up with guns.
You fuck like this is how wars get
started to escalate.
You try to control people.
You pushed too far.
You're not kind.
Instead you're shaming people.
You're creating bad feelings and
aggression,
like they've got this juvenile idea
about confrontation,
that it just goes out there and it never
comes back to you.
It always comes back.
Good luck.
Yeah,
it comes back.
It comes back.
Yeah.
Now it's.
It's people are.
I think striving for kindness is a good
thing.
I really think that trying to be nice to
people.
There's nothing wrong with that.
No,
but then if you're trying to be so nice
that now you're the aggressor,
you've gone over the side of the cliff
100 percent and that's what happens when
people do that.
So far left.
They go around the fucking equator and
they wind up on the right.
I mean,
right?
It just happens.
You become a fascist to fight off the
fascists,
so it happens round and round.
They go and the people that are
effective with it,
one of the things that's happening is
they outdo each other.
They feed off of each other,
they play to each other.
They're playing to the room and they
ramp it up so they know that there's
other people that agree with them and
then they see how far they can take it
and the further you could tell you like,
oh my god,
mike is so hardcore.
Holly's not as hardcore as paul.
Paul's out there struggling.
He's in Guatemala right noW.
You know what I mean?
It's like they.
They Pushed so hard like this social
justice front that they're doing it for
each other and imPressing each Other and
impressing these communities of people
that get together and then somewhere
along the line they forget how cruel
there being two people who disagree with
them.
Yeah,
they're being vicious and nasty and uh,
trying to shame people and write blogs
about them and attack them and videos
and they do not realize that while
they're doing this,
they're just setting a process in motion
that is unavoidable.
You putting out
negative and it'S going to come back and
you will not only that,
you're going to feel personally the
effects of all that stuff.
Like when you're shitting on people,
you ruined someone's life with some hate
blog or something like that.
And tHen that person attacks you and
toxic.
Yeah.
And people are gonna know that you did
that.
So they're going to want to come back to
you.
They're going to feel that you put
something out there so they're going to
root for something.
Come back your way or oh,
I don't know how people survive that
way.
I really game.
That's their game because they don't
have a real physical conflict.
Conflict comes.
Then they probably came from families
where they like to fight a lot and it
was like they're kind of built for that.
There's no sensitivity to get
programmed.
Yeah,
it's a strange existence.
Well,
we've all been in arguments before and
we've all had that feeling after.
It's over that gross feeling of the
conflict,
feeling like,
oh,
I hate this.
Like how did I get sucked into this
again?
Like what did I do?
Like why did I react like that?
Like why am I here?
And there's people that have that
feeling and they're constantly trying to
avoid those situations,
but they still come up occasionally and
then they feel even woRse when they come
up.
For me,
conflict today feels so much worse than
conflict felt like 10 or 15 or 20 years.
Have you personally?
Yes.
When I'm involved in conflict,
I'm so much more sensitive to how people
feel than I used to be.
Twenty years ago.
If I was in an altercation with someone,
I would like to go fuck yourself by.
Really.
I'd walk away like it was nothing really
think twice and then as I got older I'd
always think like,
how am I coming off to that person?
Like maybe I could've handled it better.
Like maybe tHe communication if I was
just more calm initially they would have
been more calm.
We could have laughed it off,
you know,
like a kid in the pool hall.
But the kid in the pool hall was not a
threat and he was a young kid and I saw
and I was like,
what are you doing?
You're going to get hurt.
Like,
don't do that.
But this,
this,
um,
as I get older,
I.
This is revelation that a lot of what we
get into a lot of these confrontations
and arguments and disputes and a lot of
negativity is avoidable.
Like it's not worth,
it's not worth the attack.
No,
it's not.
It's a.
I always felt that way,
that it's a little more zen.
Like to let it go with it.
And uh,
and then,
um,
my buddy was saying,
no,
you're more like codependent.
You are like,
you are a,
you're trying to make other people happy
to a point where it's a negative for
you.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Know what I mean?
Like when you were talking about you
being 20 and just being like,
go fuck yourself.
It's like I never had that and I always,
I was always a little envious of that.
I had too much of it like being on the
road and somebody cuts you off and it's
just like you feel so bad and you're
like,
if someone gives you the finger,
it's like I carry that with me all day.
It's such an upsetting integrate set.
I would still get me wrong.
I was totally upset all day.
Yeah.
But I wouldn't feel bad.
Right.
I'd be like that fucking piece of shit.
Like what I would that.
Yeah.
I wouldn't feel bad that like,
ah,
I could avoid that confrontation.
Right.
It wouldn't feel that I'd have a stupid
way of looking at it where instead of
like being philosophical about my own
role in having this take place in my own
inability to manage the communication
header.
Yeah.
How To handle it.
It's like everything else,
like you get better at catching balls,
you know,
like some dudes are way better at
catching a baseball than you.
RigHt.
And if you go out and try to catch that
baseball,
you couldn't be caught.
it was out of my hands,
but meanwhile someone who's way better
at it but just snatch it out of the sky
and be like,
I got this easy,
easy out.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
It's essentially the same thing when
you're communicating with people.
If you're,
if you're not good at communicating,
you have these awkward moments and you
are as much responsible for someone else
getting paid even if they did something
wrong,
like you're as much as responsible for
it going bad as they are in a way.
IT's a difficult thing because you can
sometimes be very aware of it and very
sensitive to people and try and make
everything cool.
And then somebody says something or does
something and you're,
there's something inside us that just
flares.
It just like specially with booze.
Yeah,
yeah.
it's just like,
no,
you know,
and it catches you by surprise.
It's like,
yeah,
and then,
but the problem is when it catches me by
surprise,
I'm always like,
oh my god,
my mouth is moving faster than my brain
here.
I'm just saying aggressive things and I
don't.
I'm not.
Haven't thought this through like that.
People do do that and then you're like,
oh shit.
Better be poised for violence.
So you're look like your brain's on.
Then the communication skills are even
worse because I'm not really thinking
about communicating.
I'm thinking if I feel like you're
moving in my direction too quickly,
I'm going to act right now.
So we're,
we're in this stage.
Do you?
Because I was.
Do you have,
because you know violence or you know
fighting,
you have been trained in it.
You know it.
You've lived aspect of it.
Does it put you more on alert physically
when you're out in the world?
I've seen people get punched.
I've seen people geT punched with.
I didn't expect to get punched.
I've seen people get sucker punched and
knocked unconscious.
It's fucking terrifying,
but I'm saying people do do it.
I know the consequences of it.
Nobody.
so do you.
When you walk around the street,
are you more,
are you,
are you looking for violence more than
someone that wasn't trained?
Not to,
not to engage in.
I know what you're saying.
No,
no.
You.
Are you aware of it happening?
I'm definitely.
I definitely try to be aware when
there's men and they're drinking when
whenever there's men and they're
drinking or if you're in a poor
neighborhood like we were talking about,
you know,
being outside of a resort in Mexico and
you see the military and you realize why
it's there.
I jusT think that for the most part
you're safe like almost everywhere and
it's being a man,
especially if you're a woman,
be a very different thing because you
have two things going on yet.
One,
the majority of the People around you
that are men can overpower you and to
the majority of people that are men
might fuck you.
Right.
You know,
I mean if you're already active woman in
particular and you're walking around,
you have a nice body,
like you're juSt a god damn asshole
target.
It's everywhere you go click.
He put those yoga pants on those
lululemon's.
Yeah,
it was a fuchsia,
oh my god,
pants.
And you got that big juicy ass and
you're walking down the mall,
you're going to get bombed on.
It's going to happen.
Are you saying when I'd wear it?
Yeah,
juicy guy.
But when you're,
you're,
when you're not in those heightened
situations,
you're not thinking no.
right.
But when people get inflamed,
I get super nervous because it's similar
to the gun thing.
It's similar to like,
well,
it is a gun.
Well,
if you have a gun,
you're living.
Your reaLity is different.
Right?
Right.
Well there's that.
But there's also like when people get
upset and you know,
we were talking about things ramping up,
like the momentum of them gets away from
you and then you're saying things you
haven't thought out yet.
People make actions that they haven't
thought out yet and you're a reasonable
guy.
And um,
I tried to be pretty reasonable and if
I'm saying this and I'm admitting to the
emotions can get carried away,
especially when there's danger involved,
I can get to saying things that I should
have probably never said.
It just got away from me.
What about an idiot,
what an idiot who had been abused as a
child would have been an idiot,
has been beaten and abused as a child
and it is almost like feels like they're
at such a deficit of love and they were
owed so much violence that they're very
caPable of inflicting violence on random
people for no reason.
It's just how they're programmed.
yeah,
and that goes back to what we're talking
about earlier about real leaders.
If we had a real leaders in real
direction in this country,
we would.
We would fix the educational system in
these Bad neighborhoods and spent a ton
of money to try to rejuvenate these
neighborhoods or have some sort of a
plan to eliminate crime,
to reduce crime rather to to make it
safer.
And you got to start with kids when
they're really,
really young.
Yeah.
I can't wait until they're 16,
17 and go in and just throw some money
at it and expect it to.
You've got to work.
You've got to just dump tons of money
into it.
You know,
the private sector is the thing that's
do that,
does that more than more than a couple,
but what they,
or even the nonprofits like I did this
gig last night when I was saying with
common last night,
it was this group called the group.
So did You just stand up?
I did stand up and hosted the whole
night and uh,
it's all about kids.
It's in la and it's all about helping
autistic kids,
kids with special needs and you just
watch.
It's such a nice thing to see all these
people donating money,
spending the night to support this
school,
that this woman's passion just purely to
help autistic kids survive and find a
way in the world.
That's awesome.
I like those kind of efforts.
When you see like bill gates giving all
of his money,
there's sourcing does the opposite of
what bill gates,
just trying to find programmers for
windows 30,
seen them now and it's like autistic
kids,
they fucking wicked programming.
Just sit in front of a computer breaks,
just give him coffee.
He calls it a camp,
but it's reallY the back of microsoft.
Come on,
do I can't
believe you.
Do you know that ones and zeros can
represent computer language.
What does that mean?
This is interesting.
Show me more.
So your parents,
you want to live with me?
Kenny.
You can stay in the place where I keep
my submarine.
Wow.
Interesting.
How does it propelled?
You could pound when you get them,
but it really is pretty hopeful when you
see these,
these private groups with a lot of
money,
like pushing it.
Well the government doesn't do it
anyway.
Feeling anYtime.
You know,
if someone's doing something nice,
that feeling,
that feeling of oh,
a person's doing a nice thing to see
what the pope said about panhandlers and
sweet that you can fuck them.
Like your four kids,
you know,
you've read it.
No,
this,
this pope is antiquing and he's not like
that last guy.
No,
he's.
Yeah,
he's totally not into it.
No.
What did he said that,
uh,
he said,
you know,
in the question of whether you should
give or not.
Uh,
it always comes up and you think,
well,
what is he going to use?
The money on him is just for drugs or is
it a,
is it,
am I doing it just to make myself feel
better?
All these kinds of questions come up
when you pass someone who's asking you
for money and he said there's nothing.
There's never anything wrong with
giving.
There's,
there's never anything wrong with giving
to someone who's asking.
They're asking for some reason as a
human being,
it's okay to give,
and I thought that's great,
and then I thought,
but when he's not taking into
consideration is,
but then what about the guy?
Then you walk a block and there's
another guy and another guy,
you run out of money,
or you vaden decide,
now I gave to that guy and you're still
in that space of,
no,
I'm a good person,
but you still have to go through all
that stuff in your head.
good point,
right?
Yeah.
When did you decide?
at what point does it stop?
I'm good enough.
He got the pope has never been to santa
monIca.
Oh,
that's right.
You know what I mean?
It's right.
One after the other.
Those homeless dudes backpacks.
Yeah.
Dogs.
Almost dudes with dogs are the weirdest.
Like you are not winning anything.
You fuck?
How are you feeding your dog?
Never roof.
It's so shitty.
It's totally shitty,
but it's also broken people.
It's like,
well,
who raised that guy will a guaranteed.
It wasn't some really awesome dad like
tom papa and some really nice
neighborhood and everybody loved them
and there's a lot of family and friends
around and know our times.
Hard tImes.
My heart fucked up times.
Yeah,
it's hard being a person even if you're
just normal,
if you're just.
It's hard to keep it together.
It is,
man.
It's hard fOr everybody.
For all of us,
and it's hard for a bunch of reasons and
one of the biggest reasons is that the
reality of being a human being does not
make sense.
It just doesn't.
Right?
Well,
you need a job to do.
You gotta keep yourself busy.
That's the only way.
Otherwise you start thinking,
oh,
here I am clinging to this balls.
It hurdles through infinity,
right?
You got to bring them up.
The news,
when I remember like when your kids
first show up,
some of first things toys
are like kitchen sets and and work
benches and [inaudible] and they just
gravitate to it and want to do a project
and they make together fake breakfast
and bring it over to you and give it to
you.
They want to be busy.
You want your head to do something.
You have to feed your brain some
activity.
You really do tv,
no dangerous.
It doesn't have to be something big
either.
It could be something small,
just be into something and that's why tv
so dangerous because you can live your
whole life without ever developing any
interest.
That's right.
Going from show to show to show and your
mind is now occupiEd,
occupied on some other actions,
extraneous actions.
They're not even in your immediate
vicinity.
It's a positive thing.
When people ask me if I've seen this
show,
I don't know what we just binge it.
you've got the more shows.
I say,
I haven't seen it means I'm doing
something right.
one show.
do you have a role?
Ira?
Allow myself one show that I'm watching.
Oh,
that's a good,
that's a good role right now it's house
of cards,
which is great because I just got into
it a little bit ago.
I'm only on season three and it was like
two whole seasons to watch.
Right.
That's good.
That's a good spot.
Shows good.
So I'm wondering if I watch an hour of
tv a night.
That's good.
That's a lot.
That's plenty.
I uh,
yeah.
I can't,
you should be doing something else.
I need to do more shit though,
you know,
but I'm feeling right now.
I need to do something new.
Oh yeah,
I am.
I'm like,
I'm,
I don't know.
I'm not,
I don't feel like I'm stagnant because
I'm constantly in motion.
It's all very positive and I appreciate
all the good things that are happening
and I appreciate all the people that
enjoyed the podcast and the comedy shows
and all that stuff.
But man,
right now I feel like I need to wrap my
brain around something fresh and novel.
New.
Have you ever tried baking bread?
Not interested.
So what do You need it?
It's what you can give your kids.
Did my kids shit that I won't even eat
bread?
Tastes awesome.
I would,
I would do bread like once a week.
It isn't maybe a cook bread on sunday.
It's a great mental.
Uh,
it is that thing that I found like I was
kind of the same way and it kind of gave
me.
I'm not saying this to be bright,
but some kind of thing like that where
it's something that grounds you.
I think I'm going to write a book.
Yeah,
that's a good api.
Gearing up for that over the last couple
of days.
Thinking I need like some sort of a
project to wrap my head around,
other than all the shit that I'm already
doing.
I'm writing one right now.
I have a deadline in may.
How many pictures isn't it there better
be alive.
I'll read both pictures right now.
It would have to have a lot of pictures.
That's a photo shoot.
You and me.
We're at a podcast.
Why are there 20 pictures of you and joe
rogan?
We need to fill pages out of my check.
Please.
Wasn't writing a lot though.
You said 200 pages,
200 pages.
Fuck you.
That would be perfect.
It's a bear to do blogs all the time and
I think it.
Yeah.
I live very least.
I'm gonna start writing blogs again
because I.
You should do a book.
I don't want.
I'm not trying to talk you out of it.
I would see it as a fan and a friend
would like to be joe rogan bootcamp.
I'm going to lie about everything.
We make up stories.
I'm going to make journalism book where
I'm going to have like some aspects of
my life and then it'll be like.
Remember when chuck woolery,
not chuck woolery,
chuck barris barris.
They did a whole movie about him being
an assassin for the government.
He was part of the guy.
He was the host of the gong show and
killing people for the cia.
I'm gonna do that.
I'm going to like have most of real
stories of like my childhood intertwined
with like murderers and werewolves and
fucking that's a great call it truth or
not.
You see this fucking latest shit.
A wiki leaks saying that the cia has
access to all of our phones vault.
Seven leaks today.
Yeah.
What is looked through it yet?
Pull up a full.
Because edward snowden was saying that
it's not whether or not they can access
where they have access to your ink
encrypted shit.
It's like they've hacked android and
ios,
like they get into android and ios.
So if you're some.
But here's the thing,
they're saying they use it for
espionage.
right.
So like if the russians are here,
they want to find out what they're up
to.
You could hack into their phone and get
their data.
They are doing it too.
So like if,
if somehow or another we stopped the cia
from doing it.
Right.
Here's the question,
would you want.
If Russia is doing it in china's doing
and North Korea and then all of a sudden
the cia can't do it anymore,
aren't they at a disadvantage?
Yeah.
That seems.
That seems like we don't know what the
fuck we're doing psa.
This incorrectly implies the cia hack
those apps,
these apps,
ford slash encryption,
but the doc show ils ford slash android
or what got hacked,
a much bigger problem,
so still working through the
publications,
but what wikileaks has here is a
genuinely is genuinely a big deal,
looks authentic,
see,
but I just,
I feel like we have to be very careful
if other people are doing things right.
So like if you talk to people in the
intelligence community,
and I don't talk to a lot of them,
but I have talked to a few,
well they will tell you is you have to
understand that what the majority of the
american public thinks is going on in
the world and what their motives are and
what kind of espionage and fucking dirty
tricks take place.
It's way worse than you think it is your
way.
Lucky that you're sheltered from all
this stuff and they're just,
there's some bad fucking things that are
going on in the world and one of those
things is what you're looking at in
Russia right now is like an emerging
superpower run by a dictator.
Yeah.
And anybody who opposes him winds up
dead.
Yeah.
Have you seen all those fucking russians
that have wound up dead recently?
They're attached to these leaks.
There.
Wasn't there?
Like what's the latest count?
Six yesterday.
I don't know if it.
I think there was a shepherd one
yesterday that died.
Just taking people out.
People would just mysteriously getting
whacked.
And they're billionaires.
Oh really?
Yes.
They're whack.
And billionaires.
Jesus.
They're just whacking people,
you know too much.
Oh yeah.
Come fish.
Let's go fishing.
These guys are disappearing.
They're not fucking around.
Tom.
Papa,
do you think that control?
Do you think that they,
uh,
did they look at that?
Russian diplomats keep dying
unexpectedly.
Look at his face.
Holy shit.
He just terrifying to me is terrifying.
He's like one of those help pigs.
We want to think that the world,
the world has learned from hitler and
stalin and mussolini.
The world's learn.
they're not going to do that again.
I don't buy that.
No.
The number.
what they say.
The number one it says on here,
six have died since november.
This was.
So does it make you more frightened that
they were interfering in our election?
well,
they certainly were aware of what was
going on and they certainly had access
to some documents about the dnc.
The what?
What concerns me is people that are
ignoring.
Although that is an issue for sure,
right?
But they're ignoring that.
What they did was they let us know about
some horrible shit that the democrats
were up to where they were rigging the
primaries and fucking over bernie
sanders because he was too powerful and
too dangerous to hillary clinton.
So they concluded,
they all used,
they,
they conspired rather,
and they all use their influence to fuck
over bernie sanders and then saying that
the russians hacked the election because
they exposed that the democrats are a
bunch of cheat and creeps is kinda
disingenuous because yes,
they did hack the election because they
did release some of that information so
they did have an impact on it,
but that impact was essentially the
truth and something that we really
deserve to know in the first place.
We deserve to know the inner workings of
the dnc.
We deserved to know that,
that they are getting in the way of
democracy.
They're rigging it.
Yeah.
Well there,
you know.
Yeah,
they're rigging it.
Politics is always dirty.
There's no politics.
It's illegal.
What they were doing was wrong.
Like what they were doing was they were
interfering with the democratic process.
Whether or not it's illegal.
It can be argued in court and maybe
should be,
but it's most certainly not what anybody
wants.
We want the dnc to dictate who we are.
What are the primary is
we want people to dictate it.
We all sit in one,
Joe Kennedy putting people didn't want
Joe Kennedy putting his bing in and
stealing votes for his son to be sure
that this stuff is always go on,
but that doesn't excuse it.
But now with the sidling up to that guy,
you know what I mean?
That that guy,
for whatever reason it is,
he wants to defeat us.
Right?
So any kind of,
any kind of influence in that,
people within that campaign are now
having to.
They're getting caught talking to them
and then they lied about it for some
reason they didn't want people to know
whatever that was about,
and now you have this foreign enemy who
is now sidled up with a lot of the
people who are now running our
government.
A government,
by the way,
that isn't.
That is hell bent on tearing a lot of
stuff down.
You're right,
but what they.
The only reason why it worked at all was
because the democrats were involved in
shady shit.
It's not like they made up some stuff,
so she's not.
See what I'm saying?
Yes,
she's dirty.
They were dirty.
The dnc was dirty,
but okay.
I'll give you the results.
Not good results.
Not good.
No.
Having Donald Trump win in this fashion
and having the russians interfered and
then also having some sort of an
influence on him financially,
all those things are not good.
Yeah,
but it's a little disingenuous to the
store.
The fact that hillary was a terrible
candidate.
Yes.
She was so compromised from so many
different angles.
I mean,
she didn't support gay marriage until
2013,
I think it was.
She didn't,
um,
she not only that,
she,
I mean like the clinton foundation is
just a disaster,
like the whole thing and even filled
with an scary shit and look,
she was definitely disliked by a lot of
people from being there for a lot of
time doing stuff that made a lot of
people very nauseous.
Well,
she was got all of that,
but I don't want to,
I don't want to go back and redo the
election,
but just that,
just does it concern you that if,
let's say let's be conspiracy theories.
Let's say that the russians,
that the russians have so much more
influence over this president by the
way,
putting his America first is using
russian steel for that pipeline that's
going through the indians.
Uh,
if he's that tied to them and their.
And Russia is an enemy of ours.
They want us to fail and now they have
an administration that wants to tear
stuff down.
It.
Could that be a conspiracy theory on
that side?
Certainly could.
But here's the problem,
what you're saying,
they like the russians.
They want to do this,
they want to do that when we're buying
their steel.
They don't operate as an individual.
You know,
there are a bunch of people that are
trapped in this dictatorship,
but yeah.
Well the pooting,
but it's when you are buying things,
if you're buying things from Russia and
so are there individuals over there is
everything Russia and entity and that
entity wants us dead once it's doomed,
isn't it possible the people,
well,
isn't it possible that their government,
their government can evolve like and
they can eventually not have that guy in
place that there's some thumped,
something can take place and they could
also prosper from this age of
information and that 100 percent right?
People,
the people 100 percent.
Yeah.
I mean this guy is doing this thing.
I don't know what he's doing.
Art guy.
I don't want to say this conspiracy to
just to.
Just to take the fantasy of are these
guys right?
Because like you're saying,
the wiki leaks,
expose that to the dnc.
There's also a lot of dirty stuff we
don't even know right now.
It's going on for sure on both sides.
Let's just take this fantasy of,
okay,
so putin is really aggressively wanted
this administration and they wanted a
bannon who wants to tear stuff down.
This is an advantage for us.
If you can expose that.
I think that's a.
That's a big deal.
Yeah.
It's scary,
but here's the problem.
You're making a bunch of stuff up in
order because it is a fantasy.
Yeah,
but that's.
I,
I get what you're saying,
but I mean,
I'm not saying you shouldn't be able to
do it.
Of course you could and it's something
that should be considered,
but it's a weird thing when you start
making up motives and potential outcomes
and look,
it's not good now.
That's why they're investigating because
they try and find the answers of what
this stuff really is.
Well,
there's all sorts of shit that's not
good.
There's all sorts of shit that's not
good about this.
This whole situation.
Yeah.
There's like there's way too much power
and influence by one person and that
person's that person's cabinet in that
person's choices.
What choices they make on the rest of us
and we're,
we're seeing that now.
Wayne gets way too much,
way too much,
and it's more than we've ever seen
before.
We've never seen someone come in with a
sweeping brush of change and just
decide,
nope.
Fuck obamacare.
No building that fucking wall.
No,
we're running those pipes.
Nope.
Dakota pipeline.
Fuck.
You were coming through like,
whoa.
It's,
and it's happening within the
60 days.
Doesn't it seem a lot of.
It's mean,
mean let's take dakota pipeline on both
sides.
Dakota pipeline seems mean.
Seems dumping waste into the water.
Seems me.
What does that waste and water where
they're dumping coal waste?
Whereas I made it illegal in West
Virginia and so that you couldn't,
um,
now drop it again.
Now you can dump it again.
Like there's like,
I want to talk about shutting down.
I'm scary.
Pbs.
Well those guys are monotone.
This is all means shit to the people
making cooking shows.
So those people were attacking him,
right?
Is that what it is?
No,
it's always a republican thing.
I think it's just to get people mad,
but you know what?
I mean like just can't you act out a
kindness if you enjoyed any part of this
program and you'd like to donate,
please do.
We survive on donations.
We appreciate you.
I always think that those guys just
can't wait to,
as soon as that fucking shows to run
home and put a ball gag on punch
themselves in the dick and just there
are so tied down.
That's so not how a man thinks or talks.
It's so funny for tuning into.
Its very interesting fresh air with
terry.
Gross is up next.
Very interesting.
We're going to talk about who are you.
Fuck.
What would you do if a terrorist attack
is happening right now?
What would you do if a man came in with
his dick in his hand,
I'm going to fuck your mouth.
Well,
I mean there's probably a reason he
wants to do that.
Wow.
We have to understand that I'm not
consenting it sending to you doing this
to me.
This is probably a very good reason.
It was his father probably did it to him
and I just
don't.
You know what I mean?
I just.
It feels like,
like can we come from a place of,
of,
of kindness rather than,
well,
he's
prosperity right now.
He's,
he's ramping up the prosperity.
That's what he wants to do.
I think he feels like he can get people
to love him again and yet the country on
track,
if he creates all these jobs.
That's why I had this big video
announcement,
your story where he was talking about
exxon investing in the gulf coast and
they're going to get all these jobs and
there's going to be like 45,000
jobs and the jobs are going to be paying
$100,000
on the average,
so all these great jobs and he's very
excited about announcing that.
Most likely it's all tied to oil.
It's all tied to oil.
That's where the money is in resources,
right?
In that model,
in that old model,
you don't.
It doesn't have to be that model,
but he wants to get America putting tons
of people to work.
Thousands.
There are thousands of people.
They're fucking driving cars.
They're killing people.
I love people like brought up two people
have died too.
We're acting like hawks by the way,
who were like,
I'm looking at videos on his ipad.
Dude.
Autonomous cars are coming.
Whether you like it or not.
It's the best.
Do you do it with yours?
Yeah,
he turned your chest.
Just start beating off?
Yes.
I'm hard right now that you just said
tesla.
Do you do it everywhere?
It just on the highway or how do you.
The on the freeway?
Yeah.
You put your hands on the wheel at all?
Sometimes.
A little bit.
Yeah.
I'll keep them loose on it,
but sometimes if it's traffic I don't
touch it at all.
And um,
just uh,
she just turning emails.
You're returning emails while you're
driving?
I'm not driving the cars driving.
That's so nuts man.
Yeah.
If you're in traffic,
just going to do.
And so the car takes over.
He takes us exit that it's supposed to
take.
You got to do that.
You take over when you leave it.
Oh,
it's the next version that comes out.
The end of this year is going to be
doing when you leave it the freeway.
Oh,
so it only works on the freeway?
No,
it works on the side streets,
but it doesn't read stop signs or
traffic lights.
What kind of piece of shit is this guy
hasn't got the uptake.
It needs the gps and all this other
stuff to,
uh,
to work,
to do surface streets.
It was when it's on the freeway,
the car is reading the cars in front of
it,
around it,
but doesn't have gps and the,
and the um,
the signs,
the signs for a how fast you crossing
deer crossing deaf child,
a family.
That's the most depressing fucking thing
ever.
When you driving from san diego,
you were an immigrant crossing.
This is a mother holding a child's hand.
The father's holding her mother's hand.
Like,
oh man,
I was just,
those fucking people come over here.
This is the worst.
I was just in Mexico doing a gig and um,
they,
uh,
I kept asking people about,
about uh,
trump.
They would ask us about trump or you
know,
the whole mexican bank.
And a couple of them,
especially the last guy was like,
yeah,
I know everybody I know.
And I don't know.
He seems bad,
but have you met our president of their
presence?
Terrible.
It's the most corrupt guy.
He doesn't help any of us.
He's awful.
It was like.
Oh right.
Yeah.
He's way worse leaders.
Just shithead too.
Yeah.
All these leaders.
All of them.
Yeah,
and these are like the leaders that are
probably the best.
Yeah,
because you go.
How about that guy in the Philippines?
It's just shooting people.
Yeah.
If you're out there doing drugs,
I'm shooting you shoot and drug dealers
killing everybody.
You got to do what you gotta do.
So that's how I roll.
So I clean the streets up.
Bullets tired,
bad.
Want to have a sandwich,
you know?
So I hit that tesla and it just like,
especially when I drive to school in the
morning and drop the kids off.
Don't you think now?
I mean I'm,
I'm always trying to be.
This glass is half full guy.
Don't you think that the reaction that
people were having to all these new
policies is going to invigorate our
political system because it's going to
inspire people to act and to do
something and to make some positive
change.
And the people are going to realize how
important it is to get involved and what
the consequences are to the environment,
to the world,
to the future.
If we let someone come in and just
solely concentrate on profits,
which is where what you're assuming that
they're going to do and they're going to
lean towards that and they're going to
lower the environmental protection
agency's regulations and lower the
standards for emissions and more
pollution in the fucking coal mine shit
and all that.
Because it's running it like a business.
People are going to have to react to
that.
Yeah,
and then there was a swing the other
way.
There's actually an editorial of the guy
who was the head of the epa during
reagan and he was warning pruitt that
americans have a breaking point.
They do not like it when they think that
they're.
That the environment and their health is
in danger because that's our families.
That's our children.
That's our lives.
And reagan came in and he was going to
do some big sweeping things that we're
going to be more profitable and give us
more jobs.
And the,
the fierce fight back from the americans
had to make them change course.
So yeah,
I think you're right.
I think especially with that issue,
I think it's entirely possible that you
could deal with eco terrorism as well.
Whereas someone could decide that this
path is wrong and evil and that the best
way to subvert it would be to do
something below something up or
something,
you know,
have some sort of reaction where you
damaged the company or damage the public
image or mean all this is really tricky.
Five dimensional chess that these people
are playing.
Yeah.
You know,
especially when you're dealing with
foreign entities now,
north korea's is tested nuclear or
ballistic missiles rather.
Yeah.
And Russia is mean the whole thing.
Barely.
That's what obama told Donald Trump when
he was coming in that his greatest
concern is North Korea.
Of course,
that guy is a fucking psychopath.
Yeah.
He just.
His half brother
was.
He had someone spraying for airport.
Yeah.
Like the people that were doing it.
Thought it was a prank.
Yeah.
They were dressed like a,
like they were doing a prank,
didn't they?
Think they were doing a prank.
They didn't realize.
I believe that the heat,
they didn't even realize that they were
doing it all really?
I don't know.
Maybe I made that up.
No,
I think you're right.
it's a crazy world joe rogan,
but I think you got to have hope and
there's lots of good people out there
doing good things and you can go see tom
papa live at a standup comedy club near
you clubs in colleges.
Occasionally theaters everywhere.
My podcast come to papa or watches new
special,
which is now going to be out onto hulu.
It's coming on hulu when tomorrow.
Oh shit.
What's it called?
An amazon.
It's called human mule.
Oh wow.
Like a drug meal?
No.
What's it about a father?
Oh,
well tom,
dad,
we got to do this more often.
Why don't we say this,
but I'm glad we did it quick compared to
the last one.
Yeah,
this is fun,
man.
I always fun talking to you.
I always love coming in and I would love
your fans.
Can I say your fans are great.
They're nice people.
They're such nice people.
They really are great people.
You know,
I've done some very popular radio shows
where people are awful,
you know,
funny but awful,
right?
Your people are like,
I get more responses of people asking
about how to make bread is sending me
the recipes and stuff and just really
funny it was.
See this like perform together,
whatever.
They're just a uva
crowd.
Well,
if you really enjoy you to and the kind
of perspective that you provided today
where you're leaning towards just being
nicer and being kinder and not getting
involved in any bullshit and,
and recognizing that that's what makes
people happy.
It's just to find,
find a passion,
follow it,
enjoy yourself,
live your life,
be nice.
Is it?
This is it.
We are in prime time.
If you are listening to this show,
if you're doing this show,
it's not.
This is it.
This is where this is the good part.
This is.
You're not getting more hair or
stronger.
It doesn't get better.
We're peaking,
everybody aching,
feeling it,
feeling the best time pop might be too
much.
All right folks.
We'll see you soon.
Bye
and
mm.