Do Do, do, do, do, do
five, four, three, two,
one, boom and bird live.
Mark Della [inaudible] Hey,
what up?
Most of the time if you and I are talking
on a microphone and it's when you're
in the truck and I'm
talking to you and you know,
and like right before a big fight,
people don't realize like you're,
you're the guy I talked to. Yeah. Man.
A lot of shit. Talking to a lot of shit.
A lot of things that we
probably shouldn't say.
Luckily it doesn't make the broadcast.
When that one got leaked,
when Aldo was about to fight Conor
and I said, he does not look good.
I said he looks nervous as fuck cargo.
His body looks flat. Often flat. Yeah.
And then you got flatlined.
Yeah, we'll, yeah, you right.
I was right in that regard.
That did make program,
didn't it? Well, people,
what happened was somebody recorded it
because a, I was talking to you I think,
and I was talking to
Bruce and um, it just, uh,
somebody just decided to be a
little twat. Dude, that shit,
I know it in that truck.
Sometimes you have to be now wrong
fucking button and I'm going to be talking
shit to you or matter. And I said,
well, that was one where, um, was uh,
it was interesting. I was like, oh,
okay, well somebody's fucking asshole.
Like you're,
you're privy to this sort of inside
banter to like to release that like,
and make it public.
I would never say that publicly.
So I was very upset that they did that.
But it was honest now here, right.
It was honest. He did look like shit,
but damn, he looked good last weekend.
He looked on unbelievable crazy man. I
let to ask before. I love Jeremy Stevens.
Great Guy. I mean, you know, we called
everybody worked for the company.
You've got to get to know everybody.
You gotta be cool to everybody.
But it was good to see you Jose Aldo back
on top, man. He needed that bad dude.
Well,
when someone ever,
I'm always happy when someone
live wins with a liver shot. Oh.
Because it's such a,
it's one of those weird punches.
Like you'll see someone will see two
guys and they exchange good shots to the
body and they seem like they
have no effect. You know,
obviously they hurt but they'll
deal with it and keep fighting.
And then every now and then you see whap
and then he see that liver shot where
the legs go out and the body gives in.
It's like man that is crazy that we
have this one area that sometimes works.
Yep. Cause sometimes it doesn't work
right. That's right. Liver shots,
weird man. And it's delayed.
That's the funniest part about it.
There's like a split second delay way.
Like I got this fold
over if you saw that too,
like there was a body
shot that that he threw,
he threw like a rear right hand to
the body and then the left level shot.
So I think it's Kinda like,
you know,
you take the first punch and then you
brace and you got it and then you relax
for a second and that's when bullying,
gang,
diaphragm and you'll live as that's
vibrating. I wish it made sense.
Like here it is right here. We
can see it again. Weird video.
She throws the right
hand to the body first.
Okay.
What was he got there? It is and there
it is. Oh, gobble body shot. Yeah.
In Jeremy's a bang,
a two man,
that's a tough dude man.
To get dropped from a body shop and
to make that face to hurt so bad.
Well Kevin Ross is the only guy that
I've ever seen hide it. Kevin Ross got,
he was fighting in
Beltour not as last fight,
but maybe the previous fight.
And uh,
he got hit in the first round with a
spinning back kick right in the liver and
he just felt like, yes, yes.
He just kept moving and he said he
was an ultimate agony. Absolutely.
But he didn't show shit
and his opponent did. No,
I mean he really pulled it off.
He really pulled it off.
He figured out how to just,
he's so mentally strong though.
That guy crazy.
He just figured out how to suck
it up and just deal with the pain.
Tough to do and kickboxing and boxing too
because it's not like you can jump God
or stall a cry. Yeah. You can't
hide that. You know, you get,
you get hit like that and
you've got to keep fighting.
It's especially kickboxing as opposed
to Moitai. You can't even really clench.
Right, exactly. Especially
with these New Orleans.
What do you like that do you like? Oh, I
don't like it. It's not the art, you know,
I think everything that's going
on, you know, with, you know,
these new rules came even when k one
first came out and all that kind of like
what I consider like a, a takeoff
of Muay Thai. It's not my type,
but they call it moy. Tai. Yeah. I
mean it's not more tight, you know,
it's not the real art. K One was like the
Japanese said, not enough brain damage,
not enough.
You need more brain damage.
And I think they just
suck that the clench,
which cut the ties are so good at it and
they wanted to give themselves a chance
to actually compete with like some of
the best in the world. So they said,
all right, let's limit
their weapons. Let's,
isn't that interesting because wouldn't
you think that they would just learn the
clinch? Man, I wish they would. You know,
that's one of the most intricate
parts of Moitai. It's one of,
that's where all the gambling goes.
That's where all the points come from.
Can Punch the shit out of somebody
and you get nowhere and then you start
clenching and then east.com and in
the little turnovers and trips ties.
Love that shit man. That's
that. That's the real art.
There's so much grappling involved in
Thai box and that's overlooked, you know,
into, into, to have rules that take
away grappling. Takeaway clinch work.
It makes no sense to me.
It's half the art at that point.
It's also a really underappreciated
thing in terms of like how they score it.
Like we don't,
we don't score the same way.
Like if you're watching a Thai
fight and if you were an American,
you can go cause a bunch of hugging.
Yeah, you got off a couple of needs,
but the other guy hit him with some
good right hands and a good jab.
So it's funny you say that. I just had
this lesson, my students the other night,
you know, doing uh, let's talk about the
rules, how to, how to win the judges,
so to say.
You know,
and the Dutch rules are different than
the Thai rules in America is kind of
fucked up and lost in between
all of it. You know, like the,
the Dutch consider like a hand block,
like a,
if you block with your hands like this,
it's a block in Holland.
The ties that's not a block. That's a
point. Like you get the point, you know,
really? Yeah man. It's different.
You have to block with your legs and
tie box in order to show that you've
blocked in,
nullified the attack and the points
like the punches ScoreBig and Holland,
low kick score big and they mean shit
to the ties. You could punch the shit
out of somebody for full round and
then just get to clean body kicks off.
And then all the ties like, oh, hey,
you got that again, once starts going.
So a lot of these foreigners go to
Thailand and they think they're doing well
and then they lose decisions
and they wonder why.
It's because they don't
understand the judgment.
You don't understand the
rules and vice versa.
And the ties go to Holland
and you know, they, they,
they think they're doing well and the
guy's punching the shit out of them and
then they kind of block in partially
and then they lose decisions as well.
So it's very different between the
judging and the scoring between Dutch
kickboxing in, in real
Moitai very different. Yeah.
I remember when Ramon Decker was fighting
over in Thailand and one of the things
that he shocked a lot of those guys
was with his, uh, his hand techniques.
Yup.
And he was able to close the distance
and just unleash a barrage of explosive
knockout punches and take guys out where
I think they'd become more accustomed
to that not happening.
Very true.
It also become accustomed to not
being assaulted in the first round.
Very much so. I remember one of the fights
I had early in my career in Thailand,
I was so excited to be fighting at a big
fan of big festival fighting this big
name ty. And I threw an elbow
on the first round, you know,
and I kind of had the opportunity to
throw the elbow through the elbow and you
know, I landed and the
guy wiped his, you know,
put his glove up to his head
to see if he was bleeding.
And he gave me that mean look and
nodded and it was game on from there.
And I went back to the corner and my
tie trainers are yelling at me like the
fuck are you doing? You throw, I
was like, elbows illegal. Yeah,
but not first round now he angry at you.
I was like,
what the fuck did he angry you?
Tigerfish halftime having a bad dude.
It was apparently I was just excited
to be fighting in Thailand using elbows
cause a lot of times in the states,
you know,
we can't use them and
the rules are limited.
And I was in Thailand and
it was a festival at night.
And the fucking lights are on and the
ties of baton and I was like, game on,
let's go. The train isn't mad
at me for throwing the elbow.
And then there was other fights
where I had where they were like, Oh,
be careful for elbow this festival fight.
No doctor here hospital far away.
It's like you guys have fucking my
head. All of them. The other doctor,
he far away, I remember my train of saying
that, he's like, be careful for elbow.
I was like, thanks fucking tips. Like I
know watch over her elbows. He's like,
yeah but no doctor. Yeah, not
stadium. This fest. Devo hospital,
long p band.
Oh Wally [inaudible] you get such
a good [inaudible] is on point bro.
Don't even go there. The only
thing can go there. So we make,
we do a lady boy heavy Boston accent dude,
Debbie.
Debbie is stitched her and speak tied,
stitched it some rnr and uh,
in the service like in a, in
Thailand and man like, you know,
you see like so what the hell? That's
like the property. He's like, man,
it's still what the cup he likes. Speaks
like a tie. That's hilarious dude.
It's the funniest thing.
Then how do you say thank you again?
Cup Cop Capcom Cup code. Yeah. If
you roll the R's, it's like real,
like almost like a risk
of craddle like you just,
you stick out like a sore thumb. If
you're a white dude, women don't say that.
They say cup, coon, CRA car.
Her car, like the feminine,
Polite Particle X.
I will say so cop like crop and it
looks like Krup but it's actually a cup.
That's the, the male play protocol
and then in everybody, ah,
[inaudible] stretch everything
out. Everything is like, oh,
I go with you.
It's just like,
I don't know,
it's the Twang I guess is that tie to
Ang did the nicest people on earth this
week as sweeter. So nice man. Not
all of them. It's the land of smiles,
but you'll find some fucking
frowns here and there.
I'll tell you how much to the course
who, especially in the fight game. Yeah,
there's no getting around the fight game.
You're going to have some mean
motherfuckers. Very true. But the, the,
the fighters are cool though,
man. I remember my first,
one of my first fights in Thailand,
well at least my Roger dominant and
fight in 2003 I had breakfast with my
opponent and it was like real
super. Yeah, super chill.
Like we weighed in but naked next to
each other, which was awkward as fuck.
But like we really have to be
naked and the ties like, yeah,
you got to get down bro. And I was like,
I don't want to get naked. I'm on wait,
don't worry, I'll eat. They're
like, no underwear off.
That's how we do it at Roger Down
in San Diego. And I was like, shit,
but naked way to my opponent.
Went next door and had breakfast with
him shooting the shit. But it is,
it is a cool place, man. I remember
the first time I went to Thailand,
I came home and I was homesick and I
was fucked up. Dude. It felt weird.
I was like, I felt like lonely and loss
and I had family here. Like, you know,
I was, I was with my, currently my
wife now, I was with her at the time.
We weren't married at the time, but you
know, I was, I had family, I had friends,
I was very much connected, you know, old
school, Sicilian family, Boston base,
you know, deep roots and I
just felt awkward and weird.
I was like away from home and I
was like homesick. You Ms. Tyler.
I missed Thailand my very first trip.
I remember leaving the airport and I
was driving and I had nothing but smiles
for like a month and a half straight and
I was leaving Logan Airport in Boston
and some truck Jabba cut me off and
stuck his head out to where it's like,
fuck you man.
Gave me the fear to chill,
like wanting to go out and
fight. And I was like, Bro,
I'll snap your neck but I don't want
to fight nobody. Like I'm Buddha now.
Like I like, I like this vibe and we go
back to Thailand. Like it was weird man.
It was definitely trippy though. But
something brought me something very deep.
Lake and spiritual brought me to Thailand.
Brought me to the guys though.
The opposite way I feel about Boston.
When I go back to Boston, I see hostility.
I got my smile on my God,
I remember this right,
and people copy blow off.
You fucking quit. Oh yeah.
So this is where I grew up.
It has always been,
there's something unique about Boston
people that man, I told you, man,
I've told this to people.
Like,
you know when you got to get up at
fucking six in the morning to shovel 17
inches of snow off your fucking frozen
windshield and go to work and sit in
traffic and beep and be angry at each
other, like just makes a different person,
you know, definitely makes a
different sense of humor for sure.
There's a certain connection that I
have to those northeast comedians. Yeah,
guys like Bill Burr.
Like we bill an,
I did a show Wednesday night and it's like
whatever. We're out a guy from Boston,
it's like, it's so obvious. It's
like there's a certain end is
also a certain respect for
people's attention span very much.
This is one of the good things about
starting out in Boston was like,
people didn't give a fuck.
Like they don't have any time
for your dilly dallying up there.
You better come with the jokes.
[inaudible] first trip to la on
now was the La San Francisco,
I think at the time when I was younger,
when it's like some random sandwich shop,
I think I'm hungry. I was like, give
me one of those giants right there.
And the guy like was taking
his time and I was like, Bro,
I'm gonna fucking Russian Lake. And my
buddy was like, dude, watch the f bombs.
I was like, what do you mean?
He's like, just watch you have on.
So the guy comes out with a sandwich
and was his little fucking peanut half
sandwich. I go, what the fuck am I
gonna do with that? And he's like,
I'm sorry like to, and I was like,
where's the other half? And he's like,
that's it sir. And I was like, Bro, I
need another fucking sandwich. He's like,
I'm going to have to charge you
for it. And I was like, charge me,
do whatever you gotta do,
Bro. I'm fucking hungry.
Like literally everybody behind me in
line just out of disperse and it'll like
left the store. And my buddy
was like, Bro, I can't take
you anywhere around. Yeah,
it was how many years back then?
Probably maybe 2020 years old,
maybe Tennessee.
That's a different mark.
Della grotty and a different
San Francisco. Very true.
San Francisco was like
super calm lefty back then.
Now San Francisco's different.
San Francisco is homeless people
projectile shitting into the streets.
So yeah,
I didn't actually expensive real
estate and Tech Tech Dorks who uh,
speak and they have a specific language
in San Francisco. Ray Little, yeah,
it's called up speak.
Is that a fact? Yeah.
This is how I describe it as a language,
but tech people in San Francisco and if
you're a tech person in San Francisco
and you do this, stop it. As they do this,
they talk like here's the deal.
Like what we're trying to do with
our start up at the end of all,
you know the car at the car at the time,
San Francisco, San Francisco's
version of that and it's up speeding.
Everything at the end goes.
Uh,
so what we're trying to,
and what it is is like they're faking it.
They're trying to like when you want to
pretend to be intelligent or tech savvy
or in,
and it's a very left wing thing to it.
So it's only people who are super
liberal and super progressive.
Like you can't say it. You couldn't
talk like that and go Donald Trump,
although he's problematic, has some
really good points in regards to business.
Like you couldn't say that Bro,
please stop.
He was a lot of good enough,
a lot of good combat sports come out
of San Francisco. Absolutely man.
I think about like the,
the history of like you got the Gracie
Gracie Baha contingent up there.
You know how if Gracie is got one of the,
like northern California,
the bay area areas,
Dave terrail,
the Diaz brothers, obviously Cesar Gracie.
Yup. And then you had an Alex Gong.
He used to be up there
just going to say the fair
tech's crew, that old school fair tech
school. Alex Gong Johnson unfair techs.
Did they ever catch the guy who killed
him? Yeah, I think he killed himself.
Actually, no, Alex Gong
got killed in a, someone,
someone did something and he went out
like someone would fuck with his car or
something like that and somebody
outside and someone murdered him.
The way I heard it was he was training
to the gym and somebody sideswiped or hit
his car or something like that.
He ran down the street after him
in a pair of fucking boxing gloves,
which probably wasn't,
you know,
I mean obviously you see some fucking
savage running appeal window boxing gloves
on. So the guy shot him. Yeah.
But I think the guy had some mental
history and he was like, you know,
he was unstable or something like that.
From what I understood,
I thought the guy actually committed
suicide is suspect. Yup. You're right.
Suspect that killed.
So shooting killed himself.
That was fucked up man. What uh, what,
uh, uh, a waste though, huh? Yeah.
Got crashed into a parked
car. So he chafed after it
is. Yeah. I didn't know that.
It was making shit up for a minute
though. Not Man. That's sad man.
He was a great fighter man.
I remember watching like number,
like I ask like kickbox and back in the
day when like the fair tech's crew from
Chandler, Arizona, who's the big icon,
Yow Johnson fair tax and a
fair tax was you got the guy,
I was the smaller guy too. I forget
his name, I'm drawing a blank.
But that whole fair tech's crew man
back in the day, man, they just,
they came from Thailand and just fucking
threw up like this aluminum building
and Chandler,
Arizona in the desert and just started
fucking flying people in to fucking learn
when we tie and they were kicking ass.
Dude,
they kicked everybody's ass back in the
day that Iska kickbox and scene. Well,
when you started fighting,
there were very few people that were
like formerly trained in Muay Thai in our
area,
in the Boston area.
Like we knew a rich vast
Poli. Oh Man. What a name.
He died in the triathlon
to kicked in the head,
but he was swimming and during that crazy,
he's crazy man of all the
shit you did and your life.
You've fucking got kicked by a swimmer and
drown. Yeah. And he was like, you know,
all it was done fighting. It was
in his 40 [inaudible]. Exactly.
He was chilling at the time.
So I need to say that, man,
because back in the day I thought
about this coming out here, you know,
I remember the, the first pair of Moy
Thai shorts, I saw her like, dude,
that's funky. Those, those we had
led us on the front leg and it was a,
I don't you remember a
guy named Ed Babylock,
I think his name was Kim Mkhize and
Australia. He was a sig aton guy too. He,
but yeah, man. He was like, you
know, I remember back in the day,
he was one of the first guys in the area
to have a pair of Moy Thai shorts and
he was training with Deena Rosenblatt,
Joel and, but that whole crew,
it's funny because we have similar
backgrounds in martial arts in terms of
Boston. It was the only legit
into each other back then.
But I think you were a little
bit ahead of me at the time.
I think that was the general Shapley
on my way out to when I was starting to
train with Joe Lake.
Um,
I started training with Joe Lake
when I was teaching and revere.
I was teaching it, not yes, the
code is, and we on that joint. Yeah.
So I was teaching this teaching
taekwondo there.
Um,
I w Joe Lake was lifting weights
over there and Joe Lake, uh,
came in, he started, we had
heavy bags and the whole set up.
And then he started talking to me
and asking me questions. And, uh,
we made a deal where he would teach me
how to box and I would teach him how to
kick. And so he came
over and we started, uh,
doing some, um, you know, submit
work and doing some things.
Then I started working with him and
Dana Rosenblatt and Dana was only,
he was in high school at the time I
went to Malden Catholic with, yeah,
I think I was 20 and I
think Dana was 18, 17, 18,
something like that. Began his career
as a kickboxer. That's right. Again,
it's crazy.
Kickboxer and there was no money in it
and he was doing well with his hands.
So I told him to stop kickboxing and
he convinced me to stop fighting,
sparring each other and he went on to sell
real estate. Now he's like successful,
really successful boxing career too.
He stopped Teri Norris.
That's right. He, um, who's the guy
who used to be the boxing coach?
Howard Davis Jr. He stopped
him. I remember him. He used
a boxing coach at att. Yup.
I know John took her. He beat some
good guys. He beats him real good.
Five's a southpaw too, wasn't
it? Yeah, he's a tough kid.
But he also came up,
you know,
one of the things that I've said about,
uh,
one of the things that I learned from
my kickboxing training was how dangerous
it is to meet heads bar. And all
we did was meatheads. That's,
I mean it started off with like, you know,
me and my brother would like, you know,
hockey helmets in hockey
gloves and try that out.
And then little by little it
was like, I right. You know,
get into a gym and stopped boxing.
Man.
I remember the first time I went to a
boxing gym and like the Boston area, man,
it was on back then you went to a boxing
gym and I remember literally like my
coach said, sent me up the spine, it
like a boxing club. He's like, all right,
you realize like you're the new guy.
I was like, yeah. He says that man,
they all know each other.
They don't know you like yeah,
you've got a big target on your back.
And I remember like the night before,
like I would go spa like felt like a fight
and I was like, yeah, I'm in a fight.
And I'd get to the gym and it was
on dude back then it was like,
it was extremely unintelligent, you know.
But that's, we were cavemen at the time.
That's all we knew. I remember, you know,
there were holes in the walls
that like rich, vast, the police,
different people get knocked back in
the sheet rock was kicked out the sheet
rock. You're crazy man. We didn't know
any better though at the time I started,
I knew a rich vast Poli from Dana.
I became friends with Dana and we started
training together and then we would
sometimes train over at richest place.
And that was when I got introduced into
Moy Tai Cause one of Dana's friends had
uh, gone to Thailand and he had done
some training over there and come back.
And that's when I realized
like how effective leg kicks,
where like I'd never been leg
kicked before except by accident.
And then once I realized like
shins to thigh, like what,
how much damage that does and how
easy it was to, that happened to me.
One was how easy it was for
me to get punched in the face.
And that was when I first met from a
traditional martial arts background.
Taekwondo.
Taekwondo was so delusional because
you often taekwondo as well too.
You couldn't punch to the face,
so you had a very distorted perception
of what you could get away with in a
fight where there was no rules.
You just had this real and so one
of the same reality check. Yeah.
So boxing alone was not good.
Kickboxing was better because
I could create some distance,
but it was still way easier than I
liked to get punched in the face.
But then Moitai was a big one because
the moment you take that first leg kick
and you feel that thud and you're like,
oh shit,
this is that easy.
It's that easy to diminish me.
Like almost instantaneously
you're diminished.
I feel it. As you're talking about
it. I took a low kick from Peter Arts.
No, and oddly enough, a, another
trip was, uh, was it, um,
he drove his, oh no, he
might be the worst. And you,
I thought my femur
fucking cracked in half.
Never felt pain like that from
a pay Peter or, or from Pedro?
Both at different times.
Pedroza the scariest guy I've ever seen.
Kick kicker back. I've never seen anybody
kicked her bag so hard. I agree man.
I trained with him a little bit
in Thailand back in the day.
We used to train at a gym called ISS,
which was like a,
a takeoff of like sick aton like a,
we sold some fighters and some trainers
to a friend of Korea tongs. And uh,
we would train on the roof
of this building on Lake
Sukham vit highway in like
the sun. What like a canopy like above us.
It was pretty, pretty, uh, pretty rough.
But Peter Arts was their training
at the time. And Pedro, his, Oh,
came through there and I mean I was a lot
smaller than them obviously, but Jude,
why did this, why'd you spar with
them anyway? Because I'm retarded.
Stupid. Cause there's the
opportunity man. They were like,
oh we need guys and I was
actually helping someone else,
another one of my stablemates get ready
and he just happened to be there and
he's like, Oh man, let's move
around a little bit. And I was like,
this is probably not a good idea, but
it's an honor. You know what I mean?
So I'm partially proud of getting
kicked in the leg by those guys. But I,
I probably shit have done that dude.
What's worse though nowadays it,
you seize that calf kicks more damage
from those man. I'm telling you,
I'll still meet down there road.
I'll take the kicks all day long on the
thigh now man, those 10 debt tender area,
like I remember losing
a fight in Thailand.
I didn't really have an
extensive career as a fight,
but I did have some quality
fights and that will vary.
That were valuable lessons to me. And I
remember I was blocking wrong, you know,
the whole fee.
Every time he low kicked I would block
and I would take it right with a calf kit
goes like on the low part of the Shin.
And I was pointing my toes down.
It's always controversy of toes down,
toes up.
I always teach toes up to flex the Shin
Muscle to flex the muscle around the
shin bone. And, um, I was blocking
wrong and I'll never forget that man.
I was bed ridden from
blocking kicks the wrong way.
And it was that same area with
this, like you said, there's no,
how long were you bedridden for?
Two weeks probably.
I remember like trying to go to lake,
it was in Thailand.
I came back from Thailand.
Dude was a rough flight
like oh awesome, great. Lots of
pain medication for that flight.
But uh, I remember literally like after
some of the fights like that I've had,
you know,
I was literally bedridden like couldn't
go to like family barbecues and shit.
Like just like, dude, I can't get up.
I get a lot of those kicks in the UFC
that we've seen emerge over the last few
years and I always give
credit to Benson Henderson.
So being the first guy to start doing it.
It's funny you say that because I threw
a lay up to Anik like the last show and
I was like, oh, but maybe we
might get and it's like, yeah,
I'm not mentioning that name.
Like Benson Henderson for photos
over and bell. Correct. I mean,
it is what it is, you know?
That's crazy. That's so crazy.
You gotta give it up. I said it. I
said, man, you know, just a quick tip,
like a little fun fact.
You know,
Benson Henderson is the guy that
really kicked that off, you know,
for lack of a better term. And he's
like, yeah, copy that. I was like,
I'm not gonna mention that name. I was
like, all right, cool. Respect. I get it.
I get it. You gotta do what you gotta
do in this world. He was exactly,
we got to eat. You know,
he was the first though,
but he doesn't have the same effectiveness
for whatever reason that these guys
do now. Um, there's,
there's guys now that are doing it where
you see like one kick in the guys. Fuck.
Yup. Absolutely. And it's such a
lower risk for the take down too,
because you just, you're not traveling
that far. You know, the high you kicked,
the more risk for the down
just seems awful. You know,
like the legs just to
immediately stop working. Right.
I've had a few of my athletes suffer
some serious trauma from those kicks and
fights. Man. It's not, you can't really
prep for those. You really can't. Like,
it's just all about managing distance,
you know, control on the range. Cause you,
you can't really check it. It's too low to
check, just condition it. No, not at all.
There's nothing to really do with
it other than just, like I said,
you've got to manage distance properly.
So you just, either way in a way out.
But in that middle weight, like you
get kicked like that man out. Gee.
What are your thoughts on this?
Robert Whitaker kick,
I mean a call it the Robert Whitaker
kicked because Yoel Romero fucked him up
with it and their first fight,
that side kick to the knee.
Oh you refer to it as John John. John's
really one of the first school. John.
It's actually illegal in some
commissions, right? Is it legal or not?
I think it's illegal.
It's illegal in some,
some commissions don't allow it because
of the danger of like attacking the
joint. I have a hard time
accepting that cause it's okay to,
to attack your fucking face.
Why is it okay for me to kick you in
the face but it's not okay to for me to
kick. Exactly. That doesn't make any
sense. Well they say that, you know,
and even in Thai boxing ticket, not so
supposed to deliberately attack the joint.
Yeah. John, there you go John.
It's actually w and g quinto
on the philosophy of Brucey.
They believe they call it like it's a
Kung Fu kick. It's called the dumb tech,
I believe. Well the way a Winkle John
started teaching it and you know, we,
his students started doing it
was the oblique style. Yes.
But then they started doing
that sidekick style too.
Like that'll bleak style is very
interesting. Yeah. Was my face.
And I think that,
um,
in my opinion it's, it's, it's a super,
super effective technique
and didn't take it out.
It doesn't make any sense to me if
you still allow heel hooks. Yeah.
And he's still allow,
I mean,
especially since he allowed kicks
to the fucking head. Yeah, true.
And I'm a fan of the kick. You
know, I'm, I'm not against it.
I appreciate it that the,
one of the things I tell
fighters all the time is the,
if y'all going to do anything,
if you're going to kick me,
if you're going to punch me, if you're
going to try to take me down anything,
the first thing you need to do is take
that step. What that lead leg. So if you,
and this is something Bruce Lee you
talked about in his art and philosophy,
but there's always disruption
disrupting that lead leg,
stopping that lead leg and the ties
use it all the time. A lot of times,
you know that teeth, the front
kick, they Tepe the leg a lot.
It's not always taught like a lot of,
a lot of people overlook it,
but I'm a huge fan of
attack in that front leg.
Like keeping the front leg
side kick in the front leg.
So the first thing they need to do to
close this and says take that step. Well,
anything also to create another variable
that the fighters to think about as
they're moving in stops. And I'm like,
the worst thing you could ever do with
a fighter is give them something that's
real clear and easy to plan for.
Yeah.
You do the same technique over and
over again. He can time it, you know,
the same predictable series of movements.
You can time it.
That's why I got like Dominick Cruz is
so difficult to deal with because Dominic
like good luck,
do shuffle in his left.
He variety from the hips and knees.
That's actually how my dad, oh,
he's so awkward that he has been,
but he makes it work for Frank Gay.
Then the key thing with him to have
that and that it's difficult to do that
oblique kick or that that
front stop kick is, uh,
is the lateral movement and if you're
going straight in all the time and you're
walking straight into that,
you're going to be susceptible.
Dominic's always stepping off to the side,
but there's a lefty or righty.
He's always creating an angle
which is huge in combat.
You know, who does that? Oh,
oblique kick fucking better than
anybody. Lorens Larkin. Yes.
Lorens lark and throws
that shit to another body.
Like a sidekick and since dude's flying,
I remember when he fought in Neil Magni.
Yes, I do. I was like, dude, he's
a stud. That guy, he's clean.
I watched him warm up.
I think he fought in the Boston show.
I think at the time I was training.
He throws that shit to the body, dude.
He's a stud man. I, you know, I don't,
I don't know why he wasn't as successful
as he could have been or should have
been.
Here's what happened.
He went over to belt or and he
immediately fought lean. Okay.
Lima's a fucking monster.
He loses a decision to Lima.
Then he gets into s lug fast with Paul
motherfucking daily who might have the
best left hook to world's ever
known name for MMA boxers,
base Plat.
That fucking left hook he's got,
it's just insane because I met
him back in the day. We used to,
I first time I went over to London,
we did a show called La cage rage
and I took Jorge her very, very,
with this fight, this fight,
there's an Silva Silva.
We played that the other day. He was
just teeing off on them from the clinch.
Anderson is just taking one on the
chin. Want to hear a funny story? Yeah,
I see Anderson and all I can see it's
like George has got his back to me.
Jorge's got us back to me.
So He's have palm lane in there in the
center of the cage and they kind of in a
tie, Clinton Georges throwing
vicious uppercuts, vicious apricots,
an overhand and upper cuts,
dirty box out thunder in his hands and
he's throwing like these big bombs over
the top. Everything in all I can
see because Georgia's backs to me,
I can't see Anderson's face. All I
can see is his head. Bobblin you know,
taking the hits. I'm
like, yeah, go, go, go.
And then over Georgia shoulder
I see Anderson's face and
he's laughing at George.
I'm like fuck. And then he
just blitzed stone. He do that.
Did he roll with them slightly? Like
what did he do, do it? I think it's,
it's all a matter of like, you know,
using your shoulders to protect impact,
you know, shrugging. And
so to say, the first,
first thing is bite the first
line of defense, bite down
second end of the fence,
brace your neck, you
know, and he just, yeah,
duty mean he's gonna fucking Pumpkin head.
He's got a big dome dude. Well, I mean,
but you stop and think
about later in his career,
he couldn't take those kinds of shots.
They add up after a while it
gets put back in the day. Man,
I remember coming into that,
you know,
I had followed Moitai had followed
shoot box. I'd follow, you know,
Palae those guys. So I knew Anderson
Silva, a lot of people like, oh,
it was this guy, Anderson Silva, he's
coming over. A lot of people didn't know.
So I knew what we were getting into.
I knew what type of fight it was.
But the funny thing is when he
came to the UFC member, he debuted,
I was there at the hard rock. The joint
is Chris leaving and everybody's like,
oh dude, the bets. Like, I
was like, I saw the odds,
I like the Mandela and I was like,
dude, I'm all over this. What was,
it was just some crazy, I forget
at the time, but like it was,
they had Lieben in like, like being
like the favor. I was like, dude,
nobody knows him. Like Johnson.
Yeah, I knew how to man.
I'm the Promo. One of the things I said
is you gotta be ready for this guide.
This is, this is a different animal. You
experienced the same with rich Franklin.
Man, I riches my boy love you rich. But
you know, I bet the fucking house on that.
And I did really well because the odds
were just everybody thought rich was just
going to steam roll and you don't want
him to simply because rich was a stand up
fighter. Right. Primarily. And he had a
ground game and he was on top at the time.
I mean he was,
he was way on top,
but Anderson was just on a whole different
level coming into the mixed martial
arts coming into the UFC.
He was just on a whole different level.
Especially the style of
the Chris Liebing hat. Yes.
Style was so perfectly tailored.
Exactly. Exactly. Walk forward.
Throw bombs. Anderson's like a
smooth retreating defensive fighter.
He's came from Thailand. Pretty
cool. Pretty Dope, right? Yeah.
The Chinese I believe.
But yeah, they're not tie.
I think they're more and more of a
check. They like damn, they got me,
they got me in the door of a Chinese
influence now. They had dope man.
Thailand was sick. Huh? Loved
it man. Yeah man, I love it.
Cage cage rage was an interesting
place because there was a,
that was a wild west of fights. I remember
when Lee Marie fought Anderson Silva.
Yup. I do. You know, got into a broad,
the Wayans lead Maria for apparently
like when I started going over there,
they're like, oh, leave my, I was
like, yeah. Everybody said gangs. I,
everybody's a fucking,
this motherfucker was
a real gangs that way
to deliver like ticket sales, like money
from ticket sales and like I'm black,
like leather black Duffel bag
just stacked with fucking pounds.
Just like who is this guy? And
the promoters, Dave and Andy,
I think at the time when I was like, no,
my ace allergic gangster and I was like,
whoa.
Do you remember when he got stabbed in
the heart in a knife fight and then was
training six weeks later?
I do. I do remember that.
I don't recall details but I do remember
something to that as London shoe fires.
Our Good Buddy Marius was a
training at 10th Planet Jiu Jitsu.
He came to La to learn Jujitsu and he
was one of the head guys over at London
chew fighter. So I got to
get in with those guys. Yep.
I'm familiar with the car before all
that shit was going on and he was telling
me about Lee Marie like way early,
like back in 2000 you know,
so it was, it was way early,
way back in the early days.
It's so funny too because somebody
brought it to my attention and I do it.
Did you see Lee Marie is
fucking palace in Morocco.
Like he took the money and ran, barely
made it. He made it poster Jorge.
It's a mural.
It's like a 30 by 30 48 hour girl
or something like on his wall and,
and he's putting the arm
bar on George Rivera. Yeah.
And on the back of Georgia shorts is
a big sea Tang dotcom. I'm like, fuck.
The only time I didn't want the plug. Well
he was caught him in a triangle. Right.
Triangle. Yeah. Triangle
around, you know, that came on.
That was unexpected, you know, but
you know, it was tough man. You know,
George was a, a very emotional
fighter. You know, he was,
he had a rough upbringing with his family.
You know, he's very connected to his,
to his family and you know, it was, it was
a rollercoaster working with that dude,
man. But he was my first man. You
never forget your first, right. Yeah.
He was a great dude, man. I don't
talent, that's for sure man.
If you go back and look like he fought
like the WHO's who's of like the UFC like
that, everybody he fought was
legit. He had, he had, he,
there was never a dull moment
of any fights that George had.
He had a good run for a while though.
It was the early days.
I remember we were in uh,
when we first started doing shows.
It's funny, there's another,
there's another picture too.
It's a weird mural too because it's
guy like go large on that again,
another one to portions are off.
So whoever did it was fine.
It horrible out a sign of a shit. Artists,
he might actually done that himself.
Might actually fucking had someone come
in and put some numbers up and fucking
paint by numbers.
The old UFC logo,
he's got the Mandalay Bay logo.
It's got him getting him in the triangle.
But if you'd like it,
the one when he's flexing like
that's not even the same dude.
Like look at all these extra meat to
his lats and is lower terms. I'm very,
I've seen another one too. He might
have a few in his fucking house of him.
Murals of himself looking so
ridiculous. What is the one mute? Why,
why one image of the two of them
clinching? Like look at that.
How bizarre.
Like,
why put that picture and it is some
wads a yoked up though. Rock and dude,
good job. Maybe fan of
clean. We put the clean chin.
I want the Mandalay bay or
scale. That's hilarious. You.
I make your arms bigger and then when
you get him in the triangle I'll
make you 10 that's like, he's good.
He's not going to say he's not even in
the same tent. He's a different guy.
That's hilarious. Yeah. Is
that, is that his place?
So he's still in the pokey
for people who don't know,
Lee Marie was a part of the,
one of the biggest armed robberies,
I think the biggest in the
history of the UK. Yeah,
huge money they made away with millions
and millions of dollars and some of it's
still millions of pounds I think.
And then do the trend.
Did you know the areas we would go out
with a fucking mask on like Hannibal
Lecter. I remember, I remember
that 1 million pounds.
It's 53 what's the conversion on
that, Jamie? That's ridiculous. Money.
That's crazy. Yeah. It's hard to tell.
Like at the time we would have to go back,
figure out what it was, but
a fuss. A lot of money. Yeah.
And I think a lot of it is still missing.
But yeah,
they had like Ninja masks on and they
were dressed like they were in that movie
heat. How did they, I thought there
was no extradition like from Morocco.
That's why he fled.
They ended up extraditing him though.
Not that who know what happened,
but yeah, I thought that too.
It wasn't that where Badr Hari
went to [inaudible]. I was like,
fuck this and we'll come catch me. Not,
they always want to wind up leaving. So
they, they, you know, bought heart. He's,
he did his time.
He went over,
he came back and he got Badr Hari got
arrested for stomping a man's Shinon half.
Oh yeah.
There was some sort of a dispute in a
nightclub and Badr Hari does not play.
This is a video of him walking into a
hotel and the hotel guy says something
stupid to him. So he goes behind a
counter and smacks him in the face.
I should that guy. It's my hotel.
He's a fucking giant too. It like six,
five world heavyweight kickboxing
champion and it up for Roche is terrifying
man. Who fucks up grown ass people.
Yeah. Here's the video. Yeah,
I dunno what the guy said, but bought
her heart was like, what? Excuse me?
What the fuck did you just say? It
just goes by. Welcome to the Marriott.
Uh, we're going to have to see a
credit card. It's like, no, look.
He gets right behind the camera. Fuck.
He smacks him in the back of the head
the way it did it.
It's like super dangerous.
Super scary looking to me like
stocks and walks him down downstairs.
He smacked him very dismissively.
It wasn't like worried
about counter. Exactly.
Like smack them with a little kid in the
back of the headlight tips is singer.
He was just like, hey, hey, what
the fuck are you talking to Asia?
We've got to pick and choose
your battles wisely, man.
I saw about a hiree walking towards me and
like, Oh sir, how can I help you? Yeah.
What may I do for you? Credit card.
That's not, that's ridiculous.
You're sweet is ready. Your champagne
would be brought up to the room.
He's Muslim. He probably doesn't
drink. Right. I don't know. Hmm.
He's a beast man. And He's good. He's
supposed to be on his way back. Right. He,
he fought Rico Verhoeven and he broke his
arm freak incident in the first round.
It's breaking shinbones
breaking arms broke. No, he broke
his arm. Like he fought Ricoh and a,
I think he was blocking a kick
and his arm just broke. And uh,
he realized that somewhere in the
middle of the round he's like,
we've got to stop it. Just like this is
broken. Who just broke down recently at,
during a fight. Was it? Um,
what's it like Paul Felder? Yeah,
during the spinning back.
Cause I saw a common man. Yeah,
that fucking spinning back.
Always read the spin kicks.
Like no matter how many angles
I have in that fucking truck,
no matter what I'm looking at as much
experience as is, you know, I have like,
you read the Spin Shit,
like you see it coming a mile away as
it's because you have so much experience.
Like with the SPEC kicked shit dude,
that was your shift.
But you see it like a lot of times you're
like, he's setting up. That's been,
he said out the spending.
I'm laid up their hips.
I mean that was my number one technique
from when I was fighting was spinning
back kick to the body.
I just knew that it was
such a short amount of time
that I needed to deliver it.
And if you were in range and I hate you,
you're Foxville cause I knew
there was just like this. We've,
we've laughed about this before cause I
tell you like I've never held for a kick
is how to show, isn't
it? I was like, aw dude,
don't honey Dyckman you bullshit me bro.
It's not fun holding pads view.
Then there's times like when you
texted me and I'm just like, fuck fuck,
don't return the text. Don't
go, don't go to syndicate.
I don't go to performance and
student hold pads for Joe. Dude.
I remember one time I helped Patsu and uh,
I remember literally like I couldn't
grip a coffee mug to like drink.
My four rounds was so trashy.
I remember that night pushing talk back
buttons on the truck at the truck and I
was like fatigued.
Just my fingers wouldn't function bro.
I'm telling you no bullshit.
I've held for a lot of guys.
I've held for a lot of fighters,
a lot of big guys,
small guys I have never held
even that's a round cake.
That's not even some
spin shit that you do.
Like just the basic Thai round kick bro.
Nasty, nasty, nasty. You did it
on that machine too, didn't you?
What were the numbers on it?
Something silly like,
well this is a guy who's figured
out how to beat my number.
He a guy at the performance institute.
I got 152,000 and the dude got 188,000
and what he realizes if you hit it with
the instead,
see that number's larger a with the Shin.
I got to hit it with the instep.
I'm healing a slight meniscus tear
that I got when I was doing it with Joe
Schilling with no warmup wearing jeans.
I was fucking asshole.
It's fishy years old.
Full blast kick.
No Warren Dick measuring testosterone.
Like what you want to kick, dude,
we're going out.
We're having a good time and Joe shillings
here and he's kicking that thing.
Yeah. And he got some pretty
good numbers. You know, he was,
he was smashing it so it was like, he's a
mean dude. I love that dude. I love that.
He's a sweetheart though, man. You
know he's such a cool guy, dude.
It's fucking terrifying. Well, I was,
I was talking to someone about him and
they were saying that he's like one of
the most risk taking elite
fighters you'll ever see.
Like he's a real elite kickboxer but
he's been knocked out before and stopped
before just because he's so,
he's not risk
averse. Yeah, he'll, he'll take big risks.
But it's one of the reasons why
he's so fucking exciting. Yep,
exactly. I was just going to say
the same thing. That's what they,
that's what the fans want to see you
man. Yeah. I want to see conservatives,
you know, he's a fan favorite for
sure. You can't stop crazy like that,
that whole song, credible way of
looking at things and his whole motto.
That's why I like the, you
know, the bonus, the bonuses
with the UFC and all that.
You know, Dana putting
that together. You know,
I remember back in the day like one of
the early fight or meetings at like,
you know, when we do the way ends and
then Dana would be like all high fighters,
only backstage, you know, they do
fighters only, no coaches, no corners.
And Dana was like, yeah, you know, game
plan, no strategy. Fuck all that is.
Go for it. Like you want to get paid. Go.
And one of the examples he would use his,
uh, Chris Lytle Democrats, Slidell lake,
he had like a losing
record and you have to see,
but he was just went for it every time.
And we'd go on this all the time,
you know, so I wouldn't give that speech.
Now we have a very different speed.
Y'All speech can says the
fight your best fight,
fight the way you're supposed to find.
That was the message.
But the idea was don't, don't know. Leave
it out there. Don't be conservative out
there if you want, your
opponent might not, you know,
this is the thing I don't think I don't,
fighting is very important to me.
It means a lot.
It means a lot because I used to do it.
It means a lot cause I love to watch it.
It means a lot because I'm very deeply
entrenched in the history and the
significance of it, what
it means. And for me,
fighting should always
be done at its best.
And what that means is you should always
do what's the right thing to do in this
situation. Like if you are, uh, you know,
you could break it down when
individual arts, right? If your, um,
if you're doing Jujitsu,
there's a,
there's a correct way to do
an arm bar counter, right?
Don't do the incorrect way because
the fans want to see, right.
That doesn't make any sense to me.
If there's an exciting way
to get out of an arm bar,
that's not the right way
to do it with the fans,
but it might well pick them up and slam.
I'm works if you have to,
but I'm saying like just as
a rough example, if, if you,
if there was a way to defend an arm bar
that wasn't the correct way to do it,
but the fans liked it more.
Don't do that. Don't do that.
You want to fight like a maestro, right?
You want to fight like, like a virtuoso.
You want to fight like mighty mouse. There
you go. Exactly. What I tell everybody,
you look at my mighty mouse has had
moments in his career like the Ian Mccall
fight is a good example where he was,
he also had a fulltime job,
wasn't dedicated the way it should be and
got into a brawl and Ian took us back.
Why not pounding them and mighty
mouse had vertigo after that fight.
He was really fucked up and
then quit his job. Realize like,
I have to go full time. I have to dedicate
myself to this full time, you know?
And when he did that,
then under the tutelage of Matt Hume,
he became the mighty mouse we see now.
But in my opinion,
one of the things that sets him
apart from everybody else is that he,
he's not running away from
you and not getting hit.
He's running at you and
not getting hit or, I mean,
he's coming straight forward and
then cutting angles and doing things to
you that you didn't anticipate and he's
not there for the counters. So he's
fighting correctly. Seamless too.
Yeah. And it's incredibly exciting.
And that was one of the, the,
the criticisms of him really early on in
his reign was that he wasn't finishing
guys and then he knocked
out Joseph Benevidez.
Then he started finishing
guys in the final seconds of
the round. Right. You know,
I mean, he's, he's just a monster
man is man. He says fucking monster.
But he fights correctly,
I would say don't fund all,
no disrespect to Chris Lytle,
who I love. He's a great fighter.
I was just watching as well. His fight
against Brian Foster, you so skilled,
like people who've got all good. Chris
Lytle was won that fight with a leg lock,
you know, and he's known as a brawler and
people forget, he fucking spun around,
got that leg and snatch it out and
extend it and really fuck Brian's leg up
crafty veteran. Here's a
crafty guy, but broad a lot.
I'm not a fan of PR. I'm a fan of
watching brawls when they take place.
I'm not a fan as well either.
You know what I mean? I'm
more of a fan of a, of an,
I train a lot of my guys like
almost offensively like backing up,
like retreat fighting, you know,
constantly trying to jockey for position.
I call it like right place, right time
all the time. And that line of fire,
you know, we're with jockey and
for that position, you know,
and it's a lot of times it's
easier just to take a step back.
If we're fighting each other with
standing in front of each other,
I take a step back, what do you
naturally do? You Walk to me.
So it's the timing of catching them on
the way in. And guys like, you know,
great fighters in my opinion.
A more like defensive fighters like you,
like you said earlier about Chris
Leben coming into Anderson Silva,
Forrest Griffin.
Sure.
Trying to attack like
you're more vulnerable like
recklessly like you said like
brawling recklessly coming in against
somebody skilled as Anderson silver with
Demetrius Johnson, you know, so I'm
all, I'm a fan of the retreating attack.
I call it Anderson was
such a retreating attacker.
Then he had a problem when guys
didn't come forward. Right. Exactly.
The stinkers that Talus Talus later.
So painful to watch those [inaudible]
Patrick Kotecha coattail was very smart
when he fought him damaging.
I camped him that whole fight.
I will fight. I had the experience from
Jorge, I knew Anderson Silva, you know,
he spent that entire camp in Boston with
me. Um, he did have a knee injury, uh,
going into the fight we knew like it
was going to be an issue but you know I
said that I actually said this to him
part of the game plan and strategy.
It's funny you say that was to let
him come to you like everybody when,
cause Patrick was the type of
fighter that was a go getter.
He had that big overhand right.
You know, he would, he would,
he would put pressure on you and
I said, Patrick, I'm telling you,
you can't fight the way you normally
fight against Anderson Silva. Even if,
if you hear boos with following the
game plan, you know, if you hit,
if you hear the boos from the crowd,
like with doing, doing the right thing,
don't fall victim to it.
Don't try to lunge at them.
Don't pro big power punches.
Let him come to you.
And we did.
And that was actually the first
time we took a Anderson past.
The third round I think
was either third of the,
we actually going into the fourth,
I think that ended up stepping in to
throw a kick in his leg blew out. Exactly.
Yup. Yup. I told her that
was in Chicago. I called it,
did we get an MRI before that fight?
I think, uh, if I remember correctly,
he had an issue. We knew going into it.
We didn't want to pull out of the fight,
you know, down shoe. Uh, it was,
it was pretty severe and after it,
I would think that was
just the icing of the cake.
It blew out completely during the flight.
So he had a partial tear of his ac,
something like that. Something to that
effect. Bring up that flight. Jamie.
I'm curious now. It was weird. It was a
weird blow out because it's almost like,
I was just going to say there was like,
it wasn't during an exchange. I think,
like you said,
he went to push off his back foot.
I don't want to be curious to see if
it's been a while since I visited that.
Yeah. I just remember not knowing
what happened and he fell down.
And you called death light on C, right?
Yeah. That was before. What's that,
Patrick?
Coty and so yeah,
from probably 2000 what was that?
Nine maybe a little later?
Yeah, maybe nine or 10 yeah, 200
suppliers at this point. I know.
Some flair to it and then like 400 Joe.
Yeah, that makes sense. Yeah, I see.
That was a while ago. Yeah. Wow Man.
That was the rain that was going to
Anderson. He had, he was, he was the king,
but people didn't appreciate him
the way they appreciated them.
After he knocked out Forrest Griffin
and Stephan Bonner after [inaudible] for
that front kick to the face. Yeah. That's
when he became the goat dude. He was,
he was like,
like literally feared like I think a lot,
a lot of fighters just like,
ah,
that call came and it was
like Anderson Silva like fuck.
Well he was also so calm.
Yeah.
You know there was something
about him in those days.
He was so used to always say this and I
told Jorge this at his cage rage fight
with them. I said, do it. He beats
people at the weigh ins. He's like,
what do you mean here?
Like what do you mean he has this thing?
It's funny like when he goes to weigh
in with you like you don't normally like
people go like face to face.
They get real close.
Like he would walk up to
as if you're going to,
and then he would thrust his neck forward,
like his head would like fucking gadget
head like would come out and he would
just be all up in your face and they
would like surprise you. Like, you know,
and I told Jorge that. I said, Jorge,
be ready at the way in like he's gonna
put his face like he's going to come a
distance quickly. Like he moves his head
like fucking shit. Ne Ne like, he's like,
I don't know your dad.
He puts his head like way out and he did
it and I was like, Oh man, there it is.
Well that was one of the ways that Chris
Liebing overcame him psychologically at
the Wayans crew. I remember Chris saying,
I'm not afraid. I'm not afraid of you.
Yeah. He was looking right at him
and he said, I'm not afraid of you.
And he probably wasn't, man wasn't
afraid of him. He wasn't afraid of him.
That was Chris when he was in his prime
and that's when they were kissing at the
way in when Anderson got so close.
That's right.
They were literally lip to lip and
Christy just judge somebody just spoke of
something about him fighting in that
bare knuckle league or something against
Phil Baroni or something like that. Chris
Leben verse Philbrick Cook. Which leap?
Yeah, but I said Chris Weidman.
Oh, Weidman. Weidman's I
did say Weidman, right?
No leave. And I thought I said
Wiedemann I've combined the two man.
Did I say wiping or
leaving? Leaving. Okay.
I might have fucked up Chris Weidman
when Weidman beat. Oh, he, yeah,
he beat him at the way they got face
to face. Yeah. And he said, yeah,
I'm not afraid. I'm not afraid of you.
And when he was looking at right now,
because I'm not afraid of you bro. And
then you could tell Anna, she was like,
Oh shit, he's not afraid of that and see
what happened that night he had event.
What's interesting in that fight too
was that Anderson could, I mean he was,
he was clearly scoring with heavy leg
kicks and putting Lieben in jeopardy.
I mean, he was damaging that leg. Say
Liebman I said it again. I said it again.
What's wrong with me? Why am I confusing
those two? They both Chris, fuck it.
I should just say Chris. I just
say Chris, Chris, Chris, when uh,
Weidman Weidman's got 'em down the first
round, almost got him in a leg lock. Yup.
And then they got back up to feet in an
industry and started fucking him up with
leg kicks and Anderson was hitting him
with some nasty, nasty leg kicks up.
And he was uh, he was saying in between
rounds like, come on, stand up with me.
Yeah, come on. Stand up with
me. It was weird. It was
weird that he was doing that.
Like he was, it was totally out
of character. He said, no, no,
we're not going to go do
it. Come on, stand up.
And I know he got some funky moments in
the [inaudible] down the fucking on Bach
and moving his hands off on tour
before he freaked dancing and shit.
Like I remember there was
a couple of fights. Well,
the fight with the Damien Maia was just
referring to psychologically fell apart
in that fight. He was screaming at
Damien Maia yelling things at him.
And Damien Maia is,
is still plugging away.
He took a lot of shots and that
fight but then was their third,
fourth and fifth when Anderson wasn't
doing shit and it was just like moving
away from that. The fight, there was a,
there was one flight to where he was
like in the center of the Octagon Control
on beat and I'm striking and
like, I forget who it was.
It might've been the day,
it might've been somebody else,
but he uh,
he actually stopped and step back and put
us back to the fence and say, come on,
come on, let's fight on the fence
now. And he like backed his self.
Oh Stephan Bonner's.
That's right.
And that's what he got caught with
a spin and elbow. Was it a no,
Stephan Bonner tried to spinning back,
kick him and he just slid out of the way
and they went right back to the fence
and went, come on. That's what
it was. Exactly. Fucked him up.
I think he hit him with a knee to the
body and then dropped him and then,
and then beat the shit out
of him. Yeah. That was just,
he was just so calm and relaxed in there
and bond or was so stiff and tight and
I think that was on her
style too. Was it? Yeah.
I've worked with Stephen
for a bunch of fights.
I didn't work on them for that fight.
I don't recall it,
but that was also a fight where um,
I think or pissed hot.
I think he had an opportunity. Yeah,
I think he's just like, listen,
I got some injuries but I'm
just going to juice it up. Dude.
Pissed hot is better than shit hot cause
when he fought Sam Hogart at the Thomas
Macarena, you fucking shit himself during
the fight. Oh Sam a Hogan. I was like,
Bro, it's like on top of that graph and
he's like probably fucking stinky shit.
He's up. And he's like,
yes I did. Stuff like that.
And the worst part about it is we
come backstage, you know the tie cups,
they liked the string up, the crap, the
butt crack. He's like, coach, get my cup.
And I was like, Bro, you're
on your own home. He ended
up with scissors. I was like,
cut it off dude. I'm good.
It's Hilarious, dude.
I got the corner I think for that
fight with the great coliseum.
Crazy at the time when it
has happened several times.
What was one of the fights at themselves
via shit himself once when we rent to
the, uh, went to the Reebok uniforms and
dude's wearing white. I was like, Bro,
that idea.
No white shorts.
Like stay away from white shorts
Brown. I think you'll, well dude,
you will vert mayor de Dynisha. Yeah, I
think he sharded one of his fights too.
One time. Michael Kia. So when
he fought by Neil Darr, you, she,
right before the fight start, he
leans over to me. He goes, dude,
I might shut myself over
that before the walk. Dude,
they almost had to postpone the walk man.
He was going to run to remember
UFC staff started. Yeah, UFC staff.
He was in the tunnel getting
ready to walk. He's like, Bro,
I got to go the bathroom. They're like,
no, no, you're good. You're gonna be like,
why didn't you just let them go? How long
did it take? I don't know. 30 seconds.
We'll cover what the guy took a dump.
Right. And then right behind him,
production time, the format,
fucking schedule, whatever it is,
but do when a man's got to shit, he's got
a shit. Here's the Anderson and Patrick.
Yeah. So is this on fight
pass? This is the first round.
So it didn't happen till third or fourth
of whatever it was. I think it was a,
I think it was the third round,
but see Jesse Anderson was just
moving around real relaxed.
Didn't do much.
Oh yeah.
It was an interesting fight because
Kobe didn't fight his normal style.
He stayed real like boxed
up. Oh, I forgot this.
That Anderson had him down at
one point in time and listens.
Grappling is underrated to have and he's
a good grappler. He's just long as fuck.
He's built to grapple to like this.
Even when he was kicking it. Look,
he takes him out. He's like, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no. I think this is,
his knee was already, I think
we knew at this point. He's
like, my knees, Jack. Dot.
Dude.
My knees checked up.
I remember him talking to me during the
fight and in between rounds. But uh,
he definitely, uh, he definitely
been put up a fight at least.
And at the time nobody was even
close to putting up a fight.
Well it's right before then.
Patrick was super fucking dangerous.
Ah,
see this is where we set out with the
first one to take them to the third round
cause nobody had passed the second
round with him. Well, not only that,
it was a totally uneventful three rounds.
There wasn't even a moment where
Patrick was in trouble, you know,
and he was fighting for the title. It
was main event, title fight. You know,
Patrick was always dangerous.
He always had that one bomb
that could put you out.
And Anderson knew that, you know, so he,
he was, he was fighting a smart strategy.
But it was interesting because it
kind of showed a hole in his style.
His style was so counter attacking.
He did not write that. Oh,
that's what he did.
He tried to lift his front foot up,
almost like to fake like a front kick.
Bring that back to me that he tried,
he tried to pick up his front leg
to fake like a tea but a fake,
like a front leg attack and then he hopped
on his back leg. Yeah. It's rough man.
Weird. Yeah. See right
there. There it is. Yeah.
Cause he's in a lot of pain to coattails.
A tough duty to Amanda.
See Him wins and go down
like that is the issue.
Was it a meniscus issue or was it all,
I'd be lying if I made some shit up
right now, but I think it was some,
something like that and
assist a ball joint.
That's why you always had in mind for
call dude. I think he had issues too.
Like he had a staph
infection in his knee,
like repeatedly.
Like I remember he had staff in
his knee like a bunch of times,
so I don't know man.
But he uh, you know his,
his best punch to was not on his overhand
right, but it's rear uppercut. Nasty.
Nasty. Yeah. He asked me the
fuck up a bunch of times.
It's, it was weird. His power.
It's not like he didn't look like a
strong guy, but his power was weird. Yeah.
See you watch, he hops up on
that front leg and do you see it?
Just keep that tonk.
Yeah.
Dude. Knees back, nasty
injuries. All those leg lock.
Motherfuckers all fucked up knees.
Eddie just had to get his meniscus
fixed to up meniscus operation pretty
recently. Yeah. He had
shoulder surgery recently.
He had back surgery recently. Yeah, he
back surgery a little over a year ago.
Knee surgery recently.
He's not doing that stem cell shit
you're talking about now. No, he hasn't.
I think he did something, but he didn't
do it with the place that I go to,
but it's just, you know,
years and years of Jujitsu.
It's just not good for your body.
Everybody that I know is righteous
Jujitsu, bro. I'm telling you, I,
I s I sustained most of my
injuries and Roland like, yeah.
It's like almost like I can't get out of
a Jujitsu session like g o Nogi without
getting something tweaked to something.
You know what I was talking the other
night with some guys from team Alpha male
number. We're talking about
guys who have fake discs.
How many guys have had artificial discs
put in their necks and then their backs.
It's a fucking terrifying number.
You keep going on and not used
to like he got one too. Yeah,
he's got two in his neck like watts.
He's got one in his lower back. What?
God dammit, he's 30 and this guys like 30
years old. The fake bags. Combat Sports.
A rough man. Yeah, body, particularly
wrestling and particularly Jujitsu.
Wrestling. It seems to be a lot
of the neck and the Jujitsu.
It's neck and lower back.
The lower back seems to get jacked done.
Almost everybody. I've been lucky,
knock on wood, I've been lucky.
I haven't really suffered any serious
injuries in my training career.
I wonder too how much,
uh,
Thai training and throwing kicks because
it's so core intensive kicking it so
much, so much. I think it protects
you because like a lot of my leg,
my lower back, it's very heavily
muscled. The lower back in the mid.
It's one of the first things
like I actually look at
when I'm like studying like
a fighter as I look to see
his back pack and I was like,
this guy is going to be strong.
What makes you say that? Like Dude,
look at his lower eye.
Lower back specifics.
I say that I'm like
look at his lower back.
You see guys with like jacked
up like lower back muscles.
Do you know their core
strength is just off the chain?
Do you have a reverse hyper in your
gym? Do you have one of those? No Dude,
that should be standard in any
gym where they wrestle really?
And that's the one where you while lie
down on the table with your upper body
and your lower body hangs down and hooks
into this thing and it was created by
Louie Simmons,
that guy from west side Barbell,
the power lifting monster and
when you lift your legs up,
it's strengthens your back.
There it is right there on the way down.
It decompresses the spine lengthens.
Almost like decompresses. See,
here's a video.
If you show him the video,
he'll get a chance to see what it is
and the video Louise explaining it.
But we have one back here and I've,
I've had one for a couple of years
now and it's, it's just go forward.
Just go forward and you don't need to
see the vault here, the volume. Um,
see as she's going up it's strengthening
her back and then on the down it
extends and it lengthens the
back and decompresses it.
It's active decompression.
It's one of the rare things that provides
active decompression in contrast with
strengthening.
So it strengthens it on the way up and
then loosens it on the way back and that
activating the muscles and
the strengthening portion
portion of it and then the
decompression portion together.
It's uniquely good for
a uniquely effective for
strengthening and rehabilitating
lower back issues. Interesting. Yeah.
He developed it because they
were trying to give him surgery.
They were trying to,
they were trying to fuse this
together cause he had a bulging disk.
So he's trying to figure out
how to fix a bulging disc.
And that's how I figured it out.
But it's now like universally praised
has been one of the as being one of the
best exercises to prevent injury.
But more importantly to rehabilitate you
if you have something like that going
on. I gotta check that out for sure.
It should be standard for every gym.
It's one of those pieces of equipment
that I think like one of the big things
that happens with guys is compression
and very few fighters in particular spend
time doing spinal decompression,
like on those inversion table version.
Those are great and they're great.
Just just chill on one of those,
those teeters chill on one of
those for 10 minutes a day.
Just put the boots on and
kick back and just and,
and then tighten your backup
and then let it loose.
Tighten your backup and let him choose
and he could push on the handles,
give yourself some separation. You're
just, you have to do something to,
to compensate for all the pressure,
right?
So there's all this compression and
you've got to do something to decompress.
Seen something to like with a,
like a band around your neck.
You lay in the floor and I'm just like
put it on a door knob almost like,
and it pulls your head up. You ever seen
something like that? I have one that's a,
it's a thing that you put on your
Chin and I put it on a, a unit, like a
barbell.
So I hook it up to the barbell and then
I sit underneath it with a chair saying
that I'm extending my
neck. It's a click, click,
click like two inches tall. Itching. Yeah,
like you said to wrestling as
the worst man. Just like that.
Always shooting that single
sheet. Wrapping and calming
the back of your head.
Yeah, it's rough. Well
ty too, right? Oh my God.
I remember the first,
one of the first experiences I had clinch
and with guys in Thailand, you know,
I was one of the bigger guys,
they were like, oh, I need, you
need you to clench. You know?
And he's tied to just hanging on my neck,
hanging on my neck, you know, you know,
for an hour straight.
And I've never felt anything like that.
And then my neck was completely locked up.
I couldn't turn.
I had to actually get one of those. Uh,
the neck braces there, the callers? Yeah.
I had to get like mid massage,
like every day I literally,
I was out of train and probably for
four or five days I couldn't even train.
I couldn't answer that.
It's almost like having a stiff neck,
but it was horrible man.
Those muscles don't get used that much
or you're not doing the correct. Yeah,
if you're not doing like neck extensions.
And then I went to my trainer and I was
like, how do I make my next stronger?
And he took me over to this coffee can
filled with cement and a rope coming out
of it and he said,
you bite the rope and you go in a member
of ringside had like a thing like that.
They,
they put that like thing like a strap
around your head and you put the chains
real weight. I did the, yeah,
but biting it seems better to get
your work in the mandible as well.
The problem was, is everybody
fucking bid on the thing and they,
and the fucking good,
all the bad mouthpiece.
But
I remember being in a bank in,
in Thailand,
in patio once and like there was like
a water like thing, but there was,
there was no plastic cups.
They was,
there was no like a cop's
like disposable cups.
There was a plastic cup with
a string tied to it. Oh,
we'll just go and fill it and just lip
on it and put it down. I'm like, Bro,
this is rough dude. Right. Well I got to
figure, it's like I'm not that thirsty.
Those moist environments, like there's
so much bacteria in the air anyway.
Like how common is, um,
how common is staff? Dude,
it's so funny you say that because you
would think it would run rampant like
ringworm.
Like I remember,
I remember one of the first times I got
ringworm in Thailand and I like had a
bandaid on it and I was clenching when
one of my train upon his tie guy and the
band aid came off and I was like, hold
on, let me go it. And he's like, well Nah,
don't worry about it. And I was like,
no, like, let me like, cover this up.
And He'd like, he touched it and
he was rubbing it like, I'll do it.
Don't worry about that threat. And I was
like, dude, no, no, no, no, no. It's like,
it's ringworm bro.
And like it's like the like Thai
led the skin is like immune to it.
They don't fucking get ringworm. They
don't get staff. Like it's weird.
Like you don't don't get it. Not Common.
No, it's weird. I'm sure they do get it.
But it's funny like it doesn't
like run rampant in the gyms.
Like you would think like
a bunch of sweaty tie dudes
training with no shirts on
clinch in hanging all over each other.
You know, and they, they, you know,
they laying on the ground doing sit
ups and pushups and all that bullshit.
And is,
it's not common.
Like there's not a lot of
ringworm in the gyms is not a lot.
A lot of staph infections.
I don't know if just the their body
builds immunity to, I don't know.
It's just not common. It's not common
American gyms, it's all am I, God,
I remember being on the ultimate fighter
season when I coached us season for the
comeback. Would Jorge Patrick Hotel
all the time, met all those guys, uh,
Chris Lytle, et Cetera, et cetera.
Matt Serra was on that show. Uh,
who was it that got it? Edwin dewees I
think got a staph infection and nobody,
everybody's like, oh, what the hell's
wrong with just getting, I was like, Bro,
that's like, that's like the Heebie
jeebies that's like the matte scabies,
like that staff. And everybody was like,
what? Like wait you stat? And I was like,
Bro, that staph infection like one
was a lot. And I went to the UFC,
the production team and I said,
when was the last time you guys
wipe clean the mats? Like, oh,
like we cleaned them like once once a week
when I was like, whoa. I was like, Bro,
you got to clean these mats
with like disinfecting every
single training session.
And they're like, all right, that's cool.
And I was like, how about that wall?
Like the padded wall? Like, oh no, we
never cleaned that. Like Bro, there be,
they have no shirts on.
Their grappling with their backs on the
wall sweating all over the wall and they,
I brought him,
brought it to their attention that listen,
everything needs to be cleaned in the gym.
How Bill Dana literally said you go
back and you watch like the box series.
Like I still got as like DVD series like
and it's like literally Dana said like
Delaguardia pretty much saved
the show, the whole, the whole,
almost the whole both teams got staff.
I was like get the vans detail,
like get the vans Etl, clean the
mats, cleaned, stability balls.
I made everybody get tea tree and
Eucalyptus soap, you know, it just,
nobody was educated at the time about
it and it just, it's a plague man. It's,
I, if I see anybody would
ring where more staff,
I literally light fucking bombs and the
gym and burn the fucking place down or a
new maps from zebra and rev gear.
It's so common.
I was just reading one a Gordon Ryan's
posts on Instagram that he got Mercer for
the second time and that medication
resistant staph infection.
That's scares the shit out of me dude.
I had staff,
I can't really claim Coty I'm
not going to blame you bro.
But it was oddly enough right around the
time we had Kobe had staff in his knee
and I was camping.
I'm,
and I was very active at the time training
with these guys and I got staff onto
my armpit both fucking on pits.
I literally had,
I had to walk around like
with my arms up like this.
I had wicks coming out of them like nasty
dude staff has no good. They put wicks.
What they do is they actually,
they make an incision,
they drain the abscess cause it's an
abscess essentially they drained the
abscess and then a packet with like,
it literally looks like a
wick from like a lantern.
It's like hollow in the middle cloth and
they pack it in and they leave just a
little tip out and as the wound
drains and heals, the wick comes out.
So I had like these two inch like like
a tip on strange basically and wasn't
medicated the, the no, they just, they
cleaned it out. They make an incision,
they cleaned it all out.
They flush it with saline and they,
they pack it with a wick and they dope
you up with cal flex usually is the
weapon of choice for antibiotics I think.
Believe it's called Catholics and they a
picture. He's too tired walking
upstairs like everything.
That's when you see when guys fight
on that. I remember what's his name?
Rockhold against Chris Weidman and
Kevin Lee recently to a member.
We noticed it during the breakfast was
didn't take any medication specifically
because he knew it would zap has cardio.
Yeah.
Well I'm sure the stabs
zapped him to period. Yeah.
But the antibiotics on top of it,
forget about it.
I remember when we called that fight,
you call that fight and I was like, dude,
that's staff on us.
And we were talking about it and it's
almost like the guys in the truck, like,
I don't know,
I don't mention it though.
When they told Daniel Cormier and not to
say anything unless they brought it up
to Carmax, her, I said, does that look any
staff too? And they're like, don't bring
that up. That's definitely staff. Joe,
you don't give a single fuck that guy.
He was like, what are you talking about?
Don't talk about that. Yeah, you got
it. It was, it was blatantly obvious.
So it was so obvious. How could anyone
say to not talk about, it's funny too,
because I don't think the commission is
supposed to allow you to fight if they,
if you got like a Herbie on your lip or
something funky or you got staffed bout
scratch. So I was shocked because
it was so blatant. Yeah, exactly.
Olin and he and I think a makeup on
it on the way and yeah, that's right.
That's right. Yeah. Susie touched it
up a little bit, which is hilarious.
She's complicit. Everyone's
involved. Susie is awesome. I've had,
I've had times where like, I've
had fighters like, oh my God,
he took a cut during the camp. Like
you're trying to kind of hide it. Yeah.
Hairbrush crazy. Yeah.
Kevin Lee. That was, uh,
that was really unfortunate timing because
I wanted to see what would happen in
that fight. I mean, that was
a, you saw Kevin get Tony down.
He's beating him up on the ground.
I was just going to say,
who is he fucking is Ferguson.
He got his back dude cabs a style,
you know,
fucking huge for 105 pounds.
I, when he first emerged, like, and I was
watching him, I was like, I wasn't like,
I want to say I wasn't impressed,
but I,
I had no idea like what
his capabilities were like,
and I started watching him fight and
I was like, dude, this guy's legit.
He's in his prime. It's a how
old is he? He's 26. I think. Now
he's the, he's very young. Final
hold. Kevin Lee is, I think, uh,
I think he's a few years. I think he's
a few years from his prime. 25, 25. 25.
20 bucks. A young dude that is
a young man, young, youngest
fuck smart as fuck too.
In a month. He's 27. He's a cool
dude too. He's a very cool guy.
I had him on my podcast and I think it
really changed people's perceptions of
him.
You realize how honest he is as open
and teligent and just really considerate
and thinking about all the
various aspects of his career.
And even when he's talking
about like other fighters,
he wasn't shit talking necessarily where
it's like really just talking about his
own skills versus their skills and,
and even Ferguson when he's talking
about Tony, he was saying, man,
this injury is a real bummer because
it's going to impede what he does.
Like his whole thing is that
he can do anything right.
He's like loose and he takes chances.
Like if he's got this need,
it's fucked up that he doesn't trust like
that could really get, I'm like, Ooh,
that's a good point. Yeah. He's
got a knee that he doesn't trust.
It's going to keep him from being
is like freewheeling. You know?
One of the things about Tony
is he's so unpredictable.
Like how do you prepare for a guy that
just moves crazy and has knockout power
and Nadine endurance, he
trained with Eddie still. Yes.
Yes, he's still with Eddie.
What a freak accident, man. Imagine
you're on your way to a fight.
You're doing press and you,
you're going to talk to somebody.
You trip over some wires.
Is that what it was?
A production wires like camera wise?
Yeah.
And UFC tonight and blew
the fucking, the, the,
the ligament off the bone law.
You ever see the scar? I haven't.
Oh my God. It's like a Hayley.
It's like a 12 inch scar.
There was no previous injury or anything.
So that literally just came out of
nowhere to fucking the wires and fell
sideways and literally,
which is,
how does a guy like that fall down
even you would think he's so athletic.
I forget what it was.
Ordinate in the day we had,
remember when you used to do the UFC
workout rooms? Uh, they would put,
oh man, he fucking scar.
It's like 80 staples. Yeah,
it's nuts. It's one of the bigger needs
scarves I've ever seen in my life.
That is nasty sky. Yeah. But now he's
uh, he's running around. He's moving.
Yeah.
He's a freak man.
They were doing some UV light or something
like that on it. But you know, he's a,
he's starting to hit the bag again. He
throws kicks and punches on the bag now.
We've lost fights in the past
for those of, you know, like,
I was just going to say we had those,
the, you know, the foldout maths,
like the bi fold maths or maybe like
somebody got their foot caught in it,
roll their ankle. It was like one show
a long time ago. And you know, uh,
we started talking about it.
I think it was a Jimmy Gifford works for
Lorenzo back at the time. Uh, I was like,
man, you need those dollars. Are those
rollout Maths d seems a no good man.
People are tweaking their ankles
left and right, man. We'd like,
we'd lose a fight occasionally,
like backstage,
just I'm like somebody rolling in their
ankle in the cracks of the mats or
something stupid like that.
But what a freak accident to,
to think like and how close he was
really close to that fight, wasn't he?
He was a couple of days out.
Do you remember when, um,
Kevin Randleman was backstage and he
stepped on some pipes and flew through the
air and land on his head and
knocked himself out back off stage.
Scrapping for the main event of a fight.
It was like UFC 13 or 14
or some shit or something.
He lost the main of it.
Lost the nightmare.
I don't remember who he was supposed
to be fighting. I do not remember,
but I remember Kevin Randleman stepped
on some pipes and fell and hit his
fucking head. Yeah, I remember. I remember
thinking what? Yeah, what are the odds?
I've maybe you're supposed to be fighting
Pedro his though I do not remember who
that's going way back. Randleman days is
gone. Was It Pedro? His Oh yeah. What,
what, what, when did you
come on? Like 12, 1997.
Was it does it with her at the time
or was it as CG? It was Bob Myerwitz.
Campbell Mclaren hired me.
No,
she was Tony Blauer did it
before me and they needed a new,
a backstage interview or Guy Ufc 12?
Yeah,
in Alabama Sun. We're supposed to be in
buffalo. It's supposed to fly to Buffalo,
New York, and, or Albany
somewhere in New York.
But New York state made it illegal like
right before. So they had a change.
All the flights move the octagon
flying down to Dothan, Alabama. Yeah.
Puddle jumper. Plane. Yeah.
Yeah. I remember those days.
I was not involved with the
company at the time. I got,
I think the first fight I cornered was
like UFC 36 or something
like that. But that was it.
That's early in the day
to UFC 35 and a half.
It was when I came back. Yeah.
That's what I did. My first comic.
Who's the first versus Vittorio,
what I did,
who's the owner of that sounds
at heart Davie and was like,
I think Davies was one of
the original guys. Yeah. Uh,
he was a part of seg. Yeah,
it was art Davies. Uh,
Bob Meyrowitz. Yeah. And I guess
Horian Gracie was involved in the very,
very beginning. I remember we did the
20 years, Ufa, 20 years, whatever.
Like we're backstage will
coming in to the, uh,
to the MGM in the back of the
arena. And you know, uh, you know,
everybody's pulling up. You know, I got
the Ferrari's Lambo is caught up in out,
Davie pulls up in a fucking Saturday.
And then I was like, oh boy,
you have time changed. Times
have changed. Like a busted,
like Nevada plate you didn't get,
Oh man.
Missed the boat was like fuck,
times have definitely changed.
Lambo is Ferrari's like black SUV
and then a Saturn reiki racket
come squeaking. I'll see
body dude though. I like,
Hey [inaudible] bought the UFC for $2
million, right? I don't think of that.
And they,
what 4 billion was the sale price.
Talking about profit on return or return
of investment, but is a long time.
And when they bought it in 2001 and you
can imagine how much money the Fertittas
Lorenzo and frank and Dana, they are,
how much money they put into, you know,
so yeah,
it's not like they bought it for a clean
two mill and had smooth sailing and
then sold out,
you know,
well they were in the hole for $40
million by the time 2005 roll out.
So 2005 was the first season
of the ultimate fighter
and they were in the whole
$40 million while they were doing,
while they're in production and
they were trying to sell the,
they were trying to sell the UFC and
Lorenzo called Dana the next day and said,
fuck it. Let's just keep going.
Yeah. Like he was saying like,
see if anybody wants to buy it. And they'd
decided, fuck it. Let's just keep going.
I'm glad he did. Here we are. Yeah. Yeah.
But you got to think that the number,
the amount of money they have to make
every month just to make the nut on 4
billion. Exactly. Yeah. It's
not an easy company to run.
I can imagine. Yeah. I mean,
I don't really talk to Ari much when
he's back there and I just say hi,
shake his hand,
but I don't know how well it's doing.
I've never met him. I just miss them.
Actually in Dubai. It was Lorenzo from me,
a fucking big lay up and sent me over
to Dubai to train od Prince. Tada. Noon.
You've trained him several times, right?
Uh, I had one trip I spent about a month.
Yeah.
But I ended up just instead of teaching
them Moitai just ended up doing Jujitsu.
It Marcella gas here everyday,
which was fucking awesome.
I show up in Dubai like do not,
it was funny because he got off the plane
the first they send me airline tickets.
Learns is like, Hey you want
to go to Dubai? You know,
train, train, talk to him.
I it's absolutely right.
Yeah, it was Abu Dhabi. Dubai.
I'm telling you I would not be, but
Dubai is like right there. So you know,
so going out with Dobie like I got
the airline tickets, I was like,
what the fuck is this ets something
airlines and listen bullshit flying some
fucking weird. Ilana and I looked
it up and I was like, Oh shit.
It's like gold toilets and shit. And I
looked in my and I told him, I was like,
I need them to assist them to go at me.
Like you may have an assistant.
Then I was like, perfect. I looked
and it was nine grand each a ticket.
It's like 18 grand. Felt like the
flights, it wasn't like full beds,
like little capsules. You can get fleas
and shit. And we got there, there was a,
there was nobody at the airport. And I'm
like, fuck dude, I don't know who to call,
what's going on. I have no idea. Right.
Some guy walks over to
me and he hands me a box,
a mobile phone and I opened
the box and as a funny goes,
the phone would ring when he needs
you. And I was like, what does this,
and then a seven series,
so check this out,
a stretched out seven series BMW comes
and like the guys like, you know,
he comes over,
he grabbed my bag,
he puts him in and he takes us to
a place called the twin towers.
You motherfuckers, oddly enough, right
after nine 11, I'm like, oh, I get it.
Fucking twin tower is fucking put the
American guys up in the twin towers and
like we get the end of the middle
of the night. Me and my buddy Neil,
one of my students at the time
and the Ligo, we ended up um,
going up to the room and they was like
nothing. Then I was like, no furniture,
like the beds where it
wasn't like a hotel.
It's like an apartment because we were
going to be there for a month and I was
like,
dude,
is it like a fucking target open right
now and get some bed sheets and stuff.
I need like soap I need. Like she
like it, there was nothing there.
And we literally sat in that apartment
going across the street to the market
will be the only white dudes in the
market just getting like cans of like tuna
in olive oil and like
bread just to dip it in.
We would like survive
in for like two days,
just staring at the fucking phone every
day. Like he's gonna fucking ring.
I know what's going provide
fool. Listen. So then,
so then the phone rang and he said,
I'd, there'll be a driver outside.
You know when you get there, like when go
downstairs, they'll be a driver outside,
you're going to go to the palace.
So we'd go downstairs as driver outside
and he gives us the whole rundown about
do not make eye contact with a prince,
only called him in Sinus and this
and that. And I'm like, dude,
this is trippy as fuck dude.
You got to do Jujitsu with this guy.
So now I'm supposed to
train him in boy ty,
he wants to learn Moitai cause you say
yes. Lorenzo. He asked Lorenzo like,
you know,
you know who do,
who you do when we tie what I was
wondering about when we tie solar,
Renzel mentioned me and
that's how I got over there.
So I get to the palace and I show up in
the work and this workout room and uh,
I'm just sitting there, I'm
like, dude, this is so weird.
Like w no one's telling us what's going
on in Marcello Garcia walks in with a
gym bag and was like, holy fucking
shit. That's how I got to see it.
We ended up like a ton
of new and came out.
His hind is talking and came out and we
did a little bit of more time but his
passion for Jujitsu was so overwhelming
that it's Ali wanted to do is do Jujitsu
and he's like, do you like to do too?
And I was like, I love Jews. He's like,
let's do Jujitsu.
I ended up training everyday what Marcella
Garcia for like a month straight and
we did like maybe we did like maybe in
a month's time we did like maybe three
hours and when we tie.
Yeah and then as like going back to
the Irish story as I was leaving,
like I think Ari was coming in
doing some type of business with,
with his highness at the time or
something. So we just missed each other.
That was my,
my point to tell you about Aria,
like hanging out with
cause all that eye contact.
She had seems to go out the window once.
Yeah. Once you, once you get to know him,
once I got to know him and you know,
I've got a little more
comfortable around them. Like
he was super cool, like super cool
dude. Really intense dude man.
Like everything to the extreme.
Like I want to hike Mt. Everest.
He hikes fucking Mount
Everest. He's like, aw dude.
Everything like he said he had like an uh,
the Cha,
what's the elevation chamber like the
elevation 10th and stuff like that. Yeah,
just everything he does.
Anything he did was like to the extreme.
I mean obviously like you're talking
like a, an extreme do at a trillionaire.
Like you can do anything.
He wants to let trillionaire Trilly
and this is the other half peach.
Brilliant people don't understand. When
you hear about the world's richest men,
those are people with public
incomes. Yeah. This is not, yeah,
he's of above and beyond fucking forums.
500.
He's literally a prince.
He was funny.
He told me his story about how Hanzo and
I've live laughed at this weight. Enzo,
Enzo.
Uh,
they had this big horse race that they
do when they race across the desert and,
uh, they needed another ride and you
do it like with no saddle or something.
It's this crazy like long lake, 20, 30
mile horse race or something like that.
And I don't know the details of it,
but Henzel was there at the time and they
were like, uh, we need another rider.
And then it was like, fuck it, I'll
ride. And they're like, no bro,
you don't understand.
Like it's like you got like a fucking
scarf around your throat and you're like,
just get on a horse and you go for
like whatever it is, how long it is.
And Hanzo did the race. He likes,
survived the race. It was crazy. Yeah.
Ask him about it sometime.
It's funny,
I saw that 51 I was saying to myself,
what's he doing?
Like is he gonna he's gonna fight it
and he's really doing this like at first
key condo and he took his back with a,
took him down with a very
slick move. Yeah, yeah. He,
he hooked the leg and then went through
the underside and butterflied the back
of the other leg and drag them down. I
saw the finish. I didn't see the fight.
How long did the fight last? It
wasn't that long first. Yeah,
the first round and second Hanzo still
getting added honey go up earlier than
this. You can see the, the actual
take cause it takedown slick. Yup.
So he dives in and a very dangerous guy,
Yukon Yuki Kondo stops Sahlu he
barrow like Yuki Kondo was a beast.
Vicious, vicious fucking
striker. But you know,
also 50 years old himself think so.
Hanzo gets a single,
takes the same trip.
You'll see that and butterflies
the the opposite leg.
That is a, I love that. Masta
Henzel Gracie. Unbelievable man.
Such a great person. Great. Jujitsu has
been an inspiration to us all. Is this,
he's 51 with his body. He doesn't, it
doesn't look like he's juice to the tits.
You know, once he's in this position
right now, he's got his back. He's like,
I got you motherfucker. And so it gets on
your back. And that's how we're wrapped.
Pretty much. Yeah. And condo was
always a striker. Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Is this like 50 50 year old division
going to manifest something?
They like talking about this master's
league or something like that?
Is it actually going to manifest? I don't
know, man. But in Japan, you know Japan,
they'll have anybody fight.
Yeah.
Gabby Garcia fight old housewives.
They don't give a fuck.
They have grandma's fighting Japan.
They'll do anything.
And then what they're doing and what an
IFC, I mean, they're basically, look,
they're rehabilitating careers. I
mean, look at fucking Brandon Vera.
Brandon Vera is a monster over
there. That's right. Yeah. Dude,
you ever see what he looks like now? I
haven't even followed it in a while. Yeah,
he looks like a poster boy for
Usada Sniff test. Oh Shit. Gigantic.
His neck starts at the top of his head.
He's Yo, he's a huge heavyweight now.
He was always big, but he's yoked
up now. Oh yeah, dude. He's,
he's for sure on Mexican supplements
and good for him. Go for it.
It's got that too on a test.
I don't know what a look.
See if you can find a video
of him fighting because he
looks like a fucking go.
Really now. What does it say he
weighs? Was does a say there?
He was only four years old at age 46.
Four six to two 30.
It says then he was a very light to 50.
Now 59 yeah. See, see if
he can find a video of him.
Go that. Yeah. Get go deep into
the fight. You see how big he is?
Oh, he's so big. He has a pig.
He's a real heavyweight now.
He's a, is he living in Asiana weird
that I don't think so originally.
Still Right. He's still San
Diego had kicked from hell. Yeah.
Dude, he's a monster. His chits is
good to dean. Lister gets us on. Well,
um, I think he started with Lloyd
Irvin. Okay. Yep. You're right. Yeah,
I mean he's been, he's gone
to a bunch of camps. Yeah.
I had a chance to train with him when
he was at Eddie's place at the old bomb
squad. He came in and it was
before he fought in the UFC.
And I remember saying to him like, what
way do you find in it? And he's like,
heavy weight. And I was like, wow.
He didn't look like a big guy.
He wasn't a big hip. No, he's
very light for a heavyweight.
But he was fucking people up
because he was your mentor.
I think he trained with
two and say Rob Cayman.
Rob came in and rob Kamins guy for a
while and then him and rob had a dispute
about, you know, percentage payments
or something like that. You know,
there was a kid though that I
think managed them in my area.
I forget his name back in the day, but
he, uh, he had some money issues too.
I don't know what happened with rob. Rob
Vanished. Never see him and yeah, man,
it's funny. He was like, he, he was
around for a while and he disappeared.
Then he'd come back around for a
while and then before you know it,
I saw him like fucking eating fucking
space cake on Instagram in Holland.
I was like, I guess he's in Holland.
Not like, I don't think so. Yeah.
I think he had like just some ups and
downs in his life and he just needed to
get the fuck out.
Just go back to his roots.
I saw him like videos like him in like
a field like frolicking and fucking off
like my man rob.
He though some thing that he was putting
together like came in one oh one some
workout. Yeah. Yup, Yup. He was,
he was nasty back in the day, man.
He was like one of the first uh,
foreigners that Korea Tang of the
CEO, Tom Camp Lake. I remember
the Duke Roufus on the podcast years ago
was talking about rob came in and see a
tongue. He was like one of our first
like foreign foreign superstars.
Like you know him Rehmann Deca
those guys done a big guy too for,
for a guy that was fighting the ties.
He was not a little bit about him.
And two as a southpaw, he would
attack the back leg a lot. Oh yeah.
That's the worst way to take us.
He would do that slight step to the side.
Go across both legs.
Oh,
right across the three jet [inaudible]
what is that? What he's saying? Hood.
Hood. Hood hurt Jeb. Jeb like je be dead.
What does that mean? She gets
hurt. Jet. Yeah. Hurt Jeb. Hawaii.
If I say Jeb, that means heard.
If I want to say it hurts a lot.
I say mock like my name, mock
check mark. Like happy Dji,
very happy. Dhi Mac. And then you
can throw the type thing but oh,
Dji Macklin.
Could you read tie?
I'm just now my brother Joshua who is a,
one of my students back home,
he's a Buddhist monk. A white dude
with a man bond drives a jeep.
Like you'd never know.
He's like,
he's teaching me how to, how to read
and write, you know, I can speak.
I knew I could speak.
Uh,
I knew I could speak Thai pretty well
when I actually started talking to people
on the phone,
like people from Thailand on the phone
because if I'm in front of you like,
and it's like any language, like you
go, like you fly, like what time?
Like you can fucking caveman language
and you can figure it out, you know?
But once I started talking to like Thai
friends on the phone, I was like, dude,
I got this. Like I'm not using
like my, my hand signs and whatnot.
So if you had to say someone in Thai,
like the weigh ins are today,
but it's not the real way in.
It's a ceremonial way, in the
real way. And started at 8:00 AM,
what would you say the ties don't
even go that far. That's way too much.
Really? Yeah, Dude. Like
it dude. I'll explain.
I'll explain Thailand, which
you right now. You Ready?
Let's take the verb to like or like you
like something chop karate. Chop Chop,
right? I like, okay. I take
the word Mai Mai right.
If I put it before it a fight. If I
want to ask you if you like something,
I just say Chop my,
that means mine is at the end.
That's I'm asking you a question.
Chop like my do you like if you like it,
you say chop, right? If you don't like
it, you put the mind in front of my shop.
It's literally like, like no,
like fucking cave language.
So if I'm like, all right, you
know, take the word, like I said,
like go like bye bye means go right by my,
are you going Mike? By not going.
If you're going to just go by,
that's, that's the crash
course of time right there.
But the best in the kingdom Bro,
is knowing the tie glitch.
Me and my trainer crew toys see a
tongue. The son of Koreatown, uh,
always taught me English because it was
the fastest way from a to B. It's like,
all right, if you want to say water,
like it's nom, but rather than say nam,
you just say what the, I'm like, Oh shit.
Like airports and Ambien just go airport.
So they know what they, oh dude, if I,
if you say [inaudible] and you
say it like with the wrong tone,
like it's something different.
Like it's like the word my, my,
my dog horse come.
Oh Jesus.
That's why you can really get fucked
up trying to speak Thai in Thailand.
That's why I teach all my
students and CrashCourse Bro.
Tagless like you want water? What
the, you want to go the airport app,
hot passport, passport.
You just have to say it.
Just say it. It's literally like
you almost like mocking them like,
but you're not like they get it right
away. Oh, that's so strange. It's weird.
Like I've had like literally people
like, dude, like don't hit it.
You're like fucking ranking
on the guy. Like, no, I'm
not dude. I'm talking to him.
They, they all spoke English
almost everybody for the
most part nowadays. Yeah.
Yeah. Nowadays for the most part,
yeah. Everybody speaks depending on go,
it was more, it was more difficult to
communicate. Well there was less tourists,
you know, and now you know,
it's over. It's plagued with
like Germans and Russians.
I was like,
everybody's going to Thailand.
I saw a Ferrari driving down the
street for the first time ever.
Like a couple of years go in town.
I was like a fucking Ferrari in a city.
Thailand, it's all Russian money. Like a
lot of big Russian money, you know? Yeah.
There's a lot of like gangster activity
specifically like Russian, like Dutch,
Russian. Yeah. What are they doing
over there? I Dunno. I Dunno.
Seller selling.
People I don't fucking know can buy a
liver for fucking 500 baht in the street.
Like I dunno bro.
I don't know.
But I definitely know that there was a
time when I was going to Thailand and it
felt like Thailand and then I
went back once and it was like,
like everybody was speaking Russian
and it was like white dudes everywhere.
And I'm like all for wrong,
like all foreigners. And I
was like, I think Russian.
Why do you think,
I don't know what's a lot of,
a lot of a European vacation in Thailand
too. You know, it's like we go to,
like in America we go to like
a Roomba, Bahamas, Jamaica.
Like that's our vacation.
Like the Brits, like from the UK, they
could go to this go holiday in Thailand,
you know, they go to tie that
Australians, they go to Thailand,
like they go to Southeast Asia. So
it's just, I dunno, just a, it's a,
it's a big tourist attraction
in Thailand. Pho, Pho,
pho for Europeans and funnel Russians.
I saw a lot of older European or
American looking men with hot young Thai
checks. Yep, absolutely. I was like,
look at the mock really cheap.
You get a,
you get a fucking great deal over there.
They run specials like, yeah.
Now you see it all the time.
The worst is like the fat German guy in
the fucking man Thong walking down the
street and it would have fucking little
boy like a 14 year old boy. Oh Dude.
I've seen some weird shit in Thailand man.
As I said earlier in Atlanta smiles,
but this does not always smiles worse if
it's a 14 year old boy versus a 14 year
old is it?
It's all the same at that point.
I don't know man. I don't
think, I dunno. Worse.
I think the 14 year old boy
probably take it better.
I never thought of that then I don't
want to probably less scarring if that's
what he's into. So you don't see a
lot of that shit up in Chiang Mai.
Like it's not like you,
you were more like the elephant country
and like that's real Thailand to me like
that, that Chiang Mai, that northern
Thailand is like the real Thai culture,
you know. And then you as you go
down south you get more touristy,
you get more of a freak shows. You got
elephants were everywhere in terms of art.
Yep. Elephant Park, huge prevalent.
It's very prevalent and tie cogens it's
the Southeast Asia that's, that's the,
the, the fucking animal God.
Like that's it. Like the
elephants, everything to them.
The Thai Thai box and started,
well at first it was a,
what they call [inaudible],
which is known as a in Thailand is a
fan dab, which means like long short,
and that's the old to you see of sword
play, like the ties use and swords.
And they dressed up these elephants and
like Amr and like road baskets and just
shot arrows from, from, from
the top of the elephant.
So the elephant has always been a huge
part of that. Even in warfare. Yeah.
They use the elephants
in, in combat. Yeah. Yeah.
So they would like put these armor plates
on the trunks of the elephants in the
body of the elephants,
and they would put baskets on them and
they would just go off in a battlefield
and just be plucking people with arrows
and just dropping spears on them.
So the elephant was always prevalent
to the success of Thai culture.
You imagine going a battle
riding a fucking elephant.
It's something up there in the
Internet. Would fucking, well,
was that all elephants? 300 something
like that. Yeah. There you go. Right?
There you go. There you
go. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The ties were doing that shit against
the Burmese. Like back in the day,
they'd dress mellow fucking war with a
bunch of come towards you on elephants.
A giant fucking horse like coming at me
is one thing, but an elephant like, ah,
dude, we're out numbered here. We've
got to fight them. They're so big, man.
I was so nervous around them big time.
It's weird.
We went to a place that rehabilitates
them and they reintroduce them back into
the wild. Yeah, it's a, you didn't
write it though. I think you did.
I didn't like it though. Yeah, I just
didn't think it was necessary. Right.
It's like this thing
doesn't want me to ride it.
A Lincoln rejects that King
of Sam's offer of elephants.
This is an 1862 civil war.
Abraham Lincoln.
Oh, find that candles. War found that
camera thing the other day and I was like,
I wonder if they used them here.
What? Camels. I just, yeah,
I found something the other day when
we were talking about something and I
stumbled across another article that said
there were camels in the west and they
used him to travel. You can carry
things to help develop the west.
At some point they abandoned
them and there was like a, uh,
they call them the red ghost.
It was like a myth of this mythical
animal that was 30 feet tall,
supposedly eight grizzly bears,
like I told you.
And like that was a camel
and ended up being a camel.
Yet people are just shooting them on site
because they didn't know what it was.
Is Is Lincoln pointed
out that steam power had already taken
the need for heavy animal power was just
gonna say the train. That's the railroad
system coming into play right there.
They like Lincoln was like, fuck you and
your elephants man. We've got trains,
dude. Yeah, I guess. But once the
battle actually starts a bunch of,
when you hear them trumpet,
like we were pretty close to one when it
led out like maybe within like 15 yards
and it just went
whoa. Serious animal. Real
life. That is so loud.
They're majestic, they have
such a presence. It was
raining out constantly there,
you know,
during the rainy season.
So this elephant was moving through
this unbelievably beautiful,
lush green landscape with like
fog and mist is fucking beautiful.
Huge tusks. And He lets out that
trumpet and you're like, whoa,
that's crazy animal man.
It's got to serious presence.
Being around a funny students just walk
right up to him, pat it and touch it.
Like they were really well cared for it.
But we went to a tiger.
San was just gonna say, do
you do the tiger though? To
the opposite of the Tigers.
That was not, I didn't like that at all.
They were drugged up or they had a knife
that was disturbed. Hey
gotta be man war. Well,
the guy's got a can on top of it.
He's going to another dog
and elephant and a fuck.
That's dude as a canon. A cannon. That's
a legit cannon as a civil war can.
And on the top of these got a machine
gun. Look it. He's got a 50 cal.
And what year is this?
This is a picture that shows
up with that yellow phones.
Wow. Dude. Fucking
elephants, man. Oh 50 cal.
Look at this thing. See? Wow. Look
at all the guns, guns and spears.
Who did all the shit.
And that's what I was talking about is
the shittiest way to see an army coming
towards you. Riding
elephants. That's like brave.
I like do not retreat.
Hold your ground. Fuck you.
There's such a peaceful
animals too. Yeah, it's such a,
they eat so much to,
you can't believe how much they eat.
Do they walk around in the streets?
A patio like a handle of we'll walk up
and down like the city streets just for
like, then they give you like fruit to
feed them like Papaya. They're like, hey,
you want to eat the elephant?
You like tip the guy and they're like,
you see like an elephant? Like walking
down the street through traffic and potty.
It's fucking weird.
Huh? That's cool though.
But every now and then you see
them just get pissed. Yeah.
Do you ever see like the
elephants gone wild videos?
They start tipping over cars
like the cardboard. I've seen the
stampede and the stopping
their trainers all pissed off.
Apparently they have a tigers
or wild in Thailand as well.
They really do have tigers.
You know the tiger is another,
another one of the time.
Do you think that it's maybe something
in their diet that protects them from
staff and from ringworm and all that
jazz in terms of the fighters? Yeah.
Perhaps
because they eat such spicy food is that
was wondering be related because they,
when I tell you to Thai spice,
like some of the kids from the camp
would literally be like dripping sweat,
like eating the spicy.
I like sweating like dripping
profusely like sweat and eaten food.
I was when I was like spicy food
and I told him to go hard. Yeah.
I said do it like you would do it.
Yeah.
How you like fucking juice it
up baby. Yeah, and they didn't,
they fucking, they, they still remember,
I remember one of the first
trip we had a Thailand.
I was with one of my buddies
then there were no Vietnam. We,
he ordered some dish and the ties
lake. No, that's, that's hot and spicy.
And he's like, no, that's all good.
Like, like, no, no, no, no, no.
That's really spicy lake. He's like, Nah,
no, it's good. I like speech, spicy food.
I'll just drink a lot of water, whatever.
He goes, AH, Ethan hot for Thai people.
And I was like, Bro, are you
listening to what he's saying?
They live in hot button, but he didn't
know any better and he went for it.
And I'm telling you bro, there was
three of us in a hotel room in Pattaya,
Thailand and I woke up in the middle of
night with to him fucking shooting ass,
piss ass soak the mattress,
the bed, the sheets.
He's found him in a ball
on the bathroom floor.
Do we have to take this kid to the
nearest hospital that he couldn't eat?
We had a ride them on the bike.
We had to ride three people.
One driving the kid in the middle and
me behind holding them up because he was
like out of it from spicy foods.
Dude,
he got so like she wasn't food
poisoning. No, no. It was just a spice.
Just kicked his ass so bad.
He probably burnt a hole like
an ulcer in his stomach. Dude,
he was in the hospital for
like three days on an ivy.
Got a bill for like fucking nine
bucks and we wrote that was a rap.
But he never eat the fucking same
dish again though. Spices. Yeah.
I don't fuck with this place is too much.
I love Thai food and I'll like,
I'll experiment with it,
but I'm not like,
if my mouth is so hot and I can't taste
the food, I don't enjoy it. I'm just like,
this is too much.
It seem right to me.
That seems like it would be more of a
food poisoning issue. It could have been,
but all I know is that I'll never forget
the smell of that hotel room that was
proven. You know, it's bad when
it soaks through the mattress. Oh,
the Thais do they fucking
flip it over next?
I remember my buddy rented a house,
like a little like village
house behind the camp and um,
this Australian guy was like, Hey,
you mates fucking pretty scrappier.
And I was like, what do you mean?
He's like, I'm hey lips rough man.
I know you like to do to tie
thing and you know, but you know,
he's got fucking money. You don't have
to live like a fucking bum, you know?
And I was like, all right, why?
What's up man? He's like, man,
the fucking house he's living in.
Man,
a fucking woman died of a fucking
snake bite, died in her fucking bed,
got bit by a snake and wait,
what? So I told my buddy, bro,
he flipped the mattress over.
It was fucking soak in blood.
They flip the mattress and they
fucking rent it to the next barn.
I like coming in
and I remember like literally like,
like literally like going to
visit him and like, you know, put,
taking your shoes off,
going in his little fucking one room hut
and then going to put my shoes on back
and he's like, shaky sneakers,
shake them out. I'm like, well,
I shake a fucking tarantula. Automate
sneakers. You got to shake you sneakers,
you got to shake your sneakers before
you go around. And in the morning.
That was one of the first things
I learned in Thailand. Dude,
at the first time I went to town, like
I was jumping on the ties, you know,
I didn't know if you're familiar with,
they have like a truck tire.
They lay down and they bounce on them. So
it's, yeah, it's great. What's that for?
It's literally like jumping rope cask
strength. It's like jumping rope,
but it's awesome because it's
not pounding on your joints.
So you get the bounce of the tire and
they just kind of alternate stance and you
bounce on the tire and it's like,
you know your warm up,
it's part of your warm up.
So I'm bouncing on the tires and there's
Jack Thai guy and it comes walking out
of the room and he grabbed a pair of
gloves and they usually put the laces over
the ropes. They hang the gloves
to dry over the ropes and he,
he's like mean as fuck, look. And he puts
his hand in the glove, he goes, put it,
he goes and he pulls his hand out in
a fucking tarantula, hit the ground.
Literally you could hear the weight
of the spider, like your link.
I heard it hit the cement,
like the weight of the spider in this
fucking thing moved so fast about,
covered about 12 feet in,
jumped up four feet into a heavy bag
and crawled in between the crack of the
leather of the heavy bag. And I was like,
what the fuck was that? My buddy goes,
oh, that's a, that's a a Birdie and
spider. And I was like, a bird eating.
Why do they call it up? Wait a minute,
it can fucking catch birds. I was like,
what the fuck is this?
Like?
And then literally every time I put my
gloves on that I always like peek in them
and like tap on it.
Like walk away and like look at the glove,
like kick the glove a little
bit. Like, all right ones good.
Let's try the other one on
like every morning, just like
shaking Scorpions, audio,
Gotti, sneakers and stuff.
Pretty tricky. Something
crazy. We never had a rat problem
here at all and we had nothing.
And then my dog was here one day.
Uh,
I brought the dog by and um,
then all the sudden we started
having rat problem we had.
And then Jamie looked it up and
rats are attracted to dossiers. Yes.
Yes. I thought that rats
eat it's dog shit. Yup.
I was just gonna say,
you gotta be the feces.
So we literally didn't have any
problem. And then Jamie was like, dude,
there's rat shit here. We found
ratchet and then, uh, Jeff,
the other guy works here, uh, found
a rat and killed it. Yeah. He,
he grabbed it by the tail. Ooh,
just smack that motherfucker.
How gangs does that?
Grabbed it by the tail tail,
poking out from behind a box
and he grabbed it and stopped it
because Marshall was running around here
that the rats smelled that the dog him
in there and they got in there,
let do this crazy dog dog tracks
rats because they'd like to eat it.
Plain and simple. In fact, dog poo,
this had to be the number one food
source for rats and developed areas. Wow.
Marshall didn't even shit in here.
Just the smell.
They might go to smell like smoke pissed.
He pissed outside and he accidentally
pissed in my gym and he lifted his leg to
pee on the rug box, the, you
know, step up box. And I go, hey,
cut the shit.
We're inside.
And then I took them outside
and then he finished his pissed.
So maybe the rat could smell the
rationale. That's fucked up though, man,
that was fucked up. I never
had a, I want to homework
like those rat terriers,
they have dogs of that shit though.
Wrapping a little rat terrier. I get
a few of those motherfuckers. Right.
Those little things. Things
never shut up. Yup, Yup, Yup.
They're go, go, go. My friend
Vicky Lewis from a news radio,
one of the actresses on news radio. She
had a Jack Russel. Yeah, there you go.
Great Dog. A big dog in a little
dog's body, like a huge attitude.
Like they step up to like big
mastiffs and fucking punk on the cool.
Then we'll do a little rat killers.
They're rat terriers, like the terrorist.
Did you ever see that documentary
on Netflix about rats? Horrific.
Really horrific in terms of infestation
gusting how many of them there are in
big cities. Like you realize like how,
what, what real issue is and my wife,
my wife freaks the fuck out if she sees
a fucking rat. She's smart. She's smart.
Well,
we had like a little incident.
We will fucking pocket a parking
garage on the 4th of July.
We parked the car and walking down and
walk the to watch the fireworks and she's
standing there and she fucking felt
something on her foot and she looked at
giant fucking rat. She went on
her fucking nail Polish. She
freaked the fuck out. Never been the
same. You literally like Mike, my son,
Dante always fucks it up. He's like, mom,
look a rat and she's fucking freaks
the fuck out, right? She's like,
that's not funny. Stop that
shit. And He, we all laugh at it.
It's fucking hilarious. Deathly
afraid of rats. Rats. A nasty dude.
They're so gross. That's a nasty in
the documentary that you saw this dog.
Don't they control something in terms
of population? They have like benefits.
They're good at keeping rat
populations high. That's about it.
What are they good for? The good for
cleaning up dog. Shit. That's nasty.
Even imagine that's their number
one source of food. It's gross.
What the fuck, man? He
must have horrible breath.
Creepy little survivor. Uh, but the,
the documentary on Netflix is brilliant.
It really got to check it out.
And one of one of the scenes,
they have these rat terriers tearing them
apart where they're digging into these
holes on the rats come out and the
dogs just grab them and mangle them.
That's what they're followup. Do
you think they're like, I'm just,
I just read something quickly
and it doesn't really say much.
You think they just like to
eat trash and they help us? No,
don't do that. They control some
population. They, they're good.
They gotta be good for fucking something.
I know this is an ecosystem, right?
Exactly. Every animal has its little
spot. Do we get the Big Boston rats?
They literally like,
they fucking punk cats.
They look like they're like the
size of like a possum. They like,
there's survived bigger than like any
jacked up squirrel or anything like that.
They're just big,
big,
the triangle tails like asti
after survivor cat rats,
rather their deer out in the cold winter
and then figure out a way to get the
fucking Boston rats.
I get accents and shit
like fucking scally cap
running around eating dog shit.
Do you ever think about Bailyn the
fucking winters there and everything?
Does it get to you all the
time? All the time. Yeah. I
mean, my parents are elderly,
like I got to keep an eye on them and all
my family's in Boston and my
businesses in Boston. But you know,
luckily I travel a lot, so it's kind of
like the, the vent, you know what I mean?
I get away and I'll fucking do like a
day or two on a beach somewhere at a UFC
event, like, and, and that'll
be like a little recharge.
But man, I'm, as I get older,
I never really was like,
you know,
overwhelmed with winters until I started
getting older. And now I'm like, do it.
My body hurts, my muscles ached,
my joints ache, the cold's nasty.
Especially that New England cold man.
And it's like wet cold. It's so long.
You've got the fuck out. And I remember
we talked about this, you're like,
fuck winter, fuck snow. Like fuck
that. Well, here's the thing,
I like some places where it gets cold.
Like I love Colorado.
I remember you lived there for a little
bit. Yeah, I would move back there.
Jamie and I have talked about it.
That shit gets different cold though.
It's like the fine. Yeah, it's not as
bad as like the New England winters,
so it's like wet, nasty four wheel
drive, snow tires, warm clothes,
fireplace.
Archery's do it.
It's just it Colorado. It's sunny.
That's the other thing. Good point.
Colorado's sunny like 300 plus
days a year. Boston. Yeah,
months with that crazy shit.
And this guy,
we don't see past the clouds now.
I never seen nothing.
Just just a dog gray blanket
hanging over your head follows you around.
The women,
the attitude they have like
when are you going to do for me?
It was just the, you wonder why they're
like this. Fucking miserable. Yeah.
But I'll tell you what though.
Boston in the summer,
I love Boston this summer that, oh, it's
amazing. When is like the sun's out,
guns out. Everybody's running around
girls addressing half dressed.
Somebody looks happy. Exactly.
Like everybody's happy.
Everybody's chose Boston in the summer
was cool. I liked Boston and I'm, I'm a,
I'm a Boston native.
I always will be true and true,
but definitely not a fan of the
windows and I've got to bail someday.
I'll probably, yeah. Where are you going
to go? Come about question possibly.
Mm hmm. You're looking
for work. You hiring?
Listen, I was going to hire a
Moitai coach. Started up a gym.
I like it located a few times. They
could use one out here. Honestly.
Yeah. There's not like a real dedicated
more time Jim anywhere near me. Yeah,
I got offers, you know,
obviously like working, you know,
for the company and whatnot, you know,
some offers to move to Vegas and whatnot.
And at first I was like, Fuck
Vegas, I'm never living in Vegas.
But then I started hanging around with
like the right people and like Henderson,
oh dude. Out of Summerlin, like,
like Lorenzo lives, like hanging out,
going to like football games at Lorenzo
and a fan. Like, dude, it's like families,
little kids riding bikes down the street.
It's like it's normal. It felt normal.
Like Summerlin, Summerlin and
Vegas felt normal to me. Like,
I felt like I could actually live
in Summerlin. Like, you know,
the thing about it is I need to be
near the ocean, all connected to the,
the Evil Dick of Vegas.
You know,
it's so like all the ges comes
out of the Dick and Amy hours,
full feed economies. Those
communities wouldn't be so true. No,
you're absolutely right. The casino.
You're absolutely right, man.
The worst is seeing like the locals like
get their check on Fridays and they go
right to the fucking casino and they
just blow through it. Fucking sad to see.
Man. Biggest is a fucking weird place too.
And I'm, I'm way over Vegas. People like,
Oh, you want to Vegas? It's fucking
awesome doing it had been, I'm like, dude,
it's not an awesome about fucking,
the good parts are really good.
Like the restaurants are really,
absolutely.
Vegas has some of the best restaurants.
They still have 24 hour pool hall.
I was just gonna say, that's one thing
that I like about Vegas. It's not,
nothing's ever close.
You want to fucking Burger,
it's fucking four o'clock in the wind
and go fucking get a burger somewhere.
You want to go out, you want to
have a drink, you want to play pool.
Like we've done many a times like
late at night, middle of night.
That's what I love about it.
I'm a night owl for sure.
Like I don't sleep well
at night. Like if, if,
if I were to choose like
just to like operate the lake
from, from uh, the sunset,
like sundown to Sunup, like,
and then sleep all day.
Like I would like other than laying in
the sun, like I'm a night owl for sure.
But that's the one thing I do like
about Vegas. So I said nothing.
Nothing's difficult. Feel weird. Like
why can't I buy a drink at 3:00 AM? Yeah,
exactly. Why do you, why? How come I can't
have a beer when I want to have a beer.
I had grown man. Yeah, exactly.
Everybody gets crazy. Yeah.
That's what's going up at the
time. Or like we tell you, look,
you've got to go to bed.
Yeah.
As if it's going to like give us
structure and like teach us lessons,
but I guess it's does, it does,
right? Like the gambling thing,
the thing about gambling as if gambling
was everywhere, then it would normalize.
Right. But it's not everywhere. It's just
in a couple spots. So when you get to it,
that's when people are
like up playing cards.
If fucking morning bleary-eyed
Betten their mortgage. Yeah.
Pumping oxygen into the casino, show
many people go there and lose everything.
Everything they had. I can't even fathom
that. Like it happens all the time.
You see it? No, not really.
You know what I mean? I'll,
I'll entertain and play
like some blackjack or
something like that if like my
buddy's a plan, but I'm
not really, like, I don't,
I don't go out of my way to gamble.
I like that.
I was just gonna say the same thing.
I like bet and fights.
I like doing stuff like that. I just,
whatever, best with friends, whatever.
But then fights just makes
it more interest. Absolutely.
Yeah. Like, you know,
like yeah, give me a 50 bucks on this.
And then while you're watching it,
you're like, come on. Exactly.
Yes. And then you agree,
you always feel real sneaky when
you get a shit decision. Your like,
we won that one. You deserve it.
You know, my buddy, one of my, uh,
one of the guys I train Rico to shoe low,
he bets fights and he is fucking spot on
man. He doesn't miss. He said, I'll do it.
He can. I literally, I can sell
it in between cause I, you know,
Marion and the truck, I'm
always bet. And what Marin,
we're always just like betting
on fights and uh, I just,
I go right to my buddy Rico. I'm
like, Rico, he got well you're like,
did you consult on about this weekend?
Ah,
yes and he was spot on with every
flight except for one, I think. Uh, uh,
Nicola Mateo, Sa Niccolo, who,
uh, got caught by a Dustin Ortiz,
I think that was the only fight he missed.
That was crazy head
kick. It was man. And he
set it up nice to you.
Set it up real nice because you know, he,
it almost looked, it was like delayed.
It's like, it's almost like one speed and
then it, and then it changed direction.
It changed us speed and he went high with
it. He set it up good and it was done.
Not a question mark kick
but like to the middle,
bring that and then you went up high.
Take a peek at that because it's like
he was establishing like a low kick at
first and then it's almost like he went
to look like it was going to throw a
head, a low kick, and then he
changed the speed of the kick.
I called them the like the delay.
If you delay the kick and you change
the timing of the, of the kick,
it's hard to read.
That's how we caught them.
You actually had a glove up
to oddly enough, but it went
right through the glove.
You know, it was a, doesn't look good
though, man. You look good. Yeah, yeah.
He's a stud, you know? Yeah. He really is.
Well they need people at
that weight class. You know,
who the fuck is there this
weekend? Yeah. Who's, who's there,
you know, good question. I mean, unless
TJ comes down or Cody comes down,
depending upon who wins this fight.
Yeah.
Apparently they can both make the
weight and that's another thing too,
wasn't Demetrius concern with that?
He's going to commit to having a fight
with one of them and then go through a
full camp and then they miss wait
and then fuck. So he said like, yes,
take a fight. Yeah, I agree with
that a hundred percent yeah, I do,
but I don't think they would miss weight.
Those guys are super professional.
Both of them are and and TJ dirty already
said he'd made the wait before. Wow.
He's tried it. Yeah. Yeah.
He's got an interesting,
well he seems smaller than he used
just going to say. Yeah, he's,
he's definitely a lot leaner than he
used to be. You know? Is this it here?
What part of the fight you want me
to get to? Dante's little thing.
Just a knockout itself to finish the
Dustin Ortiz finish against them.
Mateus Niccolo was it? This
is a chick fight, dude.
You don't know what you're doing.
Crazy son of a bitch.
That kid a Mateus though.
Niccolo. He trained,
he came through the gym through a
couple of my Brazilian students,
a Sabal and Rodrigo and here it is.
He a, this kid's tough man. So Dustin,
those impressive when you know,
yeah, I mean there are literally are,
see how it kind of delayed.
Do you see that kind of back again?
He changes speed in the kick.
I noticed that in the replay when we were
calling them. I was like, look at this.
How he does it. Let's see here.
Yeah, that's right. A lot.
She's watched the speed change.
You see in the beginning.
That's what made it difficult to read.
It's kind of like came up at
a weird angle. Yeah, it did.
It came up like at a 45 degree
angle. Yeah. He won't let go. Nope.
Did he bonus for this fight? I don't
know. I forget who I do not like bonuses.
I do not like when bonuses
that don't like them.
I don't think cause I don't think you
should be paid more to when everyone's
trying to win.
I don't think you should lose because
of fucking judge who has no idea what
they're talking about. Look, he be
blocked that fairly decent. Yeah,
he had the glove up and still got chaos
right through. It just got rocked.
I don't, I don't think, especially
since they haven't dealt well at all
with the judging issue.
I mean they really have done a terrible
job with judging these state commissions.
Yeah, there's so much bad judging.
So if you have three people at the,
I think the system sucks.
I think the judging system itself,
the 10 point must system is outdated.
It's not right for MMA.
It's great for boxing.
It's not good for MMA.
I think it needs to be revamped and
restructured and I think it should be a
completely different system.
And then I think on top of that,
the judges are in competent.
There's so much in competence
is what those factors.
And then you have wind bonuses.
So you have bad decisions all the time
and normal with these bad decisions,
you give a wind bonus to the wrong person
and the wrong person gets fucked over.
You know? And the, the swing is half the
pay and that the level of the pay scale,
it's just like they're already
making fucking peanuts. Yeah.
And if you're not making peanuts,
it costs you more.
Could cost you a hundred grand
cost even more than that.
If you make one 51 50 and then you
should have won a fight and you lost,
you lost $150,000 because it was three
people are in competence. Exactly.
Cause they did a fucking eight hour
course on a Saturday. Never fucking put,
they don't care. This is the thing.
They're not, they're not fans.
They just do that because that's their
job. It's a cool job. Yeah. It's,
tell the boys it's cool job.
There are some judges that,
that do know what they're doing. So then
I, this is a small handful. There is,
there is, yeah. And they have to, they
have to helicopter the men. Pretty much.
It's a crazy system.
The system of badly needs to be updated.
I don't understand why they haven't, it
just doesn't make any sense to me. Um,
what you owe me,
but I don't like the wind bonus thing bad.
I just think you should get paid.
You should,
it should be a flat rate like it
is in boxing. You know, it just,
I don't think it incentivizes people
to fight harder. I don't believe that.
I think the winners are always going to
try to win. You know, I don't and I think,
and it's like I said about fighting,
like don't, don't fight technical.
You go out there and you let
it all hang out. Don't do that.
Do you get to have a nice short
career if you do that? True.
And that's what happens to those guys.
It's good for the business.
It's good for the company. It's good for
the, the, the, that night, the views,
the boy, the people are watching. It
will be little bit more entertaining,
but you're not going to make it.
You're going to,
you're going to leave half
your brain in that octagon.
It's another thing to have.
And we talk about that all the time too,
is that seeing that these guys
take trauma the way they do, man,
Todd to watch man, as much as we've, we've
spoke about this briefly in the past,
but uh,
you know,
as much as a fan as I am and as
involved as I am in the sport, man,
it's hard to watch sometimes fancy.
And these guys take the damage they do.
You know, I remember like I told you,
I think I told you the story before,
Marcus Davis, after his fight, coincident
laying off, I believe with Chris Lidell,
he lost his sense of smell for
like seven months. He couldn't,
he couldn't smell them. And I
told you about this, but you know,
he couldn't smell like anything, which
means you can't taste. So like he would,
he'd be like, Bro, I smell like shit. And
like people would have to tell me like,
Bro, you fucking stank. And then it'd be
like, I put on too much call and be like,
Bro, easy on the Cologne.
Like he had no clue. Like,
you know, he couldn't taste like
lemonade. Tastes like fucking fruit punch.
He had no fucking clue.
He had no sense of smell
or taste for seven months.
Imagine that he's, it came back,
he had lit thank God it did. Yeah,
but he even said, I was like, what'd
you, what'd you miss the most like,
and he's like the smell of my
daughter's hair. And I was like, Whoa,
that's fucking trippy dude. And he
counts check please. Like I'm all set.
And he kept fighting it too.
And that was, that was on,
I don't want to say early in his career,
but maybe halfway through.
Well he again came from that school
of hard knocks and Boston Charlie bar.
Exactly. Yup. Hard sparring.
Hard training and does what I was saying
about Jeremy Stevens earlier two to
bring it all back around.
Jeremy spars hard. You know,
I was talking to Jocko about it. It's
like, you know, Jeremy's and animal.
I remember, I remember discussing that
with Lorenzo back in the day as a,
he went to Brazil when they were
doing the Aldo pieces and whatnot,
and he went to Nova
and down. He said, man,
these fucking guys kill each
other in the gym. He's like this.
It's like literally like there are 100%
head hunting trying to kill each other.
I don't agree with that at
all. Obviously. It's horrible.
And there's so many guys that get really
badly rocked on their way to fights.
Yeah. Oh yeah. All the time.
It's like sometimes like if a,
if a guy takes a big punch, like, and
he gets a flash k o like in, in uh,
in the gym. Like if we got to pull
them from a fight because of that,
because he's affected at that point.
It's like still this residual, like the,
you know, mean it's still
lingering. No way around it.
No way around it, man. Yeah.
I even had like a, a student in
mind. My Guy, Tommy ended up, ah,
he had gotten a car
accident, you know, like a,
a week before his fight and this
kid's got a granite Chin and he got,
he got caught like, and we attributed
to the impact of the car crash.
Like we said,
it had to have been like you suffered
some head trauma cause he hit his head in
the car crash and he was susceptible.
He was vulnerable to the Kol
because of the trauma that he took.
So you're taking big punches in the gym
like that and then you go on on fight
night, it's that much easier for you
to get likes out, you know the percent.
But it's so hard to make a tough elite
fighter without subjecting them to
exactly what you see. Like Robbie
Lawler, like, like he's talked about,
he doesn't inspire anymore.
Like,
well he didn't for a long did it
take when you went to att? Okay.
But for a long time he didn't like all
through his strike force Craig Ryan's bar,
which seems crazy. Like I already know
how to fight. I'm not going to argue.
It was going to say that boy can't fight.
You can't fucking flight deck.
I know he's had a lot of fun,
a lot of tough fights.
That's why I was so impressive
with Rafael dos Anjos did to him.
It's like dos Anjos just sort of
dismantled. I didn't see that coming.
And then Colby Covington and
Mandel dos Anjos so I was like,
what in the hell?
He took them apart to gas
tank for today's list.
Fucking pressure. I got the hired watching
the fight. I was gas in the truck.
Like meanwhile Dosantos
known for his cardio.
He's wanting Nickerson's pupils. So
he's like, you know, trains in that mob.
Marinovich honestly like around
the second round, I was like,
there's no way he can keep this pace up.
He's got a fade and he never
fucking hate it. He never faded.
Do you see him hand the, the Bolt Josh
Rob, I was looking at it on the way here.
I was looking at it. I was like, this
is crazy. It said something like an MTV.
Jackie Lake he comes through
with is as, as uh, as stated.
He comes through with us was going to
bring the belt to white out fucking Donald
Trump.
What a strapple so funny man.
Maggot hat on the red hat on.
Dude.
He's fucking sold it man.
He has miss.
You got to remember early and
Colbys career. He wasn't like that.
He wasn't like that. He just figured
it out. Where'd he come from?
I know he's had 18 again, but wait,
where was he trying to before? Att?
That's a good question.
I do not know cause he kinda loud when
I say came out of nowhere like he earned
his way in but he really liked
it was like, oh I love it.
It's so funny that a red hat with
white letters can get you punched now.
I mean they could say anything.
What? This girl had a hat on,
it said make bitcoin great again and
they fucking, they, what's that spray?
What's the make America great again.
Yeah,
but on the red hat with white letters
is racist now be a Nazi flag to some
people. But this, this gun so
crazy. It is crazy right now.
Topsy Turvy world we're living in
and flags and shit. Ridiculous. Well,
listen brother, we got
to get out of here. Yeah.
We can go away and spend to the Wayne's,
is it three o'clock today, right?
I believe so. Three o'clock
in the Orpheum. Yeah.
And it's probably a three hour drive to
take karate. Sit. Y'All Tang in Boston.
Tell people how they can get
to your gym. Look me up, man.
Facebook of the very best boy tied gyms
and MMA gyms on the planet earth and
it's in Somerville. Uh,
spell it. S. I. T. Y. O. D.
O. T. O. N. G. See y'all Tang. Yes.
And it's in Boston, Massachusetts.
Awesome. Don't sleep.
Markdale grotty. Love you buddy. I
love you, Bro. Absolutely rise to it.