Her low freak bitches about um,
these Nazi furries like Neo Nazi furries.
Well,
the absurd obscure a subculture of
furries has a problem with mean any,
any groups of sexual
abuse and a lot of Nazi,
I mean,
cut the fucking shit.
Please just please cut the shit.
Please,
please.
I can't,
I can't keep going.
It's just too crazy.
Every day it's more
and more fucking weird.
This stuff I can get,
I think this is the same people that
watch those youtube videos or make the
youtube videos.
I think the people who
make the youtube videos,
dude,
I think it's just like they're,
they're in Asia or somewhere like that
and they have a script and they just keep
throwing the script over and over and
we're looking for like hidden messages in
the script.
I think the script is
probably just fucked up.
They think it's fucked up to have a
cartoon character hit himself in the head
with a bottle and I think
you're probably right.
Like maybe these fucking child predators,
maybe they communicate on all
sorts of different websites.
Maybe they just decide like,
hey,
let's meet on this tire forum and we'll
just say things in code and attire means
this.
I mean,
it wasn't that always
the shit with pizza gate,
like they thought that
they were talking in code.
Like all the conspiracy theorists thought
that a slice of pizza meant like a kid
and the youtube one,
I mean them being there being so many of
them sort of says that there's money in
it.
They've tapped into the algorithm
and they're just beating it to death.
Yeah,
and they just have the same script and
they just do it with a computer change.
One little thing,
a little thing here and there
and that's what I think it is.
I think it's not as nefarious
as everybody likes to thank,
but it's really fucking weird to keep
seeing the same video playing out over and
over again with a bottle flies through
the hair and the baby gets hit in the
fucking head.
And utilities,
I think the activity was a little weird
or when it's people actually people
doing it,
you can't just grab a computer,
make it to where people are.
God damn nuts.
They're nuts and they're out there.
I like furries.
Uh,
I get that.
I have a bunch of outfits that I make
videos with and stuff and that's pretty
much what that is.
That's just ice ugly cross play.
Like a role play.
Yeah.
They're having fun yet having fun.
They don't feel like normies right,
I say,
right?
Yeah.
And I'm sure having sex like that,
it's probably fine.
That's Kinky.
Like,
hey,
you're dressed up as my
pretty pony and I'm Spiderman.
Yeah.
Probably a lot of that.
A lot of dude on dude crime
other wearing these hats.
They're wearing fucking weird animal hats
and their bone in each other and hey,
why not man be know why?
Because this is crazy.
So why not?
Why to do it?
Why not do it?
See,
look at that.
Just like a Fox and your fucking each
other in a fox is fucking the chicken.
Why not?
Why?
Really?
Why not?
I just,
I don't know.
Why not?
I can't tell you.
Why not.
Why is it okay that people were crazy
fake eyelashes and extensions in their
hair and they pumped fat into their ass
and put silicone bags and their tits?
Why is that okay,
but it's not okay to dress like a big
chicken and get fucked by a big rooster.
Why isn't it,
why can't you pretend to be
like a fox in the hen house,
right?
Why not?
Like if as long as everybody agrees,
like,
do you agree to be the Fox?
Okay,
cool.
I want me to pull the dog.
I'm going to be the bulldog mascot,
the big bulldog head
and we're going to bone.
They're going to make some,
some Ron Davis.
Why the fuck not
have you seen the movie?
I hadn't,
it wouldn't work down during the movie.
I still didn't like him during the movie.
They asked him,
they asked him.
Do you have any,
uh,
good recollections of when you see
t growing up when he's trying to,
do you have any fond
recollections of you and cts?
You know,
as a kid and I,
boy,
I was looking at them jobs
waiting now where I really,
I really want to hear if he was
going to fabricate something,
right?
Because I didn't have man.
And I'm like,
oh,
I want to see with this month are going
to say that this questionnaire and he
didn't have anything.
And I was like,
okay,
cool.
You know,
a loans.
But I was ready to stop the fucking
movie and just make an ass out of myself.
And like,
no,
that's bull shit.
We ain't mad.
You ain't one fucking time that we
ever did anything pleasurable together,
motherfucker and was very go off.
But he didn't have any.
So when he didn't have any files,
okay.
Now that's the same recollection
that I hadn't done it,
but I really didn't forgive him
until this last heart attack in June.
And what happened then when I had the
heart attack in June and it seemed like,
uh,
revelation came to me and he was like,
I'm,
it's not hurting him.
It's not hurting him at all.
My Dad is 86 years old.
He's fine,
man.
He,
he's,
I don't,
he's like,
well,
you know,
I don't think he thinks that he
has anything to be sorry for that.
I think he thinks he's,
he's done a fantastic job of raising me.
And,
uh,
I was just waiting on the policy
who was never going to come,
but I,
but it was still that hate that
I have for him was eating me up.
I had to get that burden off me.
And I think having that labs harder,
I didn't want to die carrying that
burden with me of hating my dad.
So I went to my dad and I
asked him to forgive me.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Damn.
How did you say that?
What did you,
what did you say?
I said,
you know,
look,
Dad,
I have blamed you.
I told him that I had recently had a
heart attack and I have blamed you my
entire life for a whole lot of things
that went bad or when you know that I
always blamed you fix and,
and,
um,
and I'm sorry.
Uh,
know I don't,
you know,
I don't want to blame me for that anymore.
And would you please forgive me
for carrying this against you from,
you know,
my whole life.
I don't want to die,
you know,
letting you think that you know,
I love you man,
and I want you to know that.
Wow.
Yeah.
How good does that feel?
I can't,
I don't wake up punching,
see any anymore.
I probably be out of
breath if I date anyway,
but I don't wake up with those night.
I haven't had that nightmare since then.
Wow.
Yeah.
How did he react to that?
He was,
he was a fully accepting of my iPod.
Pete grace me,
you know,
he was graciously accepted.
My apology.
So yeah,
because I have zero
musical talent or zero.
Have you ever tried to actually
hold a tune trying to just try this,
try to sing all serious.
Don't laugh.
Try to sync.
Just look at me.
It's embarrassing.
But do it.
Try to sing.
I won't sing silent night.
Holy night.
Try to hit it then do it right
and then I'm going to try it.
It's so hard.
So nervous.
It's so vulnerable.
I'm asking you to think two verses,
but isn't it funny that like
making noises with your mouth?
It's vital?
Nah.
Oh really?
It's not bad.
Oh,
this
copy that was spring.
Can you get a little power?
Oh,
where's Bra
drought?
What's the rest?
I don't know.
Thinking heavenly peace.
Holy infant.
So tender and mild.
Oh,
so,
eh,
when the PE,
I went immediately to the dish bag,
singer voice that whispery I know,
but you,
but you know what you had on tuned.
Do I think you were,
he was tuned,
wasn't he?
Yeah.
You know what I used to do two though.
I only,
I only told Collin Quinn distillery.
Oh,
when I grew up in these apartments,
Pembrook apartments in
Prince George's county,
Maryland,
there was this one bullied,
uh,
who would steal people's bikes and shit
and he would start fights and whatever.
And so I had,
I played sports,
I,
you know,
so one of my trophies broke and my
mom took me to some place to fix it.
And I did not know that there was a
place that existed when I just thought
trophies appeared.
You know,
I mean,
as a kid you just get shot,
right.
So when I saw this was the spot,
what I used to do,
because I was saving my allowance and I
would go to the trophy spot and buy like
a karate trophy,
just walk around the neighborhood just
long enough for this one dude to see me
who I knew would be like the town crier.
And I would always act
embarrassed about it.
Like,
Oh,
you don't understand yet.
And that's how we talk.
We say young and stuff.
And then when my mother got
me taking karate and shit,
I'm wanting to stay with them.
Oh,
you,
you wanna cry you nights like that.
Don't tell nobody,
man,
I ain't gonna say shit.
And then I would see.
So then,
uh,
and then like,
you know,
a couple of months ago by,
I go by and by a little bigger too.
Dude never messed with me.
He never met.
Thank God.
No one was like,
oh,
I could fight,
but I did.
You know what I'm saying?
But it was like the word got out enough
because nobody knew what I'm saying.
Like if you heard a d
a Dude Dicker Ronnie,
that was enough.
Like you didn't want to get embarrassed.
So he gave me like free passage to do,
to be my corny self be out.
You know?
That's a very clever way of handling it.
That's what I did when I saw that store.
I was like,
and this the piece of whom
they would like five bucks,
seven bucks,
three bucks,
and then we'll go put it on,
and then someone was
acting at an early age.
There's all of that shit.
I said,
I know where he going to be.
As soon as he saw me,
I'd go back and I also,
I didn't want him like a big,
you know what I mean?
That's very clever.
Okay.