Eagle right out your door and in the
most awesome hiking spot ever.
And we're live,
ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you.
Thank you for joining MPR.
Uh,
please,
no,
I don't want to do that.
Brotzmann Jeff Evans,
but Brotzmann good friend of mine,
next door neighbor and uh,
Jeff Heavens,
his buddy who,
uh,
apparently has lived a fucking crazy
life rescuing people off of Everest,
traveling up there and bud told me we
were at this little carnival with our
kids.
It's like,
got to get this guy on.
Got To talk to him.
So no pressure.
Yeah.
Your arm got put by hunch your
shoulders.
No,
it didn't.
It sounded good.
I was interested in this asshole on how
did you get involved with,
first of all,
when was the first time you summited
everest?
2001.
God Damn Man.
How many times you've done it?
Just once.
Just put good on how to get a 1.5 cars
out of blonde dude with me.
Yeah.
So you took a blind dude all the way to
the top.
Why didn't you take them like halfway?
Yeah.
Below it is face.
Dude,
you made it.
You're one of the rare ones.
The funny part was we got to the top and
we were like,
man,
we could see the curvature of the earth
from here,
Bro.
When he goes,
I don't give a shit.
Like I want to get out of here.
I can't see anything I want to go.
That's actually not true.
What he said is,
Hey Eric,
take a look around,
take a look around instinctual or were
you just fucking with them?
I mean,
I think it was a little bit of both.
I kind of instinctively fuck with him.
Right.
Um,
we've been bros for a long time.
I mean,
it's a very fraternal relationship that
we have.
So I by nature,
just sort of automatically fuck with
this guy.
I know I'll enjoy it and he enjoys it
back because he is super blonde dude.
Right?
Know the whole world,
loves,
loves him.
Some.
Eric,
and I'm probably one of the few people
that just kick him in the nuts,
you know,
giving a little bit of a hard time.
Yeah.
If you're a blind to the climbs Mount
Everest people just give you a free
pass,
a lot of stuff,
and suddenly that he claimed.
What else do you claim?
Well,
he's done a bunch of stuff,
but he just kayaked the Grand Canyon two
years ago in his own boat,
the whole thing.
277 miles.
What did you have a guy behind him going
left?
Right,
left,
right.
They had,
you know,
these ear pieces and you know,
he asked me to go,
I'll climb everest,
but I sure it's fucking,
I'm going to take you down the Grand
Canyon.
There's something that people really
love about someone risking their life
and then pulling it off.
Right.
Something,
assuming you pull it off.
Yeah.
Assuming,
yeah.
If you don't,
then you make one of those instagram
greatest fails.
Yeah.
They were telling us before we went up
there,
like,
you know,
blind who's going to die and when he
does,
what'd you think was gonna Happen?
They were telling me.
Oh yeah,
we heard that.
The sherpas are who?
No,
no.
Just the Everest experts.
You know,
this member,
this is back in oh one this was whenever
it was Sushi.
Yes.
Two little bit.
Little bit more raw than it is now.
How is that?
What,
what has happened?
Because on the outside,
what I've seen is all the expos,
a's that show all the human waste that
they leave behind and including actual
shit,
right?
Tents and people pay people to kind of
do all the hard work and then you just
kind of show
up and still hard.
Right?
But not as hard.
You got to put in,
you know,
you've got to put it in his steps.
We've got to put in the work.
But it's so commercialized that it's
been,
it's been diluted to a certain extent.
And you know,
I'm,
I am a Sherpa advocate to the core,
you know,
these guys do the work.
I mean they put it in every single day
there humping the loads.
They're cooking the food,
they're setting the lines there,
they're taking the biggest risk and then
allowing,
you know,
other folks to move through a little bit
more effectively and faster and not have
to expend as much energy.
And so over the we Kinda,
we kinda got in there and no one towards
I think,
I think on the head ahead of the curve
just a little bit as to when it started
to sort of change the face of Everest
changed a little bit.
So how did they make it easier?
Like what do they do that made it more
commercial?
Yup.
Um,
no money number one gets in there and,
and pays a lot more sherpas to do a lot
more work.
Um,
so the lines are fixed.
The weather forecasting models are more
effective and more efficient and say the
lines are fixed and the lines are fixed,
meaning the ropes,
the ropes on the mountain.
Oh,
there's fixed Dan,
you clip in.
Yeah,
you clip into a rope so when you go up,
okay.
So the ropes are there.
Before you get there,
all you have to do is just kind of like
huff it.
So it's not like before.
So you kind of,
wow,
that's weird.
So it's almost like you're on like a
theme park,
like an Everest.
It's,
you're still an everest and you still
could get fucked up by an avalanche.
Right?
There's no question.
It's very dangerous.
There's no way to mitigate all of that.
But you know,
it's uh,
it,
it has been,
it has been eased up a little bit.
The edges have been taken off just a
slight bit,
but it also adds that they're dangerous
because one of them,
if I was looking at it,
it's sometimes more dangerous now
because there's lines,
there's sometimes 300 people,
600 people in a line and you're waiting
from some asshole who didn't train and
you're watching him trying to climb up
this little 20 foot cliff and they don't
know how to work at Gmr.
They can't climb.
What's a Jew Mar to hand to hand things
in the sending device.
It's like a one way of sending device to
go up a rope so you can slide it up and
it catches on the way down pull.
But there people go up there.
And when we were up there,
they had people,
they've literally,
without talking shit about tracking
companies,
there are some companies like,
all right,
we're going to show you how to put your
crampons,
um,
as you're going in the icefall if she
christ.
Yeah.
They've,
they've learned like we're going to
learn,
we're going to,
they've never had crampons before.
We had to Jeff,
not me.
Jeff had to rescue risk his life and
helicopters going to high,
high altitude to pick up people who
shouldn't no business on the mountain.
So they didn't manage to get their body
acclimated.
Is that what the issue is?
They didn't put in the the
apprenticeship cause you know,
and nowadays the commercial component
allows folks that have enough money to
pay and then show up and get guided
basically to the top.
So back in the day it was,
you know,
if you didn't have your teeth cut,
you,
uh,
you know,
it was on you.
And nowadays you can just show up and,
and you know,
generally someone will be taken care of
you whether it's a god or whether it's a
Sherpa.
Uh,
and so yeah,
it's,
it's changed.
Um,
but you know,
I don't,
I don't want to take anything from the
folks who still go out there.
It's a dream for so many people,
you know,
and it's still an aspiration and a in a,
in a life goal for,
you know,
a lot of folks and it's still very
difficult.
And so for instance,
last year we just saw,
I mean we saw a really nice cross
section of,
of skilled,
experienced climbers trying it,
but then we saw a shit show,
you know,
we saw a lot of folks who should have
been on other peaks first and then they
weren't,
they skipped to the top,
you know,
you know anything in life,
you,
you bypass the work and you get smoked.
Yeah.
And we did a,
we,
our rescue team,
ars rescue team,
our five Sherpas did the highest
altitude rescue in history at 28,500 off
the balcony and a girl,
husband.
And wife.
I don't know if they did.
Did she summit?
I don't think she summited though.
Um,
as she was coming down the summit,
some of the 29 35,
she's at 28,
500 and she decided to sit down.
Husband left her,
she's tapped out.
How's the left foot?
People quit.
So she sat down,
but she sat down and he left her.
Yeah.
Oh wait,
there's more to that story.
So he left her and then we go rescue.
Or should he say,
sit right here.
I'll come back in a couple of days.
This is up for questions.
It's like there,
there's two ways to look at,
we were talking about this last night
was she may have just been a tap out
bitch and just said,
I quit.
And he tried to employ,
please come out,
come out,
come on.
And finally just left her.
That's one scenario.
The other scenario is,
um,
you know,
he just was like,
peace out.
Good luck.
I'm out.
Here's the problem.
I do it this way and I understand about
diving.
So let's say you and I are diving.
We're 300 feet below the blow the water
right and my air goes out and I know we
can buddy breathe,
but let's pretend there's nobody
breathing and you're going to stick
around and watch me die and you're gonna
end up dying or I'm going to grab a hold
of you and grab your regulator and
you're,
we're both going to die.
You can't help anybody at that level.
You can't,
you're,
you're tired.
Your body is eating itself.
You're basically dying in the death
zone.
He could explain that basically.
And if your,
if your wife says,
I'm sitting down,
I'm going to get up in five minutes,
you go ahead and she's got a Sherpa with
her and then you go,
I go ahead and you get back to camp
four,
which is exactly what happened.
Get down to camp four and look around
you.
Why it's not there.
Holy Shit.
And then they call us and they wake jeff
and I up and were like,
you're going to what?
So I was,
I was with her right at base camp when
she,
when we delivered her to her husband and
I was trying to gauge like,
is he going to be one of these guys?
It's like,
oh my God,
I'm so glad you're alive.
Or Holy Shit,
she's alive.
Fuck.
You know.
And I think it was the former,
I think he was really ecstatic.
He was crying.
Remember?
He was really,
he was really upset.
But then hold on all they'd say,
no,
no.
It goes back because actually the first
first kick in the balls,
so without taking the whole thing to
this.
So what had to happen is,
as Jeff and I and our base camp manager,
Anthony had to take for Sherpas from
camp to or can't for,
took two Sherpas and then two more in
the middle of the night.
So six o'clock,
seven o'clock at night,
the most dangerous type winds are
blowing 30 40 miles an hour.
It's 20 degrees below zero.
Nobody,
nobody's ever done.
You don't do it.
And we sent them up there and we said,
can you go get her?
Oh God.
So,
and you've got to find this person on
the line.
So they walked and they kept walking and
they kept walking.
And we have video.
Remember meagan was video.
How long does it take to get up the
line?
Like how normal normal human being you,
the three of us,
how long would it take for three of us
to get from the south call to where she
was pro three or four hours if you're in
shape.
So take me out of that because I'm not a
runner.
Yeah.
But I'm not doing any high altitude
hiking.
Gimme five hours.
Okay.
So,
so it's like very dangerous.
Extremely dangerous.
Especially at night.
At the worst.
Getting it out.
Yeah.
At the worst time.
Not even no one,
no one knows where she is now,
but the terrain dictates that she has to
be,
unless she's fallen off the side,
she's on a spine basically.
And,
and you know,
if you go up the ridge,
you're either going to find her if she's
alive or she's tossed off the side.
So she,
and also she's dealing with super low
air,
no air squeezing,
extremely cold.
Nowhere bringing third of what you got
from,
they bring tanks.
Yeah.
But her era was gone.
So you're drinking your,
your,
she brought no air with her or she
brought with her.
She's done.
She was abandoned basically.
So they left her.
So you know,
generally you would have somebody with
an extra tank to be able to help her
out.
But I get the sense that she just said
I'm done.
And she sat down and everybody tried to
kiss me and then no one,
no one could get her to get and want to
walk back with her.
Can't,
you can't,
you can't carry [inaudible] 29,000 feet,
28,000 feet.
So keep going.
So she,
the oxygen up there,
33% less than what's here at sea level.
33% 33% so at 67% less authored.
Yeah.
Wow.
Normal auction.
She was no auction,
so she sat down.
So the boys,
we have gopros on him.
We had special cameras and pockets and
all kinds of weird shit to film on the
mountain and the boys are walking.
I have footage of a Mingma Mingma's
walking up there and he's going,
I swear to God,
I'll,
I'll say this for you.
He speaks decent English the whole time
and I'll,
I'll send you the clip.
It's the funniest clip you ever seen.
He's,
I'm like God damn mother fucking fucking
fucking mother.
And He's discussing every step of the
way he's fucked up scenario and you
know,
it's middle of the night and he's
looking at,
you know,
potentially dead person in the death
zone.
Yeah.
In the desks.
A cool situation to tie.
Why is it the death zone?
Because of the,
because of the lack of oxygen,
your body's body starts to conspire
against you.
I mean you,
you,
you know,
you can't assimilate any nutrition.
You know,
you're,
the fluid in your body starts to go to
places it's not supposed to go.
So it goes up in your brain and you get
cerebral edema and you make that
decisions and you get a headache and you
lose your vision.
And then you get pulmonary edema.
Your lungs fill up with fluid and you
drown in your own fluid.
You know,
it's,
it's uh,
this is like stepping out of the state
capitol and Mars and I wonder what this
is going to do to my body.
And you step out and shit starts
popping.
It's,
it's strange up there.
Wow.
They've done MRI studies.
Actually that's where it is right there.
This was the line that Jamie pulled up
over to the red zone.
Lack of oxygen above 8,000 meters can be
fatal to climbers.
So see that labs and feet is fucking
high.
8,000 meters.
That is,
that's the same.
See that last dot before the summit?
That's 26,000 feet,
which is right there.
Exactly,
Jamie.
That does that.
Where she goes above.
That's what the campaign up and that's
the balcony.
Right.
And she was almost there 500 feet.
She was 500 feet from the top.
She may have,
who knows?
I don't know if she made it.
She was,
she was a 28,500 we have a gps
coordinates on it.
She was at 28,005 to 500 feet from the
top.
So she could almost say she summited
Everest.
She was like,
she could see like Everest was like
where your car's parked.
Yeah.
Except things.
A lot of crazy ass terrain in between
where she was and across.
That's where the Hillary step is.
And that's where the ridge goes.
It's no louder than your laptop and
sections and it's a 10,000 foot drop
into Tibet.
Right.
And a 6,000 foot dropping it in Nepal to
the left.
Either way it would hurt pretty fucking.
This is wine is a laptop in sections.
It's pretty,
pretty narrow,
you know,
but then it wa it,
it opens up and it,
and it shrinks down.
But I mean it's no place to screw the
pooch and she did.
So,
oh my God.
So this is right here.
Unless the Hillary step right there,
which by the way,
it was really interesting two years ago.
I remember the earthquake two years ago
in the fall.
So it knocked that whole boulder off
that boulder that people are standing
out.
Right.
So Hillary Sta.
Imagine if you're on that,
you're like,
I made it
go on for the ride.
That's at the peak of Everest.
Their Nav.
You Bro,
I'll fucking hop off and grab a hold of,
maybe you bro.
So that's,
look at that.
Look at that clown show.
Oh my God.
So many people.
So if someone falls onto you,
you got a real problem too.
Yeah.
So the year we were up there in 2000 the
year before the fall,
before there was a British guy,
I can't remember his name,
but he got caught up in the ropes
descending from the summit down the
hillary step and got caught and there
was nobody there with him.
And he got caught caught and he got
stuck in perpetuity.
So we thought that for sure the first
people that were going up and oh one
that were like a few weeks before us had
to cut him free cause we were,
you know,
we're speculating.
Like if we're the first group that gets
up there going to have to scoot around,
uh,
this fella,
you know,
so he's just stuck on this line.
But he wasn't there when we got up
there.
He wasn't somebody who already come
from.
Yeah.
Now what did they do?
Push them off the side.
Well,
here's something for Jamie.
So there's 248 bodies on Everest right
now.
Still there.
And these climbers,
I didn't go up.
I was at base camp [inaudible] the
climbers use them as mark markers.
You kind of go up here.
There's the original climber.
The guy for the first kind of make it,
well,
they found one.
Yeah,
but he's on the south summit.
He's on the other side on the north side
and Ted Malerie malerie they found
Mallory's body body back.
Right.
Is back until they're frozen.
They're weird.
Yeah.
Ivory skin still flesh like,
yeah.
Still flush their fleets.
Cryogenically frozen.
The crows pick at them,
they eat them.
There's crows at that,
at that altitude.
They pick at him.
This guy,
mallory,
Jesus,
look at that.
That's so weird.
But that dude's a bad dude,
man.
That is a very bad man right there.
Because they went out with some hobnail
boots and some marginal equipment and
everybody was telling him that they were
going to be dead for sure.
And they said we're going to charge
ahead.
And they did.
I mean this was,
this was back way back,
man.
This was in the 20s.
Right.
So,
and there's the controversy that he,
that boot the controversy that they
summited first,
but they can't prove it.
So that's a big controversy.
They thought Irvine and Mallory summited
and then they fell on their way down.
So crows pick at him.
Oh yeah.
But what are the,
obviously he's still there.
Um,
yeah.
I mean,
I don't think get at him as much,
but there's,
you know,
there's things,
there's this,
there's a lot of stuff there,
you know,
I ain't get a lot of,
yeah,
there's a lot happening there that's
sitting on the mountain.
You have to walk past that.
I didn't see that guy.
But you've never seen that guy.
I didn't see that.
How many of the 200 plus bodies have you
seen?
You know,
the,
the conditions changed so dramatically
over the each season depending on snow
fall.
So you know,
Jesus or some creepy things up there,
zoom out on that dude's face.
I mean there's,
it looks happy.
I made it.
I don't think he,
and you know that nice jacket that's
pretty fresh.
That's a nice looking down seat.
Yeah,
it's what I'm saying.
Like how many people die a year?
Well,
I think the average is,
you know,
nowadays is usually I think somewhere
under 10 but you know,
between six and 10 every season.
And how many people attempt it?
I didn't get it.
The,
the,
the grade is,
is increasing every year.
I think this year was the most,
it's summited,
the most attempted in most summited was
this year.
And I think close to 300 people,
some of the diseases pull that picture
up again,
that image of death star Sherpas and
regular folks.
So a lot of the Sherpas died too,
Huh?
Yeah.
Well I mean there they go.
They're higher in concentration.
They do the majority of the work as
well.
And,
and that's one of the reasons why we
went out there.
We saved more sherpas.
Um,
and we,
we pull a lot of Sherpas off cause we
need more,
more often than not,
they don't have helicopters and they'd
all have helicopter insurance.
And so we would go and I would pay for
it.
They would go,
there's a Sherpa who's really sick and
he's going to die.
And then jeff and I would just decide to
pull them off.
Thing they don't have is they don't have
life insurance.
And,
and you can imagine,
so a lot of these families,
a lot of the Nepali in the high altitude
workers,
families,
they lose their only source of income
when these guys get get killed.
So actually a friend of mine,
Melissa,
or not,
who was the first American woman to
summit Everest without oxygen?
Just uh,
last year,
um,
uh,
she started a fund called the junior per
fund and it actually compensates the
families when their loved ones or killed
on the mountain.
It's nice and it's good.
It keeps them straight because they
don't have a choice.
This is [inaudible] to you live on the
Lake Gail,
you're going to be a Sherpur reporter at
the highest level.
You can be your Sherpa.
You're a guide.
Wow.
So what happened?
This lady again?
Oh,
oh yeah.
So mean.
What goes up there?
They're walking up there and they need
some help.
So they,
they,
and I have it all on video and he's gone
fuck a motherfucker.
He passed.
So funniest thing in the world.
The comedy show.
So then they,
they hear music.
Not Kidding.
They hear music.
So she has a phone on her.
I don't know how the batteries lasting
and she's sitting at the balcony but on
the ice and just barely breathing and
listening to music.
And then so they go to her,
Brianna or some shit?
No,
I would say with some kind of Indian
music and
her curry rock or whatever the hell it
was.
Um,
and then she Indian?
Yeah,
she was Indian.
Her name was,
uh,
Chetna.
You don't want to say her name,
Huh?
Well,
no,
she'd been a disparaged her.
She's alive.
She's good.
She's stoked.
She started to me a Christmas card.
Okay.
Yeah.
No two of us.
Nice.
Yeah.
Very cool.
Okay.
Switch card with her kid.
So what happened?
So then they get to her and,
and then they start calling her momma.
They're like,
Mama,
you need to wake up.
You need to wake up.
We didn't go.
And she's like,
no,
no.
It's all in video.
Like leave me alone.
Leave me alone.
I don't want to do it.
And then they put oxygen downer,
crank up the bottle,
try to get some blood flowing,
get stuff.
They sit up there at 8,000 feet,
35 minutes,
45 minutes trying to Jesus trying to
coax her.
Yup.
Trying to coax her to get her down and
that was it because of her personality
or is it because she's so like so
diminished cognitively things go south
to ride.
So she was,
she probably had pretty profound
cerebral edema.
So her decision making was in the
toilet.
So you become really apathetic.
It's impossible to carry someone down.
You can't carry something,
you can lower them down,
which is what happened.
You can tie a rope to their harness and
short rope.
I'm down with,
you know,
with two or three dudes like working
really,
really hard sort of loaner down and
that,
that's how they got her down.
But you know,
she,
she quit and a lot of people quit.
I worked search and rescue in Alaska on
Denali for years and,
and you'd be amazed at how many people
are just like done Tuesday,
just lay down and they're done because
they're not rational enough to know.
Like if I sit down and I just took just
a little bitty nappy and getting back
up,
you're taking the snow nap and you're
done.
No,
now,
yeah,
it won't snow now.
I don't like that.
So that's a weird term.
But with hypothermia,
the interesting thing that happens is
you get euphoric,
right?
You'd go through this,
this stage of super cold,
super cold,
and then your core temperature drops low
enough to where euphoria comes in.
So oftentimes it was same people,
we would find our undressed.
So you get hot,
you get warm.
So their gloves come off the hats,
pants andZ unzipped.
And you know,
everybody's,
everybody's buck naked on the side of
the mountain right before they die,
before they die.
So I mean,
not that I want to go out that way,
but now I can think of worst way.
So it gets you for it apparently.
Wow.
Because we also pull people back.
I've seen multiple times when we pulled
people back and they discussed that,
they described it.
Um,
and then we start rewarming there,
frostbite and shit's not right after
that.
That hurts out.
That hurt.
Frostbite is so horrible to look at too.
It's just shoot this stuff we had to see
and her fingers are still half,
half fingers are off her.
Yeah.
She sent me pictures.
She's missing fingers.
Missing tips.
Tips.
Yeah,
she's lucky.
Some of the Phalanges are gone chopped
up.
So they got her down.
They ended up hours and hours and hours
and we're tracking and where we're
trying to talk to them.
They get her down to camp four.
What does that track that you saw then?
The trickiest part as he'll tell you,
cause I can't tell you can't afford a
camp three.
Yeah I can't afford a cam three and then
camp three to camp two which they didn't
even do.
They couldn't get,
they couldn't get to camp two which is
straight on the lhotse face.
Lhotse face.
It's a,
it's about a 60 60 degree ice face,
which is slick.
So when you're roping somebody down,
you know,
it actually does provide,
less friction.
You can actually slot somebody down but
you can't get going too fast cause you
know,
so now you're at 25206207000 feet,
you're 130 pounds,
125 pounds shirt and you get a lower
this 200 pound lady down hard oxygen.
And these guys are working there and
met.
She's 200 pounds.
Well,
she wasn't that big,
but you know,
with all our gear and all that,
it was 160 170 pounds worth of weight,
you know,
dead weight,
lower down.
So we got her down,
we got her down to where we could go in
with the helicopter and we picked her up
and took her back down to base camp.
And that was when the meeting took place
between her and her husband.
The tearful rejoicing and no though.
So the,
the part you missed was the helicopter
landed it,
it couldn't land at camp two.
We weren't supposed to go up to 23,500
which at the base of low t a crampon
point,
Andrew got there and said,
I can only pick one of you.
And she looked at her husband and said,
you stay until he made him stay and take
the next helicopter out.
So we got her down and she looked at her
husband and said,
you stay like pitch.
You quit.
Well,
she was mad because he got left.
She was pissed off that she was pissed
that she got left,
but he couldn't have carried her.
Knowing that you're switching it
depends.
There's ways of looking at it both ways.
Somebody quit,
somebody gave up,
somebody said no.
I mean who knows?
But I'm sure they had to go sue through
some deep ass therapy when they got
home.
Okay.
So I'm gonna,
I'm going to fill in the gaps here.
So fast forward a nine or 10 months and
dude,
husband has a,
he has a heart attack and das.
So he died.
I'm sorry,
I'm not,
shouldn't be laughing.
That's Kinda fucked up.
It is good.
Fucked up man.
Come on Everest.
And then you fucking,
but what's the Karma though?
They left her.
I mean,
what is he going to do if he doesn't
leave her?
What does he do?
These sits out there with her.
He had told people that she's up there
and she's panicked.
She was panicking on the phone.
He was there.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean,
we talked about it last night,
the romantic story.
You huddle up with your girl and you're
going to die together.
Whoa.
Right?
And then,
or you get,
you go down there,
tried to get her saved and you get rid
of killed for leaving.
It's easy to Monday morning quarterback
any of those situations because all bets
off when you get above 26,000 feet,
I mean it's,
it's,
it is,
you're,
you're kind of hanging on a little bit
and that's why,
you know,
you get these big into thinner stories
that happen and no one really can
remember exactly the details and,
you know,
it's,
it's a little bit sketchy.
Like I,
I in my intentions were,
and I did,
and you did.
And I mean,
summit notes and 26,000,
26,000 foot peaks.
There's always,
there's always variables that come into
play and it turns into theater.
I mean,
it's a stage who even make choices.
People make mistakes.
We had one guy on,
on,
uh,
what's her face again?
Grace's team.
He was a triathlete.
He went up,
broke a bunch of rules respectfully.
Oh,
with regards to climatization stuff.
Commonization pushed himself too much.
Summited,
got back down and died in his tent.
Oh,
his fifth attempt up there.
You can look it up.
It's on the end of that.
His fifth attempt up there pushed
himself way too hard rule.
The rules are,
if you don't make it to a certain point
by a certain time,
you should turn around and save your
life and come back another day.
And he said,
no.
He said,
no,
I'm pushing through.
Got to the summit too late.
Came back really exhausted.
16,
17 hour day,
died in the tent.
He was 35 years.
What did he die from?
Exposure.
Cerebral Edema.
He might've thrown a clot.
It could.
I mean,
I don't know.
I don't know the autopsy,
but I mean he,
you know,
it was something fairly acute,
it wasn't just exhaustion,
you know,
it wasn't just hypothermia.
He made it back to the tent and then
just expired in the tent.
So not sure.
I mean there's,
there's a lot of things that can go
wrong and you have a small window to get
it right.
What is good about it?
Well,
that was something big ass mountain.
Yeah.
Um,
you know,
I think that's a tough question.
It's a pretty nebulous thing.
It's very subjective.
It's very selfish.
There's no,
there's no chance.
I used
to climb pretty hard and then I had a
kid and my sense of objective risk
changed significantly at that point
because climbing by nature is a very
selfish pursuit.
You're going out there to do something
that is bring,
it brings me joy and it brings me
fulfillment and it gives me a sense of
connection to the people that I'm
sharing a rope with.
Cause we're on a rope man.
I mean,
we're going to win together,
lose together.
I mean it's,
but jeff doesn't do that selfishly and
you give all these climate shit,
like that's a very selfish thing to do
for him.
But he did it because Eric did it.
Eric wanted to do it.
So he like,
Oh,
you're a selfish prick.
You summited Everest.
He goes,
no,
I've,
I've helped my blind friend go to the
state.
It really wasn't his goal,
his goal to help the first blind guy and
everybody on my team.
It wasn't just me.
I had an amazing team that was there
was,
um,
you know,
with all our Sherpas on summit day,
we were 19 of us.
And at that point,
I think this record still stands.
We're still the highest number from one
team and one day to stand on top
together.
And I attribute that to the fact that
just as you said by like that was just a
bunch of Bros who weren't commercially
God and we were just friends and we were
there for something that was bigger than
us.
We were there for Eric.
We wanted to get him as high up as we
could and getting back down.
And if that meant the summit,
awesome.
If not,
we'll come back and we'll still be bros
and maybe we'll go do some other cool
shit,
you know?
So what happens when you don't go up
there for me to plant my flag is we've
got the summit.
I got to stand on top.
You know,
it was pretty,
pretty cool.
Um,
what is the feeling like when you get to
that top and you realize that you have
summited Mount Everest well up there and
you're looking around,
you're like holy shit.
Top of the World Ma.
Well,
just like so many other times with him
and the stuff that I've done with Eric,
um,
I was worried about him getting down.
That's all I was,
I was obsessing on it because there was
a storm coming in and we heard all the
radio check.
How much time do you have a storm?
I mean it's,
shit is barreling.
I mean it is moving quick from the uh,
from Tibet across,
I mean we could see it coming and it was
probably nine,
10 in the morning.
And you know,
that's early.
And when it comes out early and monsoon,
the edge of the monsoons is late.
The monsoon starts to pick up in late
May.
You don't want to be anywhere near,
but Joe,
you talked about all the time the
adrenaline dump.
So imagine generals dump in a cage and
you talk about all the time now you just
summited Mount Everest,
but you're only halfway done.
8% of all matt mountaineering accidents
happen on the decent.
Wow.
He must sas.
That's why.
Why is that?
Because your decision making comp has
compromised and Yup.
You,
um,
and you,
you did what you went to do.
You know,
you're like,
Ooh,
let's fuck.
Can you relax your adrenaline?
You like,
I did it.
And all of a sudden they're like,
oh,
I get down.
That's why more technical,
to be honest with you,
that's somewhat of a rookie move.
Um,
and I,
you know,
experienced climbers always know to have
a little bit more in the tank.
You know,
it's just like a fighter,
right?
You know,
you've got to save some for the fifth
round,
right?
And you got to,
you got to know that it's coming and
it's gonna hurt.
It's gonna hurt bad.
I mean,
I remember my legs like I was,
they were jelly man.
I mean,
tried to come down from the Hillary
stuff and I was just jacked.
I was like the gumby man coming down and
I actually fell,
I fell onto a fixed drope right.
Right below them or right above the
hillary step.
Yeah.
And I got caught by a rope and it was
one of the only times I clipped in that
whole day.
Oh Jeez.
It was,
it was Kooky Shit.
Did you clip in cause you felt like your
body was getting wishy washy?
It's again,
I knew like a little bit not ride.
I've shot my shot,
my wad coming up.
I dug some ropes out with my buddy Brad
Bull,
uh,
for the team.
Um,
earlier that that morning that were
buried.
We were the first people up.
I mean we were the first people up and
all these reps were buried and we were
digging them out in the ice and they
were buried under a foot to two foot of
snow at 20,000 feet.
And I made Brad and I made that decision
to,
to dig those ropes out because not to
know which way to go up but to,
to make sure they were there for the
decent cause.
That's when the weather comes in.
And that's when the blind lead the blind
down.
You know,
it's,
so we dug the ropes up and I knew when I
did that,
um,
that I was going to be out of gas and
sure enough like coming down I knew it.
So that's when I was clipping it.
And that was a little bit,
it was a little bit more fastidious on,
you know,
making sure if I fell that I'd be
caught.
Sure enough,
wow.
On the rope.
And they got back on and was like good.
That woke me up and up and you get a
jolt.
Yeah.
Shake it off or look around.
I've got,
damn,
I wonder if everybody saw that and then
started at that.
Yeah.
So is it the appeal of like
accomplishing some of the very few
people accomplish and joining like a
very special club?
Cause I what,
what motivates these people?
Is it just a really difficult task and
they want to see if they have it in
them?
I mean,
obviously everybody's got a subjective
answer to that.
And mine is,
I liked to be with my people in the
hills.
That's my church.
That's where I feel the most
comfortable.
It's where I feel safe actually in the
hills.
Right.
And you're around other very rugged
people.
Well,
just people who make good decisions,
you know,
and then,
the,
the cathedral of the big mountains makes
me happy and sort of rejuvenate my soul
and,
but there's,
there's something to be said for,
for seeing what my body and my mind can
do.
Um,
you know,
I think that a lot of people would,
would agree that that's probably one of
the,
the main reasons why we get out and do
these things.
But I mean,
it's no joke.
It's dangerous man.
I mean,
you saw one of the most accomplished
mountaineers that probably the best
mountaineer in the world just died,
you know,
under two months ago you will lay stack.
Yeah.
How did he die?
He fell.
He was getting ready to go do,
he's trained and up in the,
in the valley and that Western coon from
that camp two on Everest that you saw
that image.
Um,
he was going up the west shoulder of
Everest with one other Sherpa who was a
friend of his,
not just a page Sherp it was as calming
partner and they were going to go up a
route that has yet to be successfully
seconded.
So these American second,
he's like,
so it's been done once people have died
trying to do it again.
Oh,
just several parties and he was going to
go do it.
It's these two Americans,
willy on unsold and Tom Hornbein did it.
Um,
and it hadn't been repeated cause it's,
it's straight up commitment.
Nam Balls like,
but his Sherpa was sick,
the stripper was sick.
So ulay uh,
was out training one one morning and I
think it was around four or five in the
morning.
Yeah.
So he was up in that sort of circ and he
was over on a mountain called
[inaudible],
which is beside everest and he fell,
who knows why,
maybe slipped through,
he got hit or something.
I have to see this guy,
this guy,
you can see the videos online.
Uri Stack is this guy,
no ropes,
no nothing.
He's got two ice axes.
And he runs up the hill fast and you can
run on pavement.
Sure,
sure.
[inaudible] calling the Swiss the Swiss
machine and believes a video of him
doing this.
Hundreds of lots of,
how do you spell his name?
You lay.
So it's u l I deck now the incredible,
when you see it,
the incredible thing about it that you,
you're at the six degree pitch ice
walls.
He's at 26,
27 20,
you know,
23,000 feet and he's just gone bang,
Bang,
Bang.
Yeah.
He's in like a video game.
He's a ridiculously committed.
He was athlete.
I mean he's committed to his craft being
as strong as he could be,
you know,
technically capable.
Um,
but you know,
it's,
it's still roll the dice and how many
people died trying to do this.
I want to do Everest.
The second seconded one,
a good handful.
I don't know exact numbers,
but several from different
nationalities.
So everybody is either failed or died
except one person who's the one person
to two Americans that was willie unsold,
Tom Hornbein.
And that's what they do.
The ones they summit once the,
once the climbers are in it,
just,
you know,
humans in general,
these climbers do it.
Then they want to find a more difficult
route where they do with that oxygen.
So Uli was going to go up and do that.
This fucking guy is going to go do that
and then come around summit everest and
then go check that out dude.
He's like a fucking goat.
Look at this.
Look at that.
That's incredible.
So his aerobic,
you know,
he's got that ability to kick out the
lactic acid.
Oh my God.
That is insane.
I mean,
he's an absolute beast.
It's a shame.
It was a big loss.
It's just because he's been doing it for
so long.
Shit,
no ropes.
Oh my God.
Okay.
For people just listening.
What is the name of this video?
Jamie.
So,
uh,
Uli,
New speed record,
Uyghur 2015.
So this is the north face of the eiger.
And so he's a Swiss dude and he grew up
sort of cut his teeth in the Alps and
just all this,
I want to be clear though,
this is that this isn't like the first
time he did this right.
It's probably the 50th time he climbed
that route and he did it over and over
and over,
got it dialed,
figured it out,
and then went out and did these speed
records,
you know,
and set these big writers very similar
to what just happened on El Cap.
Cathy Tan,
uh,
last week.
Did you hear about Alex honnold and what
Alex?
Oh yeah,
I did.
I watched the,
the pictures and video that he's been on
the podcast for.
Alex has,
yeah,
he's a freak.
Yeah.
So would he,
is what he did,
what he did,
and my,
my great way was like landing on the
moon,
dude.
I mean the,
the ability to pocket fear and just
focus on the three square feet in front
of you on paralleled.
Yeah.
I can't,
I mean I've climbed El cap and I just
can't imagine being up on those slats.
How long did it take you when you find
oh cap,
three days.
So three days.
So it can four hours free soloed that
deploy ulay people look at that and
they're like,
well it's just got super sweaty on mine
aren't mine are too by the way.
You know?
And I think that,
so if they look at you and you see this
video and you're like,
wow,
he's crazy.
He's crazy.
Now he's calculated and so is Alex.
Alex super calculate.
Like he'd climbed free rider the route
that he did a few weeks ago.
He did it several dozen times and would
fall on it,
you know,
with a rope and he just was in the right
headspace that day and went up and did
it without a whole lot of pomp and
circumstance.
Just went out and nailed it.
Look at this.
There's going to be a crazy ass video
that Jimmy Chin,
Jimmy was shooting it and his tea.
Yeah.
Jimmy was near the top with no,
what did he,
did he shoot it like next to him with
ropes and,
no.
So,
so Jimmy was very respectful of not
getting in his way because this is a
very obviously very intense thing.
Oh yeah.
And how's it going?
You look down there.
Fuck.
What'd you do that again?
I missed the shot.
Can you go back up?
Hey Man,
can you give me a thumbs up?
Selfie governance smile.
But Jimmy is a very accomplished climber
and he's an amazing set of a dog.
Jimmy Chin,
National Geographic [inaudible] top.
And he was at the top and him and his
team,
I think lower down and uh,
and yeah,
greatest,
greatest athletic human feat.
I ain't going to lie.
I have to agree because it's,
if you think about true athletic feats,
it's not just obviously the,
you know,
the core poral sort of,
event.
It's just the whole mixed bag of who you
are as an athlete mentally,
emotionally,
behaviorally,
physically,
how you execute in the moment when shit
is just on point,
like right in your face.
And he did it like to this level that I
can't even,
it's unbelievable man ripping out of my
hands.
I mean these guys,
I mean once you get 30 feet off the
deck,
it's game on you man.
You know,
and then now put,
you know,
a power of a hundred on that,
but there's very few sports where one
mess up,
you're dead.
That's it.
Does he have any like guys that are
trying to be the next Alex honnold that
are chasing him?
Well,
I just read something today this morning
about the,
there could be some emulators,
Eh,
who knows?
There's other super tough badass
climbers that are out there that are
also free solo on and doing shit without
ropes.
But um,
he's at another level and everyone knows
that,
you know,
there's this other low,
well first of all,
like what is,
what separates him?
Yeah.
Well there's a lot of body chemistry
that that is sort of a mystery.
Like how does his pituitary,
how does his adrenal gland not just
flame out?
Right.
How does he control that in a way that I
can't write?
I mean,
my,
yeah,
we're sitting here at the desk and my
hands are sweaty just thinking about it.
Right?
So there he is as calm and collected as
he can be.
They've done studies on,
on Alex,
they brought him in and like,
you know,
buzzed his brains like where are you,
chemically,
biochemically when we introduce,
introduce assaulting sort of variables
on you and he's just flatlined.
So he's the perfect blend of
biochemistry and physical capacity but
also devotion and commitment to his
craft.
I mean,
he's an artist,
right?
That's so,
and he,
he got down from that,
from that climb that day,
just a couple of weeks ago.
And they were like,
what are you going to go do now?
You know,
this isn't a Disneyland.
He was going on his fingerboard and he
was going to go train and do like,
you know,
fingerboard workout that afternoon
because climbing El cap for four hours
was not enough workout for the day.
And it was like
whatever.
He says what?
I'm in an MRI and showed them images and
this,
that's what was his response was it
brain is brains fear levels.
After looking at gruesome and a rousing
images,
he commented,
it was like whatever that is.
That dude,
he's so mellow.
Right.
But that's what,
how he described it.
When I said to him,
I said like,
what is it like?
Are you freaking out?
He's trying to keep calm.
It's like you're really mellow.
He goes,
if,
if anything is like,
if you,
if there's anything wrong,
it's so wrong.
Like when it goes wrong,
like you're fucked.
Like so you're always,
he's his way of putting it was mellow.
Yeah.
You're really mellow video I believe,
and it may be Alex and maybe some
another other climate,
but thinks is a video of him probably
they'll cap when he was three solon
before this one where he says gimme a
minute.
It was northwest direct face of half
dome and I've climbed that route too.
And I'll tell you I,
the only time I've ever seen him flat,
that was the,
that was the iconic image on Nat Geo on
National Geographic magazine of him.
Just in his plaid shorts shirt,
like on the ledge,
you know,
leaning back.
And it was,
he reflected on that.
They asked him about it later and they
said,
you know what was going on?
He says,
I just needed a minute.
And he got it and he calmed himself
down.
Whatever was happening in his head,
who knows?
And he recalibrated and went up,
you know,
no gear.
So it's just,
who knows?
There's,
there's a right there.
That's when he needed a minute.
No,
no,
no.
There's a,
there's another one of Jamie.
It's it,
it's,
he's in that green.
There he is over there on the right.
Yeah.
That one.
And the green or the gre or the right
above it right there.
It's uh,
the one where you stand in there.
I was sort of on the left.
Yeah,
that's,
that's the one that I think was the nat
Geo and that's the one he says,
I just need a minute.
Just need a minute.
That's um,
that's a thousand feet off that debt.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I mean,
imagine if that's your kid.
We all,
you know,
and you're like,
what are you doing today honey?
So apparently he has a very,
very close relationship with his momma.
He grew up in Sacramento I guess.
And I'm guessing he just tells his momma
what she needs to know until after it's
over.
Yeah.
Fucking Christ.
It's just like that is a,
that's a crazy thing to be awesome at,
you know?
All right.
All right,
hold on.
Wait.
So we're talking a lot about Columbia,
but there other reason why I want to
bring Jeff here.
We're not changing subjects.
I don't know where the fuck you think
you're going.
This,
this guy like,
so you said that there are a few people
that are trying to emulate what he's
doing.
Well,
I think there's just a few guys doing
their own thing and it happens to be
free soloing and you know,
he's,
he's the pioneer and there were other
guys before him.
There was a guy named Peter Croft.
It was out there for many years,
sort of,
you know,
he did a,
he did a route called astro man in the
valley.
That was at the time.
And I remember I was in my,
I think my early twenties when,
when Peter did that.
And I remember reading about it and
thinking,
no,
like what,
how,
how does one want to,
and I was just really getting into
climbing a lot and I just couldn't,
it didn't compute.
But Peter Croft I think and guys like
him and like Alex just have a wiring
that's very,
very different than the rest of us.
And it seems reckless to many,
many people.
But what I do seems reckless to many
people.
So it's so relative and there's a scale,
you know,
and,
and people that would look at Alex and
be like,
you're crazy man,
that shit,
you're going to get to it.
And like he's like whatever man.
I'm sure.
Yeah,
there is a scale.
There's a scale.
Yeah.
Well what about physically?
Like is there like an optimum building?
Like for basketball you really want to
be tall and thin,
right?
Is there,
is there an optimum billed for what he
does?
I mean,
I think,
you know sinewy and,
and the strength to weight ratio is,
is obviously,
you know,
the best climbers are usually thin,
pretty thin and you know,
every themselves well and you know,
it's,
he's got big hands,
like not necessarily big like basketball
player,
but like his fingers sausages is these
fat fingers from constantly training
them and almost calloused.
Yeah.
Well the,
just the amount of weight that he can
carry on his hands,
he's gotta be pretty unusual.
Yeah.
This,
so this finger thing that he does,
like what is the thing that he did?
The campus board or a finger or one of
those peg boards,
like for wrestling,
that's kind of like a campus board is
like an inverted sorta board that you
climb up just for strength and it works
your core and your arms and your chest
and your delts and stuff.
But then,
then the fingerboard allows you to get,
you know,
Mano Doit doubled Deloitte,
two finger strength so he can then slot
and then pull on one of those.
So strengthens all your tendons in your,
in your hands and your fingers.
Particularly.
I'm just a little holes carved out of,
uh,
sometimes it's uh,
it's a,
that's her right there.
Yeah.
So sometimes it's more,
sometimes it's a composite.
It's like almost like a little cubby
shelf.
And so you stick your hands in there.
Yeah.
And then there's routines.
I used these two finger pockets and
three finger puck.
Oh Wow.
You use one too?
And I do,
yeah.
Wow.
He's one,
two.
And then I'll try and hang,
you know,
and then count the 30,
hang and then go to finger and hang.
And he did this after he summited.
So we went down and was like,
got to interview and he goes,
sorry man,
I've got to go do a workout now.
How's that?
Tired?
Well that's fine.
That's why he's the best,
right.
I where he is.
Wow.
Workable.
So did this exist 20 years ago?
Was there a lot of people free soloing
20 years ago and I'm,
he's like,
that's the Peter Croft,
you know those guys.
There was a few.
And,
um,
back in the old camp for Yosemite days,
I can Yosemite valley,
I mean it's,
this was the place,
this was the birth of it.
And then there was some dudes that were
not far from here.
Um,
and Joshua tree that we're doing some
pretty balls out solo and Joshua tree.
Yeah.
In j tree.
Um,
and I lived in Joshua tree for a while
just living in my van down by the river
there and climbing all the time and
eating ramen noodles and growing my head
a little bit.
You know what I'm saying?
Um,
and in the tree man,
and,
and cause you know,
there's a lot of climb in there.
That's,
that's uh,
it's pretty,
there's high ball stuff.
Know if you could look at like the
amount of mushrooms that are done,
like in a specific location.
And then look at Josh,
which be like the high concentration.
I saw so many people go to Joshua tree,
just,
just throw him out.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'd like to look at that map.
There'd be a big target.
Yeah,
seriously.
Probably a big cluster,
right?
Yeah.
I mean I've,
I've,
I've seen some good stuff there,
man.
I mean,
that was when I was sort of really,
really diving in.
I was diving into climbing those things.
Those two things were conjoined was
psychotropics and in a way,
and climbing,
they are the,
with a lot of folks.
Well,
it's that extreme connection to nature,
right.
And to life.
And like you were talking about it a
little bit ago before we came on air.
It was,
you know,
when,
when you're stoned,
you see the ball track better when
you're playing pool.
Oh yeah.
Right.
You feel like the revolutions of the
ball,
like you feel like how well you could
touch the ball
and get it to move.
Like you're too bulky for me at least.
Yeah.
You know,
I feel I play like 10% better when I'm
high.
Yeah.
For whatever reason.
Just feel more in touch with things.
Yeah.
That's why I like the social sliver.
Social Sliver.
Ooh,
what's that mean?
Liver microdose.
Oh,
micro of,
of mushrooms or acid.
Mushrooms.
But I'm,
yeah,
so the new medium for us,
I don't know if if,
um,
if you've,
if you've heard of it,
is,
is Goo,
do you know the Goo Goo?
Nah.
So it's super concentrated.
Siliciden so they take mushrooms and
they,
um,
distill it down,
concentrated up,
get this liquid turnitin in and do a
tootsie roll appearing,
uh,
consistency color.
Give it an a halloween,
get a stick.
Yeah.
And you get a stick and it's literally
the size of a tootsie roll.
And we just took like a little,
just a little nip and that's the social
sliver and like,
ah,
and then it makes you just a little more
tuned in.
I mean,
a lot more tuned in.
I have a buddy who's a high level
kickboxer world champion.
Kickboxer started microdosing few months
back,
does it hoover every day,
micro doses.
And he competes on it fucks people up.
Always.
Microdosing so with what?
With el or with now mushrooms.
So the,
I think,
and you might know more than in the zone
to me,
but if you,
if you take it seriously,
it starts,
you lose,
it gets diluted over time.
Yeah.
But when he takes,
when he stops taking it,
he feels that he misses it does,
yeah.
Every day.
Like a vitamin.
Yup.
I think that's called addiction.
I don't think so because not addicted.
Addictive.
But it's like you get addicted to
washing your hands.
If you're one crazy ocd guy,
I gotta wash your hands one more time.
Like if you really,
you can get a mental pathway that's very
destructive,
you know,
you can call it addictive but it doesn't
demonize washing your hands.
And you know,
I think his issue is uh,
um,
when he doesn't take it,
he says it just,
things aren't as fun.
It doesn't feel as good.
But I've been around him when he's
taking it and he's 100%,
they're like,
it's not,
it's not.
He's like,
wow man,
I could like see your eyes and I'm
thinking you're eyes are looking at me
and what is your eyes seeing?
I assume they're seeing with homes now.
He's there,
there like you're there but broad needs
a little experience and it's like you
agree really like calling over here
cause I have no idea what the fuck you
guys are talking about him with the
social sliver before.
Just to see what happened.
Good farm go either way with him though
should hotbox and right now that's fuck
him up.
No,
no.
He's scared.
He's going to do pee test.
Interesting.
D Pts,
he owns his own company.
That's a fight to say because to me
testing themselves.
Joe's been trying to get me,
he just likes to visit and those are
trying to be high for about 18 years.
I have exaggerated,
I had the microdosing the Goo man.
It is,
it is.
Well,
let's talk later about,
I know there's people,
there's,
there's conversations that need to have
to happen.
The absolutely.
So are a lot of these climbers doing
that?
I don't.
I don't think so.
I think,
you know,
I think that,
uh,
you know,
there's,
there's probably a handful of us that
like to mess around with those things
all together.
And not to say that I don't like to,
you know,
trip my balls off and go get on a rock.
Of course right now,
in fact,
I've had a few sort of spooky times just
being really stoned and being on a rock
and not liking the situation I was in.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I've been that way.
Just normal life.
Like you get too stoned,
especially like edibles.
Chiba chew fuck me.
Oh,
they'll fuck you up.
Uh Oh fuck you.
I had a bit off my last special.
That's based on the truth.
I hate a fucking gummy bear,
a pot gummy bear and a this the guy told
me to just eat the leg.
It really is a true thing.
I'm like,
why the fuck are you making a whole
bear?
Then if he wants him to eat a leg,
it's this tiny little thing and I hate
the whole bear and oh my God.
For the fridge for a while too.
It's long time till it's metabolized
rights,
hours,
hours.
But you feel so good when it's over.
You feel like I needed that.
I needed all that pain and fear and just
say I got through it and it's like a
near death experience,
you know like something,
something about it like it's cleansing.
Eating a gummy bear should have that
kind of a shouldn't but it does and when
it comes through on the other side like
it's beneficial as long as you could
keep it together,
you know as a person who's,
that's why bums me out that you don't
smoke pot or do anything cause I know
you could keep it together because
you're a tough guy.
You keep life together.
Like you would just,
it would just make you more aware of but
here's my,
here's my teen.
Years ago we started this company to
take on you.
Bud is a on the death bed.
I'm going to get them.
Hi Bud likes to be in control.
Yeah,
that's the problem.
And he's afraid that he might not be.
You ever look at the closet?
I did.
Does it shock you when everything's
black?
It's a little confusing.
So I had a 10 minute conversation with
this dude last night.
Like dude,
that kind of fucked me up.
Looking at your closet
there.
The fuck out of my sight.
I don't like other colors.
Everything's black.
It was linear feet of of one shade.
Variation of the other black shirt of
the other books.
He's a fucking Ninja.
No play makes jack a dull boy.
All work and no play.
Makes Jack a dull boy.
Oh yeah.
No,
no,
no.
It's efficient decision making.
Right?
I don't have to make that decision.
The other shit that goes on the left so
I'm going to wear that.
I feel that I could feel that.
I get it.
I understand that guys guys,
everybody develops a uniform in life.
Right?
When you,
it doesn't matter if it's a khaki shorts
and a blue everybody,
as long as you develop it.
It's interesting though,
if it was orange it would be a big
issue.
If you are walking around with orange
sneakers and orange pants and orange
shirt,
like this wacky motherfucker,
but somehow or another because it's
black and like,
oh it's bud friend of mine,
Tom Dupont is a head of the,
he owns the Dupont Registry magazine,
green pants,
like shitty looking green pants all the
time.
Like,
what's with a shitty green?
Okay.
Whatever the fuck I was,
we had vetted chemicals.
Fuck off
his reality.
It's probably so confusing.
Everybody remembers me.
My green pants.
I was in Lynn,
I recently,
and Larry Ellison owns the whole,
the whole look and island.
He owns the whole,
I bought it and built it well,
was a dole.
Pineapple owned it.
First of all,
don't pineapple bought it off of,
I was there.
I read the history of the islands.
Amazing.
A Mormon owned it,
some crazy,
but they don't even think it was really
a mormon.
They think it was just a con man who
used being a mormon to lock people up.
Fuck wives.
Yeah.
There's this probably a lot of stories
just like that.
Oh yeah.
There's quite a few.
Especially with Mormons,
that's very,
very interesting religion.
Right?
When you know the guy who made the
religion,
like there's two religions like that are
pretty prominent.
L Ron Hubbard of course,
and then Joseph Smith.
Mormons,
you know the guy kind of a comment.
Yeah.
Oh,
100% I got to jail was 14 and found a
golden tablets.
They contain the loss work of Jesus and
only he could read them cause he had a
magic seer stone had a stone that he
could look through is to read these
fucking Christ broke out of jail.
He jumped out of the window and was
murdered.
Yeah.
Got Murdered in jail.
You know,
he got killed in jail.
I think what the,
the funny thing is,
I think it didn't,
if it was him or somebody else who
invented the polygamy part,
they're like,
wait a minute,
I got another tablet.
I can fuck all the bitches I want.
Hold on.
Every guy that was many wives I want.
Yeah,
it's uh,
yeah.
Good luck with all that.
That never works.
But the,
um,
why would you want more than one?
I know I can't handle one.
Some people just like danger,
like Alex honnold likes to solo climb,
you know,
I mean it's just people like chicks
yelling at them.
I don't know,
whatever.
It sounds like it,
I'm not here to judge overload.
I think it should be legal.
I think if those 19 women are into it
and you're into it,
why,
why is it even legal to get married at
all?
Why is it when you see 50% divorce and
people get their,
their lives devastated,
when does the government step in and go,
hey,
you gotta stop doing this.
This is just ruining all these people.
Like the kids,
it ruins more people than ne thing.
It just stop getting married.
Keeps the loggers afloat.
Yeah.
It does.
That is it just stop the fucking lawyer.
Yeah.
It's a big business and weddings and
lawyers can,
we can't stop that won't make any money.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Fuck all that.
But um,
so this guy who's this crazy mormon guy,
sold it to the Dole company who used to
run pineapples there.
They used to have just massive pineapple
plantation and that was what it was
forever.
And then,
um,
some other dude murdoch,
but not Rupert Murdoch and another half
of Westlake.
Yeah.
Almost all of it.
That dude bought it and then he sold it
to Larry Ellison who just runs around
and gold underwear and fucking ass
people carry him like he's an emperor
kind of curse,
making that up.
Colonel Kurtz on and I don't even know
where he is.
He keeps it plays out there,
I guess,
but he just wanted to own it.
It's a fucking baller place to live
though.
So there's not,
how many people live there?
3000 there's 15,000 access dear though.
Oh yeah.
So am I right in remembering that the,
the concentration of people,
it's not necessarily on a coastline
nights in the middle,
right?
It's in the middle.
Yeah.
Smart people don't live on the coast.
[inaudible] smart.
They're like,
I'm,
this island's not that big.
And sometimes shit goes bad.
Well,
it's not pr where the water has got,
we could go to the fucking water.
It's right there.
It's the asshole American like,
Oh,
I want to live there.
Anywhere you are,
you can take a hike to the water.
It'll take a few hours if you're in the
middle,
but get there like you don't have to
live there.
Jesus Christ.
So tell me about the access to,
I want to hear it.
They're everywhere.
Not even sporting or,
oh,
it was definitely sporting.
Cause these animals,
they evolve to run from tigers.
They are the fastest fucking animals I
have ever seen in my life.
Like in terms of like their ability to
react.
Like there would be a deer 60 yards
away.
You draw back on it and launched the
Arrow and it would be nowhere near that
Arrow by the time the Arrow got.
So you lost a few sharp sticks while
you're there while you go five lighted
nocks.
I can see them in the,
in the grass,
but I lost two.
But the arrows are going 275 feet a
second.
And the deers like
chance to the island because there's no,
there's no indigenous mammos on that
island.
Everything is invasive and everything
has no predators.
So they bring in these rangers and seals
the snipers.
They bring them in,
they set up on a bench and they just
start pumping.
But Bang,
they started taking them out and they
have decal.
Yeah,
well no they don't have to use a 50 cow.
We'd probably use like [inaudible] or
something.
But why do that when you want the meat,
the meat is outstanding.
It is some of the most delicious meat in
the world.
But these animals are so on point.
So for bow hunters it was like one of
the best places for spot and stalk.
Like if you could put the smack down on
an axis deer,
like you either got lucky,
which is me or you got some skill,
you know,
like I've got a little bit of skill but
the guys that I went with it are really
good.
Like Remy Warren,
I think he shot three or four while I
was there.
My friend John Dudley shot for
worldclass bow hunters.
Like as good as it gets.
Those guys killed quite a few.
But it is,
you got,
it's a great learning ground like for
stalking cause you,
you blow so many stocks getting it.
How long do you smell you?
Um,
I only hunted for three days because a,
I had a problem with my bow that I had a
fixed once I got there.
And it took a day to do that.
But once you get there and you see how
many deer,
you realize like,
oh,
okay,
this is like this place is overpopulate
so,
but in those three days,
all right,
I saw thousands.
You saw shit.
Thousands,
I mean thousands and you took a few
shots.
Yes,
I took a free shots.
Yeah,
they're tough animals too.
So are you moving?
Are you literally,
are you moving in stock and then pause
it and holding?
Yeah,
you're doing what you call steel
hunting,
walking.
And then you're looking for an animal
that you're,
you're constantly using your wind
checker,
which is like a wising bottle with the
talcum shower.
And you bought $100 a while just
recently started.
So you puff that in the air and you find
out which way the wind is going.
My guide though,
he knew where the wind was going.
He just knew from his face and his neck
and his skin.
Like he can tell,
of course the wind blowing and he's
like,
like this.
And he just puffed that smoke in there
and sure enough it was going exactly
where it was.
Shout out to roll man.
But his,
uh,
his ability to sneak up on these animals
is pretty fucking impressive to,
you know,
I do a lot of crawling,
like a lot of the grasses like waist
high,
so you're doing like crawling where
you're moving like literally like a
snail's pace.
Try not to make too much noise cause you
know,
they're over there and I'm already
reading glass and you're on an island so
they can't really go that far.
They're fine.
There's plenty of room for them to go.
There's a,
I mean this is not like you're hunting
them in a 100 acre confined high fence
place.
It's all wild and free range and it's,
there's mountain terrain and there's
plenty of places for them to get away
from,
but they're aware of one Predator
humans,
you know,
so now that they're not scared of
anything other than people when they see
a person like,
fuck this,
but are there a lot of bow hunters that
go over there?
There's plenty of bowhunters ago over
there.
Yeah,
it is.
Um,
it's,
it's a pretty amazing place,
man.
But Maui is another really great place
for bow hunting too,
apparently.
And Molly also has pigs.
Maui has a axis deer.
They have a deer,
a ram called a move.
Flon that apparently is unbelievably
delicious,
but the locals think it tastes like
shit.
Some local set of tastes like shit and
some local sets the most delicious meat
ever.
But the bow hunters that I was there
with,
there's a move flon the bow hunters.
I was there with,
see if it's sunny on remy Warren's page.
Remy warrants instagram I think has
cause he shot one beautiful ones.
That acts is better than venison.
It's not better nail.
It is delicious.
I wouldn't say it's better than elk.
Elk is my favorite meat,
but it's right there.
It's right there.
It's really good.
Yeah.
Cause you know,
like an analog ended.
I'm not trying to relate those with
Angela.
There's remy super say,
Gee,
this is a one that he shot in the nice,
it's a really small animal.
Right.
And,
um,
they are,
you know,
they're on this really rugged mountain
terrain.
Lanai is so fascinating.
It's such a fascinating place.
And the people that live there could not
be nicer,
could not be cooler.
It's beautiful.
Gorgeous Paradise.
Yeah.
But um,
yeah it's weird because they've decided
to introduce these animals.
I think they did it.
Wait,
wait back hundreds of years ago and they
have to keep those populations in check
and sometimes again they bring in
snipers and they put a bench down and
they just set up shop and get those long
range skills.
Go on Papaya.
So I was,
I was on Maui,
um,
probably about,
I guess a month ago now.
And I went over to my buddy's house and
he has a pretty sweet spread.
It's at the top of this canyon and
looking down upon the,
up on the hill going towards Holly
Aquila and um,
he's like,
man,
you can come on my property anytime and
shoot these fucking deer.
Wow.
Cause they come cause he's like,
they're just,
they're a pain in the ass.
They're everywhere.
We need to get rid of them.
They come in and eat.
My orange is and this and that.
So,
but what's the tax situation
like?
Do you have to,
I mean,
is it part of the blame license?
You get a license.
This public land,
we hunted public land and 100 private
land,
but you get a license and then you shoot
as many as you want.
No limit.
Didn't want to.
They mean to have a pride them.
Yeah.
I mean it's not a problem.
It's not like they're not sick.
There's not,
there's plenty of food for these dear.
Yeah.
That's why we're not getting chronic
wasting.
No,
no,
no.
It's beautiful.
Lush and green.
But they're just everywhere.
They're everywhere,
but they're not easy.
You know?
If you had a rifle,
it's pretty sure,
but it's a pay and pack and get them
back to the states.
Did you go over there?
You want to shoot 10 of them?
As long as you get out of here,
fantastic meat.
You,
your organic couldn't be healthier.
They even serve it at the restaurant at
the four seasons in Lanai.
You know?
It's just,
God damn.
It's good.
So good leaning good.
Oh,
so delicious.
You feel the nutrition in it.
It's just so fantastic,
you know?
And when it comes to like sustainability
and ethics,
it's like one of the best places.
Like that's the place where you actually
should be hunting these animals.
You know,
whenever I go to Hawaii,
I always just feel like I should show my
passport.
They like,
it's just not America in stole that
Shit.
That shit is straight up.
Like it's a foreign contract in a
beautiful way.
Yeah.
In a beautiful way.
It's its own thing.
Yeah.
I mean,
I liked the fact that you can go there
without a passport,
but I agree.
But I'm one of those Weirdos that think
there shouldn't be passports,
should be able to go anywhere.
It's part of our problem.
But everybody's all locked into these
land masses.
Forbidden areas.
Yeah.
Break those boundaries.
Tear down that wall.
I was just in Iraq and you talking about
some boundaries and sort of lines in the
sand and so forth.
Boy,
you know,
I'm sure.
What were you doing over there?
So I went with,
uh,
so back up,
um,
two years ago,
the earthquake in Nepal that killed
nine,
almost 10,000 people throughout the
country.
19 on the mountain,
I'll never Australia.
Yep.
A lot of people got dead and people
died.
And that one,
was it an avalanche?
Yeah,
well,
so the earthquake triggered a lot of
glaciers that are hanging up around in
that cirque and it released in a lot of
stuff just blew through base camp and
killed folks.
But throughout Nepal,
throughout the countryside,
I mean we're talking villages that have
stone huts and no motor and no rebar and
you know,
just shakes just a little bit and she
falls down.
I mean the place was desks.
It's a house of temples.
Yeah.
So,
so lots of devastation,
lots of people dead and lots of
injuries.
So that day that happened,
I knew I wanted to go to Nepal to help.
I'm a PA,
I'm a physician assistant and I've
specialized in emergency medicine.
So I knew I wanted to be there.
And more than anything like focused on
sort of austere medicine.
You know,
like I want to go out there where Shit's
a little bit off and try and help the
best I can.
So I went over there,
I located in an Ngo called Nyc medics
and what's Ngo?
A nongovernmental organization.
So not supplied or you know,
subsidized by the feds.
This is just like sponsorship.
Basically donation money gets you over
there and you do your work so you're not
under the auspices of the phets.
So went over there with these guys,
Nyc medics,
which is a group of former and you know,
New York City paramedics that realize
they wanted to take their skills and
could do some cool shit around the
world.
So I,
I found these guys,
I went over with them.
Um,
I was on the ground for a month way,
way back,
like in the way back this place called
dotting Bessie,
which is right at the base of the
connection mall.
So this is a place that we landed in
some helicopters and set up shop and
there was a lot of these Nepalis that
Tamang Nepali there.
That's their ethnic tribe,
not sure,
but,
but Tamang they see the helicopter come
in and these white dudes get out of the
helicopter and like,
what the fuck we need help.
Are you here to help?
Yes,
we're here to help.
So we had three helicopters worth of
gear downloaded.
It's set up our clinic and we're there
for a month.
We saw,
I don't know,
seven or 800 patients in the course of a
month.
And what started as trauma from the
earthquake sort of then segwayed into
primary care and infections and I mean
injuries and also believe it or not,
like a lot of of of you know,
psychological pain.
Like they were scared of the earth was
shaking still.
I mean there was tremor after tremor,
after tremor,
I mean every day the earth would shake.
I got home and for a month after I got
back from there,
I still felt the ground shake.
And in Boulder,
Colorado,
because it was just,
my body was still sort of equilibrium
was weird.
So tremors every single day.
So these people needed,
you know,
anxiety,
medicines,
you know,
to be able to take the edge off.
So I was over there for a month,
we saw a bunch of people and it was very
worthwhile.
So it got connected to this,
this,
this organization and became good
friends with,
with all the folks who run it and they
do amazing work.
And so I got a call,
uh,
in January from one of the heads of the
organization says,
we got this kind of Kooky thing that
we've been asked to do by the World
Health Organization.
Would you be interested?
Kooky.
The word,
that's the word he used.
Kooky,
Kooky cheese.
Just so who the fuck uses Kooky?
So it,
well,
I mean it comes to going to Iraq,
12 years in medical school,
not understanding what it was.
Fire is,
it was a little bit cookie.
So He's,
he frames it up for me and he's like,
listen,
here's what's going on.
We've been asked by the World Health
Organization to go in and be a trauma
stabilization point in Mosul,
which means you will be as close to the
front line as possible.
Embedded with the Iraqi special
operations forces and your job will be
to lead a medical team of,
we had nine of us,
um,
within 2000
meters of the front line.
That was the way it was framed up and
that's what we all sort of signed up
for.
And that was the agreement with the
World Health Organization.
And so we would be the first point of
contact as these Iraqi special
operations guys were going in and
putting the fight to isis to liberate
western Mozel.
So,
you know,
eastern Mozal been limited.
We're liberated,
you know,
months before.
And he volunteered for this by the way.
So that's all eastern Mosul and the
[inaudible] side of the Tigers.
And then on the west side,
you know,
Isis was still sort of dug in right
there and they were there ready to put
the fight down.
They wanted to get after it and save,
you know,
that's where their caliphates supposedly
started or was,
was settled.
And so our job is to Tsp.
That's trauma stabilization point was to
be as close to the front lines.
We could be.
And this is the,
this was a kicker,
you know,
within a margin of safety,
but still be close enough to where we
could receive the casualties as quickly
as possible,
stabilize them and then get them to a
Ford operating operating suite,
which was typically run by allied
forces.
So our guys,
so,
um,
I said yes before I asked my wife,
which now in retrospect probably wasn't
the best strategy.
Um,
cause she was not super stoked,
but she,
uh,
you know,
I pitched it to her and I've got an 11
year old kid and she gave me I think the
least amount of pushback as anybody
around me and my close network.
I mean a lot of my boys were like the
fuck dude.
What are you thinking man?
Like what's,
what are you getting?
What's your point?
What are you doing this for?
What's your intention to go over there
to a war zone,
to a combat zone,
volunteering,
you know,
and,
and helping a group of people that you
have no affinity for.
It made sense going into Paul,
cause I love Nepal,
I love,
I love everything about Nepal.
Love the Nepali people,
so that good.
Everybody got that.
That's the weird thing about jeff
because he was on the phone with me the
same time saying,
Hey,
are we going back to Everest?
Go rescue.
So he's going to no matter what,
sometime in the spring he can put his
ass on the line to help save people.
He was calling me again,
we're going back and I'm like,
I don't know if we're going back,
the network may order another season.
We'd probably go back and I started
lining stuff up and just in case then it
was aired yet.
Yeah.
Ever stared.
The name of the show is ever stare at
air.
Uh,
November of last year.
Everest air and what network to the
airline travel channel.
Six episodes on travel channel.
It's on itunes and couple of other
places too.
Okay.
So people could get it right?
Yeah.
So,
uh,
so you tell you wife.
Yeah.
And she,
you know,
she knew what she signed up for when,
uh,
you know,
when she married me.
So she knew she was kind of getting a
little bit of a,
you know,
a little bit of a,
of a wild book in her hands,
but,
um,
this was different,
you know,
I can go climbing,
I can set my sights on this and that get
out there in the mountains
or do adventure races and stuff and all
that's cool.
But then,
you know,
mad respect to the men and women that
serve in our military man and put it out
there every day.
But I had never been in a combat zone
and that shit is crazy,
man.
I mean,
it is,
it was real.
Um,
and I have no,
uh,
predications that I had any experience
close to what our men and women have
experienced.
But from a medical perspective,
it was intense to say the least.
I mean,
it was a mind bender at the first,
after,
after the first three days,
I remember texting my wife just saying
like,
I don't know if this is sustainable,
like just this,
my emotional state,
because every day was immense volume of
profound penetrating trauma.
Panic.
I mean,
never was there.
Very,
very rarely was there a guy who had one
gunshot wound,
typically,
you know,
seven or eight or nine.
They were leaking from there,
you know,
from lots of places.
You know,
these dudes were getting shot up and
then the ids and um,
would blow these guys up and we would
get them,
you know,
they'd be youngest.
This was just screaming and drop these
guys off.
And then five minutes later,
another ambulance would come in with two
other dudes.
And it was just constant,
constant.
And we would do the best we could,
um,
to stabilize them or call it.
And um,
the ones we could save,
we package them up and stabilize and try
to control the bleeding.
We'd intubate him if we needed to and
put chest tubes in and,
and crack them in some cases and
stabilize their extremities and pat's
their halls and then send them on.
He would do these weekly daily blogs,
right?
So people who know him,
Rove there,
we're waiting,
watching CNN,
seeing if he's going to be on what he
was.
And he'd do these daily blogs,
these long,
long diatribe,
which is I think how he stays somewhat
sane,
but to get shot at,
there's motors come in and their
compound to where are these blocks on my
blog?
Um,
which is,
yeah,
it's on my website,
Jeff Bm.
And so there's,
I like to write,
do you haven't dot com [inaudible] dot
com so I like to write and Budgie right.
And I like to have the time.
Well,
so this is what I would do at night.
Like if I would lay down and we were
sleeping on the floor on these,
you know,
these Iraqi blankets,
and we would just lay down on this,
we,
so we'd go into these abandoned homes
and we'd set up these trauma bays and
we'd sleep in a room off the trauma bay.
And so I,
you know,
we,
we do our day.
I,
I very rarely wasn't dressed and ready
to get up and go because then any tom,
the head logistician,
we'd be like patients,
you know,
and everybody would pop up and get
ready,
didn't go out.
And the ambulance would throw people on.
Mostly during the day,
but fighting with generally subside at
night and we'd get a little bit of rest
and then I'd write and I'd write and it
was important I think to sort of,
you know,
percolate that shit out a little bit and
let it,
let it sit.
So we were,
we were in this one place for a couple
of weeks and then came the request from,
uh,
the head of ice off special operations,
General Abbas,
and he's came to our head logistical gal
and he's like,
listen,
you know,
as the front line is moving forward,
we would like for you guys if you are up
for it to move forward as well.
The only problem is,
um,
it's not going to be within that 10 to
2,500,
you know,
um,
meter cushion from the front line.
It's going to be more like 500 meters
from the front line.
500 meters.
Yeah.
Which,
you know,
that's really class really close,
especially since the front line is
pretty fluid anyway.
Right.
And this is a conventional warfare,
right?
These guys are,
you know,
they're isis is,
was reinforcing these,
these vehicles.
And,
you know,
steel plate,
and I'm up and then taking civilians and
handcuffing them to the,
you know,
to these steering wheels and tell him
you best job and they drive and then
they'd be packful of explosives and c
four and they blow them up,
you know,
and,
these are guys would,
Iraqi dudes would be like trying to pelt
him to take the dude out.
I couldn't get,
you know,
like Shit was really archaic but
effective,
you know,
and so,
so they told us,
you know,
we'd like for you to move.
And then our head logistical gow Cathy,
she's came to the whole team and she
said,
this is our,
this is our option.
You don't have to do it.
You know,
no one's obligated to do it.
Y'All are volunteers.
And,
and,
and we,
by the way,
we were close to begin with.
I mean,
it was,
it was constant every day,
just mortars and small arms fire.
And there was bunch of,
um,
of,
uh,
of artillery that was set up all around
us,
outgoing.
So we got used to the sound of outgoing
artillery,
but we didn't hear a lot of incoming,
um,
because they just did pushed him back.
So,
okay.
We all said,
let's do it,
you know,
if we can create positive impact and we
can save more lives by being closer,
let's do it.
So we all gotten this big osh kosh and
Humvee,
um,
convoy and uh,
and drove down past the airport.
And I think a lot of military folks that
listen,
we'll know that airport,
um,
in west Mosul very well,
probably.
We drove right through the old busted
up,
you know,
it was just rubble,
the whole airports rebel.
It's just completely,
it looks like fucking,
you know,
bedrock flintstones,
it's just a mess.
Drove all the way through there and then
went to this house and we set up our
clinic on a street corner,
um,
covered by an a corrugated metal roof
and put all our,
and we put six trauma beds and got her
traumas,
sleeves up and everything was ready to
go.
And then we,
we set up our residents across the
street at,
uh,
some other abandoned house and we're
down in the sort of concrete bunker,
so to speak.
And we started seeing patients and,
you know,
day one,
shit ton of people and of lots of things
happen.
I mean,
talking dozens and dozens of,
you know,
multiple gunshot when paces multiple
careers that I experienced in that month
of just the flow of volume of,
of penetrating trauma.
So then,
then,
uh,
it was day two or three,
all these displaced locals,
um,
basically got released,
so they'd been holding him at a
checkpoint fingerprint and the fighting
age males,
making sure they're not on a record and,
you know,
making sure everybody's not,
not strapped and letting them through.
So on day three or four,
they just let this flow of humanity
started walking down the street,
about 60,
70 yards from us,
from where we were set up.
And they'd see the Americans and they'd
see the stethoscopes and they just start
running towards us because these people
had been captivated for,
uh,
in,
you know,
held captive and hiding out in their
basements,
eaten grass,
you know,
trying to find any fluids at all to
drink.
There's no rain water,
you know,
is this fucking rain there.
And,
and uh,
just just eking by.
And little kids,
I mean there's just civilians,
these little bitty kids and they're
hiding out in these,
in these homes.
And they would just run,
they would just take off running and get
to these checkpoints.
So on day three or something,
they,
this flow of humanity comes by.
You guys are starting to sort of bum
rush our spot and everybody starts to
get a little bit panicked cause we
weren't quite sure what was,
what,
you know,
there's a lot,
it turns out a lot of bad things can
happen,
you know,
in that situation.
So we sort of get our,
our security detail to keep everybody
away and we,
we treat a shit ton of people.
Day four rolls around and we wake up
that morning.
And the first patient I have is a five
year old little girl that had been just
absolutely like homicide,
like killed shot right in the head,
assassinated and back of the head,
back of the head.
Yeah.
And that was how our day started at like
seven in the morning.
That was it.
And the day got worse.
So,
um,
the first incoming landed about,
I'd say about 75 yards from us,
an RPG.
It landed in the neighbor in the
neighbor's yard next to us and it just
blew a bunch of debris up and it landed
on our corrugated roof there.
And we were all like,
damn.
But we kept working.
Then 10 minutes later,
maybe another one came in and it was 50
yards and just getting closer this
second,
it's called a grid as a clit and he just
get a little click 50,
25.
So we didn't know it at the top though,
but yeah,
you're right.
That we did not know this at the time.
So,
uh,
that one obviously got everybody Super
Tingley.
Um,
but there was still a shit ton of people
coming in.
We had patients mean we were working and
we had our kevlar vests on and we were
trying to,
you know,
say then,
then the third one hit and it landed,
um,
right outside the door and it blew a
shit ton of debris.
I mean,
we felt the blast and one of our medics
got a big piece of debris in the back
was leg.
It knocked him down.
So we went into this bunker,
basically the staging bunker and we sat
down in there and you know,
no matter what,
we couldn't,
we weren't going to go out into that.
But then 30 seconds later,
um,
one of our,
uh,
security detail dudes carried in our
head of security and he was lifeless and
dropped him on the table.
This is the dude we'd been,
you know,
eating cookies with and drinking tea
with like a half hour before,
an hour before,
you know,
standing at the door,
uh,
in between,
you know,
ambulances czar,
czar guy,
you know,
and he was dead.
And so we all looked at each other and I
was the team lead.
And I tell you,
man,
I wasn't about to ask anybody to go out
into that.
And no one even hesitated.
Like we went out and started working on
how Steve and we,
we,
uh,
we got on and quick and he was out and I
listened to his lungs.
He didn't have any lung sounds.
On one side.
I saw penetrating entry wound in his
chest,
put a chest tube in his,
in his,
uh,
right,
and his right thorax and about a liter
of blood poured out from his pleural
space just like that.
And as soon as that happened,
he could inspire again.
And so we started breathing and
resuscitated him.
So he was dead and he came back to lunch
and he was,
he was,
he was unable to,
to inspire.
So,
you know,
his whole body had shut down from number
one,
from the shock blast.
Right.
And,
and being hit that hard by,
by a piece of shrapnel and just being
that close to the impact.
But then also,
you know,
there's penetrating a piece of shrapnel
went right through his chest and didn't
hit any of his vital organs,
just cause this hemothorax this blood to
fill up in his plural space.
So,
you know,
I evacuated all that blood and he
started to be able to breathe again.
So there he is,
he's back.
We get him out,
we go back inside the,
the uh,
the bunker there and a couple of hours
later we got out.
So we find out the next day that a dude,
not a fighting age,
a local guy was a sleeper cell and that
he had come back in the neighborhood and
was three or four houses down and was
communicating with his operatives,
his Isis Bros,
you know,
two,
300 meters away and was releasing
pigeons to identify our position.
So the way they figured this out,
one of our security guys would see a
pigeon go up and he didn't think much
about it.
And then a mortar hit and then,
you know,
10 minutes later he's like,
there was no pigeons around there.
Right?
Cause I mean,
Shit's crazy.
It's combat zone and birds don't dig
combat zones.
So he kind of started to piece it
together and then he realized on the
third one he's like,
he saw a pigeon go up and he goes,
we're about to get hit.
Sure enough.
So we got out of there,
saves us,
he gives life.
He got out and they went and found this
dude and got his phone.
And sure enough he was doing all this.
Any admitted it.
He was like,
Yep,
that was me.
I was doing,
I was releasing pigeons to identify your
spot.
And I was told they took care of the
situation.
That was what they tried to kill the
American tour and trying to help
everybody.
Well,
yeah.
So I just wanted us,
I mean,
they wanted to get us because we were
there.
We were helping the enemy.
Right.
So that was,
that was a couple months ago.
So they documented on his,
on his website,
CNN was interviewing him and there
there's mortars dropping crazy.
Yeah.
It was heavy.
It took a little you over there for
about a month.
Yeah.
But aside,
when you're leaving,
well there was,
they knew this,
this nyc medics,
they knew this ngo knows like it was
hard to sustain that,
you know,
I mean,
the concentration of can't help but
affect you.
I mean,
that's why so many of our,
our military folks have such profound
ptsd,
right.
It's just from getting your ass kicked.
Like damn,
these guys go through these deployments
that were just months on end of that.
Right.
And you just can't imagine how much,
you know,
how that hurts and then go back to
Kansas and they had to go to the grocery
store.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's hard to fathom,
you know,
the black tar tootsie rolls,
right.
So,
so social,
it's not black tar.
The fuck it is.
I'm just
Johnny Cash in their dope,
these young kids.
Wow.
Yeah.
So that was Kinda,
it took me a little bit to,
to,
uh,
to roll out of that and thank God for my
wife,
man.
She came back and we went on a run up in
the hills like a few days later and we
got up to the top of this hill and I
just,
I just cried on her shoulder.
I just let it go.
And since then I'm,
I'm fine.
But it gives me such a deep appreciation
for how hard it must be for,
you know,
for these men and women who come back
from these deployments and they've been
a part of these things and,
and been affected so profoundly.
It's,
it's,
it's got to hurt.
You know,
I'm on a very deep emotional level.
I can only imagine,
man,
what a crazy life you live helping
people that are involved in traumatic
situations over and over again,
various traumatic situations,
whether it's getting stuck on Kaytoo or
whether it's getting,
yeah,
but he seeks it out.
That's what he does.
I just wanted to bring him,
he sees like,
what am I going to do this spring that's
going to change 50 people's lives?
Where's Kate too?
That's the twos in Pakistan.
Pakistan.
Yeah,
that's a,
is that a more dangerous one than the
first?
I think generally the consensus is it's
more technical.
It's more dangerous and it's not as
commercialized.
Right.
So it's not a same more technical.
What do they mean by that?
Well,
there's this longer bits of terrain that
require more high level technical
climbing skill,
so more exposed,
steeper,
you know,
more,
uh,
you know,
longer stretches of,
of hanging it out there kind of terrain.
You better have your shit dialed or
you're going to get smoked and you,
and when they go on these like I'm crazy
hikes that you have to have very
specific kind of gear too.
Right?
Like they must have like the clothing
pretty dialed in.
I mean,
look,
remember this pictures of Mallory,
right?
Yeah.
It's come like this dude was in wool,
which by the way,
we'll,
it's pretty good.
Pretty good.
Yeah.
It's pretty good.
Better than cotton.
A lot there in cotton.
Um,
but now,
you know,
it's,
it's a matter of getting the right gear
that works.
Um,
and you can rely on it.
You know,
it's,
I mean,
I don't want to be 20 miles back and you
know,
in the back country hunting elk and have
my thermarest have a hole in it.
So I slept in the dirt for five days,
which is what happened to me last fall.
I was by myself and you know,
it was way,
way back in the first night.
You know,
my thermarest had a whole lot and now I
don't know,
it's late in the dirt for five nights.
How was that Dick off?
Yeah,
you get cold from it to fluff your pad.
Clipped my,
I have to put my pack on it.
Yeah.
I've had some nights like that.
So yeah.
Maybe you were upset because he had a
hole in your air mattress.
It was,
it was flat,
man.
I had nothing I'd done the Japanese guy
cause he had a hole in his matches.
Well,
which guy?
The guy that came down.
Yeah.
Well he called a helicopter and I sucked
it up.
He called the helicopter him because he
had a hole in his mattress.
This is funny story.
So we,
I got a call said there's a Japanese guy
and he's dying at camp to dying.
Dying.
Yeah.
It's telling everybody's fucking dying.
He's dying.
So we were like,
Holy Shit.
All right.
I was like,
I got to get the helicopter,
get a helicopter.
They risk their lives.
They go up there and get him fly him
down base camp base camp to Luke Lowe
where our race station was.
Get that helicopter and I'll let jeff
take over.
Well,
yeah.
And then I started asking him,
he's just pleasant as he can be and
what's going on?
Do you hurt?
You have pain,
you know,
it was very,
very tired,
very,
very tired.
Um,
whole in mattress and I,
you have a woody what?
And he said,
I have a holding a mattress and he was
at camp two and was sleeping in the snow
and had a hole in his mattress and
didn't tell anybody.
He just was basically,
he was done like we were talking about
earlier,
like he's just,
he was done and because he's got money,
he's calls in the calvary says bring the
helicopter.
Jeff was pissed.
I was fucking pissed.
Hist is a lot of people risk their
lives.
I saw a dude on Denali do that and it
base camp in 1996 or seven this dude
shows up with a,
I like a boy scout,
old school boy Scout,
like we below looking fucking thing,
you know,
like made of cotton I guess.
You know,
it's like some weird synthetic shit.
And I,
he's,
he asked me for a knife to be able to
cut the plastic off of it,
you know,
and,
and I'm like,
man,
that's not a good idea.
Where are you going?
And I didn't want to,
I should have questioned him.
Two weeks later we get a call,
have to go up to 17,000
feet for a guy who had broken his ankle.
So we land the helicopter down at 17 and
he runs towards the helicopter,
which everybody knows is you don't run
towards the helicopter.
It makes a little lift.
He runs to the helicopter.
I'm like,
he's got a,
so it turns out he was just cold.
I'm telling you man,
like a lot of people just tap out and
because they know there's an
infrastructure around that,
we'll pull them out instead of being
accountable for themselves.
That's where I get pissed.
So we pulled this guy off and we
interviewed them and then jeff goes the
nicest thing.
He says,
have a nice life,
walks up and just started to cuss it and
Piss.
He's paid.
He didn't want to do an interview with
just the Johnny's gun in want to talk
about them and to know when you need.
It's very dangerous to fly a helicopter
that out too.
Right?
Selfish.
Anything can go wrong.
I mean we are,
our helicopter pilots were up.
I mean,
absolutely the other,
the military pilots got to be the best
helicopter pilots in the world.
I mean,
these guys are so skilled and understand
what those conditions make you do as a
pilot.
It's,
it was,
it was phenomenal.
But that being said,
machines break.
I put him in a helicopter one time.
I put it the one to helicopters one time
and that helicopter and that pilot are
dead now.
Yeah.
From that.
Well,
no,
like a few months later I was in the
front with Daca.
How I'm fine.
He crashed into a cliff.
Won't they won't name the company,
but yeah,
we that there was a one little flight,
we put them in there.
Yeah.
And then a rack that was a rickety old
helicopter
do all these really high stressful,
high danger sort of situations.
You're constantly around people that
have this extremely high threshold for
the extremely high tolerance to
discomfort,
to uh,
you know,
pushing your endurance levels,
overcoming obstacles.
Like be you,
you're around people that are like
really solid human beings.
Like they're very on.
Like we were talking about people that
are willing to summit Everest people
that'll rescue people.
That summit Everest,
people that are willing to do these
medical stations 500 yards or 500 meters
from the front line.
I mean,
you're talking about some really solid
human beings,
very,
very unusually solid human beings.
When you come back from that and deal
with people like,
oh,
I'm a fucking cell phone,
such a piece of shit,
you know,
like,
oh my God,
this traffic.
Oh my God.
Like that.
Is that one of the hardest transitions,
like the modern first world problems,
gripes,
the bullshit that people whine and bitch
about?
Yeah.
That was part of the discomfort I had
when I came back from my rack
specifically,
um,
was,
you know,
the delay and flights and just how
pissed businessman Bob gets,
you know,
like,
come on dude,
I let like Louis C k you know,
that,
you know,
you're not fucking walk in,
like 13 of your dead when you that,
you know.
No,
I'm just,
I've been on a gratitude tour since I
got back.
Like I'm just grateful for everything.
I'm so grateful that I was born by like
random stroke of luck,
you know,
in Roanoke,
Virginia with,
with good parents and a good family
structure and was given all the
opportunities that I was given and I
wasn't born and Mozal and hardened in a,
you know,
a seller from the most evil dudes on the
planet.
Yeah.
I mean it's just,
uh,
it's,
it's quite,
so I've come back and instead of getting
mad at those people are frustrated with
those people.
I just try and smile through it and just
think,
you know,
to myself like,
man,
I've wished you could taste what I
tasted just not,
not long ago.
You know,
like,
it really recalibrated me.
Um,
where it's,
it just doesn't,
you know,
I just let it teflon off,
to a certain extent.
And with regards to the people that I
work with,
I tend to,
I think,
gravitate towards people who,
um,
like these chaotic sort of environments.
Um,
and I got turned on to this,
uh,
this thing,
it was this,
this concept is acronym.
The American Military Academy kicked off
a few decades.
It goes,
I think 30 years ago or something.
And then they started referring to
working in these Vuca environment,
volatile,
uncertain,
chaotic,
ambiguous environment and how we operate
in those environments and how true
champions and leaders like Alex can
operate in these places and these
atmospheres that are just absolutely
shithouse sideways.
And when things go crazy,
how do you handle,
how do you manifest it?
You know,
what do you,
what are you doing?
Are you flipping the fuck out?
Are you withdrawing?
You know?
And,
and we all have different methods for
dealing,
but I feel like I've kind of gravitated
towards those kinds of people.
Uh,
yeah,
I just got done reading Sebastian
Junger's book tribe.
I just read it to when I got back.
Amazing.
It's amazing.
It reminds you of,
of where we are and where we've been,
and also why people do gravitate towards
those environments and like what it,
what they get out of it and how this
life in these intense environments sort
of,
uh,
it,
it magnifies so much of what it means to
be human and to be a part of something
that's bigger than you.
That's the phenomenal thing.
And I read,
I read a younger,
I read that book too right when I got
back.
So just like last month I read it and it
was a great tool for me.
My,
um,
my seal team buddy,
uh,
told me to read it when I got back and
it says he,
all the team guys have read it because
of that.
It reminds them of why,
why,
and then why things are a little bit,
you know,
the threads come undone a little bit
when you're not in that tribe.
Right?
Yeah,
pretty much.
Yeah.
And how many people live in environments
where they don't know their neighbors
there?
There's no danger,
there's no excitement,
there's no nothing.
And they live this muted,
terrifying life.
And a lot of ways it's terrifying
because there's nothing there.
It's empty.
It's,
there's a void.
And it's not how human beings are
supposed to be.
We're supposed to be confronted by a
certain amount of difficulty,
supposed to be challenged right now and
life's very insulated and uh,
and soft.
And as a result,
we insulate further,
I think from that.
And then we medicate to deal with the
hollow feeling that you get from being
isolated and insulated.
But then it's the quest is for earlier,
which is why people climb Everest while
you've climbed k two while you go to
push yourself,
you push yourself.
Why anybody does that?
A lot of the people push himself.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well,
and why w why do we hunt?
Yeah,
why do we run?
why did we do the things that we do?
Cause it be,
it creates engagement for me and no I'm
not,
I'm not running for my life but creates
struggle.
I did run for my life just a few months
ago,
you know,
and,
and I,
you know,
I look back now and that was,
that's the fucked up thing that I think
so many military folks really struggle
with.
And that's what younger talked about in
that book was how would you find the,
you know,
the environment you were in was so
precarious and it was just so tenuous.
Like it could be wiped out in any second
and yet you want to go back there.
You know,
I got my,
I got an avalanche on that mountain,
almost dead.
It turns out I want to go back.
Why,
why?
Like what,
why,
what is that,
that,
that wiring that that makes you want,
but you know why?
Because they want to be with their boys
and their gauss and like,
you know,
in it,
in it connected feeling like,
you know,
our shit is tied together.
Why do I want to go back in the
mountains?
It's same reason cause I want to go with
the same boys and get the same sort of,
you know,
intense experience.
And I think that we missed that.
I missed that.
I really like it.
Jeff's got the thing he wanted to teach
his son and when we're up there in
Everest,
he kept on talking about teaching his
son to serve others,
phoebe positive or a role model and
serve others.
And I don't know where that comes from
him,
but he,
that's what he always talks about.
Well,
I think it started with Eric,
right?
Because that was the foundation of my
relationship with this,
with my blonde buddy.
I was a selfish dirt bag climber in j
tree,
you know,
and the,
in the mid nineties and I met this blind
dude who needed an ally.
He needed a friend,
he needed a guide and he did not just a
guy,
but he needed,
as he did a teammate and not somebody
that would,
that he could trust,
but somebody that would eventually trust
him.
And that's pretty,
Dow's pretty wild for him to ask at some
point for a sighted person to trust a
blind person on the side of a rock face
or the side of a mountain because you
know,
it's hard enough with everything and you
take away your,
your vision and you know,
Shit just gets amplified.
And Eric's pretty famous and he's,
he's summited,
what does it,
what does he summited?
Well,
he's done the seven summit,
so the highest point and each of the
seven continents.
I was on six of them with him and he
went down to an article while I was in
medical school.
Uh,
but then,
you know,
he's gone on to do a lot of stuff.
He's a,
he's a bad dude,
man.
He's a speaker.
I mean,
he's a great dude,
Eric Wimer.
So I mean,
but to be honest with you,
he'll tell you,
it'd be the first to tell you that
kayaking in a,
in a boat by himself down the Grand
Canyon was way scarier than anything
he's ever done.
Whatever.
Could you,
you don't know what's going on.
There's the violence and talking about
chaotic environment around you.
Just you carefully here,
the dude and your ear and sometimes not
at all.
All you can hear is this violence.
And somehow he just paddled through and
then,
you know,
he'll get tossed and go under and have
to roll back up.
And I,
it was,
he tells me that,
you know,
he had his own little version of ptsd
from that,
from just being freaked the fuck out and
having nightmares.
How long was that travel?
200 and something miles on that tank.
It was a couple of weeks.
Yeah,
12 days maybe.
Something like that.
I think it was pretty remarkable and
pretty remarkable.
Yeah,
I can imagine.
It's a,
yeah,
it's a bad dude,
but yet it does.
Um,
it is a reoccurring theme.
This,
uh,
this thing where people are in these
incredibly hostile,
dangerous scenarios and they want to go
back,
they'd get over it and then they want to
go back.
Yup.
And the challenge,
whatever you get out of it.
Is that him?
Yeah,
that's him.
Oh,
there's a video of him doing it.
Oh yeah.
You Bet.
Was He born blind?
So he was born with a degenerative
retina disease called written look at
that shit.
Oh my God.
I mean that will swallow you bro.
How do you spell his last name?
Jamie.
So wine is what he does in the mountain
sometimes.
And then mayor of the city.
Well that's an old,
that's an old woman.
She's got hair right there.
Wow.
Uh,
but yeah,
that's him right there pulling up the
top.
But he's a,
he's a bad man,
dude.
And you know,
everybody loves him.
Some super blonde dude,
you know.
And I think that's why our relationship
is so strong is because I'm not afraid
to give him some shit and kind of
keeping grounded.
But behind the scenes,
he's,
he blows me away.
I got a lot.
Yeah.
He's a very special human being,
a that he could figure out how to
balance that and figure out how to go
left and go,
right.
Well,
he's an amazing athlete,
first and foremost.
I mean,
if he was cited,
he could been like a pro ball player.
You know,
he's just got that sort of body
awareness.
And then until he was born with a
degenerate retina disease,
so he was those under,
he was blind,
legally blind,
but then his retinas unraveled and at
the age of 13,
it was totally lights out.
And then his mama got killed in a car
wreck two years later.
Um,
and so he,
I mean,
it was,
it was step up.
Fortunately for him,
his dad,
uh,
his was a marine fighter pilot.
Ed and Ed was not about to let his blind
son sit back and let life go by.
So he grabbed him by the scuff of the
neck and took him on all these are all
these,
you know,
uh,
around the world as he got stationed in
different places.
And,
and,
uh,
and Eric just realize like pony up and
no time to feel and got Tom for sitting
around,
son get up.
And he did and he found rock climbing
and then rock climbing turned into
mountaineering.
And that's when we met
23 years ago,
23,
four years ago now.
I think this is all very hard for some
people to process,
especially people that haven't
experienced very difficult things are
very scary things or dangerous things.
You know,
that this,
that people would long to do this to be
a blind guy who's going through 270 plus
miles of water in a kayak.
Or to be someone who wants a summit
Mount Everest or to be someone who wants
to be a medic in a war zone or to be
Sebastian younger who was out there,
but you know,
embedded,
embedded.
Yeah.
For years,
right.
Years.
I,
and I think that maybe the general
population might look at that and feel
like maybe it's reckless or some are
super inspired and like,
Pan,
it's so great.
And then others are like,
yeah,
I mean I,
I'm,
I'm down.
Dude.
I'm psyched that you're out there
charging because then that sets the
template and what it does.
I think for a lot of people that just
says all that bond guy can do it well
then that means I should stop feeling
sorry for myself cause I'm feeling low
today.
There's their guarantee you there was a
lot of times when I don't feel like
training,
I don't really feel like going out and
doing something hard and then I'll think
I need to train harder to be strong
enough that when shit goes sideways I'll
have his back.
Yeah.
I know when you do train for something
like Everest,
how do you prepare for something like
that?
Climb.
Just climb up and down,
up and down.
Lots of weight.
Like a place like you know you go to
boulder or somewhere in the mountains
above it or yeah,
like way up in the hills and like big
long days,
long days.
Like 10,
12 hour days.
That's how he trained.
Yup.
To how many of those you do a week?
Um,
you know,
I mean two or three probably like big
long days.
I try to,
you know,
get broke the fuck off at least,
a couple of times a week where I'm like,
oof,
okay,
I know you can wait on your pack and
doing it the whole deal.
Those days of carrying big heavyweight,
I've kind of stopped doing that and I
just go,
uh,
because I like to feel a little bit more
free.
There was a time when I would put on a
big pack,
um,
you know,
and just,
just to feel that weight on my traps and
just only asking if he's experiencing 45
pounds,
he put it,
he has a new vest.
He was,
he was testing out the other day.
I saw,
I'm asking because it's crazy how 45
pounds,
which is not much at all.
No,
but it's a lot when you start walking up
hills.
Yeah.
You know,
some of these guys are probably carrying
way more than that.
Right?
Like 60 70 oh,
on Denali,
Denali packs close to a hundred as a
guide.
That's insane.
The clients would typically have,
oh,
it's a hundred pound pack and a 20 to 30
pounds sled.
And that was,
those were Denali days.
That's the 1213 14,000 feet.
That's not Bell Canyon.
That's,
yeah.
What are these guys built like?
Well,
I mean the ones who are good are pretty,
pretty narrow.
How the fuck are they carrying that much
weight?
I carried that much weight for years and
years and I mean,
I was a buck shifty back then,
you know,
and,
and we carry a hundred pounds and it
hurt,
you know,
but you just remember mountaineering is
slog.
I mean,
when you really move and luck on that
kind of mountain,
it's a slog.
It's really slow.
And then you've got a technical
training.
You best lighten your load,
that's,
you're not carrying a hundred a hundred
pounds,
then you caring,
you know,
or light light pack light is right.
You know,
ounces make pounds,
pounds make paint.
You gotta you got to feel like someone
carrying a hundred pounds.
You have to build up to that.
No.
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
There's all these weird stabilizing
muscles and your hip muscles and your
lower back and,
oh man,
I couldn't do it now.
I mean,
I couldn't do it.
I'm just,
I get sore thinking about it,
but I mean,
this was back in my twenties when I was
doing yell back to back Denali trips and
he didn't know any better.
I didn't know any better.
And it was like,
this is fun.
It was fun.
And it was cool.
I used to do a lot of expeditions
because I was the quintessential dirt
bag just so I could go eat,
you know,
so I could get fed and I didn't even
care.
I mean,
I would have done it for free on
expeditions just so you can get some
clues just to eat,
to know I was going to eat some dee dee
hydrated food.
Yeah.
I mean I was,
I was the,
I was living in my van man,
like start out being this guy
I grew up in.
I was born in North Carolina,
uh,
in the smokies and I grew up in Roanoke,
Virginia.
Uh,
and my parents are not adventurous at
all.
Uh,
but you know,
my dad and mom were both just working,
oh,
you know,
middle class,
hard working middle class folks.
And I was just a restless punk,
you know,
I was just super restless,
getting in trouble all the time.
And um,
you know,
I got arrested several times before I
was 18 and just bad,
just,
just restless and dumb like most of us I
think.
And went to school at,
at Tennessee for a year and got a 1.2 my
first semester and a 0.6.
It's possible to get a 0.6.
Wow.
Yep.
I had a d in racket ball.
No,
no three store.
You just weren't paying attention?
No,
I was,
I was drinking brown liquor and chasing
women and I was good at it.
A bit of both those things.
And so I failed out and then,
uh,
moved to Colorado in 1989 and uh,
moved to boulder and it's just a bunch
of hippies and like I was into the
grateful dead and I was,
you know,
tapping into some good fun things and
grow in my head.
And I fell in with a group of climbers
pretty,
pretty quick off who are a couple of
years older than me,
and they basically took me under their
wing and sort of gave me this
apprenticeship and taught me how to
knock it dead.
Wow.
Yeah.
Boulder's a real weird spot.
Right?
This is like fly fishing there and
kayaking and hikers and everyone's
riding mountain bikes and everyone's
fit.
It's weird because where's the fat
people?
There's no fat people in boom.
It's so weird.
You walk around,
everybody's got like Solomon's on and
shit.
Like everybody's coming in from a
workout.
Yeah.
Whole foods.
Just everybody stinky and find some
granola.
Neural Sinewy and shit ranchers.
There's a lot of people.
So I just,
I've,
I've lived in Boulder on and off for 28
years.
I went to medical school in Philadelphia
at Drexel Medical College,
Pennsylvania.
Other than that,
I've been in and out of boulder for 28
years and I,
I,
I'm,
we're moving to evergreen.
Uh,
we're moving to evergreen,
Colorado,
which is a super sweet spot,
but that's the reason I'm leaving
boulders because it's just,
it's pretty congested,
man.
A lot of people,
oh,
areas.
Lot of people live there.
And now I'm riding on the four oh five
here,
200,000 people.
I don't know how y'all do it.
One of the people I was talking to
alumni,
she was saying that she's going to bring
her nieces to California.
They'd never been outside of Maui.
They'd been a Lanai and Maui.
That's it.
So they haven't even been to fucking
Honolulu and now she's going to fly him
to Los Angeles.
They're going to go to Disneyland or
universal like what in the fuck she gave
him some mushroom.
See what happens.
Just don't need to that to be
overloaded.
I remember when I was a kid and uh,
we went from a New York too,
or from Boston rather than in New York
for uh,
some,
um,
I think it was for a karate tournament
or something like that.
But we were driving up the west side
highway and you see the city looming in
the distance,
like the death star.
And I remember thinking,
what in the fuck is this?
Like how are there,
I'm going to so many bills.
Boston's a city,
but it's not that kind of city.
It's not Manhattan.
It's,
yeah,
Manhattan.
It's something very unique and special
and it's,
yeah,
and you pull up to it,
you're like,
what is this?
This is,
it was so fun.
Intimidated.
Well that could go either way for those
kids,
right there.
Can't just be fascinated by the energy
or bug the fuck out and you know,
can't wait to get back to them.
And all this amount of stimuli that you
get in an environment like that,
it's just overwhelming.
But you're like,
boulders too much.
It's too much.
Too many people now there's almost a
hundred thousand,
well do this any longer.
I don't like to sit in my truck.
I like to move,
you know,
if I'm going to go drive somewhere,
I want to drive there and park,
get out and go in and do my deal and
come back.
And then,
you know,
the trails are pretty,
pretty populated to you go climbing,
you've got to wait in line.
Um,
and sometimes you gotta go up like,
like roped climbing when people are
going up sides either getting their
stuff at dawn really can get up.
Yeah.
That's a lot of people getting busy out
in the woods,
which is cool.
But you know,
I'm just feeling like,
you know,
it was a lot of,
a lot of folks,
it turns out the older I get,
the less people he wants to talk to you
soon.
I think also that's,
you know,
you're involved these intense situations
like being in Iraq or like being on ever
since.
Sometimes you just want to sit back and
process it all.
Yeah.
It would sit on the rocking chair and I
liked to,
you know,
I want to mow my yard.
I would,
or I want to drive my tractor around and
sip on a beer.
I'm a,
I'm a southern boy at heart and I like
quiet things.
I know a bunch of guys who've moved out
there for that very reason.
Yeah.
It makes sense.
And uh,
so we're moving there here in a couple
of weeks.
That's awesome.
The in the landscape couldn't be
prettier.
It's nice.
Beautiful.
It's real nice how the winters are
brutal.
They ain't gold hill winters though.
No,
no.
That's,
that's way worse.
But it's brutal,
you know.
No,
it's real.
You gotta read.
You gotta get ready.
Yeah,
we live on,
we live on a dirt road.
Holla out there.
Huh?
I pulled up the Joe's house.
There's an old power wagon,
his old house in Boulder and old power
wagon with a snow plow and there's a
couple of snow machines down there and
I'm pulling my,
do you know why those things are there
joe?
Cause you've got to pour yourself out.
No Snowman.
I,
when I lived in Boston,
I drove a van.
I drove a delivered newspapers.
I drove 365 days a year.
So I drove every fucking day.
Every time a blizzard hit,
every time snow hit,
I'm not scarce now.
I know how to drive in snow.
I mean it's not fun to get stuck and you
will get stuck,
but it doesn't bother me.
It doesn't freak me out.
But to someone who's never been in snow,
yeah,
it ain't the place to play.
But if you had to choose between,
like it's,
you know,
it's a tough call because like would you
rather live in like Phoenix right now?
I heard it's 124 degrees that they're
canceling flights because it's so hot
that canceling flights.
Yeah.
You know,
I mean I don't do something about that
cold and snow too.
That's like really peaceful.
Like there's something that people don't
like.
I remember when I was a kid,
one of the things that I really liked
about snow is a special,
when I had to deliver newspapers,
it's like I would have to be out there
and you would hear nothing because the
snow muffles all the sound.
So it's like you get a kind of peace and
quiet that you don't,
no one's driving cause it's,
you know,
there's two feet of snow.
So you were out there and it's just
nothing,
nothing and everything soft and you hit
it,
watch,
watch for of your feet on the ground and
that's it.
You know,
it's like you,
and then I think people that live in
those environments like live in the
cold,
you'll appreciate summer for real.
Like you really appreciate summer out
here every day.
Summer,
nobody gives a shit.
It's 75 degrees perfect in January,
you know,
and you go into boulder and on the cu
campus,
you know,
like you get a 60 degree,
50 degree day in the spring,
you know,
get you to just go down to their daisy
dukes.
Whoa.
You know,
like they're like,
he needs to put up those feathers that's
sent fly.
Well,
yeah.
Wow.
So what's next for you,
man?
What are you going to do now?
We're going to figure it out between now
and next spring cause springs when I
start getting the Itch,
uh,
you don't have to go do something.
And so how do you guys work it out?
Do you like come to him with an idea or
does he,
do you guys sit down and talk about it?
Well,
we can't talk about it or can't talk
about financial.
Well,
he just pitched something to me
yesterday that's pretty interesting and
adventurous and fun and curious and a
mystery to that of a Jeff Good tv.
I mean,
he's a good person in general,
but he's also really good tv.
We have a mystery.
Two guys have already died trying to do
it.
Oh Jesus.
Check,
check.
Yes.
And it's pretty dangerous.
And I want to put a team together and
Jeff leading the team and see if we can
go pull it off.
Oh my God,
Dude.
Well listen,
don't die.
And uh,
come back when you live and we'll talk
about it.
Come back when I live.
Yes.
I like that idea.
It's fun living.
It turns out,
oh yeah,
I enjoy life.
And do you enjoy it more when you come
back?
Yeah.
Once again,
like gratitude to her.
Like,
you know,
like I love it all.
I don't want my kids a total slob and
like really drop shit and makes mess
everywhere.
And I'm like,
I love that boy.
You know,
like you're a little fuck up.
And I just love you.
Remember what you were like.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Boy.
I mean it's,
it's,
that's the universe saying,
what's up bitch?
Yeah.
Here you go.
What are you going to do with this kid?
You gotta take him to Everest.
Uh,
he's a little long haired kid that's
just trying to find his way and I can
relate,
you know,
he's trying to figure it out.
No one just knows their way.
There is no everyone find their way.
No,
you have to.
I'm still looking,
man.
And you always will be.
Yeah.
And that's the good thing.
I think that's part of what I'm doing
while I'm doing it.
I'm still looking a hundred percent,
you know,
I'm still trying to figure it out and
I'm trying to do the best I can help and
people where I can,
I don't have,
I don't have a wide array of skills,
but I know how to help people when
they're having a hard go.
That's a great path though.
I mean,
the path of service,
the path of helping people and the
gratitude and the,
the experience that you get from that,
that's,
that's very positive.
Yeah.
I mean,
I feel like if I can instill any of that
in my boy,
like I win,
you know,
it's be,
be grateful,
like,
yeah.
Live,
live a grateful life.
And,
and by living that,
what does that mean?
It's like,
you know,
pay it forward,
show gratitude,
show love,
show compassion,
um,
and,
and allow people to,
to be the best version of them and do
the boats you can to make them better.
You know?
Well said and I didn't know.
I didn't know that until I met Eric,
you know,
honest with you,
he was a catalyst for all that.
Wow.
That's amazing that one person can
change the course of your life that much
just by existing and being around them,
experiencing how they navigate life.
Yeah.
That's how I learn.
Well listen man,
thanks for doing this.
Really appreciate it.
Thanks for bringing them on.
We'll do it again back when you guys
survive cause you're going to survive.
Right.
Okay.
We'll do it again.
We'll do it again and we'll talk about
it.
All right.
That was fun,
Bro.
Thank you.
Joe.
Ya.