And we're live. Hi Sir. What's going on
man? Very well. Thank you. First of all,
thank you very much for
the coffee machine in this.
I just learned that it's turmeric.
I used to say Tumeric,
I used to not even think there was an RN
in there for some strange reason. Well,
in Hawaii it's Olana. So it just depends
on which country you're in. Yeah,
it's a diff what did, what is, what
is, it's a root, right? Yup. Ginger,
the ginger family. And is it, why
do they call it Olana? Is that up?
That's just the Hawaiian name. I mean, the
Indians probably have another, you know,
in India it's probably one of
the most use, uh, you know,
are our route. They, it's in every era.
All Indian foods. It's full of it. Yeah.
Yeah. It's really healthy for you. Right?
It's great for inflammation. At what?
Gut Health too. So you,
uh, gave me this layer,
superfoods coffee machine,
and I'm addicted to this now.
This coffee with turmeric.
I've never had it before. Well,
there's some other minerals
and stuff in there too.
So if you're addicted to it is because
there's things that are good for you.
Yeah. Like I crave it. Like it seems like
something that was your body wants it.
Yeah. I, you know, I think
sometimes people think
cravings are based on negative.
Like, oh I just, it's bad cause I crave
it. But I think cravings are natural.
I think it went, but it's, you know,
we abuse it when we use garbage,
but when you craving something like
that, I mean there's, you know,
a bunch of minerals in and a bunch of
good fats and there's a bunch of good
stuff in there. Yeah. It's
hard to tell though, right?
Like sometimes you crave sugar,
sometimes you crave ice cream. Yes.
There's some cravings that are not
good. Exactly. Other ones are exactly.
But the system of craving,
I believe,
what is part of a natural human thing
that we have that was meant to crave good
things, but we abuse it with cause
sugar and nature is meant to be safe.
That means it's safe to eat. Right, right,
right. So, so yeah. So then we, so that,
but then we abuse it by disguising a bunch
of garbage with sugar and then people
think, oh, that's great to
eat. That makes sense. Yeah.
Cause whenever I lift weights,
I crave protein. Yeah.
Crave like fish or chicken or steak
or something. Yeah. Well you're,
you're beating up muscles.
You want protein. Yeah.
But it's an instantaneous craving.
Yeah. It's like right away I'm like, Oh,
I've got to eat something. Yeah. Um,
so you've got me crank in the sauna up.
Uh,
your wife told me that you crank
years up to 220 degrees. Is that real?
That's real. God Damn Man. I get
to two 10. I'm like, this is,
how long do you do at two
20? Well, it depends on how,
how cold you go into it. Oh,
oh. So if your, if your body,
if your core temperature is weighed
down, you can, you know it, if you,
if you've got off the stationary bike
and your core was nice and hot and you
went in there, you know, you'd be lucky
to get 10 or 10 or 15 minutes out.
If you come out of a ice tub or you've
been outside with minimal clothing,
you could go in there and for 20
minutes at two 20 so it just depends on,
you know, where your, what your core
team, you know, where your core is.
Is that how you do it?
You do from an ice bath.
I will do it from a nice path that
just, you know, I, you just break it up.
It's just like anything,
any kind of training,
you just want to constantly
stress the system.
And if you're used to a certain
pattern, you know, go into it hot.
Like if you go into a sauna hot coming
off of some cardio that it's twice as hot.
If you go in cold then you can
go for a longer period of time.
And same with the ice. I mean, if you go
into the ice cold, the ice, we'll tap you.
If you go in hot,
you can be there.
So they're doing some studies
now on hot yoga at a Harvard.
They're trying to figure out if hot yoga
mimics the positive health effects of
Sauna. And so the idea is that, you know,
because you're straining and resisting,
it's,
it feels much hotter than 104 degrees.
You have a journal that was 104 hundred
five degrees would be nothing for sure.
But Yoga at 105 degrees, it's pretty
rough. Rough. Well, because again,
core temperatures spot. So
we do some stationary bikes
in the sauna. Wow. And that,
I mean, that's just a, it's like you
can always up the ante, you know,
it's like a weight stack. You just
slap more led on there. And we'll do,
we'll do,
we'll go in this with an assault bike.
I have an assault bike and one of the
Saunas and we'll crank that thing up.
And you know, I mean, you're lucky if he
might be five or 10 minutes and you're,
you're, but I think, you know, we're
such good adapters or our, you,
our adaptation is amazing and
you do some stuff for a while.
I think you did it pretty soon. You're
like, oh, I can handle, uh, you know,
an assault bike and at, at a survivable
pace, you know? Yeah. Survive.
That's a rough machine. Rough machines.
I have the rogue versions of echo bike.
Yeah. That thing is fantastic. I love
it. For sure. That's all four limbs,
all four limbs. It's one of my all time
fee to two Bottas Tabata sprints on it.
An all time favorite method of
Cardio for sure. For sure. Well,
low impact on the system. You're not
beating every, the joints. Um, every,
all four things are working and you could
throw in some nose breathing in there
or something and breath holding
intervals or something just to, you know,
we're seeing in suffering. You were
explaining nose breathing to me out there.
Yeah. How nose breathing is better. Better
for you because of, well, first of all,
you were designed to breathe your
sinuses and your nose were designed for
breathing. And so you actually
admit a gas in your sinuses.
From my understanding, a gas called
nitric oxide, which is a vasodilators,
helps you absorb oxygen.
So by breathing through your nose,
plus you reduce the amount of intake
that you have and that gets you CO2
tolerance. So all of a sudden you're,
you're breathing less volume. I mean,
you know, from the fight game, we, as
soon as the guy goes to mouth breathing,
you're like, he's toast. You know that,
right? That's your first giveaway.
So your ability to deal with stress
and breathe through nose, I mean,
everybody should be breathing
through their nose in their sleep,
walking around.
I mean,
we somehow we became mouth breathers in
the last 200 years and they're not sure
why. There's a great book
called the Oxygen Advantage,
uh, by Patrick Mcgill that,
uh, he actually is on our board
of XPT but he, he, you know,
kind of realized that our issues really
stem from mouth breathing, chronic, uh,
mouth breathing,
which is scrubbing our CEO to and
keeping our co two levels down,
which is the market of absorb oxygen.
So when your co two levels are down,
you don't absorb the oxygen from your
bloodstream. The cells don't take it.
As soon as this co two goes up,
then the,
then the body starts to pull it
out of the blood. Interesting.
So smaller amounts by breathing through
the nose actually makes you absorb more
oxygen while keeps your
tolerance and tolerance.
But definitely get your
CEO too tolerant up.
But the smaller volume helps your body
become more tolerant of higher levels of
co two.
But the nose,
the sinuses themselves emit a gas that
helps the lung absorb the oxygen is,
and that's, you know, that's
what I've been led to understand.
I had a broken nose until I was 40.
My nose was useless.
I couldn't get anything out of it.
It had been broken,
like who knows how many times.
Yeah.
And it was all the inside was all caked
up with scar tissue and calcified.
And when I got it fixed, it was like
the world change. It was like, ah,
I couldn't do that.
I just couldn't breathe out of my nose.
I would go to yoga class. They tell me
to breathe at. All I know is I'm like,
I don't have one. Yeah, I could
smell farts. Yeah, that's it.
I could smell gas and gasoline. Like
it has to be rough for me to smell it.
But now I have a real nose.
Yeah. I always encourage people,
if you have a broken nose, please get that
deviated septum fixed. Well, you know,
it's surprising if you
start to nose breathe,
even if you have struggle because of the,
that gas is helps you open
up a lot of people. I mean,
I'm not saying that you have that,
but a lot of people actually will gain
volume after a few weeks of forcing
themselves to nose breathe. They'll
actually start to open up all of that,
that system. Does that make sense? So
your body would just adapt and try.
It forces it to, to open. But yeah,
no it's all about nose breathing.
I didn't think,
I just thought it was just more difficult.
So it's probably a good thing to
do for discipline. Absolutely.
And if you can do your cardio
and retain a nose breath, you're,
you have another gear because then when
you go to mouth it's like you gotta it's
like having a blower on your car or
something. You open up the, you know,
you open up the air and
it's a whole new game.
So by being able to sustain a
high output nose breathing then,
and like I said,
it's all about the tolerance for CO2.
It's how much co two you can
handle in your system. You know,
like that's why altitude screws people
up cause the CEO two jacks up and they
don't have a tolerance and then you get
all wonky and you feel like crap. Yeah.
And it's interesting that you're talking
about cravings because one of the
things that I've noticed since I've
been, I cranked up the, to the,
the temperature in the sauna for the
first week to 200 degrees that I've been
doing to 10 for the last few days.
And uh, you crave it now. I crave it.
Like when I'm at home,
I'm like,
I can't wait to get back to that
God damn song again. Meanwhile,
when I'm in there, I can't wait to get
out. It's weird. They're within lies.
The struggle. I mean ice is the same way.
Like I have an addiction to ice and I,
you know,
uh,
recently I've been just came back from
Hawaii and I'm like dealing with ice
machine's broken down.
I've been waiting for the new one.
I keep calling the guy and go, hey,
when are you gonna put the thing in?
And He's thinking it's like
a luxury. Like, yeah, you're,
you know, you've got it.
What do you need an ice
machine at your house for him?
Cause I have to like restaurant
size ones. Yeah. And,
well I have a lot of friends, but
he's like, what do you need that for?
And I'm like, I like just just get, you
know, he's got the tubs. I'm like, I need,
my body craves. You get it. Listen,
your body is just craving the things
that are bringing the hormones and do it.
I mean it's like why you crave exercise.
You know?
I have a theory that the reason why
people are hooked to cardio activity is
because it's forced breathing that people,
because you wouldn't willingly just sit
on your floor and breathe heavy for an
hour. So your body's like, okay, let's go
for a run. Like let's go. You need to run,
you better run,
and then you go run and then the
body gets that absorption of, oh,
it gets at a oxygen.
Then it really wants to feel.
I feel like there's probably several
factors cause also I feel like when I'm
really consistent with my workouts,
I know that I'm gaining momentum and I
know like, ah, you know, I'm consistent,
everything's going great,
I'm in great shape right now.
I've got to keep pushing this. Yeah.
That feels like it's, it feels like a,
like just,
just positive results are being achieved
and you can sort of get addicted to
success. Well and, and it, but
also to the body, the adaptation,
if you ever put yourself under some
real severe stress in multiple days,
the first day you feel like you're
not gonna be able to make it.
The second day you're feeling, you know,
like you can't really can't make it.
The third, pretty soon, the
fourth day the body is like, oh,
this is the new house we're living
in. Like this is where we're at. Okay,
well we're going to adapt and modify.
And then pretty soon you're doing even
more your than you were doing the first
couple of days and you're not even
feeling it. And so it's like we're,
that we're an amazing, an
amazing machine. You know,
we're an amazing creature. Just the
way we can handle the load and the,
and especially in this, in our
new world where we, you know,
don't have to do much unless we want to.
Um,
do you know Eddie Izzard is, yeah.
The comedian. Yeah, yeah. He,
he ran a series of marathons all around
the UK and we did one in South Africa
and he was on two weeks ago.
And he was telling me that when
you first started doing it,
like the first few were really hard,
but then your body's like,
well this is what we do.
We run marathons and then like day three,
day four things started picking up day
five and by the time day 10 came along,
he's just running for
sure. Yeah, for sure.
I've got a friend ran 125 in a row and
then he ran the Boston after that and
then he had a fight in Vegas and he ran
a marathon in the morning and then he
like knocked the guy out in
the third round and after,
I mean he says he met his marathon in
the morning and then fought that day.
Holy Shit. That's a cause.
This Tom Jones. Yeah.
Moitai seven time white Thai
world champion. Jesus zone.
Yeah. Yeah. The fuck man.
You run a marathon a day,
you fight it magic put dude,
knock two out. I'd be like,
I'm done. This is not me. Yeah, I'm
going to learn how to play golf. Yeah.
Fuck this. Moitai fuck this
Tom Jones. What I would say,
that's crazy.
So he got 125 marathons in a row,
so 125 days of marathons, two
Boston, and then he ran the Boston.
When he got there,
he ran across the country.
What he ran across the country.
So that's how he got there.
So he did run America, took a nap, ate
some food, ran a marathon, took a nap.
It's like, what the fuck
buddy? But just shows you that,
you know, that ability to adapt and
what we can, you know what we can do?
It's amazing how the body will just,
when you push it and you keep,
it'll just be like, it'll ramp. I
mean, and I think for us in this,
in our new world that we live in,
that seemed so crazy,
but probably in the past you were like,
oh yeah,
well we went all the way down to South
America and we did some hunting down
there. And then we, you know,
trek marathon or two per day and we came
all the way back to Alaska, you know,
like right. You know, like that
was just our life a lot. Yeah.
Well especially when they used
to persistence hunt, you know,
when they would just run an animal down.
Yeah,
the animals are great for sprints but
for especially like gazelles and things
along those lines. But you know
what though? You know what though,
the real technique really is
based on is that our breathing,
that breathing is what gives us,
we have an ability to adjust our breath
so we can actually adjust how many times
we breathe PIR motion where a lot of
these animals are breathing for a Rep.
Every rep is a breath.
So every step is,
and we can do multiple steps in
one breath and so that why are,
that's why we can outrun a horse.
At the end of the day,
you always see the in the cowboy movies,
a horses laying dead in the desert
and the guy still going along.
But because the,
those mammals are breathing every breath
as a rep and you imagine how tiring
that is.
Like you're a horse ride [inaudible]
right there breathing every and where are
we running full speed,
but we can just do a breath and then do
five or six or eight reps and that gives
us that endurance.
That's why we can run those gazelles
down because those guys are just breathed
there. Their breath out.
That's interesting. Well I'm,
I'm always very appreciative of guys
like you that are in my age range.
I'm just speed limit.
Yeah, speed limit. You're,
but you're also very fit and
very active and you keep going.
Whereas a lot of guys around 55
like it's a wrap turn off the car.
Yeah,
it's,
there's not much in the tank and so
I like to see guys that are in my age
bracket or a little bit ahead
of me like, oh, he's going go,
I can keep going to full spin.
I think a lot of that is just
thinking and knowing that you can,
because I think so many people feel like,
Hey, I'm 45, it's time to settle down.
It's time to relax and wind down this
exercise. You know? I bet you know, I,
I think, but I think that people use
that as a disclaimer and not do the work.
It's like, now I'm 45, so now I
don't, now I don't, I'm too old.
For me, I think that's a way
out. Right? That's a way to go.
Hey, I don't want to do the work anymore.
And you know, I have, uh, my, uh,
one of my best friends just passed this
last year and he was 85 when he passed.
And uh, and he was crazy. I mean,
he did the iron man 10 times.
The first time was when he was 50.
Um,
and then he's done the race across
America three times and he does just,
he was just an animal bang iron every day,
ride the bike to just a 85.
He was doing all that stuff and
animal an animal till the day he died.
I was like, wow. And His name was,
and this is the irony was
his name was don wild man.
And so like that's his given name.
No, I'm serious. That's, it's amazing.
His given name. I go, anybody named the
wild man. Got to keep it up. But he was,
you know, like you're talking about,
uh, when you can see it right. When you,
what does it look like when
I see, I mean, you look at,
it's interesting to see
in sports right now.
We have a lot of athletes right now
that are operating as though they're the
oldest that, you know,
that they, that we've seen.
And I believe a lot of it has to do
with the fact that that, uh, you know,
that they've have some examples, but
they're also not take accepting that, hey,
now you're too old like that. Just
because that's a decision like, Hey, oh,
now you're too old. Oh yeah.
You know, you're going to
keep doing that. It's like,
yeah, you're going to do it all the way
until they throw the dirt on the box.
You know, like we're going all the
way full speed. Until we're not.
And then when we're not, we're not,
what did Mr Wildman die of? Uh,
it was eventually it was a cancer that
he couldn't get a fight through chemo.
And so, but, but, but it was within like
couple of weeks, like he just was like,
shut it down. Um, he was at
one point, he was like the,
he was a little bit like the everready
bunny and, and Humpty dumpty,
like he would just like double
knee surgery, like within,
like we hit a broken leg and he'd be on
a stationary bike with a crush on one of
the pedals and he'd be peddling and
crutching well on the other leg, I mean,
he was just absolutely
out of his mind and,
and the doctors would be like, oh,
you're healing faster than a 30 year old.
And I'm like, yeah, well he's,
cause he's just a cardio monster.
And so he's getting that blood
flow. And, uh, and he, uh,
we were helicopters snowboarding in Chile,
the s uh, last summer, not this one,
but the one before. And I was with the
run with the guide and the guy goes, hey,
you know, I'll hold your
buddy. And I'm like, oh,
he's 84 and he looked at me and he's like,
yeah, no, no, I mean, but how old is he?
And I'm like, he's 84 and he's
like, yeah, he's 84. Like,
check it out buddy. He's
going fakey. And like, I mean,
you know, he was, but he was our, he
was our poster child. He's our guy.
We looked at, we go, I mean, and I've
had a few of those. I think it, you know,
that I've been exposed to in my
life where there's guys that just,
those are the guys that I always admired.
I always admired the guys that just
were always going full speed and never,
never sir can, you know, they
didn't sir come to all that,
all that pressure from society. Like,
Hey, you're old now. We can still do that.
What do you think you were a kid? Just
all the bullshit that you can feed into,
uh, and, and be a victim of. Yeah.
We have these preconceived notions of
what it's like to be 30 what it's like to
be 50 what it's like to be 85
and some people like, yeah,
you could fuck that. I'm
not interested. Yeah.
Because they're never looking at ages.
Some as some like feeling
like they're like,
they're never going all 35 you feel like
this at 40 all you're slowing down now,
I'll da Da da. You know, and not get any,
just you lay down. It's like, you know,
I always say if people stop doing
something, like they go, oh,
I'm going to retire now, man,
I'm getting old in the sport.
It's really not that they're getting old,
it's just that they've made a decision
that they would want to do anymore.
And they just used the age as a, like
a disclaimer. Like, Hey, I'm, I'm good.
You know? Yeah. It was. For some folks,
I think it's a mental tiredness for sure.
Keeping up their enthusiasm is probably
the difficult thing and that's why I
think a lot of people look
forward to retirement, right?
They look forward to those golden
years where they just holding hands and
walking towards the sunset. Just
jump on a sword. I mean, no, I'm sad.
I mean it's like at that point you're
just so then you're just alive, dead.
You know, you're, you're, you're,
you're dead, but you're alive. Like,
but I think some people look forward
to some day where they don't have to
struggle then they can't be on
earth. Yeah, you can't be, you can't,
well you can, I mean like, I'm sorry,
the system is a little
bit designed to struggle.
Everything that we do that's good for us
has a, has a certain amount of stress.
Just like you want to get that sauna,
you want to get on that salt bike,
you want to jump in that ring,
you want to hike that mountain.
It's all stress driven.
And the fact is that's our universe.
That's the universe we live in. And, and
so if you got some other, and you know,
and I appreciate,
let's hack our way through it and I think
there's waste that hacking supports us.
We can hack our way to, but only
support the things that we're doing,
but thinking that you can just hack your
way through and not actually suffer,
it's impossible. You
just, you got to suffer.
I also think you don't appreciate the
good times unless you suffer absolute
outside. I think I appreciate
food more when I work out.
I appreciate life more. I like doing
things more at when I struggle.
Absolutely. I can tell you, I know
sitting down is an incredible thing.
Like when you go, wow, this feels
so good, I just sit down. Yeah,
because you're streaming. Yeah, for sure.
But a lot of people don't
recognize that that's a lesson.
I think people really need to get drilled
in their head. It's not that tricky,
right. No. I'm going to say this isn't
rocket science. This isn't like elaborate.
It's available for everybody. Just
move. Yeah. Key move. Just keep going.
Drive it hard and I can promise you
you'll, you'll, you'll sleep better.
Like everybody, we have a lot of sleeping
issues right now and I'm just like,
well, people aren't tired
enough. Yeah. Like my daughter
was like, oh yeah, you know,
having a hard time sleeping.
And now she's been banging tennis balls
seven hours a day and I'll tell you,
she and I have a problem sleeping now.
Right. She had been real well. I'm like,
yeah, it and I, you know,
I think there's a lot of,
it's just a lack of movement or
this, we just stopped moving. Yeah.
And then your brain races because
your body's not getting exhausted.
So you've develop all this
anxiety and all this weirdness.
Hunter gatherers did not have the
need for Ambien. I guarantee it. Yeah.
There was the other day,
there was no Melatonin. They
were showing me. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. The melatonin was, was, you know,
created in their retina from staring
at the sun and the early morning light.
I mean that's,
they were up,
they were moving and they were up
early and they were, and they were,
and they were going
until dark and that dark,
it was time to lay down and then you just
did that and you were not sleep issues.
We're in a problem back
then. It's, it's interesting.
I'm learning from my dog because my dog
is up first thing in the morning when
you start things up and
then when it starts getting
dark out, once he eats, man,
he's just laying down. He was like,
what's up? Chilling over here. Oh yeah.
Well and I, I'm a constantly studying
my dog. I would have brought him,
but he's getting his nails done
today. This is really, yeah. Yeah.
Well cause he's just ripping up the floor.
He's got some hooks but uh,
but I watch him never leaves his bed
without stretching first in the morning.
First thing dumped up dog down,
done full up,
down dog and then he full speed
80 miles an hour, like a rocket.
And then just write to the couch and
lay down and then just be totally asleep
and then just up full speed back to
the couch and lay down. I've got, I go,
there's something to be said about that
thing. A little stretch, full speed.
Lay down. We'll speed laid out like, but
no warmup, no warm up. That's no warm up.
But people need warm up. Do you agree?
I don't know if I had, I don't know.
I don't know about, I don't know about
warm up. I think warm up is being alive.
I think you know, I mean, I
mean never warmed up. I mean,
what's that? What about if you're
going to lift something heavy?
Do you think that you should
warm the muscles up first? Well,
I think if you set the thing up and you
put everything on and you set it all up,
you're already starting to warm up and
if you're psyching up and getting your
brain ready to do something aggressive,
I think that you've already,
the adrenaline's already going and
you've got a lot of stuff. I mean,
I know if you just get up off the chair
and walk over and try to grab a giant
bar with a bunch of weight on it and
lift it, that might be a problem.
But that wouldn't be,
you would never do that in nature when
you were going to lift something heavy.
It usually,
there'd be some lead up to it,
whether you walk to the place that you
were gunning when you've got the thing.
And, you know, I mean, you know, I
don't know. I don't know about about,
cause I think there's mixed
opinions about, you know,
people say don't stretch
before you work out.
And that's been the most recent
thing before it used to be all yeah.
Loosen up before you work
out. And I'm like, I mean my
dog does down dog, you know,
up dog down dog.
And that's only after he's laying down
and then he just goes full speed at,
I mean well I know that if I do Moitai
if I'm hitting the bag or something like
that,
I don't go hard at first to break a sweat.
I do the first two rounds, I'm just
shadowboxing. Yeah. I'm just putting,
I mean I don't fully full blast
the bag until I'm sweaty. Yeah.
But that's just my thoughts.
I mean I just,
I feel like that's the
way you're supposed to do.
That's what I've always been told.
Yeah. When, I mean I think the,
I think I would connect that more did
part of it is because of what we are now.
[inaudible] cause I sedentary
and cause, yeah, we're not,
we're not what we, you know,
we are not fully in our,
in our nature essence, we're
not, we're not wild. You know,
if we were wild, I think we would need
as much any warmup up. When you're wild,
you don't need a warm up.
But I think because we're not moving as
much because if you're moving all the
time,
you'd already be warmed up there.
Would like to see a human
from like 5,000 years ago.
I'd love to be around like a hunter
gatherer and see what they looked like.
Their pain threshold was crazy. First
of all, they are what they could endure.
You know,
their pain threshold was just [inaudible]
of the cycle of pro bono arm and be
like, we'd still be operating with broken
stuff. No problem. What did they do?
They just kind of like tied
it up or something. I mean,
I don't know what that was. That was
when they advanced into medical, right?
Yeah. A lot of them probably just
hobbled around until it didn't hurt.
That's where inflammation came
in. Everything got inflamed.
So they would hold it,
you know, naturally the body would
hold it in position so that you,
I mean inflammation is designed to kind
of immobilize a cast. It, it would,
you know,
if it was your ankle,
it just gets so swollen I couldn't
move but they'd still be on it.
They'd still be role and it just,
they wouldn't be moving it around because
the body would naturally do down the
future of humans is not look so rosy
when you really think about how we're
slowly deteriorating becoming
these gelatinous balls of
meat and what issue and
the bodies are connected to the brains.
And so that's why we have some mind
issues too because at the end of the day,
the bodies aren't functioning correctly
so that it's not feeding the brain
correctly. And so the
brain, that's why we,
I mean I think that when you're really
physically well then your thoughts are
physically well. I think it's
definitely, it definitely helps.
But people do not like to hear that. Do
you notice that you noticed that? Yeah,
absolutely. If you don't, I didn't even
like you, like you seem like a happy guy,
you know,
I don't care if you're on any medication,
but some people who are want
to think like, no, no, no,
I have a medical problem and I need this.
Even if they don't exercise, they go, no,
no, no. You don't understand. And then
if I say, okay, but do you ever exercise,
they get mad at you. Absolutely. They
get mad. Like, absolutely you're,
you're suggesting I'm lazy,
but you're suggesting I brought this
upon myself because of my behavior.
I know I have a disease.
Yeah, no way. Again,
I think that's a disclaimer that's a way
out. To not have to take, be accountable,
be accountable. Like, Hey,
that if I was out doing moving and doing
things that it would actually make this
go away. You know? I mean, I, I think
that, uh, you know, I think a lot of,
a lot of depression is
connected to, to the, you know,
I believe ice icing could
cure a big PR portion of,
of depression just because of the
hormonal to the system and the, you know,
I mean normally when people are depressed
is connected to some sort of hormone
imbalance and to have a doctor
tried to figure out what that is,
it's pretty elaborate.
That's pretty tricky. Well,
they've shown in studies that regular
exercise is as effective at ssrs or more.
Exactly. Yeah, exactly. I think
also diet because of inflammation,
the inflammation for sure leads to
all sorts of different ailments,
which could lead to a depressed feeling,
feeling of unwellness well just eat a
bunch of garbage for a week and see how
you feel. Yeah, I can talk,
I'd be depressed or just drink
some layers to the coffee stuff.
That shit, man. So the sauna thing,
what is the benefit of
getting it that hot?
Well [inaudible] I know they
said, honestly, my problem
is, is that, you know, if,
if, if a lot is good, then even
more is better than, you know,
that's a little bad to
my, we're both like, Hey,
no, I'm just saying like, yeah, you know,
if ten's good than 20 he's got
to be even better. But you know,
I think part of it is
the natural evolution.
If you're sitting there doing time
at, you know, 180 degrees and you,
and you can go on there and you're,
you know, you're hanging out
and then just 20 minutes,
it's 30 minutes.
So you might as well just
try to turn it up. And, and,
and my understanding is that the
Europeans, I mean, I'd be, you know,
you look at a sweat lodge and you,
I mean,
it ain't one 80 you know,
if you go into any kind of sweat lodge,
if you go to Europe, all the
Saunas are a much hotter. Like,
it's like you go into a rush
and, you know, steam thing.
It's not like those
things are, you know, I,
I think that they're pretty
conservative with it. I think.
I think you just listen to your body.
If you'd go in there and you start
hallucinating, you might want to step out,
you know, you might be
like, Hey, you know, uh,
maybe I eat something wrong or maybe
I need to just get my body a break.
But I think you just use your, you
know, use your, your, your own feeling,
uh, as a, as your guide and, and
you know, I know that I, if I,
if I'm height properly
hydrated before I go,
my tolerance is substantially greater.
Like I can really measure it.
I can be hydrated, go in and
be like, oh yeah, no problem.
And I can go and dehydrated and feel wonky
and be like, hmm, yeah, I'm not as good.
So that makes sense. Yeah.
I definitely have adapted.
I've definitely adapted to 200
degrees because when I go to yoga now,
it does not seem nearly as hot 105
degrees. Even at the end of the class,
I'm like, this is interesting. I was
thinking of the last class, I was like,
this doesn't feel that bad. Exactly. Yeah.
Well that shows you right there that
you're adapting and then all of a sudden
your tolerance.
You know,
a thing I really like about the sauna
is I think it really plays into into
overheating as an athlete.
It over, you know,
you overheat and that's usually
when you have issues, right?
As you overheat and then you and then you,
your performances is encumbered,
right? You just see it and so the more
your tolerance is for the heat, the less,
the more
you can handle overheating.
Pretty soon you don't overheat and then
you just don't have that cause that,
that,
that's one of the factors that gets an
athlete I think as in any performance as
you overheat, if, whether you're fighting
or marathon running or basketball,
any sport, when you start to overheat
your, that's usually when you're,
you're toast, you're done, you start
losing your motor skills and you're tall.
If you can build that tolerance up.
And I think, like you said, hey,
if I go into 202 20 and then all of a
sudden you're at Yoga, uh, you know,
you're at hot yoga and it's 105 and
you're just like [inaudible]. Yeah,
it really does make a giant difference.
I've only been doing it at
200 for a couple months now.
Really in to 10. Look for,
like I said, last few days. Yeah. But you
have been doing it this hot for how long?
Well, I've been doing it for
a while, like I've been doing,
it's been over the last couple
of years. You know, I did one,
I did a protocol that, uh, I heard on
a doctor, Rhonda Patrick's a show and,
and it was a holding, uh, a one hour,
a one hour straight at
somewhere between 170 to 180.
Whoa. So that's another, and you,
if you do that 10 days in a row,
I was doing it twice a
day for 10 days in a row.
And you're supposed to get like
some 1600% hormonal boosts,
like your whole body just goes into this
radical hormone [inaudible] 72 one 80,
somewhere in that, right?
Yep. Interesting. One 71
day, one hour straight.
I was doing that and I'd get it twice
a day for 10 days in a row. And, and,
and uh, and, and, and at the end of that,
you've got a different gear. It's like
all of a sudden you got o d in your,
in your, in your, in your
gearbox. Interesting. Well,
it definitely increases the red blood cell
count. Correct? Absolutely. Yeah. I mean,
I don't know all the science. I
just usually go off of, you know,
I usually go off of, uh, of
instinct and then, and then I,
and then sometimes it gets validated by,
by science and so at the end, you know,
[inaudible] I mean, I, I think and,
and I, and there really isn't any,
any studies on it, but I
truly believe that, that,
that he is better after
performance for recovery than ice.
I mean, I think isis
comfortable. Um, I had my, uh,
I don't have a whole thing about
paying a relationship with pain and,
and I was doing a thing with, uh, I
had a hip hip replacement and, uh,
I was set up to do all
this icing before and,
and then I learned that icing
suppress the, the, the, uh,
healing hormone, IGF one,
there's a healing hormone that helps
your body heal and pain is kicks that
hormone off. That's how the body
knows. So when you suppress pain,
you stopped that healing.
So you're going ice,
you suppress that hormonal
release of IGF one,
it's the healing hormone and all of a
sudden it's going to slow your healing
down. So if you do it cause it makes you
comfortable, like, Hey, if you've been,
you know,
running around in your overheating and
you're gonna go on ice tub because it
feels good, that's one thing. But if
you think that it's going to benefit,
I'm not sure.
I don't know yet.
I think he could be the better benefit
because you've got heat shock proteins,
which deal with damage cells and all
that stuff. Um, and I'm not listening. I,
this is just stuff that I hear that I'm
feeling and then just claim we're both
love dogs. Yeah. Fall. Yeah.
Dennis Miller, this is my opinion.
I could be wrong of course. So you know,
the uh, but uh, you know, so that, that,
that and,
and,
and then they talk about growth hormone
that your body produces growth hormone
in the heat, right. As another one of the
side effects. And so, uh, from a, again,
from my understanding, and
I'm not a doctor, um, so I, I,
when I hear that, I go, well,
and heat should be the thing you do
because after every game, every football,
every basketball player, every athlete
goes right to the ice tub. Yeah.
I think if you're going there for
comfort, okay, cool, that's great.
But if you think that that's actually
the thing that's really benefited,
you know, really going to bring
you the best recovery, maybe,
maybe heat's going to bring
you the best recovery,
but it's going to be miserable.
Because last thing you want to
do after you finish a workout,
it's go sit in a hotbox. Just not,
yeah, interest, happy. But these,
but for injuries though,
for injuries,
they say you should
reduce the inflammation.
But if what you're saying
that's interesting, right?
Well, the more pain, the more,
you know, you know, the old
saying no pain, no gain, right?
No fruit, no pain, no gain,
no pain, no gain. I mean, everything's
painful. Like if you go on the heat,
it's just comfortable. You
going to workout, you get
sore. I mean, no pain, no gain.
So if we go with the old, that
old, you know, no pain, no gain.
I believe that the pain is associated
with the healing because of that hormonal
response that pain
brings into you. So, um,
I would attribute like I had
a s a fast recovery, but I,
I attribute some of it is because that
I was not suppressing any of the pain.
So if, I think if you take pain meds,
that's suppressing healing. So if you say,
Hey, I'm so uncomfortable,
I gotta pop pain pills to,
to endure this because it's so hard,
we'll then just extend the
healing that you're just going to.
And the more you suppress the pain,
no matter which way you do it with
its ice pain, pills, whatever it is,
I believe the longer you extend the
healing, the more pain you can take.
I mean inflammation is the marker
for that healing hormones. So again,
reduce inflammation.
I don't know if that's,
that's again I would like to a a doctor
to and somebody to tell me that really
has a study that's that they know that
they've really looked at to tell me that
that's really working,
that, that the icing.
I mean if you do it immediately
right when you get, you know,
you snap your ankle and you go right in
a nice tub bucket and keep it from fully,
uh, you know, inflaming maybe
in the, in that instantaneous,
but doing it over days and
I think that's just paint.
I think that's just comfortable
making more comfortable.
That's interesting because you always
see basketball players ice on their
shoulders,
ice on their knees like right after games
cause they have clay comfortable. Yeah.
I was just thinking that they have to
play so many games in a row though. Yeah.
But it's also comfort,
comfort. Like, I mean,
I think it's because it feels good if
your shoulders all jacked up and you numb
it, you know, just like
a pain pill would do.
And this is just a topical numbing
icing, just creating, uh, the, you know,
the guy that, uh, that created
rice, which is like rest,
ice compression and elevation. He came
out last year and said I was all wrong.
So no, he did. That guy came out and
just here. Well then the last two,
couple of years he felt really bad.
Well,
I'm saying so he came out and said,
you know, that he, he was, you know,
that he, he, he takes it all back. So I,
you know, I dunno. I mean, I just think,
I think there's no absolutes. I
don't, I, but I, I, I'd be interested,
I've been trying to learn
about it. Like, Hey,
can you really tell me what really is
the best thing? Or maybe it's heat,
Nice Combo, you know, that, that heat,
Nice Combo because that does so much
flushing to the system, you know,
squeeze down the ice,
squeezes everything.
And then all of a sudden the heat expand.
So your contraction expansion and that,
I know that that is, uh, you know,
but that takes energy to that tires
you down more than you know, than the,
than the heat. But you do do ice
bath, he ice pass heath back to back.
Yeah, I'll do it. Like sometimes
I'll take, I'll do it on a Sunday,
I'll do like seven rounds of that stuff,
you know,
nine or you just get tired. You
get, you get, you know, you're well,
that's why we want the intensity.
Right, right. So the colder it is,
the shorter you have to be there
and the hotter it is, a shorter,
you have to be there.
So if you're hanging out,
so if you could get it down
to 15 minutes and you know,
three to five minutes and let's say
three minutes in the ice in 15 minutes in
the, in the sauna, then
all of a sudden, you know,
let's say 20 minutes around then your
tea, you know, then here you, here you go,
you got, you know, two and a
half, three hours, you know,
that's why one seven, two,
one 80 you do a whole hour versus, yeah,
but that's a whole different protocol.
That was just a, when I heard about,
and I just try, I tried it. Paul,
part of it is cause hard to stay in
that thing for an hour straight at 170.
I mean it's,
that's not an easy task.
Are you listening to anything in there
or are you just the beat in my heart,
not putting anything in the
music or anything. Yeah,
I'll listen to music or something like
that or a more a podcast or get somebody
else to suffer with me. Uh, yeah, just
to get some, try to try to set hard,
try to get somebody else and maybe they
come in for half and then they're back
out and then they come in for the other
part of something. When I'm on the road,
I tried to get comedians to come on the
song with me at a hotel and it's only
like 150, 116. They're
like, I'm out. I'm like,
you're out here for 15
minutes, say shit. So it's all,
but it's all what year? It's, it's in
your brain. It's in your mind. It's, it's,
we're so, uh, you know,
domesticated for so domesticated.
Oh, it's hot. It's cold.
It's this. And you
know, we're just, we're,
we're as this something that you,
or is this the,
the whole surfing community?
Are they end of this kind of
stuff? Uh, no. I mean, I, I,
I, well, you know what's interesting
is, is because I'm a surfer,
obviously everybody thinks, oh, you know,
all the surfers and you're
friends with the surfers.
I remember actually I had not,
I really am kind of outside
of the community itself. I
have sir friends at surf,
but I'm so not part of,
you know, and in my career,
I haven't been part of the industry
of surfing and, and uh, really,
so in a way I'm,
I mean,
I have friends that surf that come
and do it and we've definitely,
there's been some influence into surfers
in general, at least the good ones,
or are, you know, training and, and,
and using these ice heat protocols.
And so they're, they're, they're, uh,
you know, they're, they're aware and,
and motivated. Uh, but the, but
surfing in general is, you know, uh,
I mean, I don't even know what
half those guys are doing. Well,
I would think that they would
be looking to you. I mean, if,
if I was a young surfer and say,
man, I fucking love surfing,
I'd like to be doing this when I'm
55 was Laird Hamilton doing? Yeah.
But I don't know. But I think
sometimes the, you know, I
mean, I think for a lot of,
obviously it's changed now, but
in the past, I mean, you know,
and it happens a lot with the younger
people in general. Uh, is just like,
don't tell me what to do. I
can eat whatever I want and
do whatever I want. Yeah.
I can go to Taco Bell and Burger King and,
and still,
and stay up all night and
still, you know, rip, you know,
or do or do my thing. And it's true
probably in every sport. Um, and then,
and then, you know, I always say
there's a thousand, you know,
20 year olds and then there's 530 years
olds and then there's 250, 40 year olds.
And then there's like, you know, and
then he'd just go as you go and, uh,
there's less and less. And it, you
know, I always loved that, uh, the term,
the victory through attrition. You know,
when you just the last guy, if you're,
this allows guy and you're standing,
you don't even have to be any good.
You'd just, when you're like the winter,
like you won, you're the only guy left.
I kind of things. Yeah.
I like that. Just you,
you've been following this just to
improve your physical performance just for
life. Absolutely.
Absolutely. And, and, uh,
you know, I, I think I really
cherish, I cherish, uh, feeling good.
I care's feeling good.
Like I really enjoy feeling good.
And so that drives me towards, you
know, wanting, and like I said,
either whether I had Paul Chek years ago,
uh,
went and did an assessment with him and
he's an interesting guy. Very, yeah.
And Watson and stuff a lot online.
Yeah. And, and, uh, him and I had a,
an instant connection
and, and, but, you know,
I love the philosophical approach
to certain things. Like he said,
and this had a huge impact on
me, you know, 25 years ago,
or he was like, you know,
the three white devils are white flour,
white sugar, and white milk. And I'm like,
okay, like drink. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Just put [inaudible] on it.
But if you couldn't rock a cow and raw
milk together, that's a powerful drink.
Yeah. That's for real. But if you put
dead milk, homogenized, pasteurized, yeah,
just abused.
And then you,
and then you take some really bad cacau
if there's any at all in it with a bunch
of, who knows? You can't pronounce
it, you know, he said, uh,
if it wasn't here 10,000
years ago, don't eat it. Uh,
and if you can't pronounce
it, don't eat it. You know?
And then the three white devils,
I mean,
that's a philosophical hard time
with turmeric though. Yeah. Why?
Let's just say the word oh
struggled. Pronounced. Yeah,
but it was your 10,000 years ago,
so you've covered some fun. Yeah.
Those are good pieces of advice though.
Yeah. But just to look at food that way,
it's like people go, what's
your diet? I go, plants and
animals, plants and animals.
Like what? You don't like it don't
make it difficult. Don't be like, well,
I eat this and debt.
I think that the stress around
that stuff is crazy, but I,
I,
I really believe that to truly be,
to have optimum performance and to be,
and to be optimum that you have to have
the whole every spoke in the tire that
you need,
every single spoke,
that you have to have a good
relationship with your family.
You got to have love and you got to have
good things with your kids and you've
got to have friends and you got to have
your health and you've got to sleep well
and you've got to be hydrated and
you've got to work out and you've got,
and you've got to have a, you know, your
business thing and you've got to have,
I think you just have to have all
these things to really have balance.
And I think if you,
if,
if one of the spokes isn't tight that
there's a bump in the wheel and then
you're just not gonna,
I don't truly believe that that you,
you're performing at your
optimum because you need,
your head needs to be clear when
you go into your performance,
whatever that looks like.
I think that's excellent advice.
I think that makes a lot of sense.
And it definitely keeps your mind clear.
You know, you have your bases
covered, covered. You're not just,
you're not here but there,
but somewhere else. I mean,
and I know I've dealt with not being,
having all the spokes good.
And I know that the, how that feels,
and I know when it's good, you're,
you're clear, you're good. Yeah.
You're, you're, you're, you're,
and it's how we're meant to be. I mean,
we're meant to have that be real clean.
We're meant to have that there be
some silence. Balance. Got To have it.
Yeah. That's why, I mean, even overworking
mean people think that, you know,
I think that's a badge of honor. Yeah.
Yeah. Like, Oh yeah, I worked, I think,
and I don't sleep and Dah,
Dah, Dah. I'm like, Oh yeah,
well then you're compromising yourself.
I told the Ilan Mustang digital. Yeah,
I was, I went to space x one
time and I pulled him aside.
He was standing out and go, hey, you
know, you got to take care of this,
but my hand on his chest, I just
go, yeah, take care of this.
But you've got to take care of you.
What'd he say? He just, she had the,
I don't know if he understood
he's a robot. Yeah. He,
I don't think he understood that he
barely a person. I'm just saying,
I don't think he, no, I don't think
it with all due respect and, yeah,
but I don't think he understood what I
meant. I, I didn't, I felt like, you know,
someone like that if they were really
taking good care of themselves,
getting the right sleep, getting in
the right food, getting a workout,
all those things. I imagine, imagine
like, if they can do what they're doing,
you know, burning it on both ends. Imagine
what they could do fully balanced. Well,
I don't think he wants to do
any more than what he's doing.
I just think he's so with
getting Tesla to run correctly on,
he was sleeping on the floor of the
Tesla factory and working 17 hours a day.
I mean that's, that is, that's
an insane person. I mean,
he was just there all day long
trying to make it work in it.
Obviously it does work. They are amazing
cars. Yeah. Everything's, yeah. It's,
it's beneficial. Yeah.
This drive that he has,
but I agree with you like for
overall enjoyment of life,
that's not the way to go about it.
You have a blockage there though too.
I think if you don't,
can't pull back and look at it from
a distance you and you're in it.
I think you get too detailed
and then you can't, you know,
you can't be, I think you, I think
it could be better because of that.
I think maybe, maybe it'd be
profitable. Yeah. It's hard.
It's a hard fucking
business. I mean, you're,
you're competing against
the big boys. Yeah. Right.
But what's interesting is even though
they are doing that, they've managed to,
he's managed to make something that's
so different than anything else.
You have one that now I don't,
fuck man. They're crazy. Yeah.
I was reluctant. I told him I buy
one when he did the podcast. Yeah.
But I was like, God damn. And I like
muscle cars. All, I hear an engines.
But I drove that thing. I was like, Oh,
other cars are stupid. They're all stupid.
They are, they're archaic. They are here
to that thing. They are well and healthy.
And you see all the companies
going that way. Now you can see,
I mean we were cause uh,
my buddy,
while Ben and I were into
electric stuff and uh,
and we went and there was a guy that has
electric dragster and we went down and
with this electric director and it
just smoked any top fuel dragster,
like beyond at, but it didn't make noise,
so no one wanted to watch it. So I mean,
and you're like, what? I'm been, no, no,
no smell, no noise, no flames. Right.
You know, and tell him no good
still burning gas. No, no,
no pollution, no pollution.
So people were like, oh, that's no fun.
So yeah, but when you drive a Tesla,
like I've a the model s p
100 d I think it was called,
when you drive it, it's
effortless. Like everything,
just you just go where you want to go.
Like I like to be over there.
It's like a video gal.
Like all of a sudden you're over there.
Well you have to get used to it cause
I've been in them and driven, driven him.
And it's interesting how the body has
to acclimate to the acceleration because
you're used to that jolting shifting, you
know, first gear, second gear, third gear,
all that delay like a, it's like ac
versus DC. Normal cars are like Acu,
a little gap between the power and when
you get that, you know, it's, it's,
the body has to get used to the,
I'm still not totally okay
with not looking where
you're going and just flip it
on auto pilot. But I guess
that's, yeah, the next generation,
well that's fun on the highway,
but yeah,
I look where I'm going to
keep my hand on the wheel,
but it is fun to like shut 10% of your
brain off and just let the car kind of
handle the speed and one it does it well.
Does it well, does it well? Yeah. Well,
I just,
like I said,
I think you need a person who's as
obsessed as Elon Musk is to make something
like that. But I agree with you if, if,
if he wants to enjoy his life, well,
just live longer. They have more ideas,
have more influence, like just be,
I am only speaking that way. I've just
been in the way of optimizing him, right?
Talk to mizing him for it because of his,
he's so amazing that,
okay,
let's optimize your amazingness by,
by making you like be healthier,
like be take care of yourself so you
can be around longer and maybe do more
great things. Right? So it's again, I,
you know, I'm just speaking personally,
but when you try to look at
optimization, right? Like you're here,
you only get so long, you
know, what are you doing and,
and are you really optimizing
it by, by, you know, burn by,
by taxing the system and not,
not getting all of it that
out of it that you, you know,
but I guess in a way it's kind
of like unhappiness, you know,
people use that as a workout.
So that's a little bit,
it makes you tired and you're
get hungry and you know,
yeah, there's always that. Well,
it's the choices you make, right?
Like sometimes you just get stuck in
the momentum of the choice that you made
and it's very difficult to like
take that pause and go, okay,
am I doing this the right way?
Maybe I need to reset.
We needed to just take some time to
really consider if this is making me happy
and how many years I'm going to be
able to do this and sustain it. Yeah.
Well that's a tricky thing, right?
That's a, that's a, that's a self self,
uh, you know, analyzing
yourself and putting that up is,
I think it's easier just to keep going
the direction you're going to take some
Adderall and keep it in
the can go full speed.
How long have you been living in Hawaii?
Uh,
well my mom took me from San Francisco
and I was six months old. Whoa.
Wow. Pretty much. It was only a
technicality that I wasn't born there,
which actually worked against me
because you know, when you're not born,
then when you're not born there, then
you're not from there. So they're low.
You're not born here and they're like,
oh yeah, but I've been here since I was,
you know, since I can remember. So
let's just put it that way. Right.
Remember actually worked,
they still hold it against you the six
months that you weren't oh yeah. Oh yeah,
we missed you bro. Oh, it's
months. We're, yeah, yeah.
Paying them out of your mother here
in the state. But yeah. But yeah,
since I was a little kid,
I mean my mom took me, uh,
I was born in San Francisco and she
took me when I was a few months old.
I have a theory about people from Hawaii.
There's a groundedness that they
seem to exhibit that is universal.
It's almost,
you very rarely find completely frivolous,
dopey people that live in
Hawaii that they're not. Yeah,
I'm sure you find some people
that are not that smart, but you,
there's a groundedness.
There is so many of them have because
they're on a volcano. Yeah. Ocean.
And you know,
it was interesting that you talk about
that because yesterday we were having a
conversation about what is that right.
And we have a term, a couple terms.
One of them is Mana, which is the power
from the land. Another one is Aloha,
which is our kind of a spirit of
how people act, uh, from Hawaii.
But I believe it has a lot to do with
islanders. I think islanders have that.
And I, and it has a lot to do with, uh,
it has a lot to do with the ocean
being around the ocean that the ocean
surrounding you and the ocean is the
most conductive substance on earth.
So elect electrically and there's all
this thing. So you get influenced by this,
you know, and I think energetically
the nature is so powerful.
I think it puts us into a,
there's a certain kind of humility that
you have when you're in that you're next
to a volcano that's 14,000 foot and you've
got a 2000 foot waterfall and you got
a giant wave. I mean, this is
stuff that kind of goes, oh yeah,
we're just a little ants. We're this
little specks and we don't, it's humbling,
but it's also inspiring and energizing.
Gives you power.
The Mana,
Mana.
I've always wondered why people
that live in peach communities are,
they're so chill.
Like I've wondered,
is that because of just the humility
that you get when you just looking at the
ocean, the Blue Boomerang, have
you ever seen that book? No.
It's called the blue mind.
The guy's pretty interesting and he
does a study of why we gravitate towards
being on the beach, why all the most
expensive real estate is beach front.
And that something about
when we stare at the ocean,
they did all these studies where the,
it just totally lights the brain up.
That our whole something about the
horizon and about the ocean itself,
that that affects our whole
wellbeing. Uh, and, and part of it,
we don't even know why, but we're just
drawn like, why, you know, why is,
why are we drawn there? Why do
we, you know, and it has, it has,
uh, you know, an effect on our system.
I wonder if that's because we evolved
to be close to the water because that's
where the bounty is,
where you can get fish.
And while we evolved from the water
without true, so here we call that the,
the whole aquatic ape theory. If you ever,
yeah, no, I haven't really, uh, you know,
uh, I haven't, I haven't, I haven't
really studied that. I, I mean,
you know, I, I know that,
I know that when you're around dolphins
and when you're around Wales, um, how,
and like, you know, it's interesting
today I was in the ocean and, and I,
and I felt something was
around and I could feel it.
I just knew something was around. And
then it just five, 10 minutes later,
a big sea lion kind of popped its head
up and went. But I could feel before,
uh, but, but you know, when you're around
those animals that are in the ocean,
you definitely feel a kindred spirit with
them unlike you do with land, animals,
you know, you don't really
have that mean. I mean, okay,
maybe a wolf for dogs because we were
connected with them for 30,000 years.
We have that relationship. You feel
s something with a dog. But, uh,
but with the sea animals, like I say,
when the dolphins come around and you're,
you just feel some kind of,
there's just some there, you know,
and they say they've done some
studies with, you know, dolphins,
how would they effect kids that
have, you know, different, uh, uh,
disabilities and stuff and how
it, it totally helps them. And,
and so there's some healing ability and
actually dolphins are capable of having
a collective consciousness. And that's
why they, when they get surrounded,
the big ones don't just jump out of the
net. They, everybody stays together.
So they, but, but again, you
know, the aquatic eight, but the,
that were from the ocean. I mean,
listen, we call it the super life, right?
They ocean is the,
is the reason why this,
why were we were here and why we can
be here? Because if it wasn't for that,
we would be, it'd be Mars and
it'd be hard to live there. Yeah.
There's a, this something that
attracts you to it. It's very strange.
It's very true when you stand there,
just so you could,
it's peaceful just to sit down at the
beach and just stare out at the blue.
It is. Yeah. Well the
blue mind is a great book.
It's a beautiful book about talks about
that and the science behind that and the
effect it has on our system.
But you know,
in a way watching the ocean move is
a little bit like watching a fire.
You know how fire is mesmerizing.
You have a fireplace and you just watch
the flames move while the ocean has that
movement. Um, and, and, uh, and, uh,
I'll sometimes I'll go to the beach and
I'll do a headstand and stand and look
at the ocean upside down,
which is crazy because now it's the
ocean is the sky and the waves are moving
opposite to what your brain is used
to. So it, it, it, it's, you know,
it's something when I'm doing,
when I'm bored at the beach.
Do you think you could
ever live in a city? Um,
I've stayed in a city for a
little while before. I mean,
I moved to Manhattan at one
point. We lived in, yeah,
I lived in Manhattan when
I was about 17 or 18.
I had some friends that
used to come to Hawaii.
They lived in Manhattan and they invited
me back for the summer and I lived
there for a summer. Um, and, uh, you
know, it was dangerous for me to be there.
That was dangerous because you're
kind of more trying to pull the wild,
you're a little more wild,
you know,
you're a little more like an animal and
then you're like, you're in confinement,
you know,
and there's just not enough nature.
Like I go to central park and swing off
trees and stuff, but that, you know,
that you only set only didn't so much.
How old were you at the time?
Like 17 or something like that.
You felt like a real urge to
be around nature always. Yeah,
always pulled. Pulled too. I mean, I would
just go to central park all the time.
Yeah, no, that's interesting. Yeah, I
was just, I needed that. And you know,
people don't realize when they
lived there, but when you,
when you're in a place with giant cement
buildings, you know, they're tall,
you're in fight or flight the whole time
because the big, yeah, because you're,
you're threatened by these big masses
that could fall over and hit. Yeah,
absolutely.
And you intuitively,
you're living in that and then the noise
and all of the, all the people. Cause I,
you know, I, I grew up sitting in
the back of the class, right. I,
I go to a restaurant, I find a
chair against the wall. Like I,
I go look for a chair and go, where's,
you know, I'll sit in the corner.
I want to see what's coming. I like to see
what's coming. So, and you go, you know,
you go to New York and there's just,
you're bombarded from every single
angle and so you're in fight or flight.
You're just, you're constantly
on guard too. You know? You
don't know what's gonna.
You know, I'll take my
chances in the ocean. Yeah.
I love
visiting. Yeah. I love visiting.
Yeah. But as far as living there, man,
I just don't in my,
my friend Jeff lives there and he's like
the energy of the city who talks about
the energy. It's amazing. I'm like,
okay, well it's retail therapy too. Yeah.
Retail pair.
They said,
we tell Mecca gets why every
woman in the world moves there.
The other along the shop shop,
shop, and then your friend goes,
there's a lot of energy here is
all the people. People are moving,
they're doing things and makes
me want to do things. Yeah.
But I want to do things anyway.
I don't need that. Yeah. Yeah.
Well we weren't meant to live
stacked on top of each other.
That's not in our nature.
That's done in our biology.
Now is there an abundance of everything?
Yeah,
there's a lot of things that
make it attractive right
into the tree. True. I mean,
there's beautiful women
that make it attractive.
There's don't blow all the food you ever
wanted to make it attractive. You know,
there's all, there's an abundance of
stuff and there's always something you do.
You go to the theater,
you don't have to be self motivated,
you don't have to be self driven, right.
You can just, there's always three,
you know,
10 parties and a bunch of
things and speakers and Cyan
and just anything you can
think of,
there's every aspect of it.
So I think that's has an
attractiveness about it.
But in our essence,
do we belong in these,
these metropolises? Mm. They don't
really have any in nature that we,
so we wouldn't actually, that
wouldn't be a place that, you know,
and we can only handle so
many people at once anyway.
Like we can only have real intimate
relationships with like a hundred and,
I don't know, 130 people or
something. Some crazy. That's
like one fifth yeah, yeah,
yeah. I'm, I'm, what I'm
fascinated by though,
is that these things
exist everywhere and it's,
cities exists in almost
every single country.
There's a place like a Manhattan or like
in la where everybody is just jammed in
together. Like what is it about people
that makes us want to live like this?
That's an interesting thing.
That's an interesting question.
Why are we attracted to that,
to that? Well, the abundance,
you know, that we're all,
and we're, we're drawn to
go where everybody wants to
go a little bit like sheep,
you know, like we all go where everybody
wants to go. Opportunity. I mean,
there's all these things that, you
know, why does every, why, why did,
why does every city draw every young
person from the countryside, right?
Because of opportunity and
excitement and possibility.
The possibilities.
My friend Michael Mouse was on the show
yesterday and he was telling me that he
was choking.
He swallowed a piece of food and he got
it stuck in his throat and he went to a
table in Manhattan. He was in
Manhattan and he was like, I'm choking.
And he said this to this table people,
and he said,
this woman just stared
at him with no reaction,
like didn't smile on anything and he
coughed in the food, came up, he goes,
I was choking to death. And she said,
well, you should take smaller bites.
Like just the harshness, the harshness
of New York. It's like the, the,
the value of a human being is so,
so much less because there's so
many of them. Yeah, that's true.
That's a problem in the earth.
Yeah. Right now our value for,
and we become such a void where we
become such voyeurs of like, we'll,
I'll just watch you die. I'll just,
I'll get a video of it and put it,
you know, post the stuff that's, I
mean, yeah. Instead of like, wow,
that guy needs help. He's hurting. Let's
let me help him right now. It's like, wow,
let's see. You know what I mean? You
see it's a, it's a strange phenomenon.
You'll get more help when there's
less people around then you will,
when there's all the people
around. Yeah. They'll,
Debbie thought a thousand people and
they'll all just sit there and stare at a
guy that's bleeding to death,
where when there's two people there,
one of the people will tourniquet the
guy's leg. Right, right, right. Look,
if you've met,
if you saw someone in the woods fall and
break their leg and was just you two,
you'd feel totally
connected to that person.
Whereas if you saw someone
who's 100 people around,
the guy falls or gets hit by a car,
you're like, well that ain't my problem.
That ain't my problem. And everybody
goes, that's not my problem.
So I mean you the fusion
of responsibility. Yeah.
It happens in large groups of people.
You feel like somebody is going to handle
this and no one does. Yeah, no one does.
So yeah, there was a video that I watched
recently of this guy. There was a,
I don't know what was happening,
but it was outside at night,
some sort of a nightclub,
sort of a situation.
This woman hit this guy and
this guy knocked out this
one woman and then another
girl came out of me, knocked her
out too. And the guys filming it.
Someone's filming it and then not
doing anything about it. No one's,
no one's tackling this guy.
No one's grabbing.
The guy runs away successfully and then
the LAPD put a thing out looking for
this guy.
I'm like,
how the fuck does the guy with
the camera live with themselves?
How did you just exit them? Exact guy
punched to women. Exactly, exactly.
Unless you're a woman too. And the only
kind of what this guy fucking me up to,
I don't know who all, you just hit him
with a brick then if I mean, you know,
whatever. I mean just saying,
just, you know, drive your car,
you drive your car on them. I'm
just wondering, you know, but it's,
it is strange how we lose
our humanity in these jobs.
We're doing it more to them now.
Just with all of the,
there's a bunch of factors that are
playing in, into, into that right into,
into us.
Kind of separating ourselves
from the person next door.
They're right there, but we're,
we're over here. We're on our,
on our device looking down, and they're
right next to us and we're like,
it's almost like we pray. We think
that that's an invisible screen. Yeah.
This is all the thing about Hawaii
that I've always found interesting.
So you kind of know everybody,
so you can't be an asshole.
That's a beautiful thing. Yeah.
You accountability, accountability,
you're going to see him at the,
you're going to see him at
the store in five minutes.
So either you work it out and you agree
that you don't like each other and it's
just like an accepted thing and, or you
work it out and you get through it. Yeah.
I love that.
Well,
I love that about small towns to
small towns have the same thing.
But the thing about an island, it's a
small town with the notion around it.
So there's really nowhere to go.
And you live on Kauai?
Yeah, I grew up on Cola. How many people
live there? About 60 something now.
65,000 or so. That's hilarious. Yeah,
that's less than the big island,
which is pretty,
but it's big
giant and Chinese like a hundred
something, right? Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
I lived on Maui for a while, um, as
well, but I grew up on Coleco eyes. My,
the is my, you know, that's my, that's
got my heart. It opens my heart.
So gorgeous. They're gorgeous.
And then you've got Honolulu,
which might as well be Chicago
or something. Absolutely.
It's like city problem.
Absolutely.
Annual city problems and a heavy military.
So they have a huge military, you
know, and in the military, uh,
influences a city like any, any, any
city that it has no military next to it.
If there's an effect that the
military has on the city. Sure.
In Honolulu has that Honolulu is connected
to the military cause you got Pearl
Harbor, all of that stuff. So, and then a
million people, which is insane. Insane.
I'm the only NP gathering pay.
Honolua means the gathering place.
So it's like where everybody goes to,
you know,
and that's where the state capitol
is. That's our whole, that's our,
that's Waikiki. That's, you know, that,
what does that one place become
so populated? It's, I tend to him,
I don't know why it's, it's, you
know, I think it has to do with,
if you look at most places
that cities have been created,
it's usually some geographical design,
some shaped like a good harbor
and obviously Honolulu's
and incredible harbor.
So great harbor, great protection. Um,
so that probably has a lot to do with,
with, uh, the fact that it was developed.
Like it was because of the
nature of, and it was, you know,
I used to say it like if you went to Rio
de Janeiro and no one was there and you
showed up one day with a boat and
there was no one had built anything,
it would be amazing if you showed up in
Manhattan and you went up the Hudson and
you pulled up onto that island, you'd
be like, wow, this place is amazing.
So in most of these places,
you know,
if you're in Paris and you went in the
sand went around it, you'd be like, wow,
this.
So most,
most of the places where cities have
been developed are amazing geographical
locations. And then
they, out of necessity,
they were easy to get through with boat.
You know,
that that has a big factor to it.
There's always some sort of, you know,
Stra strategic, there's
something to astray, you know,
being a strategic partner,
a location as well. But yeah,
well, I don't know why Honolulu, I,
other than great for moring and harbors
and unprotected, real protected,
all that Pearl Harbor
stuff is very protected.
And so that made it very easy to develop.
If you didn't live there, what do you
think you'd live in another planet?
I Love Alaska. You know, I, but I
don't think I honestly, you know, uh,
both Gabby and I had been,
uh, splitting the years for,
since we met and I realized that
I am, I'm nomadic. Like I'm,
or I'm that I really like,
like the animals.
I like to move in a season. It feels
more natural actually. And I, we,
I kind of, with my daughters,
we of influence them that way,
but I don't want to be anywhere all the
time. That's what I really realized.
I realized that I'm not
good. Then I just, there's,
well you'll get caught up in a domestic
with your neighbor and you'll just,
they're just,
there's something about being in one
location all year round and it feels more
natural to move according to
the seasons. Right? Like, Hey,
it's summertime energize you go to, you
know, we come to California in the summer,
the surface down in Hawaiian
in the summertime. That's
when the waves are flat.
So there's, they don't,
I don't have the sea to,
which means I would shifted
to other land stuff.
It brings a whole set of opportunities.
It's like why would we go north? I mean,
why would we go, uh, you know, in
north, in the summer because the,
it'd be a more abundant,
but in the winter you wouldn't
go because he'd be too harsh.
So it's a little bit like that
mentality where you move more.
Like if you're hunting and gathering,
you'd definitely be moving
according to the seasons.
Like you go where the fruit was
when the fruit was, you know, good.
And you'd go where the hunting was great.
When the hunting was good
and all of those things.
And that feels natural for me to just
be, you know, to be back and forth,
but to do like six months in each
places at what you did. Yeah.
So you have Malibu and you could
die. Yeah. Yeah. That's nice. Well,
and then you get to see both things
to both things and to open your mind,
open your mind, open
your mind. And, and, uh,
energetically Malibu is very
powerful. Like where we are, you know,
it's like Indian mountains and the
mountains meet the sea. And there's some,
you know, people don't realize
how abundant that see life is too.
They always all Malibu. They have like a
preconceived idea about what Malibu is,
but Malibu's has, has, uh,
you know, Malibu Means Kate
Way to the sea and to Gash.
That's a, that's an Indian
word. Malibu is the gate,
which is in a way as the valley that
opened from the plains where the buffalo
were to the fishing and the, and the,
and the ocean. So there's, there's some,
you know, something to that place
that, that we feel comfortable.
And if you're going to be here for us,
it's a, I can still be in the ocean.
I can still have that nature part
by then I can run into, you know,
La and try to expand my brain a little
bit. Yeah, it is really a weird spot.
Right?
Look,
Malibu's got a weird combination of
really rich people that are completely
detached and they're on pills and the
PCH is a terrifying place to draw one of
the most dangerous,
so many fucking drunk driving and
it's windy and you have the ocean.
So good them houses on cliff on the other
side of narrow winding and bad drivers
in general. Just all our
drivers in America are terrible.
It's even the one that,
there's something about that range too.
There's so many bars and restaurants where
people drink terrace areas. That's a,
that's a wickedly dangerous road.
But this, this detached people.
And then I've had friends that had their
kids go to Malibu High and the Lord
Jesus Christ's, everyone's doing
drugs. It's all fucked up. Yeah.
And the children of these rich
people are often neglected,
raised by their nannies. Oh
yeah. Parents aren't home.
And yet they're just so you have that
contracted by some of the coolest people
ever. And so you, and you have some of
the people that don't to live in town,
that work in the industry, highly
successful, that want this.
They want nature and they want
to be in there and they'll,
they're willing to drive that coast
highway every day and go to work in town
just to have the balance of being in
the sanctuary. So, you know, it's,
it's what we always say, bright, light,
dark shadow. I mean, it's the nature of,
it's what you get with it, you know, with
the, with the greatness you get is the,
you know, the destruction that
attracts weirdoes. Yeah, it does. Yeah.
There's so many strange, eclectic people.
ECLECTIC. Yeah. Which kind of makes it,
but it makes it great too. Like if you're
up for the good group, you got guys,
you know, you'd go to the store and you
got guys that are, that are, uh, you know,
that lived in Malibu for their whole life.
It's their kids. They don't, you know,
they live up up one of the canyons
and they're totally grounded and, and,
and you know, and then you got
right next to him, some, you know,
giant mansion and it with like you said,
you know,
kids that are neglected and yeah,
but there's some good ocean there
and there's some good mountains.
So for like mountain bikes and, and
ocean activities, it's pretty, you know,
the land stuff's always going to be
tricky with the humans. You know,
you get the humans,
they're on land.
We rented a place on the water for like
three months when we're getting our
kitchen done. And it was crazy. Like you
just sit there, wake up, eat breakfast,
you're on the water. Yeah. It's just,
yeah. And the place we were at it was,
the water would literally come
under the edge of the house.
So it looks like you're
sitting on the lot. Well,
it's like being on a boat and you watch
and do sea otters and all this wildlife
and birds. Yeah. Amazing. Yeah. You
don't want to own one of those houses,
but they're nice to stay in. Well if you
own it, you really don't own it for long.
No, not in this day and age.
Especially if we get it.
We never know we're
going to get a big wave.
So I'm always gun shy about being on the
water, you know, living on the water.
I think I, when I was a kid
we had to evacuate and so
I'm assuming something, uh,
for giant surf, huge, huge surf. So we
had to leave our house in our house.
A bunch of houses got push across the
road and Whoa, 1969 which was a surprise.
Yeah.
So I've always been,
I think I've had a thing in the back
of my head like at one besides highly
expensive, but just living on the beach.
It's like, no, I'll go to the beach,
I'll be at the beach all day.
But then I want to be away and like I
want to go home and be away and not have
sand in my bed and not have salt
on my TV and you know, not have,
like everything gets corroded, corroded.
Well you have to build a boat. Yeah,
you should.
If you build a house there,
just pretend it's a boat
and that you don't have to
worry about sinking or maybe,
I mean it might say, might say slowly. How
far away do you live from the water? Uh,
I'm about a mile as the crow flies,
but I'm up a hill so I overlook a,
I overlook the ocean and I could see a,
and then I don't have any neighbors.
I have only one neighbor on the front and
back and that both sides, no neighbors.
So it's, I've always liked
being on hills and being back.
I just seems that's where I end up.
I just saw some views,
I think views really good for your brain,
good for your brain to be up and, and,
and let everything fall below. Good
for the brain. Soothing on the mind.
What is this a physical training
company that you're doing?
You're doing something XPT
yeah. What is that? X T is a,
I would describe it as a,
a kind of a,
it's a lifestyle program that
evolved out of what, how I,
we live like what we, what
we do. And so we started a,
an experiential thing where people can
come for like two and a half days and go
through this,
you know,
get exposed to speakers and they do
heat and ice and we do pool training and
breath work and mobility and
conferences and stuff there. Uh,
exposed to speakers. Like, what do
you mean? Well, I'll invite, you know,
I would invite you to come
and speak for an hour or I'd,
I'd invite a Paul Chek or we'd have
somebody speak on longevity or somebody
speak on, you know, just have during the,
during the experience we'll have a couple
speakers talk on, you know, nutrition,
fitness, wellness, career
whenever, just as something as a,
another piece of the, of the element.
And then, uh, and then, and like I said,
we have pool training and then we try,
and we've been certifying trainers now
to kind of help people go through the
process as well. And so
it's, you know, it's,
it's really about rest and recovery
and breathing. It's more based on,
on that part is not just another training
thing of like, hey, how, you know,
how we can hammer you. I mean
it's, I think that's overplayed.
I think the ways we can train and, and
how we're training is really overplayed.
I think we're, we're not creating enough
things that nurture the system, you know,
and really look at trying to, to
support people in their, in their,
in their already, you
know, hammering life.
They're already just beating
themselves down. It's like,
let's get off the red eye and then
we'll go to the gym and we'll hammer
ourselves there and then we'll stay up
all day. And, you know, and I think we,
they need some support. So
breathwork is a big part of it. Um,
knowing how to move correctly,
I think that's a big part of it because
plenty of people hurt themselves,
especially in the gym,
be without, you know,
without some knowledge
of movement in form.
And then I have a pool
training system I developed,
which is the Gabby was telling me
about. That sounds crazy. Yeah.
That's the most proprietary
thing I think we have is, um,
it's a marriage between the CIM and the
in the pool because I despise swimming.
Um, yeah, I know. I do.
I just want to you if you
said go do laps in the pool,
I'd be like Shambhu and I'd get the
floppy fin and all. Yeah, I just,
it's just crazy out here.
Fucking serve. Know what I'm
saying? But, but if you said,
hey, we're going to take these masks in
this fins and we're going to swim this
coastline where the waves are breaking
on the rocks and we're going to go for
five miles. I man, like
I, but if you said, hey,
go down there and, and, and,
and where some swim goggles where you
can't even see and swimming some murky
water where you don't know what's in
it and we're going to swim a mile down
there and you're going
to do that every day.
That I'd rather step on a
rusty nail than do that.
I mean it's like that's so because of my,
my disdain for swimming, that kind
of swimming, I mean, I, if it's,
if it's in the surf and the waves, that's
a different, that's a different game.
That's a whole different, they don't want
to do laps in the pool. You'd kill me.
I'm going to die. I just, I
would rather, yeah. I just,
I'd rather hit my hand with a hammer,
just enjoy moving in the water. But
I do with some dumbbells. Oh, okay.
So carrying a dumbbell and
jumping with and dumbbells.
And why did you start at x p t like
what was the motivation because you're,
you're obviously into doing
this stuff yourself. Why
create a foundation or, well,
the reason why we started it was because,
uh,
an opportunity to expose this stuff
and share it with more people.
We were doing it ourselves naturally.
And then we have friends come and
they were like, this stuff's awesome.
And then can I invite my friend?
And then we were,
we realized that that if we really wanted
to expose it to more people and share
it,
we were going to,
it was going to be a limitation if
everybody had to come to my house.
Do you have like a website and everything?
Yeah. What does the t stand for?
Xpt Lie, uh, XPT life.com
and XPT stands for,
well, my, my concept is it's an
exploration in performance training.
Ah, there is high performance
fuels, a limitless life.
Dumbbells in the pool. There is,
oh yeah. So this is all yours.
[inaudible] I need to, yeah, you
have to come. Well, I'm just,
and it's Kyle Kingsborough. Yeah.
I love that guy. Yeah. The, uh,
while I have some beautiful guys come,
like,
I'll give you a great thing that you
appreciate it as a, I have this whole,
well first of all there's a bunch of
things that happen in the water, right?
Which one of the things that
happens is when you're underwater,
the compression of the water allows the
blood to flow through your lymphatic
system, which normally takes about a
24 hour period. It happens in one hour.
So imagine compression tights, like
you know, if you wear compression,
it really helps the blood flow, right?
Well this is the ultimate compression.
The water is right.
So then you deal with the psychology.
So it's good for fighters
like Aye, Aye, Aye,
Aye fighters because of the psychology
of what we can do because you deal a lot
with stress.
So we're able to implement stress in a
very controlled environment. Um, and then,
and then, uh, and then
like for example, uh,
and grant hill at one point in his career,
but I have loved friend joke, Kim Noah,
who's a basketball player
and we were doing these, uh,
we're doing these in the water. We're
doing these dunking drills last summer.
So I trained with him and get a bunch of
stuff cause you can do a lot of highly
explosive,
heavy loaded movement with protection
because now you don't have to worry about
momentum, which is what you're
going to pull your shoulder out.
It's gonna throw your hip,
it's going to hurt your knee.
Where I could take a basketball player
and I can run him through thousands of
jumps. Thousands, which at the
end of, if I did that on land,
he would be broken.
He's already jumping much in his season.
He doesn't need to jump more.
Right? So I could load him up and,
and make him do these dynamic movements.
But now he's protected because he's,
because we've taken gravity out. So we're
at, so it's, it's like, it's like saying,
hey, we get to go trade in outer space,
but it's in my backyard right now.
What kind of results of these
athletes boils parents? Well,
so Joe Kim in his career, and I don't
know how many years he's been in the NBA,
he came back after doing this dunking job,
just using this as an example. And, uh,
it had the most dunks per minute that
he's had in his entire career. Whoa.
He was like Dunkin on it.
It was slamming on everybody.
I mean it helps that he's seven feet
tall. But the fact is, is that he, he,
he noticed now, uh, uh, you know,
grant hill was talking about he gained
three inches in the last year of his
career after playing in
the NBA for 20 years.
All of sudden he's jumping
three inches higher. Yeah. Yeah.
So I mean we're getting,
we're, I'm, that's the kind
of tangible stuff that I'm,
that I, that I'm getting just
that there's a lot more things,
a lot of it has to do
with breadth because, uh,
in the water it's all
controlled breathing patterns.
So everything is controlled because you
can't breathe until you get to the top.
So if you're doing a drill where you're
jumping, and in most of the things we do,
our leg driven swimming is mostly arms.
And part of the reason why people only
use her arms is cause you use five times
the oxygen with your legs
as you do with your arms.
So the legs are very
inefficient for swimming,
but yet they create a lot
of load on your heart,
which that can boost your breath holding.
And so there's a bunch of other,
other, uh, things that happened,
but a lot of it is just that
environment is very protective.
So for recovery too, for
like what somebody got a hurt
knee, hurt, hip, hurt ankle,
you can go in there and start moving
dynamically early before you would ever do
it on land and be protected. So
there's a bunch of, you know,
and then we can just ratchet it
up. I can make, you know, if I it,
I truly believe if you
gate, if you said, you know,
I'll get few Phelps is going to come
to your house and you're going to have
Phelps for three months. I could
make felts faster. Yeah. This is,
this is this.
I'm so I'm,
he's doing a dunking drill and
he's using a medicine ball,
but he's having to jump out
at three feet of water. Right.
So when he gets on land,
when he gets on land,
it's like he's like a he, it's
like a whole other game. Yeah,
I would imagine a whole nother game.
Now did you invent this protocol?
This whole thing of yapping and doing it
in the water. What, what motivated you?
Well, I came in the original
concept came out of the a a drill,
not a drill. A thing we used to do
in the summer when we were kids.
That's a Hawaiian kind of watermen drill
where you run on the bottom with stones.
So seeing that Bj Penn does that
stuff. Yeah. So you get a stone,
you run along the bottom,
then you put it down,
then your friends swims along the
surface. And then when he, when you go up,
he swims down,
grabs it,
and then he goes along as far as he can
and you swim and you just go back and
forth until neither one of you can do it.
So it was based kind of on that concept.
And then,
but I wanted to expand that
because that's kind of limiting.
You just swam and you run and you
can't isolate movements and you're not
working, uh, a like
you can with dumbbells.
So now I shift dumbbells into the water
and, and I have all different weights. So,
depending on your skill level,
you know, everything we do.
And that's one thing about,
uh,
everything that I'm involved in
is it usually has to have a spa.
It has to be able to be, uh, you
know, for everybody to do it.
It has to be old people and kids too,
in my mind,
that it's not viable unless it's,
if you can appeal to everybody
that you need, you need to,
a kids needs to be able to do it. An old
person to be able to really be valid,
that really have legitimacy.
You know, it's like, okay,
the coffee, it's has to be,
there has to be things that the kids can,
can have that creamer.
The old people can have it. It's gotta
be good. You can't just be specialized.
I think the specialization of some
of this stuff is, creates, uh,
the lack of validity.
I don't think that it's valid
if it's specialized and so the,
I can take a little kid,
like my daughter does a bunch of the pool
training stuff, right? I have an older,
older guys that come and do a bunch
of the pool training stuff. You know,
I got Pat Riley comes in there and he
trained in the summer time with us and
stuff. Yeah. Yeah. So we get a fairly
broad spectrum of people and that,
and that confirms to me that
it's really legitimate. Right?
Because then it's like, no, this
is real. Like the kids can do it.
The old people can do it. The top guys
can do it. The bottom guys can do it.
Everybody can do it. Then you know
that that's something that's, that's I,
I just think that that's, you
know, what, what, what is real?
So how many years have you been
doing this? Um, XPT well, I mean,
the pool training I've been, I developed
over the last probably 10 to 12 years.
About 12 years now in the pool
with any of you have evolved it.
So you start off with a couple ideas.
I avail.
I had like a velcro wait jacket where you
felt crowed. Like, Oh yeah, wait, yeah.
Jumping into the deep end.
It was a little scary to get the
jacket off and how can you get up?
So that wasn't, that wasn't,
that wasn't viable. So that was,
so then we moved to have dumbbells where
you can drop them. But, but we, you know,
there's probably 20 exercises that
we watch. Are you using, it depends.
Sometimes we're doing, we have a move
called the gorilla where we're using,
you know, 60 to 70 70 pound dumbbells
where you're doing a curl, press jump.
So you g and you're jumping on the slope.
So your curl pressing and jumping with,
with uh, with, you know, 60, 70 pound
dumbbells, depending on your size.
We're swimming with 50 pounds,
60 pound dumbbells.
We're jumping off the bottom
with 15 pound dumbbells.
That depends on the exercise.
So it's all depends on the person's skill,
what the drill is. But we, I have a whole,
I have all the weights next to the pool,
so we have everything from seventies
to to five pound dumbbells.
I love that idea of the jump press,
like doing some sort of a, Oh yeah,
it's all, you'd love it. It's crazy.
I call it the gorilla curl.
So it's a squat curl,
press jump. And then you, when
you come out of the water,
you just let the weights drop
and then the water catches him.
You could never that Atlanta d rip
your shoulder out. Right? Right.
How deep you do this in the water while
you very on your height. So I have,
I have, uh, about, uh, 11 foot
deep end, and then I have a slope.
So you can choose every depth all the way.
And then I have what you
saw in that last video.
It's about a three and a half foot
shallow end. So this is the first pool.
I'm trying to build a couple. I'm trying
to build one in Hawaii right now. That's,
that's going to evolve from what I
learned from this pool. So this pool,
I just kind of built it with,
you know,
with the hopes of designing a program
and then out of it came all they,
all this stuff. What are
you going to alter? Um,
I'm going to create multiple depths.
So I'm going to do like
an area that has 12 foot.
Then we're going to shift back to feet
and have a 10 foot and then another flat
area of eight foot.
And then another flat area is six foot.
And then I have the magic width is about
somewhere between 35 to 40 feet wide.
And that's like if you're
trying to swim a heavy Dumbbell,
you know we do a lot of individual limb
stuff so that you isolate each limb.
So we'll do pistol squats and Russian
lunch squats and a bunch of other,
you know,
and and movements that you can,
you'd be very vulnerable if you
did that in the gym. You can,
chances are you could hurt yourself,
but because you have that stability in
that environment, it totally supports you.
So you can, you can be a and go into
ranges of motion that you don't have.
Like you,
you know,
you might not be able to go sink all the
way down into a deep lunge on one leg
and press out with dumbbells in your hand
on land. But in the water you can and,
and the water actually makes it lighter,
so you have to boost the weight and stuff.
So there's a bunch of great stuff
that comes out of it that sounds very
attractive to people that
have had injuries. Beautiful.
And what, but the irony is,
is it kind of,
it's a little bit like what comes out
of Rehab where you actually get better
performance to like, like, you know,
a lot of a lot of rehab exercises
become performance driving exercises,
you know, it's like, Hey, don't do
that shit. Only when you get hurt,
start doing that and get strong that way.
So then you'd maybe won't get her. Yes.
Yeah. You know, so it comes that
way too. It goes both directions.
And do you have workouts that people
can follow online if someone goes to the
XPT life is XPT life. Yes. And help me
to life website. Yeah. And we actually,
the thing that we have, the,
the thing we have right now,
there's probably the
most, uh, the most, uh,
kind of prevalent one thing
that's happening as soon as,
as we have a breathing APP coming out.
So we have a breathing app that has
almost every different modality of breath
work. And so there's some
pretty cool stuff in there
where you can go choose, hey,
before I go to sleep or before my
workout, after my workout, you know,
during my thing. So we have a bunch of,
we have a pretty cool breathing app, uh,
that, that we're working on as well.
So you ever talked to Wim Hoff? I know.
When do you know him? Oh, absolutely.
Yeah. Oh yeah. I'm doesn't,
he doesn't give a fuck if you breathe
out of your nose, your mouth. I was like,
just, I know, I know.
He doesn't get so crazy.
I love that guy. He's comedy.
No, I have, I've had a few,
I've him women. I've had a few,
we've had a few experiences,
let's just put it that way.
But we've had him at it.
We've had them at a couple of experiences
and I've done some stuff with whim.
I've known him for like four or five
years now. Maybe, maybe a little longer.
So he'll keep,
comes usually when he was in town,
I think the last time maybe when
you, when you saw him, he, he came,
he comes to visit. So I get, um, I,
if I, usually when I go with whim,
I usually translate for him.
When he goes to one of his classes,
I'm usually like trying to, oh, in case
people don't understand all I know,
but I'm just saying sometimes I'll
be with somebody, they'll be like,
what'd he say? I'll be like, what he
means is take a deep breath. Yeah.
He's such a character.
He is a character guy.
Went to fucking the top of Everest
barefoot. Oh yeah. Like, well, yeah.
Almost lost his toes to, yeah, yeah,
yeah. No, he goes, yeah. Well, he's,
he's his art actually, uh, is, uh,
two ml is, is a, is a derivative of to,
and I'm not sure if you know what to mow
is, but to moe is a Himalayan breathing,
uh, technique that the, that the, uh,
the monks have that they were, they, uh,
they have this one thing where they
dry sheets. So they have this thing,
the ceremony where they go at night
in the Himalayas when it's frozen,
it's snow and the guy sits there and they
put wet sheets, wet blankets on them,
and they breathe and get their bodies
so hot that they dry the blankets.
And then,
then the guide that can drive the most
blankets at the end of the night is the,
is like the guy, you know,
but it's, yeah, yeah.
It's called [inaudible] and it's a,
you can go online and look it up. Uh,
to moe is a,
is a,
is a Himalayan breathing technique that
that was never exposed to westerners
big, um, until just as of recently.
But the whims whims a work
is a derivative of, of tumo.
But nose breathe,
it's all about nose breathing.
It's all about nose breathing and
when you understand the science of it,
but he's right about getting people
to just breathe because people are not
breathing. And um, we just had, in
fact we had another, uh, Bill. Lissa,
what's your, I want to save,
uh, it's a Russian name but,
but she has a great book.
She trains fire, fire and
police and military, um,
breathing. We just had her at, we
did an XPT in Miami about a week,
two weeks ago and uh,
and she came as a guest speaker and we,
and was working on really trying to
create more volume and then are a lot of
people's rib cages aren't moving
and so they have a whole, you know,
there's ways to try to increase your
movement of your rib cage, your rib cage.
You'd actually open,
like you,
you could take a tape and measure your
rib cage when you are fully exhaled.
And then when you inhale it
should expand like, you know,
three inches or more for you to
be really optimally breathing.
And a lot of people,
I mean,
part of it has to do with the whole
six pack abs and what's aesthetically
pleasing. But meanwhile, when you have
a real nice six set of six pack abs,
you don't, you're not able
to diaphragmatically breathe.
You're not able to use your diaphragm.
You're not using your diaphragm when you
have that. Yeah. Because you're, you're,
the tightness isn't allowing the diaphragm
to push down the diaphragm and the
pell and the pelvic floor actually
squeeze your organs together. And,
and that is actually massaging the organs,
which influences your
digestion and everything.
And the deals with a bunch of acid
reflex and a bunch of others things.
But when the, when the, when the,
the ABS are so tight that, that the,
that the stomach can expand,
the organs can't push this belly out,
then you then, then you have
a limitation in your, in your,
and then the ribs aren't moving.
I mean,
it's just the guys are gonna hear this
and go, good, I'm going to stay fat.
I don't need a six pack.
Well, but, but no, but,
but I actually, if you're really using
your lungs, you, you can, you'll,
you'll strengthen your core
in a way that you'll get core.
You could have six pack abs
and not have core stability.
Like, so, you know, I mean,
and, and you know this, I mean,
when you look at a lot of not every
single great fighter is just ripped.
No, some of them biggest ones ever
not ripped it all at Fedora. Exactly.
So let's talk about that for,
for uh, an example of, you know,
the aesthetic isn't always
function right and, oh,
and of course we know the mind
is always ahead of everything.
I don't care what the car looks like. If
the God no motor, it doesn't do anything.
So it's, the body only goes where
the brain tells it. But the fact is,
is that that you see some of
the best athletes when you
look at certain athletes,
you're not like, they're not the
physical specimens that you've ever seen.
You're like that,
that guy's the most ripped and shredded.
A lot times those guys get knocked out.
You,
you see the guy come in and you just call,
this guy's going to kill this guy.
And then he just gets,
you know,
annihilated by the guy that looks
maybe not quite as hard. Right.
Part of it is genetics. Max Holloway's
perfect example. Hawaiian guy. Yeah.
He's not like shredded.
I mean he's strong obviously,
but he looks more like a swimmer.
Yeah, yeah. Well, and you,
you might find that his breathing,
he might,
he might have better air volume
because at the end of the day,
a lot of it's about oxygen cardio and
Max is cardio is off the chart. Exactly.
So he's getting more movement out
of there. I mean, you know, again,
we've created these, you know, aesthetic
things in, in our culture like,
oh six pack abs a sign of
this and Dah, Dah, Dah.
But when you look at real breathwork
and how the diaphragm works and how the
ribs expand, you realize this, like we're,
none of us are really doing it. Right.
You know, and you can actually
create more volume. You know,
you said you like cordyceps
mushrooms. Yes. Well,
those are actually a vessel dilate.
Those helps help you absorb oxygen.
You those can up your vo two Max,
right?
There's only a couple of things that you
can, how to increase your vo two Max.
But cordyceps is one of them.
Beaches, beaches, another one. Um,
you can create more volume
by expanding your lungs.
So by opening the rib cage and
creating more room that can create, um,
promote your vo two Max.
And what people are hearing this and
hearing breathwork folks who have never
done anything like that,
they don't,
they really don't understand
what you're saying. Like,
what do you mean by breath
work? Like, give us an example
of like a protocol. Well,
I mean, a real simple, I mean, they do
it in Pranayama, they have it in apnea.
There's a thing called
holotropic breathwork. Really is,
is when you isolate the
breathing system in and you know,
the simplest way. And
that's why Wim says, Hey,
I don't give a shit how you breathe,
just breathe. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So you know,
like we'll do a breadth routine and
we'll sit somebody down and we'll say,
okay breed like you're running where you
think you're running and you will tell
the guy breed like he's running and
they'll go, I go, that's a slow run buddy.
Like breed like you're running
right. You know, like, like any time,
any, any movement in any air in and out
is going to, is a form of breath work.
Right?
And especially when you isolate the system
and you're not doing it because of an
activity.
The fact is that when you use that
system and you work it and you're not
detracting from it by doing an exercise,
if you're doing the assault bike
while your arms are working in,
your legs are working.
So all the oxygen that you're absorbing
is going into your arms and legs.
When you're isolating,
you just do the breathing alone.
Now the oxygen's going into that system
and that system is going to develop and
get better. Then when you do your assault
bike after you developed that system.
So we'll isolate breathwork and we'll just
do it alone. Well, whether we're doing,
you know,
whether we're doing breath holds,
we're doing some kind of apnea
breath work, which is w you know,
we can do a pattern where you're doing
like you hold for 30 seconds and then you
breathe in for 15 and then you breathe
out for 15 then you hold the yet,
then you go in and out and hold in
and out and hold. That's one pattern.
Another pattern is in hold out,
hold in,
hold out, hold in, hold out. All like,
you know, again, those are, there's,
you know,
and then there's Pranayama
apnea holotropic there's
just somewhere your oxygen
in the system where you know,
like wimps,
hi,
how are you?
Just get that rhythm going and do that
for five minutes and people know by feel
light in and I go, yeah, because you
haven't had oxygen like that in your head.
You haven't had oxygen in your
system like that. Right. So again,
a conscious co bringing
consciousness to your breath.
We're not just walking along in life,
like not thinking about breathing.
That's the beginning of breath work.
Just awareness of, hey, I need to,
yeah.
You know, I need to breathe in
and out. Stay conscious. Yeah.
And that's a big one with martial arts.
You see in Jujitsu with beginners,
when they first start
sparring for the first time,
they panic and they have shallow breath
and you've gotta tell him us. Okay,
stop right now and just breathe. Oh
yeah. Oh yeah. We'll fight or flight.
Fight or flight. But it's interesting how
they can't get a deep breath. Yeah. They,
they, they hyperventilate.
Yeah. We'll you,
we'll put somebody in the ice for the
first time that hasn't done it. Yeah.
That's the craziest. Want to see it?
That's an incident Caney though. Oh yeah.
He can't breathe. Oh yeah. But
you eventually learn the system.
The system turned. That's actually a, uh,
an involuntary response to get out. Right.
Strike you. You have the option. So
you should exercise that option. Well,
that's an involuntary response. That's
your, that's your subconscious mind.
Protecting the organ organism. Like, Hey,
this in your body intuitively knows
this is dangerous environment. Get Out.
And so that reaction is to
get you to get out. When you,
when you make a conscious effort
to not lead that environment,
then the body goes, oh, okay,
you're not going to get out. Okay,
well now I'll organize.
I'll bring the blood to the
organs, all adjust everything.
I'll boost your hormones.
And so,
and then pretty soon you don't
get that response anymore.
Once you do it on a regular
basis, the body just goes,
oh, we're here we are again,
back to that ice thing. Bring the
Ba, you know, boost the hormones,
bring all the blood. No, Oregon's,
you know, that so, but that, that's,
that's a similar thing to what you're
talking about in Jujitsu where people are
the stress on the system. They're
stressed and so they're involuntary Italy,
you know, and that's fight or flight.
One thing you can really do to calm,
like calm a kid down. This is the way
you get yourself into parasympathetic.
Where you bring your thing down is when
you extend your breath for seven seconds
on the inhale and the exhale that reduced,
that'll bring everything down. Like,
if you want to calm down in your or
your kids straight, your little kid,
just all and you get them to just
breathe in for seven seconds. You know,
and I tell people,
think about Osi,
my youngest daughter, when she would
get upset, she would do that too.
And I try to like, you gotta breathe,
you gotta breathe, calm down,
but seven seconds is a magic number.
If they,
if you can extend the breath for
seven seconds and the body goes into
parasympathetic and totally like that's
what you do to like go to sleep at night.
Like if you're having a hard time.
So there's a bunch of stuff to learn
about the breadth, which is amazing.
I think the reason why the, the breadth
has always been so important to,
to me is this because of the ocean.
Because you know,
growing up when you almost drowned, you
know, a thousand times you, you, you,
what is important you,
you get to know,
you just get to appreciate like there's
none down there and it's all up there
and so be cooled down there. So when
you see you can get back up. Well,
I've learned I'm breathwork because
of Hicks and Gracie are watching Hixon
Gracie practice yoga. He's a friend. Yeah.
You know he does that. What does that,
yeah. What does that stumble?
That's, that's the uh, Pontiac. Yes.
But there's a name for it. Yeah. Where
you twist the, yeah. He really sucks.
Is Oregon's. Yeah. In his son can do it.
Amazingly crone can do it amazingly. Yeah.
Yeah. It's super good for you.
Well that for the organs. Yeah.
And that the ability to
control your breath like that
is so critical when you're
sparring. So critical to, to get oxygen.
These long training sessions will
for your life, for your life.
Anytime you're in this stress,
if you can control your breath,
that controls your heart. Yeah. Do you
ever do 30 seconds in, 30 seconds out?
Do you ever do that? Yeah. Just
slow, deep breaths in. Slow,
deep breaths out.
That's an amazing exercise cause well
that's the extension of that. Yeah.
That certain parasympathetic
that's bringing in seven.
Just the minimum amount.
Like whenever you go into any of those
long extended stuff. And then the,
and then those breath holds.
Anytime you hold the breath,
then you get that co two level and that's
what gives you the anx to, you know, uh,
what's interesting cause you know,
whims done like some record breaking
stuff and you have that free diving stuff
where,
where they scrub oxygen,
you know where they hyperventilate and
scrub the CEO too and get that real low.
But you have to be careful
about shallow water blackout.
So we don't really practice any of that
stuff. We do more like assault bike,
jump in the pool and see how long you
can hold your breath and then it's,
and then, and then you know, five, 10,
10 seconds is like, that's big time.
15 seconds. You're like, wow, that
was amazing. At maximum heart rate.
How long can you hold your heart?
I mean,
how long can you hold your breath
at some that's a challenge.
So I keep an assault bike right next to
the pool. Yeah. Oh yeah, just punishment.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Oh
yeah. Wow. Yeah. Wow. God,
there's always another twist to the
pretzel. Now, what are the, I mean,
because of your hip,
do you have any limitations on other
kinds of stuff that you can do? I'm not,
I'm not just running would be a
real cool. Yeah, no, I, I like deep,
deep texture running so soft sand because
of the foot and the articulation of
the feet and not chew and non not
wearing shoes. Um, so I'll do beach,
I'll do sand running and
like if I'm in the snow,
like Alaska or something like that.
But I love barefoot and deep stuff.
I don't like running on hard ground. I
just, first of all, we, as soon as you're,
you know, if your two 15 or two, you
know, whatever, anything over 200 pounds.
I mean,
you shouldn't be running more than a
couple of miles a week if you're over a
buck 20. I mean, it's
just, it's a, Oh yeah,
it's so hard on your sis on
the hard ground. Absolutely.
That's stuff is just
pounding you. You, I mean,
it's one thing to go in a soft t,
something that as absorption, you know,
like if you're running in the sand or
you're running or you're running in the
snow or you're running into some deep
thick grass or something that's got
absorption. But yeah, you
go run your, you know,
your 180 200 pounds and your run and you
just pound, everything's just, you know,
seven times your body weight on the
download and then you're wearing a shoe
that's, you know, that's kind of deceiving
you. It's a little bit like a Sunglass,
you know, you think it's blocking the
light but it's letting old bad light in,
you know, you think it's
blocking the absorption but
you're just getting pounded.
I mean your and your feet or you know, I
mean barefoot is so important. Grounding,
so important. I mean these are, these
are things, but uh, I have a new, uh,
I have a cool bike that I just,
somebody just gave me recently
called a standup bike,
which the company called elliptic go.
But it's a standing bike, its position,
so for standing alone. And so
the postures, unbelievable.
And you want to grind on a hill.
I mean,
you don't need running and then you have
zero impact. It's like, you know, it's so,
I think running is hard. I mean, I
understand that high of running and uh,
but you know, if you
want to, you want a real,
for me real running is
barefoot and some soft sand.
I had this one beach in
Hawaii that I run on that,
that that's a little bit like quicksand
and probably you'll sink in like mid,
lower, lower, lower calf.
Like you'll sink in a foot into it.
You don't need to go far,
but you don't need to go. And you know
what a Taro Patches. No. So I grew up, uh,
we got grew up farming.
I like around on a pig farm and
then with Taro Patches and fishing.
And so I kind of grew up in a, but there's
a terror, a Taro Patches, uh, as a,
as a rice patty, pretty
much mud. Right? And so you,
we grew up working in that stuff and
walk in and carrying buckets and being in
that mud. Slushing the mud, like a
foot deep. My, but what I'm saying,
an environment like that where you have
to pull your foot out and then sink in
where it's absorbing the impact. I
mean that's where work, you know,
I always question the damage
versus the work, right?
Like the pounding that you
and most, I mean, you know,
once you're a certain size, the
war, the pounding that you get,
I think you can get all the cardio.
You want to jump rope.
Trump rode straight landed on your toe,
you're doing the thing about
when you're running every in,
inevitably people go to heel striking.
They're landing on their heels
because they have a shoe that they,
so they think they're getting,
you know,
they think they're getting protected
because they're landing on something kind
of soft. But it's still
sending the, you know,
that impact up your spine and
inevitably anything you do and you,
and you come back and your back hurts. I
have to question like, is that optimum?
You know, and that wasn't dead lift
either. It was, you know. Yeah.
But what about your friend, the Moyie
Thai fighter? Well he, but he runs,
he runs like on the very shipper short,
short step balls of his feet like,
like, and I would, I wouldn't even,
I would call it more like a, I don't
even know how to describe the pace,
but it's a slow,
a slow,
a slow pace that you're landing
on the toes the whole time.
So it's not like a run, you know, a
hard run where you're pounding. So,
so he's probably only doing like 10
minute miles or something like that.
I don't know.
I don't even know what is his ranges?
You'd have to ask Mr Tom
Jones? Well I think, I think
running off your toes. Great.
Yeah. I mean there's some as the who
does those, the running, who does it?
Who Does it? I do. I run
with minimal issues. Yeah.
But if fortunately standing bike,
that is ridiculous.
I wouldn't be caught dead in that then.
Well back for me that, that there,
that's the elliptic go. They have the
new, a new one that's just a pedal.
I'm just kidding. Yeah,
it looks awesome. No.
But you know why the guy made that silly
cause the guy was a runner and couldn't
run anymore. Got Injured. Uh, and then he,
and he started the bike and
he said biking's not running.
And so then he developed that thing
because it's simulates running without the
impact. So that's, I'm like I said,
that's why I liked the pool. That's why.
And I think too, it's like if you
think about doing things forever,
we're talking about doing things
forever. Yeah. Right? Yes.
So we're talking about
doing things forever.
So how are we going to do them so we
can do them forever? No impact. Well,
so reducing impact. And if you
actually started doing that initially,
then you might not have to worry about
trying to recover from all that stuff
that you,
so it's like we don't want to train in
a way that we're going to have to change
our training to try to make up
because all the damage we've done,
let's try to avoid the damage
from the beginning. I'm a,
it's already too late for me. I got
seven, you know, I got six broken ankles,
got broken, arches broke again. What
the hell did you just do your ankle?
I like what's been broke six,
six or seven times broke the arch,
broke all the messages from surfing
all different motorbikes, surfing,
snowboarding because you mess up your hip.
Uh,
probably cause my broke walking
on a broken ankle for uh,
all those years that cause each time I
broke it I have five or six different
breaks and then I would keep going.
So I would keep walking on it and,
but I'd means I had to carry
the load on my right hip.
So I think I just wore the cartilage out
from offsetting and carrying the load
of the broken Lake Jesus. So
that was, but so I mean it's so,
it wasn't like one injury where you
hurt your hip. It was just slung.
I just wore it out.
I just,
I said I lived a couple of lives with
[inaudible] is that that was only on one
life hip and I had three lives in,
uh,
what is it like having a fake
hip, insane, incredible bionic.
That thing's not even in
my, in my, in my brain.
Not even how so it does.
I just,
I don't ever even bring it into
consciousness. It's in, it's slicker.
It's like a Mercedes Benz ball joint.
I mean it's absolutely perfect. Wow.
And you know,
I mean I've had ACL,
had some knee stuff before that was
harder to recover from than the hip.
The hip was.
I just felt like I got kicked by a horse
for a couple months and then after that
it was like no brainer. Jump off
a cliff, go stand up, paddle, run.
I mean I tell you to not do
certain things. Nope. Really? Nope.
You could like,
you could just start,
he don't do anything you should
do with your real one. Really.
That's don't do anything you shouldn't
do with your real one. Yeah, absolutely.
That was the only thing. I mean the guy,
the doctor Penn Nunberg who did mine,
he,
he did it to a contortionist I guess some
contortion has had some blown hips and
he'd get it to the girl is still
performing and stuff. So I don't,
I think it's, I mean this stuff
is, the technology is amazing.
And the thing that I,
the thing that I would consider if I ever
had to do it again is that the atrophy
from the, the, the,
the initial problem is harder to recover
from then you just go in and getting
the new one. And I think when
people push it, you know,
they used to prior to push that stuff
because they wanted to wait for the
technology got better and they only
last 15 years and all that stuff. Um,
but the atrophy that
you try to recover from,
it was harder to recover from than if
you would've gone in and gotten it done
when you need, when, as soon as you
needed to have. So the one you have now,
you have to get it swapped out
every 15 years. No, no, no, no. But,
but in the back in the early
days, well, they, they,
they don't know how long this
new stuff last. They had some,
they had some material that that wore out
after. Like they, cause there's a, uh,
like a, uh, some kind of poly urethane,
some kind of psych outer layer.
Well like a cart lit like a,
like a manmade Cartlidge between
the ball joint in the socket.
And so that stuff wore out in the past.
But yeah,
and they had this new stuff that,
that has been in for 10 years and a lot
of people are already and they've seen
zero where on it. So you don't
know. It could be 30, could
be, you know, could be 10.
I mean I was actually, uh,
I stayed conscious in, in,
I was able to stay awake
for my hip surgery that uh,
cause I didn't want to have to recover
from the, from the uh, yeah. Yeah.
It takes people a month to get the
anesthesia their system really. Oh yeah.
To try to get the anesthesia.
I mean anaesthetise controlled death.
They're just put you right to the
edge of dying and keep you alive.
I mean anesthesia,
some hard stuff on your system to
get that stuff out of your organs.
You've got to do like a
full detox cleanse. It's not
dislike. Oh yeah. Anesthesia.
I've never heard that before. I
didn't, I didn't know that. Oh yeah.
I thought you feel like shit for a
day or two, but I didn't know it.
That's shit's in your organs and stuff.
There's no way that stuff
to go that they can't,
they can't Doshi out and knock you out
like that without that stuff lingering.
I mean, you know, how long does it take
to when you've got a hangover? I mean,
so that they do like an epidural
block on your epidural block. Yeah.
And they had it so good that
they could just isolate the left,
the left hip.
They did that to me when I had my first
ACL surgery yet I wanted to see it. Yeah.
Cause I was like, yeah, I want to watch.
I felt like I'm only going to do this
once in my life. I want to see this.
Turns out I had three of them. Yeah.
Three knee surgeries. But yeah.
But I wanted to see it. I
wanted to, I wanted to be
there if it was pretty freaky.
Yeah, I was ACL. I had ACL to had
ACL. The right light on. Yeah. Yeah.
And a cadaver. I had a cadaver on my
right leg. Left leg, had a patella tendon.
Oh yeah. Yeah. So now your hip
doesn't even, you don't feel it.
You don't feel anything. Not even in
the wheel. Not even a thought. Wow.
Not even like amazing. And it was, I was,
it was debilitating. I could barely walk.
I mean, I could still surf, but I'd get
to land and I was hobbling around like,
you know, move and, uh, Maynard from tool,
you know the band tool. Uh, Maynard is a,
he's a Jujitsu enthusiast and
he had to get his hip done. Uh,
and he fucked his hip up from
stomping on stage. You know,
cause he's always like stomping with one
leg. Yeah. He blew his hip out. Yeah.
Well I think mine's attributed a
lot to my back leg and surfing. Uh,
so I'm on that back leg and
that leg is loaded, loaded.
So I think that, but,
but I know the brakes,
the brakes and the other in
the left ankle and left foot.
And how many I had and that I was always
on it. I know that attributed to a lot,
cause this,
this,
this right leg carried the load for that
thing for it to get your left leg fixed.
My ankle. Ankle. Yeah. I just let it,
so every time I went I went to my knee,
uh,
to get my knee worked on in the guy goes,
he saw my ankle and he goes,
and then he saw the,
about how much mobility I had and he
called in some foot specialists and they
had to take x Ray. They just wanted to
see, cause I have no metal in there.
There's no screws, there's no
nothing. I just let it, you know,
and just so every time you just
let it sort of heal itself up. Yep.
So it snapped and you just walk
around on it? Yeah, pretty much. Cut.
The cast off.
The first time was I was 16,
so I cut the cast off and you know,
and I went at rebroke it
the first time and then, uh,
and then I had broke it other ways had
got a little smarter after we broke him.
But yeah, that's, and then arch the arch.
I broke the arch because
the ankle was so cows,
so a bonded that when I broke it,
I actually broke my arch.
That was probably the most painful.
That was the most painful, uh,
break down in that area. When I talked
to Kelly Slater, he broke his foot.
Yeah. Yeah. The same sort of his
was just recently. Yeah. And his,
his was fucked up for a long time.
He said that's a painful thing to snap
your toes. Like you're the middle.
The metatarsal a crazy. Well, yeah.
You have a 75% of the bones in
your body or blow your ankles.
What really?
75% like times of numbers.
Yeah. Numbers of both.
But your feet, your feet have like
half the bones of your entire body.
God, I never thought of that.
That's crazy. But it made,
there's a lot of shit down there. A lot
going on. A lot. Little, little ones,
little nubs and weird little ankle.
See that's why kickboxing so stupid.
You throw in those things at people
and slamming him in the elbows,
knees and stuff. I
fucked the clods big. Oh,
guaranteed. I've broken my,
that didn't like kicking
something. Breaking your feet.
It's a little embarrassing if it's a
wall though. Is that what you kicked?
No, I'm just saying no. Mine was,
I, like I said, I broke my bro.
Mostly sports related motor,
Mike. Uh, wind surfing,
you know, towing. Yeah. Yeah.
Well I guess with as many
injuries as you had though,
you do understand like what's good
and what's bad for you. For sure.
You hope. But you know, it's interesting.
It's a little bit like in karate where
you know you, when you know how to heal,
you know how to wound. Hmm.
Interesting. You know that the more,
the more you understand, it's like I
think, I think my injuries, first of all,
it's a form of failure.
I think that is taught.
I've learned a few things
from them. And, and,
and you learn how also how
to recover and how to heal.
And so I think that feeds into how to
train and perform like a thing that's all
interrelated because you start to have
a more intimate relationship with your
body and know how it responds. So
I think there's something, I mean,
you don't learn a lot from winning,
you know,
and succeeding that doesn't teach you
anything compared to losing, you know,
losing teaches you in any way.
Injuries are f forms of
loss there, there, you know,
on unsuccessful endeavors.
Yeah. Yeah. When you lose your,
and then you lose your ability to do
stuff and then you wonder why you're doing
it and if you're going to be able to
do it again. Yeah. All that stuff.
Do you float at all? Uh, no. But I saw
your float tank. You've never done it?
I haven't. Oh Man. I've thought
that'd be right up your alley. I know.
I just haven't, I just, I've been invited
by a friend who has one in Malibu.
I just haven't ever, you could use
this word anytime you want. Yeah,
I should try to come up on the float and
then come on down and they tell you one.
It's like I can tell they're
salt in there. By the way,
the everything's crusting up
in the back. Guaranteed. Yes.
Thousand pounds of Epson Salts. Oh
yeah. Tank. Yeah. Yeah. If you're,
anytime I have a notion, so I float
there and there's a lot of noise in the,
oh no, it's true. It's just for,
but that's what you love about the
pool because you're floating already.
As soon as you go under actually has
speakers underwater. So cool. Really? Oh,
you play music. Oh Wow. So you can
get Dan, you can get lost over there.
It's pretty cool. So what other
things do you do besides the,
a curl pressed jump thing?
Like what other or the types of
exercises are you doing in the pool? Um,
we're doing, we're doing, you know,
like single dumbbell cleans, clean,
single arm dumbbell, and then
stroke, get a breath free fall.
So you're doing single arm jumping.
Okay.
And then we're doing single arm
swimming. Ah, single alarm, swimming,
carrying dumbbell. I call that ammo box.
How much weight are you doing that with?
We can do like 50, 60 pounds. Wow.
Do an APP. It's called an ammo box.
It'd be like if he had an ammo box.
Again, you swim across the river,
like that's kind of the concept. We
have cell phone, we have the Yuki,
we have a phone.
Do you keep wanting to out of the water
polo and swim with your handout? Oh Wow.
And then, uh, and then a budget, like
I said, single leg stuff. So a lot of,
a lot of like a Russian
pistol squat, jump, lunges.
Uh, uh, what else? A bunch of,
a bunch of old fast breaks where we're
doing this one where we dropped down.
You run along the bottom with
two dumbbells to the other side.
You set one dumbbell up, you jump up, you
bring one dumbbell out, you go back down,
grab the other one,
bring that one out and then pull both
of them out and drop back down and run
back out.
We call that one fast break kind of
mimicking like if was basketball court,
you'd run down, you jump up twice
and run back. Jump up twice. Um,
and then we have spider
man. We have, I mean we,
they just spider mans one where you swim,
you carry a dumbbell and you descend
into one end, you jump up, you grab,
you get a breath, you just send
it into the other end. And then,
and then all these exercises were able to,
we to make them harder.
We'll do them on an exhale so you can do,
so we ramp up,
you know,
we can either increase weight,
we can create increase distance or
we can do an egg, do it on an exhale.
So when you developed all this stuff,
did you run all this down from your
own practice? From all trial and error?
Like how did you develop this? Well, some
of them came from failure. So you know,
you try to do one move
and then you'd fail.
Some of them came from friends that I
was working out with. It would hold,
well let's try this. And
then we'd modify it. Some,
some of them came from my daughter.
I watched my daughter,
my one daughter swim down one day and
grab a weight and then try to swim up with
it. I'm like, oh, that's a great
move. And we, you know, so we, we, we,
some of it came out of
necessity for movement,
like certain dynamic movements
that the basketball guy, you know,
one of my friends needed or a,
and then it naturally all the
movements kind of naturally evolved.
I think that's why they're also great.
And there's an isolation to each limb.
So we have an isolation so you can really
see if the dexterity of your right arm
versus your left arm and how
strong it is versus the other one,
how strong one leg is next to
the other one to have the Mo,
the ranges of motion and the
mobility we're, we're doing,
we can do a front back flips
and front flips multiple.
So you jump up and get a breath and
then do multiple flips and, and uh,
and extend work time so that your extend
breathwork where you'll do, you know,
like three or four moves in one on one
breath. So we have a bunch of ways to,
to ramp it up as we evolve.
Because you know how it is.
It's like in any exercise you get
proficient and then you're like,
well how do I make it harder? While
you make it longer, you make it faster.
You make it heavier. I mean these,
but because you're in the water,
we always have the breath holding element.
Uh,
and then we had the distance element and
then we have the weight because we have
weights so we have the weight elements.
So those are different ways that we
can ramp it, you know, ramp it up.
So when you're developing this program,
are you writing on this stuff down?
Are you doing these workouts
yourself and saying, okay,
I really started to fatigue after
30 of these, so we'll try to,
well I have a group of friends,
I have a group of guys that train that
come to my house to train six days a week.
So there's like days a week?
Yeah. In Malibu? Yeah. Malibu. Oh.
So because now the pieces show
Malibu's is summertime, right?
Summertime is when it's really like a,
the season for training because
there's no surf in the winter time,
you're not going to train and then
have a giant swell and be tired.
That would be just stupid.
So you never want to let the problem
with it is that you get, you know, I,
I tell people, I go, listen
in probably in any sport,
you get the most out of
shape during the season.
You're in a certain kind
of shaped game shape,
but you're really not in
shade because you can't,
you can't have a regimented workout
routine if you're competing now and so and
so. And in my case, uh,
the oceans dictating the performance,
right? So you can be, oh,
there's going to be 20 feet to
next, you know, in three days.
And then all of a sudden you show that
there's not, there's no surf said,
only half the size or the wind
screws it up or something.
So you get all that build up.
So we have to do things to
kind of exhaust the energy.
But you can't be in a nice Monday,
Wednesday,
Friday pool training with Tuesday,
Thursday, Saturday, you know, um,
lifting mobility in yoga and whether,
you know,
it's like you can't get into
that kind of a rhythm and a,
and Hawaii not conducive for that. Anyway.
It's part of the beauty of it is like,
I always so beautiful,
let's go to the thing or we're going to
go down the coast cause it's a nice day.
It's a good day for fishing,
go to the mountain.
There's just so much other activities
to be done. We're in this environment,
you're in the desert and it's kind of
like, okay, it's a June gloom, no problem.
This bang iron or you know, ride the
mountain or do whatever you're gonna do.
So that's, uh, the end. But
in that summertime routine,
uh, I have a group of guys in that we
bounce everything off of each other.
So I'll do the, we'll do 10 and he'll do
10 and he'll do 10. I'll be like, yeah,
that was good. Okay. Up the way. Okay. Oh,
twenty's too many or that weights
too much or that way. It's enough.
And so we just kind of, it's evolved
naturally that way. And then, uh,
and then I got some other friends that
are a little bit more professional.
We have a, uh, my friend of mine, PJ,
who's been involved with all of the, uh,
stuff around XPT to write programming
and do that kind of stuff that changed.
He trains a lot of fighters and
great and mobility and, and, and uh,
and to other training stuff. So
he, he'll come in and they go,
they start to really break it down
and make it into a real program.
But we have routines that we do.
We have circuits that we do that we know,
you know, how, you know, when
we're taxed. And you know,
it's an interesting thing about what
the pool really teaches you is that,
you know, you have a volume of energy
available. We go, okay, well, you know,
you got a 50 gallon tank and I can
do three or four drills in fifth,
10 or 15 minutes that does,
you just, there's none left.
You just blew all 50 gallons.
You do.
Extended breath holds with super hard
work where I can, you know, make the,
give you some things that are a little
lighter and now we can take that 50
gallon tank, we can drag it out and
make it, make it last two hours. Right?
Cause we do these, we're
doing higher volume, less
weight and so we're, you know,
breathing more often,
we can expand that thing.
So everything in between just
blowing that whole tank up at once.
Right. Through real intense breadth
hole with maximum weight as you know,
Max breath hold Max weight, uh,
Max Rep. Okay. We're good. We're,
I mean it's, and I think
liftings the same way. You know,
it's like how many Max lifts do you have
in a certain day and how many per week
do you have though? It's real tangible in
the pool. The pools reel, you know, the,
the, the interesting thing about
the pose that it doesn't get,
you don't get muscle soreness
because of that compression.
So you don't get that like wow,
I'm sorry. You get, you go.
Almost every single person that comes.
And it's one of the A, I always say,
you know, you got to call me and
tell me if you fell asleep at lunch.
And every guy, every, every,
every person, you know,
I was in the thing and just in
their desk at the work or whatever,
just fall asleep, like guaranteed
at some guys, you know.
Oh I fell asleep for an hour.
I saw 20 minutes, 10 minutes,
you know, but everybody,
why is nighty night?
I don't know.
I think it has a lot to do with
the oxygen and that and, and the,
and the taxation of that environment.
But it exhausts you in a, in a,
in a, in like a terminal way. Like
it's, it's, it's a complete exhaustion.
And I, and I don't know why, part of
it is the threat of being underwater.
Part of it is though that the water is
sucking the, the calories out of you,
you know, because it's
like, uh, when they, uh,
when they were talking to a Phelps
about burning all those calories, while,
you know,
three quarters of the calories,
he was burning his cause he was in a
70 degree pool and people go, well,
our 75 degree pool, and I go,
yeah, but the by the body is 98.6.
So for the body to keep itself warm
over in three hours, it's at 75.
That's 20 degree differentiation.
You've got to keep the bodies just working
to keep itself warm and that and that.
And because the water affects you more
than the air, it's, you know, it's,
it's more intense on your system.
They just, you just get tapped.
So that the water temperature, the,
uh, the, the, the oxygen load, the,
the psychology of being
underwater with weights, you know,
the workload that it's taking,
all those things play into just full,
thorough exhaustion and
nothing, nothing. I do, uh,
exhaust me more thoroughly and yet
more kind of comfortably than that.
You know not, you don't have to
expel. You don't still want moving.
Well you're not wounded. You don't come
and see if I train that hard in the gym,
I'll feel hurt after I'll be,
I'll be wounded.
I'll be a little like and if I move wrong
or something I'll be like, oh you know,
you feel like something,
you tweak something.
So this allows you to do this six days
a week. That's one of the reasons why.
Well it actually helps flush the other
days when you're doing other land
training. So actually helps support
your, but no, I mean we're not doing,
we're doing pool training probably
every other day and it just,
I ended up turning the kind of, I love
being in the pool so much that we have,
we do a thing called surf and turf,
so,
so we have surf and turf where you're
doing like some sort of some sort of
burpee press,
some kind of lifting on the deck into
the water and then a routine in the water
and then back on the deck and back
in the water. You might be doing a,
we have one of a move called a sea horse
where you hold a dumbbell between your
legs and then you hold your feet up in
front of you and you swim like this with
a dumbbell in your lap. And then when you
get to their side than you do pushups.
So you do pushups on that side. You, you
see horse over, you do push up that side,
see horseback, you do that. I mean
you just blow up. Right. So we, I,
I think I, I enjoy that, that part
of it, just, just being creative,
making it fun, making it interesting.
That's the part that really is enticing.
Just the dredgery and the
monotony. Like when you said,
Oh yes, swimming laps, I go,
that's just like dredgery just, ah,
like, which there's a mentality for that.
I'm good. I can be good at
that. Like I can get on a,
I can get on my board and you know,
I've, I've done some endurance stuff.
I palled 22 hours one time. Um,
I've done some much two hours. Yeah.
Oh yeah. So I've done, I did actually,
I actually did a thing on
Hawaii called the Hawaii five,
we call it the life 500 we started
on the south point, a big island,
and we biked across the big island,
so 125 miles. Then we paddled to Maui,
uh,
38 miles,
and then we biked across the valley and
then we paddled to Molokai and then we
biked across Molokai that
we palliate to a Wahoo.
Then we biked across the wall who then
we paddled to Hawaii that we biked across
the Hawaiian. We did that in five
days. So that's what's day six.
Like that's when you start coming.
Good.
It's the end. But you're, but you're good.
No, explain. It's what you said about,
you know, about running. Yep.
On Eddie, Eddie, when you know,
all of a sudden you're, the body's
like, oh, is this our new house?
Is this, is this what we do? What
we just, what we do? Yeah. Once we,
once the body makes that
decision, all of a sudden you're
good. Like, okay, I'm, I'm,
I'm, I'm good. I mean the hands
had blisters everywhere, but the,
the body felt like, oh,
this is where we, you know,
I did a race across America with done
with wild man. He talked me into it.
I didn't want to do it. And he suckered
me into, into it. And uh, he said,
cause I was like, he
had other plans. He was,
cause he was an operator and he's like,
he wanted me to go in this race.
And there's four, it's a
four man team, you know,
ram is now called the race across America.
It's a bicycle race across America.
You start in Oceanside
and in and Delaware.
And so you bike across and each
guy just goes like 45, 45, 45, 45.
And then you chase the other guy
when he's riding and you get out,
then you just go full bore as hard as
you can for 45 minutes to the next guy
gets on.
He goes,
but you're riding in the car chase and
the other guy and you do this day and
night, right? All you're doing it
day and night. And He, uh, you know,
we, the first couple of days we felt
pretty sick. Like you felt you don't even,
you don't even want water, like water.
You look at water and you're like,
that's when I really learned to
appreciate Kombucha, but, uh,
but we don't even want water. And then
day two, day three, all of a sudden,
day three, you're like, wow, I stomach
thing goes away. I'm ready to go.
I feel good, let's go. And uh,
but it was that thing about the
body being comfortable with that,
that kind of dredgery but I,
I don't mind the monotony of that,
of that kind of like,
Hey,
I'm going to go that on and just you're
gonna Paddle for. But if I do it in my,
in a routine,
like something that's a little
more not out of a mission.
Right. And then I'm like,
then you're just, you know,
I don't want to go in and do the same
lifting routine did day in and day out.
It's just not,
Eh,
I'd prefer creating new stuff and making
it interesting and, and having that,
that the distraction of the,
of the challenge of something
new and keep me interested in,
or did it make sense? Do you, what about
massage? Yeah. Love it. Live for it.
We'll kind of get,
uh,
only good ones get a
like deep tissues going.
I've done to kind of almost every single
modality you can think it's usually
about the person. It's usually about
the person that gives it and, and,
and how, if they're healers or
not. So I just try to find healers.
And when you say healers, what
do you mean? That people, that,
that do it because they're
into taking care of people.
Then they not doing it as a profession.
Like they don't do it to make money.
They make money as a side product,
but they're healers. They, that they,
that they just have a gift that
there you go, you, you know, you can,
you can get 10 massages, right. And,
and, and they're all can be good,
but there's just one of the people
that they just have a skill.
They know how to touch.
They know what it is.
They know where they know how to feel it.
They know how to,
they know how to use the
system. Um, you know, I've done,
uh,
that my,
the thing that I'm crazy about right
now is I'm crazy about dry needling. Um,
that's the thing that has been the most
profound, uh, I mean, I've done, uh,
you know, I've done, uh, oh,
she ought to and acupuncture and that
thing and just, I mean, I, you know,
and Rolfing and I've done the 10
series three times and I mean,
I've had all those different modalities,
but dry needling has been, you know,
and then I have another person
that, that, that just does,
and I don't even know what art it
is. It's just massage. And she just,
she just is able to understand the
tissue, no loud, and she's relentless and,
and, and, uh, and, and won't,
won't leave and won't leave
it until everything releases.
And she knows how to release it.
In Dry needling to people. Uh,
dry needling is,
uh,
a technique where they use acupuncture
needles on soft tissue and they,
um, touch the trigger
point and get the system,
the stuff to release. Like it's, uh,
it's not acupuncture. It's, it's a,
it's a different modality that, that, um,
that I'm not sure if it's,
uh,
what states it's legal or not in,
I know most of the athletes that I know,
they used to do it a lot in
Australia. They do it in Europe. Um,
emotional in some places. Some places
it's not legal. Yeah. Why? I have no idea.
It probably because it works and
somebody threatened by it. I mean,
isn't that usually the case?
Well,
gas or someone doesn't understand it
and they think someone's a quack and get
those needles. All of these people,
you don't know what you're doing.
There's no science here. Yeah.
Well there's some science
behind it and uh, and it,
but it absolutely is the
most, uh, functional.
I mean,
I've got friends with giant knots in
their traps in the one session that then
goes away. Extremely
intense. Yeah. Intense,
intense. But it, but dry
needling is, you know,
if I ever have my friend who's really
good at it, comes through, I'll, I'll,
I'll steer her your way. Cause it's,
it's, it's, it's, it's the most effective.
I mean, I, I, you know, uh,
I think, uh, as someone, uh,
that you are always looking right, we're
always looking like, what, what, you know,
hey, we need the heat, we need the ice,
we need the thing. We need the food.
We need the thing. Where's
the tumor? Where's the, you
know, we always are looking.
And so when I run into things
that are affective, I'm,
I cherish him because I
know that you know it.
And the problem is you have a high bar
because when you've experienced great
work, you just, you can't,
you go get somebody who does
a little mushy mushy and
you're just like, ah, don't,
I don't have time for
that. I'll, I'll, I'll lay,
I'll lay still for three hours if I
know somebody knows what they're doing.
Right. But I won't be there
for 20 minutes if somebody,
if I feel like it's like half ass.
Yeah. Which is a lot of it, you know,
a lot of that stuff's out there
and PR and no fault to the people.
I think part of it is just, they probably
just don't know. And their intentions,
it's gotta be your intentions.
Why, why do you do it? You know,
it's interesting how some people can just
find those problem areas. They just, Oh,
it's right here. I don't even
know. They know. And they,
and they feel it with their hands.
They see with their hands and they know
right where it's like connecting where
to dig in and, and how to release it.
Yeah. That's an art. That's what I said,
which will release. It's real. It's real.
When you're good and you and somebody
really knows what they're doing.
That's why I say more about the people
than the technique because there's, I can,
yeah, yeah, yeah. But, but give me the
person and, but that dry needling is,
is it's the most effective of any of the,
uh,
of the stuff that I've used it in. This
person is in California that you use, uh,
the girl that helps me as in
Hawaii. And then, uh, they,
they teach in Colorado.
It's actually a,
it's actually a technique
that they developed. Uh,
some guys that were studying
pain is from my understanding,
they were studying pain.
And so what they did is they had all
these people that were injured and
different areas and then they injected
them with different solutions and they
injected them with like a placebo and
like Celine and Novacane and all kinds of
different things.
And everybody got better.
And what they realized is that it was
the needle and the acuteness of the
needles themselves in the areas that
were painful, that were causing,
that was causing this release.
And so they develop the whole
pain referral chart and a,
and then they die and they developed
this, this technique. And uh, it's,
it's cause everybody always
confuse miss confused, you know,
confuses it with acupuncture. They owe
Yaki book drag. No, it's not acupuncture.
This is in the soft tissue acupuncture's
on the Meridians and on the electrical
system. Right. This is
soft tissue. This is,
this is to get the soft tissue to release,
but they'll take stuff that you've had
that cyst like a cable somewhere or not
or something that just won't
release and, but it's, you know,
it's back to that no pain,
no gain. Oh yeah. For sure.
There's always that.
I've got a lady that does trigger point
massage and it's the most painful shit
I've ever experienced in my life. It's
like you just want to quit. Absolutely.
When I get out of there the next day,
everything's like loose and pliable and,
and I've had things that are like,
well, I've really injured myself. And she
fixed it. Yeah. And then like a day later,
like it doesn't hurt anymore.
I'm like, this is strange for,
and it's been hurt like for months.
Yes.
So there was something in
there that was not enough.
And I always assume that that's an
injury and sometimes it's not an age.
It's not, yeah. It's just the tissue. It's
just not really set up. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
and they've tested it up to them to deal
with the Fascia and some other stuff
going on that did that,
that they have to know how to release it.
And saunas seems to help
that quite a bit too crazy.
The combination of those two are,
I mean that's,
that's what I found is that sauna and
ice kind of eliminate the need really to
get worked on enlisted super cute.
Like if it's not, if it's super cute,
then there you, you, you know, you need,
you need somebody to go in there and,
you know, put the Jack Hammer on it.
But, but if it's not a cute like that,
just the normal maintenance and,
and,
and actually preventing the stuff from
getting to a point where you really need
to get the work, the sauna ends
magic. That stuff is crazy good.
And it seems to me that when I've
been ramping up the temperature,
like in the two hundreds and now in
the two to it seems more effective,
more effective, more effective. It's
more intense. More torture. Yeah.
More towards her, more results. But I'm
a little bit, you know, and I don't know,
maybe it's something you can find out,
but I this thing with,
I'm a little rocky right now with the,
with the infrared was going to ask you
that I'm a little rocky with the infrared
right now only because, uh,
of just some of the, uh,
something that happened to me with
my skin and then, and then met,
I met a dermatologist that was pretty
educated and he was saying that, you know,
that that,
uh,
that he says is that it damages the
Collagen and then it does, yeah. Yeah.
Damages the Collagen in
your body. He's way, hey,
affects the structure of the skin
because of the penetration of it.
And that the most you should ever do is,
this is, and these are my words, but the,
uh, the most you should ever
do is, is, is, you know,
three times a week for 15 minutes
at the most for infrared. Yeah.
And Andy was saying that,
uh,
and you should never look at it as well.
Jesus,
like it's harmful to the eyes. Yeah. So,
so I got a regular sauna just because
the protocol that the doctor Rhonda
Patrick was talked about for
those, I guess it was uh,
was it Norway? Yeah. Yeah.
That was all regular songs.
Yeah. So I'm like look,
if they're getting into this
results from regular sauna,
I'll just do a regular sauna.
Well I like regular anyway cause
it just seems like it's natural.
It's kind of like ice. Like people go and
Cryo, hey you want to go cry? I'll go.
I have a nice tub. I don't eat
crow. And by the way if you,
if you want to do a real
ice going on ice tub,
cause Cryo is cake walk
compared to a real iced up.
You can only do Cryo for
a couple of minutes to,
and you don't have heat next to it.
And I mean you can not only do ice for
a couple minutes till it's like think
about cryo though is you can do
cryo and then work out. Yeah,
you can do Iceland workout too and know,
yeah I do that all the
time. In fact, we incorporate
ice into training.
And so one of the things that we do is
we'll three quarters into the training,
we'll just pull out,
right when you start to kind of lose
some of your juice and you'll go do like
three minutes and come out and
then try and you have another gear.
So that's another little thing
to incorporate ice within
that within that system.
Or we'll do ice as we,
as we train as one of the stations,
imagine doing a circuit. And
one of the stations is, you
know, we are doing, uh, uh,
we're doing a horse a couple of
months ago on the last season maybe,
but we were doing a, uh, like a,
an iron horse free standing in a horse
position with your arms and we'd stand in
that position for 10 or 15 minutes
of course, position with your,
on your musical horse stance.
Yeah. Horse car. Yes. Yeah. Okay.
So we're in a horse stance with where
the arms are straight out. Okay.
You're holding, so call it the iron horse
or whatever, just standing in the horse.
So He's standing in the horse position,
10 minutes, go on the ice, three minutes.
Oh, come back out San,
they'll send another thing,
go on the back of the ice in the thing.
Blow you up,
explode you like crazy. So I
mean there's always, like I said,
there's always a little, you
know, a little hook to give it.
But the ice to incorporate it within
your training I think is phenomenal.
Like people, that's why I questioned
warming up because people go warm up.
How about do three to five minutes ice
and then go start all your cardio and
start to train. Right now your body
will just be freaked out, freaked out.
But it's, the ice makes you stimulate
it. Like when you feel the system, it's,
it's cold but you're not cold.
Like it's trying to heat up,
heat up Michael Phelps in the pool,
heat up. It's revving. Interesting.
So there's all of that.
That's like the science of the
fun, you know, the, uh, the,
for me,
I look at it like a laboratory.
It's a little bit like being an artist
and playing all that stuff that brings,
makes that keeps me interested. It keeps
me excited about about learning. Uh,
learning. Cause I think it's about
learning. It's all about learning. Yeah.
Learning about your body and learning
about what to affective. Yeah.
Well that's why I'm glad there's guys
like you out there. The Guinea pigs. Yeah.
Well the Guinea pigs, Guinea pigs. That
again are in my age group. Yeah. So like,
I know that it's possible because they're
in this 55 absolutely long after that.
Well, listen man, thank you. Thanks
for coming here. Thanks for doing that.
I want to do your workout too. Yeah.
Well you're, you have an open invitation.
I happen. I gotta I gotta I'm still a
after the fires, I'm still cleaning,
so I got this weekend. I
should, we are doing a cert,
so we're training some people this
weekend, but after this weekend,
I'm open for the summer. So if you, you
want to come and, uh, you know, beautiful.
We'll do that, Ben. Let's make it happen.
[inaudible] Aloha to you too. Thank you.
Thank you.
Bye everybody.