Three to Jamie with the quick count.
Jimmy Dore.
We're live.
Oh,
fantastic.
Do you use headsets or.
No?
Oh Shit.
Sorry.
Headset.
It's up to you.
I just feel lonely if I'm the only guy
with headsets.
Oh,
okay.
Is there a better trigger?
What?
Hey,
what jobs did it's one,
one minute after 1159 minutes before the
top 12 hours.
Did you ever do that?
Do you ever do like a regular radio
show?
I had in college.
I had a radio show,
but it wasn't real.
It was just broadcast to no one actually
it turned out to the campus.
It was it just to the campus we're
supposed to be going out to the campus
and then we found out about three months
in,
it wasn't going out to anybody.
I always had dreams of doing a radio
show,
but I always knew that I would fuck it
up,
you know,
I'm like I'd get fired or something.
I never and I never thought anybody
would hire me.
I got in trouble at that station for a,
a,
for playing the same song three times in
a row.
It was so good.
Yeah,
I liked it.
It was a song,
I don't even remember.
It was like some off brand and I never
heard of them,
but like the Rabbini brothers and I was
like,
this a fun song.
They fired you from a college station,
fire me.
They came in and he yelled at me and I
was like,
this doesn't even go and go to anyone
and if it was a nice day and I had to do
my radio shift,
I would just come in and simulcasts with
the FM because that was on am simulcasts
with the FM station because I wanted to
go out in the quad.
I want to sit in the studio.
It was next day.
I wonder if anybody has done this.
I mean I don't think you could do it and
put ads on it,
but you could do it.
It was just a fun project.
Have your own radio show on a podcast.
We'd just play songs.
Could you do that Jamie?
No,
I think because you can't give.
If you give people a download of a song.
That's right.
Yeah.
That's why.
So you could stream it though,
maybe like stream it on youtube,
maybe,
maybe but not,
but you'd still have to pay some kind of
royalties for those songs.
I don't know what.
Even if you weren't making any money off
of it,
you don't have to pay.
I think so if someone is streaming your
jokes,
they have to pay.
Yeah.
But the thing is nobody wants to hear
your jokes more than once.
That's the problem with jokes.
That's not true.
Joe.
Really?
Alright for first of all,
let me blow smoke up your ass a little
bit.
I'm not actually,
it's just sincere.
So I've seen you do comedy before I saw
you.
We did the 2004,
I think it was the aspen festival.
We were on the opening night show at the
Wheeler Opera House.
And then I saw you do sets at the Improv
and I always thought you were funny,
you know.
Uh,
but I never remembered any of your
jokes.
And then I saw you at the comedy store a
couple of weeks ago and I've been doing
your act ever since.
I've been telling you jokes everywhere I
go to anybody who will listen and
everybody falls down laughing.
Those jokes that you have,
first of all of the joke about Weinstein
is just so God damn funny.
And then the joke about the wrestling,
God damn it.
You know,
and I,
it's,
it's hard for me to not say them right
in your face right now.
I know how that would be not good if I
did your jokes right to you,
but I can't not do.
Those are some of the funniest jokes
I've heard in a long time.
I know
people are going to be saying,
oh,
he's such a kiss ass.
I'm not kidding.
I love comedy and I love jokes and I can
remember jokes that I like and a few
whites theme that's so rushed to get
that onto a netflix special because I'm
worried it's going to get old.
Yeah,
right.
Right.
Now,
you know,
it's like it happened a couple of months
ago.
It's still okay and I'm recording in
April and one.
I'm like,
boy,
April is like the wire that's like under
the wire.
Yeah,
I think it'll be okay because they're
not going to be a bigger rapper or
whatever.
Then Harvey Weinstein could come.
He's.
He's the pinnacle.
Right.
Like if you had a cosby joke today,
it's still okay because he's such a
raper.
That's right.
I forgot cosby your ride.
You forget.
Did you see the recent shit?
We're cosby was at a barber shop.
There's videos of him hanging out at the
barber shop talking about jazz,
a trivia barber shop guys and Philly.
No.
Yeah,
he actually performed recently at a jazz
club.
Yeah.
He showed up at this jazz club and
perform and then announced that he was
going to perform at another place.
He's like,
he's back while he's in between trials.
Wow.
So see,
that's the weird thing.
I always wondered like he was still
selling tickets.
Yeah,
like people will still show up to see
him,
but before no one before anyone knew for
sure what was going on.
There was a couple of accusations and
everybody was like,
what is this?
Like,
what is this really?
Is this real?
Is this someone doing a shake down?
And then they started the.
Just the fucking tsunami of accusation
started piling in,
which is really incredible when you
think about it,
how many years that guy was doing that.
It's unbelievable how he could get away
with that for so long and terrifying and
then something and then now it's like
you just go on a bad date and year you
get in trouble.
Like Aziz Ansari.
Yes.
Yeah.
Now,
well it's the pendulum swings,
you know,
I think it's,
it's,
it's kind of open season on men right
now and it'll swing back around and it
will be normal again and you know,
it makes sense.
You know,
you,
there's so many of these accusations
that happened.
You know,
after awhile they pile up and then
there's this like anti male resentment
and then it'll swing back and it'll
normalize and people were sort of
reacting theses thing and they say,
well that went a little too far.
And then the woman who was in charge of
the California woman who was a big me to
support her,
she got busted and you see that?
Oh No.
Yeah.
She was grabbing some dude's Dick,
his ass.
And she was drunk and she's just a
congresswoman.
No kidding.
Yeah.
You ever had.
I've ever grilled do that too.
Yeah.
I've been grabbed,
you know,
like bill burr said this famously in was
100 percent correct.
It's after shows drunk women in their
forties.
They get a little liquored up,
they get crazy and they just get a
little grabby.
They grabbed that ass,
they'll go for it.
And you know,
uh.
Did you,
did you feel violated?
No,
it's anybody who says it's not different
for men is just a liar.
It's not physically scary.
It's like if my daughter comes and
punches me and kicks me,
you know,
like she'll do that for fun.
Just as a joke.
It's not threatening.
Right?
It's fun.
It's silly.
But if you did it,
I'd be like,
Hey man,
I'm fucking hit me.
Like a man hits you.
It's different.
Like if a man is trying to grab a
woman's ass,
you're talking about someone larger,
grabbing someone smaller.
It's scary.
It's dangerous.
The real threat of rape is actually know
40 year old lady's gonna rape me.
You know,
it's not going to happen unless I want
her to.
It's just not.
It's not going to go down that way.
They're really sick to be something
really wrong with me.
Well,
there was this guy and see this how I
like remembering jokes.
I haven't seen this guy probably tell
jokes for 25 years.
His name is Paul Kelly and it was right
in the,
in the eighties or at the end of the
eighties when when women were in the
workforce and that was like one day at a
time.
Remember that show was all about women
and so things were weird in the
workplace.
Men didn't know how to talk to women and
how to act,
and then they would go,
oh,
she's just like one of the guys remember
that.
They would say that that was the highest
compliment you could give a woman.
She's like,
one of the guys,
we don't have to act weird around her
and this Guy Paul Kelly,
that's when people started talking about
sexual harassment and he said,
see men,
we don't understand what that is.
It's like a.
wait a minute.
You mean you're,
you're,
you're gonna Touch my dick while I type
and I get insurance,
we say that,
but my friend Tj,
do you know the amazing atheist?
Do you know who he is?
Oh,
I do know who he is.
I've seen his show woke up,
but I'm
to a very funny guy.
Yeah.
He told me and he's kind of an
introvert.
He told me that he was working in an
office,
wants in a woman who was his boss was
sexually harassing him and it was
completely unwanted and she would grab
them and he would lock up or freeze and
be uncomfortable and,
and it was gross.
You know,
he said it was.
He was real,
but he's a big guy.
I mean,
he wasn't physically in danger.
I'm sure it felt super uncomfortable,
but it's always going to be a notch.
Several notches less scary.
Well,
because she can't take out her dick and
stick it in you.
There you go.
That's a big difference.
The thing is the violation.
That's like the fact that someone could
physically hold you against your will
and denigrate menu.
Take.
Yeah,
get into your body.
Yes.
Inside,
inside of you,
like a woman literally can't do that.
She can engulf you.
That,
that could be scary.
So when engulfing you,
Jesus just doesn't seem as scary though.
Just the same violation.
What happened officer?
Well,
uh,
he said he wasn't gulped.
He uh,
engulfed my dick with his ass.
He just took it over.
Just tell you Weinstein joke.
Just tell it.
No,
it will be on.
I'm,
I'm recording in April.
So it's close.
We're only two months.
So what have you done that rustling joke
on a special.
But now that's all.
All this stuff's new.
It's all this stuff is from my,
from my last special,
which was last year to now.
Well,
you know,
I have been.
What it,
what makes,
I think that sets stick in my mind also
is that it made me jealous,
right?
Like,
you know,
when you,
I don't know if you get Jello,
I still get jealous when I see someone
doing something better than me.
I want to do it.
And I'm like,
God damn it.
Uh,
it made me want to get out and calm
because I haven't been doing comedy as
much.
And you know,
it's like a muscle.
I think Jerry Seinfeld said,
if I don't do comedy for about four
days,
the uh,
I notice a difference.
And if I don't do comedy for five days,
they can notice.
So I haven't been since I started my
youtube show,
it's a,
I haven't been to a standup as much as I
should and I stopped touring like I
should and uh,
and I miss it.
I want to do another special.
And watching.
And that night of comedy at the comedy
store made me go,
God damn it,
I gotta get out here and stuck at my
desk.
The highest compliment you could pay a
comic.
God dammit.
It was like that many times,
you know,
that feeling of just being inspired,
just wanna go home and right.
Yeah.
And I was,
you know,
I mean my son went fine,
but it wasn't a.
I'm not on my game right now.
Right now I have to really start working
it again,
which I have started and I'm going out
and it's,
uh,
it's my,
I forgot.
It's like this is all I ever wanted to
do in my life.
Was standup comedy and like being a
standup comic to me was like being
really Yoda in goodfellows,
like,
you know,
I didn't wait in line,
I fucking wanted something.
I took it.
I fucking follow rules or listen to your
bullshit.
I fucking do what I want.
I say what I want and they pay me for it
and that's,
I just fucking love that shit.
And uh,
in that.
And then I started doing the youtube
show and it becomes a job for me and
it's a grind in a sense and doing
comedy.
I so miss sleeping till noon and then
getting up,
working out,
having all you had to do is figure out
who am I going to have lunch with today.
That was my big decision.
Who am I going to have lunch with?
Then I go home after the lunch,
I have a nap,
then I go out and do a show.
It's fun.
It was the greatest life in the world.
Why did I fuck it up?
But you must enjoy doing your youtube
show too.
I do because it helps me to discover who
I am more because as a standup,
I,
um,
I was like,
Bill Hicks was my favorite guy when I
saw bill Hicks in Chicago almost quit
because I was in comedy about three or
four years.
And I was like,
I fucking know what I'm doing,
you know,
before I got on stage,
I'd be like,
wait till they get a load of me,
you know,
I was like,
that guy,
oh,
the fucking baddest ass in Chicago.
And then everybody's talking about this
guy,
Bill Hicks.
Right.
And I was like,
oh,
I'll have to check this guy out.
So I sat down and he starts to set and
about two minutes in I started drinking
and then about five minutes and I
started drinking more and about 10
minutes.
And I was convinced I was going to quit
comedy because my whole life,
you know,
I always thought like George Carlin was
my hero and I was like,
you know,
if I do everything right,
uh,
I could maybe be like George Carlin for
one special.
Like maybe if I get everything right and
I really work at.
And I saw Bill Hicks and I knew that it
wasn't,
I was always going to be competing for
second place and so when he died it made
me feel a lot better.
I was like,
Oh fuck,
I'm with the saddest thing.
When he died,
of course he was my hero.
And um,
you know,
I didn't really know him.
I knew him tangentially and it was weird
to feel that kind of sadness for someone
who you don't know personally.
And um,
so that was a big deal to me.
Watching Bill Hicks had totally changed
my life and I tried to be like him,
of course,
like an idiot.
I tried to be like him in you can't
write.
And uh,
and then one time I was dating this girl
and might be my wife,
I don't know who told me this,
but she said,
you don't look like you where you come
from because I come from the south side
of Chicago,
grew up poor 12 kids drinking powdered
milk,
you know,
and having the Shit beat out of me from
the fucking morning till night,
right?
Because I went to Catholic school,
tough neighborhood and my,
so,
uh,
and she's like,
you can't be angry like bill Hicks
because you look like you come from
privilege money and you're dressed well.
I always like to dress nice because I
grew up poor.
I was wanting to be.
And uh,
so that's when I had to like pull back
on the anger on stage.
And I was like,
if you watch my specials on comedy
central,
I'm very nice.
And uh,
doing the youtube show is what,
let me connect with my anger,
which is always what drives me.
That's interesting.
That is what has connected with people.
And that's when I really started selling
tickets and my everything,
you know,
everything I wanted to get from comedy
in a sense I got from this youtube show,
so now I can go wherever I want and do a
show and my fans will show up.
It's the greatest thing that ever
happened in my life.
You're very good on your youtube show
and you're also very fair.
You know,
one of the things that I really like
about your shows you,
you are,
you're obviously a left leaning guy,
but you very balanced in your criticism
of the left and you criticism of
criticism of the left and well,
if you have to lie to make your point,
you don't have a good point.
I agree with you a thousand percent.
It's such an important thing that's
being missed today.
Yeah.
And I don't know that.
And I don't know.
I've gone back and forth on issues.
Everybody.
I couldn't be allowed to go back and
forth on issues,
you know.
Um,
I was,
uh,
I was against gun control.
I was for gun control than I was against
it again.
I mean,
you know,
uh,
so,
um,
the thing that people give me a lot of
heart I get,
I get more of a hard time from people
who consider themselves on the left than
people who consider themselves on the
right today.
Today.
This is a new thing though.
It's the new thing in the last decade,
right?
It's because it'd be less than a decade.
Well,
to me it sends it,
it's,
it really started with Bill Clinton in
92,
but it didn't get really ramped up until
Barack Obama in 2010 when it was clear
that Barack Obama was a neo liberal
corporatist who was going to do the
bidding of the war machine and Wall
Street and big Pharma,
which is why when the Democrats got
control of government,
they had the presidency,
the Senate filibuster proof Senate for a
few months and they had the congress and
the house and
they didn't pass single payer or even a
public option.
What did we get?
We got a right wing healthcare plan
anyway,
which is a giveaway to the Pharma and
health insurance companies that left out
$28,
million fucking paper and infuriated
small business owners,
infuriated people that were,
that had a small practice.
There were doctors and you know,
and all sorts sorts of people that are
better than what we had.
It was a bad solution.
It wasn't a solution.
What it was was a solution for the
pharmaceutical companies and the health
insurance company.
That was it better than what we had way.
Well,
because you before there was preexisting
conditions and you couldn't get covered,
so then it was supposed to.
So now you can always get coverage and
that part was better.
You can get covered even if you had an
issue.
Right?
Right.
So then you could go and you could go on
an exchange and stuff like that.
I didn't ever had to do that.
I always got through my wife's employer.
I'd always had my health insurance.
Right.
And by the way,
having health insurance is doesn't
really mean that much.
I got really sick until you were talking
about this before,
but that's a different thing,
but I got a,
had a,
a,
an illness that they couldn't diagnose
for a few years and it almost killed me.
Right.
And it wasn't,
it was called hypophosphatemic
Osteomalacia and it'll be on late night
TV.
One of those commercials.
Do you have Osceola?
Trisha was side effects.
Side effects include death.
I,
uh,
what is it a,
it's a,
it's a bone disease.
So my bones were admitting to the bottom
line is my bones were having a bone
disintegration woe.
So yeah,
I used to be much taller.
I know.
That sounds funny,
right?
Has actually true.
Is that true?
When we met I was taller than you.
Get the fuck out of here.
I'm.
How tall were you?
I was around five.
10 and you'd shrank to five?
Eight.
I'm a,
I'm a little,
little under five.
Eight.
Wow,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
So,
um,
I know.
Right.
And when that happened I was going to
kill myself trying to stretch yourself
out.
One of those things.
They use the medieval torture devices.
So I'm one of those guys who,
if I want something,
no matter what price I have to pay
physical,
whatever,
I'll pay it and I'll do and I'll get
that thing I want,
right?
Like,
I'll get it.
But this book,
can you mind elaborating on this thing?
Yeah.
So,
so I couldn't fix it by stretching.
I couldn't.
It makes it,
it's just joking about that.
But,
but,
so what does it do to your.
It's making your bones shrink so it
gives you osteoporosis.
And then my bones got hollow,
like a Old Lady.
And then,
uh,
my spine collapsed when I stepped off.
I stepped off a curb and too hard and
they,
they didn't know what it was.
I like talking about too much,
but uh,
they told me all different kinds of
things.
Oh,
what's your muscles?
It's their nerves.
That shit in your head.
It's in this.
And,
and um,
I was limping for a few years when
people were always like,
how are you doing?
I'm like,
oh,
I'll be all right.
And uh,
you know,
because no one likes to hear about
anybody else.
And so,
um,
and then now when that happened,
they were like,
oh no,
what's your bones?
I was like,
you motherfuckers so everybody me that
you should go.
So I started going to bone doctors and
everybody told me I should go see this
guy,
Dr Charles Sharpe.
And I called him and he was expensive
and he didn't take insurance.
And so I was like,
well,
I'll go to someone he trained so I will
go to someone who trained.
I wouldn't get any better.
After six months I go to someone else,
he trained,
he wouldn't get any better.
So if I was just about to die and uh,
I went to him to see him.
I like,
I was going to pay the money and go see
him.
And uh,
he,
he figured out what it was like that.
And he says to me,
he goes,
you know,
no one in the nowhere you go,
no one's going to know where,
what this is.
I go,
yeah,
I know I've already been everywhere.
And he said,
I only saw this once before in 1968.
And he says,
and you haven't.
Yeah,
yeah.
So then any causes it,
uh,
it was just a,
my,
my own,
they didn't know at the time,
he thought I was a tumor,
but they fit since figured out it was
just my own bones leaching of hormone
that makes your body a leach,
the chemicals that I need to make bone.
So anyway,
this is boring,
but no,
it's not boring at all.
So,
uh,
he fixed me and I started to fix you.
He just diagnosed me what was wrong and
what I needed.
And so I need to take supplements,
right?
Uh,
for my bones to make bone,
like some people take calcium.
So I take this thing called phosphorous
because phosphorous and calcium and
vitamin D to make bone,
right.
So,
um,
that we did that and it was amazingly,
you know,
he's just an amazing doctor and he's
very right wing,
uh,
as far as I can tell,
right?
We,
he,
he doesn't like to talk politics,
but uh,
it comes up and uh,
he was in the military and all this
stuff and he's just a great guy.
I just love him.
He's so smart.
He's so smart and he fixed me,
so getting back to what I was going to
kill myself.
So when I stepped off the curb and I
shrunk and shrunk even more,
they did an operation that gave me about
an inch back.
I was even shorter.
Right.
So I'm like,
holy fuck.
I'm like,
this is,
this is like I wanted to kill me.
I was literally going to kill myself.
What was the operation they did?
They had to put some high four slash
steam,
so bar or something like that.
They collapse,
they puff it up and then they stick some
in it.
Oh Jesus.
But I saw I was serious.
I was like,
I cried one day.
I couldn't stop.
I didn't,
I didn't know how to stop and my eyes
puffed up like I couldn't see almost and
I was going to do it.
I was like,
I'll just kill myself.
And,
and the only thing that kept me from not
killing myself was my manager called me
and he said,
hey,
I go,
you got that hour special on comedy
central and I have a central saved your
life.
I was like,
what?
Talk about that was the best of times.
It was the worst at times.
Wow.
I could not believe I'm like,
what?
And then I just knew I had to do this
special because I couldn't let all those
motherfuckers who said I w I shouldn't
move to La and be a coach.
I couldn't let them when it was about
that,
it was about I'm going to show everybody
who doubted me and said I was crazy and
I'm going to show them.
I'm going to do this God damn special.
It's going to be fucking awesome.
And
then I kill myself,
Christchurch and by the time.
So I had to get this.
Anyway,
long stories.
Um,
I had to get this operation in my leg.
It was the Bo Jackson surgery.
You've got a hip replacement.
It was a,
the thigh bone was dead,
dead,
dying.
And uh,
I went to,
my doctor sends me this other doctor who
vented the operation at USC and I walk
into the office just like my doctor
predicted.
He's looking at my chart and he looks up
and he goes,
what?
I've only seen this in books,
meaning what?
I have and I was like,
that's what Dr Sharp said,
and so he was going to give me this
operation.
He goes,
we're going to take this bone out from
your chin,
we're going to put it in there and then
you can't step on that foot for six
months straight.
And I said,
I have a,
I have our special.
I'm taping an eight months.
I go,
so,
uh,
I can't do this operation.
He goes,
well,
your thigh could just snap at any
moment.
And I go,
I guess that's the chance I got to take.
Holy Shit.
If I can't do this special,
I'm going to kill myself anyway.
Yeah,
give a fuck.
Right.
So,
uh,
by the time we got to do the special,
eight months later,
Dr Sharp's treatment had kicked in and
they didn't know it was going to fix it,
but it fixed it.
They fixed it.
Holy Shit.
You could've got that crazy operation
for nothing.
Fuck man.
So treatment is just supplements.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And you take that to this day,
every day,
every time I eat I have to take to
foster.
Did you alter your diet?
Uh,
no,
he just,
he tells me to make sure I eat meat
because I need to,
whatever it's in it.
I need the stuff.
Yeah,
whatever,
whatever the good stuff is,
he'll look at me like he goes,
you're from Chicago,
right?
And I go,
yeah,
go eat meat like that.
Not One of those fucking plenty.
You're not one of those,
are you right.
And sad that I'm turning into one of
those now.
Goddamn it.
What plant?
Eating asshole.
Well,
I'll stop this fucking video about cows.
I haven't seen those two work.
They know.
No,
not those.
So in the,
I don't know,
Norway or Denmark,
I don't know where.
Somewhere over there they have a law
that you have to let the cows out of the
barn in the spring on this by this one
day.
Oh,
you're talking about the one with the
cow jumps out.
So it's bouncing around like a dog.
Yeah.
So they all come out and they start
jumping around like dogs,
you know.
And I was like,
oh my God,
I couldn't eat my dog,
you know?
And that's,
that was the first like,
Gigi.
She's like,
oh Jesus,
and then I accidentally saw this thing,
this video about a pig and I can't eat
pigs anymore.
Forks.
I can't and I'm that close to not eating
meat,
but I eat a lot of pasta.
You know,
I like to.
I like to cook,
but your doctor said,
but it's terrible for you.
You've got no right to wheat pasta.
Oh,
that's not any better.
It's not better.
No,
no.
It's terrible for you.
Whole Wheat Pasta is the same amount of
gluten in it.
It's the same amount of sugars in it.
It's,
it's maybe slightly better than refined
pasta.
Like wheat bread is slightly better than
white bread,
but it's all bullshit.
It's all just filler like nutrients,
but seven grain bread is better than
horse shit.
Man.
Bread is horseshit.
It's not good for you.
Don't do this to me it just is.
Wheat is just not a good food.
It's a good filler.
I mean,
if you're starving,
you know,
keep you alive.
I mean,
that's literally what are.
They invented it for the ground up wheat
and figured out a way to cook it and the
wheat that we're eating today is not
heirloom wheat.
It's all wheat that's been adjusted and
genetically modified so that it has
higher yield and smaller areas like,
um,
there's a documentary called what's with
wheat.
It's really fascinating.
Really?
Yeah,
and they go over the details of what
happened with wheat,
but at somewhere around the early 19th
century or 20th century rather than
early 19 hundreds,
they started altering wheat and they did
it so that they can get higher yield in
a smaller area,
but by doing that you increase the
amount of complex glutens and the weed.
It makes it much more difficult for
people to digest and then that's where
you see like the elevation of all these
gluten sensitivity issues and people are
like,
wow,
I was a kid.
There was no gluten sensitivity.
First of all,
nobody knew what the fuck happened.
He got fat.
He had a heart attack and die.
They really didn't know.
They didn't.
They were much less aware of why people
are fat,
but sugar's wheat.
Those are two of the biggest problems
hitting.
Yeah,
it's terrible for you.
So when I went to this Chinese medicine
doctor,
um,
uh,
it was back when I was feeling sick and
um,
so I went to somebody recommended you
should go to this Chinese man.
I'm like,
I'll try whatever.
So what he did was he changed my diet,
so he got,
got me off of white sugar,
dairy,
even brown sugar is terrible for you and
I'm sure.
Sure.
And,
and,
and carbs basically.
And um,
he told me not to drink soda and I said,
well,
I drink diet.
He goes,
that's worse because of the chemicals in
it.
And um,
so I was like,
Holy Shit.
I was like,
okay.
So then he sells he,
these herbs for 800 bucks a month
supply.
So I realized that's all I ate when I
got out of his office.
I like,
every time I eat I'm eating white flour,
meeting bread or a pizza or a pasta or a
cheese or everything.
Everything he told me not to eat,
that's all I ate.
So I was like,
they go.
I remember my girlfriend said,
how long are you going to do this?
I go at least for a month because that's
how much these herbs are and the $800
bucks I don't want.
So by the.
By Day three I was leaping out of bed.
I could not get over how much energy I
had.
Yeah.
That's because you don't have that big
insulin crash when you're eating all
that sugar and all that bread.
Your body's just fighting that shit off
all the time trying to process it and
then there's this big crash boom.
And then you have to take a nap.
What do you eat?
I eat mostly meat and Aviva cahtos and
healthy fats and vegetables,
but I.
I hunt so I.
everything I eat is wild,
so when I'm eating meat,
I'm eating elk or deer or something
along those lines.
You don't feel bad when you see the
deer,
you just.
Yet?
I do feel a sense of loss,
but I do also know that there's a wild
animal
that had no idea what was going on until
an arrow hit it.
It's not like something that's living in
some pen and being tortured and
genetically modified and filled with
antibiotics and hormones.
It's a wild animal and their life
expectancy is very short.
They get taken out by bears and wolves
and coyotes and Pumas.
They don't.
They're not making it.
None of them are making zero,
zero percent.
They're starving to death.
They're freezing to death.
What you're doing is just dipping your
foot in the wild world.
You are taking part in the cycle of
life,
so your against factory farming and
hundred percent.
That's why I became a hunter.
I was going either going to become a
vegetarian or I was going to hunt.
Those are my two options.
I had to figure out what I was going to
do and I experimented with vegetarian
back when I was fighting to try to make
a weight class and I didn't like it.
I just didn't feel good.
And then when I started eating meat,
I did it for like six months and then
when I started eating meat I got way
better.
Like instantly,
like instantly started gaining muscle
instantly was fighting better,
instantly competed better.
And I moved up a weight class and that's
when I became my very best.
What you re class?
What did you fight at?
One 54 is when I moved up to.
I was trying to stay at 1:40 and this
was.
I fought at 1:40 only for a year when I
was 18.
I just couldn't do it
now.
Did you bring your power with Easyjet
Joe when you went up to 1:54 yesterday.
Whilst I was 18 I was still growing.
Still Thick.
And that's young.
Yeah.
Okay.
So it was artificially keeping my body
very,
very thin.
That was a very lean.
But my point is that I knew that when I
watched too many of those videos,
factory farming videos,
factory farming should be mean fuck
insider trading and all the other
problems that we have in the world.
That's all terrible stuff,
right?
Terrible stuff.
Factory farming is a goddamn crime.
It's a horrible crime against life.
And the fact that we just do it and then
we have ag gag laws.
Yes.
That's what's.
That's what they're insane.
Yeah.
Laws are fucking criminal.
They're insane.
It's
not America.
It's not the America I thought about.
I thought you always supposed to have a
free press.
That's the equalizer.
That's what's different about us.
And now they gag the press.
You can't talk about craft.
Well,
they could.
They could sue you.
They could put you in jail if you feel.
If you have tortured animal criminal,
if you film a crime.
Right?
Exactly.
So they've made a.
So what's,
there's some famous saying,
well you know,
what is exposing a crime is a crime.
You're ruled by criminals.
I don't know if that's the quote,
but something like that.
So we,
we,
by the way we are being,
we're,
we're living in a this,
a lawless time,
right?
So the old law only applies to the poor.
It does not apply to a war.
Criminals.
It doesn't apply to Wall Street.
It doesn't apply to anybody.
Giant corporations have figured out a
way to skirt the law is money.
If you steal from rich people that they
will get upset.
Like Bernie madoff stole from rich
people.
That was wrong.
He fucked up.
But if you're,
if you're jamie diamond or a fear of
Goldman Sachs and you steal from poor
people are veterans or a lady,
that's fine.
That's fine.
That done.
You become secretary
of the treasury.
Steve Mnuchin with Mnuchin is
one of my favorite evil characters of
the 21st century.
When you see him with his wife and his
wife has gloves on and they're holding
the money and he's smiling and when she
fucking tags like Gucci and cardiac and
all these different like big time
companies and our instagram posts,
when she stepping off of a fucking
private jet,
like,
Holy Shit,
look at that picture.
I love,
first of all,
the fact that she would fuck him.
That's a crime.
That woman is a thief.
That's the power of money.
Yeah.
I mean,
but it's also prostitution.
That's.
That's a crime.
You don't think she's hot?
No,
I do not.
I'm doing.
I'm going to be honest with you.
I think if you were there,
I'd say okay.
It's got a funny personalities.
Good guy.
She probably enjoys it.
You know,
it doesn't make any sense.
Well,
let me see.
Let me just say this,
there's now Steven Mnuchin is horrible
and he should probably be in jail,
but guess what?
He's not in jail because.
Why?
Because a Democrat didn't,
didn't prosecute him when she was
supposed to.
That's Kamala Harris.
So she's corrupted by Wall Street too.
So you can point your finger at him.
You're like,
well,
the reason why he's there is because of
the Democratic party is corrupted.
That's why he's there.
And what did he do that he should have
gone so well?
Kamala Harris is um,
so he ran one West Bank and they enter
in,
investigated his bank and they found a
thousand instances of criminality and
they said if we had thousands and
thousands and anything less than a
million instances,
like what the fuck?
It's water under the bridge can be
picky.
Yeah.
You got to break a few eggs.
So they said,
and if we investigated we would find a
thousand more instances of criminality.
She said don't go.
That was that.
And she never had an answer for it.
So.
And now she's the darling of the
corporate class.
The,
you know,
the same people who anointed Barack
Obama and Bill Clinton are the same
people who are annoying her.
So that's.
So that's the problem.
That's why I get so,
I mean,
if you,
Brock Obama's entire cabinet,
uh,
came from an email from Citi group,
okay?
So people trying to say that somehow
corruption started on January 20th,
2017 are fooling themselves and that's
what I'm fighting against on my.
All right.
And
you're one of the only people that are
doing that.
You're one of the only people that are
online that you,
you're not,
you're not obligated to shill for the
left.
You're not,
you're not doing it,
but everybody else seems to be.
I don't mean to everybody else.
If you're one of the people that are not
like,
fuck you,
Joe Rogan does.
Is it just a handful of people who are
not just so few.
There's so few that are calling out
people in the Democratic Party for what
really is going on.
Like I was infuriated when people that I
knew that I was friends with were trying
to tell me that,
that Hillary Clinton was a good choice.
That's the same choice.
I'm like,
look,
I don't know if she's murdered people,
but I know that I worried that she's
murdered people.
That's a real.
I really wonder like this seth rich
shit.
I know.
First of all
just lead.
You don't even need to go there.
You know,
there's so many other things,
so,
so many other things that we know for a
fact.
The Clinton Foundation for instance,
so the Iraq war,
I'm old enough to remember one being for
the Iraq war was a disqualifier in a
democratic primary.
I'm,
that's,
that's where I'm from.
That's why she lost a Bruck Obama,
the first God time she ran and all of a
sudden we're supposed to now people like
joy behar says,
that was a long time ago.
Forget about it.
Why don't you go tell that to his
soldiers,
to a mother who's got a dead soldier?
Why don't you go tell them out of the
little girl just died an illegal war.
Why don't you go tell that to a couple
hundred thousand Iraqis who are dead?
Get over.
It was a long time ago,
you.
Anyway,
so I remember that.
Uh,
also,
uh,
the Bill Clinton was no friend to the
working man.
In fact,
he was this demise starting of the
demise of this country.
So bill,
you know,
Ronald Reagan's scared the shit out of
the Democrat so much they decided to
become like them.
And so what Bill Clinton did was he got
in bed with Wall Street,
the military industrial complex,
big Pharma health insurance,
and the Koch brothers.
He started a thing called the Democratic
Leadership Council with Al Gore.
They had executives from the Koch
Brothers on the Democratic Leadership
Council.
They completely turned their back on the
working man.
And what happens when you have two
parties that are in bed with management,
you get Donald Trump,
and that's exactly what happened.
They gutted welfare at the same time.
They explored the prison population
called black kids,
super predators at the same time,
they did Nafta and then they deregulated
Wall Street which crashed the economy
within 10 years.
That's what Democrats did.
Democrats did shit that Ronald Reagan
could only dream about and his wet
dreams.
They couldn't pass Nafta.
George Bush couldn't pass.
Nafta took Bill Clinton to do it.
Bill Clinton gave the cover to the other
corporate democrats to go along with it,
so that was the beginning of the end for
the working class in America.
In fact,
now you know I wouldn't vote for Hillary
Clinton and that's why a lot of people
on the left came after me and they still
do.
Well.
It was confusing to me that you were
saying,
hey,
if you want to vote for a real
progressive.
What about Jill Stein?
Yeah.
If you vote for a party boat,
here's a program.
You actually agree with the grand new
deal,
right?
So.
And we know what it's like.
No,
that's what you're throwing away your
vote.
Like how?
How will your throwing away your vote?
So we all know for a fact because of the
wikileaks emails that Hillary Clinton
had a thing called the Pied Piper
strategy,
which was she told her minions in the
press,
please prop up Donald Trump.
Prop him up.
Why did she want Donald Trump to be
propped up?
Because you want it to run against
Donald trump.
Because she knew that she was so
repulsive to most of the country.
She needed someone who was more
repulsive than hurt.
Turns out that was a bad calculation,
is terrible calculus,
so that's called the Pied Piper strategy
and everybody.
That's why the you turn on Chris Hayes
and he would show donald trump's empty
podium for an hour instead of a Bernie
Sanders and then he wagged his finger at
people with no money and no power for
not voting for a corporatist warmonger
like Hillary Clinton who just.
Why?
Why do you think the people in Michigan
wouldn't vote for Hillary Clinton?
Maybe because she put half of them in
fucking prison,
but because she passed Nafta and Barack
Obama was trying to sell tpp at the top
of his lungs at the same time was trying
to get people
to vote for her.
They know what the fuck was going on and
that's why half the country doesn't
vote,
but you're going to wag their finger at
the people who actually do vote,
who come out and vote their conscience
and they don't fucking prop up evil.
You know what the voting for the lesser
of two evils gets you donald fucking
trump with is also a really sneaky thing
that happens where you have two parties
and one of them you think of as this
conservative warmongering party,
which automatically makes the other
party the the enemy of that.
Yeah,
but they're not.
They're not.
Well,
we have two pro war parties and that's
the point.
There's not an opposition party.
They oppose trump on the most ridiculous
bullshit.
They just voted for an extra
$160,000,000,000 to go to the war
machine.
One hundred 60 billion.
Let's remember.
Bernie Sanders wanted to pay for free
college,
which was somewhere around $65,
million dollars.
So and everybody said he's fucking
crazy.
How are you going to pay for that?
They just did that in a blink of an eye.
They passed $160,000,000,000 to a war
machine that we don't have an enemy to
fight.
You know,
Russia spending $65,000,000,000 a year
on their military.
There are paper tiger.
We got no fucking enemies out there.
We have to keep inventing them.
And the last,
the last enemy they invented was isis.
Isis.
I don't know.
You were supposed to shit our pants over
them,
Joe,
because they have kitchen knives.
They'll cut your head off with a kitchen
knife.
That's what I'm supposed to be afraid
of.
What the fuck?
It's.
It's,
it's amazing how they can keep us scared
so they can keep perpetual war going.
This isn't Orwellian nightmare.
And the Democrats right now,
she'd be screaming about the Pentagon
budget,
but they're not screaming about it
because they're complicit.
They're in it.
And that's what's wrong with this
country.
That's why we can't have nice things.
So when,
when they tell you that you were broken,
we can't afford stuff.
They don't mean we can't afford trillion
dollar war is trillion dollar bank
bailout.
Billion dollar oil subsidies and prison
construction.
That's not what they mean.
They mean we can't afford shit like
healthcare or education or roads or
bridges or firemen or libraries or
anything that makes your fucking life
better.
Because whenever they need bombs,
they got it.
Hey,
we're broke for social security.
We're booked for Medicare.
How?
Above for bombs.
Oh,
we got bond money,
we keep it running because we're not
really in a war in the sense of like
world war two or World War One,
we're in this weird war of.
It's like a calculated through all
economic words,
so they're all.
So we went into Iraq for the,
for the oil Libya based because he
wanted to go off the petrodollar,
but it is stunning how much funding this
kind of war gets versus all the
different social programs that we need
in this country.
Yet infrastructure programs,
yes.
We and people always think like,
well how are you going to pay for that?
We don't have to spend any more money.
We can actually spend less and less
money.
We don't have to spend $750,
million dollars a year on a military
that's bloated.
We have thousand bases around the
country,
around the world.
We don't even know how many bases there
are because lots of them are secret.
So what do you say to the argument that
we need them in order to stay safe?
It's not true.
That's the big argument,
right?
The big argument is this is the way we.
We've destroyed Isis because isis was on
their way to building up.
We invented this,
we invented al Qaeda,
and then we invented isis.
We certainly aided in their development,
their development,
and we then we directly funded them.
We don't know the whole Mujahideen
story,
which was Osama bin Laden was our guy.
He's our guy.
He wasn't t Russian terror,
anti Russian freedom fighter is what
they called Osama bin Laden and then all
of a sudden they didn't need them
anymore.
So why?
And we're still in Afghanistan 17 years
later,
three more years.
That word gets a gold watch.
And what did they do?
I mean,
what,
what did they do to get us out of there?
I mean literally what is,
what is there is none.
There is no exit strategy.
Exit strategy,
there is no exit strategy from the
Mideast.
In fact,
they just announced we're going to be
permanently in Syria.
So.
And by the way,
the Syrian war is complete bullshit.
Those gas attacks.
Now I've been completely debunked.
I didn't believe him the first time.
What happened during those guests tax?
So what that's called a false flag.
So what happens is they wanted the
United States to come in on their side,
the Obama side to overthrow him.
And uh,
so what they would do is they would do a
gas attack on their own people and then
blame it on his side.
And then this has been proven be.
Yes,
they did it.
Yes.
And then,
uh,
and the first time was the night think
2013 in Barack Obama wanted to bomb.
And uh,
and I knew it was bullshit then.
Do you remember when everybody freaked
out about that?
Yes.
And then he didn't bomb them.
Remember he didn't get to bomb them
because he was like,
fuck you.
Yes.
He goes,
let's put it to a vote in the congress
and the people don't want war Joe.
So the people said,
fuck you.
And he goes like,
we're going to do it anyway.
Guess what they did it anyway they
bought,
they dropped so many bombs on Syria.
They ran out of bumps.
That's a fact,
right?
So the air force was out of box.
Which year was this?
So was it 2015?
That dropped so many bombs in the
Mideast.
They ran out of bombs.
That just a fucking fact.
Look,
if you buy all these bombs,
you've got to use those.
I mean,
what are you going to do with them?
They're just going to sit around.
And what if somebody accidentally sets
one off,
whether an American soil and I don't
want that.
You can't have that happen.
So.
And here's the weird thing that the left
is doing right now.
They're attacking Donald Trump from the
right.
And what do I mean by that?
So when they want.
So they say,
Donald trump is a Putin puppet.
And the only way you can prove you're
not a Putin puppet is you've got a bomb.
Somebody you got to bomb Syria.
Remember that?
They were like,
oh,
he's president today because he bombed
Syria.
Remember that fucking Brian Williamson
was nothing in his pants.
All he bombed was airstrips.
So that's what they're saying.
So they go,
oh,
they bombed airstrips.
Oh you didn't,
you bombed the old planes and not the
new plane.
So what that is,
you're attacking Donald Trump from the
right because left people are supposed
to be for detente and you're supposed to
be antiwar and anti and anti empire.
Right?
So what new attack Donald trump going,
oh,
he didn't really bomb them.
You're attacking them from the right.
You're saying he should be more
militaristic,
which is fucked up.
Well,
it supports the argument that everything
is circular,
right?
That as far right as you get,
as far left as you get,
you really come to some sort of strange
ideological point zero point.
That can't be true,
but not in this instance because what's
happening there is corporate right wing
Democrats are attacking trump for not
being right enough.
When you're talking about is where I'm
at,
where I'm antiwar.
And then there's also anti war anti
intervention as people on the right.
So a lot of people voted for Donald
trump because of that,
because he always said he was an anti
interventionists.
He's going to get us out of the Middle
East.
It was crazy to be there and bring our
boys home and all.
And that's why a lot of people did vote
for trump because of that.
And um,
and that's why a lot of people said they
felt more comfortable voting for trump
because he was because hillary actually
promised more war in Syria than he did
and we,
and,
and that's turning out to be true,
uh,
because she wanted a no fly zone,
which means we're going to shoot down a
Russian jet.
Are you fucking crazy?
So I'm,
I'm on the,
on the left antiwar.
There's no antiwar movement in the
country that's represented by a
political party right now.
Do you think that this right though,
the way the left is attacking Donald
Trump from the right,
as you say,
don't you think it's just because they
see an opening there to criticize and
to,
to point out his vulnerabilities,
what they're doing with this whole
Russian narrative?
Is the establishment not wanting to
examine the system that gave us Donald
Trump and so they want to distract you
with Russia until we get to the next
election,
then it's working.
Yes.
That's a very good way of putting it.
Distract you from a system that's
archaic and outdated and it doesn't work
if people are not asking that question
anymore.
Why did people vote for Donald Trump?
In fact,
the only time they asked that they took
the shittiest answer was because racism
really the same country that voted for
Barack Obama twice.
Somebody just doubled down on that the
other day saying,
are there racists?
Is Berg or they're racist.
Who voted for Donald Trump?
Yes,
of course.
So what?
It's Alonzo Bowden said it best.
He said,
not all trump supporters are racist,
but all racists are trump supporters.
Fucking Alonzo.
Um,
and,
you know,
I went to a trump rally and it was
disgusting and scary and it was all
xenophobia and it was all race.
It was worse than I thought it was going
to beat 'em sound.
He tapped into that.
But what's interesting about him tapping
into that is this is not something that
he had been timing on about for years.
He was a Democrat,
but this time he's not an ideologue,
which is,
you know,
I heard when he got into office,
he was like,
why don't we just give everybody
Medicare,
which is of course the answer you just
gave everybody Medicare saving this
money instead of food stamps has given
food.
He's like,
we have this issue with people.
They buy cigarettes and booze and stuff
with food stamps.
Just let's just give them food.
It's not a bad idea.
That's not a bad idea.
If it's healthy,
good food places where people can go and
pick up healthy good food,
that might be a very good idea.
Itto A,
we need an infrastructure plan in the
United States.
Yes,
and FDR did that,
right?
He gave old people retirement.
He gave young people a job.
He put pike,
gave people dignity.
He gave him a job and he said,
if you're willing to work,
you'll have a jet.
Remember that?
The old saying,
when I grew up as they're going to be a
chicken in every pot and a car in every
garage or something like that,
something like that,
and they don't say that shit anymore,
right?
Because the government is not there to
help you anymore,
but the government does pretend that
they are.
I mean,
he has to have.
That trump has going on about is how
much job.
I mean,
how many more people are working today
than before African American
unemployment is at the lowest point.
Forty years.
The economy's booming.
All these different things.
The economy,
when they say the economy's booming,
they mean Wall Street is booming.
The correlation between Wall Street and
regular people's lives is not a.
well though stock market has been
booming.
Uh,
I remember I got called into CNN to do a
thing when the stock market crash
crossed 13,000.
Now it's up 25,000 and that was a big
watershed moment.
That was just a,
like eight years ago.
I got called in to do that at CNN.
That was like,
oh my God,
we.
So we've gone.
We've doubled the stock market.
People's paychecks have been doubled.
People's lives gotten worse actually,
but I have a problem with saying that
because there's just too many people
you're dealing with.
When you say people's lives have gotten
worse,
like what people.
Well,
I'll tell you,
too many people,
63 percent of the country can't afford a
thousand dollar emergency.
Half the country right now is either
poor or low income.
Thirty 50 percent of all wage earners in
less than $30,000 a year in the richest
country in the world.
Jack Ma,
who is the Jeff Bezos of Asia,
he runs the Amazon of Asia and he said,
you know,
the problem with the United States isn't
making money.
It's that you guys don't distribute it.
Right?
That's communist shit coming over from
China.
You're going to let that slide,
but let's call those communists.
Billionaires are buying up all our real
estate.
Did a socialist country produced all
those billionaires?
Well,
go to the.
As soon as they got into communism or
into capitalism,
rather,
they did it in a very ruthless way.
I mean,
you look at what it's really kind of
fucked up like what's going on with some
of the places where we buy our goods
like Foxconn,
where they have nets around the building
and keep it from fucking jumping off.
But when trump has been in office for
only a year,
he can't expect all those things to
change.
But his argument has been that those
things are improving.
You think at this all.
It's all horseshit.
Yes.
And so why is African American
unemployment at the lowest rate that's
been in 40 years?
Is that because it's unreported?
Like people stopped looking for jobs.
They report.
They stopped counting those as being
unemployed.
So there's that.
Yeah.
And he stopped taking unemployment and
they stopped looking for jobs,
but they don't count them.
Right.
They don't count them,
but they're still unemployed.
Real sneaky statistics.
Yes.
Also a really like it.
If someone was honest about that,
I would like it to like,
what's the real unemployment rate?
That's what we want to know.
What's the real unemployment?
Would we find that out though?
I don't know.
Maybe I noticed a guy named Mark Blythe.
He would probably know what it is.
He's an economist.
He,
uh,
he coined the term global trumpism and
he has a great line.
He tells the elites about how we're
running.
They're running the economy,
of course I'm going to butcher it,
but he says he,
the Hamptons aren't a defensible
position.
It's a low lying area.
He got a Scottish accent,
the Hamptons,
or as a low lying area.
It's a very bad area to be that,
a defensible position,
meaning when the fucking people come for
you,
they're gonna you're,
you're dead.
You get sides is a military base in the
tens,
right?
You're not up on a hill.
People can get to you.
So a lot of gold diggers.
So the jobs suck.
Everybody's job sucks.
And we know we,
we,
we hollowed out the unions.
Nafta was the crushing blow to the
unions in this country.
And um,
you know,
we need unions is one of the,
one of the things that actually cush
cushions the blow of the brutalities of
a free market,
right?
So you have unions,
you have social programs because
capitalism fucks everybody.
And so you have to have all of these
things in place to kind of cushion the
blow of it and we get.
We got rid of them,
right.
Bill Clinton gutted welfare at the same
time he did Nafta,
I mean,
and then he floated the prison
population.
But people that I know that,
yeah,
were in unions,
particularly some friends that I have
that were in the auto union were saying
that it was getting completely bloated.
They were doing were having two people
doing a job that was only for one person
and there was all this there.
There was all this real wanting,
purposeful waste,
and this was all designed into certain
contracts.
This is a buddy of mine that was an auto
worker in Detroit.
He said we had shifts where there was
supposed to be two people on the job and
everybody knew it was a real simple
thing.
You work on machine,
so I would work four hours and he would
work four hours or I would work a day
and he would work a day,
but we both punched in and that was
just.
It was just common.
And there was several of those and he
goes and you were getting $100,000 a
year,
$200,000 a year for some jobs,
just ridiculous amounts of money for
jobs that really didn't warn that kind
of income.
And he said this was all negotiated into
the contract is like it's a good thing
to get fair wages and healthy wages and
health insurance and all these different
things.
He said,
but it was unquestionably bloated,
which opened the door to all these
factories going into Mexico and all
these other places.
Well,
what opened the door for those factories
going?
Why?
Why I would say two things to that.
First of all,
it doesn't.
It's kind of anti logical to think that
the union would say,
no,
we're not going to negotiate on this and
go ahead and take our jobs.
Both of those jobs to Mexico.
So I think they had a chance number.
Right.
Number two is if you look at the
strongest economies,
right?
You look at Germany,
they have strong unions,
Japan,
they have strong unions.
And by the way,
the union sit on their boards.
Well,
there's also,
it was
a real problem in the 19 eighties and a,
I guess a little bit in the late
seventies when the oil crisis happened.
America was making dog shit cars.
They're just making terrible and then
Japanese,
we're making these cars that were
goddamn bulletproof,
right?
Like you'd make it,
you'd buy a Toyota Corolla and that
fucking thing would go 400,000,
500,000 miles when I was single problem,
you know,
you buy an oldsmobile and that thing
would shit the bed inside of a month and
a half and you'd be fucking furious.
And everybody was like,
buy American,
buy American.
And a lot of people like,
well fuck you man.
You're making shitty cars.
He's got the emmy.
I bought a dodge Daytona,
I had it for maybe three months and the
handle fell off in my hand.
I went to open the door and it came off
in my hand while he motherfucker.
And that was like,
I think one of the first car,
first car I ever bought.
That's it.
Well I was a road comic.
I'm like,
I have to buy a Honda comment.
Yeah,
I can't,
this has been a early nineties.
I'm like,
I have to buy a car that I can rely on.
And same thing.
I had an accord.
He had a civic.
So the best is it.
It never breaks.
They never broke.
So uh,
so I would look at that unions,
it's not the problem.
The unions aren't the problem.
Yang fact unions are an answer to the
problem and if you look at the
economies,
everyone wants to be like,
look at Germany by the way,
the German unions just won the right for
a 28 hour to work 28 hours a week and
they got a four percent pay raise.
I would say that's eight hours too much.
I would agree.
I really think I'm talking too much.
Yesterday with Johann Hari who wrote a
book on depression and one of the major
causes being the way people live their
lives without control,
doing things they don't want to do.
And he was saying that somewhere in the
neighborhood of 87 percent of the people
are doing things they don't want to be
doing most of the time for,
for a job.
And I was,
I was making the argument that we,
we,
we've set up this structure that's just
completely ridiculous and we've stuck
with it because it's just the way we've
always done things.
This 40 hour work week plus overtime,
it's chaos.
You're losing your life.
The end,
by the way,
we'd be working more if it wasn't for
unions.
We had weakened because of unions,
right?
Goes back to the foxconn thing.
They don't have unions and they have
fucking nets around their building and
dormitories where they live,
where they work.
So that's when people say about Amazon
too.
And my whole thing is like people's
like,
why do you still,
you know,
you can't use Amazon,
you can't.
I'm like,
you know,
it's so hard to live off the grid,
you know what I mean?
It's like I drive a car so I'm going to
have to buy gas from Exxon or shell.
Alright.
So does that make me a bad lefty?
Because I'm supporting oil.
Company's supposed to get a prius bro.
You know,
I mean you still put gas in a prius.
That's right.
You got to get a tesla.
But then your wrench,
that new tesla three is a cheaper one,
right?
It's $50 something you want on it.
It's still going to cost more.
You want to see pitches flexera
quitting.
What you gotta do is you got to get an
old car like an old civic and then
rebuild it.
Yeah.
Well the,
the,
the uh,
I least now I don't buy cars.
That's a scam.
I think buying cars anyway.
Uh,
it is for the most part,
but not if you buy classic cars.
Oh no,
that's different.
Definitely.
If you're Jay Leno and stick your chin
out when you do that.
Well in his new show is fantastic.
It's really good.
That car show is.
That's the show.
I wish he would've been doing all along
the exact same.
Are you kidding me?
Yes.
I couldn't believe how much I liked it.
I liked him.
I liked him on that.
Says,
well,
you know why it's because he's
passionate.
I like him.
It's like,
that's really was,
you know when you would watch them
interview someone,
you could tell he didn't give a fuck
about what the question he was asking.
Do you remember the Bill Hicks bit?
Yeah.
Bill Hicks,
bit of course.
Interviewing Kelly.
He got a car now you drive in,
you drive and he got a girlfriend.
He got to know bill.
Bill hugs would have A.
Jaylen will reach into his drawer and
pull out an Uzi and stick in his mouth.
I used to be a fucking comic and he
blows his brains out and it forms an NBC
peacock in the on the wall and the wall
behind him because he's a company man to
the bitter end and that was the bet
reloading.
When does it become?
Well,
that's the weirdest thing.
You know,
Jay Leno was again,
one of my,
one of my inspirations to become a
comedian was in the early day.
Yeah.
And I would tell people that and they're
like,
Huh?
Because they only knew him from the
tonight show and I'm like,
I don't know what he's doing on that
show,
but he's the funniest guy in the world.
It would be like if Dave Chappelle,
before he did Chappelle show,
decided to host a talk show and then
completely stopped anything
controversial and completely stopped
having an opinion on anything.
If you look at that one,
Jay Leno used to go on David Letterman.
He was the guy.
Oh,
it was a guy who was edgy and super
cheap,
super edgy.
He made fun of Corporate America,
like nobody's business.
He was a sharp comic.
He was a,
it was the best comic.
And uh,
so that's why it was funny when he,
when he got the tonight show,
I just didn't think he showed off his
talents,
no heat,
but for him that was making it,
he was in his head and his head.
That's it.
This is what is in our heads.
We were like,
what did you miss?
Everything,
like,
what the fuck are you doing?
You don't want to.
I was on the tonight show and um,
a couple times,
one time I was on and during the break I
sat there with Jay and I,
I said,
I think it was the first time I was on.
hey man,
I go,
what was up with that Bill Hicks?
Bit Like A.
Well,
no.
Yeah,
yeah.
I had to,
had to ask because I was like,
what are the odds I want to be on the
show again?
I'm like a mom.
Once,
I think it was the fear factor days,
which was in the early fear factor days.
I was 100 percent convinced that show
was canceled at any second now.
So I'm like,
really isn't my one chance to get on the
Jay Leno show.
Let me ask them some questions.
So he's like,
you don't yell,
you don't like doing that.
And I think,
yeah,
I,
it's not bad.
I go,
hey man,
let me ask you this.
I go,
what?
What's up with that Bill Hicks thing?
Right.
And uh,
his take on it was,
you know,
well,
I wanted to do jokes for everybody,
you know,
I wanted to do comedy for everybody.
And Bill just didn't believe in doing
comedy for everybody.
I thought it was interesting.
He just,
I don't think he expected me to ask it
to them.
You're not hitting them on the podcast.
And he was fucking fantastic because
after he'd retired,
he told some stories about doing standup
for mom people and about this guy
fucking screaming at a priest,
you fucking mother,
fuck up.
And it was a hilarious thing to watch
Jay Leno telling hilarious stories and
swearing like a fucking long shoreman.
And I was like,
wow,
this is crazy.
You're a regular guy.
Like you've always been a regular
guy.
You were just doing the tonight show.
And I heard stories about Jay that he.
He loved to watch hacky comedy.
And the reason why this stuck in my head
was because I used to do that too with
todd glass.
We would,
we would,
if the was the worst,
the comedian,
the better.
We actually have three specials lined up
for a night.
He was like,
fuck,
this is going to be great.
And we found out after I found out that
Jay Leno used to do the same thing when
he would see a comic that he didn't
think,
you know,
he thought it was horrible.
He would hunt down a tape of it and then
everyone would have to come over to his
house.
And they've watched it.
Oh,
that's just a story I heard.
So maybe this is,
but it's true.
I'm sure.
And I'm like,
holy fuck,
that's what I do.
Well,
he just turned everything mild,
you know,
he turned everything mild for many,
many years and just didn't.
It just wasn't who he was or what made
me like him.
And it confused me and I felt personally
let down by him.
I felt like he left on comedy because
now he was supposed to show the old
people what the new people were doing in
comedy and then he just kind of didn't.
But now you see him and he's like a very
likable person.
He's fun.
Like,
could show is fun.
That's Joe.
Look,
it's because exactly he's talking about
shitty cares about that show was not
made for him the tonight show.
He.
But he was the number one show.
So what do we know?
Right?
It was still the number one show,
so maybe I'm wrong.
Oh,
it was a different thing,
you know,
because like letterman seemed
passionate,
like he seemed to be enjoying it.
And when he would say like witty things
and sharp things to people,
he would,
you could tell he was getting a little
bit of a thrill out of it.
There was some excitement to Letterman's
position that you didn't sense with Jay
Leno.
Jay Leno was just like,
well,
you know,
making everybody happy.
So the thing I liked about late night
shows when I was younger was that there
was a sense of danger that anything
could happen.
You didn't know what was going to
happen.
Right?
A Burt Reynolds is going to come out
drunk,
you know what I mean?
Like that.
Yeah.
And they used to smoke and you know,
there was.
And they would talk about things.
They were talk show.
They would actually talk about things
and I get to watch a Dick cabot.
And he would,
he,
I remember he had a,
uh,
a mort Sahl come out with Jane Fonda and
Peter Fonda right after the easy rider
came up and they're all talk and you're
like,
this is a fucking counterculture.
And it's right on.
And so it was really good.
That's when shows,
but now shows her now they're all fluff.
It's all fucking bubble of that stuff as
well.
There was an outlet for that though,
and it was filled by comedy in podcasts
just so now.
Podcasts are doing that and those late
night shows,
I have no idea what they're doing or why
they even exist.
We're even Stephen Colbert,
Stephen Colbert show on comedy central.
Just a brilliant,
brilliant show and now he quit to get
way more money to do a more popular
show.
That is way less relevant.
Interesting or creative,
but it is funny when you fucking mocks
trump.
It's funny how hard he goes.
The fact that he said why trump's but
did he uses his mouth is Kootenai
Putin's cock holster.
The fact that they said that on CBS,
I was like,
wow,
this is what happens when you have to
compete with the Internet.
Who the fuck could have imagined every
doing mccarthy smears,
but who the fucking thought a job,
but a joke like that.
A can I get the mccarthyism thing,
but the joke of a cock holster,
the president's mouth being used as
Putin's cock holster that,
that would be on CBS.
I get that.
You're applauding that.
He broke a boundary.
Well,
I'm a,
I'm not applauding it.
I'm just saying it's fascinating that
we've changed.
What's the bar?
What's,
what,
what you're allowed to do,
like you've changed.
Ever end because it's trump.
Like if they said that about Hillary,
Hillary Clinton,
he said,
well,
because look at all this Russia dossier
memos.
Shit that's coming out.
I mean it turns out that a lot of this
stuff is horseshit.
So a lot of people who weren't around
for the first mccarthy a shit,
they're getting to experience it now.
This is what it's like.
Yeah,
this is what it's like.
And you're like,
what?
Even the media is.
Yeah.
And the media goes along.
Yeah,
this is what it's like and you know,
um,
I don't,
I don't want to spend any amount of time
talking about it,
but it's so unbelievable because people,
they forgot you're talking to a wall
when you tell people just go,
well,
you mean there was collusion?
I got one.
Well,
it's collusion.
What does that mean?
Collusion,
that trump colluded with the Russians
hacked into the John Podesta's emails
and somehow they need to trump to help
them.
What the fuck?
Right.
That's the because that's what they're
saying.
Exactly.
And that there's some kind of quid pro
quo and that now trump has a Manchurian
candidate and that he's Putin's puppet.
And uh,
but you noticed they're moving the
goalposts every day.
So now it's,
oh no,
now he's,
he's in bed with Russian oligarchs doing
money laundering.
Well,
you don't know there's a sale of a home
and it was a Russian bought it Russian.
So they've totally moved the goalposts
from being treason to now he's just
regular corrupt,
like everybody else.
Because let me tell you something.
Everybody else has regular corrupt,
like trump,
but I don't even know if it's regular
corrupt because we're talking about a
sale of a house.
Well,
there's quite a few years ago.
Well that there's more than one thing,
but they're talking about lots of other
things,
right?
And I say you want to talk about
collusion?
He opened up eight businesses in Saudi
Arabia during the Goddamn campaign that
there's your fucking collusion,
but nobody talks about that because
Saudi Arabia is supposed to be on our
side,
even though the repressive theocracy
that beheads people in the streets.
But we liked them because of the
petrodollar,
which no one ever talks about the
petrodollar serving.
It's dope.
Well,
that's what props up our dollar right
now.
The economy.
So what people don't know is that in the
early seventies,
Richard Nixon took our country off the
gold standard and uh,
we went on the petro dollar.
And what was that?
When we promised Saudi Arabia the use of
our military anywhere they wanted,
as long as they would convert every
dollar of oil that someone bought for
them in American dollars.
So if you want to buy oil from Saudi
Arabia,
first have to convert your currency into
American dollars,
which is the real reason why we invaded
Iraq the first time.
Well,
it has a lot to do it.
The patent.
It's why we're
in Yemen right now.
We're doing siege warfare in Yemen,
which is a war crime.
That guy just got convicted of it,
uh,
at the Hague.
So we're doing that in conjunction with
Saudi Arabia.
And why are we doing that?
Because of the petrodollar.
That's what's it's all about.
Why are we in Africa?
So every,
everything comes down to money.
And why are we in Syria?
They wanted to put a natural gas
pipeline through Syria and Russia
doesn't want it because they want to
sell the,
the natural gas to Europe.
That's what this is about.
So if there's a,
and it's not about babies,
it's not about freedom.
It's not about liberty.
And you know,
we got it clearly.
Don't like country music,
country music,
real country music.
I like country,
like the outlaw.
Can Be Merle haggard.
Yeah.
I like that guy.
Like waylon jennings.
Yeah.
I like Willie Nelson.
Not these fucking pussies and want to be
boy scouts and my Mama and all that
shit.
What?
Who Sees?
I'm not supposed to say pussies.
Well,
it's going to be a time where we can't
say pussy shit,
Piss fuck cunt.
Cock sucker.
Motherfucker and tits.
So a lot of people are trying to use
Hashtag me too for a puritanical reasons
and that's not what it's about.
Hashtag me too is about fucking stopping
men who use their power and station in
life to hold it over women for sexual
sexual purposes.
That's what that's about.
It's not about being a puritan.
It's not about being anti porn.
It's nothing wrong with the lusting
after a woman's tits and a woman's ass.
There's nothing wrong with that.
And there's nothing wrong with a woman
wanting to be fucked by a man.
That was our normal things there.
So that's okay.
And don't let people hijack that
movement and try to use it for
puritanism because what a lot of people
are doing shit.
Piss fuck on cocksucker motherfucker.
Intense.
I'm triggered.
Triggered
to.
Yeah,
I mean absolutely.
I mean,
I think that what what we're dealing
with is an exposure of sexual assault,
exposure of sexual harassment,
sexual assault,
particularly in the workplace.
You know,
and this is a giant issue for people
that have to work alongside men and
women and they develop these little
communities inside these little boxes
that we call offices and things get
really fucking weird and if you have a
boss,
it's a piece of shit and he's constantly
harassing the women that work there and
it becomes a living hell with them.
Their stress they're going through.
Maybe it is a crime.
You're doing something to those people
that work there.
You're,
you're,
you're putting this pressure on them.
You're fucking up their life.
Could you imagine?
Could you eat?
The last thing I would ever want to do
was imposed myself sexually at a woman
who didn't want it.
Right?
While you're a healthy person,
like I mean some people,
it's just about.
We've all been into the end goal.
We've all been drunk,
right?
We've all been on a date or a woman
didn't want to have sex and we did and
we pushed the issue.
But,
uh,
you know,
I,
I just can't imagine.
Like,
I just never,
I just can't.
I don't get that.
She doesn't like you.
Oh,
I'm going to make her go feel
uncomfortable.
Like,
what the fuck do you get out of that?
That's just weird.
Well,
there's people that hate the opposite
sex.
I mean,
and I say the opposite sex.
I don't mean just men who hate women.
There's women who hate men.
There's people who have associated
the opposite sex with rejection and pain
and frustration all of their life.
You look at a guy like Harvey Weinstein,
that is an ugly fat guy,
right?
There's no women who are lusting after
him.
It was his power and his money that got
him into a position where he could get
some pussy and then having power over
all these actresses and then hearing
whether it's Uhm,
uh,
Thurman or whatever,
you know,
famous actress Salma Hayek,
all these superstars who were fighting
this guy off and hotel rooms.
I mean,
it's fucking crazy.
he is a maniac,
but he's a disgusting guy who has no
shot at getting someone to appreciate
him physically.
They might like his personality,
but for someone to be physically
attracted to him is almost impossible.
Right?
I mean,
he's eating himself into this disgusting
shape.
Unless you have a fetish or whatever.
Yeah.
You might just into getting fucked by
Jabba the hut.
Just big fat guy with pockmarked skin
shooting loads all over you.
There's no way it makes any sense,
but if he was going to put you in
ocean's 11,
you got to do what you gotta do.
Well,
you know,
Matt Damon said,
what?
What did Matt Damon's say?
They were trying to get them out of that
new oceans movie.
Well,
it didn't.
He say something about there was a
continuum or something that that
everything is Harvey Weinstein.
Wasn't that it?
I don't remember the exact quote,
but it was something along the lines of,
we have to make a differentiation
between sexual assault and men hitting
on women.
What's really interesting is seeing how
they're acting about this in France,
in Europe,
a lot of women,
especially older actions.
Did you see?
Did you see that's wild.
They want men to be men and and France.
I mean if they're just France part on a,
they're just different over there.
This,
there,
they have a different attitude.
The same as Brazil.
My friend Tiago from Brazil told me
once,
he's like,
man,
he goes,
if you're in Brazil,
and he goes,
if you're with a girl,
you don't try to fuck her.
She's like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
Like you're not even trying to fuck me.
Like,
what the fuck is wrong with these?
They'll get mad at you.
Like they appreciate like in Brazil is a
very aggressive.
I have sexually aggressive place.
I,
I have had a.
I'll never forget,
I was working at a comedy club and there
was a girl there who was beautiful and
um,
she flirted with me and uh,
well I,
I didn't know if she was flirting with
me because I was just,
she was just beautiful and she talked to
me.
So I'm like,
oh right,
and so,
but I wasn't going to make a move at her
because I'm,
I'm considering every comedian who comes
into this club makes a move on this
girl.
She's the prettiest girl around.
Right?
So I didn't do anything because I want
to be that guy.
Right.
And then I'll never forget by the end of
the week,
it was the last night and she's like,
Hey,
there was a party at my house tonight,
are you going to come?
And I was like,
oh sure.
Right.
So I went to their whatever cut to,
I'm leaving and she goes,
are you fucking kidding me?
And I go,
what?
She goes,
I threw a party just to get you to my
apartment and you're going to leave.
And I was like,
Oh really?
You want to?
And so we had
damn should've beat you over the head
with it.
Yeah.
So,
so there was a woman who was,
but you didn't want to be the guy that
was super aggressive against a girl that
was like,
Hey,
I just like you,
you just fun guy to hang out with.
Does everything have to be sex and I
know every guy in the world hit on her.
You,
you know what I honestly,
I mean,
I don't want to say this because w,
w,
it's almost like in this day and age,
you got to get to know someone forever
before you fuck them.
I mean literally forever.
You're got to fuck my wife.
The first night we went up.
Good.
Good for you.
And she wouldn't,
uh,
which has probably worked out because
we're still together and uh,
but I kept,
I did it in a charming way.
Right,
right.
I would say,
honey,
I.
Oh,
can we ask you this?
Why did you try to fuck her on the first
night?
But it took you five nights for the
waitress because I didn't want to be
that guy at the club because that makes
sense because it's a work environment.
Yeah.
So you're the opposite of a sexual
harasser?
I guess.
So I guess now that I look at it that
way.
Yeah.
Not that I did not have sensitive.
Not that you weren't attracted to her,
you just didn't want to be a dick.
Yeah,
I didn't want to have that reputation of
that guy and plus there's plenty of
women in the audience.
There's plenty of women.
Right?
So what I would tell her,
I remember the first night we were
together,
I was like,
Hey,
I know you.
I know you're going to say you want me
to go home,
but you're going to worry that I'm too
tired to drive and I might get in an
accident so you don't have to say that.
I'll just stay.
That's hilarious.
She's like,
no,
it's okay.
I go,
it's nice of you to say that you're
strong,
you're brave,
and I know you're gonna worry.
So I'm just staying.
Then I think I did end up staying,
but we didn't have sex.
Right.
And I'm like probably two more times,
two more times like that.
But also it's,
you don't really know someone's
personality for a long time.
I mean that's part of the problem.
The problem is people have physical
needs and they get attracted to each
other.
And then next,
you know,
look,
there's been many times in my life where
I wound up having sex with somebody who
turned out to be crazy and then you
know,
you're one,
two dates in and like,
yeah,
she seems cool and next thing you know,
you're hanging out in a week or two
later and she does something completely
fucking insane.
And then the crazy just starts leaking
out of her pores and you're like,
oh well now what have I done?
I've been tangled myself with some
person who knows where I live and
expects me to call them every day and
we're going to get together and I have
to figure out a way to back out of this.
And then he tried to back out of it and
they get fucking angry at you.
And this is back in the old days when
people would actually call you up,
call you to.
There was no text messaging.
You can just pick up the phone if
someone started yelling at you or I
would just duck them for awhile until
they found some new guy.
Remember when people used to answer
their phone,
they don't ever answer my.
No one ever answers their phone.
When I get too many phone calls from
people.
I don't know.
I just get phone calls from numbers.
I'm like,
where's this going to get my fucking
number from?
I have no idea.
I just look at it and my.
Did you ever have.
I answered a call because I didn't
because uh,
you know,
you're like,
oh,
maybe it's that business.
I just called her con.
You don't know.
Right,
right.
So I took one one time and it was just a
number.
It didn't come up and it was someone
asking me for money to borrow the money
was just a person,
you know,
I knew tangentially in comedy and,
and I,
and I didn't say this and I was like,
do you know that your name is not even
in my fucking phone book and you're
asking for any money from.
That's a desperate move.
That must be a person who's like a
gambling addict or something.
That's what I thought right away.
But getting back to this thing about the
women,
you know,
one time I had a woman when I first
moved to La,
I was dating or,
and uh,
I went to her house and she was really
creative and she's cute and she wrote
songs and she would sing them for me.
I love that shit.
And uh,
I remember she,
like,
we were going to go have sex and she
went and she was hanging on and she
went,
took a drink and I go,
what?
She goes,
do you want to drink?
I go,
no.
And she goes,
Oh,
hell on.
And she's like drinking.
And I go,
what are you doing?
Because I have to have a couple of
drinks before.
And then it made me not want to have sex
with her.
Isn't that fucked up?
I was like,
wow,
you have to have,
you have to drink so you can feel
comfortable.
I took it personal,
which of course it was just her,
it was,
she needed to relax because she had
fucked up.
She had it or not.
She had issues or whatever.
Right.
And so,
uh,
that was it.
I was like,
I can't be with the girl has to drink
that accessible,
isn't it
to the window.
Especially when you're young and single.
It's like you don't,
you don't want to get stuck in a bad
situation.
You know,
like I'd seen a lot of bad situations
when I was young,
my own parents and other people's
parents.
So I'd see anything fucking sketchy and
like where this is gone,
I don't want to deal with your problems,
you know,
I don't have those kinds of problems.
So.
See Ya.
Yeah,
I was the same way.
My,
I had a lot of bad examples of people.
I have no idea why these people would be
with the spouse there with like,
why would you do that?
Well maybe that's going to happen to me
because it's unconscious.
So I started reading self help books and
watching John Bradshaw videos that I
don't know if he knew that his John
Bradshaw,
he invented that term inner child and
all the inner child work and all that
stuff.
So I got fucked up
people's ads.
I'm getting your child pitch,
you're 40.
But he was,
he was helpful to me because he broke up
the family dynamic and he talked about
how people act in fact come from a big
family,
12 kids and that,
you know,
how it's like,
it all balances out.
You'll have a bad kid and as an angel,
you know,
and all the and everything in between
and he talked to him and so it helped me
understand myself a lot.
Uh,
and we're.
So I wanted to understand my motivations
so I didn't make bad choices in my life.
Like I had seen people around me making.
And because it's unconscious,
right?
So you just do what's habit,
you know,
you don't,
you don't even know why you're doing
what you're doing half the time.
You're not conscious of why you're
acting the way you're acting or why you
like what you like.
You just go.
I like that.
Why
when I was struggling as a comic,
one thing that I definitely did is I,
I only gave this.
I only gave a certain amount of room to
relationships because I knew that I've
really had to concentrate on my career.
Yes.
I'm like,
if I don't,
I will.
It will fall apart.
There was a kid that I started out with,
we both started out together and it was
pretty funny guy and he got this
girlfriend that was just very demanding
and he stopped doing stand up less and
less.
It was.
It was doing less and less sets and then
eventually he dropped out and then I ran
into his
son many years later and his son,
you know the,
the.
They wound up having a baby and his son
was saying that his dad just really
regretted not getting into comedy.
I'm sure he's happy.
He has a nice sun and all that stuff and
he had a family but it just,
it tanked him.
There's a saying,
I think it might've been Carl young who
said,
nothing affects a child more than the
unlived life of its parent.
So imagine.
I mean,
imagine being a father and you went
after your dream and you gave it
everything you can.
Now you can impart that to your kid and
your kid just absorbs it.
Being around you.
Now you didn't do that.
You have all that on resentment or
whatever you feel because you didn't
live what your life here supposed to and
then you can pass that off and your kid
absorbs that.
I knew it was so hard to do anyway.
It was going to be so hard to make it
in.
The odds are stacked against you.
You've seen everybody else drop off like
flies.
You see guys can't get gigs.
They wind up quitting.
They get a day job,
they work less and less,
and the next thing you know,
they're just completely stopped doing
standup.
It's so common and so when I would see
relationships and see those signs where
girls are just demanding more and more
of my time,
why do you have to go up tonight?
I'm like a four or five nights a week.
I have two kids.
Yeah.
I'm like,
you can come with me.
I've seen your act 100 times.
Well,
what I do,
this is what I do.
You know I can't.
I don't know what to tell you.
I meet guys who they their,
their spouses,
their significant others aren't into
their comedy and I'm like,
it's awful.
It's awful.
That's the thing that sap.
What do you,
what,
what do you like about me?
My wife is,
I would say she's a,
she's a fan of comedy,
but she's been around me for a long time
and she is,
she's hard,
like if she wants to stand up and it's
not good to like,
this sucks.
Well that there's nothing wrong with
that.
No,
it's good.
It's a good thing.
You know,
she's,
she's got an eye for it,
she understands it.
But I have friends whose wives hate
comedy and they do stand up and it's
quick,
it's easy.
And they associate comedy with like
taking their boyfriend away or taking
their husband away.
Like this is that thing that takes away
my time,
you know,
from me with him.
Now he's off doing these joke things.
Fucking bullshit.
So it's super selfish.
You need this,
you need a better woman.
Someone who's deeper yet.
Well,
you just fucking settle.
They just settle.
They settle my what my.
Anyway,
I,
there's so many.
I have to,
I forget where out of show sometimes and
he'll probably hear this.
And so,
um,
when I started comedy,
uh,
I was dating this girl,
sweet,
sweet girl and she wanted to get married
like you would expect,
right?
So I was 24 at the time.
I was six years to get out of college
and um,
so she bought me a suit so I could go on
interviews to get a job.
She wanted me to get a job and I had
started doing comedy
that the right then.
And so about six months into doing
comedy,
I started getting Saturday night spots
at a real club.
They would let me go do 10 minutes,
not paid,
but I could do it on the regular show
guests set.
That's huge.
I thought,
oh my God,
are you kidding me?
It's a godsend.
So we go out loud part.
Yes.
So on a Saturday night I take her with
me,
we're going to the,
it was called the comedy cottage and I
do my set and there was lots of other
like,
um,
new new comics like me and they were
like,
oh Jimmy,
you know,
that was great.
That was a big deal.
It's a big deal for us.
One of our own got on and,
and in the car ride home,
she's not saying anything and finally
she just turns to me and she goes,
you're really gonna do this,
aren't you?
I go,
fuck,
yes.
Did you just see what happened?
Of course I'm doing this.
What does that mean?
That she was like,
she knew that I was going to be a
comedian and not married to her and
that's what that meant.
Wow.
You couldn't be both.
Not then I couldn't get married.
Even if I couldn't get married.
Jim Brewer is married.
The same girl he's with.
When I met him,
I met Jim in 1991 and two happy kids the
whole deal.
Super happy.
She's super nice.
I didn't.
So the problem with standup comedy is
you don't know where you're gonna end up
of course.
So when you start,
you don't know,
can I even do five minutes?
And then we're like,
what can I do 15?
Can I get paid?
Can I do an MC?
Can I be consistent?
Can I middle can I hadn't read.
I don't know.
Can I work in a room?
Can I get on TV?
You don't know.
You don't like.
If you go to any other job,
you go,
well,
if you do this,
this and this,
then you'll get the promotion and then
get that.
You have to meet your number and then
you get,
oh,
okay.
I can meet my numbers.
This.
There's no handbook.
No.
Even
to this day,
like my.
My agent called me to schedule something
in New York for November and I said I
can't,
and I said,
I'm doing my special in April.
I don't know if I'm going to have an
hour by November.
I assume I will,
but I don't know.
I go,
I can't.
I'm not going to fuck people over at
some big fucking theater and not have an
hour yet.
I'm gonna.
Do my best,
but may June,
July,
August,
September,
October,
November,
seven months.
Most likely I'll have a new our most
likely,
but what if I only have a half hour?
What if I only have an half an hour
fucking bomb?
What if I do half an hour of good comedy
but not the best?
And then have nothing,
I can't take that risk.
Like when I'm ready I'll call yet.
So when April rolls around,
after I'm done and I chuck everything
aside,
I'm on a fucking rampage for like three,
four months of just doing 10,
15 minutes spots,
writing a bunch of new shit and trying
to piece together an hour.
Then it's going to take me a month or
two to try to sort that our out to
figure out where everything goes and
what the punchlines are.
Listening to recordings,
writing things down,
burning the midnight oil late at night.
This is,
I don't know if I could do it.
I mean I'm assuming you do it,
but once I chucked my act,
decide once the act that you saw that
you thought was funny,
that fucking
things going to the toilet.
It's over.
So over baby.
I'm lucky in the sense that no one saw
my last special.
So I think to do those jokes I get to
keep doing those job.
What about your fans know?
So I did.
This is funny,
right?
So I did a to comedy central specials.
Then I did,
my last one was for Hulu and it was in I
think 20,
15 maybe or 1415 and uh,
so,
uh,
so because of my youtube show I'd sell
tickets now so people come out and so I
got a,
I was doing a show maybe six months ago
and I do the opening joke from my
special and it kills and I go,
you motherfuckers,
none of you saw my special.
And then I was upset for a second and
then I was like,
oh,
I get to do those jokes again.
I'm going to do my own special and put
it out on my own thing because I don't
know where that even like that Hulu
special.
It's only,
it lives on Hulu somewhere.
Is Hulu is still a thing?
It's still a thing.
Well,
Hulu was still a thing.
I'm thinking of CSO.
CSO is not a thing anymore.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Lisa went under.
Yeah.
That sort of Stan hope at a special.
Diaz had express.
Really?
Yeah.
A bunch of guys who were really funny.
People had specials on seesaw and now
see,
so is it doesn't exist.
Oh yeah,
I've heard about that.
Going under.
Yeah,
they've tried it.
A bunch of.
Cecil was a Sony thing,
right?
Wasn't it?
Or was it NBC?
NBC,
NBC.
I think you're right.
Yeah.
Now like Sony had crackle.
Right.
That's just such a funny.
I was thinking that Qualif Tompkins bit
about crackle,
crackle.
I can't remember how it went,
but only if they're called crack crack.
We cute and so funny.
I couldn't remember how it.
It's so funny.
Uh,
yeah.
Well it's now.
Then I got to tell Ya.
I was happier before.
What do you mean?
I was happier when my whole life was
ahead of me and like when I first
started hanging out a largo and doing
sets at the Improv and being in and
meeting all my heroes in comedy,
like to me that was a headier time.
Now it's like I feel pressure to stay
on,
stay where I'm at or be successful.
I don't know what it is I feel,
but I feel like I'm working too hard and
I'm not able to enjoy what I've
accomplished and that's why I've been,
um,
I've been trying to,
like I told you,
he showed me that,
that tank.
I've been trying to figure out how to
stop my thoughts.
You can come into a tank anytime you
want.
Don't sit.
No,
don't come into the tank.
But you could because people do do that.
There's a tank center,
a place,
a find out the name of that place.
Give them a shout out.
So the float lab in Venice is my spot.
That's the spot that built my tank.
They have a place in Westwood and they
are the best in the world and they
actually supply the tanks to the place
in Pasadena.
The guy who will put this,
my friend crash,
who put it in our studio just float,
just float is the place in Pasadena and
I'm pretty sure it's the largest float
center in the world.
So does that help you stop thinking?
No,
the opposite I think in there,
but I relax.
It's very relaxing physically because
the water's warm and you float and you
can do it after the show if you want.
I got
another show that goes until two if you
want.
You totally can.
Thank you for the album.
Going to be the second person outside of
me to be in there.
Dan Harris from ABC.
Good morning.
America is the only other guy that's
been in there.
Dan is a big meditation proponent,
so I tried meditating and it just hurts
my back and oh well that will be really
good for your back because it's become
weightless.
You just float in there and the water's
the same temperature as the surface of
your skin so you don't feel the water
after awhile and you're,
you know,
you're in total darkness and total
silence and you just chill out in there,
man.
It feels.
It feels good.
Okay,
I got to do it.
I gotta do something.
You know where I've heard this thing by
Alan Watts and he talked about how we
know,
we know how to prepare for life.
We don't know how to enjoy life.
Once it gets here,
you gotta get good at that,
man.
That's,
that's,
uh,
something that you really need to
concentrate on the.
I don't know.
I know you're doing really well right
now and I'm a fan of yours,
so when you say you're not happy,
that bums me out.
I'm stressed.
Yeah.
Well you gotta figure out a way to enjoy
this.
I know.
That's what I'm trying to be more silly.
Just smoke weed.
We'll smoke a little bit more.
Just just enjoy it a little bit more,
you know,
just smoking weed in the morning and now
I can't because I have to fucking do
stuff.
Oh,
you definitely can.
Yeah,
you'd have to trust me.
It can be done,
but then I can't do anything.
You can know you can.
Um.
Do you exercise a?
No,
I can't exercise.
That's the problem.
I used to be athletic.
I used to love them at all.
Because your gallbladder?
No because of my bones.
I every once in a while I'll forget I'll
do yoga or anything.
Um,
no.
My doctor told me don't,
don't do anything.
Your Dr told me to swim.
Oh,
that's nice.
Yeah,
swimming is great.
So he said I could swim.
Oh,
okay.
So the most boring thing.
Swimming man.
I like getting high and swimming.
Oh yeah,
it's fun.
It feels good.
But you,
um,
you can see every exercise like lifting
weights or anything along those lines
because your bone issue.
But I would think that lifting weights
would enhance your bone density.
Um,
it just hurts.
So I can't,
I can't even pick up a suitcase.
Really,
really fuck man.
Have to be,
I forget often and I will then fuck.
And then my back hurts for the whole day
back.
So yeah,
cause,
uh,
anyway,
um,
but it's about being coming present.
And I love listen to this guy.
Eckhart tolle.
Power of now.
Oh book.
Oh did you?
Yeah.
So that is a really getting me a.
she's still alive.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So that's really getting me,
you know,
um,
when things frustrate you.
I love what he says.
He goes,
the world isn't here to make you happy.
It's here to frustrate you.
So you wake up,
Huh?
Oh,
when I'm like,
oh,
so now you can use your frustrations as
reminders to wake up and so whenever
something,
and it's hard because,
you know,
I,
I have a temper and I,
uh,
and that's the weird thing.
Now I,
I hid my temper,
my anger through my standup and I was
successful.
I had specials and everything,
but now I don't hide it and now I'm
really sick.
Now I'm selling tickets.
Right.
Because that's the ultimate goal is if
you could sell tickets,
then you don't need anybody and yeah.
Why?
It seems like there's some sort of
internal conflict between you getting
angry and ranting and talking about
things that are very important to you
and then going on stage and doing
standup.
I don't think that they should be
mutually
inclusive.
No,
I'm trying to bring them together and
then my wife would always tell me,
you got to rent on your set,
upset you gotta read,
you gotta get angry.
And I was like,
okay,
well I would never really do it.
Well you just got to balance it out.
Just going to find out a way to make
that ramp.
Funny,
and then,
you know,
find perspectives that are relatable
where you go into this rant,
but then bring it to these people in a
digestible way,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
Um,
what's happening is I'm showing videos
now at my live show and those get me
into that groove and I just dropped a
video kind of videos.
Like I just dropped a video about it.
I did a live show at the flappers in
Burbank and I did,
uh,
I showed a video of Keith Olbermann
apologizing to John Mccain and George
Bush on the view and that.
Yeah,
what does,
what does that.
So He,
I dunno,
he's trying to.
He was talking to Megan Mccain and this
recently,
this was a couple months ago,
he going crazy because he retired from
that show that he was doing it in a
basement.
So trump excites the lizard brain of a
certain kind of neo liberal.
And Olbermann is certainly one of those
guys.
He pretends all the problems in our
country started on January 2017 and
that's certainly not it.
Like he was great.
He could deconstruct what was wrong with
Hillary Clinton back in 2008 when she
was running against Barack Obama and he
could deconstruct it was wrong with the
Iraq war and what was wrong with Bush
and Cheney,
but I don't know.
Somehow all of a sudden now he pretend
it's like again,
he trump excites,
says lizard brain and all his critical
thinking skills go out the window and he
pretends that all our protest,
trump is the problem and not a symptom
of the problem.
Well,
it was a scene
in a movie when he was doing that.
It looked like he was doing a show in
the basement somewhere with this weird
background who was called the
resistance,
the resistance,
but he was also.
He didn't.
Wasn't making connections like was that
law that really a pretty conservative
girl.
Tammy Lauren,
is that her name?
She did a thing where she was covered in
the American flag and he was talking
about how hypocritical it is to be
standing there holding draping yourself
in the American flag.
And then Donald Trump jr posts a picture
of Tammy Lauren right next to him.
Doing the same thing and Donald Trump jr
says,
it must be painful to be so stupid.
Like in like,
well,
I don't even understand how he could
have not known.
He took that picture to be draped in it.
Yes.
Like how could he not know that he took
that picture?
So he admitted on so smart.
Well,
that's the thing.
Listen to him.
He's incredibly articulate.
He's A.
I love the skill
in which he writes is a great form.
Was my key dormant.
That's the whole thing.
Yeah.
I was a huge fan.
It was great with sports.
I mean he's sort of old school lead type
delivery that I enjoy.
He's a great broadcaster and you always
hear stories about his idiosyncrasies,
like he's a prick to work with and stuff
and you go,
well fuck.
I gave.
What are you going to do?
So who cares?
I don't.
I don't work with them.
I want to watch them.
Right.
Well that's the truth with a lot of
people that are apparently.
One of the things about being great at
something is a lot of it.
You're fucking fanatical about it.
You get crazy,
completely obsessed and something is
embedded.
Your people skills are out the window
because you're so completely
concentrated on something else.
Yes.
Yeah.
So I could,
uh,
so he,
he apologized.
He said that Donald trump was worse than
nine slash 11 and Megan Mccain said,
do you really believe that?
And,
and his big comeback to that was your
father was my favorite political figure
of the 21st century.
And I'm like,
really?
Who was the second Bernie Madoff?
Are you fucking kidding me?
John Mccain's a warmonger who thrust
him?
Sarah Pailin on us and playing poker
while they were trying to decide the
fate of live.
Remember that whole thing?
We'll talk.
Do you remember that thing or John
Mccain?
There were in the middle of what was the
exact scenario that they were in the
middle of some meeting in the Senate and
they were deciding something incredibly
important and they busted mccain playing
poker.
No area.
Yeah,
it was about bombing Syria.
Look at this because he's four he
doesn't do is it doesn't need to hear
that look.
They're playing poker war games.
Mccain caught playing poker on iphone
during Syria debate.
Just fucking imagine the type of person
that could do that.
You're in the middle of talking about
dropping bombs that are going to kill
people.
Yeah.
They're absolutely going to kill people
and they're gonna be come flying out of
fucking high speed jet and he's either
playing poker.
This is boring.
Are new to find out if I can get another
ace.
The whole baby up my stream suck on it.
I mean,
so this is what I saw.
And he called brand Paul a Putin puppet
because he was against Ukraine joining
NATO.
I mean that's what jumped decker Kinda
Shit.
John Mccain,
you know,
there might be I,
I said this at a live show.
I go,
I don't disrespect to service.
Nobody disrespects the surface except
the president said it stayed,
which was the craziest thing ever.
I like people don't get caught.
I was like,
how the fuck can you say that?
So much of the shit that he has said
just bounces off of,
um,
like,
I was at,
I was at the comedy store the other
night and somebody was trying to say
that,
that stormy weathers chick,
is that her name?
Stormy weather.
Stormy Daniels.
Sorry,
sorry.
Stormy weather.
It's a fuck.
Was saying it.
What the fuck was saying it?
Um,
Africa who said it,
but they were saying,
oh,
she's our Monica Lewinsky.
And I was like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
That stormy Daniels is going to tank
top.
I'm like,
you're out of your fucking mind.
I go,
it's going to go right off his skin like
a water on a duck.
It's not even going to affect at all.
He's going to say fake never happened.
He's going to keep moving.
And that's gonna be the end of it.
And he's like,
no fucking way.
He's gonna get in trouble for that.
And I'm like,
no,
he's not.
It's not going to be anything.
You don't understand all the things that
he's done so far,
grab them by the Pussy.
All these different things.
It's like Charlie Sheen.
I read an article once that said,
when is the me too movement can hit
Charlie Sheen.
I'll answer that.
Fucking never.
You know why?
Because you can't shame someone who
doesn't have any shame.
Right?
It doesn't work.
That's it.
If someone's not embarrassed,
you cannot embarrass them.
Right.
You know,
I mean,
if someone says to you,
hey,
Jimmy Dore,
what are you a fucking comedian?
You're like,
yeah,
I'm a comedian.
People call me dumb.
Yeah.
I call myself dumb.
That doesn't,
that's not going to get.
Doesn't bother me.
Yeah.
You need something more than that.
Charlie.
You're a fucking whoremonger.
Uh,
yeah.
That's what I do.
It's well documented.
I smoke crack and I bang horse.
Any other questions?
I got to go back.
Horse smoke,
crack.
I don't have time for this.
I have HIV and that's what I go.
And that's all.
It's not gonna work.
You Know Charlie Sheen is out there
doing terrible things to women.
Yeah,
he pays him.
That's what he does with all that.
Fucking two and a half men money.
That's how I always felt about being a
comedian.
Like I,
I don't play by,
you don't get to judge me,
I fucking judge you.
Like,
oh,
you're very aggressive to the point,
and then shit,
I never,
I never advocated for a war like The
Washington Post New York Times,
MSNBC and CNN and you can't.
You're going to judge me over some
fucking thing I said,
or did I never advocated for a war.
I never fired a guy who was speaking out
against the war like Msnbc did in the
New York Times.
WHO DID MSNBC fire?
Phil Donahue.
Phil Donahue had the number one show on
the network at the time and they fired
him because he was against the Iraq war.
That's your.
When they fired him the first time,
Rachel maddow or Chris Hayes says
anything that costs MSNBC a nickel,
they will be fucking fired.
Just like.
And that's why they don't.
They don't.
And they're paid $30,000 a work day.
30,000.
Yeah.
That's what she gets a workday day.
And I used to think she dislikes
Oberman.
They were fantastic.
And then trump excites their lizard
brain and she's lost her mind.
She's pushing a fucking red scare and
mccarthyism and she should be,
she should be shunned.
Do you think that she's doing that
rationally?
Do you think that she is confused,
please being coerced and pushed into
that sort of that certain direction?
Um,
I think she's being coerced and push,
but I think she goes along willingly and
getting that 30,
30 k a day.
She's not going to talk out against,
make a t shirt.
She's like 30 k a day.
I will.
You can have your way.
I mentioned it all the time.
I show.
Can I steal that phrase phrase?
Okay.
I think I may.
I may make a day and you could have your
way.
The real problem is neo liberalism,
Joe,
the real problem is the system and
they'll never talk about that.
They want also tribalism,
right?
Anything that opposes the other side
must be good.
Right?
In anything you can use on them must be
good.
Well,
that's what's happening right now with
trump and it's disgusting.
It's like there's a way to oppose trump
and it's not the way you're doing it.
The fucking will
affect the way they're doing.
It enhances trump.
It makes them more powerful.
You keep coming at him that he'd go with
his guy,
with the battered wife,
and he gives up.
Meanwhile,
they're spending 160 billion more
dollars on bombs that nobody wants.
Meanwhile,
half the country is poor or low income.
Sixty three percent of Americans can't
afford a thousand dollar emergency in
the richest country that face of the
earth has ever seen.
All the benefits of this recovery has
gone to the upper one percent.
People haven't had a raise.
You know,
I just saw the afl cio was telling you,
people give me shit because I wouldn't
vote for Hillary Clinton.
Right?
And I just saw the,
um,
the AFL cio tweeted out last week that
the union unions have helped give
Democrats complete control of
government,
uh,
four times in the last three decades.
And they have done nothing to help
unions.
And they're saying vote third party
they've got.
They got together with the Teachers
Union and the postal union and they're
like,
hey,
let's reveal voting isn't working.
We have to somehow come up with a third
party,
so they're.
They're talking about it now,
so people who are wagging their finger
at me,
I go,
hey,
even the unions agree with me now that
we've got to have a third party,
and if Bernie Sanders would have went
with a third party instead of propping
up that corporatist warmonger like he
did,
he could have really changed politics in
America.
If Jill Stein and the Green party would
have got 10 or 15 percent of the vote or
even five percent of the vote,
it would have completely changed our
politics in America because now the
Democrats,
they wag their finger at their base and
then they move to the right.
Like Hillary Clinton wagged her finger
at the base and then picked Tim Kaine
who was to the right of her.
Right.
And so if,
if Bernie Sanders would have went with
the Greens and they would have made it
showing,
now they can't do that.
They can't dismiss them anymore.
Now they have to come together in a
coalition,
but she was doing it in a calculated
manner to try to get some Republicans
that thought that Donald Trump was
republican.
Hillary Clinton,
their whole strategy was work.
Fuck overworking people that we're going
to try to get white collar Republicans.
That's not what your party is.
There's already a party for those
people.
There's a part is called the Republican
Party.
You're supposed to be the party of
fucking workers and that.
That's why we don't have an opposition
party in this country.
Joe,
and we have to two parties at a pro
management.
You know that Nissan.
Nissan has 49 plants around the world.
Three of them are not union.
You know where those three plants are?
United fucking states.
So we've got a broken system,
right?
Are are the problem is the Democrats are
bought by the same people.
They're just a little,
you know,
and people go,
why did the Democrats keep caving?
Why didn't they stand up against trump
for Daca?
They're not caving.
They're standing up to you the voter,
and they're standing up to their donors.
Their donors don't want the government
shut down for one minute and that's
where they're standing up for.
They could have stood up for the voters
and and stood up for Daca,
but they didn't.
They stood up for their donors,
so it's not like they're spineless.
They appeared spineless because it looks
like they're not doing what they're
supposed to or what they say they're
not,
and they're not doing what they said
they would do,
which is stand up for the people,
but they're secretly standing up for
their donors.
They have a steel spine when it comes to
their donors,
which is why they gave the trump
$160,000,000,000.
Can I make one last point about Donald
Trump?
So this shows you how they're full of
shit.
When you say Donald Trump is an
existential threat to our country and a
maniac and he has his finger on the
button and then you vote to give them
$160,000,000,000 more in bombs.
I think you're full of shit.
When you say he's existential maniac.
When you say that this guy is unhinged
and you can't be trusted,
and then you vote to expand his
warrantless wiretapping and spying
powers on his own enemies in the
country,
that's what I know in your fullest shit,
because if they really wanted to check
trump,
they would check him on the military,
the Pentagon budget,
and his spying powers and they've
expanded all that stuff,
so if he's really a maniac,
those motherfuckers are the most
irresponsible people in the world.
Giving him all this extra power for the
Pentagon and spike,
but they know the only reason they hate
trump because ain't part of their
fucking club.
Jimmy door just laid it down.
Now you're going to get hate mail from
people that are Hillary Clinton
supporters.
Yeah,
come.
I hope you're ready.
Yeah,
but getting it my since 2016 thing that
always killed me about Hillary Clinton
more than when or when I would talk to
Super Democrats,
like people that were just completely
tribal there on the democratic side,
no matter what I go,
you know,
she didn't support gay marriage until
2001.
Yeah.
She,
you know,
there was a sexual harasser and her
campaign in 2008 and she didn't fire the
fucking guy.
In fact,
she covered for him and anyone onto
sexually harassed again in another
organization tied to Hillary Clinton.
Correct.
The record.
Yeah.
Well the problem is,
I think when you're close to her,
you find out all the dirty details
what's going on behind the scenes and
it's just a creepy,
creepy organization.
She was the.
She was such a flawed person for
feminists to wrap their flag around.
She.
She's not the person.
There was another woman running in that
race.
It was Jill Stein.
I voted for her.
Nobody cared about her though.
That was a weird one.
It's because trump,
it was exactly what Hillary Clinton
wanted.
The Pied Piper Strategy.
You can't even entertain not voting for
Hillary Clinton because of this
existential threat of trump and he's
such an existential threat.
We're going to vote to expand its buying
powers and given by bullet of military
budget.
Well,
we saw this Hashtag.
I'm with her stuff to where they wanted
to have one female president.
That would be a historical victory.
That's why so many people were crying on
television because they were watching an
avengers movie.
They weren't really involved in the
actual political process itself.
They didn't understand what was
happening and they didn't understand who
she really was.
That's it from the beginning to the end,
and if you go and there's just so much
evidence.
You remember that off camera interview,
which she was talking about Kadafi.
We came,
we saw he died.
She's laughing like psychopath.
What kind of a person is that?
That's a crazy person now in Libya.
It's a failed state.
Exactly.
It's a haven for terrorists.
Slavery's back.
See that shit?
Yes.
On Youtube you can watch slave trade in
Libya.
That's,
that's her success story.
Yeah,
it's,
it's her horrific.
But don't you let me ask you a question.
Uh,
Joe,
uh,
I dunno if you like my.
One of my big things is,
is the reason why I have a show is
because mainstream news media sucks so
bad.
And the reason you have this show
is because late night talk shows suck so
bad,
right?
And,
and it's,
it's established stuck.
They have commercials and they have
these things that they do and they have
never had this conversation.
Now you would.
They would.
Someone would come and Jimmy.
Joe,
listen,
you can't listen.
This is not the time for this.
Just want to talk about this in your own
time.
At the time,
Hillary is this,
a lot of Hillary supporters on staff and
they're very upset right now and they
feel that you guys were massage and see.
Did you see Jimmy Fallon?
No,
I don't know Jimmy Fallon and I've only
bumped into him and he's always been a
gentleman.
Nice Guy,
a gentleman and a nice guy and nothing
bad to say about Jimmy Fallon,
but they did a,
um,
a segment where they had Hillary Clinton
on and her writer's could in his writers
came out and they all wrote thank you
notes and they read them to Hillary
Clinton.
And at first I'm like,
this is going to be hilarious.
And then it wasn't,
it was actually sincerely.
They were thanking her for what?
For being then running for fucking
brick.
The fact he got shot him and left his
wallet and his has watched there.
That was amazing.
That was a botched robbery,
Joe and yeah,
sure.
Four o'clock in the morning.
Did you see that?
Took anything from um,
see Donna Brazil happened to leak.
So yeah,
she called him a fucking hero.
Donna Brazil said that that was scared
her to death.
She started pulling the blinds in her
office.
She should.
So now the Washington Post this what I
wanted to ask you,
they wrote a whole thing about how
anybody who questions seth rich is
crazy.
Of course
they do that they make you look like
you're a fool because it's a conspiracy
theory.
And can you say conspiracy theory,
conspiracy theorist,
and you're wack job.
But what is one big conspiracy theory?
Right?
But just put it down on paper.
Let's just look at what.
Look at real hard facts.
Seth rich was a Bernie Sanders
supporter.
Seth rich was a Patriot seth,
which according to Julian assange and
wikileaks,
which have not been proven to be liars,
never had to retract anything they
printed.
They've never had to do that.
He's saying that he leaked stuff to him.
There are consequences leaking stuff to
wikileaks.
Seth rich was murdered at 4:00 in the
morning,
shot in the back.
They said it was a botched robbery,
but no one took anything from him and
there's never been anyone that's charged
with it.
And there's no suspects.
I don't know.
I don't know what happened to him,
but that looks very
well.
You're not even allowed to ask questions
because I covered that story one day.
I covered it one day because that guy
wheeler came out and he was saying he
had all this.
He saw the computer and all this stuff.
So I covered that in your piece of shit.
And you're a conspiracy theorist.
In that video I did.
I literally said,
uh,
I don't know if this is true.
We're waiting for evidence,
unlike the mainstream news media with
their Russia bullshit.
We're gonna wait for evidence.
I literally said that inside that.
And then the next day I did another
video which debunk that Guy Wheeler who
was pushing that,
that story because he turned out he was
full of Shit.
So what was the response though?
People still to this day,
it's fucking smear.
Meet with that thing.
Oh,
you pushed it.
I go,
I covered.
I would do a new show.
I covered a new show.
By the way,
why aren't you allowed to ask questions
about an open murder investigation?
Not only that,
this is a re look.
This is a guy who was a real Bernie
Sanders supporter,
open Bernie Sanders supporter who worked
for the DNC.
The DNC absolutely rigged the primary
against Bernie Sanders.
He was aware of this.
He was there while this was all going
down.
So is Donald Brazil.
Everyone was aware of that.
The guy got fucking murdered after he
leaked information to wikileaks.
If you don't think that's a little
weird,
what are you looking at?
What?
What delusional rose colored glasses.
Are you looking at your party from a.
You think you're in some Julia Roberts
movie from Nineteen Ninety.
This is real shit.
Some guy got killed.
He was 24 years old.
He was a young guy who is very
optimistic and have this view of the
world where he meets the guy fucking
war,
American flag pants and shirt.
There's a famous picture of him with a
beer on me is the Patriot that a lot of
ways he wanted to be involved in the
political process.
He was very idealistic because is.
He was probably shattered by finding out
the party that he was working for was
corrupting the democratic process.
And because I've said this before,
you know,
I've been accused of helping Donald
Trump win by really wacky people online,
but pointing out all the flaws of
Hillary Clinton,
like,
look,
man,
you can't ignore that shit because you
want one side to.
When I've talked about all of his flaws
to it,
there's a lot of flawed human beings are
run for president pretty much all of
them.
I mean,
it's very rare you have someone who's
not flawed,
right?
Extremely flawed.
We're all flawed but extremely flawed.
Who wants to be the fucking King of the
world?
It's very rare.
Well,
uh,
you know,
not to change subjects,
but Barack Obama,
everyone thinks is the greatest guy in
the world.
Do you know,
in contrast to Donald Trump because he
was polite,
was a statesman,
he was a good speaker,
live site,
but at the end,
but he was polite at the same time.
He let cops correct the heads of
peaceful protesters at occupy Wall
Street all across the country.
He said he put on a soft shoe to stand
up for unions.
He fucked over unions in Wisconsin when
they took the teacher's union away,
uh,
he opened the Arctic to drilling twice
whenever Shell oil won.
And he said,
okay,
and he only closing one.
They didn't want to do it anymore.
He took us from two wars to seven.
He cooked out five point 1 million
families out of their homes instead of
helping them.
And he made Wall Street whole
motherfucking over everyone else.
So this guy,
he ended,
he made the Bush tax cuts permanent.
So there was,
um,
uh,
what they say is,
it looked like it was changing on the
outside.
Continuity on the inside.
Well,
the hope and change website had to be
altered because there was all these
things in there about whistleblowers
about.
And then he prosecuted that.
Exactly.
But he takes,
he took it out of the website,
right?
He had all these segment sections on the
website about offering protection for
whistle blowers and the.
And also they were like the worst when
it came to the press.
Yes,
yes.
When it came to the press and people and
freedom of the press and people getting
in trouble for leaking information.
They were the worst.
The worst,
much worse
than Bush.
They used the espionage act to prosecute
journalists.
Yes.
And
then they,
that's a fact.
And everyone turned their head.
You know,
Greg Glenn Greenwald used to be a hero
on the left until he started telling the
truth about Barack Obama.
And now he's a pariah.
So,
uh,
up to the people,
you know,
Thomas Frank,
I don't know if you know you,
you would love that guy if you ever met
him.
He wrote that book called what's the
matter with Kansas,
which is examining what's wrong with
conservatives.
And then he wrote a book called Listen
Liberal,
which came out I think two years ago,
and he is persona non grata.
MSNBC,
CNN,
nobody will talk to him because he
critiqued the left and he talked about
the,
yeah,
you can't no room for discourse.
You can't even get a job in the United
States.
He has to write for the Guardian in
England.
That's a true story.
So I've had him on my show.
People love him and he comes out and he
tells the truth about the last Frank
Thomas Frank,
and he's got a great sense of humor too.
And he's real personable and he's a
hero.
He's an academic,
but he doesn't talk like one.
And um,
his book,
listen liberal is what radicalized me to
not be able to vote for Hillary Clinton.
It opened my eyes to all the bull.
You know,
people still fucking blame Ralph Nader.
Just unbelievable.
Like you're allowed to participate in
democracy.
And Hillary Clinton was the only
candidate in the history of politics who
wasn't expected to garner votes by
campaigning.
You just were supposed to over your
fucking votes.
If she doesn't have the votes,
you're supposed to go get the fucking
votes.
That's how it works is the first time
ever I've seen.
She was of poor health and shame.
She was having a really hard time.
Donna Brazil would almost want it to
replace her.
She said in the book that Brazil set,
her health was so bad they want it to
replace her.
That was another thing that I got in
trouble for not for,
for people were saying like,
why do you keep talking about her
health?
Because it's a huge issue and also I
happen to know a lot about brain trauma.
She had brain trauma and she passes out.
They said she was a.
She was hot.
She didn't take her coat up.
Listen,
I've been hot many times.
I go in the sun all the time.
I never faint.
Okay.
And I don't want to run for president.
You can't just fall asleep while you're
standing up and be president.
That's not,
that's not in the books.
Like I have a joke about it in my act.
Like I was like,
if that was my mom,
but be like,
mom,
you can't be president.
You can't stand up fast.
She can.
It's true.
If Hillary Clinton stood a Fascia,
her eyes would roll back behind her head
and she'd fucking cracker head off the
linoleum.
That's just a fact.
But if you say that you're a misogynist,
you're a.
you're all right.
I've been called alt right for that.
Like you're helping.
You're helping Donald Trump.
We're helping trump like this.
Seth rich thing is a real symptom and
the ignoring of that case is a real
symptom of what is wrong with this.
You can even tribalism.
You can't discuss it.
List.
That's crazy that you're even talking
about it.
I can't believe that you talk about it
so openly.
What do people.
People don't try to discredit you
because of this.
It doesn't matter.
You can't.
What do I do?
MMA cage fighting.
Commentator.
Go ahead.
I'm a pot addict.
I smoked pot.
I got problems.
Listen man,
I'm not a fucking reputable person.
By political ideologies.
I mean I'm just
not.
I'm,
I'm not well read.
When it comes to politics,
I have my opinions on things,
but when it comes to things that are
rock solid and clear like that seth rich
was murdered and people want to ignore
it,
I'm like,
what the fuck do you think happened?
This has to be some sort of a disconnect
here.
When a person is giving information to
Wiki leaks that exposes corruption
inside the very organization that's
responsible for the fucking Democratic
Party and he gets murdered and you're
like,
oh,
the conspiracy theories.
No,
he got murdered.
There's no conspiracy.
It was a botched robbery.
Says who says who wears this?
How come his wallet was there?
How come his watch was there?
How come they didn't take his phone?
What the fuck are you talking about that
I'm a conspiracy theorist when I just
tell you the facts.
So this,
this wiki leaks thing with Julian
assange is the craziest shit ever.
When he said there's consequences to
sharing information with us and
everybody's like,
he works for Russia.
Now he writes for Russia.
So is the darling of the left when Obama
was in office,
do you remember that?
Amazing.
So Julian decides he's just a great news
guy with whose tough as nails at dances
creepy and might've fucked some girl
while she was asleep,
whatever,
whatever.
He's can't leave that stuck in the
Ecuadorian embassy the way that that
case was so fucked so far.
So fuck teeth.
He's been so fucking.
It's because the ca wants him so bad and
they control everybody and now they're
trying.
They have influence over Ecuador and
they're trying to.
They're trying to get a Halliburton guy
to be their new anyway.
They might just blow up that place.
I thought gas will no doubt have bright.
I wouldn't be surprised if shit like
that.
More stuff comes out like the seth rich
stuff,
the amount of people.
And this is where I leak any conspiracy
theories,
the amount of people connected to
Hillary Clinton Organization to the
Clinton Foundation,
to Bill Clinton.
The amount of people that had been iced
is stunning.
But then some of them are bullshit and
coincidental and you know,
people and they're in a weird job and
people get go.
There's a lot of people that have been
killed,
but,
but don't you think,
uh,
what I love when they talk about the
uranium one story,
like it's debunked,
right?
Bill Clinton got a half a million
dollars put directly in his pocket from
a Kremlin bank directly and then
$142,000,000 float into the Clinton
Foundation.
And it was fun to punch a bunch of
motherfuckers surrounded a nuclear deal
because they wanted to do charity.
So what's the argument that it was
debunked?
They though they say they say,
oh no,
this,
this is.
She was only one of nine things that had
to sign off,
but there was all these other agencies I
had to sign off on it and this and that.
And it's all bullshit.
That was all influenced by date.
Someone gave Clinton Foundation $142,
million dollars.
That's to buy influence and a half a
million dollars in the Bill Clinton's
pocket directly.
It's because they like how he talks
pretty English in Russia.
Are you fucking kidding me?
So that it's all bullshit.
So people go,
oh,
it's the bugs.
NAFTA,
bunked.
It's that fucking you tell me why they
gave $140 million dollars anonymously to
a fucking Clinton Foundation.
That is such bullshit.
There are so corrupt.
If you believe trump is corrupt by doing
deals with oligarchs,
this is Dylan radigan talking.
You'll also have to believe that Hillary
Clinton did arms deals around the
country while personally enriching
herself and Barack Obama has paid off by
the Wall Street and the health insurance
companies and big Pharma so we don't
have a functioning out of money sector
or the healthcare sector.
It's hard to believe one and not believe
the other two.
That's what Dylan Radigan says,
and I believe that fucking guy.
He's an award winning journalist and he
said,
if you believe trump is corrupt in this,
and he goes,
and it's easy to believe it's all no
fucking bro,
but you also have to believe this.
You have to believe Hillary Clinton did
arms.
Deals are all around the world and
enriching herself to the tunes of
millions of dollars.
The same thing with Barack Obama.
You can't believe one and not the other.
So my whole point is when people try to
pretend that trump is the problem,
they're missing the problem.
The problem is the neo liberal system
that gave us trump that renders 63
percent of the population without funds
to handle a thousand dollar emergency in
the richest country in the world.
That's the problem,
Joe.
And that's what people are.
If you think it's trump,
trump is a symptom of a bigger problem.
I don't even think that guy wants to be
president.
He doesn't think he fucked up and he was
running to the dog shit tires now and
people will taste like shit
will hate him so much.
They want to.
They want to impeach him.
Right.
Favorite parts of the election process
was when he was saying,
I gave you money.
I gave you my that.
So again,
my favorite part,
I was like,
got it.
Who would have thought it would be trump
fucking out?
These people know Eddie has.
He did.
He did it when Obama was mocking him at
that.
A press junket thing.
What does that thing?
It was at the Gulf War correspondents.
Yeah.
The correspondence dinner when he was
mocking him and he said one thing that I
am that you'll never be president of
United States,
and,
and you see trump's in there going,
oh yeah,
mother fucker.
And like that very well could have been
like he was talking about running for
president the eighties.
Right?
But he never did.
Never did.
I thought about it in the 2004 election.
But that fucking Straw snap and he did
it and we're on.
He did it and he always,
I always in a.
do you think that it's a good thing to
have someone that's fucked up is he is
like in terms of how we view a precedent
in terms of like all the grab them by
the Pussy and the paying off 100 women.
That's all the crazy shit and all the
lies like he gets caught in lies all the
time.
And what's worse,
Donald Trump says,
grab them by the Pussy or Barack Obama
says I'm going to fix everything for
you.
And then he kicked your family Outta
your house.
Five point 1 million families out of
their house while making Wall Street
whole and then when he leaves then he
comes back into public life after
retiring,
the first thing he does is give half a
million dollar speeches to banks.
You fucking tell me what's worse.
Is that what he's doing now?
That's what he did.
Yeah.
When he first,
when he works,
he went wind surfing with Branson and
then he came back and he gave speeches
to the Carlyle group and some other
people I had half a million bucks a
crack and Chris Hedges says,
which is why I love Chris Hedges.
He was a guy who told the truth about
the Iraq war and the New York Times
fired him for it,
which is why the New York Times and you
can't fucking believe that you listen to
these male
establishment newspapers where they talk
about war.
Right?
So,
um,
now I fucking forgot what I was saying.
God dammit.
I'm Obama coming back in the office.
So Chris had says they steal right out
in the open.
Now they don't even try to hide it.
And that's what that is.
Well,
that was one of the funniest things
about the Bernie Sanders,
Hillary Clinton debates.
He's like,
why don't you released the transcripts,
relates to transcript.
It must have been some kind of a speech.
600,000 dollars.
I'd love to hear what you had to say.
Yeah,
that was fucking Debbie Wasserman
Schultz.
Yeah.
People keep it.
We're.
We're so fucked up in this country,
Joe,
that we nominate the most repulsive Neil
Liberal,
corporatists warmonger and the history
of the Democratic Party,
the most unpopular nominee ever.
She loses to a fucking game show hosts.
It doesn't even want to be president,
and what do we do?
We blame another country.
We talk about not wanting to examine the
system that gave us.
They taught and that's all they'll talk
about is blaming another country and
what is the big news of the week that we
really concentrate on his hair flopping
off in the breeze in France.
That's hair opens up and you see the
back of his head.
Oh man,
I did a video on that bucket.
The comb over.
Look at that column over.
Look at it.
It's right there.
Well,
it wasn't new,
but it was dramatic.
It was dramatic the way it blew open and
was like a wing opened.
It was like.
It was like you seeing something you're
not supposed to say yes.
Like up a skirt.
It was like his head had an ass.
Yes,
I heard that.
Someone say that.
Yes.
That's a good way of looking at it.
Like this is his head was mooning us.
Yeah.
It was a.
and by the way,
people are going to mistake everything
I'm saying for defending trump and
that's he shaved his head.
Take it from a guy who's got his head
shaved Donald.
Now,
how long ago did you shave your head?
Because I don't ever remember.
You're having.
I don't ever just like you in my head.
11,
2011 maybe.
I think like when I met you in 2004,
whenever that was I,
I just remember you being bald and even
though you weren't obviously now in my
head.
Yeah,
memories do too.
I look at pictures of me from Fairfax.
I'm like,
oh my hair.
I don't remember you ever having hanging
on though.
We started those guys who can pull it.
I,
I couldn't pull it off.
You could pull it off.
I don't think you couldn't until you do
it.
And then you realize it sometimes can do
gray hair too.
I can't do greg fucking really can't do
it.
I have to dye my hair all the time.
But when you let your hair go gray,
you have that are,
uh,
of,
you know,
distinguishing this distinguished
gentleman.
You're,
you have aged and learned and he,
I don't need.
No,
you don't want to die that I don't want
to die and I don't need to be
distinguished.
I want everyone to think I'm the Jerry
Seinfeld when he was getting an award,
he said,
I don't like doing this.
I don't like getting awards.
I'd rather be sat in the corner making
fun of the Guy Getting an award.
And that's exactly how I.
Yeah,
that's me too.
I don't want an award.
I don't want to be in your club.
I don't want to.
You know what?
So what do you think about the
Washington Post is owned by Jeff Bezos,
the richest guy in the world.
Hanni.
Fascinating,
and he sits on a Pentagon board and he
has 100 million dollar deal
with the CIA and he runs the paper up.
No wait,
wait,
wait.
$600.
Million dollar deal with the CIA.
Yeah.
Which is like something on Amazon.
Alexis Dillon.
So he's on Alexis.
Just gathering up information on
everything you do.
Yes,
it is fucking shit out of me.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's not good.
Jamie and I were just talking about that
new apple home thing,
which has the most amazing microphones.
Jamie was saying that while the music is
blaring,
you could say,
Hey Siri.
Oh,
it was real quiet.
Hey Siri,
punch.
Suck my Dick.
Seriously,
I can't do that sir.
Details about the CIA's deal with
Amazon.
$600,000,000 computing cloud built by an
outside company is a radical departure
from the risk averse intelligence
community,
so now they're in bed with the
Washington Post or Jeff Bezos.
Now he also sits on a Pentagon board.
He's got so much money.
He's fascinating to me because like
what?
How do you keep going when you have 105
billion?
Like what's getting you up in the
morning?
So he's a megalomaniac,
right?
How do you accumulate more wealth than
any person in the history of the world?
That means kings,
Queens.
That's not necessarily true.
The reason why is we don't count the
same kind of money that the oligarchs
have.
Like especially people that.
First of all,
people have said that it's very possible
that Putin is the richest man alive
because they.
They're not counting how much money
Putin is stolen from all the various
companies that he's just sort of
absorbed and that he owns all that
stuff,
but also we don't count all these kings
and princes in the Middle East.
They're not publicly,
they're not public people,
Telco,
so,
so let's say of all the people we can
count,
he's the richest guy.
A billionaire friend of mine who's a
legitimate billionaire,
told me that it's entirely possible that
some of these guys are trillionaires.
Some of these Middle Eastern guys.
He's like,
you've never seen wealth like this.
It's insane in do you know in the United
Arab Emirates,
they make it rain every week,
once a week they make it rain.
I mean they see the clouds really get
rain.
Yeah,
because they're in the desert and I'm
like,
Eh,
I don't like this like a drain.
So they fucking put all that shit that
they have to put into the sky to make it
rain,
which they've been doing forever.
Cloud seeding,
but insanely expensive.
But they do it once a week,
so 52 times a year at range there.
So what do you see?
You see a problem with the richest guy
in the world owning the political paper
of note and being in bed with the CIA
and he's on a Pentagon board.
No,
it's all spooky.
It's like some kind of Orwellian fucking
nightmare.
We got so much money and you can't
criticize him in the paper.
They won't let you know.
The people who write for that paper
aren't going great session and post duct
can't write anything bad about it.
They're not going to write.
They wouldn't imagine they would even
dare.
One guy wrote something bad about Amazon
and the Huffington Post.
He got disciplined.
There was a guy who was a writer for the
Washington Post,
wrote something in the Huffington Post
that was critical of Amazon and he got
disciplined at the Washington Post for
doing that.
So that's the world we live in and then
we have the government and if you ever
try to tell about a crime inside the
government,
then the government would use the
espionage act to correct on you.
So we're again,
we're living in an oligarchy joe.
We are d
democracy has already been taken from
us.
So you know that this isn't a democracy.
They've done studies.
This is provable.
Was the thing about from the Huffington
post to derail us,
but was it valid?
Was it a valid criticism?
It wasn't about.
He criticized about how Jeff Bezos
treats his workers.
Oh,
okay.
That has been an open area of discussion
that they like.
I've talked to someone who actually work
there and they were saying that they get
like a countdown.
So say an order comes in,
they literally have like a countdown on
their tablet when the countdown says,
you know,
like,
I don't know what the net amount of time
is,
but you have to run and find that
fucking product and get it into the box
and get it shipped out inside a very
small window of time.
He goes,
so I'm literally running.
I go,
you run?
He goes,
yeah,
you literally run because if you don't
meet your countdown,
he goes,
you could only get away with that for a
certain amount of times.
Then you get in real trouble.
So they also have these new things,
the risks,
the bands that they developed a shock
you or shock,
you know,
will you serious?
I was joking.
They tell you,
they just fucking shot.
He'll pull it up.
They've,
they'll vibrate.
And if you're,
if you're,
if you're moving the wrong way,
it'll shock you back.
It'll shock you back to the requisite
hurt.
Or is it like,
have you ever been to her new Cadillac,
new cadillacs?
If you,
if you go too close to the side,
it gives you like zip,
zip,
zip gives like a little feeling Amazon
wristbands designed to track and
employee's movements.
So Jeff Bezos,
it's been reported it,
which is true,
is that he would rather,
it's not running,
run my shit that day.
So now there's plenty.
There's a couple different fixes for
this.
The problem of robots,
uh,
one of them would be a unions,
right?
So I'm like,
my whole thing is why can't we unionize?
Amazon,
why can't we use a Nice Walmart?
I know they make it hard.
Walmart literally shut down their
meatpacking in Texas because of the meat
packing group.
They unionized in Texas.
They fuck it.
We're not going to sell meat anymore in
Texas.
That's how we'll fuck over the union.
So,
but we got to figure out a way to get
unions in there.
There's another thing,
you know,
Teddy Roosevelt was a trust buster,
which was a,
he was a monopoly buster.
You know,
50 percent of all online purchases go
through Amazon.com in the United States.
Fifty percent.
Yeah.
Fifty one percent of households in
America have Amazon prime.
Only 49 percent have a landline,
so more people at Amazon prime in the
United States then have fucking
landline.
So what is that?
Real Teddy Roosevelt would come along
and go,
we got to break this company up.
Wow.
He would say,
this is a first.
First of all,
Jeff Bezos,
because he owns the paper,
he got the trump was right when he said
he.
He's there to get the texts in his favor
because he was able to go around and
hollow out economies,
a mainstreet little small towns all
around because he didn't have to pay
taxes,
the income tax and for Amazon and so the
brick and mortar places did.
He closed them down by undercutting
them,
right?
Because he and now he's opening up brick
and mortar stores.
He closed out all the barnes and nobles
and borders books and now he's opening
up Amazon bookstores.
Did you know that?
No.
Amazon 64,
40,
64.
There you go.
Even up higher than than from when I
looked.
They have Amazon prime.
Now.
How many of those people use it for
television?
This is my question because I know that
Amazon started to make apparently some
very good shows,
but I don't hear anybody talking about
watching them.
Like apparently billy Bob Thornton has a
really good show on Amazon and I know
there was that,
um,
Jeffrey tambor show that got tanked.
Do you know,
that's an interesting me too.
Story.
The Jeffrey Tambor,
one of the guys he was,
he's playing a transvestite transgender
person and
there was people and he's not
transgender and there's people on the
show apparently that were very upset
that a transgender,
a non transgender person was playing a
transgender person will.
It's acting.
Yeah.
Well they didn't like that and this,
a lot of internal dispute because of
that,
which may or may not have led to the
accusations.
I used to be much harder job.
I used to be harder on it on
transgender.
When I say harder on transgender,
I mean a boner.
No,
I mean when I,
I used to make.
I used to make jokes about them because
I didn't understand.
I didn't understand that was a real
thing.
I thought it was just guys fucking
having fun,
right?
Well,
some of them we all like to fucking feel
a little weird or whatever.
I,
you know,
I don't go out in public and so,
but then I realized this is the actual
thing with a lot of people that they're
actually born.
They have the different feeling than
they're outside.
Then I realized it was a thing and so
now I don't do that anymore.
It's gender
Morphea,
you know,
it's,
there's,
there's definitely people that have
issues in their mind where they wish
that they were a different thing than
what they are.
I think the thing that concerns me more
about transgender people than anything
is this acceptance of using hormone
blockers for young children.
And I just think that is fucking insane.
And this is something that the liberal
progressives are pushing.
Edit,
alarming rate.
It's a terrifying idea.
Uh,
you know,
there's,
there's plenty of discussion about this
online.
There's plenty of people that think that
age six is a fine year to start this.
Yeah.
We've talked,
we've had people on the podcast who
infiltrated,
um,
this,
uh,
this transgender group and we're talking
about their kid,
their kid identifies with the girl,
but the kid is six is two years too
young to start and you know,
and that is,
it's too young.
They were saying,
no,
it's not,
you know,
studies show that that's a good time.
They're just horse shitting and want
more people to do it so that they feel
better.
Okay.
Do you ever met a married guy that wants
you to get married because they're
fucking miserable as shit.
I don't want to call anybody out,
but famous guy,
how have a conversation with famous guys
telling me how great it is to be married
and his wife yells at them,
tells them what to do and all this shit
and he gets things done this way and I'm
like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
He's now divorced.
I'm married.
Okay.
So it's many years ago,
this guy was fucking miserable,
but he was trying to tell me that it's a
good thing to be married because when
you're married you have to answer to
someone that someone tells you what to
do.
I go,
what?
He was telling me that his wife calls
him a fucking asshole and it makes him
more.
I go,
no,
my friends don't call me an asshole.
Why?
Unless I'm.
And if I.
If one of my friends calls me a fucking
asshole,
I made a huge mistake.
It's like living in married to your
football coach who wants that?
Who wants to do that?
You could throw in buckets of gatorade
on your head.
Like the whole thing was ridiculous,
but it was literally a misery loves
company thing that happens.
So people who are married want you to be
married to.
Now I'm not saying that's absolutely
what's going on with people who are
transgender,
but they're most certainly in support of
more people doing it and I don't know if
that is why they would lean towards
having six year olds take hormone
blockers.
But if you criticize that in any way,
you were thought to be transphobic,
and this is a real issue today where
people bring this up over and over
again,
I don't know why anyone would think that
it's a good idea to take a six year old
and put them on hormone blockers,
but they don't know what the fuck is
going on with the world.
Their body is changing.
They're going through all this growth
and development,
and for you to chemically hijack that
for an ideology seems to me as an
outsider to be fucking insane,
but to talk about it,
you run the risk of being thought of as
being transphobic.
It's a very strange time to discuss
things because you can't have an opinion
about it because,
oh,
you're a CIS gendered white man with all
sorts of privilege.
Look at you.
You Macho piece of shit.
Yeah.
People like to say you're mansplaining.
Exactly.
It's like,
well,
I'm a guy and I have an opinion so I'm
not allowed to have that opinion ever.
I mean,
I understand there's a.
there's a time and a place to say
mansplaining.
Sure.
But I don't think there is,
but let's find a place to say that
someone is talking down to people just
happened to be a man.
That's fine.
But the problem with the term
mansplaining is that man is correct.
If a woman is saying something that's
incorrect in a man.
Correct sir?
He's mansplaining.
Yeah.
Well that's ridiculous.
So that's what it's saying too often
it's turned into that.
Just like I said,
the Hashtag.
Me Too.
We're all against sexual harassment at
work,
but we're not for puritanism exactly.
So it's when people hijacking certain
things,
I think that what we're going,
what's going on with Hashtag me too and
a lot of things in this society is we're
undergoing a radical cultural change and
it's brought about by information.
I think we're way more aware of each
other's feelings,
way more aware of what's okay,
way more aware of what we're willing to
tolerate and what we're not willing to
tolerate.
And if you go back to the 19 thirties in
the 19 forties and watch old films where
people would smack the shit out of women
and rape them and do all kinds of crazy
stuff.
And it was thought to be normal.
Those are the heroes.
The,
that a woman?
Yes.
John Wayne would do that.
Remember what he uh,
how about uh,
well it's the guy,
I forget his name,
but he took the grapefruit right in her
fail.
Yeah.
What was that?
Was that I'm John Waner was.
That's the short.
Uh,
yeah.
fuck.
Oh I counted.
And Mickey Rooney?
No,
the other store guy closet?
No.
Jim James.
Cagney Agni.
Yeah.
Up.
I couldn't think of his name.
I couldn't either.
Yeah.
Here it is.
It is.
Volume.
I didn't ask you any lip.
Actually we had a drink.
I know Tom.
But yeah.
I wish wishing stop again.
I wish you were the wishing well.
And I can tell you a bucket they in sync
yet.
What Dick?
Wow.
That's kind of an asshole thing to say.
Say that one you like better.
So she says that,
and he takes the group great,
great food right in their face.
Wow.
That is kind of a beat.
That's a dick move back.
It's so ruthless.
Fucking seen.
Horrible.
I'll try to do that today.
Maybe you know,
have some name,
a guy who's a Ryan Geisler,
one of those guys when I'm handsome
fellows,
do it to some beautiful young girl who's
a good stone.
Yeah.
How about that sucks.
Like grapefruit interface,
pupil fuck movie is.
And she just kind of cried.
She doesn't even react with that.
Men beat the fuck out of women back
then.
It was normal.
Yeah.
That's horrible.
So I think what those things represent.
Obviously it's fiction,
right?
But what it also represents is what was
acceptable culturally to witness in a
film that is not acceptable culturally
to witness in a film now,
especially from the fucking hero of the
show.
I think today we're more aware than ever
before of of how people feel,
of how people think of what's
acceptable,
what's not,
and what was wrong with the way people
used to behave.
Whereas it was just,
we were operating on momentum and the
thirties and forties and fifties and
sixties and seventies.
The Internet came along and people were
just sharing information of this
unprecedented pace.
Yeah.
Uh,
I just found out about John Lennon.
What about him?
That he admitted to beating his girls?
Girlfriends.
Really?
Did you meet her at Yoko Ono sing you
gotta you gotta give him,
cut him a break.
But it was when I was younger and he
said,
you know,
I have to make up for the things.
I can't deny what I did.
I have to make up for it.
I was like,
wow.
And you don't want to hear that right.
Data about Hendrix to know.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
See if he could find that dude.
Hendrick Hendrick story is very
disturbing because Hendrix might've been
murdered.
It's very possible that really is
You don't have to imagine John Lennon
beat women and children.
It was just a fact beat.
Children.
Who did he what children?
Terrible things the famous asshole did
during his life have written by a woman
Hashtag.
Me Too.
Yeah,
it was a different time.
I bet.
I bet a lot of people did terrible
things back then.
I guess he wasn't one of his kids.
He wasn't nice to.
I forget which one,
Julian or the other.
Anyway,
it's tough.
It's not.
You don't want to,
you know,
Steve Martin's Dad.
I might give a read his book talks about
how his dad hit him a little too hard
one time when they were never friends
after that.
Jesus.
And did you get hit as a kid growing up?
No.
No,
I didn't get your mother got hit.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
My mother got hit by my dad,
but then she left my dad.
Oh,
your dad didn't hit you completely made
up.
Jimmy Hendrix,
Australian girlfriend.
Savages.
New Film which shows rockstar beating up
her character.
Oh,
okay.
Uh,
all my sides and accuracy has been
criticized by Hendrix.
His friends,
his former girlfriend,
disgusted by scenes depicting domestic
violence never consulted her about
portrayal.
Okay.
So that might not be true.
But there was,
um,
there was another,
uh,
someone had said that there was a
situation where Jimmy was in the other
room and he hit his girlfriend,
like someone was talking about it from
first person perspective.
I don't know if that was the girlfriend.
The fascinating thing about Jimmy was
that he had this gangster manager who
had him kidnapped his manager,
had him kidnapped so that he could
release him so that he could rescue him
so that he can keep Jimmy on as a
client.
And this is all a.
That came from a really recent book that
was one of the gangster guys,
bodyguards,
like one of the people that worked for
them.
So very fascinating.
So he was afraid that Jimmy was going to
get rid of him as a manager.
So he engineered a kidnapping that he
could solve,
that Jimmy would feel indebted and bring
them on as his manager.
And this guy who wrote this book,
I don't know how much of this is real
and how much of it's bullshit,
but thinks that they murdered Jimi
Hendrix.
And then right after that,
the girlfriend of Jimi Hendrix was
thrown off of a roof.
Yeah.
Really?
And they said she committed suicide.
But he says they threw her off a roof
and she knew about Jimmy's murder.
Really?
Eh?
I Dunno,
I dunno.
I Dunno.
A stranger.
Things have happened in that job.
Well,
that whole business in many ways look at
should night,
right?
That whole business,
the music business has been run by
gangsters for a long fucking time.
Look it.
Phil Spector,
right?
The guy who was shot,
that woman in the face,
like he used to put guns in people's
mouths all the time.
That business was run by gangsters ever.
So the idea of Jimi Hendrix manager
being a gangster,
it's not outside the realm of
possibility.
You go back to the Ciro's nightclub days
where it's the comedy store is today.
That was run by Bugsy Siegel.
It was a fucking gangster joint with.
That's where they had musicians play and
fucking Jerry Lewis and Dean Martin
Plate there.
I mean really?
That was run by fucking murderers.
That was the one reason why everybody
was willing to believe the comedy store
was haunted.
If you look at like the haunted no
dictionary of like places or the
directory of places,
the comedy store's like one of the top
places on the list in Hollywood.
There it is.
I'm pretty sure it's not a club.
That's the fucking main room,
man.
I prefer them there.
I'm going there tonight.
I'll be standing right there with that
guy is.
I mean,
it's crazy that the store is essentially
the same fucking place as it was then.
Wow.
Yeah,
I bet.
I believe baton do.
They killed a shitload of people in that
place and there's a.
that's the front door.
How Nice.
That looks isn't amazing.
Yeah.
That's really dark and evil.
Meanwhile,
I was evil or then now we're just
telling jokes.
That was fun that night at.
You know,
I haven't done many sets of the comedy
store in Los Angeles.
It was a blast.
I really enjoyed that.
Sam Tripoli.
Thanks for him.
Me On that show,
doing his show tonight show tonight.
It's in the main room.
It's the place is the best.
It's.
It's just,
it's soaked with history.
Look at that point blown grant smacked
my girlfriend to finish with a
grapefruit chain.
We'll get them cigarettes,
smoking cigarettes.
Nobody worked out.
Nobody.
Nobody where everybody looked like shit.
Ronald Reagan.
Reagan.
Who's the girl?
I don't know.
That state.
That's Dean Martin,
right?
Nancy Reagan.
That's Nancy.
Know what the picture says?
It was nancy and Ronald Reagan.
Wow.
She got an even bigger Martin genie
bigger.
That's Dean Martin writing.
Martin.
Dean Martin looked weird too.
It's just a weird angle.
Is probably hammered.
Couldn't keep his eyes open like I
always wanted to be those guys like I
wanted to be Dean Martin.
I wanted to be the rat pack.
I want it to be a dreamy.
Jimmy.
Dory Leo.
You have a good chance of being Jimmy
Dore.
It's hard to find out who that guy is.
Oh,
I see.
But if you're on the outside,
maybe there's a kid right now listening
going,
God dammit.
Jimmy Dore.
I want to be.
You don't even know who the fuck you
are.
Well you don't.
I will put you here.
Have you ever thought about this?
I've thought about it like this,
if somebody would have whispered in my
ear when I was 18 years old,
you know how you.
I had a lot of anxiety as a kid,
like what am I gonna do with my life?
I had no role models to do anything.
I grew up in this blue collar
neighborhood.
I didn't want to do anything.
Anybody fucking did there.
Me Too.
Same thing.
Same Story.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
Right?
So you become a comment.
Yeah,
and that's how I became a comic and I,
if somebody would have whispered in my
ear when I was younger,
like,
Hey,
this is how it's gonna work out,
I'd have been a lot more relaxed and
yeah,
but then you would have made it.
Probably would need it.
No,
you had that anxiety is important that
the heart,
the horrible feeling of insecurity.
It all pans out because that makes you
work.
Like you don't want to be comfortable.
That's one of the things that I'd like
to do.
Things that I'm not good at.
That's one of the reasons why I like to
do yoga is one of the reasons why I like
to run hills.
It's one of the reasons why I like to do
things like archery and bow hunting and
stuff like that.
It's fucking hard to do so.
It's humbling.
Jujitsu.
It's very humbling and in doing these
humbling things,
you're always insecure.
You're always struggling.
You have to somehow or another
constantly be in a state of struggle,
but that doesn't mean you have to be in
a state of sugar all day,
all your life,
but you have to understand what that
feeling is because that feeling is the
only way you progress.
It's the only way you advance,
so the only way you get better things.
You get better at yourself,
you get better at life.
You have to go through that all the
time.
It's a muscle that has to constantly be
exercised.
It's like you're talking about doing
standup,
like Jerry Seinfeld saying,
take four days off.
You feel it.
Take five days off.
People know it.
Yeah.
That's the same thing with struggle.
You got to constantly be engaged in
improvement and trying to figure out how
to improve things.
That's how you advance.
That's how you advance technique.
That's how you advance thought.
That's how I advanced ideas
and bits.
That's how they progress.
You have to feel that fucking
uncomfortable feeling that everybody
wants to avoid.
Everybody wants to feel comfortable with
all that.
So when I was on the road,
you know,
when you were talking about how putting
together your next special and how
you're going to do it,
terrified and all,
all you have to go through.
You know,
I,
when I was on the road,
I remember like even in in El Paso,
Texas,
I'd be working and I would do two shows
and I would go home after afterwards she
has a condo and I would listen to both
shows before I went to sleep,
you know,
now I know most guys didn't do that,
but I just had to do it and it was
almost like I was embarrassed to let the
other comics.
No,
I was listening to my set,
but it was like,
just like that.
It's like I don't,
I don't want to be stuck here,
I want to be,
I have some place I want to be and I got
to get there and if this helps me get
there,
I want to get there.
I want to figure out what the fuck I
want.
How do I get to be like that guy?
How do I get to be like Jerry Seinfeld?
I don't want to be like Brian Regan,
how do I get to be like those people I
want to be like,
and you know,
I just studied them and I just.
So it's that whole thing of you have to
have a desire to be somewhere that
you're not.
Um,
well that's one way to look at it.
But for me,
the,
I feel like that takes care of itself if
you continue to improve.
So my thought has always been on the
thing itself,
like the craft,
the bits,
the chunks and there's some material
from my past I'm embarrassed as fuck
about.
I can't go.
Like if I go on youtube and I see some
old thing from 1999 or something like
let's fucking death,
I can't look at that,
but what,
what I'm concerned with is like what I'm
doing right now,
how do I get that better?
How do I tighten that up?
I'm not thinking one day I want to
perform at this place and then I'll have
truly made it.
That's a trap.
But what's not a trap is making the work
better.
Like constantly improving the work.
And since I've been focusing on that,
the more I focused on that,
the better my act has got.
Oh yeah,
definitely.
You're right about that too.
Trap.
Because um,
well why do you think it's a trap when
you say,
Oh,
I want to play theaters.
You're still use somewhere else with
that same stupid and yes,
then still bugs you and you think
everything's going to be different.
And it's like,
um,
and,
and why I think fucks people up when
they make it,
if they're like,
I feel exactly the same and if they
don't know what to do with them.
So that's kind of guy where I got right,
like oh I can do whatever I want,
go wherever I want to see the and I
still feel the same and that's when I
started listening to Eckhart totally.
And I started to try to be present and
try to learn how to enjoy the moment
more and in the doing right.
So when I'm doing.
And that's what I realized also is that
when I'm onstage stage,
I'm never more present than when I'm on
stage.
Like I am,
that whatever that magic is to be
present it and it gives you.
It's like when people say they meditate,
they have energy after I have so much
energy after I get off stage,
even if it's a shitty show because I'm
just being present the whole time.
I'm not thinking about my bills or what
happened yesterday,
I'm just thinking about right this
fucking moment and it fuels me and
that's why I just want to go.
I want
to figure out how I could go back to
being a comedian.
Well you can be.
I mean you definitely did it the other
night,
so yeah.
Yes.
You just got to do it more.
I'm just pushing my song man,
pushing myself to get out there more and
it happens to people when they get a
television show and it happened to me
when I got news radio,
I was doing very little comedy and I
wasn't writing it all and my aunt
started to suck.
I was having this.
I have the same old stupid act and I had
for years.
There was a period of like two years
writing,
write a fucking single joke.
I would just go up and do the same set.
I wasn't doing any TV sets and I just
kept bombing and one time I bombed in
front of some writers was radio and I
realized like,
Oh my God,
I have to get back to work,
and then I really started dedicating
myself and really started paying
attention again.
I bought a recorder so I can record all
my sets are even installed a dat machine
at the comedy store,
a bought it really stalled and stalled
and stalled microphones.
Yeah,
I changed the microphone.
I bought a whole new sound system for
the comedy store so I could start
recording my sets and listening to all
of them.
Fantastic.
And now I just use my phone,
iphone.
So amazing.
But kind of fucking,
you got to be concentrating on the work.
That's the thing,
man.
And the more you concentrate on getting
it better and the more you tighten it up
and that's where the real happiness in
performing is,
is doing a great job.
It's not in like the places that you go.
I still get nervous like if uh,
some,
some places they'll get nervous,
you know,
like I did the theater at Madison Square
Garden.
That made me nervous.
I was like,
Holy Shit,
I'm performing at the fucking garden.
But then after the show was over I was
like,
well that was a show.
Normal shelves.
Great.
Everything was great.
Went well,
but it was fucking weird man,
because you're just mind fucking
yourself.
It's the same jokes as people,
just a different venue.
So I used to work this club in Chicago
called the funny firm,
which was a 400 seat room right downtown
Chicago was great room around the corner
was the Improv and they made it really
hard to play the Improv if you lived in
Chicago and so I remember I had a got a,
got a shot to to do a set there and I
was freaked out.
I didn't have a good set and I can't so
much pressure.
I cave off and my friend Steve Siegrist
goes,
he goes,
it's the same fucking people that are
around the corner.
Jimmy,
they're right here.
It's the same fucking people.
And I know he's right.
I know he's right.
And,
but I still fall into that.
But if you went up a week later you'd
probably be fine.
Yeah.
It's just more often it's against.
It's the newness of the situation until
you feel like that's the problem with
filming a special.
When you film a special,
it's like,
here it is,
ready go.
The camera's on.
Oh my God.
I gotta get right.
Got To be relaxed and be normal.
I have one chair,
when I did my hour special for comedy
central,
I thought we'd shoot too and then we put
it together,
but for whatever reason we only had
enough money to shoot one and I was
like,
what I should for.
Oh really?
But I could have used the first one.
You know why?
Because I knew I had four barrels.
I knew I had four shots,
but I did it before what I had to.
I did Denver.
I had to.
And the first one,
a lady heckled me and I was like,
oh no,
no,
I have.
It's terrible.
Right.
So I'm like,
you got have four and four.
I was relaxed,
like I did the fillmore in San Francisco
for my last one and it felt like regular
comedy.
It was normal.
That's a great place.
Yeah,
that's what I did.
My hour specials at the fillmore.
Where does a really great place?
Place,
but I'd done that place before I was
comfortable.
I love San Francisco.
I worked there all the time,
so everything just set right in.
But I knew I had four shows.
Like I feel like too many people put too
much pressure on themselves to do one.
And I always remember about Hicks when
Hicks did relentless.
He didn't in the UK and he did one big
show and it just was flat.
It just seemed flat.
He didn't seem loose.
The wasn't.
It was like he was just going through
these motions that he had done before
that were funny,
but he wasn't connected to it.
You could feel the tension of doing one
show.
And I had seen him many,
many times.
And I remember I watched it with this
girl that I was dating and she goes,
he's really interesting,
but he's not funny.
That's what she said.
I was like,
Damn Bitch,
wow.
You know,
it's tough debt.
Don't you know that.
How about you shut the fuck up.
You grab a great proofreader.
Faith no,
a Kiwi.
And uh,
I always thought it was that Bill Hicks
hit it just,
it's hard to capture someone on film as
a standup.
It's hard to capture that.
Like Dennis Miller is black and white.
That was,
I think the greatest example of
capturing that.
And uh,
but I just thought it was like,
well bill is funny in person,
but he doesn't transfer to tv that well
because he,
his specialist didn't come anywhere
close to being a funny.
He wasn't,
he just never.
They never got it right.
I think they needed to get him at a
club.
Said,
man,
you ever see St Mastache that captured
him?
Exactly.
Yeah.
They did that at the Houston laugh stop.
He did himself.
Right.
See that's.
But when you do that then you're
getting,
you know,
a bunch of different sets.
You find the right one,
but.
And you do it at a comedy club where
he's comfortable.
I think more people should do sets a
comedy clubs and,
and film specials at comedy clubs.
I have a couple of different theories
for why.
But one of the big ones is when you're
at home,
you're in a living room.
It's intimate.
Your want your couch.
TV is just right there.
It's not fucking a million miles away on
a giant big ass screen.
So it feels weird to watch something on,
you know,
the big ass giant place.
50,000 people that Kevin Hart did is
special.
I think that that.
It's funny,
you know,
obviously the material's great,
great delivery and everyone in that,
but I think everything is enhanced more
with an intimate environment.
My favorite spot,
one of my favorite specials that I did,
I did at the comedy works in Denver,
so like I think it's what does that
place.
It's not even 300 people I don't think
really might be 300.
I just saw Judah fried lenders and he
did his all in the comedy cellar I think
could be perfect and it was all a bunch
of different from over like a couple
months.
So he just,
you know,
he would just great.
It was.
And he did it in black and white.
Oh see if you do that man,
you get it.
You get the right show.
Yeah,
he did.
It was.
When you're trying to capture one
moment,
one night,
what are the odds that it's going to be
perfect.
Too much pressure on you.
You're right.
I never thought about that.
That you're in this big,
huge thing and people are watching it in
their little room and it makes sense.
Yeah.
I definitely want to do my next special
in a club.
Did you see Dave Chappelle's new netflix
special?
The one that he did at the comedy store,
belly room.
He did two of them.
He did want it to a good size place in
dc or just things like a couple thousand
people and then he did another one,
the belly room which was like 70 people
and I was there for that one.
Really?
Yeah.
I was like,
wow,
this is interesting man.
He's like,
it's so conversational,
but like when you're at home it's great
because it's like he's right there.
You see the people are literally as
close to him as you are to me.
And then you're right there to like
you're in the room with them.
Now check that out.
And I have an intimate.
You feel it,
you know.
And uh,
how is it funny to fucking hilarious the
one in dcs genius.
And then the one in the belly room is
great too,
but in a different way because it's
like,
it's more like really current events
stuff like he's talking about Louis Ck,
like there he is up there so it's like
Louis ck and Harvey Weinstein and Kevin
Spacey was a big part of the material
that he was talking about.
So.
And it was right after it happened.
He filmed this in November,
so it was just a couple of months ago
and it was out in New Year's.
New Year's Day.
Oh,
I'll check it out.
They'll definitely,
I thought,
you know,
I have Amazon prime.
I don't like to Brag.
Oh you.
And 65 fucking million.
What is it?
Sixty four percent.
Sixty,
64 percent of the country.
I wonder how many of those people are
watching it on TV though.
That's the thing.
Using Amazon prime.
Just for the TV part.
I mean how many of them are using the TV
part of prime?
How many of you were watching?
Because I have Amazon prime.
I never,
I never remembered.
He never used it for TV.
Now I've never.
Do you still have old time cable?
I have direct TV.
Oh,
so that's old time cable.
Yeah,
I still have it.
Uh,
I,
I'd like to flip through the.
I like cooking shows and I like watching
boxing and sports.
It's great for live sports,
but I don't really,
I didn't watch the football too much
anymore.
It's just,
you know,
I did watch the superbowl.
It was even though I loved watching New
England lose,
I didn't really didn't really.
Game just doesn't excite me anymore.
It's just,
it's just a bunch of fucking
millionaires and that kind of,
you know,
once they get younger than you to.
It's hard to get excited with all these
different things.
Is that,
I don't know,
is that stupid?
I don't know.
I mean it's only stupid if it's stupid
to you.
Okay.
I mean it just was a lot and now and
when I moved out from Chicago to La,
I just,
sports just seemed so much less
interesting.
Now I like watching sports.
Like,
um,
I like boxing because it's very much
like standup comedy.
There's no hiding.
You reveal who you are in the ring.
Right.
And just like as a standup,
there is no hiding,
there's no fucking light show or music
underneath their fucking dancing girls
just liking you and your ideas.
And so that's why I like boxing and I
and I realized again,
it's people that think I'm blowing smoke
up your ass,
but I don't like to watch.
I like to watch UFC.
I like to watch the fighting,
but only you're announcing it because I
liked the backstories and all that shit
that you give to it that no one else
seems to be able to do it.
Just kind of roles are it off of you.
It just falls out of your mouth.
Other people,
announcers,
they just,
it's just boring.
So I don't watch that.
It's very nice to you,
but it's just because I care about it.
That's all it is you can sell.
It's been a part of my life since I was
a little kid.
And so for me it's very important when
I'm watching this and explaining what's
happening,
like physically like to look to
understand what the gracie brothers and
what that,
what they did and the like.
That's interesting.
That's what heightens everything,
you know,
when you're watching and,
and that's why I liked to watch boxing
because those guys' stories are always
these unbelievable.
His mother abandoned him.
He was 80,
walked Brazil for three years and then
he started like,
holy fuck,
you know,
so.
So that's like,
that's the,
it's a do or die and it's one on one and
that's why I love box.
It's what we were talking about earlier
when we were talking about Jay Leno's
new show is that he's actually
passionate about it.
When someone's passionate about
something,
it comes through when it's real,
when it's genuine and they can
articulate it.
It comes through and I think if you're
not doing something you're passionate
about,
understand that from watching someone
who is doing something like the Jay Leno
show or anything along those lines.
When you see someone you go,
oh,
that's that feeling,
that magic does that thing where
someone's like really excited about it.
Like it's legit,
like it's in their bones and if it's not
in your bones,
man,
you better find what is because you're
missing out on,
you know,
you're only getting to seven.
Life goes to 10 and you're not,
you're not ever hitting the high spots.
You know,
he might be fine being,
staying at seven forever.
I've been to attend too many times.
He liked being at 10.
That's the problem.
Most people never get to five.
It's amazing.
Most people,
most people I grew up with and stuff,
it's just,
it's system.
You know,
comedy opened my,
you know,
I grew up on the south side of Chicago.
We could see,
I could see the sears tower,
the John Hancock building,
which are the two biggest buildings in
Chicago.
You could see downtown from where I
live.
Nobody ever went there,
you know,
it was like,
yeah,
I guess I guess if you grew up in the
bronx,
you can see Manhattan.
You never went right.
So,
but,
and then comedy kind of opened that up
for me.
I went into those neighborhoods and I
under and I was like,
this is awesome.
I love this city,
the whole thing.
It was set guts.
I said it was such a heady experience
for me and thing.
My whole life was ahead of me and no
matter who you are,
if you kill,
if you're a stand up and you kill,
I don't care if you kill Adzenys as 150
people or if you kill a Madison Square
Garden,
it's still killing the same feelings.
10,
it's 10,
you hit 10,
you,
you hit a joke and boom and you hear the
roar like that's 10 and there's nothing.
You know,
my brother,
I remember the first time I got a paid
gig.
It was in Wheaton or wheeling,
Illinois.
Anyway,
it was $50 and I was telling him I had
to drive 50 miles to go make $50 to do
comedy,
which to me it was a victory,
right?
Yeah.
And he,
he worked for the power company in
Chicago.
Come with us and he goes,
they'd have to pay me $50 just to drive
there.
Right?
And I'm like,
yeah,
but when you get there,
you have to go to work.
What I get there,
I'm the center of attention.
It's there's a party happening and I'm
the guest of honor and I'm going to get
a blow job afterwards,
which I did that night in the church
parking lot.
It was fantastic church parking lot
where the parking lot of a church.
Anyway,
so that's the.
So that's why I loved stand up comedy.
It's like there's nothing like it
everywhere you go,
you're the guest of honor at a party.
That's another thing that people
probably never totally understand about
standup that haven't done it is you
become attractive.
Whereas you're just a guy.
Oh,
right before,
right?
You're just a guy,
just a guy.
Now you're a guy and girls are going
after you and you're like,
what is happening?
I remember the first time that happened,
I was in.
I was stunned.
Like I'd come off stage.
I killed.
This girl came right up to me and you
want to talk to me.
I'm like,
is this a trick?
Some grown in Connecticut?
I'll never forget it.
She put her hand on my chest and she was
talking to me.
You are so funny.
How long have you been doing this?
Oh my God,
you know,
Larry has picked kit and I was like,
what is going on here?
This is fake,
this,
this girl,
what is she going to do to me?
Someone around going to rob me.
Like,
what's happening was so weird.
Even when a,
afterwards,
her and I had sex,
I was like,
this seems fake.
It doesn't even seem real.
First Time that happened to me,
I was,
I was working at a zany up,
maybe I should too late.
And uh,
I was,
I come off stage and this woman came up
to me and uh,
she says,
where are you going?
I go,
I'm going to the bathroom.
And she says,
do you need any help?
And uh,
and at that club there's just one.
It's not a big bathroom.
It's one stall,
right?
So you get your own room,
And I go,
I don't know if my,
if my boss would appreciate that or
something like that.
And she says,
Oh,
I'm here with the boss's wife,
which I don't know if she was or not.
And so she follows me into the bathroom.
And gave me a blow job.
It was.
I was like,
I just got out.
I had to go up and bring up the middle.
It was fucking awesome.
It was almost like,
this is,
I love comedy.
It's a weird.
A shifting of roles,
you know?
Yeah.
It was.
I remember my back hurt at the time.
I just have a bad back when I was
starting comedy and I remember I had to
like sit on the sink because I got my
back and I said she's blowing.
It was so funny.
I love girls,
don't get that thing from comedy though.
It's a funny thing that Allie has.
She's like a.
she's like,
road pussy is amazing.
She goes,
road dick is.
I don't want to do her bit.
I don't want to ruin her.
Essentially.
She's,
yeah,
it's not the same.
Yeah.
I don't want to ruin her material,
but essentially that's what she's
saying.
It's like,
it's not a good deal for gals.
It must be different.
You know,
one time I remember,
um,
I,
I have a big mouth and everything.
And so when I started comedy,
there was this girl and um,
she was pretty and I guess I must have
told people I'd like to get it on.
I can't wait to work the road with her
so I could fuck her.
That's horrible.
So people hearing that now today you're
a piece of shit.
So I don't know if.
I don't even know if I said what,
uh,
how I said or whatever,
but so that I get
confronted by her at a comedy club.
This girl comes up to me and I didn't
know she was going to say.
She goes,
hi Jimmy.
And I go,
hi,
how you doing?
She goes,
I heard you said you can't wait to work
the road because you wanted to fuck me.
And uh,
she goes,
uh,
did you say that?
I go,
sounds like something I would say.
And she goes,
uh,
she goes,
don't you want to know who told me I go,
could be anything
buddy taught you want to know?
And she goes,
she ran out of things to say yes.
And then she goes,
well,
why did you say that?
I go because you're really pretty and
I'm attracted to you,
and she totally changed.
She was like,
oh,
well that's okay.
Totally changed.
Yeah,
but this is a different era and we're
friends til this day,
but if this never had sex,
but she would write an article for some
of them online rags,
you're,
you're right.
I want to get in trouble for that piece
of shit.
But I was a kid.
I was just starting comedy.
I didn't know him and my asshole from a
hole in the ground and I didn't know
anything about that.
And when she said she goes,
why did you send them free?
Why did you say that?
And I just decided to be honest.
I go,
because you're pretty,
I'm attracted to you.
She was like,
oh,
that's okay.
I think she thought,
I thought I was saying she was a slut
and that's not what I was saying.
That's not what I was saying.
I was saying she's fucking chance with
her.
I get it.
I would like a chance with her.
That's what I was saying.
She took it.
I was saying she was a horse,
so that's not what I was saying.
So she totally.
It was that.
That's the only experience I have like
that.
Yeah,
it's going to be a weird thing.
Time if we remove flirting and clumsy,
attempt sets,
sex and there's a lot of that stuff that
turns out to be fun.
It's funny to that like one thing that
you could say to one person is highly
offensive and you could say it to
another person is exactly what they
wanted to hear.
That's like.
And you really don't know until you
essentially you say it or do it and you
read it written on paper like,
yeah,
it sounds terrible,
but in the right circumstance,
that's the thing to say.
Nobody wants to admit that.
Like,
I dated this girl once,
I'll never forget they ever read it.
When it's read back to you in court,
it sounds horrible.
But in the go ahead,
there was a girl that I dated once and
we're making out and uh,
and you know,
we're getting into it hot and heavy.
She grabs my dick and I said,
I want you to get on my knees or get on
your knees and suck my cock.
She goes,
I've always wanted someone to tie that
to me.
No Kid.
She drops down to her knees and like
she's fucking going at it.
But when she looked at me,
she goes,
I've always wanted someone to say that
to me and like,
what?
Jackpot baby?
Come on seven.
You could say that some girls,
she'd be like,
no,
like,
all right.
That's the whole.
You can say like,
you don't know in the moment.
Like I just like,
it was hot and heavy and crazy quick and
I was like,
I'm just going to roll the dice.
Let's just see.
Let's pull up.
Let's go for three lemons.
Couldn't see what the fuck happens.
You never know,
but if you don't,
you don't make any calls.
You don't make any sales.
But this was 1993,
you know,
try doing that in 2018.
You get in real trouble.
You know,
I just talked to a guy and he made
it.
He owns a bar and he was talking about
Hashtag me too,
and he says,
you know,
the thing is that women don't have to
hit on men.
Men are always the aggressor.
Right?
And so that causes a lot of problems,
you know,
like a guy will say,
I'll see a guy,
what have this group of friends and
he'll slink over to try to talk to this
girl and he's nervous and he says,
Hey,
do you want to dance?
And she'll shut him down and he'll walk
back over and like,
oh,
that fucking bitch,
you know?
And he goes,
that's what said because he's got to
save face and women don't know what
that's like.
And I was thinking attractive women do
though,
I mean one of the,
one of the things that you see from the
same people,
whether it's men or women,
is people that are constantly shut down
and ridiculed and mocked by the opposite
sex become very bitter and angry.
You see it sometimes from unattractive
women who have been shit on by men and
you see it from an attractive men who've
been shit on by women.
They developed this animosity towards
the opposite sex.
It's very unfortunate and it a lot of it
comes from that feeling that you just
get from someone.
When you make an advance,
you become vulnerable and look,
if you're a guy,
not a good looking guy and take a chance
of some girl.
She's with her friends at a bar.
She might mock you openly in front of
her friends and it's ruthlessly painful
and she's just not attracted to you.
She wants to shut down any possibility
that you might have in your head.
You go back over there and this happens
time and time again.
You could easily develop animosity
towards women or develop a very bad
association with the opposite sex.
You see that from women.
There's a lot of women that I know that
have real issues with men and they're
very unattractive and they'll say really
gross generalizing things about men.
They will make these grown.
Men are this and men suck and men aren't
funny and men aren't this,
and men are that,
and then you look at them and you're
like,
oh,
well,
you're obese.
You're.
You're unattractive and your experiences
with men have probably largely been of
rejection and pad things on top of all
the realities of what men are capable of
and the horrible things that meant
absolutely do no denying that,
but to have this gross generalizations
about an entire gender based on what
well,
a lot of it is based on their own life
experiences.
Meanwhile,
you go to some really attractive girls.
Go to,
you know,
fill in the blank.
Some really attractive girl who's always
had men hit on her.
She might be,
oh,
men are gross.
Men are discussing.
I'm just waiting for the right guy.
She's not lumping all men into this
group,
but many women that are unattractive and
had a hard time with men have the same
response towards men that many
unattractive men have towards women.
It's a real.
It's a fucking hard roll the dice to be
born in a way that just without any
doing of your own,
completely outside of your control,
you're just not sexually attractive to
the opposite sex.
So,
you know what?
I didn't realize that men had this kind
of anger towards women.
Uh,
I didn't realize men,
women had it towards him and like,
but porn a want,
it turns me off a lot.
Most of it is like this anger,
slap and forcing and jamming the COC and
the on your ear and all this and
speeding in there.
I'm like,
what the fuck is going on?
So this is,
I don't know what that is.
I,
I like when I have sex,
I like to please a woman,
you know,
I like her to be happy and comfortable
and I don't,
that whole ain't.
So that's when I realized,
oh,
there's a bunch of fucking dudes who
hate women and angry and they get off.
I'm like,
humiliating them.
Like I don't get off on that.
Yeah,
there's definitely that.
There's,
you know,
I had a friend and he was an
unattractive Gar and watched him go from
being sort of having these idealistic
ideas about the one guy.
One day he's going like he had a
girlfriend at the time and turned his
girlfriend was cheating on him and then
he had other girls and they were trying
to get his money and then he just became
this bitter fucking God.
Like over the time that I knew him.
He just became a woman hater.
I mean straight up woman hater.
You'd hit on girls and they would turn
them down like fucking dykes.
He just be angry,
like angry at women like he associated.
And I watched it from afar.
He associated women with negative
feelings.
You associate them with rejection.
He associated them callousness that they
and I,
and I have a friend who's overweight and
she feels like that about men.
Sometimes men are shit and you know
they're insulting and they're this and
that.
Like some,
some are,
yes.
Some people are terrible.
Some males and females that terrible
one.
When you're picking,
I'm on team penis and you're on team
vagina.
We've all lost because you're crazy.
You're what?
You're going to align yourself with 150
million people that you.
How many do you know?
Do you know?
A hundred and 50 of those 150 million
people because that's a lot.
You know,
you probably don't even know 100.
You don't probably don't even have an
intimate relationship with 150 men,
so you're going to lump all $150 million
to the same group that you're against an
150 million women into the group that
you're with.
That's crazy.
We're humans.
We're supposed to be on team human and
we're supposed to all figure out how to
get along.
But along the way we're trying to find
mates and we're trying to find
companionship and the.
The reality of that is it is a messy
proposition and some people get left out
and some people get shoved aside and
some people get attacked and some people
get diminished and some people feel
terrible about the experience and some
people aren't good at it and some people
are better at it than others and some
people use money and influence and some
people use their looks and the whole
thing is just.
It's not perfect.
This is not some egalitarianism venture.
So I,
I never watched sex and the city,
but my wife did good for you and she
good for you.
She talks.
I watched it once because Brian Callahan
was on.
I was like,
Jesus,
it's definitely a show for women.
Wait a minute,
what are you saying?
Sexist God.
But my wife says about that show because
it was on her when she's watching.
She's like,
you know,
these women all got laid and it was all
about them wanting to get laid and they
had resiliency and they weren't
snowflakes and they were.
And these
women could fucking run in heels and you
know,
all this.
They were,
they had grit.
Right?
And she's like,
well,
she doesn't feel that that's what's
happening today.
Well,
there's certainly no role models like
that.
But you know,
what's really interesting,
Sarah,
Jessica Parker and Kim control fucking
hated each other.
No kidding.
There was a thing to yesterday with Kim.
Katrina St.
she's not my friend.
She's never been,
I don't want your sympathy because Kim
controls was her brother died.
Someone in her family died and she sends
her best wishes and,
and she's like,
she's not my French.
Never been my friend.
I don't like her.
And apparently they were just.
Yeah.
And she said she's a shitty person.
And she said all this stuff about it.
Like right after my brother died,
I was like,
Jesus.
Wow.
What thought it was her brother?
Yeah.
Like the whole thing.
It's just like,
oh,
so this whole thing about this comradery
in this union of women all together and
fighting against not horseshit.
Yeah.
Horseshit people hate each other.
It's like the Rock and tie,
reese and fast and the furious.
They didn't really like each other.
It's a scam.
That's fascinating.
She's married to that.
Matthew Broderick,
right?
Yeah.
He was.
Okay.
Yeah.
I don't follow that stuff,
but whatever.
Uh,
that's a good point.
I think my wife made.
Yeah,
it was a good point that women with
grit.
Yeah.
I mean you don't get.
What were the role models that you have?
The kardashians.
You have sex in the city.
I mean,
I'm a.
What does that on housewives?
Real housewives.
How to Kim Kardashian and get famous
sucking Dick.
It was a.
It was a porn tape,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
She released a sex tape that was
apparently was engineered by her family.
That's what I heard too.
Crazy.
But it's not.
If you see what that lady's done,
like how she's organized it.
Look.
And it's been very successful.
She had a plan.
Yeah.
If you look at it in terms of a
financial venture,
oh my God.
A windfall.
It's unbelievable.
Believable.
Amazingly successful,
but chaos.
And in a sense they're a type of a
royalty in lot of ways.
Modern plastic royalty.
Yes.
It's the culture of nothing.
Yeah.
Culture of fake asses and nonsense.
But yeah,
they're talented.
I'm sure.
No,
no,
the talented at doing that.
I mean,
it's not a talent,
but it's a,
they've been wise strategically and
keeping themselves out in the public.
I mean,
I don't,
I'm not.
Uh,
uh,
I don't.
I'm not a Kim Kardashians.
The kardashians family hater by any
stretch of the imagination.
I've had a couple of bits about them or
kind of mocked them,
but,
uh,
I don't hate them.
I mean,
I don't think wrong with what they're
doing.
I know a lot of people that are way
dumber than them that I don't hate.
Why does she hate them?
Because they're famous.
Like that doesn't make any sense.
No,
I don't hate them at all.
I mean,
I don't even know them or watch their
shows.
I think Kim is really pretty.
Um,
but uh,
I just think what it says about the
culture,
right?
So that makes you like,
it reminds you,
hey,
your culture is vapid.
Yeah.
Well,
part of our culture is that,
and I think they came along at an
amazing time,
the time of social media where it's just
all about likes and blood pictures that
have been doctored up by photoshop and
the whole thing is really fascinating.
And then,
you know,
the father is like,
well,
I'm not getting enough attention as a
guy,
fuck that.
I'm going to be a check.
And then he gets amazing amounts of
attention.
I mean,
it's,
you could say that I'm being callous and
that's what happened.
That's what happened.
And that's so funny.
I never thought of it like 100 percent.
He's a male.
Kardashians.
That's an amazing way to look at it.
I had a bit about it in my last special,
my,
my last best.
Did you get in trouble?
No,
I didn't.
I covered all my bases,
but it was basically about it.
I can't do the bit,
but I'll tell you.
I'll tell you about it afterwards.
People that eats on triggered on
Netflix.
Go Watch it fuckers.
Okay.
Let's wrap this up.
Do you mean.
Okay,
let's right.
Listen man,
I'm glad we finally got a chance to do
this.
This is really fun.
Yeah,
this was great.
I'm really glad you invited me and so
more often a big fan of your comedy.
I would love to do it again and I hope
hopefully if you could ever come out to
Pasadena.
Mom,
listen,
I'm out in passing all the time,
so let's make it happen.
I will do Jimmy Dore,
ladies and gentleman,
Jimmy underscore door on twitter.
You got to instagram or no?
No.
Good for you.
Fucking know he doesn't need it.
Great fruit and your face.
Everything by everybody.