The Joe Rogan experience
was a bad motherfucker.
Very bad motherfucker.
He barely made any lemons.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean,
think about the shitty movies I,
Paul Newman made.
I really can't.
I can't come up with one.
You know,
I can't come up with.
I'm not familiar enough
with his entire catalog.
I remember stallone did the
comedy movie with his mother.
Oh,
it was a throw momma from the train.
Was that it was another one?
No,
no,
no.
This was um,
what was it called?
A.
This is going to drive me fucking nuts.
I'm.
Oh,
it wasn't at the same woman that was in
golden girls that played the old woman,
but she had brown hair.
Oh,
this is going to drive me nuts.
I don't know your Old Lady Trivia.
How do you know that?
I don't know.
It seems like I remember it.
Well.
Let's just look up.
Still owns the loan listening
Oscar.
It was,
it was asking.
Oscar was one.
Let's see.
That's the one that I'm thinking of.
Yeah.
Well he definitely had one called Oscar.
That's the one I was thinking you were
thinking fuckers done mama from the
train,
but it wasn't thermometer from
trying to throw my of a train.
Was that old gross lady from like
goonies or something like that?
Oh,
the fatality.
My mom will shoot stop where my mom was.
So he did two comedies in a row.
He did Oscar and then he did
stop or my mom will shoot.
That's how retarded people
were in the nineties though.
Like you know what?
Forget all these great comedians we have.
We need to get the loan up there.
They just kept giving them money.
My Old Lady Trivia,
look at this.
It was the old lady Estelle Getty
from older girls with brown hair.
That's so crazy.
And look at him.
He's like,
I can't believe.
What are you doing with that gun
for a second?
Look at the look on his face,
man.
Can't believe this.
Look a little my gun it or
has it been confirmed and or,
or like,
like completely confirmed that he
actually started out doing porn is because
that's.
Yeah,
he did a movie and it
wasn't like it was softcore.
Yeah,
so he wasn't like laying
pipe on film or anything,
so it might've been,
might've been laying pipe,
but I'm pretty sure they
didn't show it if he was,
I think it was like an angle thing and
they wanted to sell it to them for a
million dollars.
It was like,
it wouldn't give you 10
sensitive business shifts.
Budget.
Yeah.
Well that's that same thing man.
That's that thing of like wanting to win.
Like I was.
I went to eat dinner at this bar and I
was sitting next to this lady and you
know,
like sometimes you're sitting next to
somebody and you can tell they have some.
They,
they,
they're,
they're having a problem
in life or something.
You,
you either kind of looking for help.
Sometimes you get around people
and you can just feel it.
They,
they're lost or they want something and
like I'm just sitting there eating and
she starts talking to me.
Right.
And then right away she's goes into
talking about how her sister was getting
married and her sister invited her up
to big Sur to go to the wedding and got
there.
And there was nowhere
to stay and her sister,
her steps or her sister in law is a bitch.
That was the story she was telling.
But when you're looking at
someone who's like caught,
that's just one little piece
of the puzzle for them.
They're locked into this
world view of fighting.
They're constantly on the offensive
trying to like poke back at the world and
that's the one little symbol
of the thing that she could,
she could give me.
But then she said something shitty to
the bartender and then she like said
something shitty to somebody else.
You realize like,
oh,
this person just going through the world
trying to shake every living part of
the world.
She wants to cut and Shank and hurt.
She's shut down.
But inside of her,
because that's what I recognize.
I'm like,
shit,
this is like an.
Sometimes the cruelest sort of person
is someone who started off trying to be
nice and then got shut down
for being nice sometimes.
Yeah.
And I could see all this
used to be a very sweet,
nice person.
So I said to her,
you know what?
You should start doing,
you should start doing service work
or missionary work and she's like,
I used to do that.
I spent years doing that and she was,
it was like I could see that part of her,
you know,
and then I could see she thought that
by doing good things in the world,
she should get some reward for it,
but instead of getting a reward for it,
she got hurt,
whatever it was that happened during
the course of her serving the universe,
she got less of what she wanted or didn't
get what she expected and because of
that,
she's like,
fuck it,
I'm going to be a bitch from now on
because I tried to be good and I got
punished for it.
My wife has a friend that's
religious and her and her friend,
her and this other friend were going to.
This woman in her other friend were going
to get like a real estate license and
she didn't get it and she passed.
She failed her test,
but her friend passed and she was
complaining about it and the what she was
complaining about.
She goes,
I don't get it.
I'm a good person.
Yes,
why didn't?
Why didn't God hook me up with this?
And she literally said that.
That's it right there.
See,
that is the great fallacy of being a
good person is the moment you start doing
it,
being a good person,
as a job,
and you're supposed to get these fortune
paychecks from the universe in the form
of luck or good things coming to you.
That's the moment you fail.
You fail.
You really have to resign yourself to
the idea that mostly if you're being nice
to people,
they're going to hurt you.
First of all,
there's an unbelievable amount of pressure
as an artist after not having a show
in four years to,
you know,
every time I do a show I want it to be
the best show I've ever done and this was
like such a small amount of time to
put that much art together that I was,
you know,
everyone's like,
you fucking bitches in Mexico.
I'm like,
I'm working.
I'm not.
I didn't go to Mexico to fuck you know,
but you have a very strange way of,
fuck.
How do I say it's very bold.
Oh really?
It's like bravado to it.
Like you're wearing a cape.
I didn't go to Mexico to like,
you're confident way saying,
fuck,
why do I,
what do I like to do?
Fuck.
Just like,
it's like you're almost
defiant in your tone.
So I got to tell you what happened.
I,
uh,
you know,
because every.
I'm going to go off subject just
for a second because no way.
Every time on the show,
every time I think,
wow,
I've experienced a new sexual
thing that I've never like,
this is insane.
Like how many are left when
a girl's shoots the ice cube?
My butthole or,
or,
you know,
like,
or like when I'm laying down and then
like five women or just giving me a
massage,
just using their tongues.
I'm like five.
It's not going to get better than this.
You know,
like this is like,
he doesn't like a baller.
Damn.
I didn't even know who it
went to over two handed.
I thought it just stopped there.
You'd have five.
And then.
So I meet a guy yesterday and he's like,
Oh yeah,
we did some red rope
shit and this and that,
and I'm like,
I'm like,
I don't,
I don't know what that is,
is like you don't know
what a red rope services.
And I go,
no,
but please tell me like,
what the fuck are you
talking about right now?
My name is Marty and I'm the
inventor of the red rope service.
So honestly sitting there.
Okay.
So you're laying on your
bitsa massage parlor.
You Go,
it's a service.
It's not the name of a place,
like a code word you can we get.
Can I get the red rope?
Okay.
So you're getting a massage and I think
it's only an Asia and you're laying on
your back and then you go,
you know,
you get the,
you get to the happy ending point where
she gets her dick hard and everything
and you're like,
I would like the red rope at this point.
She ties a rope and here's the crazy part.
It doesn't have to be read,
it's just the rope and they
tie it to the whatever.
The bars above the massage table and
they hook their feet on it so they're
upside down and so they start spinning
around and then they put their mouth on
your hard Dick and then they let go and
they helicopter their mouth around your
Dick all the way.
And I'd never done it before,
but the guy says it feels like
your Dick's going to like,
you've never felt anything
like that before in your life.
And it feels like your Dick is
just going to explode with a,
you know,
like a neutron bomb,
the explosion and then you.
And then it's done and it stops.
And then it spins the other way
around to listen to the crafty.
Always unbelievable because they,
they really like take
sex to another level.
Like they try to figure out the most
pleasurable things to do to you and then
they do them.
You know,
you're a fucking human being.