Hello Freak bitches.
I think we will become incredibly
annoying spammers of ourselves.
That's what we're going to do.
We're going to be able to download
ourselves.
Then we're just going to fucking shoot
ourselves in the bit torrent and mega
upload.
We're going to put ourselves everywhere.
Like I want to go everywhere.
I want to go to fucking Europe,
I want to be in Turkey and there'd be
doubles and triples of people all
throughout the the this,
this artificial world that we've created
of hyperspace.
We're going to have like a hyper space
cloud drive of humanity that's going to
be just as fucking crowded as earth and
we're going to go shit,
we don't have enough hard drive space
and the fucking cloud and these assholes
keep copying themselves cause they want
to be a mortal.
So like rich guys would have like a
cloud serve reflect 200 trillion
terabytes and it would just be filled
with copies of themselves and then they
would just send out fucking like fake
emails.
Click here to see some Dick.
Whoa,
I want to see some Dick.
And you click that,
boom.
He,
it's an exploit.
It gets into your server.
Bang.
Makes copies of himself everywhere.
Yeah.
You'll be able to like get Joe Rogan in
your cars.
Your car has your brain in all your,
your past and all your memories,
but your cars talking to you and it's
due.
It's like you're my bro.
Imagine if they figure out a way to not
just download your consciousness but
take parts out you don't need.
Yeah.
Like take parts out that you don't need,
like your ego.
Take the ego out and have,
have this consciousness be completely
compliant.
We figured out a way to isolate the ego.
We're going to remove it and we're going
to put this brain in cars so he get in
your car and you're talking to you,
but you don't have your own ego.
We go,
hey man,
I fucking,
I want to have a say or where we drive.
You can't have that shit coming out of
your car like your car has to be
completely compliant.
Right.
That's how I drive.
I don't,
I don't take advice from my fucking car.
I'm driving bitch relaxed.
But if you could download your
consciousness,
your own conscious in your car,
your car would be literally an extension
of you.
And the car thinks it's you.
Yeah,
it's card.
Totally thinks it's you.
I can't see.
Well the card,
the card knows that you and it or one.
And then when you're together you're the
same.
But his,
his legs place in life is to be your
car.
It's so fucked up.
And you can start downloading you and
everything so you could download you in
the toilet microwave.
You just have little Joe Rogan.
Like who thinks it's a real person?
Yeah,
we'll get invaded.
You would get like,
someone would break your door to obtain
Dong.
You open the door a million bill burrs
compiling your house.
There's someone decided to just copy
bill burr and put all the bill birth
files out into the Internet.
You have to kill them all because you
don't want to a bunch of bill burrs
talking all day.
So you have to be like,
I'm sorry,
Bill Byrd,
toaster.
Well going to kill you.
And they would be like,
wolves.
They're really
cool.
But you have to control the numbers.
You know
that many of any of us,
imagine if there's 100 million Jamie
vernors you would go listen dude enough,
it's too many of you fuckers.
If people don't think about that shit
man,
if it's possible to download
consciousness is possible to copy it.
If it's possible to copy it,
it's possible.
Spam it.
In that sense,
your history is really kind of fucked up
and weird when you,
if you approach it with them through a
moral lens because you see so many nasty
seeing steck place and in the weird ones
are the ones where there really is no
good solution where you don't know what
the healthy thing would be like.
There's one that I was researching flora
and he's three on fire maybe a year from
now or something.
I was he searching the story from the
1980 [inaudible] in El Salvador.
At that time there was a right wing
government in El Salvador.
De was government was supporting and
there was a leftist Galleria.
There was in the logic of the Cold War,
there are only two options.
You're read pro communist story.
Our [inaudible].
There's nothing in between,
right?
So in the process of fighting is left is
gonorrhea.
The government of El Salvador is doing
nasty sayings,
right?
Anybody will criticize them,
doesn't matter whether they are
communist or not.
Get tortured to death,
chop off their bodies.
We'll leave them in the middle of the
street.
American Congress at that point,
cause I go,
shit,
you know it can't really keep sending
millions of dollars to,
these guys were doing horrible human
rights violations.
So they passed these low that in order
for any more aid to be sent to the
governor of El Salvador,
the president of the United States,
to sign off on a document stating that
these guys have made huge improvements
in their human rights record,
that they're on the right path.
You know it's getting better.
Problem is the deadline is coming up
that Reagan is each into be able to send
out all these millions of dollars to do
the government of El Salvador.
And in the moment a Salvadorian army
cous on these offensive against the
Galleria.
They find some villages that chest
wanted to be left the fuck alone.
They were not pro communist,
but they are not anticommunist either.
They were like bunch of Evangelical
Christianity peasants who just wanted to
farm their fields and be left alone.
So he,
they would lead the communist,
go through,
they will add the army,
go through a figure.
If we stay neutral,
everything works out right.
While not in the core door and the Cold
War,
there is no neutrality are either on one
side or the other.
So Salvadorian army come in and grab
every single villagers,
separate demand from the women keelhaul
demand or April.
The women don't kill them all,
kill everybody in that village and New
York Times.
The New York Times did an article on it
and um,
and uh,
Reagan was like,
Oh shit,
what do I do now?
So he said,
the guy who wrote this article is some
crazy communists.
None of these is through.
It's a smear campaign against our
allies.
The government of El Salvador has made
huge improvements.
I'm sending the millions of dollars of
course,
years down the road or south of the
original story.
It was through that the staff did that
pen and but other than bitching about
Reagan,
this is not even an anti Reagan thing is
that it's a messy situation because you
do support the government of El
Salvador.
He are literally supporting death
squads,
child rapists.
I mean it doesn't really get any worse
than that.
You don't support them.
There's a chance that so hard when the
recruiter turn into a communist state,
in which case he's not exactly what
communism around the world as a high
reputation for human rights.
It's fucking awful.
Right.
So he's like,
what do you choose?
You know the,
you choose to support them or do you
choose?
It's like how do you see where I'm
going?
Like it's a situation where no matter
what you choose,
you're fucked.
You're doing bad things.
But clearly the moment you're supporting
that squads,
that cannot be the right solution.
Not that,
but at the same time,
what is the right solution?
What is there good thing you should do?
You know Carter at the same exact
proper,
you know right before Reagan Carter,
some guide yard,
she'd be shipped off El Salvador.
This guy,
Oscar Romero,
San Te maillet there,
saints top fucking sandy money to my
government because they are doing
horrible syncs with it cart.
I was like,
Eh,
I don't want to look at this because
this is politically traveling for me.
So two weeks later that's squats walking
into the main church in El Salvador.
This guy was celebrating mass.
They gunned him down,
kill them.
So it's not a Republican or democratic
thing,
you know it's like both sides of the
game.
They are did not know how to handle this
in a situation where it's like which
mass murders do we support and which
ones do we oppose?
Cause that's the reality of it.
It was like there are the stories or
like what?
What
the fuck do you do?
Yeah,
I would imagine and probably last a long
ass time too long time.
It's a long day at the beach.
It was probably a couple solid hours of
visions then right?
With that kind of dose.
Yeah.
On and off.
There were some,
yeah,
there.
I kept seeing initially I kept seeing a
like this,
like a group of people like Kinda
eyeball on us.
I was thinking like,
I think it is take our shit.
Like are they going to try to steal or
am I going to have to fight someone?
Like this doesn't,
this is weird and this is a place not a
lot of people go to.
And I kept seeing that and then I had to
take a deep breath,
like Tosca,
like feel me,
you know,
feel like my energy.
She could feel what's going on.
She's like,
are you okay?
I'm like,
ah,
somebody kind of come.
It's like,
no,
what are you,
what are you talking about?
And she's like,
planes,
fucking sea turtle bugs and shit,
whatever.
You know,
like she's just,
she doesn't have it,
you know,
and she's looking over at me and am I
okay?
And she's like,
seriously,
you're fine,
don't worry,
you're fine.
I was like,
okay.
And I put my head back down and I kept
seeing it done.
Like this young kid kind of comes
through the crowd,
like he's going to challenge me and he
walks down.
I'm like,
Oh fuck,
I got to defend us.
I've got to fight and I know how fucked
up I am.
I can't believe we have to defend
myself.
And I'm like,
it's playing out in my mind all the ways
that I'm going to have to fight this
guy.
And I realized right then like I stand
up open.
My was like,
oh fuck,
it's just a vision.
And I was like,
Heart's racing.
I'm like,
why would I think that?
And then I realized every fucking day of
my life since I was a little kid,
I play that out.
Anytime someone gives me a dirty look or
says like we're from whatever being
picked on as a kid bully,
they can a shit.
Like I always play that out.
Like how am I going?
Am I going to have to fight this guy?
Am I going to have to fucking defend?
How's it gonna play out?
Oh,
he's,
he's got a long fucking neck.
I'm going to take us back and choke him
out.
Whatever.
You know what I'm saying?
But,
but it just showed me how silly this
dumb ass mind game that I would play and
I would go down the rabbit hole on a
fucking daily basis sometimes.
Like,
like just playing into this thought of
negativity that had no space for me.
And it doesn't mean no good to play that
out.
Like,
well that's fine cause then I'll do
this.
No,
no,
none of that shit.
I'm wasting time and becoming
emotionally attached to those thoughts.
It's not just,
Oh,
I'm thinking about this.
I'm feeling like I'm going to fight
right now.
That fucks you up.
That turns you into not your best
version of yourself.
So that vision from mushrooms was just a
fucking game changer.
It doesn't stop me from having those
thoughts,
but it allows me to catch myself.
I'm aware of it.
Okay.