Is when they walk in.
Alright.
We are live.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast.
Yes.
Oops,
that's me.
I'm the one that he has to turn off his
phone.
Oh,
you have to turn off your volume,
John,
on your computer and your computer
computer and your computer.
If you hear the delay.
John,
let's flip down the volume.
So there we go.
Okay.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the flashlight.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net,
click on the link for the fleshlight and
enter in the code name Rogan.
You will save yourself 50 percent off
the number one sex toys for men either.
Yeah.
Can you hear us?
John John Speakers and he.
John Anthony West is trying to figure
out his phone.
Please.
Did we lose the skype connection?
Huh?
Did we lose a skype connection with him?
Yeah,
but he's not a.
He doesn't hear us.
Hey.
No one I.
something is.
Yeah,
he turns the volume off on his computer.
Were you listening to us through your
computer?
Through your phone?
You need to turn the volume off on
ustream page.
So there should be on the,
if you're looking at Ustream,
there should be a mute button on the
actual video that you're watching.
What I'm guessing is is that you are
using a skype phone and so when you
muted your computer it probably needs
everything.
Oh,
that makes sense.
There you go.
So sir,
if you see the lower right hand corner
of the video,
we're under under the words Joe Rogan
experience.
The lower right hand corner is like a
little volume icon.
If you just killed that,
that should fix everything.
Corner low,
lower,
lower right hand corner of the window.
The video window window.
The video window is this thing that
literally circling thing and there's the
uh,
there's like there should be a volume
button on your left.
Yes.
The far left.
Yeah.
Just kill it and just turn off the
volume.
I did that.
There you go.
Beautiful.
Hi,
John Anthony West Egypt tologist genius,
and doesn't,
doesn't know too much about ustream.
Very limited genius.
We got one more commercial side and then
we'll just get cracking.
Our podcast is also brought to you by,
I think we have a little delay as a bit
of delay.
We're going to get this worked out.
Our podcast is also brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com.
That's o n n I,
t,
makers of Alpha brain,
new mood,
shroom,
tech sport,
True Tech Immune,
and we do have kettlebells coming very
soon.
Some people have already started
ordering them because they've gotten to
the website already,
but we're getting all the details worked
out as about shipping and things along
that nature and the hemp powder.
Hemp protein powder is coming out soon
as well,
so go check out all that on [inaudible]
dot com.
Use the code named Brogan.
Save yourself 10 percent off.
If you have any questions about any of
this stuff,
go to [inaudible] dot com and it will
all be answered.
All right,
hit the music.
Brian.
We're going to start this bitch
experience Joe Rogan podcast.
This ladies and gentlemen is a very,
very special edition of the Joe Rogan
experience.
First of all,
because the first one we've ever done
through skype and a two because it is
with one of my personal heroes that I'm
honored to get to talk to a man named
John Anthony West.
John is an egyptologist,
uh,
of,
you know,
somebody on twitter had a very great
comment about.
You said that you're more of a proof
reader for history.
It's more,
you're more than an egyptologist.
Okay.
I'm done.
School,
depending on my audience,
I sometimes call myself a rogue
egyptologist,
a rogue egyptologist.
And if you folks who aren't seeing
online,
if you're listening to this,
only on Itunes,
John has an office that is exactly what
I would hope and pray his office would
look like,
just filled with documents and
information and books.
And it's crazy,
man.
Look at all that information behind you.
You look like a mad scientist.
You look like Alex Jones,
this car.
Yeah.
You're,
you're a mad scientist,
sir.
People have called me that.
Yes.
I first was turned onto your work by the
NBC special on the Sphinx that was
hosted by Charlton Heston,
which was a very controversial thing
that NBC aired right,
and it was a special on the mysteries of
the dating of the Sphinx and became
absolutely fascinated by the compelling
evidence that you and Dr.
Schoch presented to all these
traditional egyptologists that the rain
erosion on this function closure had to
have come from literally the seven or
8,000
years earlier than they were predated
than they were dating this finks
yeah,
probably more than that Gel and we'll
get into that if we want to discuss it
further,
but that's the.
That was the most conservative date.
That shock as a,
you know,
as a bonafide phd geologist.
He's sort of constrained to take the
most conservative view,
but even had doubts about it when he was
saying it,
but now he's,
he's loosening up by a lot and it's
basically on,
on the same car as me.
In other words,
holding open the possibility that it may
be as old as actually as $36,000
bc or even older.
And the reason for that is not Santa
sizing or anything of the sort of stuff.
The Egyptians themselves in several in
London,
in a tablet,
a stele coal,
the Palermo stone because not because it
has anything to do with land,
but because that's where it is.
And another virus,
very fragmentary,
called the turn for Paris,
where the Egyptians themselves,
ancient Egyptians talk about long
periods prior to the beginning of what
we call dynastic Egypt,
Egypt,
that begins around 3,500
BC where Egypt is room for thousands and
thousands and thousands of years like
the natural,
which means the gods themselves,
which actually means I take to mean
enlightened or divinely enlightened
human beings.
And then another long,
long period where Egypt is ruled by the
ship so far,
which means the companions or the
followers of forest and the retinal that
the names of these kings are given and
the dates of these kings are given them
dope boats.
The stone is damaged on the powers and
somewhat fragmentary.
If you compute the years,
you end up with something like 36,000
BC,
which in fact is not.
There's not a casually chosen date
because the Sphinx itself,
as you know,
the going to actually as we go along
somewhere along the line to talk about
this,
because I can send you all kinds of
interesting texts,
illustrations where maybe you can on
your end,
I'm intersperse them into collate them
into the actual video broadcast,
I guess you'd call it so that viewers
can see what we're talking about as
we're talking about it.
Anyway,
if you can do that.
Greg bootcamp.
Yeah,
no,
we can.
We can definitely do that,
but for the audio only people.
This is a fascinating conversation
either way with or without pictures.
How did you get on this path?
How did you.
It just.
I'll tell you in two seconds,
but first,
let me just say the reason why the city
$6,000
date is not as outrageous as it might
sound is a because the Egyptians
themselves are talking about that sort
of date and also because the strengths
with this lion's body and human head
screams out as an astronomical
astrological marker and the it's meant
to commemorate the age of Leo.
The last age of Leo is where the links
in the relationship is that the Sphinx
is cited so that it looks duties and so
the last time the Sphinx looked at its
own image in the sky before the sun
rose.
That's other.
Talk about the processional ages.
If you want to get into that,
we can.
It's not complex astronomy,
but it's astronomy.
Anyway.
The last time the strengths looked at
its own image in the sky,
but at sunrise on the spring,
Equinox would have been about 10,000,
10,500
BC.
There are good reasons why 10,500
BC is not satisfactory and the the the
age before that,
the age of Leo before that is another
26,000
deals earlier.
It's the cycles,
so called procession of the economic
cycle takes 20 roughly 20,
26,000
years,
so 36,000
years would have been another time when
this links looked at its at its own
image in the sky.
I brought up the spring equinox,
so there are reasons.
I mean,
as I said,
it's,
it's not just fantasizing,
it's backed up,
it's conjectural.
Of course we can improve it as at the
moment,
but there are good reasons why it could
be as old as that
conventional wisdom is that human
civilization and the,
you know,
in the form of cities and such that,
that didn't exist before 10,000
years ago.
Right.
Well,
it was conventional wisdom until very
recently.
It's one of the battles that we've had.
We've had to fight.
But you see long story,
Shaka and I are writing a book.
I'll tell you more about this as we go
along,
telling the story of this whole strength
thing because we presented.
This is a geological argument.
Um,
it's about the water,
weathering to the sprinkle the
weathering to the sex with shock as a
geologist in the specialist in these
things.
It took a lot,
a lot to get him on board.
Mind you,
this is a long.
It's a big,
long,
funny story.
I won't get into necessarily right now
here though,
since we have an open ended,
we have an open end show and I have
plenty of block in the freezer and we
might go on for quite awhile.
But anyway,
the,
the point is that it's a geological
argument.
And when I got shocked on board,
he took him awhile before he
acknowledged that it had to be correct.
I mean,
he was putting scene for me to be a
heretic is easy.
I don't give a damn.
I mean I don't like these people and I
don't respect their intelligence or
their integrity.
So,
and I have nothing to lose,
you know,
shock as a tenured associate professor
of geology at Boston University.
So he has,
he puts his neck on the line.
That means something eventually took a
bit of dual.
Anybody he did it.
And then we presented this evidence
first at the,
at the,
you might call it the super bowl
geology.
It's called the,
um,
the,
the annual meeting of the Geological
Society of America.
This was in 1991.
We were the stars of the show.
I mean,
they recognize the deal,
logical society recognize that this was
a dynamite presentation.
And so all the precedents,
they have the science for us at the
girls and so on.
And it was that,
that actually allowed us to get this
thing passed secretary is it NBC and
then put it out in prime time with
sweeps week and the 1 million man it was
nominated for best documentary of that
year,
etc.
Etc.
So it was that,
that brought it to the florist,
the crack academics to pay attention to
it.
And I'm,
thE battle has been going on ever since.
And actually funny story because I can
say it here,
but normally I can't.
Then I'm on a,
on a,
on a normal reSpectable deliveries yet
I've watched a couple of years shows I
know I can get away with it here.
And we,
when we gave this presentation initially
in 1991,
the,
the geologists were unanimously in favor
of it.
They came to our presentation,
they walked to our display and they
said,
yeah,
you know,
I mean,
how could anybody have the most as well
as another bit of the story,
but so.
But the egyptologist and the
archaeologist absolutely incensed by the
whole thing.
And they were calling us all kinds of
names and there was one woman who will
go nameless here,
but so coming up in a book somewhere.
So who is a,
an,
an egyptologist at boston university was
shocked potentials and oh yeah,
I'm earlier.
So we were being interviewed chunk and
myself.
I'm black,
the world press really.
And so this is 1991 and at one point we
were being interviewed by the guy who
was the science editor of the boston
globe and shock teachers in boston.
So it means a hometown boy.
And so shop gave his,
his interview and chalk is that we're
good.
We're a good duo.
It's exactly good cop,
bad cop,
but no shockers,
always civil and bill.
Always professional and always polite.
Really even when it shouldn't have to
worry about these things.
I can say whatever.
Write down please.
So I guess name the channel with the
science editor of.
We should explain before we go any
further,
we should explain the argument for
people that don't understand it.
The,
the water erosion argument.
This is what people are trying to
ignore.
Um,
there's,
there's people that are still arguing
that somehow or another that could have
been created by sand and wind and that
this erosion,
um,
according to most geologists,
that's not the case.
Most geologists are stating that it had
to be water correctly.
That's correct.
But now they've,
now they've actually gone off the sand
and wind thing and now it's supposed to
be what's called salt crystallization in
which the water water soaks through the
limestone and creates chemical reactions
with the rock and that weather is off
and creates the weathering that we say.
This is actually a nonsensical argument
which we will be addressing very
shortly.
I'll take that
and there's an incredible amount of
resistance to this idea.
Even though the geological science there
are,
they in agreement on this,
almost most
of them.
There were a few who aren't,
and I'll get into this too as we go
along.
It saved the point.
What's at stake here was not,
this is not,
this is not just a scholarly quibbled
because for the strings to be watered,
whether then specifically by rainwater
means that it has to have been there
when it was raining needs for you.
See,
there's almost no rain there now an inch
or so a year,
the sahara desert formed around 10,000.
They sAy before ground was fertIle
savannah,
sort of like modern day kenyon,
maybe even wetter than that.
So for the swings to be weathered by,
by,
by rainwater means means that it has to
have been there before,
before or during the time that lots and
lots of rain was swelling.
Now what's at stake there?
When you were saying before the
civilization,
according to the standard scenario,
civilization begins around 3000,
3,500
bc,
more or less simultaneously in Egypt in
scenario in China and India,
but all of it is around that day,
but the strengths you see as really as
the most spectacular sculpture on earth,
it's 240 feet long and 66 feet high and
it's a magnificent,
absolutely breathtaking sculpture even
in ruins and the temples around it,
which we'll get into somewhere along the
line,
but ideally I'll send you pictures of
it.
The temples around them are powerful
stone limestone buildings faced with
granted,
but what's interesting about them is not
the size of the templates themselves by
egyptian standards metal that big,
but the stones that they're better that
comprise them weigh somewhere between 50
and 150 pounds each and the setup in
such a way that slotted into places into
place like pieces of a jigsaw puzzle.
We can't do that today.
Do you still have the old,
the charlton heston video?
It's evident evidently have seen we have
this guy jesse water and lose the
project manager of when they're building
a cogeneration plant out in long island
and he's acknowledging he's fascinated
by this because he says,
yeah,
our biggest cranes are biggest landing
bags.
PAins could lift these rocks,
but we wouldn't know how to rig them so
that we could get them into place.
So this means is that not just at the
snakes is fabulous.
Statute is much,
much older.
It was built before this supposed to be
any civilization at all,
but it means that there's a technology
in place that we,
with our brilliant science,
have produced hydrogen bombs and labile
had donald's and nerve gas in mobile.
These wonderful new developments.
We couldn't build the temples around
swings,
so that's why they're all so incensed
that absolutely.
The whole idea is we.
If this is finally acknowledged,
that means that everything,
that everything that these people have
believed about ancient,
about the onset of human cIvilization is
completely dead wrong.
so that that's why.
That's why there is angry as they are in
the air force sent because a good line
to the flack is always happiest when
you're right over the target.
You know,
one of the things I learned from
watching your documentary is I really
thought that scientists and people that
were studying the history of something
as important as Egypt that they would
be.
We'll just leave that sound on brian.
Hey,
I guess john,
you have a fan going on in the
background.
Is that your computer fan?
Yeah.
That's thing
anyway,
how you would think that these people
would be scientific in their approach to
evidence.
When you guys presented thIs evidence
that there was massive amounts of water
erosion.
The one of the things the guy said that
really disturbed me is like,
you're talking about a civilization from
10,500
years.
He was mocking.
He was saying,
where's The evidence of thIs
civilization?
Like what at?
What other evidence do you have of this
civilization?
And it's the way he sang.
It is so ridiculous and arrogant and it
was so.
There was.
It was so soaked in ego because the
reality is we don't really know how much
evidence there would be left from 10,500
bc.
That is a long,
long,
long time ago and it might very well be
that the only things that remain are
things like this face and this function
closure.
Well,
there's.
There's a good reason for that to
actually shaka and I are about to set
off on on a new book between us called
dancing down the breeds of syrah and
then the subtitle is a scholar and the
scientists send gloss the unicorns and
take on the paradigm police because the
printers that a sufi and it's.
You know,
it's so busy.
That's the mystical aspect of islam and
there's a metric.
It's a metaphor and sufi doctrine and in
order to get to the truth,
in order to get to enlightenment on the.
Let's say the seeker must must cross the
bridge of sarah,
which is described as narrow as a
razor's edge.
And on one side is the chasm of cruelty.
And then the other side is the is the
abyss of skepticism.
So to do this stuff,
you really have to have,
I mean it's very difficult,
it's easy to say you have an open mind,
but you'd be surprIsed how few people
have an open mind.
We got some experience with this
ourselves and when you say,
yeah,
you would expect that from science,
they should be open to evidence,
but in fact are not.
And so what is their issue?
They don't want to admit that they're
wrong and that everything that had been
teaching for decades was incorrect and
it's proven so.
So they hold onto the old truth.
Well,
exactly,
but I mean in the way I have a little
bit of sympathy for them even because
they put in all of these years and you
get somebody who comes from out
absolutely out of left field me and who
doesn't come out of left field?
One of them,
they're a phd geologist and highly
respected and the number of geological
solid scientific was published to say
you guys have it all wrong and
well explain to folks what your
background is and why your,
uh,
such a,
a rebel in this field.
Oh,
well,
let me,
I don't want to lose thIs thread because
I have no,
that's okay,
but when I'm on my,
when I do,
when I'm on my trips,
people always ask,
we are going through the evidence and
instead of taking half an hour of the
way we are now,
we've been ours down.
Liz links studying every aspect of the
geology and so someone,
and they always say,
well,
how they seek leave whitney said that
has the evidence,
how can they denied?
And that's.
I always were cans and anecdote that
funny when I was a kid,
I read this long before I was even
interested in this stuff,
but it was a teaching tail supposedly a
proven that this was the 19 forties.
ReAder's digest an anecdote in there
that when you actually have the asha
heifetz,
the great violinist gables,
debbie bill at carnegie hall at the age
of 11,
I think this must have been for 43,
something like that.
I was a kid.
And um,
and at the concert was the then reigning
violin,
virtuoso dynamic mischa elman.
You don't hear much of these days,
but he was sort of tinkers,
look them up today and with him was our
to rubinstein,
the great pianist and about halfway
through the concert element turn to elmo
term to rubinstein and he said,
hot in here isn't it?
And we're going to start and said not
for pianists.
So,
so,
so with our,
with our science,
the geologists have no problem with it
or the micro biologist.
So the astrophysicists,
the egyptologist and the archaeologist
that's hot.
So what,
what can be done?
I mean what you guys are presented this
evidence,
they've tried to ignore it,
but more things pop up that show that we
might be wrong about the history of
humanity.
like go back like tappy.
Exactly.
We now have the smoking guns at our
disposal.
We have an arsenal of smoking guns and
you see we have even more of an instant
was in that video we presented.
There's a lot more evidence just from
Egypt that we presented in another csa
conference in $2,000.
Again,
with the almost unanimous ascent of the
attending geologists,
but that one unfortunately didn't have
much press there,
so it didn't.
It didn't get a lot of press.
The geologists were impressed but it
didn't go anywhere,
but we now have.
We've had for a while all of the
evidence at our disposal,
the
template which you mentioned and I don't
know how many of your audience will know
about that.
That's serious.
That's the smoking gun because here's
this incredible site in Turkey and chalk
and I have visited there and spent about
a week there that was discovered in 1994
and I hope we'll get pictures of this up
there,
but it was discovered in 1994.
Absolutely.
By accidents.
Looks like a big hill.
I mean it is a big hill and you'd never
know that there was anything there.
And in [inaudible],
94 farmer was plowing the top of the
hill and he hit what he thought it was.
A boulder and plow hit the boulder and
he ran the plow back over the to try to
dislodge it and it wouldn't just lodge.
And I tried a couple of times and
nothing happened except they've met
their cloud and so they dug around it
and they discovered that it wasn't a
boulder after ella was the top of the
stone column,
so they started digging some more and
then finally they called them the
archeologists,
which now they're sorry about because
they commandeered the site and these
guys 20 years,
15 years later fighting the turkish
government is get some kind of financial
redress from stealing,
stealing their help.
Anyway,
once once they got excavating,
they discovered that this was one of the
greatest archeological discoveries
probably of all time.
I mean from,
from a hisTorical point of view,
it's even more significant and it looks
like two comments treasure because once
they stopped,
they dug up the first of these and they
found they did ground penetrating radar
or maybe seismograph.
So I'm not sure.
But certainly radar.
And this huge hill has at least 22
closely packed stone circles like minnie
stone hinges,
but not so many central columns.
There are central columns to central
columns in each of these stone circles
and then ring the round with other
funds.
I mean everybody listening to this who's
watching this will have an image of a
stonehenge and in their heads,
so it's like that except not as not as
massive,
but then further further as they were
digging,
they realized that this entire hill,
which had been at one point or another,
exposed to the elements of course had
been deliberately filled in.
what reason?
Nobody knows,
I mean is a lot.
This is acres of land and the thing had
been completely covered and they were
able to date the film because the film
has all kinds of organic material in it
and so the film they dated to $8,000.
They see things that they go back to.
The temple itself is incredible site.
Nobody knows what the air for who did it
or anything is at least 10,000
bc and the central columns that I was
talking about,
our 10 to 15 tons.
They know that the law,
I think we limestone,
but the stones come from a quarry about
three quarters of a mile downhill,
so they have to drag these up.
Now we're talking about 10,000
bc.
Has to be any civilization,
much less tools or anything of that
sort.
So here are these under 22 of these
stone circles.
Only four have been partially excavated
and not only on the four.
Out of 22,
pardon?
I said only four out of 22 have been
activated and oldest time archeology is
an unbelievably.
It's done.
It's done meticulously and nowadays it
tends to bed and not so long ago it's
just grave robbery,
but now it's really meticulous.
They going at this stuff with teaspoons,
so it takes them years and years and
years to do it.
Then I guess there isn't a gigantic
amount of funding available.
I don't know who's funding it.
It's a german team that's doing it with
a really nice,
really good guy.
Klaus schmIdt,
german archaeologist who was in charge
there,
who's,
you know,
he's not into the esoteric side of
things.
It's shocking irr,
but because he's a solid guy,
he's pretty good and a nice man,
so anyway,
the apart from the size of these stones
and the finesse that they had that then
it goes into creating them.
They're also elaborately decorated and
they're high relief.
What's called high relief.
In other words,
let's say you want to do what you want
to carve in a wild boar or bird or in
one case a lion or some sort of a line.
You cut the back.
We cut the stone away so that the image
springs out of the stone.
This is 10 times more work than carving
something into the stone and this is all
we got.
Any tunes as far as anyone knows.
Certainly any metal tools.
I'm with flint somehow or another and
you got acres of these things and they.
The archeologists do not dispute the
dating of 10,000
bc earlier.
So that's our smoking gun.
I mean we've been looking at this for a
long time and all kinds of evidence and
some of the.
A lot of the evidence is really
commanding,
but it's not spectacular looking now.
It's spectacular.
Sorry,
what I found amazing about it was that
they were trying to attribute these
constructions to hunter and gatherers.
Well,
mayBe they are hunters and gatherErs.
I mean,
you have to be a fool if there's plenty
of animals and stuff around there.
Plenty of things around to eat.
Why should you go to the backbreaking
job of farming is legible.
Actually,
I have in my first non fiction book,
I don't know if you know this,
I started out as a novelist,
playwright,
screenwriter,
and I had a lot of things done that will
make me money was probably a good thing
for egyptology black.
Um,
there's a,
you know,
if you ever heard of him,
but in the first book was called the
case for astrology,
which is out of print now,
but let's put together all of the
scientific evidence that says it's
actually something behind it.
It's not just what's a good day to buy a
poodle.
So the,
in this,
in that book,
that's my first nonfiction book,
but I quote a is a wonderful
ethnologists conrad lawrence who was
brought up in South Africa.
You wrote a wonderful book.
Bush probably still around bushman are
about his own experience and he relates
how the bushman of South Africa,
the missionaries are trying to teach
them how to farm and the machine looks
at him and he says,
well,
why should we farm when there were so
many mongo,
mongo nuts in the world?
Whatever that is,
why would anybody in their right mind
boggling the plow the land and cut
everything down when they go outside?
I feel hurt,
efficient,
untitled.
So just because they were hunter
gatherers doesn't mean they hadn't
figured out amazing constructions.
The ability to make these huge cities
and these just
that.
And in this last couple of decades,
I mean,
I've been on this quest for what?
All to swallowed the little bit in the
late sixties.
So that's when I said something like
that close to it.
And,
and,
but in the last 10 or 12,
a whole lot of really interesting work
has come to the fore proving that not
only that,
these in these so called primitive
societies that maybe we're not
intellectually sophisticated.
They nevertheless had,
they had a precise cosmological science
and actually some,
uh,
some of them like pals involved in this,
you may know some of them,
but you may not know.
Some of them,
they might be interesting guests for you
in an upcoming shows.
If people know people will really,
really get tuned into this sort of
thing.
So it's becoming quite cleAr that,
that the knowledge was all there.
I mean the knowledge is there.
The groundbreaking book,
was he making them about it?
What it's called hamlet's mill.
Do you know that?
Discuss that one.
I've heard you discuss it.
You're right,
it's,
it's georgiadis.
I mean these are two impeccable
historians of science at mit,
Georgia,
this santiana and carrots up on deck
hand and in the book as I think
published in 68.
But again,
this is the thing you have to go through
when you're,
when you're dealing with these heretical
things.
I mean these guys with all the right
credentials,
not like may not come from out of left
field and they manage the stonewall them
and try to and try to ignore their
evidence that underlying the world's
mythology,
all of these strange stories that we
know incestuous gods and all of this
kind of thing was astronomy and
astronomy presupposes the santiana and
can go into that much because they were
in enough water as it was,
but there is absolutely no point to a
sophisticated astronomy unless there's
an astrology behind it.
At least in the old days.
Nowadays they're busy looking for
quasars and black holes and all that
sort of thing,
which have no meaning at least let's
say,
at least in the emotional and
philosophical sense,
but in the old days,
whole civilizations,
Egypt included,
were attuned to the emotions of the
stars.
In other words,
there's a lot of literature on this,
this.
Why do you think that this culture that
we live in right now is so reluctant to
accept anything like astrology?
Why do you think they would like to
dismiss it so quickly?
Well,
because,
because this is a materialistic,
this is a materialist culture that
denies anything that has any meaning,
I mean material materialism,
which is the reigning philosophy.
This is what everybody learns in school
certainly get nothing esoteric and
school,
nothing mystical and unfortunately the,
the,
the skeptic,
the skeptic's of basically rationalism,
materialism.
Atheism basically is,
it's,
it's basically the religion of the
emotional,
defective and spiritually dyslexic,
and then contemporary,
materialistic science value does not
exist.
In other words,
it's value is by definition subjective,
so these people are ermine because they
can't find the meaning in their own
lives and the wrong existence to,
to foist that emptiness that neil ism
upon everyone else,
but they call it rationalism or reason.
It's nothing of the sort because it is
nothing but nothing.
It just seems to reason that our bodies
are affected by the moons and the tides
and women's periods are.
And you know,
people behave differently during
different moon cycles.
The oceans there are affected by the
tides.
I mean,
that's affected by the fact that the
moon can affect the oceans and we're
mostly water when we just assume that
planets are having some sort of an
effect on tubal.
That'S right.
Where did it all come from?
where did astrology originate from?
Like what is the,
what is the bottom,
what is at the end of it?
Like,
who invented it?
We know what we can say is that if,
if going back into the paleolithic now
we're,
when we think actually those figures
shock and I think that the figures in
the paleolithic in the beckley tapio
probably cosmological and astronomical
and can prove it yet.
However,
the santiago that can do a very good job
of showing that that's um,
that astronomy under underpins the most
ancient mythologies that we have.
And since these guys,
since the ancients I'm not just
interested in quasars and pulse and all
of these sorts of things.
It presupposes and astrology and in fact
in Egypt and Egypt was once one society
that I know the most aBout it,
but the same I'm sure applies to ancient
China and India and mayans and so on,
that the entire society is orchestrated
in sUch a way that,
that it is tuned to these cosmic cycles
and we still have,
you know,
there's a reason why christmas is the
day that it is and there's a reason why
easter is the day that it is supposed
to,
to commemorate historically in certain
certain elements in the,
you know,
in the life of jesus christ.
But actually that's,
it's much older than that and,
and the,
the ancient societies knew what they
were doing and when you get deep into
Egypt,
you see that there.
That life itself was a kind of a
magical.
It's like a magical recreation of the
genesis of the universe in which by
celebrating it in certain ways and
certain kinds Of ceremonies and so on,
human beings are reliving the cosmic
process and thereby accessing the
divinity that is responsible for us
being here,
whIch is not supposed to,
which is not creationism.
Music.
Anytime you tried to say to a rational
of scientists that,
hey,
there really is a meaningful life.
There's all your creation was you think
the world was greater than seven days?
No,
that's the name that you know god with
big white beard was up there and this
guy's angle today.
I think it'll create mosquitoes and
there's nothing to do with that.
If it'S a much more profound philosophy,
but if it is not amendable to study by a
materialist science,
but who sat and materialist science is
the be all and end all and the answer to
everything.
Only the material is to say that,
but they've got everybody,
including the people who when we put the
educational system together,
conned into believing that their science
is the only signs.
The engines new,
new much better and they did much
better.
I mean all you have to do is go to Egypt
to experience these unbelievable temples
in this fabulous art to understand that
something is going on that isn't going
on now.
This is one of the,
I mean it's a big subject.
We won't even get into it in an open
ended,
in an open ended talk like this black
chalk and I will be talking about in the
booklet where we're planning this,
dancing down the bridge of sarah and um,
and in the video,
the big followup to the mystery of the
strengths that we're hoping to put
together,
funding for,
which we hope to go as a theatrical
release,
not just on television.
Some get sales first and then onto the
videos and theaters and tb and all that
sort of stuff.
You have to have lIke an animated dog or
something to go with you to Egypt if you
want to get it into theaters to get
people to really get a interested in the
history of the banks and all that stuff,
that's going to be difficult to get into
theater.
No,
it's silly people we have in this world.
See,
I mean we had our show that mr.
banks was a huge success.
Unfortunately my ex partner now
deceased,
stole a whole lot to 150 grand from the
till so he never made any money out of
it,
but he was an interesting guy and
without going without him,
that never would have happened because
he had the energy in the eye.
I can sink but I don't.
I'm not a manifestor and he got the
whole thing going so I don't know
if you had a penguin,
a penguin,
the travels to Egypt and you get morgan
freeman to narrate it.
No jail.
we don't need it actually is that video
had was on sweeps week and had it had a
huge audience over the course of its
lifetime.
It still gets you on every once and it
was amazing.
It was probably seen by.
I tried to figure it out one day.
It was probably seen by at least 250
million people over over the number of
years that it was being shown
internationally and so on.
People Are really interested in this
stuff and still express it.
We don't need any penguins which is
paid.
In this case.
We just need the science because I'm the
see the material is is glamorous in its
own right now we have all of this other
stuff.
It's not just the Egypt.
We have Turkey.
There are these.
I don't know if you've seen this,
the truck shop very fascinated like
easter island,
which may be connected with these
things.
You know the more I have easter island,
right?
Did you know that up until quite
recently it looks like they're just kind
of these big figures that are their
heads basically heads into ourselves,
right?
we're alone.
I can't imagine them.
I took them onto just 200 years to
figure it out.
They started excavating these things and
they're finding that their full full
length statute.
So in other words,
they have built up around them maybe 25
feet,
30 feet of silt,
and now the question is,
and this should be relatively easy to
determine,
this
is part of our big project and will when
you except that the in the dome and
civilization.
The followup,
the mystery of the strengths,
because it should be possible to carbon
date the lower layers of the sill and
our conviction is that these things may
take back again,
thousands and thousands and thousands.
Have they done this?
I mean,
I've seen the excavations
not well.
They're excavating,
but we don't have any carbon dating.
Suck as a bloody.
It's julian who is the ambassador
somewhere or another.
Anyway,
he's connected to easter island.
You should be able to find out in
Florida and then not only as you see,
we've got to hold this stuff now.
It's really exciting.
The,
um,
not only go back leads happy,
but have you heard about the bracelet
that was found fairly recently in
Turkey?
No.
Are you on.
I know,
I know graham hancock's been on your
show or are you on his mailing list that
he has?
I'm sure he sends out.
I mean,
that's his whole job.
That's what he does and sends out this
enormously comprehensive list of
everything that's interesting happening
in science that either directly or
tangentially affects this whole lost
civilization hypothesis anyway.
Are you familiar with the oBject that
they found?
The bottom of the baltic sea recently,
very recently,
it looks like a millennium falcon.
It looks like,
you know,
a few took the star wars spaceship,
millennium falcon and put it in the
bottom of the ocean.
That's what it looks like.
They don't know what it is,
but they're sendinG divers down like I
believe it's this week.
oh yeah,
I heard about that.
Yeah,
and it's somebody that will say when see
will see when they,
when they figure it out because it has
to be seriously careful about that
stuff.
You know about soccer and myself.
Dive,
yes,
no,
that we're convinced graeme thinks
otherwise,
but we're shocking myself.
Convinced that this is amazing looking
place is in fact perfectly natural.
Wow.
Really explain.
Yeah.
We can explore.
We can pretty well explained how it's
done and we didn't want to think that
that would have Been a smoking gun,
but we're.
We're convinced that it's natural.
You saw those two giant.
You Saw those two giant pizza box
looking pieces of rock that were stacked
next to each other side by side and you
that look natural.
Yeah.
It's a hard,
isn't it?
You know,
it's hard to describe,
just know without having the pictures
there,
but more time and I had the big thing
with me.
We,
we could show you why we're convinced
that it is indeed completely
natural.
You've seen all the images on graham
hancock site,
I'm assuming.
Did you do any diving yourself?
A yana goes,
yeah,
yeah.
We were there for a week and then there
are a couple
of times and he's,
as I said,
it's in our own interest.
This as to see this is the evidence
we're looking for,
but we don't think it is.
We think graham was making a big mistake
and insisting that it is
dr schoch the geologist.
What was his explanation for how it was
created?
Well,
you see if you go because the people who
are taking the pictures initially and
it's they're not trying to fool anyone,
they're just taking the cool,
exciting looking pictures,
but if you follow some of those ridges,
it looks so perfectly vertical and so
perfectly horizontal.
You'll see them just kind of tAper into
disappearance living rock face and when
you get really down in your notes to the
rock,
you see the,
the,
the corners aren't finished.
You see that the rocks have been
wrenched out of their place.
It's place,
it's dangerous diving there.
and I'm not a diver.
I'm very,
very strong currents and I mean I have a
master diver glued to me,
so,
um,
but,
but when you go down the shore,
I'm in shock and I went there on this
very nice japanese in their finance.
The whole thing was really interested in
it.
We do it to be wet blankets,
but I'm the last day that we were there
we went,
we went looking around the island and
looking at other stuff when we went to a
place about a couple of miles from the
actual yoga goonie site and they're at
the water's edge and it's a certain kind
of shale.
It's a very hard shale formation that is
laid down in very regular horizontals.
But that is cross cut by,
um,
fault lines.
And it's like if you imagine a gigantic
stone layer cake that's already cut into
pieces,
but they have the pieces haven't been
served.
And so what happens is that by the
action of the winds and the waves,
because the southern formation,
similar inflammation was right at the
water's edge and he could watch the
waves pounding up against the current
running.
And What would happen is that eventually
the water,
the running water and the waves and
tides,
unos,
typhoons and all the rest sort of work
into the fault lines which are softer
rock.
And eventually they get it to the point
that the action of the waves pulls away
a big chunk of rock.
This is all set down and layers.
So that falls into the water.
And again,
we're talking about thousands and
thousands of years.
Gradually the whole,
the whole pIece of brought disappears
because it's all laid down on these kind
of layer cake layer cake levels.
And so we,
we saw this with because we had our own
skins over the course of the.
It was the last thing in the world.
We wanted to be happier.
If you believed that it was an ancient
civilization,
well we had it all planned.
I was going to write it up to the
national geographic or sony or something
like that and scott was going to write
it up that they for the geological,
the geological journals and all of that
sort of stuff.
And I'm young and we say,
well,
no.
Did you see the stone circle?
It's like a.
There's like pillars arranged in a
circle,
but you see that no.
Again,
we're convinced that there's no context
for anything there and things that I'm
not.
Things that are manmade have a context.
And as I said,
when we,
when we saw we would sit,
we would still be uncertain about it if
we did not go a couple of miles down and
watched a similar sort of thing being
formed right in front of our eyes and go
back there.
When we do this,
our next,
this next element that makes you want to
do one will be one of our,
one of our sites that assuming we can
get the funding together,
but we will be,
um,
will be concentrating upon because it's
an object lesson both in,
in how careful you have to be when
you're looking.
No,
I mean we have a stake in this too and
that where we have to give up on this.
I had a moment,
a slight pang not much because I really
liked the core academics,
but he had a slight pang of compassion
for them when somebody comes along and
destroys their paradigm,
which is us.
So anyway,
so young.
That's the only goonie and um,
but anyway.
oh,
back to back to this incredible
bracelet.
This was just a couple of months ago.
They found a bracelet somewhere in
Turkey.
Turkey is turning out to be more and
more interesting.
There are all kinds of great places in
Turkey and the just around bracelet made
of obsidian.
Obsidian is an incredibly hard stone and
very difficult to work.
And like dated,
I'm not exactly sure how their data
might be in the,
where it was found the strada where it
was found.
They dated it to around 8,000
bc,
but the,
the,
it's a very elegant little,
I mean didn't look like that much.
It's just elegant and beautiful.
And the archeologists realized when they
studied it that the finish on it was
something that nowadays you could only
do with the most sophisticated
instruments,
lasers or something of the sort and
moreover that it had a very complex and
subtle geometrical shape.
So in other words,
you cAn't do a thing like that.
It's very hard to imagine doing some
something of that nature that's really
rigorously geometrical without having
the geometry at your fingertips.
So you'd have to have some sort of a
computer,
a machine,
something has to.
You have to have something that you're,
you built to construct this,
right?
Is that what you're saying?
We don't know.
This is,
this is the contention of chris
christopher done.
They know chris knows he's.
Well he's,
he's a high tech guy and he designs
engineer.
He is,
but he's the guy who designs the
instruments,
really precise instruments that do
things like make pieces for the space
shuttle and stuff,
their instruments that are calibrated to
10 thousands of thousands of an inch and
he's done studies in Egypt and finds
that that's what you'll see all over the
place that there a monstrous pieces of
granite.
let me put this [inaudible].
He's been on a couple of trips with me.
He's a good guy and he,
he has his flying special instRuments
that you know,
a calibrated to a 10 thousands of an
inch and the places that some piece of
granite and old kingdom granite and
granted is 100 percent completely true.
And,
and chris as you know,
is,
is fairly adamant that in order to do
this they had to have had some sort of
technology that would allow them to do
that shotgun.
I'm not so sure because technology is
technology and mostly they have some
miraculous realm of technology that we
can't even imagine because you would
have expected,
particularly in a place like Egypt so
much from the past times.
Somewhere along the line you need to
have some evidence of this kind of
technology and the dump.
You mean by saying technology,
you mean something that cuts the,
like a machine,
something that can cut the marble and
polish it down to be 100 percent flat?
Yes,
exactly.
What is the conventional?
What is the conventional egyptologists?
How do they say they built it?
They don't address the question of being
since there is no.
Since there is no,
there is no evidence for that
technology.
They just assume that they did it by
hand somehow or another,
and maybe they did,
but when you realize the level of
perfection of these things and how
impossible it would be today to do them
by hand.
Um,
I mean they're just say,
oh,
well in those days everybody had lots of
time and time was no,
it was not of any concern that it could
work on it until I got it right.
Well,
that's the sort of a fudge hands.
You can't legitimately postulates and
advanced technology when you don't have
any evidence for it.
Right.
There was another issue with the vases,
correct?
The stone vases that were made that we
can't duplicate today.
Oh,
well,
maybe we could,
but we'd have to go.
We got to use a lot of very special
machinery to do it and since there's no
evidence that he had this kind of
machinery,
these rounds,
no clauses that are,
you know,
the shape like this and they have a
narrow neck and the hollow on the inside
and,
and they're perfect.
I mean they can know,
they can tap into the inside and see
that the inside is hollowed out
perfectly and we can't,
we don't know how they could possibly
have had what kind of a drill or
anything they could have had to do this
in a very hard stone.
Vases and they date from a very early
Egypt,
not I'm not a later period.
They lost the ability.
This is one of the strains and some of
the most spectacular stuff comes from
the earliest periods contract right now.
There's a terrific,
there's a terrific show.
And the,
uh,
the metropolitan museum of art,
I think the dawn of the egyptian art and
it's all the preterm nastic work force
housing five,
three,
four or 5,000
bc and they're collected.
It's not,
it's not because they do a
retrospective,
they get,
gets from here and bits in there and so
on.
So they put together this really
fabulous shoW because normally you don't
see much treated nastic art together in
one place.
And when you look carefully and you see
what's going on and you know,
what you,
you,
what you're looking at,
I mean if it was somebody who not spent
30 years studying Egypt,
you don't look really impressive.
That'S in pieces.
They're mostly quIte small.
But if you have an eye for this and
you've done a lot of study and ask a lot
of questions,
you see how spectacularly beautiful
these things are.
Zoned shows on till august.
So anybody in the neighborhood make sure
you get to the mat.
How does it happen?
an awful lot of press,
but it's,
it's a terrific show.
So you guys want to put a date of the
civilization of Egypt to somewhere
around $30,000
pc.
That's your idea,
right?
Yeah.
Probably.
It could even be earlier.
We don't actually,
we're me backtrack a little bit.
My.
My question is how did one civilization
like Egypt,
how did that one thing rises up and it
seems so much more advanced than any
civilization anywhere,
anywhere around it.
Like how did that take place so long
ago?
A little bit different than see this
physical situation of Egypt is such as
bone guys this nowadays since,
but your,
your,
your theory.
I'm sorry.
Your theory puts it in a time where it
wasn't though your theory puts the
creation of Egypt at the time where it
was lush and rained all the time.
It was essentially a rainforest.
Well that takes it way back further,
but then we go back,
we accept that and now we're talking
10,000
bc and who's to say what they haven't
discovered yet?
What was the climate?
And I find so and the other
civilizations you see he has this
physically,
physically unique situation where things
don't.
Whether away.
I mean,
once they get covered up with sand just
there and plus the fact that,
you know,
in the old days this was a,
this was a kind of blessing civilization
in which we hardly have to do any work
to get fed either the nile would flood
and we planted some seeds and I grew up
when the windows,
when the flood season game again,
we had a fairly populous,
um,
that was a substantial population there
with nothing to do.
No television,
no american idol and nothing to do all
day long,
all night long.
And so they,
they,
you know,
the whole,
the entire society was put to work
building these fabulous,
fabulous temples and monuments and doing
the artwork and so on.
So the other places,
I mean I'm pretty well convinced because
the doctrine in all of this work in the
last decade or so,
proving that the cosmology,
in other words,
the sophisticated understanding of life
and significant significance of live in
the geometry,
astronomy and so on was all,
they're universally India and China and
the other places just didn't have the
physical
capacity to build on that scale or maybe
they just play to do it anyway.
They had other ways of manifesting this
kind of,
let's say this kind of understanding.
And this is another thing that just not
even taking into consideration by the
academics.
You don't need sacred architects,
you know,
magnificent sacred architecture to
express
spirituality.
We could have a society and they
probably are some express their,
let's say their,
their,
their spiritual longings.
It's only in danced and at the end you
would have known even the society,
for example,
there are sacred dances in the gurdjieff
work that I do.
They have what are called the movements
and boy,
you're getting into these things.
I mean they're pretty amazing and yet we
do them today,
but because he,
they sacred dance exists in lots of
different societies,
but you don't need to build temples in
order to express it.
The egyptians done it that way.
I'm the chinese and the indians did too,
but not that early and there was no,
it's less than that.
what,
how did the civilization just spring up
like this though?
Created such incredible works of art and
incredible work.
You know the,
the architectural designs of these,
these buildings,
we don't.
No,
we don't know.
But when you see that,
see that's one of the eye openers of
this very interesting don and
civilization exhibit at the met because
you don't have temples and you don't
have to have big buildings,
but you have very many instances of very
sophisticated sculptured done.
Very hard stones.
I mean beautifully finished.
So they had it.
They could do it and as I said earlier,
we've got build beckley company that is
not an argument for that.
Go back to the topic of easter island.
Turn out to be ancient.
Well then they are.
I mean,
if it's,
if,
if you can date,
it's sort of amazing,
they haven't done it or maybe they have
an,
I don't know about it,
but if you can,
you can show them that the earliest
levels of filled that had buried them up
to their chests goes back to let's say
go back.
We have templates on rather than we've
got another instance of spectacular
artwork at the time when there's not
supposed to do such a thing.
I mean,
the whole thing is in the process of
being turned upside down,
ideally by us.
It's an incredibly fascinating subject
and one that it drives me crazy.
It's uh,
the,
the timeline is such a fascinating
thing.
Like where did civilization emerged from
the,
when,
how did it get so incredibly
sophisticated at one point in time,
ancient Egypt and then somehow or
another,
all that stuff was lost,
you know,
somehow or another through the burning
of the library of alexandria and the
romans and the greeks and everything
throughout history up until today.
So much informaTion has been lost is,
is there a natural disaster in the
middle of there somewhere?
Did something happen to the human race,
were wiped out a significant number of
us.
And then we had to refigure things out.
Is that what happened?
Well,
could be or it stayed there and sort of
a dormant state until it was time to,
to reinvented.
And acTually it does go for the,
that for example,
you see when you're dealing with the
academia,
um,
they,
they're very resistant to,
to interpreting their own data in any
way that disagrees with their
preconceptions.
But you're familiar for sure with the
paleolithic caves,
right?
Grants.
Olesko.
Do you know the one?
I'm the most recent one discovered in
the early nineties?
Close show today.
Hold on the same area.
You know that one?
No,
I don't know that one.
C,
h a l v,
e t,
I think I must of what's going on in
that one.
And,
and this was discovered.
It's named after the guy who discovered,
and this is up up until now,
the most spectacular,
the most spectacular of the caves was
the one that lost.
Go with the famoUs all of bowls.
And the other one,
that place called alta mira,
which again is a very high level of
artwork and both of those,
both of those caves of dated to around
17,
18,000
bc and the basis of evidence in the
caves will show that it has the most
spectacular art.
The law.
I mean it's,
it's as though it were designed by drawn
by a whole bunch of paleo,
picasso's coming spectacular stuff.
When you,
when you pull it up online will say it
and spell it again please.
C h a,
v e t or b,
e z.
I think,
wow,
this is amazing stuff.
He got it up right now.
You see this day date to 31,000
bc bright,
but they don't see.
They don't put two and two together.
They can't do higher mathematics and
academia because two and two tells you
that artwork at this level.
And I mean where are they getting the
paint from?
What are they doing with their fingers?
Presumably we can't go into the local
art supply shop and get know,
get acrylic paints the painting that's
on the inside of the cage.
It's got to be pitch black and when you
look at the level of artwork,
you realize that this is not done by
primitives.
In order to to do art of that,
on that level,
you have to have your act together.
Even if you're wearing bear skins,
you know,
it really does look like the animals
they're chasing and it's all done from
memory.
that's very impressive.
Well,
we were shocked and I think that because
there's been a very good guy minutes for
it forever,
for a long time.
He was at a conference that we did named
frank ed to interpret it,
the hall of bulls lasko as an
astronomical basically as not having an
astronomical significance of dots and
dogs on the wall that represented the
pleiades and other constellations and I
think he's probably correct and it
wouldn't have surprised me to see.
The usual explanation is,
oh,
well that's magic because of my paint,
the water,
these animals on the wall,
they'll be able to hunt them.
I'm not so sure I'm.
I'm more inclined to think that it may
be in some in some way or another star
map or have some sort of cosmological
significance and it does a book for
french member of the academy actually
going to go the sacred geography of
ancient Greece?
No,
it's another one.
It's a different moment.
That's one book.
There's another one by amateurs.
In other words,
not credentialed.
Whatever enough,
if that means anything close.
Plato's secret elliot's in which they
show that the iliad,
which is the most boring book ever
written,
is actually a gigantic,
like a planetarium and all of this so
and so's being killed.
No,
the the,
the
heroes.
Rosa here and the armies of doing all of
this sort of stuff.
It's a terrible board read,
but if it's decoding as a star map,
like as like a planetarium and the
action from about 9,000
bc on the whole thing makes all of a
sudden made sense.
This is why they go into all of that
trouble to do all of this work decoded
as a sky map.
How?
How do you decode it as a sky map?
He has to read the bucket.
It's complicated because the stars,
let me see if I remember correctly,
the army's represent constellations,
the heroes of the particular bright
stars in the,
in the,
in the particular constellation,
and the elliot is all about this army is
going here and that ami is going here
and this one is over powering this one
and if you're decoding astronomically,
if it's tracking the constellations
across the sky because the,
the relationships of the stars and the
constellations to each other,
change over time.
So as everybody knows,
why should they do that?
I don't know what he said.
The astronomy and this is now even
getting,
even the academics,
there's a realizing that that astronomy
plays a huge role in very ancient
civilizations and the only reason as far
as I'm concerned,
but I can't prove it.
We only reason it has to be not only is
astrologically significant because
otherwise we would care.
I mean,
for example,
hamlet's mill,
um,
something that can go to a lot of
trouble to show that very ancient myths
as far back as you go know about the
procession of the equinoxes.
I was just about to ask you about that.
I said I was just about to ask you about
that.
That's it.
That's amazing.
Explain that to people.
Okay.
the possession of the equinox is there
is because supposedly because of the
level of the earth with their other
other explanations that I liked,
ben made the whole solar system that's
turning around a binary star.
UM.
Anyway.
Doesn't matter.
The act is that,
let's say if you look the way that this
now we're still in the.
Let's say we're in the age of pisces,
which means that if you look at the
spring equinox,
if you watched wait for the sun to rise,
it's rising an hour before the sunrise
is.
You'll see the sun coming up and the
constellation behind the sunrise is the
very last degrees of pisces.
And pretty soon you can't synthesize.
They pretty soon it will be aquarius.
So the age of aquarius for musical was
now very gradually.
It's cool.
The precession,
the,
the entire zodiac precesses against the,
the sun.
So in other words,
it doesn't go and you look at astrology
areas,
as you know,
is whatever it is,
April 20th,
march,
22nd,
and then it goes because aries,
taurus,
gemini cancer and so on.
Precesses means it goes backwards.
So it's in pisces now and it'll soon be
in aquarius.
Now that the rate at which that cycle
takes canonically exactly,
exactly that 25,920
years.
So what this means is that for the sun
to precess one degree takes 72 years.
Now how do they figure that out and why
should it be important to you?
Imagine looking at the sky.
I don'T want people to be looking at
this guy for some reason or another and
realize that the sun takes 72 years to
go one degree.
There was a book that graham hancock had
discussed once on an interview.
I wish I could remember the name of it,
but it was discussing this,
this number 72,
and that this knowledge of the
procession of the equinoxes has been
installed in many,
many ancient cultures and religions.
Exactly.
It has met.
That gets you into numbers,
symbolism and got gets you into sacred,
so it lets us know that they knew a lot
more than we thought they knew just
about the universe itself,
the constellations themselves,
the wobble of the earth's axis,
a 26,000
year cycle.
They knew about this somehow or another
10,
15,000
years ago.
That's really.
That's incredible.
It is.
And you see it's this kind of thing that
is rigorously excluded from any kind of
academic discussions until it's stuffed
down their throats.
This is exactly what we plan to do.
The current,
the,
the conventional egyptologists date,
their construction of the pyramids to
2,500
Bc,
right?
Is it correct?
Yes.
What?
What's that?
What's that based on?
Well,
it's based on the.
It's based on the reigns of key ops,
kafra of friend and so on.
And this is.
This is very complicated
because we're chunking.
Myself and my colleagues think that in
all likelihood,
the pyramids that we see today are doing
deed date from that period.
However,
and this is again formally,
easily provable.
They are built,
they are super imposed or replace
structures that were there earlier and
even the academics acknowledged that the
giza plateau was was a single template
to some very interesting work coming up
soon proving that that's the case,
so whenever the sphinx was built,
they were also structures that we don't
know if there are pyramids or not,
but in the paramedics,
particularly the second pyramid,
the pyramid that's associated with the
spanx,
you can see that there are two different
styles,
two radically different styles of
masonry and the lower the lower courses
have built these gigantic blocks.
the size of practically the size of this
room.
I'm not quite,
but anyway,
massive maybe 8,000
ton blocks and then piled on top of them
on the much and very finely finished on
a much lesser smaller cruder masonry.
That's rather typical of of the old
kingdom.
now whenever I'm in architectural
history,
no architectural historian would not.
Contextual historian knows instantly
that when you see two different styles
of architecture in the same building,
you know you're looking at two different
periods of building.
I mean this as a rough example,
suppose you have a victorian house,
but you've got a modern kitchen in it
100 years from now,
with 500 years from now,
the archeologists come and discover that
house.
They will know in two seconds that the
houses built in the 19 hundreds or the
$1,800
rather than the kitchen is built in 2005
or something of that sort.
So this is a given.
So when you see two different radically
different styles of architecture,
you know,
you're dealing with two different
periods,
um,
two different periods of construction.
And then there are other factors in
this.
This so called red pyramid.
I'm about 20 miles away where the whole
pyramid is built and the interior
chambers are in perfect condition,
uh,
built over a ruinous legalistic chamber
that they called a plunder tomb chamber.
But it's not a plum.
The tomb chamber goes the stones in it.
I've been exposed to the weather for a
long,
long time.
It's an earlier megalithic construction.
We don't know what the dating is,
but all of this you see is,
is evidence that we will be using in our
september one if we managed to flip for
budget together and do it,
and there's a great history of people
building on top
of ancient structures that the parthenon
and the acropolis,
which doesn't get explained that,
you know,
nobody explains where those gigantic
stones came from and why they,
you know,
how they got into place.
Massive,
monstrous stones.
And so the other thing that you guys had
shown that I thought was really
fascinating was that below ground when
you showed the really ancient
constructions,
a lot of them were uncovered.
A lot of them had to be dug out.
They were,
they were actually the ones that were
under the ground under the sand were the
ones that showed the earlier
construction methods,
which is pretty obvious that much like
the sphinx,
when they first discovered it had been
taken over by saying this is.
You're talking about really,
really ancient stuff.
Yeah.
Well,
this drinks is a bit different because
it's cut into a hollow in order to
produce this drinks.
They had to carve clari the stone around
from it,
so once it,
why they did that first place,
nobody really knows.
But once they did it,
once he turned too soon to desert,
we'll leave it the 20,
25 years without sweeping it out.
If it goes 30 right up to the neck
again.
Who,
uh,
what,
who was responsible for cutting the face
into the sphinx?
Oh,
we don't know.
We're convinced.
We're convinced that it was required
because it's much too small for the
body.
It's disproportionate to the body and
some way,
well,
it looks in better shape for two
reasons.
One,
it's a much harder outcrop of stone and
b,
it's been restored.
The head dresses and all of that.
If you look at old photos of the site
taken around 1900,
so you see that it's really much more
weather than it's looked,
but they prepared the face and so on.
But I mean,
this has all kinds of repercussions.
For example,
well,
you know the story,
the
we're doing the video Mark Lane or was
the,
the loyal opposition as it were in the,
in the eighties.
Because the sphinx is supposed to look
like the pharaoh kopra.
He's hadn't looked at least like the
federal kopra,
but lana did an early computer study
when back in the eighties when computers
were still pretty primitive in which he
said kafra data into the paramed and
sorry into the computer and then
superimposed the results upon the head
of this length and said,
well blah.
The swing says conference.
Well,
last,
this was sort of silly,
but it got a lot of press was in the New
York times and I think the smithsonian
all over the place.
So when we finally got the funding
together to do our mystery of the
swings,
we really had to address that because it
was,
it was,
um,
he was well known and you know,
people say,
well,
you know,
it's been proved that this links is the
face of contra.
So how do you disprove it?
Well,
I wanted to,
I wanted to actually use exactly the
same message of that lane or years,
but seed elvis data into the computer
and proved slinks was really meant to be
elvis.
But the,
we thought that was a cool idea.
But what happened was that the elvis
foundation wouldn't let us use the
king's emits in that context and I think
elvis would have been furious.
He would love to go.
But what happened then was my,
my criminal partner,
boris,
who was an interesting guy,
he was an ex ex,
a race driver.
He drove for ferrari for years and lived
here for porsche.
It was an interesting character.
Anyway,
he came up with the idea of,
well,
let's get a forensic detective to go
with us to Egypt to,
you know,
do a study of these places and see if
they really could be the same model,
the plan,
the same human being and so song.
Couple of phone calls and we got in
touch with a guy named frank domingo is
the senior forensic detective from the
nyp ed and he came to Egypt with us and
this is more long story about how he got
frank to agree to go and he did his
study and charlotte unquestionably that
the toothpaste is could not possibly
have been the same.
Then the question came up because when
you look at the profile of the strings,
even though it's pretty ruined us
because it's been severely damaged,
even though it was damaged,
it's quite clear that not only is a
different face than that,
but it's probably a different race.
In other words,
it really looks like the sub saharan
african place,
not even like,
not like an egyptian nice.
Which would mean it was done by the new
orleans who took over Egypt libyans
earlier,
you know,
from your spouse was the new orleans.
New orleans don't look like don't look
the same light as the sub saharan
africans.
So and in fact they leave Egypt taller.
These jips egyptologists or prejudice
does everyone else.
The last thing they want to know is that
notice that the snakes as,
uh,
as,
as an african african and,
but in,
in the earlier,
in the 19th century,
lots of people just,
you know,
there was no egyptology then lots of
travelers because stuff's labelle and
florence nightingale and all kinds of
people who wrote very beautifully about
Egypt traveling in Egypt than that in
the 19th century.
Sad.
Well,
you know,
this is a negro I face and the leads of
tolerances to simply ignored that.
Well,
anyway,
with frank.
So he did this careful forensic study.
I think it's on my website.
I'm not sure.
Actually I should tell you something.
My website's [inaudible] dot com or.net
and uh,
anyway,
it's in there somewhere.
And um,
so we asked him about it that,
that um,
know what do you think is,
can this be an african place?
And domingo is a cautious.
But he said,
well,
he said you can't prove that it is,
but it is consistent with subsaharan
subsaharan physiognomy.
And so I'll actually with that was
actually my son's very,
like,
my partner was very funny when he said
that he's in like,
this is bad news for the,
the academics is that not only.
First of all it means that,
you know,
there is an atlantis,
it wasn't atlantis and second of all
they will black.
It was pretty funny.
But anyway,
subsequently I did an op ed piece for
the New York times and I carefully left
out this old because this is,
you know,
we want to go back there and do some
more work and I was in enough water with
the academics to begin with.
So I didn't mention anything about this
sub saharan african swank's.
But a few weeks later the New York times
published a letter from a,
an orthodontist and Massachusetts
orthodontist.
And the orthodontist is another expert
in facial,
you know,
in places.
And he came up with it,
not as he came up with it and said,
yeah,
this is,
this is an african face.
So that was very interesting.
And now when we,
when we write our book,
when we write the shock and I get
cracking on the bridge of syrah,
we will go into that and actually
interviewed,
um,
track him down.
I lives in newton,
Massachusetts,
the,
uh,
the orthodontist who wrote that letter
and see what he has to say about it.
But anyway,
that was,
that was an interesting thing about the,
about the head of the sinks,
that it's not original to the,
to the fates of the spanx because it's
much too small proportion of the body
and it seems to be a subsaharan african
phase.
We don't know when it was required.
Maybe the strengths snakes and we think
over 30,000
years old and it has to be required in
some period of time in between.
Well,
it may be that that's like living in
Egypt at the time.
That was the civilization of ease of
use.
When you get back far enough,
there's not much less than.
This is why,
for example,
the paleolithic caves,
he.
He'll live with a bunch of caves but
nothing else.
we don't know what anybody else was
doing.
Along comes,
go back,
locked up and suddenly the whole
everything changes because you've got to
have this extraordinary structure that
they take the 10,000
bc,
so this comes up and it's very difficult
to create a detailed picture of what was
going on.
Then
why are they doing work on the sphinx?
Why are they like fixing the pause and
fixing the ears and are fixing the head
dress and all the different things that
they've done
to the sphinx?
That seems to me to be very confusing.
I mean you have this amazing ancient
structure and they're building on it to
like recreate that.
The toes of the lion and just seems very
odd to me.
Well,
it is actually very odd.
I mean it really is.
When you get up next to it,
it's pretty crumbly and so and but
there's,
the jury is still out.
if the repairing repairs are not
actually doing more damage than would be
done if they just left it to the
elements.
We don't know what they are doing it and
I'm very often they're doing it and it's
a pretty botched up job.
It looks terrible.
Yeah,
it does mostly look pretty.
There's like little pregnancy pregnancy
from the toes.
Yeah.
It's really.
It's really quite horrible.
But you see it's been repaired.
The repair campaigns,
it's not just modern.
The earliest repair campaigns.
This is another piece of the big puzzle.
The earliest repair campaigns are old
kingdom.
In other words,
the time that the sphinx was,
the time that the swing was supposedly
built,
it was already weathered.
Well,
isn't that part of the hieroglyphs
involved in attributed to one particular
pharaoh's name,
that he fell asleep and he had a dream
that if he uncovered the sphinx,
he would control Egypt?
Yeah,
that's tucked moses.
The third,
the fourth,
and in that tablet that stele there was
subsequently flaked off the first
syllable of kartra cop named cuff.
And from that they,
they,
they reduced the extrapolated rather
instead of will come from,
must've been the builder of the spanx.
But there's nothing that says that.
Well,
we think is that comfort was the repair
of this banks because even,
I mean,
mark laners,
the loyal opposition notes that when the
strengths was first repaired,
it was already,
whether it's to its present condition.
and he nevertheless says that,
uh,
well the,
the,
this,
the old kingdom blocks that were
repetitive.
It cannibalize from somewhere else.
it's really a cockamamie explanation.
But you know,
when you,
when you were playing in their arena and
they don't like what the evidence is,
they moved the goal posts and that
doesn't work well then they changed the
rules of the game.
Is it their contention?
Is the conventional contention that the
sphinx was carved with that face
originally?
Yeah.
That's even though it's way out of.
Even though,
even though it's even though it's much
too small proportionately and the rest
of the snakes is spectacularly accurate
proportionally.
Well not only that,
we're masters of proportion that they
stick with that because it's too
inconvenient.
You don't until you've dealt with these
guys in other fields of science and
scholarship,
but not much different people are
particularly.
Men get very stubborn.
he's,
you know,
we're,
we're upsetting the apple cart and they
make a living selling apples.
It doesn't make any sense to me is that,
that's completely discounting the actual
hard evidence of erosion.
There's a very different level of
erosion on the face than there is on the
rest of the body.
Oh,
that's okay.
Because that's a much harder.
That's a much harder outcrop of
limestone.
So that's been fully exposed whenever it
was carved,
fully exposed,
and it's not really whether that much
but more than it looks.
You look aT the old photographs you see
the back of the head.
it had been fairly severely.
Whether,
but nothing like the body.
Yeah.
That seems crazy,
right?
Actually,
what?
You have to go to jail.
He's got to come to Egypt with us.
I would love to.
I'm scared though.
It was scary right now.
It wasn't a dangerous.
Oh no.
Well,
not really.
Only if you're like trying to run it.
No,
the,
this is the,
this is the prestitutes.
So it's not that they're lying,
but only unrest is news.
So even under the worst of circumstances
when the revolution was going on,
I was after the entire revolution and I
refused to leave with the group that I
was with.
I lead through the aids,
you know.
And um,
why did you refuse to leave?
Why did you refuse to leave?
Because the government said we were
supposed to leave.
We said the hell with this wouldn't,
not.
They're not after us.
So let's see what happens.
So we waited a few days and the attacker
in the streets and little of that sort
of stuff,
it's spelled the tear gas but nobody was
after us so we were a few places we
didn't get to,
but for the rest we have the time of our
lives because we were the only green
ngos in Egypt and it was quite an
experience when you used the crowds like
the superbowl to be there when the place
was empty and we didn't miss a couple of
places,
but we had this fantastic time.
So many in the middle of the revolution
you're taking tours on and through the
sphinx and the temple man and all that.
Yeah.
They wouldn't let him out after us.
Happy to have us there.
And wow,
that's a dude who's dedicated to Egypt
technology.
When you say no,
and again see at the,
at the worst and the revolution that
we're talking about this,
there were a million people protesting
and a couple of different cities,
but if there are million people
protesting,
it means that there are 82 million
lawrence.
so I have to do is not beat on tahrir
square.
What was the protest going on?
What's nowadays with cell phones,
it's very easy to avoid.
Oh my god,
that's hIlarious.
For us,
they like having us.
There were very sort were a source of
income themselves.
I'm still doing my trips actually and,
and you know,
it's not as easy to get them together
because I have to go through this
explanation all the time,
but this is the time to go there as a
running at about 20 percent.
So that's.
Revolution is good for business.
Well no,
it's terrible.
It's terrible for business but for us.
Good for the experience.
Yeah.
And actually I um,
in fact instead the next trip is in,
the next step is in october.
And I have a,
I mean,
you with your interest,
you,
you owe it to yourselves to get to
Egypt.
I do.
I have a friend who's the only ancient
ruins I've ever seen were mayan ruins
and cheech and eatsa.
That's,
that's about as far as I've seen.
Oh,
pretty impressive that Egypt is a
different kettle of civilization because
we know so much about it.
Yeah,
well usually,
you know,
so much.
If I did go,
I would unquestionably go with you a
magical Egypt.
That dvd series that you have is one of
my.
All time.
My wife would come into the room and
look at me and go fucking Egypt again
because I'd be sitting there watching
this dvd series.
She's like,
how many of these others?
Like eight dvds.
So um,
how many dvds is the magical Egypt set?
Eight.
It's amazing.
I've watched it 30 times.
I just go back and watch it over again.
But you know,
it got to,
she got a little pissed off at me.
She was like enough stupid because I was
watching it in the bedroom,
you know,
like she would come in and have to see
sphinxes and shit.
ShE not.
Oh no,
she is a little bit but not,
not to the extent.
I'm a very obsessive person.
And when I first watched this
documentary,
ed did with charlton heston narrating
that I became obsessed with the whole
idea of.
And then I bought graham hancock's book
and then it was all downhill.
Well,
it's a huge.
I mean it's really going exponentially
now.
But actually I have on my list here,
I wanted to mention it to you because
you have a pretty big audience.
And I have a.
I have a standing incentive offer that
anybody who gets 10 people together to
go on and needs Egypt.
Trump gets the freebie.
Well minus the minus the airfare and the
blockchain.
The tips.
What we might do,
sir,
is we might buy out the whole thing by
all your whole tour.
And then brian downey down to go to
Egypt.
I'm talking to my cohost,
my cohost says,
fuck yeah,
he's down to go and we'll get all our
friends together except joey because
joey,
he can't leave the country.
And uh,
we'll,
we'll take a desk squad tour to Egypt.
That might be amazing.
Wow.
I'd be down with that kid.
Would it be safe to take children?
Yeah.
Normally.
But how old are the kids?
Really young too.
And for,
you know,
they're portable at that age,
but it's done.
That can be done.
That's not what I want to hear.
I want to hear.
Yeah,
it's like disneyland.
No,
I mean depends on the kids,
but that's not going to get anything
that's spelled 14.
They do get something out of it,
but you can do is,
you know,
that the egyptians love kids,
so you're just.
Wherever your hotel is,
you hire a nanny who plays with the kids
while we go out and looking.
That's never happened.
But um,
let's talk about the temple and man,
because that was one of the most
fascinating things of that magical Egypt
series was how the egyptians,
the construction wasn't just beautiful.
IT wasn't just a functional art there,
there was,
there was a methodology to what they
were making were they were literally in
that one temple.
They neared the human body and explain.
Explain that because it's really a
fascinating.
It's like a tribute to the human
anatomy.
well,
it's not only as a tribute to the human
anatomy,
but it's stronger de lubicz.
The great genius with the
unpronounceable name mean names mean a
lot.
For example,
einstein is a great name for a genius
of.
His name was manny plotnik.
No one ever would have heard of a lot
smaller and smaller.
The luggage was a genius scholar and he
really was brilliant and he realized
it's a gun.
More long story if you're a serpent in
the sky and read my book.
No,
I have not.
Uh,
okay.
Well,
start putting the sky.
What's called In the sky.
It's called surfing in the sky,
the high wisdom of ancient Egypt at the
center of copy.
Anyway,
um,
he realized as he was doing the work on
this on,
on Egypt,
I'm the temple of luxor.
He had actually,
he went to Egypt.
He was a very interesting men,
died in the early sixties and never met
him.
Um,
and he was a practicing alchemists,
many of those floating around these
days,
but he went to Egypt because according
to the,
and I only realized this quite recently.
I thought the opposite until quite
recently,
but see the,
the egyptian tradition percolated down
to the west and what are called the
hermetic tradition,
which is astrology and magic and number
symbolism and neoplatonism and all bunch
of these other disciplines.
Never coherence as It needs it,
and schwaller went to Egypt and 37 in
order to see if because they,
the renaissance scholars,
people like jeff dunham,
brunello and capital,
and all of them were convinced.
I mean they took it on trust that Egypt
Was the founder of of wisdom.
The greeks agreed with that,
but nowadays,
see this stuff's supposed to
civilization.
It's supposed to have started with the
greeks,
but great stock,
most of what was consequential and more
accurate in their on their own
civilization from the egyptians and
they're very open about it.
It's the modern day quack academics that
want to understand that because very
interesting book,
black asina,
the aphrodisiac roots of greek
civilization by a very fine cornell
scholar called martin burnout and
basically he proves that what we call
history is really a white supremacist
eurocentric invention put together by
the,
by the ninth,
mainly by the 19th and early 20th
century historians because they were
determined to prove that real
civilization began with the greeks.
Because the greeks were swarthy little
guys,
but light enough.
They weren't egyptian or submitted or
black or anything like that.
Or subsaharan african,
like the spanx,
certainly not so.
So really history as it's taught even to
this day is really a white supremacist
con job.
So it really is possible that sub
saharan africans might've built all that
stuff.
Well maybe.
Yeah,
that could be.
They obviously built that face or or
likely built that thing.
That's very likely.
Hey,
can I take a break?
Yeah.
Get yourself some vodka.
I wish I had some over your hair.
Oh,
why don't you.
I'll fly you out fella.
Okay.
Anytime you want to come down to la and
do this in person,
let me know.
All right.
We'll be right back with John Anthony
West as john goes and uh,
get some more vodka.
Fucking love it to computer fan.
I love all of it.
I love his computer fan going off is
every time he gets an email to beep,
every time you get a fucking text
message or a message from skype,
that shit comes out.
Can you,
can you turn that off?
Skype messaging,
whatever the hell that is.
But uh,
everybody who's listening to this,
thank you very much for,
uh,
for being patient.
And then,
uh,
and if you're not familiar with this
particular subject,
it's one of my personal favorites and
john's dvd series,
which is called magical Egypt,
which you can still purchase online.
I think it's magical.
Egypt.com,
I believe you can also get it on amazon
and a bunch of different places,
but it is just fantastic and it's
really,
really entertaining stuff and it has to
do with so much of why Egypt is so,
such a fascinating and mysterious
culture.
It's really a one of the most amazing
dvd series you can get and it's at no
one,
but it would take a guy like john who's
spent his whole life being obsessed with
Egypt to produce something like this.
It's a real work of a,
of passion and interest.
And uh,
I've,
like I told him,
I've watched it like 100 times.
It's,
it's,
it's incredible.
It's great stuff because he's still
gone.
Do we have an image of him?
Oh,
you're back.
There you go.
No,
I don't think he can get it on amazon.
You can't.
I don't think you can,
but you can get it direct through me or
through that website so you can go to my
website and think.
So
I thought someone was selling it on
amazon.
Sometimes they do that.
Yeah.
I don't think it's on amazon and
actually it's really,
it's not me,
it's my,
let's say it's my work that sets it off,
but it's really my genius partner named
chance gardener who's responsible for
that.
I mean he,
he,
he was a guy making a lot of money in la
as a three d animator and he got
fascinated with this whole subject sort
of like you.
Well just john,
just to let you know,
just to let people know and let you know
because you might not know this.
It is available on amazon.com.
Not only is it available on amazon.com,
it's also available on amazon instant
video.
People can watch it instantly.
Is amazon jacking you,
are they paying you for this,
john?
No,
it's my partner handles the,
the,
uh,
it's amazon who is my partner who
handles the business side of things,
but I know really
well you've been ripped off before,
right?
He told us she got ripped off for the
other one,
but in this case I think I'll have to
check with chance check in on that guy.
Oh,
I know that it's,
it's,
you know,
the whole thing is just brings in no
money.
You know,
he's,
he's sacrificed for five years of his
life putting this extraordinary thing
together and then people pirate it all
the time.
And this thing you can do about it.
I mean it's really criminal.
Yeah.
People,
if you want to watch the magical egypt's
p series,
don't watch it on youtube or watch it on
any of those places where it is pirated,
please go and a and supported because
uh,
like I was saying,
john,
when you went to get your vodka,
it's one of my favorite all time dvd
series and it would take a guy like you
to put something like that together who
was such a work of passion.
Like very few people are going to put
together eight dvds.
Who did that really see?
I mean he,
he,
he got it going and I supplied obviously
I supplied the egyptology and we
conferred on how to do it,
but he's single handedly produced it,
shot it.
It's really brilliant.
And you know,
as soon as it's done on a shoestring so
it doesn't look like a glossy nbc
production.
But it's beautiful.
It doesn't really.
I'm proud to have been a part of that,
you know?
I mean we're partners,
but credit where credit is due.
I mean left to my own devices.
I know I could write,
I could write the script,
but I couldn't do the production.
Yeah,
it's really an amazing piece of work.
Says well worth getting hold of and
actually on,
on the subject of putting this stuff
together.
I've been talking in any number of
occasions about us doing this.
The next video they zipped happy.
The dawn of civilization.
And actually I should mention this
because I,
I have,
I have a nonprofit foundation that we
set up with that 10 years ago,
but the ancient wisdom foundation,
but it's been since most of the time,
you know,
people would contribute now and again we
use it for travel and research and that
sort of thing.
But now we've got a really bright guy
contacted me,
kind of the whole work and fascinated by
the whole thing and he's really,
he's got the smarts and the drive to put
it all together and rebid the fly it.
So it's now,
it's now the website is under
construction,
but we're,
we're now looking to both micro finance
and macro finance this show.
And it's funny because it's been an idea
of mine for decades and now it's become
a possibility.
I mean years ago.
So I haven't devoted my entire life
through Egypt and these things because I
started out as a novelist,
a playwright and a screenwriter and have
a lot of things done.
And actually,
I think you asked me this earlier,
like I wandered off from the subject,
but as a,
as a young kid,
how did I get into this?
I started out,
I realized what about the age of 12 or
13 that I was living in a lunatic
asylum.
Everyone else called progress.
But I mean I knew it was madness,
but I couldn't put it together.
But by the time I was 19 or 20,
I knew what I wanted to do.
I knew I was in a lunatic asylum and
what I wanted to be was I wanted to be a
little boy at the emperor has no clothes
and that's what I started out writing
satire.
It's brutal satire plays and things that
were done.
There might be money.
I'm trying to resuscitate some of that
stuff now.
But anyway,
and then gradually,
gradually,
gradually I understood that there was
another.
The human beings,
we're not always insane.
And one,
one music,
classical music,
beethoven's quartets and month of these
vessels of 16 it's 10.
And then when I was in the army in
Germany,
needless to say,
list drafted my.
but I had a great time.
I was in Germany,
my one and only porsche for $2,400
from the factory talking about.
Yeah,
well that's what it was.
And those was.
And I remember driving as I was driving
to France and early,
it was a november all by myself.
I'm early in the morning,
went to the cathedral of shots.
It was absolutely empty.
I mean this is before there was any
traveled to europe and,
and I realized that it was an epiphany
that,
you know,
however monstrous the church was and is
somebody geniuses,
built this incredible structure.
And then it took another few.
I still didn't put it all together and
took another few years before and by
this time I'd had my first short story
published and I was living in Spain on
the island,
but visa and,
and gradually gradually understood,
you know,
there was another side to this and then
all of a sudden,
again,
more complicated story.
But I got interested in the gurdjieff
work and be so it would become old
touristed up and connected with my first
wife and we moved to england.
She was an actress,
I wanted to get into the gurdjieff work
and they're the first,
the first nonfiction book,
the case for astrology showed up and
that's how I got into smaller.
So that's about the late sixties when I
got interested in,
you know,
when I really,
when I really got interested in all of
this stuff.
Anyway.
Anyway,
the,
the uh,
but I always had this idea because I had
enough experiences with,
you know,
with hollywood and um,
and you know,
the film,
the film industry and,
and even the apical side of things and
that you know,
that the,
the producer's own you and to get
anything that's really original,
done the way that you wanted done is
next to impossible.
and I had this idea that somehow or
another micro financing projects of you
couldn't do it in those days.
I mean,
how are you going to send out a billion
mailings or anything like that.
But now with the,
with the internet,
you can get to these huge databases.
And so and so now we've got,
we're putting in place a and micro
financing aspect of it.
And actually I have,
I've always been good at thinking up
good marketing ideas and just never do
them.
well john just get on twitter,
you need to get on twitter and then get
a kickstarter accounts.
Well,
but what we're doing,
and I'm going to talk about it now,
it's not yet a promise because we have
to make sure the lawyers that it's
legal,
but we think it's legal.
We pretty sure it couldn't be illegal,
but we have a cool.
I came up with a really cool incentive
offer,
which is that if you put in,
if you get on it for a $50 donation and
you can split it,
you know,
you guys can put it in five each and one
of them is going to win.
That'S what you put in 50 bucks and that
buys you a ticket to effectively a
raffle.
And when,
when we get up to 50,000,
we got up to $50,000.
We have the drawing and somebody wins a
free trip to Egypt with me.
So we think that that's because I'm very
interested in getting to the young
people.
Actually,
you know,
people my age will mostly people my age
anyway,
but,
but um,
but I'm particularly interested in
getting this message to young people and
you know,
50 bucks for some people is,
is a lot,
but it isn't really a lot of figure it
out.
I mean,
what's 50 bucks?
It's 10 beers that are not very good bar
or a meal.
The tool,
they're not very good restaurants.
Um,
anybody can figure it out.
Couldn't afford 60 bucks.
So we're,
we're putting this into place and if you
do go online,
I think the website is up already.
It's ancient wisdom,
ancient wisdom,
ancient wisdom foundation.org.
Now when you go on these egyptian trips,
how long did they take
the standard is now,
I think it's 15 or 16 days.
Door to door.
Whoa.
That was really intense.
I mean I'm,
I'm talking what's going on now?
Those aren't all day long.
So it's all day.
You talking for 15,
16 days.
Yeah.
That's got to be exhauSting.
Yes,
but it must keep you pretty,
pretty sharp on egyptian history.
Will we?
Not only that actually gets that.
You see,
see Egypt,
nobody in America has ever experienced
the real civilization,
what we have progress,
what we call it progress is the
antithesis of civilization.
This is shiny barbarism.
And so Egypt is an eye opener and as I
said,
I came to it,
you know,
through arts and great sacred music and
through the shop.
and then suddenly I realized how
important this loves and along came
smaller and all of the study,
but what Egypt does is that it
introduced to them through the symbolist
symbolist interpretation which was
smaller de lubicz put together.
OTherwise it's just academic egyptology
kind of like angry actually because
you've experienced this fabulous art.
you get listened to all this bullshit
that that's telling you that has no
connection with what you've actually
experienced.
So,
so Egypt,
as I often start lectins all by saying
Egypt is like sex that gets everybody's
attention lives these like sex.
Now you can read all about it and I've
kinda been fussing and you can look at
pictures and that's kind of interesting
too.
Like until you've actually experienced
that,
you don't understand anything about it.
So he ends up is like that once you're
there,
it hits,
I mean there's no mistaking about it
and,
and so it's,
it's to me it's very gratifying to be
able to be,
to be the agency for allowing people to
have that experience and unfortunately I
had originally hoped to have a little
business where there are a handful of
people who understand symbolist Egypt
well enough to retranSmit it,
but actually I'm the only one who does
these trips.
So one other person could.
very brilliant lady called normandy
ellis,
but even that doesn't have the
intellectual rigor,
the mine,
my stuff does.
So I'm almost the only show in town,
but it's very satisfying to me to be
able
to be able to open this experience to
people.
And also invariably the trips have very
interesting people on them with
expertise in a number of,
of disciplines that are relevant to
Egypt.
So no trip goes,
goes by without me,
without me learning a lot myself.
I mean I send sometimes very important
things so it doesn't get tiring and
yeah,
it's a lot.
It's physically,
it's a lot of work,
but now I'm in pretty good shape for my
age.
John,
I wanted to ask you a question about the
more recent idea that perhaps the blocks
and the pyramid.
We're not cut from stone,
but rather made out of a limestone
concrete.
Have you?
Are you familiar with these theories?
Yeah.
That's the video that's and that's been
looKed into like geologists and and it.
It's completely untenable and the video
should know better.
He's a polymer scientist or something of
the sort.
Shock has looked at this very carefully.
It would be as much work to pound the
stone into into powder and then put it
into molds and you see the stones are
all different sizes so you can't do it
that way and when you look at the stones
you see at the,
at the blocks that what's called a new
analytic limestone,
which has lots of little seashells in
it.
Looking like the shelves.
I'm going to let cockle shells and
they're all intact,
so it's.
It's a silly theory and on the surface
it doesn't sound on the surface.
It sounds as though it might be
convincing,
it was convincing enough so that
somebody,
a friend of mine put together a panel of
geologists who don't have an ax to
grind.
It's not as though there,
it's not as though they're egyptologists
are archeologists who have,
uh,
you know,
have a stake in the thing.
They go there with an open mind to look
into it.
And shock certainly does.
I'm,
no,
it's not,
they're not.
And it wouldn't be juSt as much work to
do it when they're good,
it's the self says it will take a month
to produce a limestone blocks and cure
it well enough so that you could
actually use it.
so no,
it's not.
So it's just silliness.
well,
that's incorrect and correct.
Some things,
some things as silly and then see the,
the alternative side of the argument is
as irresponsible as the academic side,
because people get notions in their head
that it's all built by alien could be
built.
My audience.
I can't disprove that but,
but there is unwilling to let go of
their fantasies as the academics are
unwilling to let go of what are not
fantasies.
But other times when they're incorrect,
incorrectly develop theories has been
that all being in I've been round,
solidly disproved like people like
ourselves.
No,
john,
there's also an issue with the area
underneath.
One of the sphinx is pause that a
seismic charting has revealed that
there's some sort of a,
um,
uh,
a room down there,
some sort of a,
there is some sort of in the cavity or
chamber we don't know.
I mean,
and edgar casey,
one of his,
one of his channels,
sessions of transits,
whatever he called him,
said that,
not the,
it was a chamber beneath this,
one of the eight different descriptions
of it,
but basically underneath one of the
flaws of the strengths that contained
the secrets of atlantis.
Now our seismograph tells us that there
is,
that,
there is a cavity there.
But,
and this is a question that comes up all
the time,
um,
and they say,
why can't they excavate?
Well,
we're the geophysicists to did this work
of in shock was there,
but we didn't get named becky who's a
geophysicist,
you know,
who does the,
it's like an underground radiologists,
you know,
the,
the seismograph reading that to you or
me would be completely meaningless,
like an x ray was meaningless to you or
made,
but the radiologist continue a lot of
very precise information from an x ray.
So with,
uh,
with a readout from the seismograph and,
and,
and the,
the,
uh,
tom to becky sent from this,
from the shape of the,
of the read out.
It looks as though it is a chamber more
or less rectangular.
It's under about 15 feet of bedrock on
top of that.
Um,
and there is actually a chamber with tom
didn't even know about behind the spanx,
a rough cut chamber.
There's a block and you pull a block
away and a little rope ladder.
You can go down into this rough cut
chamber where there's nothing and nobody
had been able to figure out who caught
it or why or when.
But there is such chamber there.
And on the,
on the seismograph readout,
the this looks the same.
In other words,
they get certain colors and stuff like
that.
It looks the same as what you get under
the sink.
So the becky who put his neck on the
line said,
well,
this looks like consciously like there
is a chamber there.
The problem is getting in there because
it's below what's now the water level,
the water table level.
So you can't really excavate or you
would be an enormously difficult.
I go under water actually.
You go under water,
you mean
as you drill?
I do a dig into it.
You would actually go under water.
In theory you could flip down one of
those little fiber optic cameras,
but if it's all water in there,
you're not going to see anything anyway
to actually excavate it would mean going
in there with,
you know,
with huge pumps pulling the water out as
fast as it came in.
And this thing says the stinks
be almost impossible.
Right?
I'm the sphinx is.
It would be possible,
but it would be dangerous because the
sinks,
as you know,
it was in pretty rough shape as it is.
I meaN,
pieces fall off that all the time,
things like that.
So it may be one of these days who knows
if the theory takes it takes root and
the,
the uh,
you know,
the powers that they realize that it's
not good pr among other things to try to
excavate it and see if there is anything
there.
Meanwhile for me,
I'll stick with the geology and the
other pieces of evidence.
I don't,
I don't give an awful lot of thought to
that,
but the seismograph says there is
something there.
Yes.
Have they detected any other
undiscovered ruins or any undiscovered?
Uh,
I mean,
areas that they Would like to explore in
Egypt.
Are they,
do they pretty much have the entire area
mapped out?
Well,
they have a complex question.
I haven't pretty well mapped out because
that I recently,
I forget the woman's name very
interesting.
The satellites flying over a gun.
I'm not sure if it's infrared or
something that gives you,
I think it's infrared photography
without that tells you if there's
something underground,
but the photography only goes,
doesn't go that deep,
you know,
it goes 10,
15 feet something I think.
And,
and if,
if we're correct,
if there is anything that's really
completely buried,
um,
it will be deeper than that and,
and celebrate.
So the photographer,
the infrared,
whatever it is,
I think in the infrared,
doesn't let him know about that,
but it ought to be there.
I mean,
look what the spanx.
For example,
if the head we're not sticking above the
ground,
you wouldn't even know about it to this
day.
Yeah,
it's true,
right?
Yeah.
But you wouldn't know.
It was just being sad.
And then why would anyone bother?
But the,
with,
with these different new technologies,
certainly ground penetrating radar and
seismographs will tell you if there's
anything there,
but they're expensive and not.
You've got thousands of miles of desert
and this is a slow process.
Whereas a flyover tells you a lot.
Something.
Know that there's,
that.
There's that,
there are lots of varied sites,
but if they're that close to the
surface,
the chances that they,
that they're going to,
they're going to support the ancient,
you know,
what we call it,
a lost civilization.
Hypothesis was not necessarily
commanding and from art for our
purposes,
it doesn't even matter because we have,
we have enough to go by anyway.
I mean go back tap night and probably
this easter island stuff and the magical
bracelet and certain of the other things
there,
a megalithic sites in sardinia,
which I'm not to be believed and nobody
even knows about this.
A treasure trove of megalithic sites.
So I didn't,
you know.
Yeah,
they didn't just invent sardines.
This as this wonderful architecture
there,
these huge beehive shaped stone
buildings that are really amazing.
So we don't need that.
All we need is the,
all we need is the,
is the financing to do our,
to,
you know,
to do our,
our,
our followup to the mystery of the
slangs.
And ideally what we want to do really is
to get it into the theaters and then go
into tv.
And uh,
and um,
you know,
in the web and all of that stuff,
right?
Well you see if something has a high
impact,
but if you see a lot of the video,
like viral videos that have been
released online that have gotten
millions and millions and millions of
viewers just by word of mouth,
I really think that video on demand as
well as a,
as another great option.
Yeah,
it is a great option.
The problem of course is,
as you must know this,
I mean,
do you have ads on,
on the show?
Yeah,
we do.
Yeah.
The ones that we know,
you don't see any ads,
we just do them at the beginning of the
broadcast,
but the fleshlight add on the,
on it,
the nootropics ad does.
Those are the ones that we do.
We do those and that's it.
And then we have some,
there's some other sponsors that we're
working with in the near future,
but they're all done just by me talking.
Okay.
Really?
I mean because I'm blabbering on here
forever and there's no ads.
No,
we don't have to have ads.
We don't have to break any of the
conversation now.
That's the beautiful thing about it.
We get it over with him beginning.
We mentioned the the.
We thank the sponsors again at the end
and it'll allows a full two hour
intensive conversation and especially
something about ancient Egypt I think
demands that it's such a.
It's such a complex sort of a situation
to try to figure out how the
conventional wisdom is saying that when,
when did they believe languages invented
about 50,000
years ago,
something along those lines.
They don't even know.
Just guesswork.
Right.
It really is guesswork when you get
back.
That's the only thing that you couldn't
see couldn't say as a trend is that the
more they study,
the further back everything goes and not
only the further back in terms of time
with a further back in time in terms of
sophistication and see.
I mean actually look,
go beckley cafe,
which is.
I mean I hope,
I hope you find some photos to or I'll
send them to you so to intersperse with
with this talk so that people can
actually see what else?
Well,
I think a lot of people google along
with the show,
so that's probably what a lot of people
are doing right now,
but go back
still if that's.
Oh,
that's fine too.
So,
so I mean with god beckley tat they were
talking about 10,000
bc now you know,
that's five times the span of time from
jesus and julius caesar to us.
Pretty crazy.
That's pretty crazy.
Wrap your head around that
show.
Day.
The cave that she'll bang.
That's $30,000.
That's three times the time from going
back from attempt.
So you'll see it means that we have this
totally skewed vision of our human
civilization and of ourselves basically,
you know,
it's fucking lunatic.
Asylum is not,
it's not civilization.
Who in their right mind would invent the
bobble head doll put on american idol or
the reality shows this is insanity.
It isn't insanity,
but it's a channel a division achieved
and incredibly high technological level
of success.
We,
it seems to be a technology of a
civilization as opposed to what Egypt
was,
which was we don't know.
That's what makes traveling there so
interesting because they also had a
technology,
I mean in certain cases we couldn't
build the pyramids or maybe we could,
but it would would probably be more
expensive than a than a space program
and they did it evidently with these
and they did it in an era where we don't
even attribute them to having metal
tools.
They had bras that are not even the
hopper
and you say,
I don't know,
to me there's not much emotional impact
from the bottle.
Had dull where disney land for that
matter and if you walk into the egyptian
temples and then this happens on the
trips all the time because I just said
it's like sex.
You don't tell you the experience that
you really don't know.
Let us,
like we go into these temples and on my
trips now it's easy business practically
notes or isn't there?
But otherwise I go to a lot of trouble
to figure out when to go to places.
So the relatively people in there,
because it's important,
you know,
I mean it's like trying to listen to
beethoven's ninth symphony and in the
super bowl you can't do this.
Um,
so if you get there and you have
replaced more or less to yourself,
the emotional impact of these things is,
is Breathtaking and I felt bad.
You don't get that from walmart's.
No,
obviously not just garbage that goes on.
It's just a faCt that are obsessed with
technological rubbish and violence.
So of course we stupid vitamins.
Our setup is obviously very different
than theirs,
but we imagine ourselves to be the more
advanced.
It just that they don't have tv.
So we were like,
oh,
they were fucking idiots,
you know,
they don't have the internet were like,
well they were an advanced,
but meanwhile they're capable of these
massive constructions.
I wanted to ask you about the
sarcophagus in the king's chamber and
the,
the evidence that it had been made with
some sort of a high speed diamond bit
drill.
Well that's,
that's,
that's kristen's theory that we talked
about.
I mentioned kristen before.
Well we don't know.
Chris has seen.
Chris has to be,
he's not a new age for my his stepson,
let's talk to that.
It's very good composer and he was
talking about all of the new age music
and and the the album covers and he said
it's all a bunch of airbrushed unicorns
and that's become a metaphor,
but you don't have to the far out new
age kind of way of looking at bad
things,
but chris is not a nEw age kind of guy
and that's his field and he know he
interprets it that way except as no.
With all of the stuff that we've
discovered in Egypt,
there's no evidence whatsoever of having
that kind of technology.
Now this,
the idea of the lost civilization is the
idea that graham hanCock's idea that you
know,
there's.
There's a missing error that we can't
place.
When.
When do you belIeve that took place in
relation to the timeline of Egypt?
When was all the information or a good
chunk of it last and they had to start
from scratch?
Well,
we don't know because you see there's
enough.
They're not lots with scattered around
so that you can say maybe it was never
lost.
The was never manifested in this
spectacular architecture.
For example,
I was telling me before about the,
the red pyramid of does.
Sure that's built over a ruinous
negativistic structure,
but that megalithic structure is pretty
considerable.
It's sort of like new grange and certain
of the,
of the megalithic structures in england
and scotland and wales,
but you know,
this is not nothing.
and then this strange stone circle,
pretty ruinous called supplier and a b
t,
a p l a y in,
in south western Egypt,
west of abu simbel.
I'm not far from the,
from the Sudan border.
Now this is,
it doesn't look like much,
but even the academics acknowledged that
it's astronomically oriented and there's
a lot about it that,
that,
that puts his date.
They dated,
they academics data to about 6,000
bc.
Well,
astronomically oriented in 6,000
bc means already that it's investigated.
That's astronomy.
Not supposed to have this fun of me back
then.
And then is an interesting guy.
He's a friend of mine and physicists
and,
and um,
archeo astronomer who looks at the
evidence and interpret it,
interprets it in a much more
sophisticated ignatian that there,
there are indications there were at
least there they are referring back to a
time of about $16,000
or so,
bc,
even though the sun circle itself
satisfactorily dates to about 6,000
bc.
And then we go to the,
go back leads epi and we'd go to the
bracelet and I were talking 10,000
bc and the bracelet,
we're talking 8,000
bc and it shows,
hey,
these fabulous paintings of horses and
rhinoceros.
This isn't a bears and lions.
That's 31,000
bc.
So how much do you need?
No,
they're probably living in tents.
I dunno.
I mean they certainly weren't living in
condos but.
But they had this knowledge and this
artistry at their disposal and they had
it out a fantastically early time.
So we just don't know when they lost all
this stuff.
We don't know when the egyptian
civilization either,
whether it was a slow erosion,
whether it was a massive decline and
somehow or another it sort of coincides
with the end of the last ice age.
Is that a.
Is that a fact as well?
Oh yeah.
Well we think yes.
Because that's when the sea levels rose
300 seat and I mean it's,
it's a chaotic time then that's when all
of the madness and the will he run our
services and all that,
have that go extinct.
So and shark actually have some very
interesting,
very interesting theories about not just
shot and other people about what made it
go extinct and you know,
maybe some sort of a plasma strike,
like a gigantic,
some type of event is pretty good
evidence for this.
But anyway,
it disappears.
the sinks,
the sinks and go back to happy maybe
after that.
But if this links is earlier,
one of the,
one of the objections we always had the
nice,
well how could this be the evidence of
this amazing early civilization and
there's nothing else.
well,
there is something else.
There's lots of other stuff.
A lot of weathering and things of that
nature and nature,
but not,
not much of it.
Spectacular.
Go back to the tap tap.
That's spectacular.
So we don't know.
Are there hieroglyphs that detail?
Any of the construction methods that
were used
a little bit?
Um,
there's,
there's one,
there's one wall reliefs in nothing to
do with pyramids.
Know absolutely nothing and nothing to
do with these things.
I mean the egyptians disks,
we are blessed.
Nothing spectacular too.
That's something a lot of people aren't
even aware of.
How spectacular those are.
Well,
there are plenty of spectacular.
There's one relief in the temple.
Eventful,
which is a very late ptolemaic sample of
between 250 vc,
you know,
into roman times,
built in stages that shows the pharaoh
with a rope around an obelisk sort of
pulling it up into position by himself.
That's not meant to be taken literally,
unless it's a very small obsolescence,
but it needs to say is like it gets.
So when you see evidence,
I don't necessarily like stare in there
on the temple walls.
Love.
You can't really ignore it just because
you want to believe that the aliens
built everything.
So there's the pharaoh pulling the
obelisk up when there's a theory
developed.
It's the one favored by the politics at
the moment.
I mean even they can't be wrong all the
time.
And a bio needs of technologists named a
lobbying.
She,
um,
which talks about how they take these
obelisks which way?
Hundreds of tons.
They somehow get them out of the quarry.
This is really in words,
it doesn't make any sense.
When we were in Egypt and you're at
what's called,
it's called the unfinished obelisk in
aswan,
and here's this block of stone that were
pulling out of the rock and they didn't
make it for interesting reasons that
develop the fault line,
but had they got this block of stone out
of the bedrock,
it would've weighed 1200 tons.
That's a big stone.
And somehow in fact,
they've got an out of the quarry and
onto rafts or boats probably in the
flood season and drifted down.
Denial.
Maybe the luxor,
who knows?
We don't know where it was intended to
go and then they would have somehow or
another had to get it up into position
and according to the lobbying,
they did this by pulling it up,
gigantic ramp and it was set up in such
a way that with a kind of a no,
the up the ramp that would come up to
the ramp with the with this bottom at
the top part and then gradually with
lots of people with ropes and you'd be
surprised how how precise you can be
with lots of trained men with ropes and
they would gradually pull it up and and
it would go.
There was a kind of a deep shaft that
was constructed that was full of sand
and they'd gradually pull the sand up
from under and all of these guys pulling
the ropes gradually leave your up into
position.
Very exactly.
Place it down on his base,
but how they get the sand out the last
minute.
When you're there.
All of this makes sense,
but it's.
It's fascinating to try to figure out if
this is how it's done.
We don't know,
but the whole be concise,
like did it and it's pretty damn
amazing.
Well,
one of the things I thought was really
fascinating was when they had to move
some gigantic statues,
they had to cut them up and then replace
them in a new area.
They,
uh,
they had to like cut giant statues in
half.
I mean,
talk about that in incredible project
and what you thought about that just
from an archaeological standpoint.
That's,
that's abu simbel.
and it wasn't,
it was statues.
They were,
this is a temple cut into the rock face
and the four statues of ramesses,
the second were sculpted into the rock
face itself.
In other words,
they were integral.
It will not freestanding statutes.
So when they built the aswan dam and
they would have flooded this fabulous
place,
they got together a whole bunch of money
and $90,
million dollars,
I think it was.
Unesco got it together and they got all
of the engineers and what they to do is
they had to basically,
they had to move a whole so they have to
cut around the temple and then they have
to cut because the scratches enormous.
Sixty,
65 feet high and then they had to cut
them into four and move the blocks
because they moved the entire.
They moved the whole up to the top of
the hill.
Where were they were they were built
into because the water would have
covered where they were.
So that's,
that's abu simbel.
And so yeah,
they have to cut,
but they weren't freestanding.
snatches,
but still it was a modern,
you know,
it was a pretty considerable modern
engineering thing.
Otherwise.
Otherwise,
an example,
there's the statue of the colossal
figure of abram says that's the basis of
shelly's famous poem ozymandias no,
I met a traveler from an land,
blah,
blah blah.
And this is the statute that ways it
ruined.
It exploded in an earthquake somewhere
around julius caesar talk.
But,
but this,
this originally weighed about 2000 tons
and they got it down the river somehow.
And that's amazing enough,
but then I didn't get it off the boat.
In other words,
assuming that they're moving it in flood
season on giant rats,
then they've got to get the rafts.
We've got to get this thousand ton block
off the raft.
Move it into place.
Well the actual moving it on the flat.
There are when you're talking about
before,
what evidence is there,
there's one or two months from the tomb
relief showing viewed sledge with the
giant colossal statue of feral on it and
then lots and lots of men pulling the
sledge over the over the land.
When somebody in the front pouring
something,
maybe some water cause slick mud
actually is remarkably slippery and you
can pull things up.
As I said earlier,
what you see is what you get.
You can't deny that evidence when you
see the evidence in front of your nose
and say,
oh well let's aliens dropping things
from helicopters and stuff.
Then the evidence is there.
That's the evidence.
But you've got to be careful about the
evidence of there are seeing symbols,
but look like alec up their template.
Bobby does,
but I'm not this complicated subject.
Yeah,
an incredibly complicated subject now,
or no,
no subject of ancient civilizations
would be complete without a discussion
of ancient sumeria and,
uh,
the,
the fantastical work of zachariah
switching.
I'm sure you're familiar with all that
stuff.
What's,
what's your take on zacharias hitchins
ideas that,
you know,
the annunaki came from another planet
for a lot of people don't know.
it's some pretty crazy stuff that states
that human beings were created through
genetic engineering and.
Yeah.
Well,
I,
I think actually I'm not and,
and I find when wouldn't sits in I,
I mean,
I can't challenge his translations from
the,
from the sumerian.
Um,
it was,
I just can't,
but they're his translations and
unfortunately are the best of my
knowledge.
I don't know of any of the sumerian
experts who bothered to take a look at
his work,
which is too bad.
I mean,
it's irresponsible,
but I do know that when he's talking
about Egypt,
he's totally off the wall.
Totally.
And from that I extrapolate and do not
much care for his work.
And when he gets into explaining who the
gods were,
um,
that they're,
they're alien,
they're aliens,
as malignant is ourselves,
who enslaved the a primitive human
rights created the gods of Egypt and
everywhere else are really just aliens
that have been misunderstood by
primitive imaginations.
This is really stupid and malignant
bullshit.
Here's a bit of evidence that one of the
egyptian creation myths concerns that
the god before there were any gods,
the god called attune,
who exists before there is existence as
it were,
and he creates existence through an act
of masturbation.
He creates the first poll,
the first polarization,
the first female,
and the male is the biblical vests.
Well,
now This is an ancient alien,
and this is a suction suction esque
interpretation.
What is it that the primitives saw?
An ancient alien whacking off behind the
trade and decided that this was how the
universe was created.
It has absolutely nothing to do with.
There's another words,
the gods of Egypt,
from the gods of all other
civilizations,
including those in sometimes think
primitive,
represent cosmic principles.
They are not people,
they are not aliens.
They are principles and they are
scientific scientists don't like this
either,
but,
but when you look,
when you look at egyptian mythology and
try to and try to historicize it as it
were,
you flying the urine,
the urine,
this is a ludicrous exercise and as far
as I'm concerned,
the whole notion that we human beings to
creators,
not searching,
but some others did create the cathedral
of shotgun and the builders,
the temples of Egypt and so on or
somehow or another diluted,
diluted,
primitive,
so were who were enslaved by aliens and
who then found a way to set themselves
free,
but remember they're alien backgrounds
and commemorated them,
and all of this wonderful law contacted
this is really stupid and not only is
it's stupid,
it's,
it's malignant,
it's malignant in the same way,
it's the opposite of that sale.
Darwinian evolution,
which you know in other words,
have it.
It deprives human existence of all
meaning,
and that's in fact what modern science
does.
Modern rational as science deprives us
of any meaning in life,
and in fact,
they're very proud of it.
You should read some of this.
Do you?
Do you contemplate how we were created
or how we burst out from the lower
hominids how there's all these other
primates running around that we did not
sure that we did.
No,
I think there's no evidence for that.
There are lower.
They were hominids and then there's us
and the further back you go.
There we are again.
This is a situation ask stuff except
it's called science that we have to have
had that we have to have had more and
more primitive beings that were
responsible,
you know,
that gradually became us being apes and
became people.
And what do you think happened?
We are doing show day and go directly to
epic and the snakes and so on.
I don't live that.
Put two seconds actually actually
shotgun.
I high up on our list.
Um,
in fact,
one of the reasons I got,
I got onto the floor.
He did a lot of times.
Um,
funny story that call I got hold of
shock because I developed the,
I developed the strength theory all on
my own.
I'm not a geologist and several months
in the in the library's working out the
geology and convinced myself,
let's put together the whole theory of
the water weathering and then it just
sat there for 10 years a serpent and
this guy was published and whenever it
was when 79,
something like that and nobody paid any
attention to it.
And then I had a friend who'd been
teaching english at cairo and american
university in cairo and he was very
interested.
he got ahold of my work,
was very interested and one day we were
having not taught at boston university
and one day we're having a dinner and he
said,
you know,
this symbolist Egypt stuff.
Your instance I think really important
as I said.
So he said,
well,
how do we,
what can I do as an academic to help
healthier?
And I said,
they're instantly.
I said,
fine.
The geologist to look into the,
the water weathering of the spanx.
And I laughed.
I said,
I knew from lots of experience that
finding an open minded scientists and
it's like finding a fundamentalist
christian who loves his enemies.
And,
and he said,
well,
wait a minute,
it seems with me anyway,
one thing or another lead to robert
chalk.
And gradually,
gradually,
at first he did,
he was interested in the evidence.
He didn't let,
he didn't want to even,
I wasn't even supposed to know his name.
And finally because he was up for tenure
and it was,
anybody thinks they're looking for a
lost civilization.
And up here we were up for tenure,
not going to get your tenure.
Anyway,
eventually chalk and I met and as I
said,
I've been,
I,
I find not evolution.
Evolution is a plaque with our windy and
evolution by natural selection is
arguably the greatest superstition ever
foisted upon the human race.
Do you believe happened?
How do you believe that human beings
came to be?
I don't know,
but I don't know how mosquitoes came to
be there.
And the,
and the.
And the darwinian explanation is so
explanation is completely untenable.
What's,
what's our song is that a human beings
would evolve through net or progress
through natural selection that's on top.
That's,
that's,
that's a lot of the key.
See,
when we shock,
and I,
let me,
let me go backtrack to when I met up
with shock and so it was very,
uh,
cautious mEeting and mean he was
involved with this loony heretic,
me and we were getting on pretty well
and having a discussion and I gave a
lecture.
He organized a lecture for me plus the
universities to the faculty and
interested students and that went quite
well.
This is what we're talking now,
89.
And then I went back to [inaudible]
house for dinner and I'm as a subject of
evolution came up and he's not just a
geologists and geophysicists but
paleontologist as well.
So he was very into the whole
evolutionary hypothesis.
And I mentioned the,
you know who stephen jay gould was?
No,
I do not ltl low lee.
They died not too long ago,
but he was everybody's favorite.
Um,
he was everybody's favorite sharpies
geologist or biologist.
He was sort of like the equivalent of
carl sagan.
You know,
he was right.
Yeah.
Well,
he was sort of the carl sagan of geology
and evolutionary biology and using the
new yorker all the time and all that
sort of stuff.
And I said the shotgun,
we got into carefully answer the whole
question of evolution and um,
and I said,
well,
what do you think of stephen jay gould?
And he's always a bozo.
I didn't know that somebody I could talk
to realize that this guy wasn't deemed
literate,
but a bozo.
And actually without getting deep into
this,
because this is,
this is our next book after we were at
the bridge of sarah,
chuck has really into this,
I hope,
the definitive anti darwin book,
not anti evolution anti darwin.
And let me just give you a little clue.
Use the language yourself.
Everybody does natural selection.
A lot of this is not science.
This is the,
the,
the equivalent of george orwell's
newspeak.
It's science fake.
If you look at the two words themselves,
natural selection is,
is,
is promoted as the means whereby sings
automatically by a series.
this is a quote from a very famous
evolution,
darwinian daniel dennett.
A series of lucky coincidence is
produces mosquitoes and us and all the
rest of it,
and this is supposed to be the agency
for this is natural selection.
Whether we look at the word natural,
if you go to the dictionary,
even the great big oxford english
dictionary that I have,
and look up the word natural,
nowhere does natural mean accidental or
fortuitous.
Natural simply means of the natural
world,
so to say that it's natural means that
it's accidental,
has nothing to do with the word.
Natural doesn't describe accidental,
has no nowhere does it come out or
suggest fortuitousness,
and then you look at selection.
This is also selection.
Selection presupposes choice and
purpose.
The roulette wheel does not select the
number that the ball is going to fall
on.
People are selected for the nba.
Draft candidates are selected for
running for office.
It suggests choice.
Natural suggests hierarchical order of
the most sophisticated purpose,
so to call an accidental process.
Natural selection is a con job.
If they wanted to describe it.
Actually.
Actually,
daniel dennett does a very good job.
he says,
evolution is nothing but a series of
lucky coincidences.
If they call the whole theory,
the siri of lucky coincidences would
stop sounding scientific.
We don't know how any of these things
developed and the,
the much derided,
what do they call themselves,
the intelligent design people also,
they use the wrong a bit.
They use the wrong language because
intelligent design suggests a designer
and then you're talking about god,
and of course they're not,
they're not going to be talking about
god and getting away with it in academic
circles.
But in fact,
if they called it intelligent
creativity,
that'd be closer to the mark.
Creativity is built into the universal
structure.
It's,
it's creativity itself,
but we're in the middle of creativity,
um,
ourselves.
So it's very difficult to discuss this
particularly because we've been brought
up in this,
in this paradigm of,
of science speak.
And actually after the bridge of sarah
and shotguns,
as much into this as I am,
and he's,
you know,
he's got all the credentials behind
them.
We're going to do a book,
I think called.
It's like if I have my wife darwin,
darwin,
suddenly cycle dddd,
edd darwin debunked darwin declawed,
darwin dethroned,
a scientist and a scholar deconstruct
the cargo cult of the west.
It's a fraud from beginning to end.
It is not science.
Evolution is a process.
This is.
This is demonstrable.
The manner in which it manifests through
supposedly natural selection is a total
fraud.
So what you're saying,
just to clarify is that evolution is
real,
but the process of natural selection due
to random mutations and something you
don't buy,
you think there's.
There's more of a design element to it
all.
It more.
It seems to be acting and responding in
a creative and intelligent way.
That's right.
In other words,
it is creativity.
Creativity is there before anything is
created.
In other words,
it's,
it's the matrix in which things somehow
or another,
and we don't know the process evolved,
but it's not.
It's not.
It probably is not random and in fact
there's a ton of stuff when you get into
this.
I have a folder this live on nolan
evolution.
That's shocking.
I will let and I will get into
what
pretty soon,
somewhere along the line that it can't.
It can't work that way and the deeper
they look,
the more they find.
I mean,
I just had today actually you should.
You should write and conquer and get
this guys is.
I worked with them,
steve
list that he sends out every week of
interesting articles.
They were.
There was one just today,
maybe one of the other science things
that I get all the time about the
intelligence,
the intelligence of plants.
We actually communicate with each other
and so on.
In other words,
we exist within the creative matrix.
It's not that stuff just happens in all
of a sudden there's intelligence.
It's that there is intelligence and we
are the results of the intelligence.
Not that god woke up one morning and
said,
well,
today I think I will create mosquitoes.
Is that somehow that it's like imagining
for example,
do you suppose that the cells in our
body have any idea of or my body have
any idea that I'm.
Here I am talking to a guy called joe
rogan,
the three hours about these subjects.
They don't know.
I don't think they know something else
that they know,
so that's something like us.
We're cells in a,
in a much in a,
in a prodigious let intelligence and
directed organism and that's the.
That's actually the.
Even though you'd never know it from
listening to the bologna that the,
you know,
the priests and the or rabbis and all of
these imbeciles talk about this is
actually what's at the basis of all of
the religions,
however corrupt they become with we have
a function to perform in the whole
gigantic structure and it's,
it's hierarchical and it's organized and
it's up to us to do our bit to do it.
But natural selection is a set.
It's a linguistic fraud.
It's spin.
So this is where it gets really crazy
because where did the,
how did the human animal emerge if the
human animal didn't emerge from lower
hot minutes and we existed in this form
from the beginning.
Is that the supposition?
Because they've absolutely proven that
there had been loW lower forms of of
human beings,
other,
other different branches of the human
tree that that died off neanderthal.
For example,
Australia.
Pithy kiss is a,
a bunch of different ones from the past.
They suppose where what they call quote
unquote early man,
you don't buy that.
That's early.
We don't know where they lived within
themselves saying earlier.
they're assuming these are primitive
beings.
When I talked earlier,
I mean we,
we're going with our strengths and I go
back in our shell date,
april who produced day and as I said
earlier,
really are our level of development is
an inner thing.
You can't tell,
anD as I,
as I said earlier,
using the image of dance as an as say an
enlightened society idea that expressed
itself only in dance and by dancing
experienced the highest levels of
creativity.
See,
this is the thing that most of these
scientists are,
are seriously defective human beings.
They're uncreative bite nature and they
distrust their own emotions.
london that grants you listened to the
beethoven quartets and walk into this
cathedral of genre of the temples of
Egypt and that tells you a lot,
even if you can't necessarily explain
it.
I mean we,
however we are at maybe let's say the
car sufis in certain of the,
of the esoteric societies,
you know,
habit that we're there from the
beginning,
but we're only made manifest.
However that happens at a later date.
There's absolutely no evidence that,
you know,
they Come up with lucy or something like
that.
We don't know.
We have no idea what went on inside
lucy's art none.
But we do know that 65 million,
sorry,
we do paypal extrapolating,
rationalizing.
Basically wHat they're doing is they're
rationalizing their own emptiness.
We know that 65 million years ago there
was a mass extinction.
There's no flowering plants before that.
There was a completely different sort of
an atmosphere,
completely animals here.
What,
how,
what happened there,
I mean obviously if most life was wiped
out and the current life that we have
right now exists post 65 million years
ago
following this stuff,
which I do every week.
There's a new theory about what happened
65 million years ago.
We don't know and we,
in fact,
we don't even know if there were people
and there's some pretty good.
We still have an instance that dog to
settle down what I said,
tell that dog to settle down and I'm
going to tell him what's.
What kind of dog is it?
ThIs dude's awesome.
It just goes against his dog.
We should probably wrap this up too,
but I want to ask him about,
uh,
how many,
how many minutes are we in?
Two 45.
I want to ask him about the stoned ape
theory before we take off.
Hey,
there he is.
What's up buddy?
Is that a dog?
Can see his face rejection greyhound on
ancient egyptian ground.
Wow.
Your chips to the bone son louie.
You know,
dogs that got me interested in needs
into the goodwill when I.
My first short story was published in
[inaudible] 57.
I went to the island of the visa in the
corinthian in the mediterranean.
And these dogs stayed secure there.
No,
I wanted it.
They got me interested in needs at the
beginning.
I wanted to ask you one more question
about the development of human beings.
Are you familiar with the work of
terence mckenna?
Yes.
Were you familiar with his stoned ape
theory?
Yeah,
and I don't go for it.
You don't go for it.
For the folks at home is the doubling of
the human brain size occurred over a
period of 2 million years,
which he coincides with the rain forest
receding into grasslands and then the
lower hominids coming out of the trees
experimented with new food sources and
eating psilocybin mushrooms.
Yes.
That's,
that's actually funny because for
somebody who did a lot of,
a lot of experimenting with I Alaska,
which I've also done excellent.
Um,
he's,
he's extrapolating and trying to make
his experience fit in with darwinian
theory and he should know better than
that because it was a smart guy.
So you're,
you're feeling.
I'm sorry,
go ahead.
No,
I'm,
I'm more inclined to think,
you know,
listen,
the,
virtually all of the ancient texts talk
about a kind of edenic state,
you know,
and enlightened states that we descended
from another word.
We start at the top and degenerate.
And to me this is not,
this is,
this is not so difficult to imaGine.
I mean this,
it happens often that things,
the great teacher comes and everything
disappears,
you know,
we tend to think that everything's like
technology and it started off with an
18,
92 mercedes and suddenly we've got a
2012 ferrari.
But with Egypt for example,
it seems to be at its height at the very
beginning with no period of development
we don't know.
So it's Just.
So it's such a massive mystery and your
all,
your years of exploring it have
literally got you to the point where
you're like,
no one knows and not talking about it.
Nonsense.
Well anyway,
talking about it as though,
you know,
definitive terms.
Yeah,
in definitive terms,
just so crazy.
We just,
we just plain don't know.
But one of the things you can depend on
actually
is that,
who are you going to take your lessons
from?
The guys who invented the bobble head
doll and the atom bomb with the guys who
did shots and the temple of luxor and
the,
and the late quartets.
Me,
I'll go with the creatives any day
because I am one myself.
That's it.
I'm not.
How long was the period between the
decline of the old kingdom and the time
where they discovered the pyramids,
which were,
there was no one living in them when
they were discovered.
When,
when,
uh,
napoleon's army marched through Egypt.
There was no one living in the,
in the,
the pyramids like they,
where we lost a lot of information as
far as anyone knows to live in that
area.
Then there no one,
there weren't.
They didn't habit that area.
Oh yeah,
sure.
Okay,
good.
I mean it was all farmland around in
there.
They're in the desert with just a couple
of few hundred yards below with a sphinx
says this valley.
So yeah.
So it's all farmland and everything.
So my point was like,
oh,
what time did it all fall apart where it
was essentially the sphinx and the
pyramids and all that stopped being used
for what they were were abandoned and
then people had to come back to and go,
wow,
look at what we have.
You can sort of put a date in.
The egyptian religion died shortly after
first,
second century add,
who was no longer being practiced.
Although the knowledge percolated down
into alexandria and dispersed around the
middle east,
the library of alexandria.
This was,
this was a hotbed of,
of intellectual and philosophical
activity always.
I mean,
alexandria was always there,
but the actual egyptian religion as
such,
died somewhere,
let's say in the middle of the third
century,
add letters and said earlier than the
hermetic disciplines in alchemy and
astrology and magic and number
symbolism,
neoplatonism.
All of that knowledge continued
throughout,
you know,
throughout european civilization.
And we know this,
the renaissance,
the great figures of the renaissance.
So we're always credited with,
with opening way out of superstition and
so on.
You know,
an answer.
Modern science,
they did open the way to modern science,
but they themselves believe that their
own knowledge and kepler discovered the
laws of planetary motion.
He said,
I've discovered the.
I really discovered the secrets of the
egyptians.
It was a given to them that,
that all of this,
this advanced knowledge was available in
Egypt,
but it was trawler who actually this is
one of his great,
great,
great contributions that human thought,
which weiler,
who proves that they had no mistaking it
and they had it and it came out of
nowhere and they had it and it came out
of nowhere and there was nothing before
and then all of a sudden this incredibly
intelligent civilization.
As I said,
no you don't.
No,
no.
Just too crazy.
You keep going back and they keep going
back in.
The further they go back,
all of a sudden they come across
something that disproves everything they
thought the floor look show gay.
This is wonderfuL.
This is spectacular art in the cave.
How would those people living In that
television sets the bobble head dolls,
but if you can tank like that,
you've got something serious going on
inside you and who says they invented
it?
You see the further back you go,
the more tenuous everything gets.
Recently,
there've been some interesting studies
on flint knapping on,
you know,
in other words,
cutting flint to make to make different
kinds of tools with this is this is
actually a pretty advanced art and
they're finding flint tools,
very sophisticated tools that go back
200,000
years.
Well,
what was going through their heads that
they're doing this stuff.
We don't know what was going through
their hearts.
They've discovered this is again only
the last couple of years that sea travel
was going on between north africa and
I'm not sure if it was cypress or some
of the greek islands.
It's either 100,000
years ago or 200,000
years ago.
So if you follow this stuff,
the more the more that's discovered,
the more you become impressed that some
kind of advanced knowledge was always
there and even that is,
is based upon a technological.
It's the only way we tend to think a
technological assessment of what they
know.
We don't know what was going on inside
them.
We don't know how intelligent they were
and that the possibility is that they
were right for this intelligent from the
beginning.
Maybe it isn't even a question of
intelligence.
It's more requests and really a bit of
experience.
I mean how much intelligence do you need
to,
let's say it's to be moved like a dates
open courts at so you don't think about
this stuff.
It's just we're brought up in such a way
by this,
by this Nicholas Church and progress.
To think that you have to be able to do
complex mathematics and all kinds of
stuff in order to be civilized and then
even even when even when you have that
point of view,
the further back you go,
you see that they had a cosmology and
see that they had a geometry and they
had technology to produce to go back,
tap in the today.
So,
so the whole.
So the whole darwinian paradigm is
exploded.
When you take all of those things into
consideration,
is it possible that the dark darwinian
model works?
If you just take the timeline way back
then people evolved over hundreds of
thousands of years and hundreds of
thousands of years earlier than we
thought,
well,
that's what they say,
but why should it?
In other words,
in other words,
what is there and the what is there and
the nature of the hydrogen atom that
presupposes that that things are going
to get more complicated and
sophisticated.
Who says,
well,
we say by our own designs on earth,
our own physical,
you know,
our creations.
Should that be accidental?
Maybe they're not be,
why should there not be,
let's say I a plan to adjust this,
for example,
just as we grow from the fertilized ovum
and we go through this complex process
of gestation and then we're born and
then it's up to us with what we're going
to do with our lives and so on.
Who says that's an accident?
Yeah.
Yeah,
and we're not acting.
I mean,
to begin with,
how do you Prove that accidents?
See these assholes who happened on
creativity in them?
Are determined,
make the world sound as meaningless as
they experience it as bland and
passionless and as devops,
not deliberate
because they don't know any better and
in fact they hate creative people for
the most part.
Well,
that's one of the beautiful things about
your,
the,
the title of your dvd,
magical Egypt.
It really is really is and,
and thank you very much for coming on
the show today,
man.
You've explained a lot of things in
incredible detail.
It's been an honor to get to ask you
questions because I have been a huge fan
of your work for many,
many years now and I'm a huge fan of
that dvd series and I would love to go
eventually to Egypt with you someday.
We should do that.
We should figure something out.
That's to be that eventual you have to
do is talk about it and get 10 people
from your very,
very extensive store of people to go and
you can get a free trip.
I could do that.
we can make that happen.
We're going to do it.
I say one thing because I have a list of
things that I want to talk about.
One of them is,
I don't know,
do you know gerald celente is?
No.
A trends analyst and he's a very,
very interesting guys.
A colleague,
his name before he,
he is working with them is I'm cold
writer and executive editor of the
trends journal and it's,
I mean he's,
he,
he forecasts is probably more accurate
over the last 30 years than anyone else.
And we put out,
he puts out,
we put out,
he puts it really,
um,
something called the trends journal and
it's very interesting because what he
sees coming up,
it was not pretty and these right a lot
of the time.
And I mean I try,
I tried to tell people that it really,
because I'm talking the esotericism and
the ancient Egypt than the meaning of
the real civilization.
And gerald waS,
gerald is the,
between us and we've got really high
level people working is a brilliant
illustrator and we put out this journal
that light we.
I mean this thing is coming unstuck in a
hurry and people don't individually and
collectively prepare florid that going
to be unprepared.
And so we can add to the trends journal.
I think it's a.
Are you talking about a collapse in the
economy,
the end of civilizations,
that kind of thing.
Oh,
the under civilization as we know it,
very likely,
unless,
unless enough people act together
quickly and they probably won't.
so we buy gold.
You've got to get away plan.
And who here,
where can people get this newsletter?
It's,
it's a,
it's a journal.
Look up,
go to the trends journal or google up
gerald celente,
c e l e n z.
He's a very interesting guy.
He's a real.
He's a real slave swelling.
That's excitable.
It's agony.
It's on Alex Jones all the time.
The journal,
the journal is,
is a really interesting publication that
I'm very,
I'm very proud to be a big part of it.
Look it up for yourself.
We'll check it out and your website is j
dot [inaudible] dot com and you don't
have a twitter yet.
You find out about the trips and all
kinds of other stuff and you don't have
a twitter yet?
No,
I'm on facebook.
I know my daughter is looking after it
for me.
Tell your daughter to get you a twitter.
We need a John Anthony weSt.
Twitter will populate that very quickly
and people could find out about your
trips
because as I said,
we're.
We're,
we're reviving where reincarnating our
ancient wisdom foundation and by the
way,
I always put a plug in that before we
end up because it's.
I told you,
I mean we're pretty sure I can't be a
promise yet that we've got this
incentive thing going and if you pull up
ancient wisdom foundation.org,
there'll be some information about the
projects that we're involved in and and
I really do believe that that unless,
unless enough of us have humanity goes
back to recreates the civilization based
upon the ancient principles.
In other words,
we're not going to be build pyramids
again or mummify or arrows or anything
like that.
Look,
the principals meet needs,
if there's a one issue,
civilization is it's based upon the
quest for immortality above the notion
of the immortality of the soul,
which I absolutely believe in,
um,
and without that,
no civilization as possible.
So,
so the principles upon which Egypt and
the other instance civilizations are
founded is the principles are eternal in
civilization has passed when I said
we're not going to multiply our parents
again,
but without that understanding and
without an understanding of where we're
heading at the moment.
It's funny,
a scary stuff out there.
A lot of it is valid,
but most of the scare stuff doesn't have
the,
the antidote built into it.
And I like to think that that we do.
I think like the conversation we just
had is one of none of despair but have
the possibility of renaissance and
light.
Not something known as let's say a
spiritual doctrine is not something you
believe in.
Believes is useless.
It's not something you do do it
well.
John.
I think also there's just the ability to
spread that kind of information
knowledge to people and to be able to do
it in a forum like this.
It's very rare and very new and I think
that the internet and this open access
to information that we have on it is one
of the best hopes that we have for
turning this whole thing around and
thank you very much my friend.
Thank you very much for doing this.
I would like to do at any other time
with you,
we'll we'll eventually have to work some
kind of a cruise thing out and we'll.
We'll all go down to Egypt and get our
minds blown with you.
Thank you very much,
sir.
I really appreciate it.
Thank you.
Take care of brother.
Like that.
We'd done that for me,
man.
Just tell me when we're off skype.
Okay.
God for being,
man,
that was amazing.
Holy shit.
That guy's awesome.
Yeah,
that was,
you know,
I mean there you need a guy who's out
there doing something like that to get
the kind of information out and just I'm
just so happy that he exists.
Check out his magical Egypt dvd series.
It'll fucking blow you away.
Thank you to the flashlight for
sponsoring our podcasts.
Go to joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for the flashlight.
Entering the code name,
rogan saber.
Suffer van beacham the number one search
toured furman.
Thank you to alpha brain for all your
cognitive enhancing function needs.
Go to [inaudible] dot com.
That's o n n I t.
We have shroom tech,
sport,
shroom tech,
immune alpha,
brain and new mood,
a five htp and l tryptofan.
Mood enhancing serotonin boosting
supplement.
It's all good stuff.
It's all 100 percent money back
guarantee for the first order.
First order of 30 pills.
Try it.
If you don't believe in it,
you don't like it.
You don't want anymore.
say,
it sucks.
Get your money back.
This is how concerned we are with making
sure that people do not feel ripped off,
but instead we provide you with
something that I 100 percent believe in,
100 percent take and we stand behind it.
We don't want anybody getting ripped
off.
It's the shit.
I take it every day.
I take it before every podcast,
take it for every comedy show to a gay
father,
joe jieddo.
That's it for this week of the joe rogan
experience podcast,
but if you're fucking podcast starving,
I'm like,
dude,
I ain't heard you talk enough.
We are going to be back brian as well on
the ice house chronicles tonight.
What is it?
June the fuck are we June 8th,
friday night.
If you want to listen to it on itunes or
any other place,
you go to desk squad.tv.
It's the icehouse chronicles and you can
subscribe to it on itunes and get that
shit.
It's all of course for free,
like all the shit we give you guys
because we love you.
Big kisses and we'll see you soon.
thanks everybody for tuning in.
Are your energy
jihad.