Two,
one end.
We're live.
Justin ran.
How are you sir?
I'm great.
It's going on brother,
man.
I'm excited to be back here.
And they're kicking ass digging wells.
All of the above trying fights.
Have you had now back in Beltour?
Only a two to uh,
but I haven't been back since the first
or second one.
So this is what you are.
Yeah.
You were here before your first one,
which was a,
you had a long break for five years and
two months and I hadn't even really
trained any at that point.
Like I was.
I was just doing the wells and going to
Congo and then uh,
got back into fighting and only had a
little bit of time to train,
but it's,
it was uh,
it was okay.
But this time,
do you have it for your first fight?
I think actually whenever I was here
with you,
I uh,
I,
I fibbed a little where I said,
uh,
it was a little longer because I didn't
know if my opponent was going to watch
her or whatever,
but uh,
my,
my fight camp got cut in half.
Um,
I was traveling,
traveling,
the book was getting ready to come out
and other stuff and try and write the
book and prepare and trying to figure
all that out where were just talking
before we got on and about just life
stuff and scheduling it and everything
and they had the book and then Congo and
then telling people about it and then
also training for a fight and I didn't
know how to balance those real well.
But,
uh,
I play in 12 weeks,
all of a sudden,
Congo corruption took me to Congo for,
for three weeks at the beginning,
so we cut it down to nine weeks and then
whenever I got back or while I was
there,
I found out they were moving the fight
up on me three weeks.
Um,
and so it cut my camp down to about six,
seven weeks.
So six,
seven weeks after being off for more
than five years.
Yeah.
And I had trained a few times before
that,
uh,
I mean like within the few months
before,
but um,
but I,
I think it was probably tops two months,
a nine weeks.
We'll pause.
Weren't you just like,
just getting over malaria?
Yeah,
and I was,
uh,
that's,
that's the tough stuff.
That's a tougher in the fight.
I feel like.
Fuck man,
we have one of our guys in Congress
that's got,
had malaria,
one of our jewelers I just recently got
real sick and it's kind of like
constantly,
it's just part of life there,
Jesus.
And it doesn't matter what kind of
medication you take before you go out
there.
And I was actually taking a.
actually our director at water four was
taking,
um,
malarone.
It's like the best anti-malaria pill.
I think it's something like seven,
$8 every pill.
So,
uh,
it's,
it's the creme de la creme of Larry meds
and it didn't work on him and I was
actually going into Congo actually.
I stopped in London,
did one of those Ted talks at a
university called Warwick University.
And the day of the talk I was at a 100,
three degree temperature,
one to three point two.
And um,
and I thought it was pulling out.
They thought it was pulling out.
We were at the hospital for four or
five,
six hours.
Um,
oh,
and dude,
even the opportunity to go speak at that
is because their team was all fans of
jre.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
that was the opportunity gap because of,
because of this.
And man it was,
it was,
uh,
it was tough during the talk.
And then,
um,
whenever I got into Congo they told me I
had the flu in London and the doctors
there and that's what I feel like here
to.
There can be tropical medical medicine
specialist here and they're probably
really great.
But I would trust a doctor that's lived
in the climate,
the tropical climate around malaria that
seen it,
that knows all the symptoms,
well knows to look for it because no one
gets it over here.
Yeah.
And so whenever I got into Congo,
I flew from,
yeah,
from work to Congo in whenever I landed,
instead of going straight to the forest,
uh,
they took me to like a air strip at a
hospital in the middle of nowhere.
Um,
so I landed,
went straight to the hospital and then
right there they're like,
you don't have the flu,
you have malaria.
And I'm like,
but I,
I've been,
I've been in the states,
I just fought and then I have a in
Europe,
like there's no normal area really
there,
but it was because it's still living
inside me.
There's like,
um,
I think there's three strands.
One live in your body for three years,
five years.
I think the other is like 30 to life or
something.
Yeah.
And so it just comes back.
Yeah,
it can.
Like when your body's really rundown,
when you're really tired,
immune system's low,
like training for a fight,
like training for a fight or right after
the fight.
Uh,
right off the fight.
Went to London,
spoke,
then I went to Congo.
But right after the fight.
So you were recovering from malaria.
You go through your six week fight camp,
you have your fight,
your rundown.
And then after the fight you got malaria
again?
Yes.
Now the sickness.
I've had it now three times.
Oh my kids.
So at least confirmed twice.
The third time they're like,
yeah,
you have it for sure.
But they,
you with malaria,
you have to get the test,
the blood test while you have a certain
degree,
temperature fever,
uh,
whenever it's cycling out of your liver
and coming out,
they have to draw the blood at that
exact time to get it.
And so that's why I was misdiagnosed
four times in the Congo and um,
what a sneaky fucking disease.
Yeah,
it's nuts.
It's crazy because they'll,
they'll hide in your liver and then they
send them out in your bloodstream,
like a,
like a platoon.
They go and wreck havoc and then they
retreat right back to the liver.
Really?
They live in your liver?
Yeah.
That's where they're hiding away for
three or five or 30 years.
Oh my God.
And what does,
is there any solution?
Is there anything they could do?
Um,
I don't think so.
And I had a couple of things that
happened where,
um,
you know,
I started trying to take the anti
malaria meds,
but I started getting,
it's the only medicine I've ever really
reacted to where get nauseous,
start dragging it.
It's awful.
Yeah.
Even,
uh,
even um,
oh,
I'm pasty white and I get real sun
sensitive.
I know another medicine called
[inaudible],
which is a think it's developed in
Switzerland or Sweden,
supposed to be an awesome new malaria
medicine.
It's actually the one thing my body kind
of responds to,
but um,
but it's actually really dangerous
because a,
I've seen people that are there for aid
work and different stuff.
And do they have to,
they have to retreat if they're there
with kids and stuff.
They moved there to the country they're
taking off because um,
cause kiddos or even adults have mental
breaks that they can't come back from.
Like you can have psychotic episodes
for.
I think they said like if it lasts
longer than a week,
it's probably in the last like three
months.
It will last longer than three months.
It's probably the last forever.
Wow.
Yeah.
So,
um,
so this is from the medication?
Yeah,
it's just the medication and it gives
you terrible,
terrible nightmares.
I almost went to Tanzania this summer.
What was going to go on Safari?
And too many people scare the shit out
of me with malaria talk.
Yeah,
I was going to take my whole family and
I'm like,
look,
I'll take some millennial malaria
medication and feel like shit,
I'm not giving it to my six year old is
not happening.
That would be.
I'm not doing enough when you.
Yeah,
but that's a real concern.
Right?
Tanzania has malaria as well,
right?
Yeah,
they do it because it's more of a,
an arid climate and we're,
it's,
they have less there.
It's not so tropical there.
I've been to Tennessee a couple times
and seeing the bar,
I mean it's just um,
I met wasn't there,
but I was saw it and it was a,
I don't know,
man.
It's,
it's a crazy,
crazy place because you go from Congo
where they have all these tropical
diseases and you go same continent,
you just go over a little bit and
there's all these other kinds of
parasites in Congo there you have very
little of a,
I believe they're called jiggers with aj
and I'm very careful when you say that
word,
but jiggers with aj I'm wrong.
It sounds like you should stop,
but they're these crazy parasites at
borough in your feet and especially kids
and elderly.
Um,
and especially kids and elderly.
well honestly,
I think one reason with poverty,
the kids don't get shoes until they can
work in biome and uh,
the elderly,
if they're not able to work and provide
for themselves and you know,
it's harder for them to,
to,
to get shoes and stuff,
but also it's just where they live
because on the sandy or it's either
sandy or the clash or silty soil that's
real red and Uganda,
man.
It just wreaks havoc on those kids to
where they're having to have people come
in every week to different villages,
sit there with a safety pins and all
sorts of these little hooks that they
dig into people's feeds.
And um,
Oh God,
dude,
it's,
it's painful.
Whenever I've seen people getting it
done,
they're literally putting their.
And I've had one in my foot and it kind
of came and gone.
It's not that bad when it's just one,
but whenever your whole foot or your
whole heel or all the,
you know,
the balls of your feet are just covered
in.
I mean,
I'm talking 20,
30,
40,
50 of these parasites.
They're just brutal.
So every step you see them when they're
walking,
they're grimacing.
When you're taking it out there
screaming.
God Damn Africa.
Africa is just,
it's such a strange,
strange continent,
but me and the people are,
are beautiful in their hearts.
You know,
they're awesome.
They're a half her probably more than
half.
If you're not a good one,
you're very terrible.
Yeah,
that's simple.
Obviously from the outside,
that's what it looks like.
Someone like me who tries to pay
attention as much as I can,
but there's only so much you could
actually know about it without being
there,
I think,
right?
Yeah,
I think so.
I think whenever you get there,
I don't know,
fall in love with the people and to
build up the relationships.
That's why you can see past all the
garbage,
all the discomfort.
You said that you were held up with
corruption,
Congo corruption.
What happened?
So they,
they called me and said,
um,
my team,
uh,
is Astrid Papa.
Papa y is like a father figure to me.
He's the one that had this vision.
I came alongside him and it's just been,
it's been awesome to see what's happened
in um,
whenever I went to him.
Actually.
What,
what was the question?
You're just asking.
I don't even remember what I say.
I said about the corruption corruption
there.
Yeah,
yeah.
He called me and said a fat you to get
back here and like three weeks and I'm
like,
what?
I'm training for the fight,
like it's coming up and I can't leave.
No,
he says if you don't come back.
No.
Like I don't know when you can come
back,
they'll,
they're going to revoke your visa.
They're going to.
And I'm like,
what for?
And so they said,
check your passport.
They said your visa is expiring in three
weeks.
And I'm like,
it should be expiring.
I have a five year visa,
but then you have to come in and out of
the country every 11 months because if
you don't,
you lose that five year visa.
And so whenever I left with my wife,
literally they just so that they can get
money out of us and steel and build,
asked for 1400,
sometimes $2,500 to get a visa like
this.
Um,
you know,
they,
they write down on your visa when they
stamp it,
the date they write it in.
And so now I know,
look,
every single time they're writing to
make sure they write the right date
because she backdated it like six months
or something like that,
or maybe nine months and then all of a
sudden I had to get back there because
they're like,
nope,
it's gonna expire.
And they thought they gave him.
Actually it might've been less than
three weeks.
I think it had to go for three weeks is
what happened because I like a week
notice I just took off when it's
actually the cheapest trip I've ever got
there because it was like the last seat
I was by the toilets in the back the
whole time.
But there's only $800 round trip,
which was incredible.
That's pretty crazy.
You can go to Africa for 800 bucks.
Yeah,
that was,
I never seen it like that,
but it was a good school.
So I went and I mean it helped because
that saved me some money that was going
to have to pay to try to get out of the
corruption and stuff.
But luckily we went there,
they didn't think I would just dropping,
you know,
be there in five,
six,
seven days.
So I took off,
went and we spent three weeks trying to
just negotiate with the courts and
everything else and say,
look,
this is,
you guys did this,
you sent me an up all this other stuff
and trying to prove them wrong.
They're never wrong,
you know,
they're always right.
And uh,
trying to show them even receipts and
pictures,
we were showing them pictures from Ben's
wedding.
He's like my best friend,
like a brother,
a translator for me.
He's our team leader and I'm literally,
we're showing pictures of me at his
wedding and luckily it was dated and
everything,
like I was here in the country when you
said I had already left for five months
before.
So,
um,
it's just not,
it's like the backdating is intentional
to do it.
I'll do it on purpose.
So that for me and my wife,
both,
they,
uh,
they made it the same date which was
like six months or eight months early.
I'm like,
we left earlier than what we did.
So from the outside,
when you're visiting them,
did they,
do they think somehow or another that
you're wealthy and that they can take
advantage of you?
They know,
they know you're on television,
do they know all that?
No,
no,
we keep that really kind of when I'm,
there I am a,
let me see if I can get the right.
I am a professor of appropriate
technologies that appropriate
technologies or like a community
development or sustainable solutions and
I go there and I'm teaching the students
at the university how to,
uh,
and only I only do like a week or two
seminar with them.
The rest of them with my well drilling
team and that's my covering.
I go there as a quote unquote a
professor commission give that up on the
Internet.
Yeah,
I'm even people.
No,
no,
no.
It's okay.
But I do that because,
you know,
when I go in and really it's not because
I'm on TV or anything like that or they
think I have money,
they just think anyone that's not
Congolese has money.
And so because that's what they've seen
from people coming in and throwing money
around.
So they want their.
Yeah,
in a lot of the ngos are like,
they,
they have quotas and everything else and
the other just a huge budget and they
got to spend it.
They got to meet those,
those quotas.
So sometimes they throw it around and
they're not,
they're not trying to be frugal with the
money because it's not theirs.
They didn't go out and get it or
fundraising or get a grant for it or
anything like that.
It just got to spend.
So they'll just give it away.
Do the people that live in the Congo,
like the,
the pygmies,
do they still get malaria?
Is it really common with them yet?
We're really common.
Um,
but it's,
it's,
um,
it's weird because whenever people come,
I guess they're more acclimated to it,
but it still kills so many.
Um,
and then,
but whenever I get it,
they're,
they're saying,
you know,
the doctor here told me because of the
malaria meds,
it would be better for you to go because
you're already getting sick,
too sick with medicine,
just go get malaria and then get it
diagnosed quick enough,
get the cure and now your body's
actually gonna adapt to it and the next
time you get it will be less and less
women.
So they told you to get malaria.
Fucking Christ one of the worst diseases
person can get.
Right?
Yeah.
But honestly I've seen people,
even even Ben Ben's nuts,
like the year that I was there,
he had malaria,
now it's almost killed them before too,
but he had malaria like three or four
times in a year.
And um,
and it just kind of really,
really common there.
But once you,
if you can survive it the first couple
times,
then they say after that it gets more
bearable because you feel it coming.
You feel the heat waves coming over you.
And then you fill the shoulder joint
pains and elbows and it just down your
whole spine and your finger joints are
just throbbing,
like you can feel your pulse.
So it's an inflammation disease.
Uh,
it's a blood parasite disease and had
just a.
But it causes some inflammation.
The parasite somehow or another does
that to your joints.
Yeah.
And it released causes a lot of pain.
I know that.
And it,
uh,
it was,
it.
I lost 33 pounds,
five days.
Um,
Jesus Christ,
33 pounds in five days.
Thirty three pounds.
Dr Oz,
Dr. Oz would sell that I could.
I could be in here.
I got a new,
a la diet for he can he really do the
Congo Diet?
Really hot,
too hot.
So that's a massive sacrifice.
You're willing to take time to do that.
And this,
the fact that it's,
it exists inside your body for an
undetermined stated time.
That's um,
that's pretty wild,
man.
It's,
it's scary.
Um,
yeah.
Honestly,
I feel like I was in a much scarier
place personally before,
before I found this before I found them
before I got given a second family or
accepted into a second family and even
more scarier because you were depressed
because you just will depress suicidal
thoughts.
I had for like 10 years,
just battled it from 13 years old,
23.
And so,
um,
so yeah,
that,
that was a lot scarier to me than
suicidal thoughts when you're 13.
Yeah,
for sure.
And I mean I was,
I was the one that like,
you know,
the kid in the,
in the class that,
I mean I wasn't,
I wasn't like,
I wouldn't say I was,
how do I say it?
It was extremely brutal,
but it was happening to.
I mean everyone gets bullied for the
most part.
Somebody is bullying you.
Yeah.
Well,
when I was growing up that from,
from third grade until eighth grade for
sure,
it was brutal.
Seventh and he throws me usually smaller
than I was like,
dude,
I was smaller.
It takes a lot of balls to bully you and
a backfire.
It's actually kind of why I found
fighting or net,
why it is kind.
It is because a,
I was 13 years old and I had just gotten
so well.
Two things.
Have you ever seen in Texas for high
school homecomings?
They have mums.
Have you heard of that?
Now it's a mom fixes tradition.
That's crazy.
Now.
All,
all,
all the kids love them.
Everything else.
But you get these corsages or fake
flowers that they put real big up top
and then they are streamers with literal
bells and whistles,
full sized teddy bears.
You can have two,
three teddy bears and when I was in high
school,
the girl would wear it on her,
her shoulder and the weird around his
arm.
Now in Texas,
they literally have to put a harness
around him and hold these things up
because they're so big and there you go.
Texas my fuck
that.
That's homecoming in Texas.
Why?
Look at that?
I'm telling you,
it's the whole state,
the whole state.
I mean every,
every homecoming that comes around tech
Texans are nuts about this.
I mean,
I lived in Texas and I was like four
months old,
so it was a.
they're nuts and they've gotten bigger
and bigger and bigger every single year
and a.
How am I just hearing about the proud of
it?
It's weird.
I mean just hearing about this Jamie.
I think those are literally like two and
$300.
No.
Yeah.
When I was in high school,
they're like 7,100.
Oh my God.
Look at all those girls.
Look at that picture that you had done
there.
There's giant group of girls with all
this.
This is ridiculous.
That not nuts.
How do you.
How do you go to the dance like that?
How do you go to the game like that?
I don't understand.
Literally the boyfriends are walking
behind him holding the stuff up for him
because why aren't the.
It's getting too heavy or their neck
hurts,
but they want to wear it.
It's a tradition.
Yeah.
Everybody gets excited.
The bigger and the bigger the mom,
the better.
The more,
the more your date to you.
Is this a mom company that you just
clicked on every single grocery store in
Texas?
Why?
Whenever it comes to like a September,
October,
November,
around homecoming time,
high school.
Like this is people's jobs,
like seasonal jobs.
He sit around and they take special
orders.
They make them for you or they sound
where he can make them yourself.
That's so strange.
Isn't it?
Nuts?
How many is this?
It always baffles me when I find out
about something for the very first time.
I don't know why I'm so confused by it.
I would like to find out where the
traditional,
uh,
came from probably.
But I mean people are just so ingrained
in you.
If you're texting that you have to get
moms.
And so,
uh,
is there any other students find out if
other states except that I literally,
Oklahoma doesn't do it.
Louisiana doesn't.
New Mexico,
Texas,
twelfth things.
Non Texas.
Need to know about homecoming moms.
What in the fuck your mom started as a
simple flower.
Hold on,
scroll up a little bit.
Mum started as a simple flower.
Guys give them to their homecoming date.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Girls also give guys one called a
garter,
like a gardener.
Other you put it on your on your arm or
garter belt or over here side.
How busy.
Like one of those things that tie boxer.
Yeah.
Being able to make moms can make you
rich.
Oh God.
See?
Sixty to $300.
$300 for fake flowers on her bucks.
It ain't cheap to electrify a mom.
Oh my God.
That's so crazy.
You can put led lighting.
Look at that.
Scroll up,
scroll up a little bit,
but you can put led lighting and moms.
I didn't know how many are doing this
back when I was in high school,
but nowadays you really want to impress
your date.
The latest and mum lighting technology
will help you do just that.
That is hilarious.
You know,
this isn't even like a juke website
right now.
They're taking it serious,
real serious,
strange [inaudible].
It's really weird.
And so when I was in middle school,
seventh grade,
I
got a Christmas tree on her tits.
That's ridiculous.
They uh,
uh,
so you want to save?
I saved it up and my allowance asked one
of my crushes to go to the homecoming
game with me.
She said yes to my surprise,
went to the game and uh,
spent pretty much all my allowance on a,
the her mom and uh,
her name's Jessica and I took her to the
game and uh,
I'm up in the stands with her and home
or halftime comes around.
I'm up to the very top left and all of a
sudden everyone looks back up over the
right shoulders at us.
And this one guy,
he was Kinda my,
my belief through elementary and middle
school for sure.
And um,
his name was justin as well.
And so he walks up and puts his arm out
to her and she puts her arm around his
and he grabs the streamer that says,
uh,
Justin and Jessica and the year on it or
whatever.
And uh,
he says,
thanks for getting her this.
And I'm like,
what?
And he goes,
you didn't think she'd come with you,
did you?
And so he just kind of walks down all
the schools looking.
They're all laughing and having fun.
But,
and,
and that one hurt,
but what was worse with the next year,
because,
you know,
people liked that part of,
I don't know,
I think
for me,
when I see bullying now,
I just spoke at a middle school and I
told one of the teachers asked,
what should you tell a kid that's
battling with suicidal thoughts or
depression even,
maybe suicidal thoughts.
And I'm like,
well,
if this is 300,
400 kids in here,
like for sure one person is dealing with
these issues right now.
And I would say,
you know,
the thing that probably saved me was my
parents didn't own a gun.
I'd probably only Texans that don't own
guns.
And uh,
then,
um,
I don't know.
I mean,
I guess one of the main things was um,
well I don't even know that I've ever
said this publicly,
but I remember,
um,
having attempted suicide once and then
I'm thinking about it again and then I'm
thinking,
you know,
what would this,
what would the student,
my mom,
you know.
And so I love my mom.
I'm a mama's boy.
Dad's great too.
But that's just who I am.
She's a tough cookie.
She's where I got my competitiveness.
She was a national champion in barrel
racing,
state champion in tennis.
And so she always pushed me,
my dad,
if he,
uh,
if he was at a wrestling tournament and
it's the finals even state,
I would dislocate my thumb or something
to come up.
You don't have to wrestle in the next
match.
Like it's the finals.
My Mom's like,
he's getting out there.
So my mom,
mom's the one pushing him,
shut up,
Jimmy,
he's going gonna he's going to go out
there and he's going to wrestle him.
He's going to win.
And so my dad was more of one wanting to
protect me and she's the one who pushed
me out there.
Um,
so I guess,
uh,
saying that except for,
oh,
that thought was just ringing in my
head.
And so whenever I finally verbalized
that and start talking to people,
that's what really helped,
you know,
it didn't have to be a bunch of people
that didn't have to go around and be,
um,
I don't know,
a drama queen or do it for attention or
whatever,
but just find one person and for me at
that age it was having a great mom and
um,
parents that loved me and I think that's
probably absolutely what saved me at
that time.
And so I was telling these kids,
you know,
hey,
tell if even if it's just your mom.
So I was taking pictures with some of
the kids afterwards and stuff and I'll
walk out to leave and I'm in the hall in
this mom stops me because she's with her
little guy and he's crying.
So a mom had come to school.
I had heard there was anti anti-bullying
doc.
She came up and I see this little guy,
he reminded me,
a lot of me,
the only difference was,
uh,
was he had these kind of big glasses on,
but he was a little chubby and had just
had one of those things that you'd see
stereotypical,
like this kid's going to get picked on.
And so I'm probably a lot like me.
He's used to getting his fat pinch tune,
nipples twisted and you know,
all that different stuff.
And so,
um,
he was out there just balling with his
mom.
His mom asked if I can talk to him for a
little bit.
I did and she was saying that he had
never opened up with her and uh,
in the last two years,
but she knew he had been dealing with
really bad depression and right there he
told her,
I've been dealing with suicidal thoughts
for two years.
And so I don't know why I even brought
that up except for like,
it's nuts.
My parents have a,
have a photography company and they made
a memorial a few years back for a little
boy who was getting bullied.
Didn't think he had an option out and he
took his life at nine years old.
Oh my goodness.
Well,
I think it was a swing set out back.
So I'm like,
oh Jesus Christ.
And so,
um,
I saw the plaque and everything made up
for them and just gut wrenching.
And so as I say that in the first story
wasn't kind of one that kind of brought
everything to a head was I was in middle
eighth grade this time,
um,
got invited to a Jennifer's birthday
party.
Really excited.
I got one of the real limitations in my
hands and
made the plans talk to my mom,
asked if I could go talk to some of the
people who else is going.
That was just kind of a Dorky kid
anyways.
But,
um,
uh,
on the invitation I noticed,
man,
it says costume contest and the winner
gets a prize.
Why certain research,
all this other stuff,
other people are doing it too.
And um,
I found out that her dad worked at Dr
Pepper in that their house was decorated
with all this other stuff.
And then,
um,
and then she loved transformers.
And so I thought,
what if I combine two things,
what if I could meet myself a cardboard
transformer from head to toe?
I think it was a 24 pack or only had 12
packs around the arms,
legs,
boots I had.
I had a chest plate at a sword out of
cardboard,
a country kid texted you see those moms,
we can do pretty much anything with duct
tape.
And uh,
so duct tape,
cardboard just made it up and walked
into the party.
And um,
her grandma opened the door.
She goes,
oh,
Jennifer's going to love this.
Walked into.
They literally had a Dr Pepper machine
where it was like old school ones you
didn't have to pay,
just push the button.
It pops out.
Thirteen year old kid.
He loved that.
So we had dr pepper can one end of the
Dr Pepper Cardboard Sword in the other
walk to the backyard when whenever the
door opens,
I opened the door and breathe there with
like some flashes of lights and fingers
pointing,
people laughing.
And um,
I remember Jennifer saying,
can't believe you thought you were cool
enough to come to my party.
And I was the only one that was dressed
up.
Everybody else had gotten there early
and they all been planning and even the
invitations are fake just so that I
would come there and dress up.
Another kid said,
I'm,
you're worthless.
So in that moment I felt worthless.
And then,
um,
the main bully said you should just kill
yourself.
And so whenever he said that,
13 years old battle with depression and
suicidal thoughts,
all that different stuff minute,
it took me on a downward spiral
tailspin.
It really sucked.
I didn't know how to cover it up.
And then I guess I'm getting back to
them and may route where I found that 13
years old at like a flea market in the
Texas and walking down these aisles and
looking for a bb gun and all of a sudden
I get to the site,
used video shop and it's got UFC vhs.
I think it was two through 10 or 10 to
11 or something like that.
And,
um,
so I just let bottom all you were on
there and do that as a horrible story,
man.
That is a terrible story.
How the fuck does kids be so mean?
I mean that is honestly,
I don't think it's,
I mean that crazy compared to,
I mean it is,
it's very like a methodical,
like very planned out.
I'm in,
a lot of people were in on it.
I think that probably was one of the
things like,
honestly Jennifer was that the biggest
crush I ever had in,
you know,
elementary,
middle school growing up,
you know.
And so she was the one that really
wanted impressed.
That's why I did that research,
you know?
And then you know,
that she was in on it.
These other guys planned it,
but she went along with it,
um,
to her to have her say that to you,
like the,
I can't believe you thought you were
cool enough to come to my party.
Yeah.
Fuck man.
I ended up leaving.
Um,
and this is before cell phones.
I didn't have a cell phone until I was
like 16 and 17 and I'm,
so I'm 13,
run out,
found a dairy queen.
And,
uh,
when the back and where the drive
through is,
there was like a,
I don't know,
the dumpster and they get like the fence
around it and I just was able to open
it,
sit there and just cried basically until
someone came out to throw away the
trash.
And then they're like,
oh,
how many got down,
what do you need?
And all this other stuff.
Can you call your mom?
I'm like,
if I have a phone.
And so I walked inside,
called her,
but she wasn't there.
So took a little while to get ahold of
my mom.
And then,
um,
yeah,
I mean it was just,
it was nuts because it's weird how you,
you will believe,
especially in today's age with social
media and all the tweets and things that
people just throw away.
I throw around,
um,
you know,
it's nuts.
How can see somebody don't even know
them.
They might have one follower,
but somehow it can still,
if you let it,
it can still affect you instead of just
shrugging it off.
That's a totally different thing though.
So insanely something on twitter and
someone saying something and looking you
in the eyes.
Yeah.
And planning out this big deception.
But you're such a nice guy.
I got to understand what,
what the fuck.
Cause it's selling to be such a shithead
like that.
Well,
I don't know man.
I think,
I think um,
I've,
I've matured a lot where,
I mean obviously 20 minutes at 13,
but uh,
uh,
I think I just became an easy target and
because you're just a nice guy and they
just,
maybe I wouldn't stand up for myself and
maybe I wasn't the biggest kid,
but I was Chubby and bigger and uh,
uh,
yeah,
I think it just was easy to pick on me
in the locker rooms,
pick on me in the.
I don't know,
I think I think have the stats I was
looking at with something like 87
percent of bullying doesn't happen in
the presence of
adults.
Adults.
Right.
And then,
uh,
I forget,
but you know,
even the people around like how you're
saying,
you know,
two people plan it out and everything
else look you in the eyes.
I think that might've been what took me
back the most because I was like,
man,
like this is if you're sitting by,
this is what I tried to tell some of the
kiddos growing up now it's like if you
think that by laughing at me or if
you're there and you're not bullying,
but you're giggling,
you're laughing,
like you're definitely a part of it.
You're an encourager,
but then if you're,
even if you're silent and you're just
watching it and you don't like now your.
If you see it,
you have a choice.
You do something bad at your economic.
And so I feel like that's a passive
standby kind of encouragement where in.
So for me it was like everyone was
there,
people were saying it,
people were laughing,
people were watching,
but nobody was standing up for me.
So it was a think that was what hurt the
most.
We'll see.
So there's two giant instances.
The one with the other guy named Justin,
so they plan that out to fuck man.
You went to school with little kids?
Yeah,
it was actually part of the same kids.
So yeah.
Damn.
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
so from that,
um,
yeah,
that,
that's,
that's definitely been the biggest
battle of my life has been depression,
suicidal thoughts,
and it was all from that bullying.
There was nothing other than that for
the depression.
Yeah.
I mean it went from technically I would
say I went from third grade to 10th
grade and then whenever I started
wrestling and my parents transferred me
out of the school,
everything else then.
But the bullying is what caused all
these suicidal thoughts.
There's nothing else that was bombed you
out about life that is so fucked up at
some shitty mean kids can all of a
sudden throw this monkey wrench in your
life.
And then I've,
I've learned,
and I mean,
of course you know,
a lot.
I used to looking back at it,
it shouldn't have.
I shouldn't have ever let it get to the
point to where,
you know,
I think I should hurt myself or kill me.
You know what?
Just a real quick put that together with
the pygmies and Congo,
whenever I opened up and shared with
some of them around the campfire,
just hanging out,
talking,
sharing life stories.
I shared that and I just remember the
looks on several people's faces just so
baffled.
Like did he just say he wanted to hurt
himself?
You suicide.
He wanted to kill himself.
I'll let him and stuff and then I start
asking me does that not happen here?
And they're like,
whoa.
Some of them were like,
well,
we've heard of that happening before and
yeah,
there's,
there's this guy that was that guy and
that guy and that guy.
We heard that someone in their village
had hurt themselves or killed themselves
or something,
but most of the people I think were
like,
no,
I've never heard.
Why would anyone.
If you hurt yourself,
you're only like,
it's only hurting you.
That's not going to help anything.
We just wanted the pain to end.
Yeah.
Here I just wanted the pain to end,
but there it's like it's not because
they.
If,
if I look at it as a little kid,
I got bullied by something,
some stupid kids,
and then look at if I look at what
they're going through and it makes it,
it makes it,
it shrinks it,
it makes it microscopic.
Whenever you stop just focusing on your
own problems and you start looking at
others,
other problems that maybe you can be a
part of helping solve that problem.
So this bullying all throughout your
childhood led into adulthood and the
only thing that made it better was you
go into the Congo and helping out these
pygmies and building wells and,
and sort of dedicating and devoting your
life to their life.
Yeah.
I would say practically that has been,
you know,
to have a sense of purpose.
I mean I think it's a,
it's a lot of different things,
but that all Kinda came together.
But for me,
yeah,
I mean when you're not living for
yourself and you live in for others,
you just want.
I mean,
I didn't know that for me,
I had a big paradigm shift or change in
my life.
Whenever you know,
coming out of the addiction,
I felt like,
I mean,
like I don't have to walk around and hit
myself in,
stay away from people because they're
either going to hurt me or I'm going to
want to hurt them.
Like,
uh,
I don't have to do that.
I can,
I can help people.
I can want to love them.
I can,
you know,
figure out something that I did at first
started at what really started helping a
lot.
Was involved with a lot of different
stuff from a juvenile detention center.
Going in and meeting with some of those
kids once a week to a homeless shelter
to becoming a official volunteer at the
Denver Children's hospital and taking
the grudge guys through there.
And I think like Rashad and Dwayne and
Shane Carlin and Brendan and all these
guys,
you know,
they were going and they actually saw me
going through the really tough,
uh,
addictions and getting kicked off grudge
fight team.
And then a year later I'm luckily able
to organize an event where the.
They wouldn't let us come in just as
fighters to visit the kids because they
were like,
fighters,
why would you guys come and visit us?
And uh,
that's violent.
And so I decided to become a volunteer
here,
go through all the processes and the
training and all the other stuff.
And then I love volunteering there.
And then after they got to know me,
I'm like,
Hey,
can we do a team visit us in there?
The best visit they had ever had was the
bikers.
I'm like,
this biker gang guys.
They always brought pizza on Wednesday
night or something.
And uh,
and they literally did look,
look rough and tumble.
And um,
and then they said ours was a second
pass.
And I'm like,
you know,
and they said,
well,
I won't say the teams,
but some of the other,
uh,
big major league sports,
they said those have been any named some
of them.
And they're like,
they've been some of your absolute
worst.
I'm like,
man,
see you thought fighters are going to
come in here and I don't know if you
thought were going to beat up the kids
or something.
But,
but uh,
no,
we were passionate about the sport.
I mean,
I think passionate means you love
something so much that you'll suffer for
it were,
or even a suffering looks like
enjoyment.
Our becomes enjoyment because you love
it and you're passionate about it.
And so,
I mean whenever you're a fighter,
you're getting beat up and all the other
stuff.
And we,
man,
we're,
we're passionate people.
We really love each other.
It's all team come camaraderie and yeah,
there's an intense camaraderie between
people that train together because you
go through such difficult sessions and
difficult sparring and difficult moments
and conditioning and all that stuff and
you push each other and it's a different
kind of bond.
Right?
Yeah.
And on that,
I think I saw someone recently posted
something that was pretty cool where it
showed a,
like a Jujitsu gentleman.
It was,
um,
showing all the different people and in
it it said something like,
this is the,
where's the one place you will,
you can find.
It was really just people in these
different skin colors.
And I forget how it was worded,
but yeah.
And we all get along and there's all
piece.
It's like,
I love that.
Yeah,
I do as well.
Did you,
do you stay in any way in touch with
those kids from back in the day from the
kids that bullied you?
You.
It was actually funny after the ultimate
fighter,
um,
I got invited out by one of the guys.
Um,
and uh,
just because I think a couple of people,
they'll just,
yeah,
saw one of the guys who was one of the
main guys and he's like,
Hey,
I'm walking around downtown Fort Worth
and say,
why don't we go out here?
Whatever.
I'm like,
all right,
I'll go.
And.
Well he had actually brought me into,
uh,
the Sushi restaurant in all around the
table was most of the people that were
not most is probably only eight or 10
people,
but they were some of the main kids that
were at that party when I dressed up and
everything.
Why?
Man,
if you,
if we'd have known you were a fighter or
you know,
you could kick their butts and we
wouldn't have done that to you.
And I'm just like it.
So I told him I was going to the
bathroom just left from,
I think that's the only time I've ever
done anything like that,
but I'm just like,
I can't,
I can't be around these guys.
Did you,
did you sense any feeling of remorse
from them or they just want to be
friends?
One,
one or two of them?
One guy for sure.
He's,
he's,
he's pretty cool now.
And um,
but then one is a,
is a knucklehead for sure and still pick
them.
You know,
it's that classic thing of kids ganging
up on one kid.
That's a weird instinct that sometimes
children have.
You remember that movie Carrie,
when they,
uh,
she goes to the prom and the,
do you ever seen these basic moving?
It's based on a great Stephen King Book.
He didn't know.
I know that cover the,
the Sissy space movie was really trippy.
John Travolta's in it back in the day,
young and handsome.
Um,
but it's,
you know,
that's the themes that they push her.
She has these crazy telekinetic powers
and they push her to this point and they
do it by mocking her and bullying her.
They take her to the prom and they pour
pig's blood on her head,
which winds up killing everybody.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
It's pretty,
pretty crazy.
But that's that thing that happens when
kids gang up on a kid that they feel
like is vulnerable.
Like,
what the fuck is that man?
What a horrible instinct like.
Is that
what I mean?
I,
I just,
I struggle to understand where that
instinct comes from or why people do it.
It's um,
especially little kids know.
I mean,
I guess I could understand that if the
kids have been abused themselves,
they want to lash out there angry and
hurt.
But oftentimes it's just,
they find someone who's vulnerable.
It's like they find the pecking order
and they'd find that one person that can
get away with and they all funnel their
insecurities and their anger and their
aggression on this one person just
because with no regard whatsoever,
what kind of impact it's gonna have on
that kid.
Yeah.
I think.
I think one of the things that makes it
so much worse now is.
I mean,
I don't know.
I get to hear some of the stuff that
they can't escape it because it follows
them home cyberbullying and they get the
text and the,
all this stuff is so it's constantly.
So I could at least escape it from eight
to three,
eight to three I was at school,
but when I came home I was,
I was okay.
And um,
maybe that gave me a break but a little
bit of a break from it.
But I mean,
that's,
that's the world that we live in and the
stuff that's happening.
I mean,
what you said happened.
Germany
and other like school shootings that
have happened here.
I was in Aurora when the,
the movie theater thing happened.
Um,
and it's just terrible.
But then I,
there's absolutely,
without a doubt the zero excuse for you
don't ever do anything like that.
But then I kind of have looked at it
maybe once before.
It might be stupid for me to talk about
it now.
But um,
I kind of can see where they've been
pushed over the edge and wait,
no excuse,
they should not ever do anything like
that.
But um,
for me it's like,
man,
they,
it was never a fair fight.
They were always cornered a outnumbered.
I'm beaten down over and over and over,
and then they just snapped.
And uh,
now it's terrible.
Don't.
Yeah.
I don't know if that's the case of the
Aurora shooter.
No,
no,
no.
He's completely insane.
Yeah.
But I think it certainly can happen to
people where they get to this point when
not only do they not want to live,
they don't want you to live anymore
either because I mean,
I'm sure if you had been in a situation
where you knew someone,
you had a friend who was in the same
boat as you,
you know,
like,
um,
those kids from columbine,
whether the two kids got together and
they sort of helped each other do
something really fucked up if you were
involved with the wrong people at that
time.
Someone had a gun and you knew where
these kids were and you know,
you wanted to do that to yourself.
Who knows what you would have wanted to
do to them as well.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's kind of a scary thing to think
about.
I did have a dark period.
It was,
I think it was in between seventh and
eighth grade where they're hanging out
with a lot of the,
I don't know,
just the,
the kids that were involved in just
darker thoughts,
music,
stuff like that where it,
um,
where,
you know,
hanging out with them and we're all,
we're all depressed,
you know,
and we're,
we're listening to that Papa Roach Song,
the last resort,
you know?
Uh,
I think it's like cut myself bleeding,
you know,
I'm never gonna I don't want to breathe
again or live again or something like
that.
And then all of a sudden they're
bringing out a,
what are those?
The big,
big black cats are those employees or
something like that.
There's a bunch of frogs where we lived
in the country and they'd go get the
frogs blow up a frog,
given another frog blow up a frog Jesus
frog.
And also like,
Hey,
this is,
this is a little way too dark.
Sorry.
The,
how do you blow up a frog?
You stick it in his mouth,
stick in his mouth and just light it
written in front.
Sorry for anyone and the frog wasn't
just keeps it in his mouth or something.
They're hopping,
hopping,
hopping with it in his mouth,
his mouth,
because I think maybe with mat they use
those because they're big,
so you stick it in there and kind of
can't get it out.
Can't get it.
Oh God,
yes.
A brutal.
Anyway,
when that happened,
I was like,
okay,
I need to.
I need to change the.
That was a group of like five or six
kids that were just in a very,
very dark place and even ones in jail.
So fuck dude,
what a bar bombing me.
I'm just going to do that every time
you've been here.
It's just been all joyful and loving and
all that.
I didn't know your history
well.
Hey Man.
It's just honest expression.
There's nothing wrong with it.
It's just it.
It makes me as an adult,
I almost want to go back in time and
stop it from happening.
You know,
it makes me,
it makes me very sad.
It's just,
it's one of the worst aspects of human
beings that they could plan something
like that and do that and just try to
ruin someone's life just for sport,
just for fun for no reason.
You didn't do anything to them.
It's just,
yeah,
it's fucked up man.
I see it as a thing that actually helped
shape and mold me now in a way of like,
I look at it,
it was Loretta while we're writing the
book,
she's like,
do you not see all these kind of
parallels?
And I'm like,
what do you mean you grew up?
He got really,
really bullied.
Then I tried to help people that are
like maybe the most bully people on
planet earth and like,
Oh,
I guess I see that.
No,
and,
or was it last month?
Last trip,
but the second last trip to Congo,
that ad was there and we're having to
get a mechanic to help.
We were tired and different stuff.
And also I'm a drunk mechanic comes out
and he's always drunk and uh,
and he comes out talking with us.
It's a little boy walks by.
He's literally,
he should be in school,
but because his family's so poor,
he's out selling eggs and if he's
selling eggs you can make,
you know nothing,
but we'll never be able to go to school
probably.
And he's just trying to make money to
feed his family.
And he's literally five,
six,
seven years old and he's coming around
with selling the eggs.
Normally they sell them hard boiled.
Um,
but sometimes they don't when they're,
when they're walking around you want eat
it then.
But this kids were all raw and so it's
even harder for them to sell them.
Um,
but the drunk guy picked up the egg.
He's looking at it,
shakes a little bit,
finds out it's raw and just smashes him.
The Kid,
this is an adult,
30 something year old man,
and this is literally a five,
six,
seven,
eight year old kid.
Just smashes it over his head and the
kid looks up at him with just fear.
I mean,
it's not smart for me because,
uh,
because,
you know,
I'm the outsider to the government's
eyes and everything else,
but like I almost got in a fistfight
with him.
I remember just pulling my hand straight
back and,
and just almost just back in them right
across the face.
And then Ben's like,
Whoa,
whoa.
Then I grabbed the,
I think I grabbed a shirt,
grab the shoulder and I said,
Ben,
translate from real quick if he ever
leaves his hands on that kid or any
other kid,
I'm only my hands on him.
And so just make sure you understand
that this kind of thing.
And um,
I don't even know a woman that except
for.
I mean I just don't get,
get people sometimes.
Um,
let's,
we'll get into some positive stuff with
that.
That will just blew me away.
I was like,
you're an old guy picking on a
kindergartener.
I just,
as a,
as a person,
I don't understand it,
but I also don't understand it.
Like logically I don't understand like
where that inclination comes from it,
like what,
what is it about a human being that
makes them want to do that?
Like what,
how,
how did that develop?
How is it so common?
Um,
I don't know.
I guess when you
put someone down you feel better about
yourself and to really,
I mean,
I know what I've found is the exact
opposite.
When you help somebody,
it actually helps you.
Of course somebody you feel more loved
when you,
you know,
so um,
so it's counterintuitive,
but that's kind of what people do re do
the opposite of what we could or should.
But it's so common.
I wonder,
like what is the cause,
the root cause of it or does it play
some sort of evolutionary role?
Like what is it like,
like pecking order with chickens?
Like they try to find out who's the
weakest one and they all attack.
They'll all tackling the weakest chicken
that'll all peck at it.
It's like,
what the fuck is that?
Like why is it,
are they trying to weed out the weak?
Is it an evolutionary thing?
Is it,
are they terrified of someone doing that
to them?
So they strike first?
Well,
you know what,
there's actually a pretty incredible
video.
Hang onto.
So yeah,
because of the voice is actually a
pretty incredible video that uh,
it was absolutely terrible whenever I
gave the speech or whatever.
But I,
I played part of the video,
cut it down to like three minutes and
say like 12,
I think it's called the battle at
Kruger.
Have you seen that?
No,
it's in Africa.
Oh,
I have seen this.
The water buffaloes are back in.
The crocodile lion takes the,
the back of the pack.
The smaller,
weaker,
younger lions all go after that one,
tackle it splashing water.
They're dragging the baby out of the,
out of the lake or river and all of a
sudden a huge crocodile comes and grabs
it and they have a tug of war match with
this baby.
I think it was a Cape Buffalo Buffalo.
Yeah.
And so,
uh,
it wasn't a will to be straight.
It was Keto flu.
I think it was one of those.
And uh,
and yeah,
it's not split.
What I love almost in that analogy of
where you know if you're standing by
like you're encouraging it or if you're
not doing anything,
you're encouraging it,
but if you just stand up,
oh,
that's the stat I saw where 87 percent
of bullying happens in the presence of
nobody,
but in the times that it is around
people.
If one person says one thing to the
bully,
90 percent of the time it's 80 to 90
percent of the time it stops within five
seconds.
The bullying,
it just stops and it doesn't have to be
anything aggressive.
It can be a man lay off of them and then
if you.
After that,
it's something like 95 percent of the
time.
If you invite the bullied victim to come
into your group or hang out or sit at
your table or whatever,
then it stops even even better right
away.
When you don't address the bully.
You addressed the person that's getting
bullied.
So it seems like the people that are
bullying,
they almost need reinforcement and they
get.
They're getting reinforced by people
being complicit or being silent or
they're joining like those lines.
One line decided to take out the little
guys.
They just food.
You were handled.
That's how they stay alive.
That's a natural instinct.
This is a weird either.
This,
the one thing I do like about it though
is with those two stats,
like say something,
don't be passive.
Whenever one Cape Buffalo turned around,
a couple of other ones did too.
And then we'll.
One came in there in the middle of the
law.
One hit one line through it in the air
and then all of them tucked tail and
ran.
Yeah.
Once I realized what a Cape Buffalo can
actually do to them,
man,
that's so terrible.
You know,
Cape Buffalo,
I was apparently are some of the most
dangerous animals in Africa and they
will charge.
You can just so used to being around
people,
um,
or around animals rather than trying to
kill them.
Yeah.
I almost got us arrested and not a,
not just a little bit where we
accidentally,
um,
believe the Serengeti in Tanzania and
we're on the border of Kenya and
Tanzania and we're taking a shortcut
from some locals,
which is always fine if you're from
there.
And we saw this awesome,
but we didn't know we were going through
the Serengeti.
They just thought it was a shortcut.
We didn't pay for a park,
pass her,
anything like that.
And also I see this gigantic Cape
Buffalo skull just sitting in the middle
of nowhere.
I'm like,
let's get that,
let's take it back.
And so we put that in the back of the
truck.
All of a sudden we're driving and uh,
we get pulled over by the park rangers.
Then they see the Cape Buffalo skull.
They say we're poachers say this,
that,
and the just swarmed by,
uh,
by all these,
these park rangers,
like three or four different vehicles
and arrest me,
all this different stuff and enter crew.
And uh,
luckily anyways,
that's a random thing.
But luckily we just said,
hey,
can I just put it right back where it
was?
I didn't,
I didn't mean to.
I didn't know we were in a national
park.
Yeah.
They don't take any bullshit from
poachers out there.
It's very dangerous.
They kill poachers on site.
Yeah.
They can kill them.
Where it's,
a lot of times it's,
I'm literally the life in prison
sentence for poaching.
Yeah.
For,
for,
for um,
like endangered species for sure,
with like,
uh,
the Okapi,
um,
one of my last trips and we'll try to,
I think I maybe said that earlier,
where a on one of the past episodes
where someone tried to sell me the meat
in the fur of an Okapi and then,
um,
oh,
cubbies are in danger.
Yes.
And they're only found in the one area
that we're,
we're kind of working in and uh,
and the rebel groups there went to will
wildlife reserve for them protecting
them and uh,
they wouldn't hurt her,
like,
uh,
I don't know,
15 or 20 of them sleep that were there
trying to help stimulate,
you know,
come help them come back in the wild and
everything else.
There's wouldn't killed them all.
Um,
yeah.
And then another guy was trying to sell
me a,
a,
a rhino horn.
Um,
and that's just brutal.
Now poaching sucks,
but I love how the pygmies culture has
with,
with hunting.
I even have a,
a quick video.
Um,
if I,
I think,
um,
did you see what they're doing where
they're making three d printed a
cloned rhino horns and they're going to
flood the market with them?
That's a great idea.
Yeah.
To see if he could find that out with
Jim Shark fins too,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
They're um,
Amelie's people.
Each arc fens needs.
It's fucked up that they're killing them
all and make soup out of them,
but she's,
at least they're eating them.
These are the Rhino thing is insane.
Yeah,
that's it.
It's absolutely based on nothing.
I mean the I medicine,
but it's crazy.
I just can't imagine that.
Here we are in 2016 with Viagra and
Cialis and all these different boner
pills you buy at the gas station.
That red bad takes.
When I was pulling this up,
I've found this bias and also three d
printing and vinyl,
not the solution to poaching crisis
experts say,
I agree that that's the best way.
Well,
I don't know if it's the best way
either.
I mean,
I just can't imagine that the rhinos are
literally on the verge of going extinct
because people want to kill them and
take their horns,
which do nothing and it's.
Isn't it like the same substances like a
fingernail or toenail?
It is.
Exactly.
That's exactly what it is.
It's like hair.
Yeah,
it's.
But they have this erroneous idea that
you eat it and it makes your dick hard.
What the fuck is going on with Asia?
That's a broad statement and that's why
I bought it.
I generalize,
generalize that a billion people folks
going on with Asian move.
I mean I wonder.
I think it's also a status symbol.
I was reading that even though it might
not necessarily be real or really work,
but it's such an ancient cultural status
symbol thing that like these businessmen
will get together and they'll have like
Rhino Horn tea,
you know,
and they.
But they think it's cool because it's
illegal and you can't get it and it's
dangerous and it's got to come from
Africa and so it must really work.
I don't know,
maybe that's what they think though.
If favorite things work this expensive,
maybe it doesn't matter their their
grandfathers said it worked.
His grandfather said it work.
Why don't you google that,
Jamie?
Does Rhino Horn actually work?
No,
I didn't know.
I mean maybe it doesn't work as good as
other stuff for fingernails.
Does that ever does.
You just got to need eat enough
fingernails.
Imagine
what's an acceptable source to find?
I don't think there wouldn't be one from
China.
Isn't that funny?
Like you have to find a website that you
trust,
right?
It's got to be like wired.com or story
on factor fiction use on it,
but what does it.
What does that say?
PBS is probably valid.
A lot of information.
I'd have to read first,
but just one article about Rhino Horn
use fact or fiction.
I always,
when I'm exhausted and I look at
something like that,
I go to the very bottom and say,
hmm,
how do they wrap this up?
Overall not much evidence to support the
claim to what?
The healing properties of the horns.
There you go.
That's a good little tip I just learned
from.
If you're not really.
This isn't life dependent.
This is not something that you really.
It's not really a factor in your life.
Just go to the bottom line.
It is very strange.
Oh,
okay.
Not believed as once believed.
It's not as once believed,
rather made simply from a clump of
compressed or modified here,
recent studies by researchers and Ohio
University,
whole Ohio.
There you go.
Using computerize.
What does that Word Tomography?
Ct Scans have shown that the horns are
in fact similar in structure to horses,
hooves,
turtle beaks and cockatoo bills.
The studies also revealed at the centers
of the horns have dense mineral deposits
of calcium and Melanin of finding that
may explain the curve and shape sharp
tip of the horn.
The calcium would strengthen the horn
while the melanin would protect some of
the core from being degradated by
ultraviolet radiation from the Sun,
Huh?
Softer outer portion worn away over time
by the sun and typical rhino activities
bashing horns with other animals rubbing
on the ground.
The inner core would be sharpened into a
point,
much like a wooden pencil.
Yeah.
There were in the horn that this kid was
basically trying to sell it.
He was like 15,
16 years old.
His Dad was the poacher and uh,
his dad didn't want to get arrested so
he sends his kid,
um,
and uh,
it had all sorts of like us deep deeply
scratches inside of it and stuff and are
just all over Canada.
The top was nicked up and stuff.
University of Hong Kong found that large
doses of Rhino Horn extract could
slightly lower fever in rats.
Imagine if Rhino Horn was a cure to
malaria when we would start breeding
them right for like we do with chickens.
And how strange it just.
I mean,
obviously it's not happening in the
western world.
It's not happening here,
but it could I guess.
Right?
I mean some people are just fucked up.
Some people,
they don't care if something's about to
go extinct.
They just want,
they want what they want and if they
want that Rhino Horn for whatever
strange reason,
it's just.
Yeah,
well it's like,
it's like a,
it's like kind of with the trees,
you know,
we were getting ready to replant.
Um,
I think it's 1000 more trees which would
take her total up the $4,500 on the land
for the pygmies and around there,
the reason that,
I mean China and all these other places
are coming in,
they're cutting down the rear hardwoods,
the Mahogany and,
and reason king leopold went,
there was the rubber boom and the trees
there and everything else.
But then,
um,
it's just nuts to me because I think
they're,
you know,
they want it for greed,
money,
everything else.
But then the people in the country,
they're starting to,
to,
to learning,
get educated in the fact that like,
Hey,
if we're cutting down all these trees,
we better start replanting some because
it takes so long for them to grow back.
And so,
uh,
no,
but it's just for charcoal or fire and
they're like,
once that's gone,
what do you have?
And yeah,
Booney actually the town that all of our
well drillers live in.
And at the university they,
um,
they used to be in a rainforest,
now you have to drive three,
four hours to get to the closest florist
you have to drive three or four hours
away.
And it used to be in the center of the
center of the reinforced,
but the edge of the reinforced almost to
be a forest.
And that's not three or four hours
drive.
Yeah,
it's all just because of deforestation
all chopping down for logging.
Fuck man,
I was in Canada.
And um,
they,
they do a pretty good job of regulating
it and BC.
But it's still disturbing because you,
you come across these,
these big gigantic fields where the
trees are just gone.
All the trees had been cut and you know,
they plant som and they have the,
they also have like purchase,
they leave purchase for animals,
which is,
uh,
probably like an awesome spot for like a
hawk or an eagle or something like that
because everything's cut down.
They can see every street to the press.
But it's,
um,
these cut out of,
I forget what they call it,
these patches where everything's cut
down.
It's so disturbing.
It's like I get,
I get that they replant,
I get that they have a cycle.
I get that,
but it just bugs me that people could do
that.
They just.
Giant swaths of the landscapes shaved
off and turned into toothpicks or
whatever the fuck they do with it.
Yeah.
And so I was in a village before my
wife's first time to Congo and it was,
I mean it was almost like,
you know,
lush,
untouched virgin forest and then all of
a sudden a come back next time with her
coming in with worse,
come back in.
It's probably a month or so because we
went to a couple of other villages,
go back,
start going to the same hike and all of
a sudden there's this huge clearing at
least 10 acres,
probably 20,
25 and it was just nothing there except
for a few remaining huge cut down trees
that I could stand in front of and the,
the,
of the base or whatever it was way
telling them I was a little midget next
to that or fuck man.
So yeah,
it's pretty crazy.
And I was telling her,
I'm like,
baby,
like when I was like,
take some picture of this,
I think I have some pictures right here
of where,
where we are right now on this trail.
And like there used to be trees here and
it was nuts because all of a sudden for
me,
if I'm in the rain forest is great
actually.
I mean it's hot in a malaria,
but uh,
she,
her but being under the canopy of the
rain forest,
going to love that because it's shaded
and everything else still hot,
still humid,
but a little bit better.
Not getting burned on,
especially.
Yeah,
you're really pale in on the hike.
I was getting burned and I'm like,
man,
this is a nuts.
Especially on that malaria medication.
Right.
Um,
that they were talking on this,
uh,
documentary I was watching about the
deforestation
of the Amazon,
about how fast it's happening and how
terrifying it is.
And a big part of it I guess is not
even.
Well there's logging,
but there's also they cut it down to
make room for cattle grazing.
And when they were showing the,
just the sheer size of the deforestation
of how much they've done in so quickly.
And then I'm also the people that live
in these areas where if they resist the
loggers or they're resist it,
skip murdered,
especially the indigenous people that
are more out there and it happens with
the pygmies because they are the weaker
and more vulnerable things that can push
around and they can't push back.
And so when you consider your life and
you consider this horrible,
uh,
these stories that you're telling us
about your upbringing,
how disturbing it is,
does it feel to you,
since you've found this like sense of
purpose in this,
um,
this real connection with these people
in the Congo that almost like these
horrible events in your life or setting
you up to be the perfect person to find
these folks?
Without a doubt.
For me,
honestly,
it's,
it's almost like a,
it's the right word.
Maybe maybe sort of my chance at kind of
redemption or,
or just not,
not being the kid that I grew up being.
Not that was a bad kid or anything,
but just I hated myself and like,
you know what I get to,
he just stopped hating myself.
I need to stop and I get to start loving
others.
Well,
not just that,
you also have this massive impact on
other people.
You have all these people that love you.
You have this amazing wife.
Now you have this amazing pygmy family.
You have your regular family.
To me,
he's like,
you have so much positive going on now.
It's really kind of incredible.
It's almost like you are the horrible
experiences you had as a young kid have
sort of made you into this incredible
adult.
Oh,
I think
I don't know about that because
I don't even know how this.
Honestly,
there's,
there's not a good explanation that I
could probably explain that like it
should be working or that it's working
like it is because it will with me at
the front of it because I don't have any
community development training or would
you agree?
Um,
I actually don't speak the language I'm
learning,
but how much can you speak when he kind
of wrote a mentoree?
I don't even like Como te Amo.
Joe?
Yeah.
I couldn't say my name is this,
where's the bathroom?
Are you doing okay?
You're sure you,
you're like,
oh,
you lost me.
It's tough if it,
the saying is it's proof.
What does it sound like?
What do they sound like?
We're talking a Jimmy Pilsen pick me up
that's called this kind of like our
walkie talkies.
Oh yeah,
I yelled that out and let people know
where you are.
What.
So what are
you saying when you're saying that?
That is actually,
that's not a word.
It's just like,
yeah,
that's actually I'm over here.
It's Kinda thing like that or we're just
checking where even just excitement,
just fun.
I mean whenever we go on hikes,
those hikes or long,
right?
And there's no tv or you can text her
scroll,
Scroll the Internet.
Um,
you,
yeah,
have each other,
which is always great.
But then he'd goof off.
I mean,
I actually know what,
uh,
I,
I bet in one of those videos it has them
speaking and it's pretty awesome.
I remember that when you're saying,
when you're saying the hikes,
like you talking like recreational
hikes.
No,
no,
no.
You just got to get you here and talk
with someone talking about hikes in La.
It's like,
oh,
I want to take my little dog to run you
in.
We're going to go hiking.
Like he say hiking,
and that's what people think of some
recreational activity with none of those
little,
a little camel things,
the little camelback water reservoirs
you put on your back when you suck on
the straws are walking.
It was funny.
I and staying hydrated,
I took,
I took a couple of those to Congo the
first couple of times and I realized
just how impractical they are and in a
real longterm,
not at,
not a day hike or three day weekend or
something.
A lot of guys don't like those.
A lot of guys don't like them.
They'd rather have a.
How do you say that word now?
Jean Valjean.
How do you say it?
I think it's like,
what is that?
It's just like a certain type of
plastic.
I think it's really hard.
Durable plastic that.
Yeah,
that people use for water jugs.
But uh,
that's what I would rather because the
other ones too already clean and yeah,
sort to fill up just all sorts of stuff.
But some people like it because they
don't,
they don't have to stop.
They can just keep walking and just suck
on that thing as they're walking.
I've never used one though.
Yeah,
I used it for the first two times I
went,
which was like a,
about a month each.
And you switched to water bottles?
Yeah.
And then even the,
they have those camelback kind of like,
I think they're called like a platypus
or something that's um,
it's a gravity filter for water where
you have a dirty water bagging.
If a clean the dirty hang,
hang the dirty and it goes down through
a filter and into the clean bag.
I've seen that.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Posed.
See if you could find that.
Does that work?
Those are the,
I think they work great here in the
states where you're not dealing with
much.
Right.
But whenever the water is dirty,
like really dirty it,
they break pretty quick so you have to
backwash from and other.
There's,
there's some that are that are good,
but even the maintenance of them just
really,
really tough.
So they work for like one filtration but
they won't work the first time I went
for about a month,
I had it for a week or two and then all
of a sudden it was heartbreaking because
I was even filtering the water,
you know,
in the town that's coming from wells
because I don't know if they,
if they did it properly right when they
call and,
and I had been sick enough.
I'm like,
yeah,
I hear Ya.
So I'm filtering that stuff.
And then by the time I get out to the
forest I was able to use a few days and
then it was out in the sun was stuck
with just chlorine tablets the rest of
the time.
And you can boil it,
but it's,
it's just impractical.
Where every single time you want to
drink,
you take,
uh,
you know,
take a container down to dirty water,
which could be 30,
45 minutes away.
I'm bringing it back,
boil it,
right,
bring it back,
boil it a filter.
Yeah.
And then all of a sudden,
all the,
the ashes getting in it.
And then it's the hot humid rainforest
on the equator.
And boiling water doesn't cool down
basically ever there.
So,
uh,
it's,
it's impractical to do it that way.
Fuck.
But what I love now is,
Oh,
you know,
it's guy.
Let's do it.
So this is this girl,
first of all,
she's way too hot to be in this video is
very distracting.
But,
uh,
they're gonna take this in what looks
like a very clean stream.
So this is so much different than when
you.
But people should also be aware that
clean streams,
although they may look clean,
you can still get Giardia from them yet
that,
that's exactly what I learned from,
uh,
his name is buddy of mine.
We,
Matt,
he was the director of implementation.
Now he's like the chief operating
officer and he,
uh,
he came out there and one of the things
he really drilled into us for a well
drilling team.
We're learning from a great guy.
He's saying,
Hey,
you can,
uh,
you can drill 100 wells or 200 wells,
but if you didn't do it right and proper
that I would have rather done one the
right way or none,
none.
If you do it the right or the wrong way
100 times,
200 times,
um,
and you are giving a village.
Like he's,
he just hit home hard because he's like,
look,
we're learning every single step.
You can't skip one week.
Got a drill us anywhere,
you know it,
you know,
because we can't skip a step or miss
something and then all of a sudden they
are looking at it,
drinking it.
It tastes good.
It's a,
it's clean,
it's cool,
it's crisp,
it's in a well,
but yet it can still still be
contaminated,
dirty.
And so get real sick if you don't
properly construct well no matter what.
Well it is the wells here anywhere.
What is the,
what are the factors like when you say
product properly construct,
like what are the issues that you have
to avoid?
Yes,
we man,
our teams getting great.
But by the way,
real quick,
last time I was on the show,
I think we had completed 20 water wells.
I went back and looked at that 20 water
wells today.
I got a picture sent to me and it's our
45th water.
Whoa,
that's incredible dude.
I love it.
Absolutely love it.
And so what's so great is seeing that,
you know,
they're,
they're taking this on as,
as their own thing,
flying on their own two wings.
They,
they were empowered in a way that's
like,
hey,
you can,
you can do this,
you can do it for yourself,
for your countrymen.
Um,
you guys are going to be more passionate
about ending the suffering because you
know the suffering because you have
suffered,
you've lost family members,
you have sick kids all at different
stuff.
And so they're going to be able to be a
better champion for this cause then I
could be,
because I mean maybe we have different
resources where I get to,
you know,
you share your platform with me,
which has been incredible.
Um,
and the kickstarter and the documentary
coming out,
all the different stuff is really great.
But,
um,
but I know that the team,
they're like,
I,
I couldn't do anything without them
doing it.
And how great they've gotten button.
Well that's a beautiful thing that
you've helped them help themselves.
Taught them how to help themselves.
Yeah.
Well that right there.
Look at that picture.
There we go.
Yeah.
I love it.
That's that to me,
if I could explain it as better than um,
I've been to the world.
I was just at UFC 200,
uh,
was that uh,
the world series,
NBA finals,
superbowl packy all fights.
I mean,
I've been to all these things and I mean
those crowds,
those huge crowds are 30,
40,
50 100,000 different stuff and that
little crowd of 100 hundred 20 like to
me it drowns out the sound of a entire
stadium.
Like it's a different kind of,
it's a different kind of gratitude,
thankfulness when you suffered your
whole life and then you,
you get to partner with people in a non.
Not even talking about me like our team,
our well drillers,
you know,
they see them coming in,
staying with them,
living like they're living,
eating like they're eating,
sitting around the campfire,
like they sit around which nobody else
does that with them.
And so sleeping in the Hudson,
these sleep and um,
which nobody else would do a in that
area.
Um,
and then like you just develop this bond
and really quickly and where all of a
sudden they're jumping in and helping
with the construction of the well and
everything else.
Now they do the simple daily routine
stuff.
Not the technical stuff,
but then yeah,
our guys are there.
They're getting to down,
which was pretty cool.
That's amazing though.
Now you're at 45 wells.
Yeah.
And what is.
Do you have an ultimate goal or would
you just like to continue?
I think the my ultimate goal lines up
with water for his ultimate goal,
which I love and then with our drillers
in Congo,
like our goal is to end the water crisis
of possible.
We think it is possible and we have the
technology.
We should be able to do it in our
lifetime.
Like before you were me past this earth.
Like we should have the technology to
get everyone clean water.
Isn't it crazy shit that is,
that's our issue.
When when over here in America we have
so many trivial things that we're
constantly worrying about and fretting
when when they get down to basic human
necessities like water,
the ability to get clean water,
which is without that,
all the,
all the other things that we argue or
bicker about,
they're all.
It's all nonsense.
Absolutely.
That's something that,
oh man,
that's something that I,
I almost like,
okay,
get this crazy culture shock because I
feel like I'm in two different worlds
and when I'm there,
so I mean there's,
it's uncomfortable,
but because I'm passionate about it,
you know,
I enjoy it.
But then getting back here,
sometimes it's like,
man,
like everything,
lot of times everything that we're
chasing,
even me,
it doesn't really matter in the big
grand scheme of things,
you know,
how can we,
how can we get for ourselves,
how can we give to another person?
Because like,
I mean,
it truly is like,
that's better than I know you have to
take care of yourself so you can take
care of someone else.
Like I,
I get that.
Um,
I just think it's kind of like this art
culture here.
You see kids and even adults,
that's mine,
right?
I mean,
that's,
that's our culture.
We say that's mine.
Give me that.
It's mine.
In Congo,
if a,
if a kid,
if a kid that had the eggs,
instead of having an egg,
if he had a bag of peanuts and he bought
it for himself and then I walked by
sitting down with them if a friend or
not even just introducing myself,
he's gonna offer me his food.
He said instead of it's mine,
he's going to say you want some.
And so it's different in that culture
where it's not,
they don't have anything,
but they'll give you everything that got
like,
for instance,
um,
that,
that knife last time,
uh,
that I was able to bring back,
that chief Leo may made,
um,
you know,
he,
he made a bow and Arrow and I'm actually
bringing that to you.
It was under our crawlspace and I lost
it when now everyone know where it is.
But uh,
it's pumped to bring that back to you.
But I mean for them to give that kind of
stuff away.
Whenever Leo May,
he's the chief of his village and now
because he's got a job,
he might have more.
But whenever I knew him,
he had maybe he was lucky if he had two
changes of clothes because most of the
pygmies have the clothes on their back.
They don't even have a blanket,
the fires their blanket.
Um,
and so it's just completely night and
day difference.
There's a lot of people that listen to
this,
that have gotten this far,
that want to figure out how they can
help.
So what,
what can people do to donate?
We're working.
They go,
yeah.
I mean water for his website.
Is that the best place to start or
forgotten.com?
Both of them are one in the same for the
forgotten Dr. Yeah.
Dot Com.org.
They both work,
both work for the [inaudible] dot com
and there's a big yellow donate button.
Click on that and have added folks.
Thank you man.
It's been a,
it's been crazy what's going on.
We're getting ready to do something that
I'm,
I'm pumped about me and Papa y and Ben
and Matt,
we had talked about it and kind of
dreamed it up and uh,
and we were saying how awesome would it
be in the center in Buena,
which is kind of a city center,
maybe half less than half a million
people for sure.
But um,
you know,
in the city center where there's a
university,
there's a community development program
that's literally changing their part of
Congo by not waiting on the government
or by not waiting on an NGO,
like they're just taking the initiative
themselves.
And so we've seen that they're so bought
in that whenever we presented an idea of
what if we could start a sustainable
solutions appropriate technology center
where there's land,
water and food solutions and then after
that maybe we can get into solar and
maybe after that we can do this or that
or you know,
whatever.
But at that place will have different
stations where here's land,
you can come learn about land rights,
how to replant the trees,
the forestry aspect,
you know,
all that different stuff.
The ports of land and we have people
there that can help and show them
things.
If a chief wants to come in and book our
well drilling team for their community,
for their,
they can come in,
see how we do it,
why we do it,
everything about it.
We wouldn't have a little conference
room where we can train people up on the
wash program because now we're doing
that.
All the villages that we've drilled
wells in,
we're going back in,
we're doing the wash program,
water and sanitation and hygiene.
And so with that,
I mean if you didn't have the,
have outhouses,
what do they use for their.
Getting them there,
getting them now.
And so,
uh,
for the year I was there,
there was one or two of the 10 villages
we were in,
had a quote unquote latrine,
but it was only like three or four feet
deep,
which isn't,
isn't a safe some,
most of them are just going in the
woods.
Yeah.
And honestly like that's if.
Yeah,
until you do it the right way with cars
outside of there,
some of those,
some of those latrines in the city's
man.
I,
I definitely think I've gotten sick from
a fly that maybe waited there.
So I mean,
I don't know,
but um,
but yeah,
so we get to go in there now,
teach them how to dig the latrines,
make sure it's way far enough away from
the water.
Well,
um,
and then,
you know,
outside of that,
that's another issue too.
Erratic and can contaminate the water if
you want.
If you have to keep um,
what is I think 30 meters away,
uh,
or more any latrines.
And then if it's a,
uh,
like a,
was that a dump?
The trash dump?
Um,
it has to be 50 meters or more
batteries,
different stuff like that.
And um,
and so yeah,
we make sure in this is what's not.
So uh,
uh,
one of my last trips I went and we're
going through Uganda on the border of
Congo and there's these people,
they're so proud of their water well,
and I love that.
But then I feel like the people,
whoever did it,
um,
I don't know,
cut them really short,
they're just,
they shouldn't be drilling wells because
I went to the restroom and then also I
look out the window and I'm at a gas
station you got,
is a lot nicer than Congo.
Um,
I mean there's still terrible brutal
party parts of that,
but just night and day difference.
Um,
and whenever I looked out and see
there's,
here's the 18 wheeler filling up,
here's someone else up in,
in between that I'm,
I'm at the toilets at the other side.
There's a trash dump.
There's 18 wheelers and trucks filling
up with fuel.
And right in the middle of the two fuel
pumps is a water.
Well,
they drilled it on the,
on the lot of the gas station with a
trash dump with a latrines and toilets.
And so it was completely contaminating
in.
The line was so long in.
And Ben was trying to tell him like,
hey,
just want to tell you because we love
you.
That water is really not safe.
Same thing,
Matt,
Matt kind of ingrained,
ingrained that into a store.
It's like,
um,
you know,
you got to do it the right way.
And so ben was taught that,
so these recent well that these guys had
put in and it was one of the,
and there's a big line of people to try
to get to this,
telling you there was at least 20,
30 people in line.
Um,
and Ben was trying to tell them in the
most appropriate way possible.
They're like not crush the hopes and
dreams of the village there,
but you also want to know like,
hey,
this water can,
it looks safe.
It's not.
So uh,
so that's why we're testing our wells
and whatever happened in that,
which is you had to leave.
Yeah,
I mean it's a town we don't,
I've been in the town maybe twice,
but um,
yeah,
it was the first time that I saw last
time.
Jesus.
Yup.
So,
uh,
but that's what's creating a lot of
people don't know,
like a,
I think it's no,
I know it is.
Half the hospital beds in the world
right now are because of dirty water or
water borne related diseases,
half,
half and half.
Right.
So if,
if we were able to,
if,
if as human beings,
if we could join forces unite,
Kinda like everyone did against a
bullet,
if we attack the problem head on and
just because we got it,
we don't pretend to everybody else has
it.
Like we could really in this thing,
we could,
uh,
we could fix it.
Like the tools are there,
the water is there,
it's under her feet.
And here we wasted it.
And there we,
they're,
uh,
they don't have it.
We don't hear about Ebola anymore.
It's like,
it's over.
It's like they moved on to Zika,
Zika,
Zika.
Are All the Olympians are going to get
it?
Yeah.
They're fucked all of them.
Oh,
this is crazy.
When I got back,
they were,
the CDC was testing me on two different
rounds of treatments trying to figure
out what.
So on that trip I told you going in,
I got malaria right now,
malaria.
I keep me ask you this because you have
malaria can somehow get it from,
you know,
if a mosquito stings you while you have
malaria and instinct,
somebody else,
they can't get it.
Uh,
I mean that's what I never heard of.
I've never thought of that one.
But remember that when people were
worried about that with HIV,
they're worried about mosquito
transmission.
That was like the big thing.
Keep away from gay people in the summer.
No,
I,
I had never thought of that.
But I know that don't shoot here on the
swamp.
I know that the,
yeah,
the doctors that,
you know,
they're always saying you're,
you're fine.
I mean I can,
I can fight and everything else.
That's crazy.
My blood.
And you have malaria and you could
fight.
Yeah.
But I,
I literally don't because it's in my
liver.
I think you'd have to go into the liver
unless it was a current outbreak.
That,
what about a liver kick?
Got Liver kicked.
Don't,
don't let out the Bazooka,
just get.
Um,
no,
but it's,
it's,
it's been a lot of fun too.
I don't know,
I,
I think what maybe kinda shifted was the
kinda grown up,
you know,
getting bullied.
You're only looking at why am I getting
bullied and all this stuff's true and I
am not a good person.
And then nobody likes me,
whatever.
Then when I got 23 fighting,
still not really fulfilled.
I was living for more for myself there.
And I'm like,
man,
what?
What am I doing with my life?
And now it's so cool because seeing that
and being able to tell you that last
time I was here 20 water wells or 25.
But regardless we've,
we've done 20 or 25 more.
And so that to me is a life that I get
to look at.
And if I were to,
if I were to die,
I know,
I know without a shadow of a doubt that
my life meant something.
And I know that I would,
I never felt that before,
during the depression,
addiction and all that other stuff.
But now I know that the life I live
hopefully will outlive my life.
You know,
like the,
I want this team to doing what they're
doing,
climb higher than I can climb,
run farther than that.
I can run,
jump higher than I can jump,
you know,
like I want my.
What's that saying?
I want my,
a ceiling to be there for.
I want them to go farther than I can go
because then that means that I actually
made an impact that matters,
that matter to them enough that it
continued,
that it had a residual effect that just
kept kept on going and me,
and that's really shifted kind of kind
of everything in my life.
Like,
man,
this is,
this is what life is about.
Like if I know I've been signing my book
recently or ever since it came out,
but I signed it live to love,
love to live and I know that can sound
cheesy or goofy or whatever,
but that's something that just really
helped me whenever I was sobering up was
man,
if that's what I focus on,
if I can live my life to love,
love now,
love the live,
but everyone wants to love their own
life that they live and so they're just
focused on that and get this and get
this materialistic thing and get this
different chick because she didn't make
me happier.
You know,
this or that or whatever.
Whenever it's like,
you know what?
Like,
Hey,
let's focus.
Let's.
I don't know if that's.
If that's a natural inclination to
gravitate towards unattainable things
like Ferrari's and mansions and you see
those things on tv and the movies and
you just,
that shows you that you've made it and
when you don't have anything in,
you're wanting for
things and you don't have money and
you're struggling,
you look at someone who's got all those
things and money and you think,
if I only had that all my worries would
be gone,
then I would be happy.
But if you have that and nobody likes
you,
you life is shit.
Yeah,
it's,
it's still shit.
Meanwhile,
you are in a hut in the middle of
nowhere with,
well the middle of the Congo with all
these people and you're having a great
time and you're making wells and you're
loving life that,
that picture that
came up,
I think why?
Why I got so excited was um,
because that night in that village,
I mean we,
I'm not kidding.
Danced and danced and danced and in and
in feast it.
I mean we just all came together just to
celebrate,
celebrate life,
celebrate each other,
celebrate.
Guess what?
Our kids are going to be sick anymore.
Different stuff like that too,
where it's just a life where like,
like what you were just saying,
you're always comparing,
comparing,
comparing.
For me,
man.
Comparison.
I think for most people,
um,
comparison is probably the number one
fif what robs us of joy,
of,
of being able to be at peace is we're
always comparing ourselves and we always
compare up.
We never compared down,
um,
or just compare ourselves to people that
are just like us.
We always look at that.
What you're saying is unattainable and
I'm always pursuing that.
And my whole thing has been like
recently just man,
I just want,
I think our,
I've learned it from our team in Congo.
Like that's been the greatest gift.
Like you were saying that,
you know,
there's been a lot of great stuff that's
been happening and that's true.
But I,
and started thinking now I think it
sounds Cliche,
but I'll say it anyways,
where men like
they've given me more of a gift than I
can.
I can give them.
I mean,
you,
you see,
I told you that the grown up and
everything else,
but to,
to find a life of,
of purpose,
have passion of helping one another of,
I don't know,
our mission statement is defend the weak
love,
the unloved and power,
the voiceless than the vision statement
is overcoming oppression with
overwhelming opportunity.
And so if we can go into these
communities and we've seen incredible
stuff,
that's what's gonna be in the Doc.
This last trip,
me,
Ben,
Matt and Derek,
the filmmaker,
we would not be,
they wouldn't be ashamed.
Me saying this,
we were in tears after an interview
with,
uh,
one of the former slave masters that ran
a hospital,
um,
in actually,
if you could pull up a picture,
it's called Cap Toula.
Um,
and we were at this,
this hospital.
And it's tough because we were trying to
get treatment for Cap Tuliza.
He's a buddy of mine that passed away.
Um,
and we spent seven months taking the
hospital to the hospital,
the hospital,
and they're just send them away because
it was the pygmy in.
And it's like,
I,
my
first song actually if you bring up the
maybe the first cap,
that's when I saw them,
that's when I saw him for the very first
time or looking at a guidance is
extremely amazing.
Yeah.
And so for me,
so what is going on with his health
right here,
right there.
We didn't know.
But uh,
I had,
uh,
I mean a gut feeling that it could have
been tuberculosis because we've,
we've helped several of the pygmies have
tuberculosis and stuff,
little grilling Faena and some others.
Um,
fema,
nettle root cause of tuberculosis.
There was some sort of a study on that.
Reasons that you have a low immune
system.
And uh,
there was something that just came out
like really recently about tuberculosis.
Were there.
I had something to do with fire.
Hmm.
Oh,
if,
if it's something to do with smoke,
I believe that because the bacteria from
person to person through microscopic
droplets releasing the air can happen
when someone in the untreated active
form of tuberculosis cough speaks,
sneezes,
Spitz,
laughs or sayings,
Jesus Christ.
Mind you get tuberculosis from a shitty
song.
Like some dude breaks out the Banjo,
like that scene in animal house breaks
out a guitar and started saying it and
it gives you tuberculosis as well as an
ir beating.
Let's see if this.
Was there,
some connection with fire.
I swear I read something really recently
about that.
Some connection between tuberculosis.
Is that it?
Here it is.
Was tuberculosis born of fire by
damaging lungs and bringing people
together?
Fire may have turned a soil.
Microbes into global pathogen.
Whoa.
Many thousands of years ago.
Chile.
African night.
That's interesting.
So they think that might have started it
all around a fire in a cave and that
were always in the fire.
I can't.
I can't sleep with.
That's why the bugs are even worse on me
because I.
I have many times slept in the huts
whenever the fires go in,
but it just fills up with smoke toward
my eyes.
Just tears are coming down with the
light.
A fire in their hut.
Yeah,
that's their.
That's how they keep the bugs out.
Oh,
well it's one of the ways,
but it's mainly for warmth,
but a benefit is there's less bugs and
then uh,
it,
uh,
and it can help waterproof.
They're tweaking leaf huts were enough
smoke and everything had kinda like a
tar.
So yeah.
Your lungs too though,
right?
Of course.
Yeah.
And there's so many kids that are
getting in at this sustainable solutions
center that we're hoping to,
you know,
get up and running.
We're wanting one for cooking where they
can use either corn cobs or a or corn
husk or peanut shells or different
things where they can put those into
little briquettes and then they can use
that and recycle it and everything else
in it,
it burns longer,
uh,
at,
at the same temperature.
And uh,
yeah.
And you don't have to force anything and
you're not breathing in that terrible
smoke.
Coconut charcoal
is a really fun.
Um,
there's uh,
some company,
a grilled tomato company.
You know what a tomato is one of those
Japanese grills.
Yes,
like a green egg,
that kind of thing.
And they sell a charcoal made out of
coconut and apparently it's one of the
best charcoals because it's really
sustainable,
it's really easy to grow and it's a,
it's much wages throw it away.
So yeah,
exactly.
People throw the outside of the cook
another way,
but apparently it's really good for
charcoal.
So Bella tour has embraced this
narrative.
They've embraced your story and they've
made it a big part of your fighting
there to,
uh,
let everybody know that you're doing it,
not just because you want to compete,
but also because you want to expose the
world to this passion that this project,
this,
this sort of life direction that you've
taken.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And I,
it's really cool that they've done that.
Yeah,
no,
I,
I agree in that.
That was the,
I love it dude.
I love the UFC.
That's what I was 13 years old.
Found the stapes and I'm just on that
real quick,
uh,
why bottle those tapes put 'em under my
bed and I would wait for my parents to
go to work or to go to sleep and I'd be
popping them in.
Uh,
the,
you know,
the vhs and my dad comes in and I turn
it off real quick,
lay down,
act like I'm asleep and it's,
you know,
the vcrs,
vhs is still moving in the,
the,
I don't know,
the screen still lit up and everything,
but he had confiscated that tape.
Then when he found the rest he thought
it was a,
all porn,
but it was a binding confiscated a lot.
I think me being 13 being picked on it.
He didn't want me to start fighting
people at school and different stuff.
And so just a,
just a precaution.
But he always,
he told my mom he's going to do that one
day if we let him keep that stuff.
I was like,
no,
it won't.
But in my head I'm like,
yeah,
I will.
I remember looking at the vhs tape and
when I turned it over and saw the
Jujitsu and sumo and boxing and
wrestling and all these different
things,
like it came alive to me and it's like,
oh my goodness,
these guys.
Well,
I think I originally connected with it
because because I,
I'm like,
well these guys are anything like me,
they could stick up for themselves.
They can,
they're an athlete,
they're popular,
probably said being the laughingstock at
the party.
It might be invited to the party or it
might be their party.
And so I mean I,
I liked that aspect,
but then I just fell in love with the
sport of it and you're watching it and
seeing how everything and now being a
fan and watch now it's evolved and
everything else.
It's just,
it's not seeing the guy like Dan
Henderson that's been fighting,
I think isn't it?
Twenty years straight.
20,
straight.
So I was there when he was fighting in
97 and I wasn't there for his first
fight.
He fought in [inaudible] 96 I think in
Brazil.
Yup.
I think that was his first.
I actually watched that first fight in
the last couple of weeks.
Really?
Yeah,
because
dude,
I loved him.
Awesome.
Yeah.
And see him even I.
because whenever he stepped in,
he was just a wrestler that had heavy
hands,
but then he just,
he didn't even have to be.
Yeah,
you're right.
You're right.
Getting it was just a down and I'm
taking them down and pound on them and
he figured out over time how to utilize
his power.
That's what I want to get.
Maybe I could bribe a den or big country
or someone to teach me that big right
hand.
Do you think someone that I don't mean
Dan's one of the guys that have come on,
but big country always has power.
Big country was known way back in the
day as being a Jujitsu guy.
He was one of Mark Landmines guys.
And he was a,
you know,
like really respected as a grappler
black belt.
But to go from that to being this crazy
knockout brawler,
it's like people rarely see big country.
He'd never seen submitted anybody.
I mean,
the closest thing was when he took Kimbo
down and got him into the mounted
crucifix and just elbowed them until the
referee stopped the fight.
But then the whole season,
uh,
he,
I think there were a couple elbows,
but when they finally stopped it,
we were all counting every single punch
and then,
uh,
but he was just,
just tapping his forehead like this one
because it wasn't intelligently
defending himself,
but he didn't even have to hurt them to
stop the fight.
I just tapping his forehead.
Well,
he was almost like a,
you know,
when you,
what does that called in wrestling when
you have so many points?
It's a technical.
Yeah.
That fall,
fall almost like that.
It's like you're never coming back to
this 10,
10 run rule and little league baseball.
Yeah,
10 points up.
You just call it.
And uh,
the big countries got very good
submissions.
But everybody expected that from him
when he started fighting.
Like if you remember back when he was
fighting for a lead ECC,
which was like the most corrupt
organization in the early days of MMA.
He had Andre Arlovski down control up
working for Komora,
had that control and had that double
wrist lock position and it was working
for the Camorra and they stood them
right up.
And I remember watching TV going,
it's cool screaming at the TV,
it's Co rob,
they had a 15 second rule,
like if you went,
if you went to the ground,
if nothing happened in 15 seconds,
I think jake shields submitted Paul
Daley.
It was one of the few submissions and
that lead to ECC,
but it's just,
he just mounted them and just
immediately went to an arm bar and
locked it in.
Well,
yeah,
I think it's Paul Daley.
I might be wrong.
I was actually,
um,
I mean,
no,
with kimball stuff happening.
It's pretty roomy.
It's sad.
Very sad that man.
I mean apparently he had a doctor
telling them,
you know,
for people don't know what we're talking
about.
Kimbo died really recently of a heart
disease and he had a doctor telling them
recently that uh,
he needed a heart transplant.
I guess he had some sort of congenital
heart disease that um,
I mean,
how could that be,
you know,
you look at them,
you guys a studies in great shape.
I mean,
how could you imagine that he,
his heart was so bad
that they were telling me you needed a
heart transplant
and this.
Yeah,
this could probably sounds cliche again
too,
because knowing him being on ultimate
fighter and a and him cooking the best
steak I've ever had.
Sorry,
big Josh.
Um,
uh,
but he,
I don't know yet,
even though we had a bad heart.
I think emotionally I had a good heart
and um,
he was always a good guy.
He's a very friendly guy.
Yeah.
Even even with,
um,
I mean technically we were supposed to
fight I think three times before or two
times elite ECC.
I wish my name was in the hat for that.
Um,
and then because I was like in 19 or 20
year old kid,
I had a decent record and then,
um,
but it was bad matchup so they scrapped
it a get.
It wasn't smart then,
uh,
then on the ultimate fighter I was
actually matched up with them and uh,
then Roy got it.
Um,
and then we were talking about it and
Bella tour were at our last fight.
Um,
February 19th I think,
Houston Toyota Center.
Um,
and backstage,
uh Oh,
actually that was this,
this will be good in a way that the dude
just loved on.
Been My,
uh,
brother and translated from Congo.
He got to actually come from Congo for
the,
my second fight.
And so the first fight actually,
if you can pull up that video,
it's a,
it's called,
um,
fight day,
uh,
talking to my guys.
But um,
it's just,
uh,
it's less than a minute I think.
And it's,
uh,
they,
they surprised me for my first fight
back.
Um,
they surprised with Josh woke me up and
it was a guy that's like when my father
figure.
Got It.
It's like my brother and uh,
just awesome.
Fight Day.
My first thing you'd see in here is
this,
this was so awesome.
Who is this that's laying down to us?
Media.
Is that your voice?
You're going to watch it?
Yeah.
You can't fall in from presenter,
but we'll record this shit.
Is it even tells you it's a beard?
He had talking beard.
Yeah,
I miss.
You guys
can stop it at a minute.
Yeah.
Yes sir.
The battle's already won before the
fight.
Hey,
your go back to can
you can,
you can stop it now.
And then,
um,
it was uh,
it was really cool.
Like,
I mean Josh was filming because he
didn't want,
I guess it was a surprise they were
going to call me and everything else,
but they were in Uganda getting more
well drilling supplies and because you
can't,
you can't skype from,
from Congo.
So they were at a decent enough hotel,
had wifi and they were able to skype
with me the day of my first fight back
and uh,
me and it was awesome.
It was so much motivation.
Seeing them here in them and then having
them come for the second fight was just
a and b.
There he was actually,
he was actually in my corner.
What you're doing is helping them by
building wells is there.
Once you do that,
like say if you establish a series of
wells and well building and everybody
has fresh water,
do you want to take it?
Another step?
Did you,
did you want to try to give them safer
housing or cleaner housing?
Do you want to try to teach them how to
build houses or are you,
are you planning on an escalating it
from where you're at right now?
Yeah,
in fact,
I went about it and it was a,
it was a learning lesson.
I don't regret it because I've got some
great training here in California as a,
I think it's,
is it called Hisperia?
California?
And uh,
there's something called cal earth and
they built eco domes are earth bag homes
and uh,
what they call them,
super adobe,
the technical term,
but they make,
it looks like pygmy huts out of sandbags
that they fill up with sand doing a
circle and supposedly there are
earthquake proof,
tornado proof,
all this different stuff.
And this is it.
Yeah,
right there in a dome is the strongest
structure known to Man Arches after
that,
or volt than the arch.
But yeah,
I was in these exact buildings.
That's like a hobbit house.
What a cool looking little house house.
It'll back up.
But I,
I went there because that's an Aztec
God,
right?
That's that Aztec snake,
snake,
feathered,
plumed serpent.
God,
Costa Rica.
It might be,
oh,
okay,
that makes sense.
Cal Earth greenbuild actually level
those guys there.
They have,
we have a lot of likeminded,
um,
beliefs of,
of how to help people.
And uh,
but yeah,
I loved it because housing was because I
slept in the Hudson the first two times
I went and got rained on and literally
one time woke up in the mud,
like sunk halfway because it just rained
and rained and rained and rained and we
were just lying in mud.
Yeah.
To where it just kept coming through was
just washing down the hill and when my
wife was there as doing it again and
hold the pygmies get up and uh,
they came out and I didn't know what
they were doing.
Um,
I thought someone was going on because
everyone was around or hunting circle.
I'm digging this trench so it wouldn't
come in and get emily wet and uh,
they're just so caring.
So awesome.
And uh,
but when I saw the Hud,
those eco domes,
earth bag homes,
I was like,
man,
that's something culturally sound.
That is something that they would want
to live in because it looks like that I
looked like their similar and so this is
something that you want to try to
implement with without a doubt,
but it has to be the right timing
because what happened was,
um,
I,
I knew pop one in the schools working on
land and I was going to help with that
too.
I had no clue how to,
how to get clean water.
Um,
I was looking forward.
I was,
I was in my backyard.
I bought everything from Lowe's back
yard and he was like a website,
I think literally something like how to
drill your own well.org or something.
And it's this guy who stand on the back
of his pickup truck and he's,
he's drilling a well,
but what I didn't know is that's not
drinkable water the way he's doing it
and everything else.
And so I'm in the backyard like five,
$600 of stuff.
Put Pvc,
trying to drill my own well by myself.
Um,
and uh,
trying to learn like me and it's so
hard.
There's gotta be an easier way.
And so I kinda stepped around that
because my,
you know what,
I can't help them with housing if I go
here and get trained,
sandbags are cheap,
get a couple shovels,
make some mud and get some cement and
make a plaster to go around it to
waterproof it better.
Um,
and that's gonna work.
But then when we kind of pastor on how
to make it,
make it out of a,
a mix of a cement and um,
soil.
And uh,
if,
if it's got the right mixture,
which I'm forgetting right now,
um,
it can be just as strong as or
waterproof as a concreter yeah.
So it's a,
it's a really great thing.
But when I get there and all of a sudden
I see,
you know,
hey,
uh,
first,
if they don't have any land of their own
than building,
these things are going to be worthless.
Someone else can move into them.
And uh,
so they got to have land.
Firstly,
there's a process,
like the most important things land in
the water is water is next then food.
And then for that,
yes it can be healthy.
I want to stay in a sweet spot in the
Middle Lane and not spread ourselves too
thin because you thought about this,
but these people that you dealt with in
California trying to bring them in and
have.
Yeah,
that would be cool.
Take over that aspect of it.
Yes,
that would be cool.
The only thing that we are,
is we try to be really protective of the
big means.
Um,
and because uh,
kind of bringing in a lot of outsiders,
um,
most outsiders that visit them,
that's not a good experience.
And so just bringing a lot of random
people,
if it was a couple of people that really
highly skilled,
had the right hearts,
their vision lined up with our vision of
how we can I do the commute development
because we want to.
There's,
I think there's a great book,
I think it's called a helping without
hurting or how to help without hurting
or something like that and have it and
you it to them.
And it's,
it's really great about how you can go
about helping people in a way that helps
them more than helps you in a way of,
like,
a lot of people help because it's going
to make them feel warm and fuzzy and um,
and,
and yeah,
and you just do that enough for random
people.
But what if you can make a difference
that,
that lasted longer and it's great to do
both.
Right?
It's great to do both.
I actually love my.
See someone else do some random act of
kindness.
Like it,
it warms my heart.
I love it.
But how can we help in a way that,
that really changes the game of,
of things there?
Well,
I think you definitely already doing
that.
I mean,
you're certainly spreading it.
I think you feel like it's a long job
and your job is not nearly done button.
I don't think it ever ever will be.
Oh well for water.
I,
I've definitely hope for that.
But then,
I don't know,
I think I just feel,
whenever he was it,
when you have that heart connection,
it's kind of like,
well,
I want to see these people if they have,
if they have everything I got to like,
I still want to hang out with them all I
can of course.
But,
um,
no,
you know what though?
It's been really cool to see.
Um,
so there's these guys from Uganda that
came in and helped train us in there
called young men drillers.
And there were these guys that were,
you've heard of the LRA and Joseph Kony
and different stuff like that.
One of the guys was,
he told me around a campfire that he was
one of two.
It might've been three survivors of a
three,
four,
500 person village.
The railroads came in,
killed everybody.
He barely escaped.
And um,
then another kid and another kid.
And it's so cool to see these young guys
all of a sudden stand up in water for,
got involved with them and train them up
on how to drill wells in their own
country.
And these are,
when I say young men drillers,
like I think someone were 16,
17,
18 when they started,
well then all of a sudden they cranked
out over 100 water wells over 100 water
wells.
They've been doing it longer than we
have.
We haven't done any.
I'm in the Congo.
We try to get them out to us to help
matt comes in to train us and to
continue training with them.
And then they were going to leave that
team.
You've got the main three guys from him,
the drillers behind to train us to
invest and impart their knowledge and
us,
uh,
Matt was doing real intensive training
and then these guys are going to stick
around for the next three months,
make sure we could bust out,
you know,
a,
a few wells and do it the right way.
And so it's so cool.
They came and stayed with us and so cool
to see what they've gone through all
that where one of the guys,
it was probably every other night or
every three nights,
he's waking up in night terrors where he
is just screaming.
And I had never been around that before,
um,
but the things he saw,
things he's been through are just so
tough.
But then to see he chose that he's going
to take a different path.
He's gonna,
he's gonna,
he's gonna find something that you can
help people with in these,
going to give it to others in a
different country in Congo.
So they came and lived with pygmies for
three years or three months.
It was awesome.
Now a ben and a couple of our other
drillers are in Cameroon.
Um,
and I,
I kinda had this thing that I haven't
really spoken out,
but I would love to see the piggies and
Congo.
I'll have water.
But then after that,
you know,
the other pygmies are suffering in very
similar ways to the pygmies and Congo.
And so what's so cool is that,
okay,
the young men drillers comes out,
invest in us,
pours their hearts lives.
They almost died.
Come in to us.
Their car flipped,
ran over a lady,
a taxi driver was driving and he ran
away.
She died.
Oh fuck.
They ran over a lady.
No,
they didn't.
The cab driver,
cab driver did and he bailed.
He,
he was from Congo,
they were from Uganda and at the border
they had to get in with a Congolese taxi
driver,
who will they do that?
They couldn't even speak the same
language and he gets in a wreck.
He knows Congo,
he does that drive all the time to the
border.
And so he just bales in literally the
people in a place called a new yoga,
which means a snake.
And it was a place of a rebel group that
used to be there and everything.
And so was very,
very bad part of town.
There's gold mines on both sides of him.
Luckily this lady took them in and held
him in there and called,
uh,
the military because people literally
had an ad whenever the not the military
about the cops.
And it was just a little shack.
I mean,
he was like,
well,
people are going to kill them because
they thought that she had killed a
woman.
Yes.
And it in there.
It doesn't matter if you know you're
guilty and we'll ask questions later
and,
uh,
someone,
it's mob justice.
Someone's got to pay if this person was
just hurt somebody,
even if you weren't driving,
even if you were one of our guys was
thrown from the vehicle,
the car went,
rolled and running away fearing for
their lives.
They had a,
I think $15,000 of well drilling
equipment and the trunk plus they had a,
uh,
a solar pump solar filter and it did
like 400 gallons of water a day.
And,
or foreign leaders,
a hundred gallons.
And anyways,
they looted the,
I think they set the car on fire.
I know they alluded it,
but then at the police station,
little shack people outside hadn't
shetty's a literal torches.
I like those hoes that,
uh,
for farming and wants to have o tires,
they're going to put tires around them
and set them on fire.
Oh God.
And so luckily I'm me and I
very luckily his miracle had a that papa
why is such a great,
uh,
like an old piece of peacekeeper.
Like he can go somewhere and talk with
him when that 70 dispute and bring them
some sort of agreement and he was able
to go out there on behalf of Blur Uganda
guys doesn't even really know him yet.
Gets them out and while they're leaving
pop wise,
really respected because of,
uh,
you know,
he,
he's actually helping people in their
country.
They like,
people know him when he's walking around
because he's like,
oh,
those are the,
that's the crew that's actually putting
what they're learning and action.
And so he went up there and as they're
getting ready to leave.
So we came up to him and whispered to
him and says,
uh,
we know where all your stuff is.
And he's like,
what?
Like everything that was stolen.
He's like,
I think it was something like he said it
to him there or later,
why they didn't keep it and why they
gave it back.
But whenever they got there,
it was a,
the case,
they've broken the lock,
opened it up and uh,
was Oh,
one other,
they open up that solar pump has got
these two different.
Uh,
Oh man,
it was more words but canisters on it
and it,
and they left it because they thought it
was a pump and so they left that and all
our wells drilling equipment and we were
able to reclaim everything,
get them to us.
They lived with us for three months,
then,
uh,
there supply chain from Uganda to Congo.
Now wrap this up where it's so cool to
see where now I'm no joke.
The guys that came out to learn from
Cameroon that work with the pygmies in
Cameroon are named a willy and turbo was
their,
their names from Cameroon.
And uh,
actually that,
that uh,
that big heavyweight,
um,
what is his name in the UFC now?
A Francis and Francis.
Yeah.
Now he's him in check Congo.
Both check on was from Congo,
I believe.
I'm not sure which one he is from.
God knows huge dude.
He is fucking you beast.
Just a scary guy man.
And both those guys ended up in France
because
the French speaking countries,
both Congo in Cameroon.
And so it's just cool to see how,
how the trickle effect comes from these
guys that are lucky to be alive then
from growing up,
then they're lucky to be alive,
coming to help us.
Then they decide to stay in the country
that they're were almost murdered in for
an extra three months so that we get it
down to where we really know what we're
doing and then they can go back and we
have this great relationship,
but now another can come and learn from
us.
And now we're sending our team out to
different parts of the continent to
Rwanda to Kenyetta Cameroon to um,
I think Rwanda,
Uganda in training up these other teams
have that are wanting to have a desire
to,
uh,
to do the same thing.
The,
a crazy story,
man.
They're so lucky.
They'll stick them and tires and light
them on fire.
Yeah.
I saw a guy,
ben and I both saw guy beat to death
because they called him a thief.
And then rumors were that,
uh,
we were kind of far away.
I try to get up Kinda,
Kinda too scary.
Close bins.
Literally pull my shirt away because I'm
seeing this,
know who he is and he's getting beaten
and kicked and most of their stuff.
But Ben's like,
effort,
we gotta go,
we gotta go.
And so he pulled me away and then when
we came back later I couldn't even bend
my body like that.
Like it's like a contortionist kind of
thing where it was like bent up like a
pretzel and just laying there.
And supposedly the rumor was that just
some drunk guys started,
rumor called him a thief,
called him a thief and when someone says
thief,
they pounce on the thief.
And so sometimes it's really a thief or
whatever.
But then other times it's some innocent
guy in,
you know,
they can.
Crazy stuff can happen.
Yeah.
I can only imagine.
And uh,
but it's,
you've seen some shit,
dude,
man,
it's been a,
it's been different,
but I wouldn't change it.
It's,
it's beyond.
It literally is wild.
Like I couldn't,
I couldn't,
uh,
I couldn't have dreamed it up for
myself.
And what's,
what's kind of funny as them,
I think,
not funny.
It's actually a.
have you ever heard of,
I think it's a book called what?
They don't teach you at Harvard law.
What they don't teach you at Harvard
business or something like that?
No,
I think the author's name is mark.
Well,
he did some pretty incredible and I
heard,
I heard about it when I was high school,
but Kenny Monday,
which he got the,
it came full circle.
He coached me in high school then for my
comeback fight and he coached me a
little bit in mma at the beginning.
But then for my comeback fight and this
last one he was in my corner.
Um,
but anyways,
he told me,
you know,
hey,
if you want to wrestle,
go home,
write down your goals.
Like write them down in this book talks
about how if they polled some class,
some senior class in at Harvard and
asked who has goals that are,
who knows their goals and some like 87
percent didn't know,
like besides I'll get my college degree
from Harvard and then I'll figure it
out.
Then they asked,
who knows,
who knows?
Your um,
I think that was 87 percent of them or
something like that and then a or 83
percent something and um,
then it was,
it was a 13 percent or something like
that where they had,
um,
I'm sorry I'm screwing this up,
but it was a,
they,
it's an incredible stat.
It's so 87 or 83 percent didn't know
their goals.
Thirteen or 17 percent did know their
goals,
but they didn't have them written down
and then only three percent of the class
had written concise,
direct goals of what they wanted to do
in their life.
I think if you went back 10 years later
and the ones that had goals but didn't
have them written down,
were making twice as much on average
than all the other 83 or 87 percent that
didn't have goals.
And then the people had written down
goals.
They're making 10 percent,
10 times.
Yeah,
10 times as all the other 97 combined
here is why three percent of Harvard
Mbas make 10 times as much as the other.
Ninety seven.
Sarika behind Harvard Mba program is
extremely competitive.
And today admits approximately 15
percent of the applicants and 19 sixties
acceptance rate was about 30 percent
down to 25 percent in the 19 seventies,
fluctuated between 10 and 15 percent
ever since.
Students who make it past the
application process are typically
standouts and already fairly successful
by most traditional definitions.
They have an undergraduate degree,
typically three to five years of working
experience hold on,
uh,
and when considered suitable for
acceptance into the Harvard business
school,
blah,
blah.
So,
okay,
so it's explaining about writing your
goals down and having a clear direction.
Make sense
in,
um,
for,
for me in seeing that,
hearing that.
And then having coach Monday tell me
that I'm honestly wrestling MMA,
having goal to focus on having a gold
write down.
Um,
I think that really helped me escape the
depression for her for a while,
for a few years because now I found
something that I could focus on and I
was passionate about it could,
you know,
that was my outlet.
And um,
but he also told me one step further,
think of said this publicly,
publicly.
But,
um,
he told me write down be what's your
goal,
and like,
I want to be a state champion.
And he said,
okay,
go home,
write that down and put it somewhere.
You can see it either on your,
you know,
your bathroom mirror or somewhere.
I put it above my bed.
Um,
but I didn't ever write down state
champion Rodeo national champion,
sir.
Working towards it was state champion
that year,
the next having a great,
great training partner and I'm,
I'm kind of jazzed up that the Olympics
has coming up into some guys that are
going.
Robby Smith,
he's a heavyweight.
He was my roommate at the Olympic
training center and travail lag if we
wrestled together and high school and
then after and um,
so I'm pumped about it.
But cds,
guys obtaining their goals,
their dreams and writing them down,
we'll then with coach money's like,
Hey,
get some of your favorite wrestling
moves,
some pictures so you can visualize and I
just see the words,
but see the actual thing that you want
to do,
like see it.
And so I went and I put one wrestling
move on the left and another on the
right and uh,
and man,
I just would go to sleep dreaming about
it basically in wake up motivated to,
to attain that goal national champion
and having a guy that's Olympic gold
medalist teaching you the basics like
you,
you'll get good quick that way.
But I'm also having the goals like I was
the first national championship I won,
um,
was with a move on the left and the
second national championship was with
move on the right.
Um,
and it was just,
it was nuts to see how all that works
out.
And looking back on this book and seeing
like,
man,
you gotta write down and I,
I need to update that now.
I've been working on it everything else.
But uh,
I think a lot of us do.
Yeah.
I think focusing on one individual goal
like that or writing something down,
having a very clear thing that you're
working towards.
It takes away a lot of the ambiguity
about that people have about wanting to
be successful.
And I'll just wanting to be successful,
just wanting to do well,
that's not enough.
You have to have like a real,
like something that you're looking
towards something you're moving and
working towards a plan and initiative.
And yet,
well that's probably one of the biggest
strengths that our team has.
Has had a,
the 18 employees we have,
um,
and at water four we write down what we
want to do and it's so cool.
When I came on the show the first time,
um,
I had gone in,
I'd only experienced the terrible stuff,
like nothing had happened yet.
I'm only corruption and me holding the
little guy that died and all this just
brutal stuff on.
But it came back and I finally was like,
okay,
I can't say no anymore.
I got to do something.
And so let's just write it down and do
it and start speaking about it and
thrown it out there.
And then to see the other team.
Like they,
they're coming in with,
uh,
with the real,
like,
here's The big vision stuff.
But here's filling in all the details,
how we're going to get it done.
And me and my,
my first time to write things down was
one water,
well on 300 acres of land and maybe we
could build a school and get a teacher
and they would help with education
because the pygmies don't have any
representation in the government because
nobody's educated and that's their
excuse,
at least in Congo what to here.
And so it was like school,
that'd be great.
One water,
well and 300 acres.
And now it's by the end of this year
will be 3000 acres of land credible.
They literally own,
there'll be 10 times more.
40th five wells at 45 wells.
That's amazing.
Teen employees.
Um,
we've got three working farms right over
how long,
how many years you've been doing this
now?
A five.
That's pretty incredible.
Over five for sure.
That's an incredible commitment.
Well,
thanks.
It's been a,
it's been awesome.
Watch even even like being able to go
back and had all these pictures to show
you a Leo may growing Papaya trees and
stand in front of banana trees and all
the different stuff in the ground on
what the water that they're getting from
the wells.
Well that's the rain forest and
everything.
So it's,
it's pretty fertile.
Yeah.
You can spit a seat on the ground.
That's gonna gonna Sprout up somehow in
the reinforced.
That's great too.
Are you bringing in seeds over there for
these people?
And they have,
they have good seeds there and uh,
a lot of those trees were doing
seedlings and they take and they know
how to garden and farm and all that
stuff.
Yeah.
Especially at the university because
they have a whole agriculture department
that teams up with the community
development department that they come
and teach the pygmies how to do it.
They come in and teach them and then
they start learning how to do it for
themselves.
And this was,
I think I can tell you two moments real
quick where you went back and seeing Leo
May and walking in and seeing all those
banana trees blew me away.
And then now there is just so cool
because I was leaving and there's a
little guy named Ipi than I've seen them
grow up.
I have watched them grow up and I saw
whenever his,
his water source was absolutely
disgusting.
Like you could not ever imagine a human
being drinking,
drinking it.
And uh,
that was,
that was their water source where they
get water.
What is that?
It's this little stagnant pond kind of
thing with all this mouse over it.
That's.
Yeah.
Now what's so cool?
Just picture green.
Yeah.
No,
it's like water at all.
There's definitely,
it's a big,
thick thing.
So they'll get a stick and they'll push
them to sell us to Jamie.
This photo,
that's what I had.
And then it all lost on.
What do other people could say?
Oh,
I see.
how's that working?
That's ridiculous.
What is it?
What,
what is wrong with the,
uh,
connection to you?
It didn't
because everything crashed on me.
I had,
dude,
I didn't even sleep last night at all,
zero because I was trying to send videos
to water for an update video and he was
at a hotel.
It was a little roach motel,
but it took like two hours and send one
video.
Then I have to do another and then all
of a sudden it,
uh,
it just,
I've lost the powerpoint that went back
to.
Well,
speaking of videos,
let's watch the video that you said
[inaudible] did for you.
Yeah,
yeah,
that'd be great.
Let's watch that.
I want to see that.
What is this?
What I'm looking at right here?
That's,
uh,
we're,
we drilled one of the new wells.
What is those things in their hands?
Uh,
jerry cans.
They're filling.
Oh,
oh,
I see.
Okay.
In fact,
okay,
so let's play this foundations.
Justin wren versus Josh Barnes.
This story of that fight was the time
off of a very talented fighter.
It been away from the sport for years.
One of those guys,
when he was active,
when he was at his peak,
was considered one of the hottest
prospects in the heavyweight division,
talented wrestler,
aggressive,
well rounded,
welcome
at the time off the ring,
rust,
the time away from the sport against
Josh Burns,
a guy who traditionally wasn't a very
fast starter.
We thought he'd have time to warm up and
he did.
Burns,
came right after him.
A Guy I think was trying to take
advantage of the fact that rent had been
off for so long ran,
handled it extremely well.
Rent had been away for a long time,
so you could see the surprise.
You could see the fatigue,
you could see the question of himself.
You could see those times when things
started working out and it started
coming back.
The story of all his time off was on his
face and his in his performance.
Yeah,
that's the guy making up for time off in
one fight.
What's easy to forget with Justin wren
story with him helping out the pygmies
with all he's done socially,
all he's done politically for that
tribe.
They can't go in there with me and the
pressure of having a big story on your
shoulders,
everybody rooting for you,
everybody reading your book,
that's not easy thing to carry into a
fight.
Every talks about how great the story is
and what it does for a fighter and what
it does for their career.
It's also a gigantic burden and not just
fighting for yourself anymore.
You're fighting for everyone who looks
up to you.
Winning that night was a big deal for
him.
People don't understand what he was
carrying.
He was carrying ring Ross and he was
carrying the hopes and dreams of
everybody.
He was fighting for it and he managed
it.
One
slash 27 real quick and pause it.
Just one minute,
27 seconds because I just,
it's great.
It's right there.
So,
uh,
the girls on the left through the cage,
this is the only time that's ever
happened.
That's my wife.
This is her first fight of mine to ever
go to or see.
And we've been together for four or five
years.
And um,
it's so funny because I was throwing the
knees right here and this is the ring
road.
The Dominick Cruz can say it's a,
it's,
there's not ring rust.
He's just way too mentally tough and uh,
and stubborn and he's away come the
awesome competitor.
But a dude,
I,
well,
one I didn't train like I really should
have turned that had a big factor.
Yeah.
And two,
it was a minute,
but one of the ring rust kind of things
was,
um,
I could hear the commentators and I
could,
I looked out,
the first person I see is my wife and I
see her make eye contact with her,
like we stared into each other's eyes
and I know this is gonna sound goofy.
But uh,
she got a new outfit on and I'm just
like,
she's beautiful.
And then all the sudden I see her and
she's like,
oh,
I'm going to fight.
And he was like punching me and I was
like,
ah,
crap.
So,
uh,
no,
it was actually right.
There was the closest part where I
almost finished them there with some
knees are Coulda,
Shoulda,
woulda.
And,
um,
and then I stopped looking at it,
my wife see her and grace,
which he came to Congo with us too.
And uh,
I see them and I'm like,
what am I doing after the fight,
I instantly thought what was I doing in
the fight looking out,
seeing my wife and thinking she's
beautiful.
So,
uh,
I don't know why I brought that up
except for this,
you know what I mean?
It was,
it was unique.
And um,
it was,
uh,
it was a blessing in that video actually
was,
uh,
I'm,
I'm glad to show it because of that.
But then,
um,
I meant to show you the one that came
first,
which,
um,
we don't play that.
But what happened for the first flight
back,
which just kind of nuts that,
um,
those guys,
the guys surprise me and called me in
the morning and I was able to see them
and they were able to encourage me for
the fight and say,
well,
no,
you're fighting for us.
All that is really great than emily sent
me a picture of her with.
It's so awesome.
Her with like 10 or 12 kids around her
and they all had the biggest smiles.
She says,
remember,
remember who you fight for and Wifi.
And so a lot of pressure.
It is,
but at the same time she,
she's,
she's so awesome.
Loves me and I've some reason I like
pressure.
I like to be under the gun or something
like that.
What's next for you?
Man?
Man,
I think um,
I think I just,
we just got pretty much settled into
Colorado and joining them and may seen
up there kind of a team take down was
great.
It kind of dissolved and I'm team
takedown dissolved.
You sort of just Johnny Hendricks left.
Is that what he's not on there.
But once you left,
yeah,
the coaches are gone.
Um,
that came in from out of state and that
was a weird situation,
right?
It was some wealthy guy was financing
the entire thing,
right.
One.
And he's,
he's a,
he's a great dude.
And then uh,
and then he brought in a bunch of other
people.
But I think,
I think for them it was just a,
I don't know,
I think they might've got burned every,
well they had a deal right where they
would pay guys a salary and then salary
require your rent,
your groceries.
But when you won you were supposed to
give them a percentage of your winnings.
I think it was 50 percent,
50,
50 percent.
But you get your house payment,
your car,
your insurance and health insurance.
You get your gross.
Great.
Until fighters making,
making 10 million bucks.
And they're like,
what?
Yeah,
that's very true.
Because if they're only spending 50 or
70 years,
who will agree to that?
To Johnny Hendricks?
Agree to that.
Yeah.
So he was giving 50 percent of his
purse.
Yeah.
I think most every team takedown guy was
a johnny,
might've been a little.
I think it might've been a little
different than everybody else's.
Like a crazy deal.
And how much were they paying?
Not Love.
I love all the guys there.
They're awesome dudes.
I'm,
I wouldn't even want to quote it,
but I know over 50,
maybe under $100 a year.
Yeah.
But uh,
well that's a good investment if you get
5 million bucks back,
that's,
that's true.
And,
but it was,
yes,
it didn't work out because when Johnny
started making real money,
that's when he.
Is that when he left or was there other
issues?
I think it was,
it was,
it was that.
And then I think,
uh,
I think internally there was some,
some butting of heads between a few
different people between me,
maybe coaches,
maybe management,
maybe fighters too.
And um,
so now you're in Colorado.
Now I'm in Colorado.
Were you trained in Colorado a while?
Be My home gym will be Grudge Training
Center,
which is actually pretty cool.
There's a instructor named drew,
that's pretty great.
He came in,
he opened,
I think he opened up,
maybe I'm wrong on that one,
but 10th planet Jiu Jitsu and I think
boulder,
but now he has one in Arvada which is
inside of grudge.
And so now we had a 10th planet in there
and he's,
he's actually so in some slick darce
jokes and uh,
and yeah,
that's awesome.
Some stuff that's his belt too.
I have a fight lined up for you maybe,
um,
maybe November,
December where we're looking at that and
the thing that I want to do is getting a
real.
I haven't given myself time to settle,
to really train to really focus and I
know that now it's a time crunch,
you know,
29.
I know that the youngest heavyweight I
think is still jds and junior.
Dos Santos and I'm in the top 10.
He's 32.
I mean Barnett's I think 38 and time to
mature later.
Forty two.
Well Brock has pretty much done now.
I think that last positive tests to
positive tests in a row.
He got one before the fight.
One after the fight.
It's most likely one and done.
Yeah.
Um,
so I,
I got,
I got some time.
You thinking about going to the UFC,
are you.
So you have this ballot tour deal is,
are you enjoying competing for Beltour?
I,
I have thoroughly appreciated how
they've been treating me.
They've been.
But you're mentioning all these MMA
fighters from the UFC.
So are you,
are you thinking about going over there?
Is that what's going on or I mean,
I would never be against that because I
love the UFC.
Love MMA and that's a big,
big platform.
How long has your deal at bell or four?
I have two more fights and um,
so I'll,
I'll,
I'll fight to more and for me,
I mean reason we're in Colorado.
First is I wanted to get my wrestling
back because I'm pretty disappointed.
My first two,
I honestly winning this was the first
two times winning felt really good
because I did it.
I didn't do it for me,
but then the same time right away the
competitor comes in and is like messed
up here,
here,
and I think pretty much every guy taking
the ground finished.
It's like,
why am I trying to outbox the boxers
whenever I need to.
I need to wrestle.
You need to take them down.
Is it difficult for you to balance the
two worlds?
Because you know,
you have one that demands incredible
attention,
your fighting career demands incredible
attention and then you have the other
that also demands incredible attention.
You have an amazing commitment to these
pygmy people and uh,
this incredible passion and love for it.
But then you also have your urine,
the date most dangerous combat sport in
the world.
I mean,
it,
it requires massive attention.
Like we were talking about Francisca.
No,
like if you're gonna Fight Francis,
now you got a fucking batten down the
hatches.
You got to be in incredible shape and
for being consistent,
dedicated and no excuses.
And um,
that's,
that's what left a pretty sour taste in
my mouth after these last two fights
because I knew I hate doing that.
Like a rushing it or getting in whenever
prepared.
And um,
are you training at all when you're in
the Congo and how often do you end the
Congo?
A now I'm now I'm going to start going
back just after every fight.
When I fight,
go back for a couple of weeks.
I'm trying to be real safe this time it
took my own food.
I'm like all of it,
like an entire check bag was just kind
bars,
Lara bars and all these different green
smoothies and different stuff.
So I was,
I was,
I wasn't even eating any food,
they're still got sick and so had
malaria.
Then after that I got shingles,
which is crazy.
It was completely across my forehead and
over here.
So there's like the middle of the trip
that's coming back at case,
right?
Isn't that like kind of a herpes,
a it chick?
It's the adult form of the chicken pox.
It's a,
it's brutal.
Like it was.
It was a different pain than I've ever
felt because it's a nerve pain and that
was out in the forest and there was a
couple,
two,
three days where we were there for the
documentary,
for the water wells,
everything else.
And we got a team that came and so we
gotta we gotta get it done.
So I kind of stayed back a couple of
days but then while we're out there in
different stuff,
like a rebel group actually came,
like I believe it was three miles from
us and only about a mile away from our
truck.
And so I'm sick.
I can't get back to the hospital that I
just came out of from getting treatment
for malaria to get treatment for
shingles and then,
uh,
so that was tough,
but for me to answer your question like
I want to be,
I want to be realistic,
but at the same time a quote my mom
taught me,
I forget who it was,
but she said something like,
uh,
I'm an optimist is someone who goes
after moby Dick in a rowboat and takes
the tartar sauce with them.
Optimists goes after moby Dick in a
rowboat and takes the tartar sauce with
them.
So for me,
I want to be,
I want to swing for the fences,
make the biggest impact possible,
but at the same time,
like we,
we're restructuring stuff.
We had meetings at water four and I
think just getting everyone on the same
page.
Well me too,
because I was listening to the biggest
thing possible is the UFC heavyweight
championship now,
without a doubt.
Is that a first ballot where then UFC or
is that a thought that you have in your
mind with.
Well yeah,
the one will be on one of those goals.
Okay.
At UFC 200 is good.
Sound goofy to anybody else.
I think a lot of athletes would probably
get it,
some might not,
but you know,
I,
I bought a UFC replica belt because,
uh,
I want to,
I'm not gonna hang it or anything,
but I want to have times where I set
that down on a table or a desk and look
at it,
think about it,
dream about it and know that before I go
out the door training,
um,
you know,
that's,
that's a goal of mine,
you know,
if I could get there then I know this
fight for the forgotten can be set up
for,
you know,
the,
maybe the rest of,
of my life there,
you know,
it could keep going on and on further
than it would if I didn't.
Realistically to try to attain that sort
of a goal.
Like it's going to require more than
just staring at a belt or writing
something down.
You're gonna you're gonna need to go on
a rampage.
Yeah.
We've,
we've,
uh,
we've surrounded it.
Will water forest surrounded,
fight for the forgotten with like a team
of like eight people from media to my
sports agent to lawyers and I'm just,
all these,
all these people are incredible.
And I'm sitting in the room with them at
a conference table like this.
And I'm like,
like,
what am I doing in a room with these
incredible people?
And they're all,
yeah,
they're all focused on me.
And knowing the story in like lookout,
I don't know if you'd call it raw or
pure or like,
like in they're getting behind it,
which has been incredible.
But then they just overwhelmed me saying
we want to free you up in a way.
We're kind of talking a little earlier
was alluding to it,
but,
um,
you know,
I,
I really got to readjust everything in
my life of how I'm training because
when,
now that I'm getting settled into
Denver,
um,
out all go up to number one to three
times a week and then also be under the
Olympic training center.
I've been talking with Brandon slay,
the old freestyle coach,
which he actually just moved to penn
state.
Um,
but,
uh,
talking with uh,
and had access there at the Olympic
training center and about,
hopefully I can get in touch with Matt
Lindland.
He's the new head coach for the Greco
team there.
Um,
but with,
uh,
have you ever heard of Adam Wheeler?
Adam wheelers an absolute beast and I
wonder if I have that video in there,
but,
uh,
there's one if you just search Adam
Wheeler on Youtube,
should we called ISO pure.
But this dude is an Olympic bronze
medalist and a black belt in Jujitsu.
Anyone Nogi world's heavyweight.
And so he's a beast,
just an absolute monster.
And so,
uh,
I was helping them train for the 2008
Olympics and stuff and um,
it was pretty great.
Oh,
here it is.
This guy's a beast.
We're not hearing anything,
Jeremy.
Correct.
She got into wrestling.
So I was in high school.
There was a point when I'm starting to
getting into a little bit of trouble and
just hanging out with the wrong crowd.
My wrestling coach,
he's the one that Kinda put me back on
the right track.
He taught me what work ethic was.
I try to be the guy who motivates
people,
pushes people.
The most peer moment of my athletic
career is 100 percent the Olympics.
Even though I didn't win,
I still was on that podium representing
my country for the sport that I put so
many hours into.
That feeling is indescribable.
And the point is,
is the guy you're,
you're working with or something.
Yeah.
And sorry,
I probably should have set that up a
little better,
but this guy is an absolute monster and
we've,
we're,
we're getting together and starting to.
We're going to start working out and
he's at Prime Jujitsu,
knew in Colorado Springs,
but they cross train with eastern's and
here's the thing.
I'm all over the place,
but he is the only guy to be trained.
So we're all jumping.
Do Squat jumps a row by row with these
bleachers.
And I promise he's skipping one at least
and sometimes too.
And he just,
he was flying up there.
People be halfway,
three quarters of the way.
This guy is six foot four,
235 pounds solid muscle freakish
athlete.
And uh,
he's just.
So there's a training partner for
training partner so,
well I guess what I was trying to allude
to is me and I feel like how water
forests around me with such an
incredible team to achieve success that
we fight for the forgotten in now and
really trying to do that with,
uh,
with fighting because if I don't then
I'm gonna fail and I'll be wasting time.
But if I,
cause this isn't a,
it's not a,
it's not patty cake,
right?
I mean we're,
we're going in there and we're throwing
down and I've got my head on straight.
You as you move up in competition for
sure.
Without a doubt.
I mean,
when you're looking at the competition
you faced in beltour there good steps.
It's tough guys to fight against their.
They're good steps.
But if you were the timing of
everything.
Yeah,
yeah.
If I,
I'm,
it's A.
Yeah,
it's not,
it's not.
I guess a swinging for the fences are
taking the tartar sauce with me.
If I see that,
uh,
that it's not going to happen,
then you know,
I hate saying that because I want to
fight so bad,
but fight for the forgotten is more
important in a way.
But I mean I think it's possible.
I really do and I think,
I think it's possible to.
I think you've also brought a lot of
people in to help you with fight for the
forgotten to pick up the slack as well
and you've started a movement.
I mean there's a lot going on here
besides just your involvement.
You've started this movement and being
with water for
and,
and writing the book and letting people
know about on these podcasts and,
and educating people to what your goal
is and what,
what you've been able to accomplish over
there.
He started a movement.
So I think man,
I mean if you really can do it,
it would be absolutely incredible and it
certainly would shine even more light if
you could really become successful as an
MMA fighter from here on out.
No,
I,
I agree with that with,
but it's going to require everything
requires everything.
And I feel like there's,
there's two parts of this where I'm mean
the,
the fight for the forgotten guy in me
wants to be,
wants to be humble and everything will
say,
you know,
it's not going to happen.
Listen to all the right things,
which is the same on the other side of
the coin.
But I'm a at the same time.
I feel like if,
if I can just get the time,
I haven't been getting the time,
uh,
to train.
And
one of the things that you have to make
the time.
Yeah,
we have to make the time and it's got to
be the priority.
And I don't think I,
it can't be some six to eight hours.
I mean like 68 whenever I was telling
the guys at water four and it's just
because they don't know.
They've been incredibly supportive.
But whenever I broke it down like winter
training schedule,
what time do you train a day?
I mean,
they know some nfl guys and stuff like
that that might train once a day for
four or five times a week or maybe twice
a day with them.
And they,
it's just so different that they're
like,
oh wow.
So that's why they've rallied around me
and I think that through that it's going
to free me up to really good all the
right places.
Get up to grudge for my strike and get
to the Olympic training center from a
wrestling.
Get around these black belts in world
champs in Jujitsu.
Get around the 10th planet guys.
Get around this so that we can,
we can take this the farthest that we
can.
Beautiful.
Yeah.
All right man.
Well listen,
um,
again,
one more time for people at home.
Fight for the forgotten.org.
Fight for the forgotten.com.
Uh,
what is your big pygmy on,
on twitter,
on twitter and instagram?
That's the big pygmy.
I've translated some abouti among both.
They go,
yeah.
So it's the big pygmy fight for the
forgotten to work.
Oh,
this is something that,
that I just found out that water four.
Does that mean $25?
Some of the people have been so
generous.
Donors have given a full water well,
but even just $25 a month,
if that's possible,
it gives water to 15 people per year.
If you do it the next year,
it's another 15 people that could save
their lives,
save kids' lives.
And so,
um,
I just know it's being used the right
way and a passionate about it,
seeing it in action.
So you're a beautiful soul,
Justin wren,
you really are.
Man.
What you're doing is absolutely amazing
and I'm so happy that we can help you
out in any way.
So thank you very much for coming on
again,
and let's do this again,
brother.
Love you man.
Thank you so much.
You've got community,
best fans.
I'm honored and I'm honored to be able
to help you tell your story is powerful.
Thank you.
Thank you my.
All right folks,
we'll be back tomorrow with Duncan
trussell.
See you.
That's going to be a great one.