Trying to watch it online. Yeah, stop
it. You don't need to look at us.
You fucking freak Spec on now.
Okay. Hi Ustream folks. Sorry.
We're off air for a little bit
with the vagina light. Yeah,
we missed the whole proof of concept.
We're working now,
you know behind the scenes type shit.
Eliza and Heffron together might rule
the world with this artificial vagina
slash he's got to get half Ron.
Except you on a team though.
But I think I can broker that
deal. I appreciate, you know,
seen as you're both last comic standing
winners you're, you're already having in,
right? We have that bond. Unbreakable.
Did you have to do the audition where
you only did stand up in front of the
judges and no audience? It wasn't
even, people don't get it. I,
my audition,
you walk into the judges aren't there.
It was just like a producer's
assistants or like talent people.
They weren't even people you know and
you walk in, you pitch your, you know,
you do your joke. And I did. I talked
for about 15 seconds. She goes, yeah,
just come back this afternoon.
And then I came back and they were like,
you're not on the list.
I was like, yes I am.
And all these people kept trying to come
back that weren't approved because it
was so disorganized.
You had to go through like a couple of
rounds before he got to it that you went,
you went twice head the head. Right.
What does that mean? That's like they,
she got challenged at the end
where it was kind of like a,
you all live in the house you lived,
there's like 12 comics
at the end of the week.
Everybody pretty much votes who they
hate the most. And it was never me,
but they voted. If there was one
other girl, they voted on her.
And then if you get voted off, you have
a chance to then challenge two comics.
So then the three of you do a show down
in front of a live audience and to get
kicked off and Wednesday.
So I won both weeks in a row because
everyone that got kicked off the house
would keep challenging
me and I kept winning.
That's the only reason I want to show.
Wow. So, so when someone challenges you,
how do they figure out who
wins? The audience decides
votes right then and there,
like a little button they
press or something. I think so.
I think that's how they
did it. Wow. And uh,
that's gotta be a weird way to do comedy.
It's comedy under the gun, you know,
that's kind of creepy if you,
if you're a competitive person,
which I wasn't until this or,
I mean,
I don't think playing Jv lacrosse counts
for anything. Uh, it's, it's great.
It's dormant. It was, it was, I mean,
I'd always played with people
that were better than me.
And then when you get to comedy, I had
never thought of comedy as a competition.
And now that's all I think of it as.
I'm super aggressive about it.
Why don't like you compete with yourself,
but it's game time to him.
Yeah.
Do you know whatever motivates you?
It's for some people it's done.
Some people get real competitive.
Some people,
I would never go up to someone
else. But you know, it's,
it's like before you play a sport,
like you psych yourself up and you get
out there and then you go for blood I
guess. Wow. That's an
interesting way of looking at it.
I saw you like two
weeks ago and there was,
I hadn't seen you before like for years,
like until that show,
like I hadn't seen it on stage recently,
but it was cool about it is that you
really have that vibe of the comedy store
and not many, uh, comics actually
carry some kind of vibe with it.
And when you watch you,
you could see the comedy store bribe.
It's the same reason Boston comics were
so good.
Yeah,
because there's so many hell rooms there
and you get used to that combat comedy
and the comedy store is combat comedy
defined. There is no organization there.
It's a chaos room. It's, the room itself
is an odd set up and it's, I come,
I like to think I cut my teeth on rooms
like the original room and then smaller,
tougher rooms not going to get anywhere
by going up in front of your four
friends and like people that
are laughing you for no reason.
So doing those bags and those tough
rooms where they just stare at you.
Some people don't speak
English, it prepares, it's
like swinging with two bats.
Yes, you're totally right.
When you go other places like
people are so much nicer,
so much about this store and all
the murder that's been committed.
There are a lot of period,
I don't know,
it was Bugsy Siegel's nightclub in like
the 30s or whenever that was and there
was like a bunch of people murdered
in that place. There was a horse.
Oh Co abortion. Illegal
abortions. This like nerdy.
People say they've heard babies crying
and like, wait a minute, wait a minute,
wait a minute, wait a minute. Hold
on a second. People are crazy.
I never heard anything about part of the
abortion backroom illegal abortions on
Bugsy Siegel days. Forties or 50s
oh my God. And they did in there,
right on the stage? No, no, no sage. But
it was like in the basement or something.
No one ever goes in the basement.
Lies is just making shit up.
No, I'm not. I promise. Come on.
Is there any documentation and can we
find out about this online or is this just
Holly? I've never heard that
before. That's why I'm shocked.
I mean I've been around the store for a
long time. I'd never heard that story.
That's right.
I heard crazy stories though.
People are always talking about ghosts.
They're like,
when they do like haunted Hollywood shows,
they always include the comedy store.
Tell me about the guy that
always does it from the Formosa.
It's always on ie and he's always
kind of like a fat guy. That always,
I would say it's all bullshit except a
few people that have said they've seen
things are like really
cool guys like Blake Clark.
Blake Clark was a Vietnam vet and he was
a standup comic. He's seen some shit,
you know,
he's been around and he was working at
the comedy store one night and I didn't
hear the story directly from him
so I don't want to paraphrase it,
but in essence,
who's closing up?
And he went into the room and all of a
sudden there was someone there and he
starts talking to this person and uh,
he,
the person's not talking back to him
and then he realizes that some sort of a
ghost. And you know what? If you
ask him what that guy looks like,
other people will be able to
corroborate the same image.
A lot of people see the same
like in the belly or have,
I think it's a guy with like a top hat
or something. People see the same things.
A girl that did our show, I do a
Monday night show, their brand new,
never been their campus here friend.
She saw something and told one of
us on not privy to the story at all.
It sounds like it should be horse shit,
because every one of those
shows that you watch,
the problem is those goddamn shows,
you know,
it's like the create this artificial
environment and you gain old cameras and
lights and everything and you're growing
and looking for ghosts and you have to
find something in every episode
and you're just knocking.
There's not that many ghosts happening.
You know, if there are ghosts,
it's not enough that you're going
to get them on a television show.
We don't ever see them.
I don't know if it's real,
but I'm not willing to say that it's not,
I'm not willing to say there's no ghosts.
I don't.
So many people are full of shit. It's
tough. It's a tough conversation.
I can't fit. I don't think you
can beat my ghost theory though.
My theory is you find somebody that was
murdered like the midnight on Halloween
and you go to the, like the wife's grave,
you know, he's like a husband, wife thing,
and you just start making fun of her on
midnight and just go, hey goes, yeah,
I'm making fun of your dead wife.
Yeah, and nothing's going to happen.
That's my ghost though.
Maybe the ghosts recognize from the great
beyond that you're a douchebag above
this.
Respecting your murdered white
ghost has crossed over.
I don't think.
I think it's what people have when they
go sidings and all this and he was an
EVP or they do the white noise thing
goes that have a problem with mean.
Yeah.
What's it?
What were you like that movie white
noise where you can turn up the right and
you can hear the ghosts like talking.
It's like a thick lens flares that goes
to have a problem with the ones that
haven't crossed over the ones that are
stuck because they died prematurely or in
some sort of horrible accident.
That's if you will.
There's people that believe
that everything has a memory.
There's a guy named Rupert Sheldrake,
I think he's an evolutionary biologist
and he has this theory that everything
has some sort of a memory
like furniture and houses.
They that even though you
can't really access it,
like the energy of the house
can be compromised by having
a lot of negative shit
happening. It's all energy. It's not
like the house becomes a creepy thing
like it has memory to it and that's
certainly what the store is when
you do like an exorcism or a sale,
if they ask for an object
or if you're in a Pluto,
it's an object from the person because
it has that energy or that's why if you,
if something comes out of a negative,
and I mean I totally buy into the whole
energy thing about not transferring like
negative energy and stuff.
And I do too if you like cooks you,
but that's what they say, Cook with love,
your love goes into it and you give it,
it's about that if you're in tune
to it, otherwise you just eat. Yeah,
no that totally makes sense.
That something,
I mean and if it goes along really with
the same idea that if everything has a
memory and if you're cooking with love
and then food has like a memory of your
love and you creating it,
people will like it more.
I sort of makes it sound totally Hippie,
but I should not eat so many lean pockets
cause what's, what's that doing to me?
All the cows torture,
torture or pigs are just stuffed in the
boxes for the heads are sideways for
half their life. It's so easy to love
Bacon. No, never had weekends. Awesome.
And pigs are cunts. Therein lies
the problem. Fuck pigs are assholes.
Pigs.
More people die from pigs and farms than
any other animal because people fall
into the pig. Sties and the pigs
just fucking eat them. Was that,
what movie was that snatch?
Yeah, that Shit's true.
I'll start of research. You
could have to that. That's me.
I'm fucking in the theater on my
blackberry writing research people and the
end of was at Hannibal.
We're the guy like the crippled guy.
They pushed him into the pigs and they
beat him up. Yeah. A lot of pig eating.
Yeah. That's some serious shit. Have you
seen people fuck pigs? So those videos of,
oh, the horrendous. So glad I came today.
Hall people fucking the
animal videos or her random.
I've never seen a video of anyone having
sex and I don't want to know, don't,
don't ever watch it,
but what you should see,
what everybody should see is a
documentary called zoo. Zoo is on,
there was a bunch of people that have
Zuph. I believe it's at proud zoophilia.
Is this where like sexually attractive?
No, no, no. They get fucked by horses.
Isn't that how like Catherine the great
died supposedly at the comedy store in
the belly room. Supposedly that's
how cats and their Greek God.
But we know for sure that there's one
guy died that way because a, it's,
it changed the law in Washington
state and Washington state.
It used to be legal to have
sex with animals mandatory.
You got gotta do what you gotta do.
You're stuck in Seattle.
But a bunch of people decided to
move there from all over the country.
They met on an internet message board and
they moved there and started like this
whole farm community thing where
they got fucked by animals.
Like there was like a whole bunch of
freaks that like found themselves.
They found themselves a
friend. We're getting boned
by. There's a horse. Yes. Look,
the guy had like blonde hair. I have
seen that. I saw a clip of that. Yeah,
and the Mr Hands is the video pony
bite her and she like likes it when he,
the pony by May. This is a different one.
That's a different one. It can't be too,
yeah, no, there's a bunch.
There's over. I don't know.
I don't necessarily think so,
but it's kind of fucked up.
I mean it just seems unnatural for sure.
It seems like you were indulging the
worst and human spirit. You know the idea.
You just want to just exploit animals
and have them fucking in the ass all the
time. Yeah. He got, he got broken
like broken open and bled out.
The Guy who died, what are you
going to go on to do? It's like,
well you subsect of the animals and
now I work at the Verizon store.
Well that's a thing. He was like, fuck,
I wish I remembered what he did.
I think he was an architect.
I mean he was like an
intelligent guy apparently.
Let me find out because this is just to,
uh,
to important in line between
intelligence and absolute insanity.
And the line is a horse cock
dog doesn't like this part.
What a horrendous way to die.
That ribbon, she removed it.
That ribbon or what does that went
around the cane. That's dessert. Oh,
she's saving? Yeah, that's peppermint. God
bless your heart a little after dinner.
Mint. So you gave up on the droid
completely. Oh, you follow that?
What happened there? I can't find,
started doing weird things. Right.
And so I was like, screw it. I'm
going to go with a droid just to try.
Because I used to have a tree. I missed
the touchscreen. Right. All these things.
It was too much and there are all these
problems. It could have made calls.
It made weird sounding calls. It was all
like warble note. Anyways, so I went,
I was on,
my breaking point was no one could hear
me on the phone, but I was
on the phone yesterday. Yeah.
Five times during a phone call.
My face somehow dialed someone else and
it starts ringing as I'm speaking to
someone else. Like three Wade.
Yeah. Who needs that? Yeah,
like the droid enables you to call
people you don't want to. So I just,
I was like, I'm done. I want
this for free. And so I got
the brand new blackberry.
Not Brand new, but you know what's
weird about Black Berry owners though?
I don't know if they know this and Joe,
you,
yours does this every time you text me
on your blackberry is that if I replies,
it replies, what? I texted you
every time you text me back.
So it's like you get like three texts.
He,
it's like it's reading like
emails style. No, it's like,
it's just crazy how much it
has to be a setting, like a,
some kind of setting in your textbook.
And it's called sock. I love my,
I will give up touchscreen any day. I'm,
I can't leave. I left my blackberry.
I'm never living in again. Sorry. My phone
is the shit, but 18 ticks sucks it. Why?
Why, why, why don't you go to the iPhone?
You seem very apple friendly. I Eliza,
it's my parents. Got It. Who, uh,
I love the, I love the iPhone.
I don't want it. I want a
keyboard. I want a full keyboard.
I don't want my face fucking with my phone
calls. Right. As I found out yesterday.
Hmm. It fucks with it that
much. Huh? Five Times.
And it was a very important
gossip conversation. Dan.
Me and my friends are defending a friend
in real life, so it was very important.
The iPhone doesn't do that
though. The iPhone doesn't
hang up on your face. No. No,
not how can you not because,
because it detects when your face as
close and it turns it off. The droid does.
Lau. Droid does. It didn't and
maybe there's a mode for it,
but the iPhone doesn't have
the full keyboard. Yeah.
But you can get more than one plaid cover.
That's pretty, they have that though.
They, they definitely have that. Whatever.
I want. God, if I, if I just, you know,
I use the iPhone more of like as a like
an internet device. Yeah. Do as a phone.
Am I get an eye touch? Yeah. If I was
a producer on the road a lot this year,
just so I can have something cause this
is not great with those are pretty slick.
The, especially the three g one
where you can pull up anywhere. Yeah.
It's pretty nice. I like that
fucking technology bitches. Yeah.
So that they've found some tools that
indicate that human beings were traveling
by boat more than 150 in as
much as 700,000 years ago.
Wow. Because a, there's an island,
I believe the island is Crete and
they found these fucking tools.
There's a hold on. He's
found these tools. Yeah.
They found tools that were way, well,
creed has been separate from, uh,
from the mainland by 40 miles
for over 5 million years.
So the fact that they found
tools there 700,000 years ago,
I mean somehow or another,
someone got there in a fucking boat
or when it was a part of the world,
like Pangea, when it was all together,
people were there and then it split off.
How's that foot? That's 5
million years. You need carbs.
Supposedly 5 million years.
People weren't around. You know,
so what they're saying is if this island
was 500 or 5 million years separate
from everybody else and nothing
developed on this island,
but otherwise it'd have
to be like parallel,
right. I believe in that
really. Absolutely. If you
have parallel thought process,
how can having you not a parallel
evolution like separate groups of people
developed on this island or like when
you come up with the same joke as someone
else and they totally, Sam, I hear you.
It's totally, this is totally the same.
I should talkative guy. This is, that
is a, is a fascinating subject though.
It's been fascinating to
me. Well, I think, uh,
like they always taught us that
Christopher Columbus came America first.
We were like dead last.
The Chinese were here before.
They use Chinese maps to
come here in the first place.
Like they were your way before.
So what you're seeing what your
textbook wants you to believe.
They found the oldest human
being in North America,
the bones they found was a Chinese guy.
Yup. There you go. 10,000 years old.
So that's even not even predates
the American Indian. I'm that crazy.
Can we pay reparations to
the wrong group? Well, you,
American Indians came from Asia to that's,
that's one thing they found out like def
definitively because this Mormon dude
was trying to do a genealogy tests on
American Indians because he wanted to
prove that American Indians
were Israelites and that
they had come here and this
would prove the Mormon text to be correct
Israel. That's what everybody thinks.
That was the idea. Yeah. So,
but they tested them. They,
when they tested American Indians there,
they'd come from Siberia because what
comes from the Bering Strait? Yeah,
a crossover when it was all on Alaska.
It's a that's fascinating shit.
You know what I mean? When I said
that, um, that the Chinese were first.
I don't think that's true. I think maybe
the American Indians were here like,
I think they crossed that
before 10,000 years ago.
I think there are probably here first,
but just the idea that here any,
I mean a bunch of it, a bunch of what
people are here. They fucking walked here.
They've walked here from
another continent. Yeah.
But not in one lifetime. No.
But it,
they took a groups of humans over time,
walk through like insanely cold,
harsh environments and got tow.
Erica got gotta be warm or somewhere.
It's fucking crazy.
I love that kind of stuff
cause you imagine if you had
to go back in time and no
one even was even riding horses yet and
you're like, what are we going to do?
We get to walk everywhere.
Don't you have like a,
you have a bit of a
brilliant bit about this,
about like what will we do with all the
lights went out? Like I can't make shit.
That's the only time I've
ever seen you in person.
I think you did a show at red rock.
It's the first time I ever met you as a
long time ago. Oh Wow. I remember that.
That was only one thing. I went on a four
year or something. And you did that bad.
I thought it was, I thought it was
very smart and so funny. Thank you.
That's all I got. I
remember that now. Yeah.
That's the idea is that people are
getting dumber as technology gets more and
more powerful. There's people that have
less and less resources of their own,
less and less ability to do things.
No littler and littler every year about
what makes everything work. You know,
in the 50s like if a guy broke down
on the side of the road, I look,
I would pull over and knew how to fix
your fucking car. Right? You know,
you've got a broken belt here, buddy.
Let's go get a belt for you. And you know,
you know that shit could work.
You could do that. Now if you're,
you're fucking Ford,
that crazy car you got that thing
breaks down the side of the road with
all the electronics and shit,
it won't start.
Nobody knows what the fuck
is going on in the day.
You know what is interesting about that?
Unless you don't have higher education,
then you're more likely to become a
mechanic or someone that knows about cars.
The more education you get,
the further removed you are from what
makes the world tick mechanically. Yeah,
that's true.
But what I'm saying is that most people,
like there's a general knowledge
that's missing. I agree. And American.
Don't touch my fucking cars when you
touch your car and do you ever have to
bring it into the shop and they fix it
and the check engine light lawn for like
two months.
I grew up here.
I grew up never ever using a card,
like a place that worked,
fix her car ever up to,
I moved here in California because
my dad like every time it broke down,
he's like,
all right,
we got to go get a new engine and
I'm gonna show you how to do it.
And like I had to Redo
that whole car. Yeah. But,
but that's crazy now because
now I have to do that.
I had to drop off my car the other
day and it was like an oil change.
It was four hours for an oil
change at this Ford dealer.
And they actually have a restaurant
inside the Ford dealer called like the,
I forget what it's called,
but you order food and the
Bacon looks like seat covers.
It's just like really long rectangle
or why can't I use a Jiffy Lube or
something? Why don't you
go to Jeff? Because, no,
I think it's something like if you
have a and you're under warranty,
you're supposed to take it to the dealer,
you know, just in case. So. Well No, no.
So the warranty,
if there's anything ever wrong with it,
they can't blame somebody
else. What I mean, yeah.
Jiffy Lube is the shit. Oh yeah. I
liked him for the pope and 10 done.
My friend's car got fucked up by Jiffy
Lube. They didn't, they stripped the uh,
oil uh, oil back in cause they use those
things like you know, things real quick.
And if they put it in wrong cause they're
doing cars all day long, you know,
it's strips it and then he just, his
car leaked oil for the rest of his car.
It was like a brand new car
died was off on his comedy is dead.
I am always the basement.
How they can always get me to buy new air
filter for my air conditioner go dirty.
It is, I'm like, it's a filter.
It's supposed to be dirty and just
take a hose to try it. I don't want it.
I don't want to die either. Fix
that shit. What are you going to do?
That fluid in there? Yeah. Do that
shit with the the red stuff. Yeah,
but those filters you just spray out and
that's all you need to do that either.
Then they started talking
transmission fluid and shit like that.
Then you're like, listen kid, you know
you don't know what the fuck you're doing.
Get out of that transmission.
If you tell me I need it.
If there's something I don't know about,
I'm that girl.
I wonder how many people get shit
done to their car every year.
They don't really need just because
someone wants to make you on my car cause
they said I needed it.
Balls that big Porsche wings.
It was English.
That's what I want.
A car with a wing on the back of it.
Literally walk into a store like
a makeup store and she'd be like,
what do I need and let them sell to me.
I don't give a fuck and I'll buy it.
I don't even wear that much makeup. I just
like to have it. I will buy everything.
Food.
I'm an easy target.
Yo, have you seen this homeless man
guy from Columbus, Ohio? This is, no,
this is amazing. Yeah, I keep hearing
about it. So I have not seen check, check
this out. I tried to show it to you,
but what it is, it's a home.
My hometown, Columbus, Ohio.
This homeless guy held up a
sign and I said that, you know,
I can do voices for food
or money or whatever. Yeah,
totally not that right. Yeah,
it looks exactly like
freeway exit ramps.
But recently there's been this guy with
an interesting sign in [inaudible] 71
and Hudson street.
His handwritten signs says he has
the God given gift of a great voice.
Hey,
we're gonna make you work for your dollar.
Say something with that great radio Voice.
You're listening to nothing
but the best of all these.
You're listening to magic 98.9
so much.
God bless you. Whoa. And we'll be back
with more right after these words.
And don't forget tomorrow morning is your
chance to win a pair of tickets to see
this man live in concert.
Thank you so much.
Mona was 14 years old. I was
born and raised in Brooklyn,
New York when I was 14,
I kind of listen to one of our
area radio announcers and uh,
as a field trip to go meet the guy.
And he looked nothing
like what he sounded like.
So I asked him about that
and he said to me, listen,
radio is defined theater of mine.
And so when he said theater of
mine, I just said, well, hey,
I can't be an actor at camp,
be an on air personality.
But the voice just became something of a,
of a development over years
and then went to school for it.
And then alcohol and drugs and a few
other things became a part of my life.
I got two years clean and I'm trying hard
to get it back and hopefully somebody
from one of these television
or radio thing, hey,
I need a voiceover or I need
something. So, you know,
I'm hoping one day watch family
guy weeknights at seven 30 on Fox,
20 year anything. But that's what
it is. And I love radio. Okay.
Yeah, I got sad at the end and
the beginning was kind of Nice.
Beginning was actually cool.
If that was a 15 second clip,
it will be the shit got weird. Who
greets those signs? That's smart.
That's really small.
The worst. That's when,
when it's the couple like it
looks like that, you know,
they just do math together and they're
just living on the road and have like a
bowling ball bag and the
worst is when they have a dog.
Isn't that awful that the dog is what
touches your heartstrings? That person,
but I totally fucking dark.
If they had a kid,
probably the kid would get taken away.
Someone protective services would come
and take the kid away most likely. Right.
I mean, you can't have a
kid and be homeless. Kenya,
I saw an episode of law and order
the election you of Oh my God.
Yeah. Madness. It gets enough box at
that kid knows how to change a tire,
eat a tire to how to cook a
tire. Well, that guy was like,
I noticed that the guidance sound or
anything like he looked, I'm like,
I felt like he was going to be like, I
was white, so I went out, died my skin,
got my nose clean. To do when you're
homeless is to have a gimmick.
Isn't it amazing that voice is like,
it's like a tool almost like the DJ voice.
Like it's such a uh,
an affection that you take
on when you talk like a Dj.
Here we go. You know,
it's like something to it.
It's creepy though.
What have you done for me lately?
That's like an old radius
thing. That's like a dying
sound. Probably though. Is it?
Because podcasts, podcasts don't do
that. There's not like the guy gets it.
Hey there. Hey, we should do that. We
should do a podcast and a DJ voice.
You're listening to red by radio.
Hey you, here we go. All right.
It's also the Strip club Dj. They're very
similar. This is this the same voice,
but with a couple of drinks.
Denver has your approval
Lexus to the main stage.
It's like the same guy over, especially
in La are, so I have a bit about this,
which I'm not going into.
They're so ignorant sounding.
There's this one I listen to like the
hip hop stations and I don't know if he's
like Latino or what. He's like, y'all,
you guide, get your ad Oh insurance.
And I'm like, why does that, the word
is auto. And it's always like, Yo,
after you motherfuckers, if they want
insurance, y'all gotta get down there.
And I'm like,
you are just spreading ignorance.
Like people think it's okay to get a
job and you're yelling at me and you're
mispronouncing everything
and have it in Spanish.
I know how to speak Spanish
properly speaking to their people,
Chichi that there's, there's a lot
of them as well. It's not that,
it's just so wouldn't, if
you're, if you're fine,
let's say you're La Rasa and
you're going to community college,
you're going to school or you're trying
to get a better education and this is
what, this is what your people are telling
you, it's okay to sound like sort of,
maybe they're just hanging out, you know?
Maybe that's just the way they talk.
Yeah, it's, I, I know what you're saying.
I do agree that maybe you should
have like better English and stuff,
but you know if you know
what the fuck he's saying,
we're not saying anything.
They're not saying no,
they're not talking about the news. It's
just like, Yo, boost mobile. That no way.
That not ghetto.
I like it.
I want to make sure there's a few ghetto
stations around so I can listen to them.
I like it because that's just connected
to like remember that old video with the
leper confound found in the
tree. I remember finding
this. Yeah. Have you seen,
oh, this is from like four years
because you will remember this.
Once you see this Leprechaun, a bunch
of people are going to be tweeting me.
They think I'm racist after this.
Y'All can eat it
in Alabama yet, but it's called
Leprechaun in Alabama and they found this.
Let me know what you're saying.
You're saying that people should speak
like they're educated and set a good
example. You should know what you're
saying is you're going to say anything.
I'm never going to listen to you because
you sound, what I'm saying is I'm,
everybody's different.
I like watching people and listening
to people that are nothing like me,
you know? So I like listening
to ghetto shows. No other games.
I like listening to them on the radio too.
That's what they want to talk.
They don't have to say anything.
Listen to that shit.
This is the leprechaun cheap.
That's what I'm saying.
As a peer with 99.6 we went back
would also force of fresh tunes.
I got to make a point for a
living and they can just blabber.
Yeah but that's what the Jew,
I mean nobody wants to hear a
point in between their songs.
I don't remember anything. I
just want you to music. I miss.
I Miss Real Dj's. Curiosity
leads to large crowds in mobiles.
Tritan mini have you bring binoculars,
Ken quarters,
even camera phones to take pictures to
me and the lack of level coding to me.
Tell your friends to go be the chief
cause that Yay
the Leprechaun only comes out.
It gets better.
If you shine a light in its direction,
its suddenly disappears.
This sketch resembles what many of you
are saying. The leprechaun looks high,
hard to believe and have come up with
their own theories and exit this real.
The image
theory is casting a shadow from.
Do they show it Liam?
Oh, oh, oh,
oh know aren't going to know faster
around stove and it told me get
up in a tree at play a Leprechaun.
Would you buy me a joint?
I England.
[inaudible] a jar a week.
You have better language,
better action,
more activities and more individual.
It's the guys on the radio and I would
point is Bella social lab is bad.
The real action? No by no
clown. Is Bush more enjoyable,
more enjoyable?
We don't get down to the bottom.
This is not the news anymore.
This is like a remix version of it
though. This is bullshit. You're fucking
with the Leprechaun.
He suited up from him was
all smells right here.
What's this is this liberal
curve probably slowed him down.
This is Nicholas.
We can having an aneurysm as we fucked
up and pick the wrong youtube video.
All right. And this is what's
called poor prior planning. So,
but there was there a real,
a real true story.
There was a real story that people
thought there was 11. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That was really, that was a mixed
in with like complete craziness.
That's know what's real though, man.
Well they haven't, that was rendering.
You know what? This has probably,
I'll tell you what it is, man.
This is probably a real
fucking Leprechaun. And this
is the disinformation. Yeah.
Government puts out of the Leprechaun.
Yeah. Fallen birds. Big It out dog.
What is your speeches over there?
Blanche,
she's under your desk following.
I want to make sure we can get
in my letterbox. She won't.
I think I shut the door. I don't
know. Blanche come here. Come here.
I've got something for you. What is
it? Sharon know she doesn't want this.
Is this a stereotype? Pretty girl with
a little dog cause she's not little.
She actually is. She's quite
heavy. Yeah, she's like 13 pounds.
And I'm not saying there's anything
wrong with it. She's chill as fuck. Uh,
you don't ever bring that dog to like
the mall Dhea. You're, you do that?
I'd bring her everywhere,
but there's not a cute bag.
It's this big like over the shoulder
baffled bag, like a duffle bag.
Like she's like a basketball player.
You use it.
Is this like a crazy special bond that
you have with a dog when you adopted dog?
Cause that dog's life could have
been super fucked up. Super fucked.
It could have been shit. I mean, you
never know. She could have been put down.
She needs anything can happen. But you
came along and got her and I, she gets,
she's very needy. She gets upset
if I leave. So I take her off.
Work is not a problem and she's not little
enough to be annoying and I'm not hot
enough to be annoying
about it. So it's okay.
What do this dogs or fucking fascinating
animals. A dog chew gum. Yeah.
Let, why don't you go the fuck dogs
love gum. They actually chew it.
That's not good for your dog. Why? Why?
Why? Why would it be round about this? No,
that's not right.
Don't get caught your dog though.
Eating chewing gum and it's just
like, oh, what are you eating?
And I'm laying around on the floor.
You fucking Slob. Yeah, it dogs eat.
No price is leave it everywhere.
My dogs really like it just gets on top
of things and gets on top of my coffee
table now or whatever. Oh really
good. You got a set of rules son.
You gotta be Alpha about that Shit.
Even with little dogs there's just
certain shit you shouldn't have them do.
It shouldn't be walking where you eat.
Exactly what their dirty shit.
I like how you said to go walking where
I eat the like everyone eats at the
coffee table and now have you noticed
like the kitchen table is like it's
getting phased out?
No.
To put on families like you eat at the
table with your kitty to the table table.
Really? We don't need it to,
you're like perpetual single guy.
Maybe he got a table that you don't
want to talk about that now. No,
you're always to go
single again. Watch out.
We should play that Pat Song Prince Song.
I've got a broken heart again,
once you pull it up, Brian,
I need to talk. We sad. No,
Brian has got to learn to once a again,
I got a broke out. A broken heart again,
bitchy girls. Is that the problem?
It's just a nice, yeah. Yeah.
He's a nice guy. Nice guy. I don't think
he's too nice. He's just, you know,
it slap him or you gotta write,
you gotta get the right combination.
I don't have it.
That's the whole key to relationships.
Not necessarily that you're
wrong and that person's,
the person that you got along with. This
is wrong. It's like the combinations off.
Some people would go great
with some one person,
but with other people
that clash and it's just,
everybody's got to find that on my brand.
Like chemistry. It's all about Brian.
It's not just about bodies, men. It's
about the person behind the body.
Sounds depressing. My dog got to
concentrate on the sole. Brian,
you've got to concentrate on being real
with these bitches and find one who is
willing to be real with you back.
See what I'm saying, Bro. Yeah,
you gotta tap deep into it.
Hang on. Wait a second. Get to,
it's real good to what's real.
And if they're not giving you the real,
then you give him the pen pal.
I get it. Give him the Heisman.
He go step out of my life. I see what
you're dealing with. Times of port.
Thanks for talking to me.
Let's get a check. A traffic.
Alright, here's Bob or the
midway. What's going on Bob?
We have a slowed down at the five.
You know,
I noticed today driving here that
if I wanted to be a gardener,
all I would have to do is walk down
the highway. I would find shoes, hats,
rakes, garbage bags. Like there was like
so much shit on the side of the road.
Have you noticed how much
crap is on our highways?
Like ridiculous things
like couches and chairs.
And is it because you think
they're not cleaning up as much?
I think it's all these landscaper guys
that just have those trucks that have
like all the shit in the back,
you know where there's just falls off.
I'm waiting for it.
Right.
I'm waiting for a rape to come
right through my windshield.
I ran over a railroad tie
once a big metal railroad tie,
you know those big
fucking things that like,
yeah know in movies get crushed
on empire. I'm sorry. Not a tie.
The Gay bar, the bar, the
middle bar or a bar. The Bar,
wherever that the railroad track
goes on a track. Oh my God.
We're all retarded part of the
rabbit with the tail. The metal shit.
The metal shed bro.
Fucking long thing that the wheel rolls.
I thought you were talking
about the state. Nope. No,
no, no. It was a bigger one.
Or are you talking about the state?
No, no, no. I'm just kidding.
Do you guys track this railroad? Right?
Not a tie. I said ty, incorrect word.
What I meant is a,
a section of track.
It was like a big ass fucking giant hunk
of metal and I'm driving on the highway
and all of a sudden I,
I see it before it's too late.
There's nothing I could do and Bob by
hit it and it just tears my wheel apart.
Smashes, it tears the wheat,
the tire off the wheel.
And I had to make a decision and I said,
you know what?
I'm just going to drive
on this fucking thing.
I'm not getting out on the highway and
like risking getting hit by some fucking
car. I'm like, I'm going
to cook this car, you know,
I'm just going to drive in this fucked
up wheel and cook this car. And it was,
sparks were flying and
shit and smoke and it was,
it was nuts because it
was like half of a wheel.
It was like half a wheel
in this fucked up time.
And I'm going like literally
you have far to go? Yeah.
I have like almost a almost a mile deep.
Did you binge it rims locked.car up I
how to get a bunch of shit done to it
after it's over. Yeah. But you
know what is better than me dying.
That's what I thought of. I, there's
a kid I went to high school with it.
It was changing his tire off the side
of the road and somebody hit the car and
killed him. Why you shouldn't
change your on tires. Well,
but have you been watching
horror movies lately?
It's always the girl getting her flat
tire and waiting for the guy to fix it.
Girls take 10 minutes out of your time.
Find out figuring out how to do it.
Just in case of emergency,
you don't want to be calling these times.
It's a physical, so truck drivers trying
to get those fucking wheels off, bro.
Those those times, sometimes it's really
hard. Sometimes it's hard for a man,
like a big man to get your
your fucking bolts loose.
I'm the first ask others for help.
Nobody would attempt stuff.
Sometimes it's a payment you should try.
You should learn how to do it if you
can, but fuck man, you can do it fast.
It's pretty easy.
[inaudible] I guarantee you some bolts
that you would not be able to crack.
I've been in.
I could look at you.
You've just rose up like a man and puffed
a chance. Never had a problem ever.
I love it. I've never had a
problem ever changed a tire ever.
Really awesome. Easy. Wow.
Between the two of you.
Who Do you just have to use the retard
strength like okay I got to do it.
I mean sorry,
not retard strength.
I changed a lot of tires when I was
a kid but I stopped a long time ago.
I forgot everything that's involved in it,
but when I was in auto shop in high
school we listed though it used to change
tires like you know, do you use
that fucking stupid machine cause
I know that moves the tire in
place and put the weights on it.
It was kind of kind of interesting
stuff but I forgot all of it.
We had this shot,
this a teacher in auto shop that all he
would do was fix up shitty old mustangs.
I wish I could remember his name
because he was a real character.
It's probably on Facebook. Probably
Facebook me Bro. You remember me?
I remember you. I just forgot your
name and he, he's probably dead by now.
I didn't want make you feel old. It
is. No, no. Getting away from it.
Every year I get a little older.
I hate when I think of like an
old actor that I think is dead.
And then I go and find out that he
has like a Facebook and a website.
Remember that shit? What? Jonathan Winters
the other day I was like, oh, he's dead.
He's still alive. He's still alive.
He's got fucking CDs coming out.
He's got paintings. He's got it
like a website. It's hard to keep,
a lot of people die.
It's hard to keep track of.
Jonathan Winters used to be on all the
time back in the day that he just kind of
remember like knew who Jonathan Winters.
Sure. Yeah. He was the guy who used to,
he used to guest on Mork and Mindy,
Remember Douglas?
Kirk Douglas, I think is dead. Oh,
Michael Douglas. Michael Douglas is,
I don't, I don't know. Right, right.
Kate,
why our queue with a capital k,
capital t k just so, uh,
you're from Dallas, right? Yes.
Four years old. He's alive.
Wow. I just won $20. Holy Shit.
Did you ever go on the Aleks and Terry
show down there or do you know those guys?
I do know that name. Uh, I'm not,
I didn't do standup and Dallas.
I've done it since, but
I didn't, I never did it.
I went to college in Boston and we sweat
this real name. You ready for this?
This is, this is Kirk Douglas.
His real name. It's, is it Jewish?
Is that what it is? It's is sir. I S. S.
U R is Sir Denea low vich.
That's his real name. It just rolls off
the tongue. I can see why he chose. Oh,
vich. Wow. It says it in Russian letters.
Is it on Wikipedia?
Yeah.
What would you like if you had to change
your name because he had it fucked up
named like that. What would you change
it to if it kind of just Darth Vader? No,
like seriously.
I will change my name to Darth Vader.
Would your backup name be like a real
name? Luke Skywalker? No. It'd be like,
it'd be like Lance Kenobi bitch.
That would be my full name. Yeah.
I don't know anything about cars
or star wars. No, you don't.
I got Kevin James had to do that too.
Well, I don't want to say his last name.
He probably doesn't want people knowing I
had to do it. I can be called Reich. Oh,
here you in. This sound rude. I sound
like it sounds like next generation. Yeah.
It's like no matter what, like people were
forced to think about the third. Right?
Right.
That's fucked up just a little bit.
They're going to not like you as much
as they should and you're bubbling.
Personality is not going to shine through
you being held back by a douchebag
name, Bro. Fuck that shit.
Can't go wrong with red fish.
Keep it as that and then just be the guy.
Be the one to change that stereotype.
You can think of. Nazis were going to give
you reinvent yourself as Red Ban, Huh?
Yeah, that fucking name. Legally, but now,
now ever since I've been rid me for one,
now there's like a red band,
like techno artists from the UK and
there's this other ripping you off.
There's all these red
bands now and it's like,
that's not fair and tell people to jump
on the red band wagon. He's got it.
You're right. [inaudible] dot com
is his, he's in the box. It's over.
It's done dude. You're like a
rapper. You've changed your name.
You really had to sell. I
can't be calling. Right. Cool.
I have my last name doesn't do me
any favors. How about Charlie Sheen?
Those guys too. There were Charlie
Sheen and Emilio Vazquez, her brothers,
but Charlie was like,
that Shit's just too Mexican.
Joey's like, I'm going with dad.
Uncle would help. Dad rocked it.
They have different fathers.
Is that what it is?
Or different fathers gotta be mothers
so they're allowed to have sex with each
other. Totally Bang. It makes sense now.
That's how they're married.
Their kids would be fun.
That's how they were married.
Charlie Sheen is holding it down though
and kind of tell you I'm talking about a
god that just keeps doing
the same shit and dislike.
Just keeps moving forward for him.
When he walks on set for two and
a half and don't like the day.
Is everyone just like quiet like
Zimmer pretend like nothing happened.
Kid high fives. I doubt it.
Do you watch that show at all?
I bet he owns that shit. The best
thing about that show is when the,
how they show the kid, like morph
into the adult. That's trippy. Yeah.
The thing about Charlie Sheen is
Charlie Sheen has like $100 million,
so he doesn't give a fuck either.
So it doesn't matter if he gets
caught with hookers. She's like,
what the fuck ever shut it. I
hope he does. Hot shots. Three d
you think you could pitch it?
What would be the is retired
navy seal guy or whatever.
He has a son,
uh,
Bieber and Justin Bieber
and Justin Bieber's he has
to train him to take over a
fucking huge mood.
We were doing coke right now.
This would be the best conversation.
Yeah. Dude, this is a fucking huge movie.
I'm telling you right now.
The agent right now,
I know Mike Young and Mike Young
knows Leonardo Dicaprio. Okay,
we're going to get this fucking thing.
We're going to put this deal together.
Okay. Mike John Rose Tobey Maguire to told
me McGuire, I wouldn't be a bad choice
and pitch it to him and see what he says.
Mike Engle price on Mike Young last night
and he said he was the Charlie Sheen
is hot right now, if that's what
you're on speaker where you do it.
He said something hilarious.
He said something Larry's.
He's like, yeah man. I saw,
I saw,
I saw Joe at the UFC MMA and he held up
and you just said something like write
more or someone. I looked up at him
and I went like this with my fingers.
Right, like from stage. Yeah. It's just,
it was very funny. He's like, he's like,
he's right. He's right. He's right.
It was an inside joke. He, we would
always joke around with, the problem was,
I don't want to do now. He's a good
guy. The wrapper, if Mike were black,
he would be Drake.
I think they look alike.
I'm going to drink whiskey
with him or was that,
my ties are Nando's hot whiskey
drinks with Mike. Heidi.
I had hot toddies last night. That's
like young or Drake, Huh? Both of them.
Who did you mean?
Initially? Mike Young. Oh,
I'm sure he wouldn't have be need for
coffee or Mike have travels with the
Russell tribes or Russell Peters
does it. Really? Yeah. That's good.
That's why he was in Montreal for the
UFC. I love his song. Take me back.
It's a fun song, man. We should
find that. We want to play that.
Is that even on the lot? That's
hard. Okay, I'll find it.
You know I could always email it to you.
I'm sure I have it on my computer.
I'll just buy it from iTunes. Also.
Port bike from iTunes. Fuck yeah,
I'll support Mike if you can put the link
up. It's actually a really good song.
Have you ever heard my caps on? You
ever heard a song? It's a good song.
We freaked out. It's really
good. I was like, Mike, man,
this is like a good fucking pop
song. I don't know what it is. Is,
is he rapping it? Oh, it
was sorta sorta wraps.
I'm Jewish. My brother's a rapper.
We love it. Where the fuck is it?
I don't even have it on this
computer. Son of bitch, motherfucker.
Oh, here we go. Yeah, I can buy
it by, by that shits on Pie.
I want to hear a song. Oh, it's so good.
Like we, I was actually addicted to this.
Shocked. I was really shocked. I mean
it's, it's not the greatest song ever,
but it's like I told him, I go, dude, this
could be on the radio, like taking you.
Definitely. Yeah, we're here. Right? Why?
What's your account has been or
what the fuck is going on? But then
we're being held back by technology,
by things. Speaking of
which, this is something,
were we talking about this before the
podcast started? Um, conspiracy theory,
punk conspiracy theory about what the
fuck is happening with these birds,
Arkansas.
Shoot.
What are you saying Joe Rogan.
Eliza talk about the birds and
the fish that suddenly die. Oh,
I didn't even see that birds and
the fish conversation. I didn't,
I didn't read the Twitter. That's all
I do. But that is what the subject is.
The um, the, these fucking birds,
like thousands of them fell from the sky
and over a hundred thousand drum fish
are dead.
And then this guy gets murdered.
Who is an expert in
chemical warfare and uh,
some guy in, there's all these, these
websites connecting him to uh, to this,
this fucking dead bird
kill that they were,
I mean who knows how much of it is real
and what speculative and what's just
conspiracy conspiracy theory nonsense.
But it's pretty fascinating that this
guy who's an expert in chemical warfare
gets a assassinated.
He's probably responsible for it.
And Peta is the one that is acid at him.
They're fucked fucking
and his favorite song.
I highly doubt it but I think
that's funny. Oh Mike Young.
Cause he plays hard.
Yeah,
I sent you, that's not the
song. Take me back now.
Funny how time disappears.
Young rebels on the street full of fire,
but fear the late night street fights
underneath the street lights Dj played on
Becca that you needed on that night too.
Young footballers just
rocking in the cost.
They'll forex in lack some neighborhood
movie stars running around town.
Now free is a bird just loud as
you can because you gotta be heard.
Your blood pumps skill. You feel real
limits at bold too. Cool for school. Yo,
I never met the principal spend
every night getting high as a kite,
just sneaking in the back end.
Everything gets site young with
the Honga fast pace, no fee.
If I'm living every day,
I'm going to live 108 but now as a kid,
never had to worry about what I did.
I'm a man now was the plan
now gotta get it done.
No time fun.
Now take me back Manassas.
A different version is a had to worry
about this. This loop is done, man.
Now maybe he remastered it. Gotta move
on those days. Someone else's doing.
Hence we sell Tom crushing. The
feel is such a rush. She was older,
so she made me promise. Maybe he had
a fallout. Condom County. Anyway,
the song sounds like of a cracker
a little bit. I was like, Oh crap.
And those guys that saying that butterfly
song, if you want to give it online,
it's called take crazy town crazy.
It's like crazy town.
If anybody wants to get it online,
it's called take me. Take me back.
It's Mike Young. It's from the album
work in progress, which is a great album.
Said. Why that place of
service og like that for sure.
You open up the flood gates of a million
angry Douche bags all over the Internet
going to fucking song.
No SOPs cock
like young, fuck my girl. How many people
are out there yelling and screaming?
You should drown in Aids on message
boards. It's going to be a thing now.
That's all it does. It's a thing
for a long time. She'd go to the,
if you go to the underground forum or
if you go to the Rogan board, you know,
or this is, those are the two forms
that I go to on a regular basis. Eliza,
you take it from,
are you addicted to any kind of web
websites or forums or anything like that?
I compulsively check my own
Facebook page, but uh, d listed.
I don't really do celebrity gossip,
but I do like that guy's writing. Yeah,
he's fun. Also one called
catalog living.net. What?
It is hilarious.
They take pictures out of catalogs and
it's these two characters and they,
if you go to it,
I'll show it to you.
They make fun of the way furniture set
up and catalogs because they set up these
ridiculous room and no
one will live like that.
It's these from the point of view of
these, I think it's Gary and Elaine.
They live in the catalog and it's from
their point of view. If you just read one,
it's so funny. I liked, I
checked that. What's it called
again? Cat. It's so, it's,
it's just, no, it's just
catalog. living.net. Do you know,
have a message board on your website? I
think so. I don't think it ever reject it.
If you want to contact you go to
Facebook or something, it's fine. Oh,
that's funny. But why do you, uh, how come
you don't want to have your own thing?
Why would you want to just have it
on Facebook? Like message boards?
It's like it's a,
it's an interesting thing to be able to
have like a whole group of people that
you're, you know, you're communicating
with and it's all hosted on your side.
I think she just think I do. Right.
But I also have one, there it is.
I have one for my web show
that we do. There's a message
board for that. And what,
yeah, what does this web show,
because you were guys were,
you were going to tell me before the
show started, but we decided to wait.
My show is called the
weekly news. Wea. Koi.
Why you've been doing that for a while.
How long have you been doing it for?
About maybe three years.
Then we took a break because we lost
our sponsor and we just got back starts
next week. And how do people
see it? Where's it at? Coda?
The stream.tv. The Stream?
Yeah, like water, str
am dot. TV slash weekly.
And now there's all these backlog
episodes and uh, we get on there and I,
I just thought it was important to do
a show where it wasn't some girl just
cackling about Kim Kardashians.
So we talk about the headlines and
what's in the news and I get into debates
with people and it's all in good
fun. And uh, it's the weekly news,
but if Kim Kardashians subject comes up,
don't be afraid of it.
I'm not afraid of it.
Fuck those motherfuckers don't
want them holding the camera.
Can you say her name's that?
People hear me saying it and then they
search or I don't want to add to that.
You don't want to add to it
for our whole family there.
What's wrong with our society?
Are you sure? Positive one.
It was like weapons and shit.
We're doing overseas with our society
more insular and not so much as the city's
actions. What's wrong with the
world? Girls like that? I can't even,
I mean you're probably friends with our,
no, no, no, no, no. I'm not friends.
You want to know? My opinion is this, this
is not a gel. She's gorgeous by the way.
I'll give her that. She's gorgeous. It's
all these women that are uneducated,
unintelligent self entitled,
did Jack Crap for anything and
now it's not even about the money.
You have all this notoriety and publicity
and there's nothing to you and it
teaches women in our society.
If you're just,
if you put on some makeup and let
someone pee on you or if you are,
not that she's a gold digger,
but if you do nothing and just
act like a total fucking whore,
rewards will come through higher
education. Screw integrity.
I see your point in any industry.
I also see it though.
You've got to let the market dictate
and I think that there's a market for a
horse. There's a morning bird is a
bargain for empty people on television.
There's a market like their players,
I mean, and not calling her a whore.
She's seems like a nice person
and she's got a great ass.
What I'm saying is there's a,
this is a market for people that are
trying to get attention for no reason and
they're doing this.
People get fascinating fixated on them
because they're regular people and they
start following them and then they become
players in of legit fucking show that
people get hooked up on and roped into.
I am part of the problem cause I
watch like real housewives of Atlanta,
16 weeks pregnant. Crazy. I've
been watching Beverly Hills.
I watch all of them and I'm so, I'm a part
of that problem. But I guess my thing,
the Beverly Hill don't be hating.
That's all. I'll say it. I hate it.
It's got to let them
let a freak be a freak.
He just got to let them just got a
lot of and watch it. You fascinating.
That's what 16 and pregnant. I
can't watch. I can't watch that.
That one good shape.
That has been beating people's,
he's been arrested like three times.
If I was 16 and pregnant,
I've been kicking dude's acids too. I sit
scary. She's probably out of her mind.
What's wrong with MTV for doing that shit?
That's well,
you know what's right with they're showing
it to us. I don't think it's wrong.
You don't have to watch it. You
know what? There's a glamorized.
I think it's not quite summarizing it,
man.
I think for a lot of people it's going
to scare the fucking shit out as I was
like,
why are all the girl's fat
catty woman? You give credit where
it's due. I mean there were attractive,
I said Kim Kardashian was pretty chess.
You did worthless but pretty worthless.
Pretty and worth.
If someone wants to fuck you,
you're worth something worthless in my
eyes cause I don't want to fuck her.
I want to fuck camp north north from the
Atlanta one. The sister that you liked,
that one that they can one the wig chick.
You like her totally have sex with her.
I'm going to have cigarettes with
her and fucking just kidding.
Brian has a tight,
tight.
Brian likes wants a big woman
that gets on top. No, no,
horrible. That is wigs. Hate fake hair.
That's just what a girl was trying
to choke you. Was She fucked you?
What if a girl was trying to choke me?
I don't like that shit and I don't
like every girl tried to do that.
I don't like crazy. There was
this girl when I went to a fight,
I went to a rave once when I was like
20 and there was this girl that I took
home and add the next morning.
She heard that we had sex,
but she was trying to choke
me it in the next morning.
She had no eyebrows that they had
like smeared off and it was like raver
eyebrows where she had no eyebrows that
were painted on and when she woke up it
was just smear it all over her face.
She wanted to,
she was trying to choke me the whole time.
It's like,
what the fuck this chicken murder
somebody by now the girl wanting to do.
I can understand that.
I've never heard of a girl like
is a big choker or he should be here.
I can see that every time I there was,
we were in Austin. Yeah,
Austin in this the whole time.
He's just sitting there
like he just met this girl.
He's just choking her the whole time.
I shouldn't be talking about this.
Is that the comedy queen made it
sound like you were in bed with no,
it wasn't like he doesn't care.
I always talk about that.
I'm sure he doesn't care.
I don't think any guy would care,
but it was just uncomfortable for me
because like, wow, I can't do that.
Can't just go up to a girl, be like, Hey,
I'm your neck. You Fun when you're young.
If you date a girl who's like really
into her feet and like playing with your
deck, where your feet you
is get like foot fetishes.
That's where they get it from. Where it
starts. Yeah. That's where it starts.
I Dunno. It's just really,
if you read, could be both.
It could be.
Could be.
Could we have a bunch of reasons
for having some weird fetish,
but that could be one that he just dated.
A girl in the sex was really
hot and she likes to get choked,
so he just started associated
like choking, like hot sex.
That's crazy. Right? I don't know.
I don't have any, don't like boobs.
That almost offends me, that don't don't
like that guy or I don't really care.
I'm like, how could you not care about,
but that's so important. Yeah, I agree.
100% are mostly guys.
Are you hanging out with what guys?
Are you thinking that they're
looking for flaws? Yeah,
I know you got a whole big tits and
shit, Blaine, and the guy's like,
just right here.
People talk on TV or male comics.
They're like a more of a buck guy.
I'm like, I don't get that at all. Um,
if I had to choose between one or the
other, I would say I'm more of a Buckeye.
Why? No, it's not the problem.
I love breasts as well,
but I've seen a lot of really attractive
women that have a small breasts and big
assets. You're looking at their
breasts more than you are there,
but it doesn't matter. It's aesthetic,
you know? What do you think is sexy?
You know, I don't mind girls with small
breasts. It doesn't bother me. I'm like,
I have, I said this before just because
you have big tits. That's all it is.
And you're from Texas. It's
like, it's a great system.
It's ingrained in your system.
That's a big titty state I lived between.
If you had to choose between a girl with
big tits and a flat ass or girl tits
and a big juicy yes she has no,
but it makes it easier to lie down.
You can touch the boobs.
No crazy. That flat ass.
I hate those acids. So flagged,
but it's really mostly,
these are people I knew a girl in college,
I had one of those flat asses that look
like where girls sometimes disturbing.
She had a little chunk to her.
I didn't want to hang out with her just
because of how uncomfortable her asking
me.
It's different than a tiny,
but like elephant butts where it's
just like a flat rhino surface.
There was this one girl
when we were in high school.
It's just one girl that had this,
the strangest body. She was like, um,
she was like five feet tall,
but she was like three feet wide and
her shoulders and her hips were equally
wise. No, she was just a
big girl. She was so big.
Like I remember just like standing next
to her. She was so fucking wine. So big.
You're like, this poor kid.
Nothing you can do about it.
She's just giant bones.
She was just like this five foot tall
neanderthal looking fucking freak,
tiniest neanderthal and the herd
that's all small. They were,
there were all little at one time.
My favorite,
all neanderthals were five feet tall,
like 200 pounds.
They were totally felt different than us.
Yeah.
They look like wolverine from the
Eczema in comic books. For Real.
That's what they looked like. Yeah. He's
really short. He's really and yoked.
But these things are actually shorter
than him. You know, we used to,
we talked about this in the
podcast and we've before,
but in the end her talls about why
they died off. Um, I don't know,
but I bet they have best the best boobs.
The, well, the reason why they died offers
because human males fuck
the female neanderthals.
But human females wouldn't let
the mail neanderthals fuck them.
But don't they rape and pillage.
Isn't that their shtick?
We were kicking their asses.
We're smarter than, than,
than we may better weapons who are
fucking them up fucking their women.
And then we just sorta integrated them in.
The males died off.
That's what happened.
Well that's why the French are so I say
we like it was me like I was a black.
The boys kicking some stupid monkey s
that's why the French are little bit you
think?
Yeah,
because of the neanderthals and that is
a part of France to do with like all the
strong ones went off to
war and they were so weak.
All the big guys died so all the little
ones were left over and that's why, wow,
what a trip, what a trip for
any culture. I guy's ridiculous.
How crazy is that?
That that's like a real concern.
Some cultures that men go off to war
and they'll die off and then leave,
like all the smart number of females.
Then the women have to become fucking
warriors who tried to fend off invading
herds of men and whatever happened to
that old school that go to war for like
three years and the chick actually
waited for the guy. You know? Nowadays.
It's like this.
Second,
people leave now world war two they were
getting closet pussy just like they are
today and it's so easy now. The girl
leaves and he puts it on Facebook. Oh,
I'm going to be lonely
for the next three years.
You know how many fucking messages
that girl gets on your boyfriend who's
overseas? You deserve
dynasty of age, right? Yes.
AIDS definitely the dumb Hugger,
right?
Unless your boyfriend's a Douche bag
and didn't realize it until he left,
went to war and then what? You get stuck
there because you want to be a patriot.
Cheat on him. Just share lonely.
Can't generalize. I mean,
maybe the poor girl just realize that
she's free now. Just fucking hat.
Maybe I want to explore my life and I
don't want to get into confrontation with
Randy because he gets fucking angry and
he shoots his guns. Shouldn't say Randy.
When Renco tourist,
one of my heroes,
I should come up with a better
name for my fake person.
I don't think he's gonna
think you know a Ronald.
I don't know why no one named Ronald
is tough. I would say Ronald Reagan.
Ronald Reagan, Ronald. He had lush,
bless you cheeks. Trying to think
of any MMA guys I know named Ron.
Fuck the Ronald Reagan,
but that's what the real name is.
Ron. If you're Ronald, you
become nerd. No one's like Jack,
Ronald or Ronny. So you have
to pick, Huh? Well the Ronnie,
but this one is the same, isn't it? This
long name is Ronnie. Really? Dave's Randy.
Hey, are you related to
Dr Laura Schlessinger? No,
not get that question all the time.
It's Hearst has a c that's gotta
be annoying as fuck. Right?
It doesn't happen enough
that I'm like upset about it.
Did they ever think that you're her?
Maybe I'll get easier upset.
That would be worse.
I said maybe I'll get easier.
It's easier to upset me than you.
It happens, but it's not for me.
It used to be like Fred Rogan,
the sports guy,
but spelled different. Worse people to
be asked if you're related or Fred's.
I'm sure he's a good guy.
I'm related to Kim's all see ag.
Who's that wig where like,
oh, you know her. You know her last
name and everything, but she goes by,
she has a song. I think she quit
smoking while she's having the baby.
I bought her CD. No, she's smoking.
She smoked emotions pregnant.
Absolutely. That's hard to see, man.
That is one of the hardest things
to see the nurse, so you know,
she saw that in Canada.
He stepped out of me and Ari Shaffir,
we're way up in fuck. I think we're
in Saskatoon somewhere. Crazy. Yeah,
it was way on the middle of nowhere.
It's really interesting.
And we stepped out of this restaurant.
There's chick there,
big fucking belly sitting there
smoking a cigarette. I'm like, wow.
Probably trying to do the kid a favor.
Get rid of it.
So it doesn't have to be
born in Saskatoon. Fuck.
People have made the argument
that it doesn't. I mean,
it's stupid that it doesn't affect the
cuboid affects the kid. Absolutely.
I blame that for awhile.
I'm fucked up. What? My mom,
my mom's smoking while I was in the womb.
That's all my issues. I remember when,
I remember my friend's mom smoked and
we'd go bowling every Saturday and she
would just sit there with the window
cracked open and just the smoke would hit
me in the face the whole way to
the bowling alley. Remember going,
oh this is the worst.
This kid I went to high school with,
his mom and dad both chain smoked. It was
the creepiest thing you would go over.
It was just a house of death. You'd go
over their house and there was smoke ever.
It was fucking cold as shit cause
we lived in Boston, you know,
so you go over their house and their
living room was just filled with fucking
smoke. It was just, you would
walk into like a death cloud,
like they're killing themselves
or choking themselves to death.
My best friend growing up,
her parents were insomniacs that
chain smoked and so she'd be like,
come sleep over my house and we'll go home
reeking of cigarettes before a formal,
she's like, come over to my house for
pictures. I'm like, I don't want it.
You'd probably be jacked from the
nicotine to. Did you get like,
did you feel the nicotine,
we kids who you're just,
you're already running around.
We have mellow child. What?
Mellow child. He's trying to
get to know you. No, no, no.
I mean, because of all the
cigarettes fellow Chow's IML a child
by her. So relaxed, but it's
such a confusing conversation,
Bryan burrough.
Yeah.
I feel really bad for little kids who's
parents smoke and the smoke around him
all the time. They get it in
their head that that's, you know,
it's just a part of life. You
know? Some people small can shit.
Maybe I should try it too. Well, it is
relaxing and then next thing you know,
you're hooked on the tit to.
It is a bizarre thing that there's no
politicians calling out for that shit to
be illegal. Is it bizarre? It's very
bizarre. Bizarre that people tolerate it.
400,000 people die every year
from cigarette smoke and no one,
no one is up arms. Do you know what do you
mean? No one is up in arms. They're not.
No one's up in arms.
No one's trying to stop and no one's
making it a part of political campaigns
probably make a lot of money from pricing.
Oh yeah.
Well they definitely do think it
should be illegal to smoke anywhere.
But in your house, like when I go out to
eat, even if you're smoking on the curb,
it's affecting me. It's such a thing
as just fish habitat, illegal period.
I think even the most smokers
would say, dude, if it wasn't sold,
if you guys made it legal,
sure.
I think you should be able to do
whatever you want to do and your house,
you want to smoke a cigarette,
I think you should be able to talk to her.
I definitely don't agree with any sort
of nanny state bullshit where you can say
that happy meals can't be legal because
kids get tricked into eating them cause
there's this toy inside of the shut
the fuck up and it's a God damn happy.
Exactly. If you want to buy a happy meal
every now and then for a Goof, what?
Who gives a shit stop? This is
nonsense. So people should die out.
We shouldn't go jazz. It
will. Yeah, I think so.
Government's job to protect is not the
government's job to make you eat right or
make things easier.
It's their job to protect your right
to do whatever the fuck you want.
That's all hers. Don't think you
should be able to tell me or can.
I know cigars can give you cancer too,
and I like us to Garvey known then I
don't think he should be able to tell him
what the fuck to do. I want to do
what I want to do, but they just,
you shouldn't be able to smoke in my face,
but there should be some sort of a way
that we can find out what the fuck those
599 chemicals that they've added the
cigarettes are first of all because of a
bunch of 'em have been concocted entirely
to effect the addiction process. No,
it's mostly spices. Spices.
It's a certain menthol smell.
It's angel balls there
should that dessert.
It's the stuff that they put
installation, you know, fiberglass.
It's in menthols is what they used to
always say, make you itchy as a kid.
You don't wait on it.
And then you'd have all,
I remember that I used to install that
shit. I used to install fiber glass,
paint stuff.
Anthrocon when I worked as a labor for
doing construction when I was a kid,
my father was an architect so I got a
lot of jobs on construction sites and we
used to have to install
a lot of that shit.
And you just go home just issuing
man everywhere hardware floors,
you get bad zits too.
That's what my attic used to have in it.
And I used to just like looking
at the pink panther logo,
so like jump in there just to look at it.
And if this summer,
summer in Boston installing that shit,
oh I get so hot there,
I went to college there and wide,
well ac in my apartment, it gets wet.
It's like that wet heat that you
don't get here in California.
California heats no big deal. So 110
degrees out here and you're like, ah,
it's hot. But no big deal. You know,
it's 110 in Boston or New Jersey or
in one of those that's just swamp.
Especially if you're like in a city,
there's no relief and
there's a steam everywhere.
You know they have bear
problems in New Jersey.
Do you know that New Jersey has like,
they just started opening
the open season on bears.
Now they have bear hunting tags.
You can get bear hunting in New Jersey
and it's not shooting bears if they seem
like they were looking at that control.
You don't realize that a big part
of New Jersey apparently is rural.
We always think of New Jersey was neural
big.
We always think of New Jersey.
He's like Newark and these industrial
areas and these dumps shit. Sopranos,
do I have a bad accident? No, no, no, no.
It's just, those are weird words. Newark,
Newark, New Jersey. I was born
and, but a huge part of New Jersey.
It's just woods,
you know,
and there's fucking bears are invading
into people's neighborhoods and one's
bears get addicted to
eating out of garbage cans.
They know how easy it is
to get the food that way.
They just go to that every time because
it's way easier than killing animals or
pulling up roots and shit.
So they just start fucking up people's
garbage and they just move into
neighborhoods and have like real problems.
Can Show your funny bear club.
It was on like the tonight show a
couple of weeks ago. I saw this in the,
and you don't need the New York cabs
in the back. They have like little,
like NBC video clips and you can watch,
right?
I was in New York couple weeks
when I saw this. Just put, Hey,
what are you doing bear?
It's literally 10 seconds and
it's the funniest thing ever.
People should look at it. It was,
they named a whole segment after it.
This is this the top one. The thing
where I keep looking for it. Hey,
what do you doing bear? Hey,
what are you doing there?
And what is it if this farmer
and he is here to us, this one,
watch this. Oh, I know what you're
talking about. Who's not a farmer.
He's a hunter to understand thing. A
farmer and a hunter's. Totally kidding.
It's close. Well, maybe
for it until he gets here.
Well anyway, what it is is, uh,
this bear decides to climb up this
ladder where this guy is a hunting.
She's really scary and
he scares it off quicker.
Wow.
Bears are highly intelligent. And that's
not the sentence. That's a different one.
It's a different one. Yeah.
That's okay. Sorry. That's okay.
It's like almost the same thing though.
Well,
I don't understand why this is parents
just get it like to the, anyway,
the barrier.
This is the best podcast average.
I hate when people can't find
the clips and then they're like,
just wait a second. It's, and that it's
not funny. And then their internet sucks.
Here it comes. Yeah. And then just watch
the bears looking up the ladder.
There's a bear at the bottom of this tree
stand and now the bear is climbing up
the tree. Stand the ladder here
comes. Yeah. It's a lot of it.
It's treestand
bears climbing halfway up right now.
Oh my God. Say something, Dude. Hey, what
are you doing there? Were you doing there?
What the fuck?
How lucky is he that that bear does not
know what's going on and just run away?
Was fucking crazy. What are
you doing there? And then
there's like a made mistake.
Wrong House. There's a guy that's pretty
relaxed. Yeah, that guy's relaxed around.
Would've been screaming again.
Bear was halfway up the fucking
ladder before he said anything.
He was hoping the bear is going
to change its mind. That's crazy.
You don't get real big when a bear comes.
You just have to reason with it.
Bears respond to logic it unless have
their babies with them and then they're
going to eat your ass
hall growing up in Texas,
asshole asshole first and they'll
eat you out from the inside.
Growing up in Texas, did you do a
lot of hunting? Like a lot of, um,
should we don't hunt for bargains?
You know what I did use
to do my friend Lauren,
her parents were into something called
like reenactment shootings and they would
dress up in period costumes like early
or late 19th century cowboy attire.
And we would go out to like the middle
of nowhere and like fresco before it had
houses there and they would have little
town set up and they would do timed
events shooting like rifles and you get
awards at the end and we would just sit
there in the back of a suburban and
drink Dr Pepper and watch her parents do
this every Sunday,
like 6:00 AM and they had like cowboy
names and there was like a little
community. Holy Shit, we got
to shoot guns. Wow. Awesome.
It's like a cowboy version of dungeons
and dragons or something. Yeah,
it's kind of like civil war reenactments,
but there's no shot shooting back those
things and like civil war reenactments
and um, I don't get them either.
I don't, I don't get the, uh,
I guess I get the renaissance thing
a little bit more. Renaissance Fair.
It seems like there. Yeah, that's what I
go there having fun. The food is so good.
The civil war thing is
like ridiculous stuff.
Are you just running around with a gun?
I don't think so.
I think they plan out the
war plan out like battles,
like this is when these guys came over
the hill and it's like an accurate
historical what happened
or believe so directions.
Well I think they just pretending they're
really doing it in real history and
they're getting a boner for it.
There's weird all civil war buff,
fucking weird man running around with
fake bullets and you're shooting blanks
and shit. And as a kid though, watching
that, that was really cool. You know?
And it showed you that something that
you normally used to have books for now
you can just be a video game. I wonder
how often those civil war reenactments.
I'm wondering how often people get
actually shot. That's like, oh,
I thought these were all blanks.
Like you did least. Who just said,
I'm just going to go in,
I'm going to shoot someone.
And I'll say it was an action.
I thought it was thought it was blank.
I'll never know who all have the same gun.
They won't know it's from me.
And they would have to figure out who
shot the real bullets. Brandon Lee,
dude law and order, civil war, the
friendly leaking, right? Oh yeah.
That always scary. It's fucking
terrifying. They changed
the rules. Now you know,
because of that movie, you're not
allowed to point a gun at a person.
When you're in a gun scene
and you're shooting at them,
you're not allowed to shoot
a blank at the person.
You have to point away from them.
So like the props I just loaded in a real
bullet on accident. I don't think so.
I think there was something in
the casing that wasn't exploded.
Like there's something in,
it was like,
there was something stuck on the top
of it. I think that's what it was.
It was like sitting and acted as a
projectile and it shot him and it was a
really close range.
I think too.
I've thought about that and I've always
thought about that as like a horrible
way to go. And then I realized
I can't even get callbacks.
So I don't think being shot on
set is like an issue of mine yet.
Like you're not gonna be that picky. When
I was, when I first came to California,
it was like 1994 there was a guy who
I was working with whose friend had
committed suicide accidentally on a
set because they had a blank gun and he
didn't know that you could just put a
blank on up to your head and pull the
trigger. The camp no blows your
brains out with the fucking wow.
I never knew that.
We wouldn't have done it,
but he took this in front of everybody
and he's like, Hey, look at this. Boom.
And he fucking blows his brains out
the force and the air of wow. Wow.
What an awful way. He probably didn't
die. Right then he died, hemorrhage,
big hole in his head, went
down, started hemorrhaging.
They bring him to the hospital
dead. That's fucked up shit. Yeah.
That was on youtube. Do you ever see
the Budd Dwyer? Have you ever seen that?
But Dwyer was a, he was a politician.
Do you want to watch it? Yeah. God,
Budd Dwyer was a politician,
I believe it was in Pittsburgh,
and he was corrupt and
he got caught and he,
they called a press conference and he
pulls out a 44 magnum and the press
conference and blows his brains
online. Oh yeah. That's sad. No,
it's going to freak the fuck out.
Maybe we'll find out what you're made of.
If you're an ice princess, you might
just look at this and go, yeah.
Lisa Cell Phone Cam. Fuck
Budd Dwyer. Fuck yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry. It's not
about you right now.
Where's Greg? Is that him? Yeah,
it's like Alfred Hitchcock. Yes.
Words. Don Johnson. So he, uh,
he wants everybody in the room and he's
got an envelope. Yes. Oh yeah. Watch this.
Here.
He opens the envelope.
Where are you looking right here?
Look at this.
Great reminder that right for the moment.
He hands out some letters
and then he pulls out the gun.
Wants you to shit.
When I
rolled with it as well,
that
all
down Maddie,
please
don't Mag.
I almost started crying.
Someone called the ambulance.
Yeah, that wasn't cool. How would
you want to watch that? Yeah.
That was in the movies. There's not
even that much blood gushing out well,
but in the movies aren't really accurate,
but you would think a movie
would do more, right? Like what?
It's always exacerbated.
Everything's always bigger.
I've never seen blood gushed out
of someone's nose like that. Yeah.
That's horrendous. I'm so sad now.
Really. What bugs in a better place now?
Probably not. Maybe so. Probably
at the comedy store placement.
He's in the basement doing abortion,
so I hate he was pregnant at the time.
That's why it's terrible. So he
killed himself. Oh Connie. I know.
It's a trip to think that the spectrum
of human behaviors that that vast,
that there's people that their
life is so far beyond repair,
their brain is so fucked or
emotions are so fucking damaged.
Everything just so much pain.
They just want to stick a tube up metal
in their mouth and just end it all but
playing. That's one of this haunting
videos that will always be in my head,
that the woman getting hit
by the train is another one.
The Guy Getting fucked by the
horse. The guy. I'll watch that.
That will make me feel better.
Monkey pull up two guys.
One horse.com like here hurts now
cause the, cause I'm watching that oil.
The DOTCOM is, well this is what I was
talking about with this. The Movie Zoo.
Yeah. It's really, they really
change the law because of this.
So what happened was, I can't wait to
watch here. This guy died and then they,
they interrogated his friends and they
found out about this farm and they went
there and there was over a hundred
hours of video of guys getting fucked by
animals. Yeah. Well they don't show
it in the documentary at the moment.
The documentary is like, most of it
is like reenactments and you know,
kind of describing everything
that happened when it went down.
It's just so fascinating,
especially from the point of view of
the people who were they living there
because you know, these people were like
in love with animals. I mean they're,
they're really, there's something
going on that's not right.
This is the question before we saw this,
when whoever built this website
was like web mastering it.
Do you think it's fair to be
like, hey, hey cutie on the phone.
How do I get that Jpeg
of the horse running?
I can be really cute on this website. You
know what the pony is it from clip art?
Like what do I get this?
We put it auto compliment the horse
cock and really well from a website from
like 1986 the two of them on two of them.
Crazy horse cock jokes.
This is obvious. Okay, this is gonna be
fun to watch her face. I don't want to,
by the way,
this is why this is 100%
no, no. There's another guy. This is,
yeah, that's why it's two guys. One horse.
That's the guys are,
look how he's holding it to try
to keep it from going into far.
That's my favorite part.
Oh Jesus Christ. Joseph.
Yup. Look at that.
Do you have any say in it too much?
It doesn't test now.
That's a horse day
and that kills him right there.
Listen to this.
Oh God, he was there.
They were saying he came,
he came. They were like all
excited that the horse came.
How vial that killed that guy?
Yeah. The guy who was in that video,
it was a guy that used to go by the name
of Mr Hands. Don't drop. You can do,
you can do this.
Eliza,
you got through the whole last
comic standing really hot and like,
what are you doing Bryan? I was trying
to cheer her up with Lemon parties.
What? Blue waffle dubois boy blue. No,
blue off blue buffalo documentary just
blew off. Why don't you Google that shit?
It's like the 20th image down. You
have to ingest it. She's really good.
The picture. Oh my God. I'm Google images.
Blue waffle
can even call it a vagina.
That's Photoshop Vagina.
I think some girls with their vagina
get that out of him. Looks like no,
that's not out of hand.
That looks like the Predator
got in a car accident
and then drown and then drowned.
I wonder if I can ever jerk off to
that picture if I really tried hard.
If you had to, if you only have
to come like a little dribble,
you could probably pull out. Yeah,
you can. Yeah, you can. Yeah. You can.
If you're not turned on. I mean you
can't control it like consciously, but,
but factors that'll how hard your cause
more comes more for guys barely turned
on. You like it? Bull bull
challenge this. No, with snow it's,
it's a fact. If a guy's
not turned on, if you're,
you're jerking off to a picture
of a fucking disease vagina,
you're not going to get a full of wax.
It's going to be like not going to get a
full much come as you would if you were
super turned on. No, no, no, no, no, no.
Do it flow. I can show you. Show you.
He'll fuck you and
everything's going to work out.
This is all been a plot by
Brian. Look, see, watch.
Brian don't do this is disrespectful.
She's a girl.
You can't do that. This
kid, that's not cool.
For the folks listening on Itunes,
Brian just pulled out a big rubber penis,
which you can't do on a movie set.
Brian, we're where we're number three,
number seven and number 29 in the top 30
podcast. Did you get that email? Yeah,
that's pretty sweet. We're just
all their episode loaded episodes.
So everybody that's tuning into podcast,
thank you very much and thanks for all
the positive emails and twitters and it's,
this is a lot of fun to do and we enjoy
doing it and we enjoy having people like
a wiser come on. Very polite dog. No,
we're going to keep this
rolling and we said time, no,
I just wanted to say thank you to
people who have to wait till the end.
If somebody said,
oh I don't know what people are tweeting
you back because I said something about
Saskatchewan, I'll back it up. Don't
just don't listen to them. You can't,
you can't be this
connected machines control.
You can machines could trailing you man.
That was a good way to,
the good way to come back. It is
a good way to connect, you know,
just don't want to connect all the time
because then you're get to eventually
it's going to,
they're going to invade all aspects of
your personal robots will take over. Well,
who's going to be some
sort of a, you know, hey,
you know a camera where you can see two V,
two views,
the view of you and the view that you
see of the world and you can choose,
share these views with people.
That's what's going to happen.
You're going to have your own little
fucking Internet TV channel and it's your
life and you know people.
Some people let them see everything.
You'll look straight.
You can see out when I'm washing myself,
but you can't see back.
You can't see me naked.
Like people would draw the line at
which cameras are going to keep on.
Really someone's taking showers and shit
with cameras on them and move around
the house.
It's called something like she's Roulette
Chevorlet oh, that's totally different.
That's dudes pulling their dicks out.
What's why it's chat. Realizing they,
I'm uncomfortable with my step mom
was telling me about this solid black.
She goes, she goes and I went
on to Emily's, my stepsister,
one of Natalie's computer and I could
see her on her friend's looking and I
didn't know what they were looking
at and I went in their room,
they were on chat roulette and they
were looking at some guy's cock cock,
no reason. She was like, it was just
a big cock and I was like, yeah,
I think half a chat roulette is that.
I've never seen, I don't know what,
I've never,
what's cool is they have an iPhone
version and that was one that that's a few
people to download and
save a bit about this.
How was one of the few people to download
it and then they pulled it off the
iTunes store so you can't
download it anymore.
There's like a good 20,000 people that
downloaded that APP that's still use it
because it's still works, but now
it's, but now there's no new people,
so you're just start recognizing
penises like, oh, here's Jim again. Yep.
Is that his wife in the
background when they pull it,
they can't take it off your phone. Like
it will still work. It will still work.
Damn well how come? No one's figured
out a way to get it back to the phone?
I don't know cause I'm just
getting everybody's fighting.
Tired of looking at the same cop
that if you ever done that facetime
thing where you have to talk. How's that?
Was that facetime and see if you had an
iPhone you could call me and do video
video. Yeah, I think it did. Yeah.
Cause can you do hit it each time?
Do you have to have a Wifi
connection now? Uh, yeah. Yeah.
You have to have a wifi connection
and showed that t mobile phone,
the new one that doesn't have wifi but it
has the four g or whatever it's called.
I don't think, I don't know if it'll
work in anything other than apple phones.
But what has this two way video chat?
I think it only works apple.
I think you've got Skype now.
If you have Skype video now,
just groups released on the
Skype video. So you can do the
same thing as this. Yeah. And it's,
that would be more universal. Skype video
is actually three g two. It's not Wifi,
uh, Skype video. So the jerking
off his back on back on,
is that what it is? A lot of that.
A lot of two way jerking off.
Is there a way to record it?
Oh,
somebody secretly record Brett Farve Dick
was to 8 trillion off totally theirs.
I don't think it's his dick. No. Why
you say that? Because I mean it was
maybe after he had um,
practice when he was really tired.
He gets it up.
Do you have imagined you could imagine
a different, right. I have in my dreams.
How would you imagine Brett farms cock
to be like a wolf shoulder pads and warp
radiator cock?
He liked to think of your superheroes
is having superior wiener is kind of a
trip when you see a dude with gray hair
out there playing professional football
and log.
Really what the hell is going on here?
What's going on? How are you doing
this? How are you playing old though?
He just has gray hair. He's 40 something
old for a professional football player,
it's the magic white is balls look like.
Nope.
There's lots of old people in athletics
that are able to compete somehow or
another after age 40 there's not
that many. It's pretty fucking small.
Yes. Quarterbacks. They're not as known
as impact as a quarterback and linebacker.
They're getting nailed on the
as often as like a bigger guy.
But when they get nailed
that getting the extra hard,
cause they are like a little bonus,
you know, take out the quarterback.
People get very excited to do that.
And the quarter in fact jail. Yes.
You know they're going to
change football though folks.
They're gonna put fucking centers in
Canton. Their helmets, they're to,
they're going to find out what kind of
impact people get. Crest has let me style.
Oh I thought you meant so.
They could have cursed my belief it
like if they were hearing it from their
point of view,
like I'm wondering if football,
the football has a real
issue with head injuries.
A lot of these guys are getting like
really massive brain damage and then as
they're older men, they're just fucked
up. They would get Lou Gehrig's disease.
They have all of these issues. They
eventually become paralyzed. Some of them,
their body just just eventually shuts
down and it's from continued head trauma
or smashing their head into
these fucking helmets. And so a,
they're going to start making them wear
these sensors that detect what kind of
impact they get.
And they do it for hockey because they're
probably not more body and on hockey
they slam into each other and everybody's
slides around too. You know, it's like,
it's probably better to be on ice when
you're slamming into each other because
even though they hit you really hard,
there's a little, there's, it's slippery.
You not dug into the ground like you
are like in a football field where it's
dirt and you're running
and you're running a,
they'd absorbed saying guess more
impact in packets it stationary. Yeah.
I just feel like you would move.
I mean that's why like hockey
fights don't seem as dangerous.
I mean sometimes guys get fucked
up and hockey fights. I saw guy,
but it's his own helmet. Oh, that's not
right. It's an accident. But it happened.
That's the Douchey move, you know, hockey
fight, everybody knows he puts the,
take the gloves off and you
circle and then he'd go at it.
You don't be hitting people with their
fucking helmet. That's this week. Shit.
There's nothing worse.
I will say this,
I just remember playing
sports in high school.
There's nothing worse than
when you aim to hurt someone,
but you accidentally hurt them in a way
you didn't intend to and it looks more
aggressive than you meant and
that's when you're like, that's,
I didn't mean to punch her in the mouth.
I meant for it and it was an
accident and it gets caught.
And so you are like a super
competitive person. You're,
you're there throwing in cheap shots.
Did you throw cheap shots on girls
in Lacrosse? A lot of yellow cars.
Oh my nickname.
You one of my Nigga was butcher because
I was defense and I took it very serious.
Oh, you're mean. So you would
just hit them with their sticks,
hit them with the sticks and shit really,
as opposed to not do it anyway. Right.
A little love tap.
He hit him with a stick.
Like I was hitting bitches with
sticks, man. She was playing Lacrosse.
He was hitting chicks
with sticks from Texas.
They don't like one of my worst memories
from high school. I got a red card.
You know what? You would be into
union. You would be into martial arts.
Have you ever done any martial arts?
You are so aggressive.
That would be such a good thing for you.
I would love to take something just
so I could back. Like when, uh,
when it's something like a girl
is a bitch and a nightclub,
I would be able to back up
my shit talking. Well, you
don't want to fight. No,
but I feel confident enough it'll,
it'll be better because you won't be
worried about it ever get in a fight.
But I would like that confidence
to know that I could handle it.
I just mean for just getting all
this energy out of you. Like in,
you mean the elliptical 20 minutes
a day isn't going to do it.
It's not going to do it. No. You need to
hit something. You need to hit something.
Where should I go? Well, I'll, we'll
talk afterwards. Tell me where,
where you live because you don't
want to tell these fucking freaks.
These online people are listening.
No, but can I tell you something? Yes.
Speaking of where you live,
somebody sent this to me.
I'll give you the address right now.
Somebody sent this to me.
There was a website you can go to and it's
probably a bunch of these. Here it is.
It's called
spokeo.com s p o k e o.com and you can
type in your name and your name will come
up where you live. Don't say this.
No, no. You can block yourself.
I took myself off of it this morning.
That's what I'm telling you. Anyone,
they'll tell you how much your house is
worth. Let's talk about this letter. No,
people should take themselves off
if people are going to find you.
If they want to find you. Oh
yeah, it's 2010, 11 nine stone.
But you should use your block yourself.
Yeah. You shouldn't promote this.
I was pissed and I said my house
was worth less than it was. Yeah.
So don't tell me where you live on
the air, but afterwards, um, I'll,
I'll find a place.
That scenario,
I don't want to get kicked in the shins
or hitting the boob or in the mouth.
You have protection for all
of those things done. But uh,
really the best thing for a girl to learn
his Jiu Jitsu because Ju Jitsu is not
really reliant on strength.
It's really more reliant on technique.
So you could actually subdue a man.
Like you could choke a man like Dan,
my friend Felicia,
she weighs about 130 pounds and
she fucks men up all the time.
She's a black belt. And the men,
it's so frustrating for men.
There's nothing they can do. Two pressure
points. No, it's just, it's technique.
It's chokes and arm locks and stuff
like that. But when you do it correctly,
so if you get attacked by rapists,
he will grab him and throw him on the
ground and start rolling around with him.
I want to learn small joint manipulation.
That shit doesn't work. Yeah.
No Dude's will let you break.
Their fingers are still punching the face.
It doesn't work. Believe me,
when adrenaline's flowing,
you're not even going to feel that finger.
Oh,
was not for fights and
still just being annoying.
It doesn't really work where it pulled
her hand away. Went fucking handbag. No.
That's why you have to be smart.
I only pick on people weaker than me.
When we get that you or your friends see
you pull them into your web and break
their fingers. So fucking
some weird maneuver. See,
you're a competitive person and this is
like, it's all natural and it's just,
it'll help you so much if you just fucking
punch at a heavy bag or do a Jujitsu
class, like it'd be so much
more relaxed. I would love to.
I would love to take something
like that. It's fun. It's fun. I,
that's not a thing you have you
ever tried yoga? I have done yoga.
I like to move and that's very, I don't
enjoy meditating and stuff like that.
That's very hard. Right, but
is not just in meditation.
It's just the ability to, to relax in
these really uncomfortable positions.
Strength Them. It's good for you though,
is good for you. You can. There's other,
I do it rarely though. I
talk a lot of shit, but I,
if I take one yoga class a month,
it's a lot. I do it when on my own,
like before shows, I always do it.
It helps you warm up, stretch out,
relax my body. I think green tea, green
tea and massages now just green tea. Okay.
Does it energize?
Got Some caffeine in I think,
but I don't think it's like as much
as a cup of coffee or anything.
I think it's less than that, but it's
probably healthier for you. You know?
It's a shit. You're a [inaudible].
You ever heard that? Yeah.
You'd be throw some honey in there.
It's a interesting t because it gives
you a different kind of stimulant.
It's different than the caffeine. Sort of
a coffee stimulant is a little clearer.
Little clearheaded.
It's not as buzzy.
It's not as fucking now it's called
fuck around and start a business.
I made some fucked up decisions,
high out coffee because coffee
will get you motivated to do shit.
I fought in a tournament
once when I was a kid.
I was delivering newspapers and I was,
I had been injured and I wasn't training
and I decided that day of that I was
going to fight the tournament after I
ate two donuts and drank a big cup of
coffee and I was fucking wired
and I'm like, I want a cool fight.
And so I entered into this tournament
just because a coffee. Totally. Yeah.
I don't one of want to be in
like really big tournament.
For me it was a u s open.
I drink a red bull before I go on an age
VCO taekwondo, I was a high
window. You guys open. It was a,
I would have never even fought.
And if it wasn't for the coffee,
coffee just had me so convinced
that it was a fun thing to do.
Let's go fucking do this and coffee. Well,
back then I was competing, so it was,
it was really the only reason why I wasn't
going to fight in a tournament that I
had an injury.
But the injury,
like it kind of healed itself over the
week that I had off and just too fucking
Boston cream donuts,
which is like,
who knows how many and sang
grams of sugars in there
and a giant thing of Dunkin
donuts coffee, one of those big ones,
like a 16 ouncers crap. Your brains out,
explosions household just
opens up and it just,
just the way it comes out to, it's
so easy. It just all comes out. Yeah.
You know what sucks on, it's kind
of on the same thing. Uh, I, uh,
did one of those things where you go
to the bathroom before you get in the
shower, you don't flush the toilet
because you don't want it. The shower,
did she use that water? And I left it
there. My cat has been drinking out.
Fuck up.
Wait,
can I tell you something
there that doesn't do a lot
of houses aren't made that
way anymore. What? Oh yeah.
Well, I'm not fancy mic.
Fancy person. My building's old. I'm just
saying like, that doesn't always happen.
You might want to flush. No, no, let
go. And I flushed. It changes though.
The water everywhere at my house. The
whole water, the water's freezing.
Freezing like 45 seconds minute.
That's ridiculous.
Oh yeah.
I live in a old ass fucking engineering
house. That's some polio. Yeah.
Anyways, the cat got in it and
I don't know what happened,
but it came outside and there's
just like Paul Shit everywhere.
She's so then I didn't have anything
to clean it up with except Windex and
pledge
shit.
It smells better, you know,
it's so I squirted on there.
The Windex actually cleaned a lot,
but then the next day I was just like
looking at my floor and he's a little
white dots everywhere on the floor and
you can see it looks like a cat ghost
walked, you know, like,
oh, that's disgusting.
It's awful.
Yeah.
There's nothing quite like a Turd that
you forget about and then you come back
to it the next day. Oh
that's, you have to flush it.
And it had been sitting there stewing.
You took a shit while you're on the phone.
He didn't want to the person to hear
the flushing and the background to know
you're a human.
I take so many dumps them on the phone,
so I take some of my
best phone conversation.
Have you ever had your
girlfriend or wife or whatever?
Like I had like two months ago,
walked in and she forgot to
flush and had one of those,
like what I was looking at
her and was like inevitable,
huge Joey Dee and shit.
It's inevitable. I hate that. Why are we
talking about poop? People drop logs, son.
It's a part of life. That's what my
daughter talks about. I call it now,
she's two and a half. She calls it drop
his log because they keep telling me,
did you drop it? Log you drop a log in
your body that got them dropping. Lars,
when kids find out what's
funny and what makes you laugh,
they just repeated over and over again.
So she has her own account comics. Yeah,
very similar.
Really the same thing.
Is that a fucked up thing when someone
goes to see you and you know they're
going to see the same show like the
next night? Just want to be like,
as I'm telling the joke, we were like,
and you probably, as I'm saying it,
I want to stop and be like, look, I
know you know where I'm going to say,
but if you could just be
quiet for everyone else,
she'll sit on your lap. Yeah,
that's a weird, like I've, I've talked
to people before shows. I go, dude,
we love you so much for coming. See you
every night that you have shows like,
Yikes,
what we've got to open every show totally
different and it makes my material up
and fucker can't tell the same jokes
over and over again with the same timing.
It takes a long ass time of repeating
a joke too to get it effortless to the
point where it looks like you're
thinking it up out in the moment and when
someone sees behind the curtain like that
two nights in a row, it's, it's weird.
I've had people yell out a
punchline before, oh that's brutal.
You get so nervous to take that pause
that you need for whatever your joke is
just for timing sake. And then they're
like goats and you're like, yeah,
that's a such a douchey move in PR.
The problem is with with youtube,
like your material gets online, it takes
like a long ass time to develop it. Joke.
People don't know.
It starts off,
starts off as like it's something funny
in this or something funny in this,
right?
I mean that's how I always started out.
Like what the fuck is funny in this?
There's something funny in this and
that a lot of times I'll have a bunch of
different ideas, different ways
to go that I've written out, but,
but it takes a long ass time to figure
out which way I'm going to go with it.
I have to do it over and
over and over again. So for,
if someone gets a hold of it,
like in that process and then puts it
up on youtube and then everybody watches
it and then they come to the show and
they yell out your punch line. Yeah,
it just doubled. Triple fucked you.
They're not doing it to be dicks.
Like they're so excited to be
there. Yeah. There's a lot of that.
And there's some people that are just
douche bags and they fuck up everything
they touch and they just can't help
them. They are, man. That's true.
You can get some toxic people.
People come up to me after and they'll
reference a joke I did not 20 minutes
earlier and I take myself so seriously.
I won't realize that they're
referencing it and I'll be like,
I have a bit about that. They're like, I
know. That's why I just talked about that.
I'm like, oh right. Do you guys want to
tee shirt? That's funny. You sell merge?
Yeah. What is your t shirt say? I have a
bunch of them. Do you have any sexy ones?
You have the Grey Cup on stuff that I
don't should do that dude by that do what?
Daisy Duke back from the old
dukes of Hazzard days. Oh yeah.
Get a tee shirt with my face on it.
If you go to my Facebook page,
you can see my album cover.
It's not sexy, but there's many,
cause he's got some glamour shots online.
I saw some cover your album
cover. It's super, super,
super glamour shot.
I mean it was supposed to be like an
eighties glamour shot thing as to what
exactly it looks at it. It's
so, no, that's not the one
I'm talking about. Oh yeah,
I like that. That's how powerful
I like that. Eliza alive. Jesus.
Your CD this out right now. Yeah, it's on
iTunes. You can get it on Itunes, iTunes,
the DVDs coming out. If you're
anti-apple where else can they get it?
Can they get it on Amazon? Your
website, [inaudible] dot com powerful.
Do you actually sell it as a physical
CD or do you have them printed?
I just got him. Isn't it crazy that
those students still exist? Yeah.
You know what I saw is it called a drop
card? Do you know what this is? No.
My friend showed this to me.
It's a car.
You pay me for the CDI give you this
card and it's so you take it home and you
download it with a code. So it was like a
free download, that gift card drop card.
That's cool. That is cool.
You know? Do you think,
I mean it's only a matter of time before
a solid state media just disappears.
Right? Like actual physical media, like
a physical DVD or a physical, right?
No, and I don't buy cds anymore. I
stopped. I just, everything on Itunes,
I just buy him to use it to snort
cocaine, cocaine off. So bad ass, dude.
You know what I love when,
when I'm in a fucking,
like there was a song the other day,
I couldn't figure out who it was.
And so I put up that Shizam thing.
Oh, I have that. Yeah. There's a,
if there were folks who don't know,
it's a program that lets you a your plate.
There's a music playing in the background.
You,
you press Shizam it listens to the music,
sends the information now
tells you who sung the song,
what the song's title is in [inaudible]
she has you will a link that you could
buy it on iTunes right
there and going to play it.
You can play it right there too.
You can play it.
Just press play and it's playing on
your phone. It's fucking incredible.
And it's called [inaudible] and I've
just been buying songs like that and just
add them to my iPhone. This all but I love
the song. Bam. Is there a way on apple,
like an apple on iTunes?
Like when I download music to work out,
I always like to do like top
40 like what's on the radio.
Is there where you can search on Itunes,
like top 40 hip hop songs and it'll bring
it off? Yeah, yeah, absolutely. Probably.
Yeah.
Well,
all you have to do is to look at it looked
like the top 10 lists and stuff like
that. You know, like maybe like just in
hip hop. I don't want like billboard.
I want absolutely. You were into hip
hop. What kind of laptop do you like?
Do you like old shit? Like Gangstarr
uh, thanks. I did. It depends.
Any one hit wonder within the realm of
hip hop, rnb or rap for the last 15 years.
I know, right? I'm more of a radio
part. I love the radiant word.
Have you ever heard of Dmard? [inaudible]
you haven't heard of the yards?
The best throw on the, uh, the video dude.
The fucking and, okay. What
does that first phase? Yeah.
No, no, no. The first video,
the first video that, that, that
launched them. I'm an angel. No,
it's not on my Ninja. The next one. Is
that funny? Yeah, it's a trip. Yeah,
it's awesome. Um, dirty.
We always overdo this video, but it's
so good. Yeah. Put on the deaf side one.
She's got to see this shit.
Yeah. Check this shit out.
That's my mom passed. Go full screen.
It's going to be a guy shooting himself.
It's going to race that.
Okay. Well not easy.
I think this with his granny and then I
lived with my mom and dad down the road.
And then you land lives
Africans for how long? The
whole time. Since we are small.
And you decided to do this, why is
this recent? Well he died. He's got,
he owns a cheesy shit.
Okay.
Makes that next level of
beats and basically like I
got some serious lag. Gags.
The skill, you know in the
mock? Yeah. Yeah. Are they
being serious? I'll fuck you.
Here we go.
Yeah. Dj Hot deck did up the
mother fucking beat box dog.
Bring that next level shit.
Yeah.
What about be so quick suboptimal.
This pops up.
You'll feel
that I need to bring light to be static.
Stepped off the box.
Digital Zone.
I'm scoping probing Mondo three last week
when I see things on the ship going to
teach today. Can I touch you friend?
Come on. This is a trip, Aisha.
You've ever seen? Awesome.
These guys are the shit person made
the video knows what the fuck her fuck.
Yeah they do. It's so awesome to
be a joke. No, it's not a giant,
a bad ass band. I met them. They came
alive. Yeah, they're bad ass man.
Good. She says cause
like some hipster shit.
Oh No, you're kidding. I love
them. They're fucking bad ass.
They have a bunch of bad ass
songs. Yeah. Tough accent.
What kind of rap do you like? All
the top 40 shit. What do you like?
I just like whatever is on the right.
Whatever's on a hip hop station right now.
I know. Wow. I just like
rap and hip hop. Oh, okay.
Whatever's on that.
Can she only no radio edits of songs?
I don't know if there's a curse word.
I don't know what cause
that's the only kind of music
you listen to really.
I'm in the car lot.
It's an excuse.
Like in the car you can only get top 40
you never know who's listening. Ipod,
I don't like listening to it unless I'm
working out. So I only like fast songs.
I can work out to my girl talk
or something. I don't know.
I've been hearing a lot of people,
the girl talks could, yeah.
I haven't been hearing a lot of people
saying that the podcast is the best for
working out nowadays because it's,
he's like,
you're not getting lost in
music and board. You know,
cause I always stop and take it out
and switch it if it's a bad song.
Right around your workout.
I got a lot of Twitter messages from
dudes listen to us when they're doing the
workouts and driving to a lot of driving
people. Yeah. I cannot listen to music.
I couldn't listen to someone talk really.
I've listened to a bunch of lectures
and I've listened to a few podcasts too.
I listen to a cool Graham Hancock podcast
recently that was listening to that
while I was driving around.
So be able to focus off it over the sound
of my heart bursting out of my chest
while I run. So you can only
listen to music as I was saying.
Yeah, I see what you're saying
when you're working out. Yeah.
You know what else works that
I found this out two days ago.
I was at the gym and I have the
TVS attached to the treadmill.
They won't like the nature channel and
I was watching a cheetah run down a
gazelle and they slowed it down and I got
so into it cause you don't know what's
going to happen.
And I found myself going faster
watching this cheetah and it was super
animalistic and he got him in
the end and I was happy for him.
I felt bad for the,
for the antelope
that antelope had to die eventually.
Yeah.
Like he's going to live forever and
cure cancer. You don't know that.
I know those antelopes. They never
give a shit. They just welfare.
They eat and poop. That's all they do.
Nothing gets done in the antelope world,
just running around, running from
Cheetahs and shit. There's just run.
It was a rush on that.
Did you see that video that someone
put on line of a African hunters like
recent? Within the last
50 60 years. I got the,
I believe it's a video from the
60s of a hunting with spears,
hunting elephants and hippos with spears.
Oh Dude,
it is a fucking rat.
I don't want to see hippos.
I to stagers animal in the animal kingdom.
You know they're giant pigs.
I did not know that. Yeah. Hippos.
Hippos are in the pig family.
They're giant fucking mean.
Pigs eat people are they fucking
warriors of the videos of,
I don't know what the name of the
warriors are because they know they were
wearing a merit like they're wearing
like t shirts and shit cause we gave them
to them probably. Yeah. Yeah. We gave
them to them in exchange for filming them.
Fucking up these hippos shit spears.
If you want to find it good.
Go to twitter.com/joe Rogan.
This thing was recorded on January 4th.
Um,
and so I'm pretty sure I put it
up on January 3rd. You should.
You should check it out cause it's
a trip. It's, it's so hard to watch.
It's really freaky cause they think they,
it takes a long ass time to kill
an elephant with spears. Sure.
I had it sounds off and they all like,
they all work together.
Like the whole tribe, we'll work
together to take down these animals.
So they have like,
you know,
literally thousands of people circling
these and they're choking them off.
They make this big circle and then they
forced the animals into the center and
then they spear him to death.
I guess they gotta eat.
You gotta eat and there's no other
way to do it. You know, they have,
they have no options. It just go to the
store. I think it would just devolve.
Why don't you have electricity yet?
You're so stupid.
It's amazing that they really are still
living the way they lived thousands of
years ago.
I went to Africa a couple of times when
we went on a safari and you get to like
hang out with the mass. I wars and
like see how they live and like,
obviously you pay them and they give you
a tour and a little bit of it's fake.
But there's like sanctions,
like in the Serengeti,
they can't go around killing like lions
and stuff so they have to eat like
normal, like they can't do it. Like you
have to be a super rural tribe to do that.
Like a lot of them,
even though they live in that land,
they're not allowed to kill the animals
cause so the ones that are super rural,
they are allowed to,
there's no one like regulating that.
But like closer to like where like
the capitals or wherever we were,
we're more tourists go wow. They're not
allowed to do. There's a great story,
not a great story, but a fascinating,
a terrible story. Terrible story.
There was a guy who was on safari and he
was in the shower and two lions came in
and killed them and dragged him out
of the shower. Wow. That is terrible.
Fucking imagine taking a
shower. What? You know what man?
He's on some safari on a hunting safari.
It was,
we saw that movie hangover movie
hangover when he walked into the,
there's a tiger in the bathroom. Yeah,
it's totally the same time. Totally is.
You say, Hey, what are you
doing there? And then they go,
you gotta be real calm about, hey,
what are you doing there? That guy,
that's the guy that's seen a lot of
bears. That's so funny. That was me.
You would see dripping from the pis coming
out of my ankles long for the fucking
bear. Got to where he was. I would be
ranting. I was a on that bear's head. Jo,
have you seen these helmets
that these motorcycle jacket
guys? Uh, where nowadays,
like my friend,
he took off his helmet and it had like
this big glass part over it and he was
just put it up and they had like the
sunglass thing that it goes, you know,
it comes down,
it opens that up and he's just
blaring his iPhone music and I'm like,
what is that? He, the whole thing is like
a Bluetooth Stereo cone. Like he says,
he puts it on God. Then what? What
happens if he can't hear fucking
thing? It's like, he's like, it's like
being in Tron. He's like, you're just,
that guy is crazy. Yeah, it's
a helmet. It's cutting out.
One of his sense is I took a photo of it.
That's the legal,
their iPod on your
earphones on and your car.
So I can't believe that would be legal.
Yeah.
Doesn't make any sense because first
of all, you have to wear a seatbelt,
but fucking motorcycles don't have
any seat belts. It's impossible.
Should check why that's the
worst thing that could happen.
And it's stuck on the bike. Is that things
rolling and tumbling and fuck. Yeah.
Better. If you can slide. If you can lay
the bike down and you just skid, you know,
if you have the right clothing on,
if you know how to ride a bike,
maybe like a CD, it
could be tethered, doc.
You don't lose it would you just don't
want to get run over by your own bike and
pinned underneath it. Smashed and have
it fall on top of you a bunch of times.
Over and over. Yeah, put down a hill.
Motorcycle accidents are some scary shit,
man.
It's like trine and see this the same
Bluetooth thing that a answer calls turn
up the volume. That's so insane. Cause
take your hand off the fucking motorcycle,
right. Handles and presses. Stupid Button.
Fiddle with it on the side of your head.
Guarantee you someone's going to die
because they're trying to make a call and
it's fucking piece of shit and
I ain't ringing. Oh my God,
that's a horrible idea.
That's ridiculous.
People are crazy motherfuckers.
You know it has to be a trip though.
The one like 120 miles an hour while
you're blaring led Zepplin and your high
high on se survive.
It must be the shit.
But I mean you've got to be a reckless
motherfucker to want to do that.
That's like only appeals
to people with Toxoplasma.
That's like a hundred percent
toxoplasma activity. What's that?
What's that cat parasite thing?
You ever heard of this fucking,
we talk about it way
too much of the podcast.
I apologize everybody who
has to hear this again,
but there's a crazy cat parasite that
affects human beings and makes them more
reckless and makes him reckless.
It makes a women more sexually promiscuous
and make some more, more planning.
I would get it from cats.
People get it from touching cat feces
or being around fields where cats and
something happens and they
touch the, the, you know,
the cat feces in a field and
she get it from eating cat.
Yes. She can get it. Yeah,
definitely. And you have to,
especially a cat that shit's outside.
Those are the cats that are dangerous.
And this is what happens.
A rat gets it and it affects the rat.
And what it makes the rat do is it makes
the rat sexually attracted to the smell
of cat piss.
So the rat start following where the
cats live and like want to be around the
cats so that it could easily get killed.
And then they would transfer it to the
cat and the cat's transfer it to people.
It's really sad. Yeah. And
people transferred back to
rats. It for recreation, not
possible to cure. Yes. But here's
where it gets crazy. Huge whore.
Well for women and makes you do that.
And for men it makes you much more
aggressive and reckless. And it's,
they say it slows your
reaction time down too.
So it was just like a bunch of juice
heads and hookers that was like in Miami
nightclub. It's like Brazil. Brazil
is 66% infected with toxoplasma.
Very good look like literally. And
Yeah, the love to fucking love to fight.
I mean it literally defines the culture.
I don't know if they were doing that.
Anyway, this is a thing that's
been around for a long time. Yeah.
Well that's one of the things.
It's connected to places where people
have a lot of wild cats. Wow. Yeah.
It's directly connected and it is an
incurable parasite that changes human
behavior and it's a fact.
It's not a conspiracy theory.
This is a legitimate mainstream fact.
It's so strange.
I know people that don't have that,
that act that way. So you might have,
it might have. So it could be a learned
behavior after people that have,
there's a whole lot of factors in cash.
Baggery that's a good question.
I don't know.
I don't know if he could pass to kids
illegal think somehow or another they
would have to get cat shit. If you want
your kid make the football team, why?
Don't know if it works that way.
But one of the things they found out
within men was that the, there was a, um,
a disproportionate amount of people,
um, like when they had, um, uh,
soccer teams that would
compete in the World Cup.
The teams that made it to the finals all
had high rates of Toxoplasma in their
countries. And they think that this,
the recklessness of this bacteria,
like what it does,
it makes you like disregard like a,
your safety and do reckless shit.
I get disproportionate number of people
who crash it on motorcycles are infected
with toxo plasma.
And so they,
they connect it to the connected
it to successful soccer teams.
And there's like a real debate about this.
And it may be one of the reasons why
these teams are so successful at soccer.
They're so aggressive and crazy as it
because they're infected by Toxoplasma.
Because a lot of, um, a lot
of athletes from Brazil,
a lot of athletes from a lot of
south American countries, poor area,
a lot of wildcats are 50 or 50
million Americans are in fact it.
Wow. Yeah, it's pretty crazy. It's the
current piece, which is like an alien.
It's like an alien that's
rewiring our brains. That's
awesome. It's fucking crazy.
Pretty soon we're going to start making
pyramids. Watch. That's what it is.
Imagine it was like some kind of
thing that gets you all, well,
if there's a little parasite,
parasites evolve, right? If
you believe in evolution,
you believe they weren't exactly this
way the whole time they became what they
are now.
Everything became what it is now and
evolve from something to something else.
Something new parasite that
evolves. I mean HIV, right.
When remember when aids came around,
there was something that came and
there's just some new shit. Yeah.
You hear about that guy that got
cured with aids. You got stem cells.
These stem cells and then cured is HIV.
It disappeared.
Where Jamba juice at?
Jamba juice. The good idea.
And how come this isn't in the news? Uh,
it is. Yeah, it isn't. It isn't like damn.
It's really recent. Like a month
ago. Three weeks ago. Yeah.
He's actually been cured of HIV using
stem cells like it was, I don't know.
I don't know the details on it,
but it's pretty much been accepted that
they figured out how it slacking on your
aids research.
There's a cure for cancer and it's
in Mexico at a clinic give you,
they give you weed and
what isn't. Yeah. There's,
there's some things that they're willing
to do in Mexico, they'd probably work.
There's a lot of people that have
said that, um, blood transfusions,
like full blood transfusions and,
and other treatments they do to blood.
It was a bunch of different treatments
that are willing to do in Mexico.
I think I'd be willing to die before I'd
be willing to let a Mexican doctor with
no sterilization putting a needle in me.
I know dudes have gone to Mexico for
surgery because my many fighters,
no MMA fighters, they're
um, they're cheap.
Are you friends with a bunch
of MMA fighters? Like I know
that some of them, yeah.
Yeah. Cool. Train. Yeah. Train. Yeah.
How do they feel about getting
hit in the face so much? Well,
I'm the smart ones know that it's just a,
you got to limit the amount
of times you get hit.
It's very important to use defense first.
It'd be very smart about why,
but you know, they also know that there's
some flights we're just getting nailed,
you know,
it's just nothing you can do about it.
Then you're talking about
about football earlier.
I mean I don't think like octagon fighting
has been and all that stuff has been
around or as popular as long as football.
So are they going to be the
same as football players?
Like are they going to end up with poor
Gehrig's disease and depends on their
style.
It depends on when they get out.
Depends on how much punishment they take
at the end of their career because the
end of the career is where
guys get really beat up.
That's what happened with Muhammad Ali
happens with a lot of fighters say the
reaction time slows. They don't
know when to get out of the game.
And then they take some fights
that they probably shouldn't take.
And then they get some,
they get some serious injuries
and they don't know when to quit.
And they keep going. And those are the
guys that wind up in real big trouble,
in my opinion,
is a Lou Gehrig's disease.
It doesn't mean it's a Nate and
it just triggers later, you know,
Louis Lou Gehrig's disease can,
it can be triggered later.
It can be something that just happens to
you, but it also can be trauma induced.
Okay. So it can be, you know, there's,
there's a bunch of different ways,
like Stephen Hawking's has Lou
Gehrig's disease and I don't,
I don't think that he was,
he might've been,
I might've played soccer or
something like that. Who knows.
I'm a fighter before he found the books
before he found all that study. And then,
but um,
w what happens is when guys get a
lot of repeated brain injuries there,
their brains start producing like
defective proteins and they're,
they're,
they're literally their body just like
eventually just shuts down and just stops
working. It starts like misfiring
left and right. It could just really,
really creepy how come on I watch and,
and they fighting,
they look like they take
breaks simultaneously.
Like when they're like in this headline,
it looks like they're almost taking
a rest. Is that like a code? Like,
I'm going to take a two second breather,
right? Don't hit me while I'm doing this.
Well, if you're tired and you sense it,
the other guy's tired and he's not moving,
you might do that.
It might take a little break then
wouldn't it as an as a killer?
Wouldn't it be like that was when we go,
ugh.
But you might be willing to forego that
just for a couple seconds of recovery if
you think you're going to make
another big explosion. Right?
You met something timed out, you
know, you're like, all right,
does a minute and a half left in this
round? I'm taking this mother fucker down,
but right now I'm gonna tell you a little
break. Do they ever talk to each other?
Sometimes we talked shifts.
Oh,
sometimes the one time that was the
weirdest one was his dude war machines
fighting this Guy Jay Rock and uh,
Jay Rock and war machine became really
good friends on the ultimate fighter.
And then they had a fight each
other. I mean, really good friends.
And it was a fucking war,
a bloody horrible war where they were
talking to each other while I was going.
I'm like, fuck man. It fucking
hurt. Like, yeah, sorry dude.
Like saying shit like that while while
they're fighting, it was really crazy.
And then it's a mind fuck. And yeah, and
then at the end when it was all over,
they were super emotional and crying
and hugging each other. It was,
it was hockey player raising
fight each other. I mean, I guess,
I don't think it was like this,
not like 15 fucking minutes of beaten the
shit out of each other is not the same
thing. Those hockey fights, they can't
get that traction, you know? And it was a,
it was a vicious fight in an ended with
a brutal Tko and there's was like crazy.
Like it was, it was so charged with
emotion, you know? And then when he,
when I interviewed him
after the fight was over,
he was crying and talking about how
hard it was and what they were saying to
each other, why they were in there. And
I was like, Whoa, that's got, oh yeah,
that's fucked up. You know? If
it was like a thousand years ago,
you had to kill him, right? Yeah.
That's what happened. Right.
That's what they used to make them do
in those fucking, those Roman cuts.
It's us 500 years from now, the new
room. I think Americans just like Rome,
it's crazy. They're sort of not the
same buildup, same decline lap bands.
That was the beginning of the end.
You fucking fat cunt, stop eating.
Just get your shit together.
You have to be 50 pounds overweight.
Do you think they give it to you if you
were like, you want to lose 10 pounds?
I thought about that. I've got like
some problem areas and I was like,
maybe I just get a lap
band like a small one.
You were guaranteed you're not the
first person to think this a little bit.
Did a lot of girls like sleep talk about
that though. Is it jokes? I know. No, no,
that girls do talk about that on the
back dated girls that actually talk about
that shit all the time.
Like I'm going to go in and get the car.
There's a girl that I dated a long time
ago whose best friend got the light bow
and she did not need the [inaudible].
She did not need the light. Oh,
she just needed to work out a little bit.
The girl did.
It didn't work out at this rather than
she got ruined man. They lumpy deer up,
doesn't it? I could be wrong
about this one after they do it.
Don't you kind of have no control over
wearing that you made how they do it.
They just don't. They
don't. You have a hunch.
No control over where your fat
cells grow back. I don't know.
Replacing one problem here with another.
So you could get huge fat arms. No,
but he kept no blood or huge bite
or a huge buck like a spider.
But like you know, spiders have huge,
oh yeah. Don't let them do that.
Don't let them suck fat out of your
people if you're willing to turn to that.
Like I can understand if you're
older and it's a serious problem,
you've been struggling all your life,
but if you're selling like 21 year
old girl that works at Hooters,
just hit the gym for an hour.
You know,
I was watching this thing online about
these two French brothers who are twins
who became plastic surgery
junkies and they're deformed now.
Have you seen those places? Yeah. Pull
it up. Brian. A French famous twins,
plastic surgery now awful.
Just write French famous twins,
plastic surgery nightmare.
They were stars of some television show,
you know,
I guess back in the eighties or so and
now they're like 50 and they look like
they look like monsters.
Like these poor guys,
like they've got some sort of a
psychological defense. I got there.
Kind of like the cat
people. Yeah, exactly.
They have all sorts of facial implants
and they have all sorts of fillers in
their face and their heads are deformed.
It is.
It's so Uber does and that's what they
used to look like. They look fine. Yeah.
He's a little weird looking
but not like he is now.
Looks like that mask from
screen. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
It looks like I'm the kid from masks,
that movie mask.
They both have pouty
lips before and after.
I know what it's not that given how they
look before that Beverly Hills show to
that one bitch that has the crazy
lip and it's like the housewives
large mouth anyway though.
Yeah, but she's got crafty
shit going on with her lips. Somebody
should have told her like, hey, I ain't,
you know, that doesn't make you look
any better. That's it. Pretty easy.
It's really the problem I think with
when you do that is your face. It has,
whether you're a symmetrical or not,
your face as a certain symmetry to it.
Anything you do to any part of it,
you have to bounce out.
The rest of the more you try to
balance it, the worse it gets. Well,
there's a mathematical principle to it.
It's called the FIBONACCI Fibonacci
sequence and then it works on faces like
talking, when someone gets
a nose job, you're like,
what the fuck is going on when your head
that's like supposed to be this big,
this is the way, you know there's a grand
design for it. Sure sounds that way.
There's that one show. I don't, I
can't watch it because it upsets me.
Bridal plasty Oh, I haven't seen it.
It's addicting. You would you like it?
What is it? Explain it to me. They go
through, they go through challenges.
They each girls or is engaged and I don't
know who's marrying these crazy people.
I don't know who would,
but each girl was engaged and they do
different challenges in order to win
plastic surgery procedures all leading
up to your big day and you can win
bouquets. You can win nose jobs,
light bulb, whatever you want.
So basically her husband's marrying a
crazy doll that looks nothing like you
know,
God that remember that show on Fox
where they used to work them all?
My God, that was insane. But those
people were really awful looking.
Yeah they were.
But I mean fuck you know,
you're getting them on a slippery slope
with some people. That was good shit.
Like to fix her teeth and you know,
you don't get to be manager at the at
and t store if you don't look your best.
When you look good you get to be manager.
That's when it happens.
That's when it goes down. What do you,
if you're at the 18 store, how do you,
how do you explain to people that
the iPhone just to fucking drops off
everywhere?
What would you say?
What did I say if you were
working with at and t store?
Well, I have no idea. I never
really thought about it.
I would probably say it's, I
mean they're all, I don't know,
but we're adding towers all the time.
Why are you asking me this all the time?
If you went to the att store and the
there was like a sexy woman and CEO was
talking to you and telling you and
trying to calm you down from the issue,
do you think you'd be more
likely to just let it go?
Do you think you would get smitten?
I think you would.
I think he lives in his like laughing
the guy, we're hot. I'd be like, yeah,
I don't want you to think I'm
crazy. Really? You would do that.
So if there was like some fucking
handsome Clark Kent Looking Motherfucker,
you would be more willing to listen to
their corporate bullshit about why your
phone keeps dropping off. Beat me
if you were hot or not. Really.
Just a light beating.
Choking. Just so like,
I'll like throttling half throttle.
Yeah.
Let's play a game called fake rape
girls like that.
I'm just now thinking about law and order.
Svu episodes are about,
there's a guy in Oklahoma
that got arrested recently
because he shot his wife or
his girlfriend. There was some
sort of a, a, a, a sex thing.
Like he would hold the gun up to
her head while he's banging her. Oh,
and it accidentally went off because
he thought it was blanks. No,
because he accidentally shot her in the
head. Yeah. She said something stupid.
He just came,
oh fuck you.
And then call the cops and
said it was a mistake again.
This made a stupid and there's
no place for him in society.
If you're willing to put a loaded gun to
someone's head while you have sex with
them, knock it till you
track girl. You never know.
Some people are little gangster shit do
that while Scarface is playing in the
background. Damn. That's some
people like to live on the edge,
you know? And I mean I don't have
to go to jail for that. It wasn't,
it was an accident. Yeah. He goes to jail
for being retarded. He has to go to jail.
That's where I belong. Yeah.
You shoot somebody in the
head, you got to go to jail.
Yeah. There's not many circumstances
where it's okay. Well totally.
If they could prove that
he came after he shot her,
then he definitely goes to
jail. I don't think, can't RB
carbing taste at it,
but it had great benefits.
This lube was shut into a dead man.
Lot of pineapple. Guy Bends his knees.
He's touching his fingers to it.
No one's talking to wait for the results.
Who's dead?
Who did with the Jackie later into
them with that cat poop disease.
Toxoplasma taste funny.
If I could've thought of the name of the
disease versus asking you acting out,
tasting seaman, be careful
with your dog. I'm telling you.
Don't let them get their toxo plasma.
She doesn't go outside to her brother.
She doesn't. She have her
yard. She goes outside.
But just make sure she's on a ride. Other
people's cats that go outside? No. Yeah,
she is not good. Where in the garage? Um,
don't tell me what part of the country
is it, but are there wraps? They're here.
Here. Are there rats in your
neighborhood? No, I got rats.
The rats are there. You just don't
know. There's lots everywhere.
Let's just bet on who she's probably
going to start fucking you and your sleep.
Well, she's more of an
affection, love, hug kind of dog.
Don't let her out to PE. She'll get
excited and start holding my arm. Really
tell you that she has to pee once a
month if I like really push it and don't
want her out cause I'm doing something.
How strange she does it to like,
like she gets so excited and worked up
and weave and then she'll just be like,
how do you a workout when
you go on the road with her?
I don't work out on the road. No,
no, no that's not what you mean.
How do you work it out? Like when you
go on the road to take it with you?
Because I was on the road so much,
I was like I need,
I need something he commanded.
So I got her and she and she travels
with you on a plane. She's like this,
she's silent. That's awesome. I
want to travel with being on stage.
You're on stage.
The other comics.
Oh that's cool. And she's a
really good girl. That's nice.
Do you have a cool little friend?
Cause she could have been crazy.
And when you bring her on a plane,
he just put her in between your seat.
Is that how you doing it or my feet go.
What if people are allergic to
dogs now round you fuck them.
She sat sneaker on,
but for the most part I pay for
her and if you're allergic will,
you'll set nigger on my bag that I have
for it looks like a duffle bag and it's
got a mesh side like she can breathe.
I'll throw my coat over and just walk on.
The people that check your ticket or
not the same as the people security and
northern St people to gate. I figured
that out. So you just walk on.
They don't want to know. If you don't
do that then what do you have to do?
Pay 100 bucks or a hundred it depends.
Hundred 50 doesn't really the scheme.
The laser, you know, it's a great
scheme. When I moved out here,
I had to move my cats out and they
lost my cats for like two hours.
Like they didn't let me have it with me.
I had to put it into like under
the thing under the thing.
I would never do that ever again and then
I was thinking about traveling with or
bring my dog to Ohio when I
went back and they s besides,
besides it being so expensive they had,
the vet told me that it's
really bad for the dogs,
the air pressure under or in
the cabinet under the thing.
I bet. I bet it's cold. It's cold on the
floor where she goes up a little blank.
It's really,
really cold down there.
There's that creepy feeling when you get
close to the window and you realize how
cold it is out there and
coming back from Canada was a trip
because we were, we were almost stranded.
We came so close to me and stranded.
The snow was just starting to start.
A blizzard was hitting's recently and if
we had been an hour later we would have
been stuck in Canada for days. I'm
sure. No, this was a different one.
This was a recent one that's Macho
Montreal. Montreal's beautiful city.
Canada itself was amazing country. It's
gorgeous and Canadians are really nice.
The nicest fucking people. A lot of crap
for Americans. I dated Canadian recently.
This is why I have all this to say.
They're very nice and super masculine.
Not Fatty at all. Nice.
So Canadians out the,
just want to let you know. No, we're
done. I'm just saying more what happened,
but he's just giving Ya.
They do say she's giving you a thumbs
up on your product. I think for,
it's always easy to make fun of
Canada, but great country. Nice people.
Very friendly. Yeah. But it's not
easy to make fun of Canada. It's me.
Easy to make fun of how fucking cold it
is in some spots, but like, you know,
as far as like, like the people
there and they're slipping.
I had some of the nicest fucking
people ever live above this country,
filled with homicidal
maniacs, you know, Michigan.
How about that dude? Did you see
those Garrett living above Mexico?
Do you see those photos of Michigan? Was
it you that posted it? That shit's scary.
Like a Michigan decline. A Michigan in
photos. It's a, it's on Joe's Twitter.
Amazing photo of somebody tweeted it.
I retired.
It's all these photos of like
ancient buildings and you know,
been around Michigan's,
it's like the 17,
18 hundreds all fallen apart and abandoned
now because the economy is falling
apart.
Like abandoned library filled with books,
abandoned police headquarter with
all the photos here. Detroit,
Michigan in general. I think it was
all Detroit, Detroit, those towns.
I was actually,
I was in Upper Michigan recently.
Second time in a year. I'm not bragging.
Give a fuck. I don't know. Fuck
time travel up to northern Michigan.
It's such another world up there.
It looks,
if you took a picture
and took out the cars,
you wouldn't be able to tell me what
decade it was. I agree to all of that.
Once for a, did a college and
all of that, Michigan, who was,
you know where all of that
is to middle of nowhere.
They gave me terrible directions to drive
there for, there's no gps back then.
It's back in the golden days,
a comedy and I had to drive to this
fucking college and stand on top of two.
Um,
there were like a cafeteria tables that
was the stand and one of them had a mic
on one end and a speaker
on the other accounts.
And there was another speaker that was
on the other table and I can go back and
forth in between the two tables if I paid
attention for then step on a crack and
punch through and fall.
I'm not kidding.
It was fucking most ridiculous
thing ever. And then, uh,
there's no opening act.
Of course it's just me.
So I go onstage and immediately start
getting heckled and they're all football
players. It's a football college.
So it's like all these animals.
Well I start to like give these guys shit.
They were like,
it was good natured heckling with,
you know,
a lot of faggot talk and stuff like
that. So I go to the guy, you know, I,
I go, whatever. I said I, you know,
I've made fun of them. And the,
the guy who ran the college
came up to me and said,
I just want to let you know
that we are not allowing swears.
You are not allowed to swear.
I was like, this is ridiculous.
These guys are allowed to swear you
fucking faggot. We love to yell at you.
Fucking faggot at me. And so then I
turned it around and said something about,
you know,
you guys are old enough to go to war.
You're old enough to die for your country,
right?
But this guy right here says that,
I can't swear in front of you.
Somehow know that you can't
handle it and then give a fuck.
It's fucking crazy. And I
was joking around by, I go,
let's fucking trashed this place.
And I'll bunch it.
Dude screamed and one dude stood up and
picked up a chair and then the guy came
up to the table and he goes, listen,
listen, listen, do whatever you want.
We'll deal with the consequences later.
You perform your normal act as
you normally do. And I'm like, oh,
can you see how I could swear now we can
swear. Calm down. Everybody calm down.
They were like ready to fight.
I was half kidding.
But I was like really instigating.
I was really instigating because you know,
they were boards and they were in the
middle of nowhere and this guy was
annoying as fuck. And I
was going, look, you know,
I just came here to entertain you guys.
Never comedy show. That was the thing.
They used to sell you,
they'll sell you to anyone.
All this is like Barry Katz as agency.
It was New York entertainment and they
would just fucking sell you, whoever.
They could sell you to any colleges.
They would just sell you two and then he
would deal with it once you get there.
And I did a Naca show and they got to
see that I was dirty and like everybody
had, you know, they said,
well if you do, you know,
Naca and they know that you're dirty,
then it will limit the amount of
colleges that you go to. But I was like,
I can't make a fake second act right.
You know, and, and just to do it,
to do colleges.
So they knew I was dirty.
So somehow or another got sold
at this college that didn't know,
but they were the most savage of all
the colleges I've ever done ever.
And they didn't want me
to switch the one guide.
It's not the college.
I think it was,
it was their policy because they had
all these fucking animals living in the
middle of Michigan. You know, we want to
keep him to keep him calm, keep him calm.
I didn't know need for swears so
many colleges the other last year.
And the thing about colleges is
like if comedy club you can go,
you can see what this, you couldn't ask
your friends with the stages is like,
cause some colleges you have no clue
what it's going to be like. You don't,
if you're gonna be in a theater, an
amphitheater outside in the parking lot,
a cafeteria,
you don't know and you get there,
you just hope it's going to be decent.
Did a college wrestling Canada,
it was weird. I hadn't done one
in a long time and it was like uh,
adults and college kids mixing together.
It's always weird when they like come
wandering it from the community. Yeah,
you can be 18 or you know, you
can, you know, 18 and above.
It was fine, but it was,
it's very strange because a lot
of college people, you know,
you forget when you're 30 years old,
you're 40 years old or whatever.
Even if you lived all this life,
these kids haven't lived at all.
It's tricky because you can't talk about
dating as you would normally or jobs or
sex cause it's just not, they
don't know that yet. Some do,
but you're dealing with a
huge percentage that don't,
I mean there's hip kids in every level
of high school and every level of college
that would make great audience
members in any comedy club.
There's kids that are 14 that get
us such as, yes, you're right.
It was such a small percentage.
But in college, man,
you'd be surprised that the number from
14 to college is not that different.
There are a lot of them the same. They're
like little kids. Some of them are hip,
so I don't know what's going on in the
world. Some of them, you know? No, but,
and another thing they like
to do at colleges is elected.
Go PC on you and fucking point out when
you're being racist or point out when
you're being sexist. You know what
though? I think they're smarter.
I enjoy college has because
it gives me a chance.
You're not placating Joe public.
These are kids that are very close to
the realm of academia that we'll get a
reference that we'll get something
about school or they're so close or they
remember it and it's a nice exercise.
Yeah,
I think it's because it's easy to get a
car if you're in the middle of nowhere
and you get a bunch of like,
I don't want to try not to offend anyone,
but like normal guys that this is
like they're doing it on Friday night.
We're going to get drunk, see the comedian
and go, fuck. It's a little bit easier.
It's a cake walk. You could, while
they're trying to have fun too,
we're trying to have fun,
just trying to have a good time.
There's something to be said for that.
I know a lot of idiots that are a lot
of fun to hang out with and they don't
want to think about the moral and fucking
wiki leaks, but you know, have a chat,
have a jack and coke with them.
We get a couple of pounds in was like
you give each other a few high fives in
there. Good company. You know,
there's a lot of people that aren't
very deep thinkers that I enjoy hanging
around with, but I don't know what
you're saying. There's a wedding ring,
Brian.
Shut the fuck up.
Don't get it. He's a mess. Oh
dare you. It's a wedding ring.
He's making a wedding ring out of
the court. But why Brian, that was,
he's laying off what you were just
talking about and I was acting like I sit
down me. Oh, so marriage. Have
you ever seen the wonderful
whites of West Virginia?
It's a must say.
Oh,
we'll give you a copy of the DVD as you
leave is a documentary on this family
that lives in West Virginia.
It is one of the craziest fucking
things you've ever seen in your life.
This wild family that just starts
oxycontin and goes in and out of jail and
everybody's all, you have
to get everything I'm doing
tonight and watch that.
Fabulous. It's fabulous.
They are. They are.
And there's don't skip the behind the
scenes interviews too cause the long in
depth interviews with each of
each of the people that they,
they do the show with our fucking fabulous
as well on my iPod or listened to all
work out.
Fuck it.
I'm sure you can buy it on iTunes and
listen to on my iPod on Bob Guarantee you.
It's just genius though, man. It's
just, this family is just completely,
totally insane. And they live
in West Virginia and they just,
it was just like ancestors after ancestor
generation after generation fucking
criminals, criminal, just straight
criminals. I mean they're just crazy.
They're there and they're all like
famous in that town for being nuts. Yeah.
So they had an interview all like
different sheriffs and all these different
towns folk and all these different people
that know them and then they all say
the same thing. These people are just
crazy, wild and good for nothing.
And none of them gonna amount to nothing.
It's one old lady. She goes and they go,
what do you want? What do you want
to happen when he dies? She goes,
when I dare fucking,
I want you to blow.
We'd smoke in buffet says
snort pills off my head.
Let's have a fucking party.
It's uncomfortable when people
talk that way. I don't know man.
It's pretty fucking awesome.
I wanted to hang out with her.
I wanted to go drink it with her. That's
all I thought of when she said that.
When she said, how are you going to die?
I want, I'm going to boast. Weeds. Moon.
Yes. Snort pills off my head. I'm like,
I want to fucking hang out with his lady.
That awful Mazda Road House.
It's like a terrible,
that is so fake like that.
This is a carnival fake reality
show called Mas roadhouse
on like TLC group. No,
it's better. It's on true TV, TV,
TV, but it's true TV. It's network.
It's a network that sounds like it's real,
but everything on it.
It's like a spray. So shitty on
there. It's like this bar in Dallas,
but the mom, she talks like
this. I don't give a fuck,
and she's like this old lady and it's
scripted, but she's still like that.
All those scripted reality
shows they're fucking up, man.
You just need to follow
those people like they did.
But the show with the whites of West
Virginia, there's no scripted reality man.
They just followed him for a year and in
a year they got just gold, gold, gold,
engraved. They all died at the end. No,
you want to keep them alive and come
up with a cart to go and make it.
Three d three d. What would happen? You'd
eat, how would they use it? Through me,
my school over here. Cherry
flavor. You've got to watch.
It's pretty full.
Most Johnny Knoxville produced it.
Apparently he found out about
it and had to be a part of this.
He just had to have to let people know.
I saw him the other day.
What did you think? And you think,
whoa, Johnny. It was everything to him.
Just think you won't even sign. Yeah, no,
he didn't. No, he didn't look healthy.
Really. I can't imagine someone that does
that for a living would look healthy.
Debt to get fucked up by that ball.
Shit. That shit. That is ridiculous.
I can't believe you did that.
Okay, so crazy. Yeah, he's
crazy. They're all crazy.
They're so crazy. I mean crazy. You
easily could have died from that,
from anything they do.
The boldo fucking Amen.
You got work hit you when you cut
your goddamn blind fold on Shit,
man. You're a movie star. Do you know
your movies? I know you want to be legit,
but fuck man.
I mean how many bones is he broken
his entire course of doing that show?
Would that help look into in general,
does that help? Yeah, it's probably me.
Would you rather take a beating trunk?
Fuck yeah. You're numb when you're drunk.
US,
man.
I think maybe if I was sober I might
be able to move a little bit better and
some of the punishment rather be silver.
That's what we're going to take a beating.
That's why,
but you're not going to do
much to fight off a bowl.
That's why a lot of the people in the
titanic that survived because they were
drunk and wailing or warm.
What the fuck are you talking about?
The water kills you almost instantly.
You're making shit survive. That dude.
Only the people that didn't go in
the water. No, no, no. The window.
It's no people in the water survived.
I don't know about that man.
Really quite drunk drive.
I saw the ones that survive because
there's so much more relaxed.
We should look that up because I'm pretty
sure that was even a premise in the
movie was that Leonardo Dicaprio.
Dot.
Cause he was in the water and he left her
on the route. Yeah, that's what it was.
You fucking queer.
You should've had a shot.
He shouldn't have snapped me at the back.
You shouldn't have snapped me at the bio.
You still be alive.
Did you know like 98% of the women
survived the titanic because women were
allowed. Sorry. Wow.
I mean you think like a lot of people die.
You didn't know that.
Did you see that cruise ship in
Antarctica that got fucked up last week?
Did you see that?
It got hit by a 35 foot wave and it's
smashed the window of the boat and leaked
all over the electronics to electronics.
I'll short it out and they
couldn't drive the boat.
Who's new loads?
We're fucked.
They had no power and they creep in on
like an a some sort of a backup engine or
whatever the fuck they had to do.
But they like,
they had a creep in that
they have the video of this,
this boat getting hit by waves.
Oh it is fucking terrifying.
It's like a cork in a Jacuzzi.
Is Bobbin just completely out of control.
I did a semester at sea last year
of college and so it's a giant,
it's an old cruise ship
that they've converted.
It's like they strip it down and it's a,
it's a college basically.
And you go around the world. What?
It's crazy. Oh, what's it called?
The program's called semester at sea
and our ship was the SSE universe.
Holy Shit. So you lived in a
boat for a year, four months.
Four to five months I think.
And so you went to all these crazy
countries and you're on, you know,
you're crossing these huge
oceans for like days at a time,
but the group that went after us,
like there's a certain degree that your
boat can't go unless we're in the Earl
said, oh, cap size, and they have
footage. They were all in the news.
They were caught like the storm and
there's footage of like all the kids books
just sliding. And they were like one
degree off from capsizing hold on.
600 kids on this thing. Oh my. They
were this close. Arbs was fine,
but I was like, wow. Yeah, it was
off. Brian, pull that video up,
see if you can find it. It was on
my Twitter, but it's a cruise ship.
Antarctica hit by monster waves,
but there's a,
when they were trying to rescue people
off the boat, they got video of it.
Like one another belt came in
close. No, no, no. Nobody's,
nobody's screaming or anything like that.
No one's Bolton got a bullet hole
in her head. Right. Cruise ship,
wave Antarctica. But in Antarctica,
and it'd be really recent.
It's a December article or December
video that's a fucking tripping.
It's so terrifying.
This fucking boat.
It's just bobbing back and forth. It makes
you realize like you're dealing with,
you know,
like you're insanely deep water there,
Blaine, as a race, a large wave slammed
into an Antarctic cruise ship with Ada,
the American passengers and 77 board,
but the ship's crew overcame minor
damage and was heading safely back to its
shedding.
Old Port on Wednesday,
the vessels operator said the called
Dhea to declare an emergency on Tuesday
reporting it had suffered engine damage
and we'd heavy season 55 miles per hour.
90 key Ph wines we need was northeast
of the South Shetland islands and about
500 miles,
845 kilometers from our shore here.
The Argentine navy said in our statement,
the International Association of
Antarctica Tour Operators issued statement
saying the wave,
the technical Dhea to cause that broken
bridges window in some electrical
malfunction.
Kemp and knock out some communications
and kill this guy and engine performance.
Anyway,
you get to see the whole
legion, Stephen Hawkin. You don't need.
Yeah, guy. But how, how crazy is that?
I'm imagine that's terrifying.
That boat. Oh my God. I mean,
look how far it goes up. Wayne's
are so huge. It's so scary.
And that's nothing.
There's been waves higher than that.
There was a wave that hit Alaska.
Um,
someone was just telling me
about this and it was in a,
I believe it was in the 1950s some
fucking wave. I should look this up.
Some wave. There was a thousand feet
high. Something fell like a shelf,
like a volcanic shelf or
you know, something off a
mountain fell into the water,
caused this monster wave
that popped up from it.
And for everything from a thousand feet
down in this area where it hit is just
dead. There's just nothing there.
Trees gone. Everything gone.
A thousand feet of water. Wrap your head
around that Shit, man. Can't impossible.
Sorry to hear how I can't quantify things.
There's a fucked up video online. We
talked about this on the podcast before.
These kids at 900 feet above this a,
there's Russian kids are walking on
these beams. 900 feet above this forest.
I can't even look at Shit like that.
I look at anything where like when I
was doing fear factor and we'd be on
buildings and people would have to like
do some crazy fucking stone where they
had to like walk across some beam or
rope or something like that across two
buildings. Just looking over the edge.
Your whole body. Just tangles. Well,
I may have a normal life. Not,
not a crazy one where I, I start.
It's hard hyperventilating,
but my body just, everything is telling
me to get the fuck away from the ledge.
Unless you need the money.
Yeah.
Well unless you know you were in a harness
and all that other good stuff. Yeah.
Obviously when I'm standing
there directing the show,
there's no harness on me obviously.
What the fuck are we talking about?
Nothing.
Basically the end of this show has
reached because we run out of steam,
but two hours in. It's hot
as fuck in here too. Is it?
That's just you and her together.
I think it's chemistry. I smell it.
It's in the air. What?
Britney spears perfume.
Is that what it is due or Brittany Spears
perfume to you. That's kind of cool.
Do you wear it to be ironic or
do you like the way it smells?
I love the way it smells.
Really. What does it smell like?
Have you had to describe it? So
it's kind of like a lotion, like uh,
like uh oh the lotion. Cinnamon Lotion.
Britney spears is like a vanilla fruity,
like clean stripper. You know that
perfume angel? Yeah, that's, it's gross.
Right? So it was on one of my
shelves from like a long time ago.
Somebody left it there. What
is angel? It's a perfume angel.
It's every woman's worn out at
some point in her life. Blue Star.
Is it like the female version of Dzhokhar?
Yeah,
but it's in this star and it's not like
one of those bottles that stand up.
It's like the most retarded
shaped bottle ever. Anyways,
I went to go grab something off the shelf
in my bathroom and I didn't even know
it was there.
I fell down and broke in my bathroom.
My fucking house smells like my
grandmother times a thousand. It's awful.
It's don't go away. It's so gay. It's
horrible. All perfumes. Creepy. Yeah.
Passion of mine. Like mine. It's my MMA.
I love perfume and smells and lotions.
Real loud. Girls are so strange.
I think smells. I smelled good and at all
times. That's a Texas thing too though.
Texas women know how to be women.
You know how to girly? Yeah.
They know how to grill it up.
You know? It's not like Wyoming.
Women take a hit on women in Wyoming.
A few in Wyoming does a few coyotes,
mountain lions and shit.
There's mountain lions and shit.
But the grapefruit I think is a, not
an aphrodisiac, but men are attracted.
This melon grapefruit. Really
Vanilla too. But grapefruits,
the one that does it but just
doesn't have great for dinner.
Do you like perfume when girls
wear a perfume? Brian? Yeah,
but there's a certain kind
of, yeah, so that's good.
I don't like the perfume.
The perfume. Me, you know,
like the kinds of perfume right now.
I like don't you are a hair
perfume and then I have a project.
It's like my own thing and I do it.
Even if I'm going to be by myself all day.
Whoa. It's smell right here.
Don't be shy. Don't be weird.
That's good. That's very
mellow. It's not flowery.
Smells like food. Okay, so
you're a true kind of sore.
You know what you'd be doing
very seriously. So when
you smell a stinky girl,
that's like over perfume and
is that offensive to, you know,
I just don't want to be here. You don't
want to be here. You feel bad for her.
Cause everybody's body chemistry
works with different smells.
Like it just depends on who you are.
Some that you could love the way it
smells in the bottle and then on you,
it either doesn't last or smells bad.
And so it just depends.
Only thing I ever do is I put on deodorant
so other people don't get offended.
You should get your photo. Timberlake's
Timberlake's is exit pretty good? No.
What does that Justin Timberlake,
Timberlake, Cologne. I'm not wearing,
just missed it.
I split some shit and land or armed.
And then chocolate one,
the chocolate one.
I went to college with this kid who was
repugnant by every definition and he was
an awful person and he was fat and he was
gross and he sweat a lot. But when he,
when he's wondering why he would come
and we'd have these meetings for this
conduct your Bros and when he would
come into meetings and I hated this kid,
I would find myself scooting closer
because he would wear acts. Whoa.
They have one that's called chocolate
paradise I think. Recommended.
I think you're a freak about this. Like
good smells. I think you're afraid.
Amazing sense of smell on it.
That's it. It's very rare.
I don't think I understand
what you're saying,
but I don't think dude should a
plan for someone like, you know,
I think it's a very rare attraction
to smells. You have very rare.
Do you get super fan and when dudes
fart like a friend or like a boy,
then my boyfriend,
like a boy that you like.
Every boyfriend I've had has not done
it in front of me cause he knows about
your smelter. Super courteous
about it. I'm not even sure.
Like the last one we dated for a year.
He'd always leave. Never hotbox to, no,
no one would ever do that
to me that I was serious.
The kind of guy that would do Brian,
you're off the list.
Brian's a hotbox or from the 80s he was
hot boxing back before I even had a name
back when it was an oven. Actually I
have a bit about that whole office.
Ford is when every time
I get in a relationship,
like this last girl I dated from Texas,
from Houston,
we had like a really a good relationship
and then she started doing these little
things that made it not romantic and more.
One of the things to steer asleep
blew a fart on me and goes,
do you want breakfast in bed? And
she goes, there's your eggs bitch.
And she blew a fart on me. And I'm like,
really? Did have that really did happen.
Yeah, I did that in my ag.
That's, and that's true.
And then that just kills a relationship.
Girls don't ever look at it.
Almost throwing up
part.
I'd done that like for sure.
I'm foreign it on accident and then
it's like I'm saying like there's things
that happen, but to deliberately
suffocate someone. Right. That's gross.
She how rude. How rude. Houston
girls, man, they're there. Hillbilly.
He'll be part of my state.
You can find some good ones.
Good ones everywhere fellow. You just
attract a certain type. I did it.
I got to do something about that. You
got to do something about that. Toby.
Blaming Texas. Well, lobby blaming
Houston for years has been Texas.
You could figure it out, bro.
You can get better. It's over.
Do you do that to your wife? No. No Way.
You guys who don't Fart in front of
each other. I mean accidentally. Yeah.
You wouldn't be like,
Hey, come here. No, no.
I don't know when he wants a
smaller farts. Farts are horrible.
There's no need for that. I eat too much.
Me are okay by the way. Someone's far.
It's in my little daughter far.
It's aren't that you like your own parts.
Doesn't eat much. She's a little girl. She
needs a lot. You'd be amazed. Her logs,
she drops logs a little or the dog shit
in the potty. I see these logs. I'm like,
there's no way.
And now she
calls it logs. I told you cause it's
your daughter, but they're huge logs.
If you didn't know her, you'd
be like, that's awful. If
I didn't know. Yeah, yeah,
of course I have to pick this.
The thing is that the parties are
ridiculous because what it is is a little
plastic bucket on the bottom.
That's that your baby shits in.
So you have this like advanced
civilization where people have toilets and
running water,
but you don't use it for little babies.
They have to shift it a little box
because you have to be what you were with
them all the time anyway.
So it's just a minor inconvenience.
You just dump it in the toilet
and all that. But, but it's,
they can't climb up to
the hook the toilet, yet.
They're not really designed for that
yet and they can't hold themselves up or
they're falling. Right. So I get her,
she's got like a little thing that sits
on top of the toilet. But then again,
you've got to pick her up. But she
drops these logs to like human sized.
I mean, if it was my poop, it would
be as big as my chest. I mean,
it doesn't even make any
sense that there's so much
shit comes out of her little
body. No, you gotta take the
famous photo of her pooping.
Now you see the baby. That's
a good one for you. Well,
that's something that everyone did as it
gets in on your, um, your Twitter, uh,
used to be, I don't have it anymore.
Let me holding my penthouse.
Let's bring this pitch home,
ladies and gentlemen. Uh,
thanks to the fleshlight
for sponsoring us. Um,
if you want to go to a fleshlight.com,
you can, well actually,
if you go to Joe rogan.net
and click the link,
you can get 15% off so you
can masturbate at a discount.
And it's a very effective item. I support
it. I went back to using it recently.
Did you? Good for you, Bro. You
can be by herself for a little bit.
You're going to be okay. I need
to do. You're going to be fine.
Thank you very much. To Eliza
Schlesinger journey, powerful comedian,
winner of last comic standing and
all around Badass bitch props.
Give me some of my uncles
check out her blog.
Her blog is really good and she
has very funny twitters as well.
Do you have a cool name on Twitter
too? Cause it's easy Eliza. That's it.
And my blog is www dot.
That's my nightmare.com yes.
Yeah and the and that's linked on the
Eliza [inaudible] dot com and so follow
her on Twitter.
You dirty bitches and follow red van too
because he's really sad that he doesn't
have any more.
He's trying to like really blow past cat
stacks and a cash tax has more than me.
I actually have a number that
I'm trying to get past right now.
What does it tell me what it is?
20 1020 1000 folks. We can do it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
just believe in the Lord and Lord will
provide and 21,000 Twitter followers will
enter a new epoch. Yes. Whatever the
fuck am I talking about? February 4th,
Mandalay Bay, me, Joey Diaz and our
Recia fear. It's going to be epic.
You fucking freaks. Mandalay Bay
theater. I think it's like 1700 people.
Still some tickets available. If they're
going fast, don't get locked out.
Thank you.
To um,
see two oh coconut water for sending
us a big fat case of delicious coconut
water. The shit is so yummy. Did you
try it yet? Yes, I've had it before. Oh,
you've had it before it, right?
You're going to just take it with you.
You're not going to drink him absent.
I said a long car ride on long car ride.
What? Bring in along car. I
don't, don't bow to peer pressure.
When can anybody see you do stand
up? Uh, re when's the next post Gig?
I do stand up nightly in Los
Angeles, uh, for updates on that.
You can go to my Twitter
and my Facebook page.
I always post it comedy
Improv or the laugh factory.
And my next eight I will be
at the Pittsburgh Improv,
the 19th weekend of the 19th of
this month. Powerful Pittsburgh.
Go see or go see a rock the house.
Thank you very much for coming by.
Thank everybody. Tomorrow, 3:00
PM Brian Cowan is coming by.
I love riding my road dog.
Just back from Thailand.
Holla at your boy
filming the hangover too.
So he's going to have some
crazy fucking stories.
So we'll see you guys tomorrow and
thank you very much for tuning in.
I love you bitches. I was
always, oh, you know it.
I don't even have to hook your nose
later.
[inaudible].