Well, we're doing it. Yeah.
Jesus, I'm not prepared.
Can experience is brought to you by
the fleshlight my favorite masturbation
toward the only one that I've
ever used ever in my life.
And if they hadn't sent me one, I probably
wouldn't have used it. But they did.
And it is awesome, is way better
than beating off and let's be real.
Everybody beats off. So do yourself
a favor and just give into reality.
Don't touch that thing. Everybody's
touched that. It's disgusting.
Everybody's knowledge
it do yourself a favor.
Go out and get yourself this
amazing beaten off and instrument.
It's really a fantastic piece of
engineering and design designed by a guy
actually whose wife was pregnant
and he couldn't have sex, you know,
cause it was like six months in the
pregnancy and it gets a little sketchy.
You know, like what the fuck
am I doing here? You know,
I'll creep mind that I'm sticking,
you know, especially if you're,
if you're like just spending putting
your mouth, you know, she's pregnant.
She had the babies inside of,
are you just trying to get your load off?
You better off.
You feel like you're supposed to be
beaten off shore from personal experience?
Like what's the cutoff point?
Misses Rogan well liked it all the
way up until the end, but oh wow.
To me I was like,
this is the deal.
You tell me when it's go time cause I
don't want to be the one that's trying to
fuck you while you're walking around
with a fucking 10 pound baby inside you.
It's just crazy. It's weird. Yes
they do. They get really horny.
They get really horny. It's supposed to
actually be good to actually helps uh,
the baby come out or something like that.
It helps dilate you or some crazy cause
he get like hotter to you as it moves
along. And they were like,
are you like, oh yeah, eight
months. This is very strange.
It is. I mean you can only imagine
it, you know, you don't know.
It becomes almost alien cause it's,
you know. Yeah. Because you know,
you're still horny.
You know,
everyone gets horny and she's
still an attractive woman. But the,
the issue is there's a baby in
the mix here and it's on her.
So it's a very different experience when
it's just a woman and her body and your
body. It's just sex. It's just fun.
It's just two people enjoying each
other's bodies and Lars did passion,
but when you got a baby inside a person,
but that's a totally different mix.
Totally different mix and knowing that
like eight months along that like it's
you doing that. That's a bay time
before. No, but it's a your swimmers,
so you know. Yeah. It's like
your own product is in there.
Yeah. It's very strange.
And it's also your, you are now acutely
aware of what the experience really is.
The experience of actually having a kid
actually the experience of making new
human beings. It is. You know, you,
you have been tricked into some ancient
mechanism that's designed to make
animals create more animals and you are,
most of your life moves in the
flows of these needs and wants,
whether or not you realize it or you don't
realize it. Once that baby comes out,
you are forced into a recognition.
It's a,
it's a real humbling experience
because you realize, wow,
this whole thing is way bigger than me.
You know, and you, you also realize, well,
hey, now there's this person that I
love more than me. There's a little
tiny person.
I'm responsible for everything that
has to do with their life and their
education, their, their experience of the
guide them and protect them. It just so,
so while this is all happening, you're
trying to shoot a load into a check,
you know,
it's like you don't feel the same way
when you put it down.
Strange.
So this gentleman invented something that
he could relieve his manhood with that
he didn't feel like waking up the wife
while she's about to throw up in the
morning and sticking his dick in her
butt. Tried to be nice. He's a nice guy.
What about your book books? Little
pregnant. Pregnant? Sure. Yeah.
So anyway,
fucking Bro, I have to do that at some
point. Like I got to make a light.
You don't have to, but you know, but
the, the biological imperative is there.
Like I'm just starting to feel
I'm 35 and it starting to like,
it's starting to kick in and it's
terrifying and not the birthing part.
That part doesn't scare me because I've
taken some huge shifts and I feel like I
could do that, but the growing
inside of me like an alien. Oh yeah.
Well your insights spread.
Yeah,
it's very psychedelic.
You know it's life becomes very
different than then it was anyway. Yeah.
If you went to in the code name
Rogan on the Joe rogan.net website,
is it a flashlight link?
You will get 15% off the number
one sex toy for a minute.
That was a commercial that was there you
guys. That's how it like commercials,
man.
This is the only way I can do them.
I listen to people do can commercials
on like other radio shows and I respect
what you're doing, but
God, that seems boring.
I'd rather really say something about it
every time I use it to fucking awesome
product.
Another awesome product is Alpha brain.
We were sponsored by [inaudible]
Dot Com and o n n I t.com.
And there's another thing that we've got
now called new mood and what new mood
is.
It's a five HTP supplement and a lot of
people like Neil Brennan turned me on to
this stuff first and five HTP actually
when you take it in allows your brain to
produce more serotonin.
It breaks down into Serotonin and
I actually makes you feel good.
It gives you like a nice
feeling of wellbeing.
And a Neil started taking it and uh,
he said he was taking like,
like three or four times where you're
supposed to take. And I was like,
is that like safe? He goes, I
don't know, but I feel great,
so fuck it. Um, but so he,
so I started taking it after he told
me about it and it definitely does
something,
gives you like a weird little,
a minor feeling of happiness is like
the best way to describe it. Very nice.
And this stuff,
this new mood stuff with this stuff.
What we'd done and we'd taken,
um,
five HTP n added l trip to
fan and l Tryptofan, uh,
actually breaks down. It's like one
of the building blocks for five HTP.
So He'd take the two of them together
and it gives you sort of like a time
release quality and it's just very,
they're very mellowing. I like it a lot.
It's a, it's really, uh, a good
calming supplement. And again,
like I say with all the,
uh, on it supplements,
if you think of are too
expensive or whatever,
you can definitely get it for cheaper,
just copied ingredients, man. Go Online,
find the,
find the ingredients,
they're readily available on [inaudible]
dot com go buy the stuff in bulk and
you'll definitely save money.
And I, I'm happy if you do that.
I swear to God that is that like calming
in general or like calming before bed
kind of thing? Well, I take
it before bed. I take it,
I take two of them right before
going to sleep. But, um, uh,
some people take them during the day,
you know,
some people like to take them if they're
not getting enough sleep or extra
stressed out or something like that.
It's a real weird world,
the world of nootropics because it's sort
of just sort of being explored now and
just sort of coming into public
consciousness and there's a lot of
misconceptions about what
it does or what they do.
And I don't think each one
works for everybody there.
There's some that I'm not feeling them.
I tried them and it
doesn't do shit for me.
And there's other people
that swear by this stuff.
So you got out kind of just without me
getting into too much depth because it
would really take up
the whole of the show,
go look up nootropics and try a bunch
of different things. It's, it's,
it's fascinating, but I think
that they can enhance, uh,
the way your brain functions.
It makes it feel a little better.
It makes it work a little
better. And, you know,
there's a lot of arguments back and forth
about this stuff and for good reason
because a,
you know,
a lot of people when you're saying
that you can make people think better,
but that sounds a lot like big dick pills,
you know?
And people always say that to me.
Like,
how is what this is bigger than big Dick
Pills? Well, you know what man, it's,
it's better in that it actually
works and it might not work for you,
but it works for me and it works for
other people that I know and it's 100%.
It's not,
it's not like a placebo effect.
It gives me the most lucid dreams
that I've never had in my life.
And the big shift has been taking
this stuff. And um, as I said,
there's a bunch of different
ones available online in
a lot of different people
have written about them and you could kind
of create your own little concoctions.
It's a fun thing to get into. It's kind
of interesting. I believe in vitamins.
I take multivitamins, I take
minerals, I take amino acids,
I take fish oil.
I take a lot of different things
as well as like a juice every day.
And I drink like this Kale shake every
morning. I think I'm a big proponent.
Well I, you know, I try to be, you know,
I try to be as much as possible cause I'm,
I'm a big proponent of
taking care of your body.
I know when my body feels better, I know
when I'm, yeah, when you look terrible,
you look right now. Thanks
Ben. When you, when you, uh,
when it doesn't feel good to me.
When it's not working well,
nothing works well in my life.
I find that my life is always best in
order when I'm in shape because when I'm
in shape and I feel good that I
don't have to worry about that,
that's out of the way. So now I
don't feel like a lazy piece of Shit.
So since I don't feel
like a lazy piece of Shit,
all these other things seem
to fall in place much easier.
You said something one time to me that uh,
I thought about my bunch is um,
you said, I think if you better
yourself in one area of your life,
it has a residual effect on,
and I think that's true.
I thought about that a lot like that
when you are doing something to better
yourself,
it's not just like if it's working out,
the benefit is there's more, there's
a benefit that falls into like your,
they can fall into your creative stuff
or your work stuff cause you're bettering
yourself and it has that residual effect.
You know what I mean?
So cause we'll leave you work
out and you take it seriously,
which I've started to more,
even though I'm still lazy shit,
like I've started to more than you think
about things more like well I'm going
to work out like this. I
need to eat better. Yeah.
And then if I'm going to be
tired I need to rest more. Right.
And that then will better your
other aspects of life, you know,
you're going to feel more rested and it's
like you got to give yourself awesome
advice.
Yeah.
The real problem is getting yourself to
do what you would advise someone else to
do. That's where it becomes
difficult, right? You know,
when you try to tell
somebody, do something that
you don't do yourself, like,
hey man, you should work out me and
my fucking eat a cheeseburger. I mean,
a lot of people do that,
right?
There's a lot of people that do that
because they know someone in the back of
their head. They know the advice
that they would give themselves.
They're just for whatever reason,
not quite bright enough to give it or
not quite motivated or not quite clear
enough or too conflicted in whatever
way and whatever area, you know,
everybody's got their own thing,
their own confliction that allows them to,
you know, branch off into
passive distraction. But, uh,
I think the big key is balance. The
big key is a a balance act. You can,
you cannot only be work, you must
have fun, but you cannot be only fun.
You must have work.
There has to be things that get done.
There has to be information that gets
absorbed. Your brain and your body,
if not given a task, if not given a
purpose on this planet, starts to think,
what the fuck am I here for? You know?
So the only way to true happiness,
like ultimately it is silly.
Ultimately we are just one frame and an
infinite movie that goes on forever and
that this life might not be important,
but the only way to enjoy it while you're
here is to find things that you enjoy
inside of it and you, you can't totally
completely look at the big picture,
but ultimately you can't anyway.
Because even if you look at
the big picture with your
life and then you get past
that, you go, well, at least I
got past that. The fuck you did.
How about the big picture of the universe?
How about the big picture of the sun?
The Sun is only going to last another
few billion years and that bitch is going
to fizzle out and everything on this
fucking planet is either going to die and
some horrible explosion when it goes
supernova or it's going to freeze to death
first. Look, it's ridiculous.
It's all temporary.
Every fucking thing that's ever been done.
So you can get crazy like that.
But what I found is we're stuck here and
the only way to enjoy here is to find
stuff you like doing. Do that and have
a good time. Have a good time with here.
And one of the best ways to
have a good time. He says,
take care of your fucking body. Okay, you,
I think you're totally right. If you ever
read Heidegger, yeah, it's a little, okay.
Well he said it.
The meaning of being capital B,
the big picture is located in care,
meaning what? We attribute our care,
what we give care to.
So you could care for a pair of
headphones and that gives your life.
Inherit me like, I'm sorry. Life
is not inherently meaningful.
Are you talking?
It's meaningful when you care about,
so you attribute care to somebody doing
Brian. He's looking at the screen.
All right, well look at it yesterday.
It's preserved. It's killing.
What is it doing?
It's kind of just making, okay, but why
are you doing that when she's talking man?
Huh? I know I was making
this special effect. Okay.
But my indirect in her
conversation and you were bro.
That's what just happened. It's pretty
sweet. Okay. We don't care though, man.
This is, a lot of people are not
going to see this on Ustream.
So let her finish what she was saying.
She said something important.
I love when you scold Brian. Okay,
well that was really, it was,
he just interrupted you while you
were on a roll. So fucking desperate.
Some childish shit. Dare you.
Some childish shit. We love you,
but you're a little baby anyway,
but you're right. And it
is about attributing care,
cause life in and of itself.
I don't think life is inherently
meaningful. I don't think that, uh,
there is some magical wizard
behind the curtain that,
that created all of us and
we're also special and awesome.
I think it is what you make of it. And
um, I wish I exercise more as the point.
I'm very sorry I'm stuck in my head.
You know what I mean?
I've been this way since I was
a little girl. When little,
when everyone else was running around,
I was laying on top of the monkey bars
and I've always been super fucking lazy
and I wish I had this,
this design,
like I wish I had your athleticism or
just something about me that enjoyed
sweating. Like I fly. I
just fucking hate it. And I,
you don't have to love it.
Everybody's different.
It takes every type of people
to make this world go round.
But we're going to give you some
Alpha brain before you leave.
Maybe wants to take that.
It'll get your fucking head and
gear and you'll see the light.
Go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the [inaudible] dot com link
and enter in the code name Rogan,
and you get 10% off. That also was, this
is a commercial and a conversation.
See how we do it.
That's what we do our commercials here.
Wow. Joe Rogan experience podcast.
It's organic.
I grow these bitches in manure.
Sun hit it.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
Oh,
sweet baby Jesus.
The dynamic duo or are here ladies
and gentlemen, the funniest couple.
I know the only couple of
comedians worth a fuck. Wow.
Wow. There's a couple other ones. I guess
Brian Duncan into Tasha are still have.
Yeah, they haven't pulled the
trigger. Made that shit legal.
Tom Segura and Christina Segura
who doesn't use the last name?
It's a girl on stage.
Why do you not?
Why did you not together you are more
strong. Do you want the real talk? Yes.
Legally.
My
name is Segora by stage
and because documents kid,
but because I uh,
my parents are Hungarian immigrants.
They escaped from Hungary
in 1969 went to Canada.
I was born there.
I moved to La in 1980.
So that stupid Polak Palicki name.
It's like my parents fought so hard to
get me here. And every time I see a club,
put it on the marquee, it makes
me proud. And it's a stick it to,
you know, I'm a fucking dumb Polak and you
guys can suck it. Yeah. That's who I am.
And uh,
you know
that's very, very admirable. Don't you
think they would like it more though?
If their name didn't hold
you back your fucking name
cause shit. Good luck
spelling that. Yeah. Good.
Let's finish you guys for all the marbles.
The other thing is at what point,
like if you've started, would you
consider like obviously you, you know,
20 years in or 10 or five,
but like after you've done a
couple things and you have your,
your name and then you change your name,
people who, who fuck are you, you know?
Yeah. You could, you could fuck
yourself up cause we learn from scratch.
You were what you were seven years
in when I already, whatever you do,
don't hyphenate that shit.
God damn cop out.
I knew a dude who hyphenated and
he took the wife's name last won,
somebody lost, somebody
failed. We're not doing it yet.
He was also a self proclaimed
feminist who was a male feminist.
Really leave that can exist,
but I don't know.
I feel like the concept of feminists
any more than I liked the concept of
masculine as don't have to concept
of someone's masculine centric.
That's ridiculous. Who the fuck
is more masculine centric than me?
I mean everything I do is meet,
had shit,
fucking cage fighting a choke
and people smoking weed.
He's talking about tags. Come on,
man, but I don't want to just be,
I'm not only concerned with
men, I'm concerned what the
whole fucking human race.
As soon as you start going, oh me, you
like to dance. I danced my ass off.
I didn't take dancing classes of that
movie. I did a dance scene. A zookeeper.
That's awesome.
With the lovely Leslie Bibb,
the the gorgeous blonde woman
from Talladega nights. Yeah.
She played my who say cool.
Rarely.
Rarely get to act and that of my
scenes are with her and Rosario,
Doris Dawson and Kevin James. I
was like, ah, that's so cool. Yeah,
she was really funny. She's
hauling changes. All those scenes.
I could tell you some shit that
this chick would say, well,
we're hanging around like in between
scenes were in the van on the way.
She's fucking hilarious.
But at a respect for her and I would not
repeat anything she said. Sure, sure.
Oh, that must be really funny.
She's hilarious. She's like a comic.
She's like a female comic. That's
great. She's hilarious and cool as fuck.
You're very balanced. You, you
like these Alpha male things.
But I find you to be very
balanced and you appreciate. Well,
I still need the Alpha male stuff.
You know what it all, I mean,
I wouldn't say Alpha male stuff, just
masculine type things. I'd slept,
but I'd like, why? Why, why?
Why am I supposed to pretend that I don't
like something? I like loud mustangs.
I like when you rev the engine,
it's stupid. He goes, no,
I have a Mustang and I'd love, it's my
favorite car. It's the dumbest car. Hap.
Yeah. Well, you know what's good about
it? It's loud as fuck. And it's stupid.
And I like listening to Leonard Skinner
did music in that fucking loud and you
know, yeah. You can go look at her,
you fucking loser. I don't care.
That's that is what I liked.
I liked MMA.
I like playing pool until fucking
six o'clock in the morning.
These are the things I actually enjoy.
I mean I'm not,
I'm not going to pretend that I don't,
cause I did for a long time in my
life when I was growing up though,
I always felt like there
was something wrong with me.
You know, like first of all,
I grew up in Boston,
which is a very pussy whipped town.
I mean it's a very manly town,
but there's not a lot of women there.
And especially amongst quote
unquote intellectuals, you know,
it's mean if you did hanging
around college people,
the amount of colleges per capita is
really high. It's like one of the, the,
the highest numbers in the country.
Then Boston one I think ridiculous.
And so most people are really educated.
Most people intelligence.
And when you get like a lot of educated,
intelligent people and they're
trying to impress people,
they tend to go towards the super liberal.
They tend to go towards the, you know,
the, there's something wrong with you.
You're a barbarian, you need to evolve.
They tend to get,
like you would tell someone that you,
you do martial arts and they would
look at you like you're insecure.
Like there's something wrong with you
for pursuing that and this is something
you need to get past.
Like I've had those conversations with
people where they judge you for the
things he enjoyed doing. And what they're
basically trying to do is they look,
no one wants to fucking run hills.
No one wants to, you know, beat a,
a t a tire with a sledgehammer.
No ones wants to do rounds on the bag.
No one wants to take class and fucking
strangle people for hours and hours.
But the only way to get good at
all that stuff is to do that.
So if you can persuade other people to
not get good at all the things that make
you uncomfortable, then you don't
have to feel as uncomfortable.
So if everybody was scrawny and sick and
smoked cigarettes and drank whiskey all
day, you wouldn't have to worry
about getting your ass kicked.
And ultimately that's one of the
reasons how, one of the things,
when the motivations for people,
when they do like get upset at people for
liking other things, you know, if you,
if you actually love, what
do you like hot rods, what's,
what are you doing stupid? You're
like hot rods and big dogs big here.
But the people that say that
are always the, the like the,
if they're that critical about what you
enjoy is because they're less happy.
It takes you a while
to realize that though.
I thought they were right and they would
be angry and critical with me about
things and I would think that they were
right and I would say, wow, you know,
maybe I'm a, and then I would then
eventually it took me a while ago.
Why do they care?
It took me a while to go,
why are they giving me a hard
time for things that I enjoy?
If I like listening to kiss, I
like kiss. Yeah, I'll be in my car.
Come on and sing along.
I fucking sing along as you think.
I think most people don't get to that.
I think it is something you start
to figure it out as you get older.
But then I was having this
thought literally earlier today.
Don't you ever look back and think about
people that like we're in high school
with you,
that you feel like had that clarity,
but you don't realize it til you're older.
You're like that person's disposition
and they're credible at like 15. Yeah.
I think it's their parents.
Yeah.
And if you grow up in an environment
where your parents or your parents don't
buy the bullshit, it's way easier to not
buy the bullshit, you know? You know,
my parents were very unusual. My
Dad is, uh, my stepfather Hippie,
and he was a computer program
and then an architect is a very,
very bright guy who was always, you
know, a pot smoker too when I was young.
Yeah. Tell you like him or would you
smoke with him or smoked with him?
When I was eight.
Hey.
Hey,
just once to see what it was like. Cause
I asked him, I'm like, what are you doing?
We guys are smoking pot. What does that?
And he goes, you want to try it? And I go,
can I? He goes, yeah, it goes
just a little, but you can
try it. And they gave me,
I don't remember the effects.
I don't remember what happened.
Probably fucked my brain up from life.
Yeah.
But I was taught or really early
on to don't don't believe the hype.
You know that there's a, there's a lot
out there that's bullshit, you know? Yeah.
A lot of laws that he like I would,
I would give it,
I got confused about something being
illegal. I'm like, but it's illegal.
This is illegal. And you know,
my stepfather was always like,
let me tell you something. That laws
that are not there to protect people,
they don't, they don't need to be there.
Those are, those laws are nonsense.
And it was a,
it was a really interesting way he put it,
the laws that don't protect anybody or
just bullshit laws. And I was like, wow,
what the fuck ever thought like hitting.
Then it really is when you really start
to think about like personal choice laws.
Like I remember in New York he couldn't
get tattooed, like tattoos were illegal.
Like for awhile,
back in the 90s I had to go to Connecticut
to get a tattoo and I was like,
how fucking stupid is this? You know,
this is the one I grew up in in Boston,
kickboxing was illegal. We used to
have to go to Rhode Island to fight.
We can fight in taekwondo
tournament's in Massachusetts,
but we had to go to Rhode Island
to find like why? What did,
the more laws there are,
the more problems there are.
Let people figure out what the fuck
they like, let them pursue it. Cool.
We got way too much.
We have way too many laws and we have
way too many people that have a career in
pro.
Not just protecting these laws,
but enforcing these laws
and building more laws.
It's like there's a whole business.
It's like, well, you know,
where are we says people always
say kill the lawyers first. Oh No.
It's like it's really is ridiculous when
they can catch little imperfections in
the text,
in the,
in the language of things are written and
they can exploit these things and it's
like why is everything so fucking complex?
It is.
Or the the lawsuit. Yeah to sue somebody
over. You know in Hungary there's a,
there's an amusement park that other
roller coasters made out of wood and it
doesn't even stop to let you on.
That was from like the Russian and it's
the most fun and scary as Shit fucking
die.
And how slow does it go?
Does it get on maybe like five down to
five and you literally like the people in
it jump off and then the fucking bar
doesn't even come down on your lap.
It's like this and you better hold
the fuck on cause you're going to get,
well you think anybody sues the
amusement park if they fall up? No.
It's your fault dummy.
Who wrote the,
I think you should be able
to sue for certain things.
I certainly think they should
fix the fucking rollercoaster.
That that's not what I'm saying.
What I'm saying is that there's a lot
of laws like that that are in place that
just don't need to be right.
Sometimes things are just common
sense and public opinion and you know,
it's common sense and not buy crack. If
you want crack, you can get crack. Yeah.
Cracks, illegal use. No,
there's no crack. Uh, uh,
people that are out the street protesting
why crack isn't legal. There's nothing.
You know, there's no crack advocates.
There's no crack legislators, you know,
but you can go get it. If you want
to go get it, you can go get it.
You want to really, do you want to
arrest the guy who's selling it?
That's poor fuck that's
running around selling crack,
which you need to do is make treatment
centers and need to do is find out what
the fuck happened on this poor kid
that he thinks it's okay to sell crack.
You know? I mean, that's the real
fundamental problem. Anybody look,
I don't know anybody. If I said,
hey man, I'm gonna, we're gonna,
we're gonna sell something that makes
your Dick fall off. You know they,
they know it's going to
make their dick fall off,
but we're going to sell it anyway. Are you
down? He went down and make some money.
I don't know a single person that would
go, what make people's Dick fall off?
Fuck. So why? Why? If you wouldn't
do that, and would you sell crack,
then would you sell something
that's going to ruin people's lives?
Of course you wouldn't.
There's no way you would do that.
You'd nobody would want that over their
head. And even if it was a lot of money,
man, you'd consider it because
you really do hate to be broke.
You don't want to do anything.
Ultimately, that ruins lives.
So that's the real issue.
The real issue is why are these
people willing to sell crack?
Why are these people willing to put other
people's lives and put themselves and
their wants and their selfish desires
ahead of all these other people's lives?
There's, that's the real
prosperity. Real world,
not the crack is legal so that
anybody would want crack the rib.
Real root of the problem is not
the cracks illegal. It's that.
Why would anybody want crack?
That's the real problem. The
real problem is who's who's educating
the children, who's raising them,
who was exposing them certain
things she was protecting them.
Who's making sure that you
develop a person that doesn't
have anger and hate and
selfishness inside them to the point
where they want to sell people poison.
There's poison that they're addicted to.
A lot of shitty parents,
a lot of shitty parents, man. That is the
real root of the issue. That's the real,
real root of the issue to everyday.
You see it in adults,
you go and you can tell right
away like you had a really bad,
but you see it when you have kids and
your kids or run other people's kids.
You see people fucking scream at kids
when you know where they learn that shit
from. You know, you see them angry and
hit each other with sticks and shit.
You know, you see weird shit
with kids that you know is from,
it's going on at home.
Did you see that video of that lady,
young girl getting beat by her
father was a judge? I saw that dude,
you don't even want to watch it.
It's horrendous.
She was 16 at the time and her dad is
a judge in Texas and he had a family
planning judge and he beat her with
a belt for downloading shit off the
internet. I think she downloaded
some illegal stuff off the internet.
Like you know, the songs was a
music. So she downloaded illegal,
he beat her with a fucking belt.
I mean beat her like full
blast whips and he's yelling,
I didn't get my Lickin,
I didn't get my licking.
And this is a guy who did not
know he was recording. Right.
And we're being recorded, right?
So this is what this guy's like.
That's when it's really terrifying
when you see people behind their mask,
you know, this guy is, uh, his mask is
that he's a judge and bit, by the way,
they're not even going to
pursue charges against this guy.
This is the same statute.
And talk about laws or statue of
limitations on that kid. That's insane.
That's a assault.
One of the David just beating your kid.
We used a weapon like I should be
in jail forever. Fuck him. You,
you pussy. You hit a little
girl with a belt because what?
Because your life is frustrating because
you're getting old cause your Dick
doesn't work anymore.
Which is it?
Which is it that causes you to pull the
trigger on beating your fucking baby
with a belt?
Oh my God.
I would never stop hitting
that guy if I saw that happen.
I would never stop hitting that guy.
I would never run out of one more.
I would just keep giving them one more.
Fuck you.
You want to beat a baby
with a belt of girl?
You fucking piece of shit that that could
even be argued that that guy's not a
plague. A blight on society.
You fucking shithead.
You could do that to your
daughter, man. Shun you. You Fuck?
You should live on a mountain now.
No one should talk to you.
You should be locked up in a fucking cage.
Fuck you mad if files too for that.
Yeah.
This fucking the Sandusky thing.
It's a joke. Paternal thing.
Holy Shit is this dark.
You know what's really crazy?
The guy who found him and turn him in,
his name is Mick Query.
It's almost like this is fiction.
It's almost like the world is becoming
more and more one becoming as 2012 comes
along, the story falls apart.
The plot starts to reveal itself.
The writing behind the script.
Look,
the guy named wiener was a politician
who was sending pictures of his dick to
girls online and thought he
could get away with it. I mean,
what rush limbo takes so many
oxycontin's. He goes deaf. Why?
That was the best writes.
What? And His guy,
Macquarie finds the most beloved football
coach ever is guilty of shielding
another beloved assistant coach from
fucking little boys for 20 years.
This guy was taking these kids on fucking
trips. They were staying with him.
He was bone, a little boys for
years, and they allowed him to,
they allowed him to. Wow. Yeah.
I mean, I don't know what the
solution needs to be killed.
You have to kill them that they've
destroyed lives. I don't think.
I think people would forfeit their
right to live, reparable, destroyed.
All those boys.
That guy fucked will never be the boy did.
They could have been without
getting fucked by that guy.
That guy owes a hundred lives cause he
owes more than he owes 100,000 lives
because he goes every live to these poor
fucked up kids are going to interact
with and perhaps molests boys
because of what happened to them.
But that happens with that. That's why
it happens in the first place. ABS.
So this guy,
this motherfucker called it caused a
ripple effect and this Macquarie Guy who
still has his job, even though he didn't
go running to the police, you know,
everybody wanted to keep
their job, it seems, it
seems like they were,
they were shooting this guy and
everybody wanted to keep the job,
but the guy who saw the boy getting fucked
in the ass should a rent straight to
the police.
But that's not what happened.
They weren't fucking just horsing around.
They were just sliding on the floor.
Guys story is,
they heard a rhythmic slapping and came
in to see a 10 year old boy with his
hands on the wall. Well, this guy
was fucking his little boy ass.
Whoa. Did you see the development
today as far as the email? No.
So McCreary sent out an email to friends
and they had excerpts of it on the news
that said that he said,
you guys know I didn't just turn
and run away like they're saying I,
you know, I had to make quick
decisions. I made sure it stopped.
So he was saying that because there was
make sure it stopped but fall fucking
pedophile suggested that he entered
intervened at that moment. Uh, intervene.
Well stopped it. In other words, the
first reports said that he walked away.
Right. He and his email is saying I
didn't just see it and walk away. I,
I stopped it from, I stopped
what was happening. Okay.
So his old version, did he say
why he didn't go to the cops? No,
cause it's just they just got a copy of
an email he sent to friends. It doesn't,
it doesn't go into these,
how did he not go to the cops?
That's the part that people are saying
that he went to his father and then the
next day he went to his father.
He went to his own father to tell him
what happened and then the next day he
went to Puerto Rico and then Pitino
told the athletic director and maybe the
president or the athletic director told
the president was that guy as a guy
who's trying to keep his fucking job,
and that's pretty gross,
grows with that guy supposed to do
is called the cops. Immediately.
Everybody needs that call is to the
cop and you don't let that motherfucker
leave. Yeah, you don't let
that motherfucker leave.
You beat that old man's senseless.
You leave her there and then you call
the cops. Then old fucking creep.
Fucking that 10 year old boy,
you're supposed to want to be violent
because if you have a tribe, okay,
it's a tribe of a few people that they
care about each other and protect each
other from all the other fucking
terrible things in the world.
When you find something like that,
that's God damn disease.
The real problem is that we have so
many people, there's so many people,
there's 300 plus million of
us on this one continent.
And because of that, not
even one continent, one piece
of the contract in America,
you know, and because of that
we've, we devalue each other man.
We don't appreciate each other and we
don't appreciate threats like that.
Threats become over there.
They're a threat over there.
We can separate from it.
I live in a gated community.
I closed my door at night and turn
on my alarm system. I have a gun.
I'm not worried. You know, we, we, we
need to get rid of all those problems.
And if you,
if you had a community and you had a
guy like this paternal fuck who allowed
this other fuck to bang little kids in
the asshole and didn't have him locked in
a
cage, you're supposed to tell
the both of them. You are not,
you're not looking after the community.
You guys were looking
out for your own asses.
All of you from the guy who caught
him, who didn't go to the cops, to,
to the paternal guy knew.
They all fucking know.
You can't be around a dude who's
banging kids in the ass and not, no,
you cannot. How this guy's taking little
boys on the road with them. I mean,
it's really dark. He had a fucking, yes,
he had a charity to help little kids
that were like underprivileged or in, in,
you know, troubled homes. And you know,
it's the craziest thing. But there was a,
some priests that had written
some stuff about finding boys.
It was really dark shit.
And it was, um, uh,
like shared emails back and forth.
But one of the things that
they were saying was that,
look for boys with troubled childhoods.
Look for boys who don't have a good
relationship with their parents.
And those are the ones they prey on.
The boys who are lost and alone because
they're vulnerable and they'll do
anything for love, you know, and
they don't even know while they're,
while they're having sex with a man,
they just know that they're happy,
that this man cares about them
because the people, the orphanage,
don't you know that this man is
buying them toys. So he would do this,
he would buy them toys,
he would take them to fucking to games.
He would do all these things and bone
them. It's like classic priests Shit.
It's the classic preciate it
the level, the level of planning
an evil like it goes into,
I'm going to set up a foundation,
a charitable foundation for troubled and
we're trying them and were convicting
them right here on the show. And I
know that's wrong. We can assume,
I know that's wrong,
but if that Sandusky guy isn't,
if he's not well arrested and that the
Macquarie Guy, how is he not in jail?
I don't understand that.
That tell you since Sandusky didn't
do himself any favors with that, uh,
that interview that he did on air
yesterday with Bob Costas at all because,
oh my God. When like there's just, you
get it. Can you get it Brian? Pull it out.
Let's see. Yeah, I mean there's the,
first of all, they're stuffy volunteers,
which if you have doubts, you should
probably have far less doubts. Laughter.
It was on NBC. It was on a rock
center, uh, with Brian Williams.
Dusky yeah. It's um, there's
certain things like if,
I don't know it, was it Matt Lauer who,
no, it was Bob Costas. Oh, Bob Costas.
He's even better. He's
tremendous cautious. A
brilliant man. Very smart guys.
His grasp of the English language really
makes you feel, yeah. He's a great guy.
I don't know words. He beat me. He
beat me up on news radio. He did. Yeah.
We had seen a fight scene
was radio and he flipped me.
He flipped me off the ground.
He's bringing by us. He's
a brother. Yeah, we had,
I got a chance to talk to him all night.
It was really cool. Very smart guy. Well,
there's just things like,
I mean,
I don't know if we're going to get the
interview or not, but like when you,
you know, when you're
asked a, are you a pet,
are you sexually attracted to young boys?
What do you think?
Like somebody who isn't, what would they
say? What's, no fuck no. Okay. Well,
what about am I attracted sexually?
I mean,
I'm not sexually define attractive.
Yeah.
Can I just bring up an
Oprah Winfrey thing?
I learned on the Oprah show
the web is buzzing of the cost.
This is telephone interview with Jerry
Sandusky speaking for the first time.
Since then.
It is then it seemed like it's a right,
it's a report on this is, this is not it,
the interview. No, they're talking about
the interview. Yeah. That's not it.
Obviously just look for the
interview. Yeah, the audio
is amazing. It's incredible.
Molested and uh,
and she had this whole segment where she
brought pedophiles on the show and they
actually got to say how
they court these children,
why they do it in any way. Basically
they groom children, like you said,
the vulnerable ones.
They can tell which boys or girls or
psychologically fragile and they groom
them. So like you said,
that's what that's called,
where they give them the candy and the
courtship and actually family members to
my last a lot.
She's like,
if you have an uncle that like is
really into hanging out with your girls,
like how loosened on my lab or that,
that's actually how it happens.
It's the neighbor, it's the
uncle. It's not the stranger.
It's actually people that, you
know, what the fuck is Redman?
I think it's like a faulty
products, you know? Is this,
it sounds like it
innocence,
completely innocent and falsely
accused in every aspect.
Good question. Well, I could say that, you
know, I have done some of those things.
I have horsed around with kids.
I have showered after workouts,
I have hugged them and I've,
I haven't touched her leg
without intent of sexual contact.
But, um, so if, if you
look at it that way,
um,
there are things that
wouldn't, you know, it would be accurate.
Are you denying that you
had any inappropriate sexual
contact with any of these
under race?
Boy, yes. I am
never touched their genitals. Never
engaged in oral sex. Right. Wow.
What about Mike Macquarie,
the Grad assistant who in 2002 walked
into the shower where he says in specific
be 10 or 11 years old that his hands
were up against the shower wall and he
heard rhythmic slap,
slap slapping sounds and he
described that as a rape.
I would say that that's false.
What would be his motive to lie?
You'd have to ask him that.
What did happen in the shower the night
that Mike Macquarie happened upon you
and the young boy.
Okay.
And we will rush showering and,
and horsing around and he actually
all the shower's on and was,
uh, actually sliding
across the, uh, the floor.
And, um, and we were, as I recall,
possibly like snapping a towel.
Horseplay
in 1998 mother confronts you about
taking a shower with her son and
inappropriately touching him.
Two detectives eavesdrop on
our conversations with you
and you admit that maybe
your private parts touched her son.
What happened there?
Well, I can't exactly
recall what was said there,
uh, in terms of, um,
what I did say was that
if he felt that way then I was wrong.
During one of those conversations,
you said,
I understand I was wrong.
I wish I could get forgiveness
speaking now with the mother.
I know I won't get it from you.
I wish I were dead.
A guy falsely accused or a guy whose
actions have been misinterpreted doesn't
respond that way.
Does he?
I don't know.
I didn't say to my recollection,
I wish I were dead. Uh, I,
I was hopeful that we
call the reconcile things.
Shortly after that in 2000,
a janitor said that he saw you
performing oral sex on a young boy in the
showers, in the Penn state
locker facility. Did that happen?
No.
How could somebody think they
saw something as extreme,
as shocking as that when it hadn't
occurred and what would possibly be their
motivation to fabricate it?
You didn't have to ask them.
It seems that if all of
these accusations are false,
you are the unluckiest and most persecuted
man that any of us has ever heard
about.
What you want me to say?
I don't think that these have
been the best days of my life.
Sandusky's attorney Joseph Amendola insist
the charges filed by the Pennsylvania
girl pregnant. You got a teenager
pregnancy a few days ago. Come out,
he 49 now you can kill it. 49 years
old. He got a teenager pregnant. Yeah,
it goes on. It goes on.
It's a of the feather,
but like doesn't let you think he's not.
I mean like if you're like,
I think you're totally right that
you, that you shouldn't, you know,
convict somebody just when charges.
But then like if you did have your doubts,
does that make them fade away? That this
guy's a creep? No. No question about it.
That's not how you respond. I of
course not you people that are guilty,
that are pretending to not be guilty, it
never realize how other people see them.
They always just tried to, you know, stay
calm and keep it together.
You would be freaking the
fuck out if that was you.
And all of a sudden someone was saying
that Thomson [inaudible] has been
touching little kids. I'm blowing him
in a bathroom. You would go crazy.
You wouldn't be, you'd have to ask
them. You wouldn't. You wouldn't.
There's no fucking way you would leave
it at. You'd have to ask them now.
He could be like, I have no idea.
This is horrifying. I, you know,
this is not only that, it's, it's,
it's put me in this terrible position
where it'll never be erased from some
people's memories that have heard this.
It's a terrifying thing. You know,
if you think someone falsely accusing
you of being a child molester like this,
you know, if someone was really
falsely accusing you would be,
you would be trapped. It'd be
like raging. You'd be like,
I haven't done anything.
What the fuck is going on?
And people have been falsely
accused before for sure.
I would like to see how they react
because then it doesn't sound like that.
Do you know of any popular cases?
I just assumed.
Oh Brian. I just assumed that
people have been, I mean especially,
I mean I'm sure it's happened
and molestation and murder
ones that always like
it blows my mind when you see like DNA
exonerates somebody and they serve.
Like that person was in prison for 20
years of their life in the hardcore prison
for like murders and rapes and
the whole time he was like,
I didn't murder somebody.
Everybody was like sure I can asshole.
Like I'm sure you didn't. Did you
see that guy that fought under card?
Oh my gosh, she's got no,
it wasn't mean. It wasn't,
it wasn't like a week or two before.
It was this guy was 52 years old.
He'd just gotten out of jail where he
was in jail for I think 29 years for a
crime he didn't commit.
He got
sad,
so scary.
He was boxing champ like inside and he
be one is to come back by 52 years old
professional box and you actually look
really good for a 52 year old is in good
shape
to,
I saw a piece on him before the fight
and just how he wasn't wanting to kill
everybody in the world even though like,
I can't imagine the anger
you got to have that you got,
how long would it take him to
be saying again? You know, man,
how long would it take him to bounce back?
That's a, that's a long Goddamn road.
Like a great attitude.
Way better attitude than people who
haven't served 29 years. Incredible.
I wonder how he pulled it together like
that. I Dunno. I really don't know. Yeah,
it's really sad.
That's,
and that's the one reason why I'm not
100% for capital punishment for capital
punishment when you absolutely
know. But the reality is, man,
there've been bad cops just like there've
been bad postmen, like there's been,
don't you think people would,
uh, not be like, you know,
there's a segment of people who oppose
the death penalty for crimes you can
commit now,
don't you think people would be,
there'd be less people opposed to it
if it were for like child molestation?
Like if you're like,
that's a punishable by death crime
now don't think less,
but you'd have to prove that the
person was 100% if they weren't,
if they were approved 100% yeah, people
would probably, well, you know what?
I think it would be harder to get
people to pull the trigger for trauma
molesting because a lot of people have
creepy uncles that they love that are
probably did. So there's,
I think it's more prevalent
in our society than we'd like to admit.
And it really is a symptom and a side
effect of the sexual repression that we
all enjoy in this country.
You know,
they're wired that way.
If you're a kink, is that,
it's unfortunate because how do
you express that cat? I think,
I think at the root of a lot of really
fucked up deviant behavior is a lack of
sexual choices and a lack of uh,
sexual education and a,
that the fact that it's dirty,
the fact that sex is forbidden,
the fact that it's something that you
feel like you're getting away with when
you do it.
And then you add to that fucked up people
that molest kids and he throw that all
in a big batch together and then you
have these kids that grow up with this
fucked up memory and they repeat the
same behavior over and over again.
And what is the root cause of it?
I mean all of it has got to
be like shitty parenting,
shitty parenting and the kid
being the less right. That's,
that's the root of all of it.
But also, you know, it has to,
there should be a little bit
more knowledge. We, we should,
we should be a little bit more open
about what the fuck is going on sexually
with people like in high school.
Do you think they have classes where they
talk about people that are trying just
trying to fuck you.
Do you think they have
class like that where they say,
Hey look this guy with candy and the
open van who's just trying to fuck you so
you understand he may just
trying to fuck you in your ass.
Wouldn't it be great to tell like 10
year olds really should know right there
cause otherwise the first time they
get raped or like what the fuck
drug,
drug resistance education.
All it did was teach me what drugs I
wanted to do when I was old enough to do
them.
It didn't really teach me shit.
Remember when you had to pass
around the fake drugs that look like
actually was real stuff that the police
had confiscated and you're like sitting
there looking at real weed when you were
like 12 going wow this is cool looking
but I've never seen this plant so my
brother's gone wouldn't have been more
valuable if they were like, hey if some
guy tries to fuck you in a van run.
But there used to be,
don't ever trust any,
any adults by themselves and wants
to take you somewhere. Danger,
danger, danger. Don't talk to strangers.
Don't open the door if you're alone.
So there is every now and then
you'll see someone somewhere.
So I'm fucking sketchy looking
at person and you just,
but it is, I do think it is the,
uh, it is the like unacceptable,
unfixable kink. It is like,
I think it's like pro,
there's hard wiring and there
are some products that you like,
this thing was done fucking broken.
It's a broken person and there's really
no cause everything else. If you're like,
this is what arouses me there, you can
get your, but this is the one that's like,
I can't, sorry. Yeah, you can't. And it's
a psychological too. It's my, it might
not even be sexual. So like making them
impotent might not even do it. Right.
They might still want to touch the
kids and do, who knows? I don't know.
I don't know if it's psychological
or it's just purely sexual, you know?
I think it's a, it's a weird fucking
obsession. Yeah. Terrifying. Terrible,
terrible obsession. You know, and it's, it
needs to be fixed. It needs to, you know,
someone needs to figure
out a way to fix that.
I think probably there is a
way with psychedelic drugs,
but they haven't pursued it enough to
figure out like what's the right dose and
how to administer it correctly.
Like if you give someone like a,
if someone's like a child molester or
someone's done something fucked up and you
give them like a heavy,
heavy dose of Iowasca or heavy dose
of Ibogaine or something like that,
my guarantee you there'd
be so disappointed and
disgusted with themselves.
They do, they kill themselves
or they would never ever
do it again. Really? Yeah,
I think so. I think, uh, I think
that's true with a lot of people,
a large percentage of the population.
I think most people, you know,
like when a guy said he wanted to kill
himself, I wish I was dead, you know,
that's what they think.
That's what they think. They,
they don't want to live this way.
They're just stuck in this
goddamn feedback loop,
this horrible loop that they
got in as a small child.
That Sanduski guy's probably
molested Williams a kid. Yes, sure.
Probably by another football coach or
something like that that I saw a story
that uh,
his parents started like a home for kids
and he lived in that home growing up.
Oh, Bingo. Well there you go.
That's where he got it. Yeah. Yeah.
He got it either from one of those
kids that he went to in the home with,
cause a lot of those had been molested.
If you're going to share a home
with troubled children. Yeah.
A lot of their troubles or
sexual, you know, God damn it
man. Yeah. God Damn it man.
Yeah.
And you know what,
while this fucked up country is overseas
steel and heroin and minerals in
Afghanistan and pretending
that it's for our greater good,
they could be over here and trying to
fix the real problem in this country,
which is fucking the youth. The
real problem is, are the, the, the,
the quality of our fucking plants that
are growing, the quality of our seeds.
That had been planted,
the quality of the human beings
that are developing right now,
and for a good percentage of them,
it's a fucking mess and
no one wants to fix that.
Could you imagine if we had an entire
country of people that lived in a good
neighborhood,
the entire country of people that lived
in a place where you didn't have to
worry about your kids getting
fucked by some creepy man, you know,
in the Netherlands even
there. Awesome. Well sort of,
but even there that look
the Netherlands in Holland,
a lot of crazy shit goes on in Holland.
You know how is a dark place globe
trotters know enough about it. Yeah.
The Red Light district,
all those words just
for tourists.
I don't think that the native Dutch,
I was just there like a few weeks ago
and just stand up out there. Yeah. Yes.
For like some, some showtime thing and
there was, the natives were saying like,
we don't go to those places.
The Dutch were actually conservative
people socially or it's a business thing.
They realize that that's what
attracts us. Dopey Americans. Woo.
You can smoke dope in public and
we can fuck hookers. And it's so,
it's so crazy to us how we can have
sex and we can do all these things and,
and that's why we go over
there and do that. Or an
English boy hall is not an innocent
place though by any stretch of the
imagination run wild ass place to,
you know,
do you know that's where some of the
best kickboxing and the world comes from?
Is that Dutch? Yeah. Yeah.
Boy Tie in in Holland.
Is that some of the
highest level in the world?
A lot of fighters from other countries
go to Holland to train in kickboxing.
I had no idea. Yeah,
there's a great culture,
great culture of a kickboxers from that
part of the world that there was a few
guys back in the day and you know, there's
a bunch of them that came successful.
It's particularly this Guy Ramon Dekkers
who went over to Thailand and fought
like the best ties in the world.
And he was a small guy.
So he's the size of the ties.
And then there was a guy named rob
came in and rob came in was a larger,
bigger guy. You met rob, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. He's a bigger guy.
It's like it would hurt. He's, he probably
the best kickboxer that ever lived.
Really? Yeah. And he's a
real super technical and he's
from, from Holland as well.
They're all crazy. They're wild wild
people, man. Yeah. To Fund people.
Did you see that sports science on
Bas Rutten's kicks? Oh yeah, yeah.
Ridiculous. They were like,
this is all wrong. All the
readings are off. He'll hurt.
And then he did it again.
Your insights are being traumatized.
Paint if you get kicked by this guy,
oh yeah.
Boss route and can kick fucking hard.
And he was one of the first guys in, uh,
in mixed martial arts fighting.
It was really fighting in an
organization called pancreas,
which was sort of a hybrid.
It wasn't quite mixed martial arts.
He had weird rules. You could kick full
blast but you couldn't punch to the face.
You could only slap to the face.
You get to like pull your hands
back and use open palm strikes.
But with boss route and figured out
how to do is pull his hands way back,
had like really flexible risks. So
really it was punching you with his palm.
So because with most guys
they were like slapping,
which doesn't have the same impact,
but boss was doing,
he was pulling his hands way back
like this and he was throwing punches.
He was the first guy to figure out that
he could throw punches with his palms
and he was fucking people up. You would
kick them and you would just go, whoa,
nobody kicks that hard. In
the, in this style of fighting,
he was kicking like a real powerful
Moy Thai guy would kick anybody who was
applying that in MMA. He was one of the
first guys. One of the first pioneers.
Yeah. It's a crazy God damn sport. The
sport of fighting. It's crazy to brag,
but I studied Kung Fu for two years,
Susan Griffith Park and I'm like, Gee,
I did. My teacher taught
us, says Muy Thai kicks,
and she said that they get like callouses
on their shins sort of deal. Yeah.
They get kind of numb. A lot of guys have
like bumps in knots and shit from me.
You know, you get like bloody spots and
bruises and the heal up and gets tough.
Eventually. Some guys even kick a
bamboo trees and shit. The cake,
banana trees and the kicker
just to kind of, you know,
it Kinda has some give to it,
but it's still pretty hard.
It does feel good to kick stuff hard.
God dammit.
Just dammit.
Just
do you think about Tom Mommy? It's
just, Oh yes. Whatever. No I don't.
I don't treat you like the enemy.
I don't have any.
How come you guys get along
so well as a couple as comics?
Because a lot of them like
you guys are genuinely happy.
Neither one of you guys just
like tortured, you know, and you,
you seem like better together.
You actually seen better together.
We all have the friend that when they're
with their other, they're different. Oh,
I know. Isn't that sad? Sad? I think
it's sad to watch. Yeah. I have a,
I have a buddy that can't do anything
right. When he's with his girl.
She's always, what are you putting
it there for? What? What does that,
why is it going to be here? Sit down.
What time is it? You are you ready? Yeah,
always. There's always a nag in there.
But you guys are like buddies. Yeah.
You know why though?
I think some women,
they make their spouse the enemy for some
reason they're unhappy with something
inside of them. But with
Tommy I think, I dunno,
I'm in therapy. I go to psychotherapy.
Yeah. When I work out my shit and I,
you know, I do it professionally and
also like, cause we're both comics.
Like I just did.
I think Tommy is way funnier than me and
I accept that and I like him commute.
I mean like I respect you as a
comic and I respect you as a person.
Yeah. So that's why, you know, as long
as he's the fucking man. Yeah. Dude,
it's awesome. Right? No. You Kiss,
you just kissing, all sang. Yeah. What
are you going to say? Maybe around man,
they just,
oh those are cute.
No,
but that was beautiful.
You know what other thing that people
ask me all the time, they're like,
are you guys a competitive?
And I'm like, what? No.
Like I guess cause comics sort of
inherently are competitive but like, yeah.
In a relationship that's way different.
Yeah.
Some people that's their whole thing,
their whole thing.
The female comedians are
considered novelty acts. Like I'm,
I think there's still enough sexism
in comedy where people were like,
are you guys ready for a lady comic?
And I'm like, the circus act right.
In a normal lineup. So, uh,
my career and what I'm trying to say
is never going to conflict with Tommy.
He's like,
it's preposterous to think that
we're controlling for the
same. No one competes with
it. Right. And that too. Yeah.
You have to realize that
somewhere along the line that you,
when your friends do better, you do
better everybody together. But you,
y'all go grow together.
But everybody gets fucking selfish and
they don't want their friends. I mean,
I know a lot of comics that,
I mean,
we all know a lot of comics that they
don't like the other people around them.
To be funny.
Oh sure.
You want to hold everything everybody
back because somehow or another they feel
like it makes them not funny.
You know?
Like I remember I had a conversation
with somebody and they were saying, wow,
fuck, do you take Joey d as in a row
with Umass? So funny. He's so funny.
He's ridiculous. I was like,
cause he's hilarious. Yeah,
we'll kind of stupid question is
that like, but to them it was,
there was ridiculous. Like what
they did, and this was a headliner.
I was talking to a national guy and
what he does is take a fucking terrible
comedian on the road with them.
And a terrible comedian would go on there
and eat his own dick for 20 minutes.
And then he'll go out,
look,
our goddamn hero who rescue
at the bar has been lowered.
People are looking to laugh. So he has a
couple inferior comedians on before him.
And then he goes out there and he looks
like a fucking Superhero, you know?
But when they see someone doing well,
they start thinking
these terrible thoughts.
This person's gonna ooze usurped my power.
They're going to,
people are going to be seeing them.
I'm going to be opening them up for
him and they start thinking crazy, man.
And it's crazy. It's stupid. It's
a dumb thing to do. It's a trap.
You can never be jealous.
You can only be inspired if you
want to feel any negativity.
Just fucking push it aside, ignore
it, rejected, refuse it and just say,
man, how awesome is that guy? I
wish I was that funny. You know,
I'm going to write more. You
know, I want to go do this.
I think that both Christina and I both
always been the type of person that likes
having funny people around.
Like we genuinely enjoy funny
people and we never like,
even when they're like huge personality,
cause neither one of us has huge like
overbearing personalities. The people.
So especially like offstage
when I'm around like,
well I feel like when I'm
around like Joey Diaz,
like a fucking movie is playing like
somebody who's pressing play on fucking
funny movie. How am I not going to like,
I'm going to watch him. I said, I've,
I've been at your shows were, um, were
backstage. I pull up a chair and I'm like,
so have you ever been asked him a
question? Have you ever been to Phoenix?
And he's like, Phoenix. And he starts on
us and we tell you something about it.
We were robbing us.
Guy Phoenix are like,
[inaudible] don't want a cap gun and
fly on his ass. Yeah. Like, I mean,
you ended up, my nose was bleeding
those up for three days. You know,
this dog deposes gone. Not only
is it like, not threatening,
it's like the biggest joy of a
night or you ask stupid Burke.
Yeah.
And he tells you, it's like,
he's like having a fucking TV on.
How about a show going on? Constantly.
Yeah. That's how I feel about it though.
We always, I always feel like Joey's
like a show that we bring with us.
He brings the party, he brings the party.
That's why he goes up first to, yeah.
I mean, he's a goddamn national
headliner. You know what I mean? Joey,
Joey's one of the best comics in
the country. And he goes on first.
And the reason why it goes on for,
cause he wants to,
he wants to go out there dancing and he
brings a party, you know, and he likes it.
And he also likes the challenge of
warming a room up. You know, it helps,
it makes it material stronger.
Joey's really calculated about his comedy.
You know, you would think that being
this wild, crazy guy that he, you know,
he's Kinda just kind of wings it, but
he also thinks about it a lot. You know,
he has a lot of thought behind
his comedy and he, you know,
he thinks that it's good for your
comedy to go up cold like that.
He likes to do it for sure. You know what
I'm saying? He used to do it in Boston.
Yeah. I was just talking to a buddy about
this. Like they used to do a a night,
like they would do like dawn Gavin's
show and Don Galvin was a national
headliner and one of the
biggest acts in Boston.
And he would go on stage first and it
was his show and he would be the host of
the show.
And so he would bring up like if we did
like we're going to do Thursday night at
the icehouse again this week. So if
you're around, come on down bitches.
Cause it's a party. It's an
awesome show. It's a really,
really intimate only 85 seats
and a it sold out last week.
It'll probably saw it this week too.
And who else is doing it? Brian,
I'm going to announce the whole lamp
tomorrow by John Reape is going to do it.
Your friend Yoshi and I got some
other secrets to hilarious dude.
It was a blast. So fun. So
cool. Yeah, this is awesome.
As crowd the best. Yeah. Yeah.
Just the best. They're on board from
the first minute. Yeah. They're so cool.
You know I, that's the, the,
the greatest joy to me is that
whenever I go to comedy clubs,
people always say how nice my crowds are.
That they're nice and generous.
I hear that all the time. Everywhere. Like
they were so nice. They tip, they try it,
they know how to drink, they fucking
keep it down and an amateurs. No. Um,
so, but like you say, this show that
we're going to do Thursday night,
if we're going to do it in Boston, I
would go on first, it would be like the,
the Joe Rogan show and I'd go out and I
bring all these different people up and
then at the end he'd do like 15 minutes,
20 minutes,
whatever it is and close it out.
So that's what the guys would do.
They would do a little bit
in the beginning and then
they would fuck around in
between each act. They would fuck around
and do that Thursday, no way to do it.
And does that take the steam
away from being a headliner men?
I think it goes a little bit,
yeah.
Awesome. I think it takes the steam away
from a set cause I want to see someone,
when I see a guy, when it gets a Stan hope
or David towel or something like that,
I want to see a 45 minutes set.
Plus,
I want to say like an hour or
something like that. Because when you,
when you see like a 45 minute set or an
hour set, then you see a real set. Yeah.
You see the,
you get to fully sink in the experience
of them shifting subjects and building
momentum and changing gears. And it's
all this one thing. You know, it's,
it's like seeing an Avatar in
two chunks, you know? It's like,
you know what I mean? Like you
wouldn't want to do that. You'd want,
it's a great movie,
but you'd want to watch the whole thing.
It'd be just as good if it, I mean, you
probably enjoy it still if somebody,
you know, put an Adam Sandler movie on
for 20 minutes in the middle of Avatar,
but it wouldn't be the same. I'm not
ever calling my act Avatar, but you know,
it's a, I think anything you
do where you're, you're fully,
wholly concentrated on that moment, you
know, I think it would make it better.
Sure. So I don't, I don't
like doing it. Right.
No thank you. Find that's the key. Like,
I mean, I, I, we always talk about this,
that how some comedians become
so well loved and so successful.
Like Larry the cable guy, I love
shitting Dick Jokes. All right?
I'm not above any of that,
but I think his fans and people that
love him just want to hang out with that
guy. Right? Like it's
friendly and it's, yeah.
It's like you want to be around that
guy for 45 minutes in here and be in his
world. It's not necessarily who's the
best craftsmen of the wording of the joke.
It's your essence. It's, you know, that's
totally true. He was a human being, right?
Yeah. And I've heard people say that he's
racist and I've heard people say, well,
he has some jokes, racial jokes,
but what the fuck you, you know,
this is the real issue.
The real issue is why we live in a
world that everyone's so goddamn fucking
sensitive. You still a joke about
everything and anything, you know,
especially these radical Muslim fucks.
These guys have really got everybody
a corner because he can't even draw
Muhammad. You draw Mohammad,
they want to stab you.
Like really dude going to draw your guy
and he can't even draw and what have you
drawn real good like this is,
you know,
it's like Leonardo Davinci wants to draw
Muhammad, he can't, you got to shoot him.
Come on Bro. That's ridiculous.
You guys are being ridiculous.
You should be able to tell when
you cut humor out of the equation,
when you're your society's humorless,
when there's things that
are off off subject you,
you cut out all lines of inquiry,
you cut out like real observing,
you cut you,
and then you force everybody to sort of
subscribe to a predetermined pattern of
behavior that's politically
correct because unless you
can tell jokes about shit,
then I don't know.
I mean you might tell a
joke about something that's
absolutely horrible and it's
not funny at all.
But in trying,
you test the waters and you know,
sometimes there's some poor posture shit
going on and if you say people can't
joke about it and then one guy does joke
about it and fucking knocks it out of
the park and everybody's Howlin
guess what? That guy had joked about.
It's got to a point and you might not
want to deal with that point because
you're living in a fucking fantasy world
where you want everybody to not talk
about your particular subject, you
know, whatever the fuck it is, what it,
whatever it is, whatever taboo
you got going on inside your head,
whether it's religion or sexual or
whatever, whether it's, you know,
saying certain words or whether it's,
you know,
saying you don't believe in
God whenever the fuck it is.
If you say that someone can't
draw Muhammad and someone
can't make a south park,
they couldn't even make a cartoon where
they pretended they were going to draw
Mohammed. I mean, what was
the full extent hummus?
Hamad was actually on South Park. He was
the early days early for this. Right.
And then the second one, he was at
black bar. Then they stopped him from,
they stop them from putting
Muhammad on again. Right, right.
And they made them do it
at like he, Mohammed was a
teddy bear. All right. Yeah,
he was a, he was a weird look and tell
him. Yeah. Yeah. I can't remember.
But it was some ridiculous shit where
they were when they were being threatened
where they like, you know those guys?
Yeah. But I don't remember that.
That was a while ago.
They were being threatened and I know
that one people have been killed for it
and it was at one woman that had to
change her identity because she tried to
make a certain day draw Mohammed Day.
Yeah.
You know,
and she kind of went on and went deep
with it and thought she was being cute and
they're like, bitch will cut
your fucking head off. You know,
you want to play cute. My appeal to
my radical Muslim friends please.
The Path that you're taking me cutting
people's heads off for drawing your guy
is not that good one. Okay. You don't
need to concentrate on such silly things.
This is a crazy way of doing it of course.
But the problem is man,
that part of the world has
a lot of shit and it's in,
it's in an environment that has been
there for 10,000 years and it's very
difficult to change things.
The best way to change things like the
way America change things by moving move.
Everybody moved here a few hundred
years ago from somewhere else,
and then this was the, the the next stage
of change. Right. But if you go, you know,
if you live in a place where there's not
that much physical change in, you know,
and over the hundreds of
hundreds of years, it's
the Middle Ages there.
I was there in July and it's literally
just like shitty brick walls and just
like mud huts and then
the woman in the Burka,
and if your husband really loves you,
he builds a wall around your backyard
so the wife doesn't have to wear a burka
while she's doing chores in the backdrop.
It's like it's the year 1300 they're very,
yeah,
he said they catch a man fucking boys.
That's right. Yeah, that's what they say.
That's the room. The oil rig, the oil rig.
Oh yeah,
man.
I did a show in between Iran and
Iraq on an oil rig oil platform.
It was a mile long,
half,
half Iraqi soldiers and half US marines
and the marines were teaching the Iraqis
to guard their oil.
And uh,
so I was sleeping on this tanker and it
smelled of gasoline all night and you
would see the spot while they stink too.
Yeah.
But uh,
you would see spy ships roll up anyway,
I got to tour the Iraqi metrics.
Yeah.
They try to black like Iran
would pull up their tank
and they would have the word
Iran on the side of the boat,
but then they would like black it out.
Like with black paint.
We are not deer run.
I pictures,
I will show you the pictures pull
up to this shit and we sold it.
Yeah.
So they're spying on us.
Training the Iraqis and I got to
tour the Iraqi barracks and uh,
it's first of all, I mean it's
just, it's completely, look, we're,
we're really great at being military.
The Americans have that shit down.
Like the Marine Corps is,
we're fucking real.
And they're back throw just wires,
loose water bottles loose.
They would take shits in over the
hang their ass over the oil platform,
take a shit in the water
and then fish in the water,
they just shit in and then eat
the fish and they a lot of water,
I dunno man.
And as a seasoning,
those guys eat it would probably taste
pretty good, but it's not bright to,
to,
to fish where you don't think they can
shit that much to have shooting a sudden
they shit around.
Really thinking what else?
Well,
here's another thing.
Oh there's probably how many guys
were on the $50 hundred dollars?
No more than 500.
[inaudible] here's the thing too is like,
if like if you're,
if you shit,
where'd you shit last night. Oh,
right here. A spot. Don't fish there.
Okay.
So I went to lick their there,
the rent and they had mattresses
that were folded dirty,
dirty mattresses up against
like this wall. And I was like,
what are the mattresses? Four?
And uh, the guy was like, well,
it's a thing called man love Thursdays
because Thursday is there Friday.
I forget what it is. And,
and he's, they say, what did
they put the mattresses down?
And then the guys, they fuck each other
on the mattresses. And I know, I mean,
who knows if that's just like a
speaking douche bags, I don't know.
But he also said that he
broke up fights where one guy,
like I'm saying like Americans being
like in the Rockies are a bunch of homos.
Yeah.
And then,
but then I had a commander telling me a
story where he had an Iraqi soldier like
pound on his door at two in the morning
and the guy had bite marks in the back
and on his back and he was
bleeding from these bite marks.
And finally the commander to do that.
He thinks some guy was trying
to fuck him and he, you know,
wasn't allowing and the guy bit his back.
So you know,
the homosexuality from my
understanding is that it's situational.
Homosexuality were like,
because they can't date women and you,
you have to just get married that,
you know,
they choose men because of
the situation they're in.
And it's not gay, it's not
considered gay. It's just like, okay,
it's totally swollen.
They don't consider themselves gay.
They can just consider themselves
really into fucking, yeah,
you're just just whatever.
Yeah, whatever happened.
Those who don't want it well,
yeah.
In places like Saudi in there too, they,
yeah, I'm pretty sure it's prevalent.
It's a really,
it is and it's so foreign and as a,
as a Westerner and you really,
I try to be open minded and wrap my
head around their culture and there are
certain ways they treat women that I'm
just like, Yo, I'm not really sure is
that as far as we know,
and we'll, you know,
there's a lot of debate about when
the beginning of civilization was,
but as far as we can tell it was there
as far as we can tell. There was in Iraq,
Sumeria. Mesopotamia. Yeah,
and that's where the first
written language first
mathematics are attributed to
these guys. They're the first,
any, any knowledge whatsoever.
It was strongly or astrology.
They had the constellations mapped out.
They had a different astrological signs.
They had 13 I believe instead
of the 12 is that correct?
I think that's something
like that. Anyway, I don't
remember how many they are,
but what the point was with these people
like had this really amazingly advanced
civilization 10,000
years ago and today it's,
you know,
it's more advanced than it was then,
but they still have like a really like
suppressive ancient style culture.
And it's like you really kind of weird
to see this combination of like modern
technology,
extreme a wealth in places like Dubai
and the United Arab Emirates and extreme
wealth, but also this
like weird, you know,
with the modern stuff and
this weird ancient stuff.
Know like the whole thing about, you
know, um, the, just the laws of Islam,
the women wearing and all of that, that,
that crazy. I mean, when did that start?
Well,
it's a theocracy.
You have to understand that even in the
Gulf countries that are more progressive,
like, um, you know, the United Arab
Emirates, where'd you buy is like,
there's places you can
drink a beer for ex pats,
not the Muslims because they
don't drink. Yeah. But I mean,
you'll be in a Mcdonald's and you'll
hear a call to prayer and the expectation
is that you got to put down your mcrae.
Really? I'm dropping. Rolling. Yeah.
Like you gotta get down. Who Calls
to prayer? Um, no, at the mosques,
like you hear a five times a day.
Like the first time I heard it,
I didn't even know what that sound was. It
sounds, it's like terrifying. It's like,
ah, and you're like, what
the fuck is happening?
So you could think of,
it's like the end of [inaudible].
Yeah, you don't. And as it, you're like,
it sounds like you just want to cover
your ears and just cry. And that's their,
that's their call to prayer. So you just
don't know what the fuck's happened.
Do you, you know, the,
a lot of people saying that
there's something to having
some sort of an extreme
discipline along those lines,
that it does keep you billing line and
facilitates family and it facilitates,
it's possible.
It doesn't always,
obviously if they're fucking
little kids in the ass.
Yeah. I don't know. Right now
people are that everybody across the
board. But the idea that, uh, you
know, some intense form of study, like,
like Islam or like Buddhism
or Christianity or like
anything where you're really
getting involved in the,
you know,
the practice of some intense
discipline and some intense study of,
especially if you have strict
enforcement. Yeah. That's that,
that's the key right there, man.
When you have like a, you know,
in Iran where they have the
religious police and in addition to,
or if you go to Saudi Arabia, they have
that they have like religious police.
Yeah.
We had somebody who was the old Soviet
Union was going to get arrested.
Oh, I almost, and Ramadan, I was there
during their, their holy month of Ramadan.
I was in the back of a van
drinking a bottle of water
and the marine I was worth,
it was like, what the fuck and
model out we're on the freeway.
If someone sees you on the freeway
drinking water when the sun is still up
during Ramadan, the religious, they
can report you to the religious police.
And as a Westerner,
they'll throw you in jail.
And that's in the hip city of Dubai.
Oh yes,
and you get sent to jail for like two
months and it's like a $3,000 penalty and
they all feed you.
They don't feed you,
so your relatives have to come and
feed you if you have the misfortune of
getting put into jail in the Middle East.
So I don't know why they don't eat and
I don't know why they're plugging Dubai.
Is this like wild west? This like
Vegas of the Middle East? It's,
it's still Muslim.
You guys like it's not it.
It enraged me to see sex in the city,
to taking place in like Abu Dhabi.
Like are you kidding me?
Like this is not a place for you
slut. Yeah. Dot.
Don't old sled and really confused
thinking that sluttiness was acceptable
and not sad. Oh, that woman's not
sad. She's all fucking panther.
She's out there having a good
time. She's hot. You go girl.
And all these women with broken vaginas
lined up to see this fucking crap.
You get them off the sloppy Ted's just
like Clint Eastwood had people thinking
they can keep an orangutan as a pet.
Right? You can't fucking do that, man.
I think I'll rip your arms off.
Stuffed them up your nose.
Did you hear about that guy with the
hippo? You didn't hear about this guy.
I saw something.
It was a guy's famous on the Internet
for having a pet hippo that he rides.
It actually rides this hippo.
He found it when it was a cub raised it,
it's whole light waves that well,
it finally fucking chilled them.
This poor fucking silly cunt
was killed by the animal.
Shocker.
That kills more people
in Africa than any animal
to be fucking oh yeah, dude.
Yeah. Tigers are actually in Asia,
but um, they, they, they bite people
in fucking half, man. They're,
they're actually like a tight,
well,
I think there's somehow or
another like cousins to a pig. Uh,
they used to think they were like really
closely related, but another thing,
there's some just shoot and they're like,
but whatever it is,
they're all this fuck.
Well,
they are as a giant fucking animal that
is super aggressive and really mean and
just bit the fuck out of this guy.
And they found this corpse
mauled in the water. Well,
he thought it was cute that
he used to ride this thing.
You can't grow up with an animal from
like from an early age that and it would
not fall in love with you
that it would still do this.
It's got a weird still in some ways I
think people get aggressive with people
and they hit people,
you know,
like brothers and sisters hit each other
and they don't have enough strength to
hurt each other, you know? But if
your brother was a fucking gorilla,
an 800 pound gorilla and you were a two
month old baby and your brother got mad
at you and just fucking club do you
in the head and he would kill you.
The problem is, you know when, when
babies get managed or they're, well,
they're both babies and they really
don't have much impact to their slaps.
This is a completely different thing.
That's Hipaa.
This hippo got mad like for a moment, this
guy's probably an annoying douche bag.
Why is he riding his hipbone the
first place, right? They're fed him.
This guy's fucking crazy.
He's a crazy person.
This is not what you're supposed to do.
What's everybody knows that you're not
supposed to fucking even make contact
with these. There's this guy
bald, by the way, he's a big guy.
What city was it was a marble.
I think there's a South Africa.
Um, yeah. Why do people need exotic
pets? Why? Why must you see that?
You saw that you guys saw the
guy in Ohio, right? Yeah. Yeah.
The crazy guy who had all those
animals who killed himself.
Let all the animals free kill themselves.
At least that guy had them in
cages, you know, and that guy,
they knew it was a fucking,
uh, who is a loose cannon.
They said that he had threatened to do
that before they had an issue with the
cops.
It's like all like these fucking animals.
It's crazy asshole.
When I was going to say that was the
district of upon us might not even want it
to kill him.
He might have gotten mad at him.
Like he would bite another hippopotamus,
like, get off me bitch. Stop writing me.
I want to fucking rest. But when you do
that too, a little flimsy ass person,
they break and they die.
There's a video that Brian turned me
onto of lions trying to kill a hippo and
it's the craziest thing ever.
They can't kill it.
The jump on his thing bite then
it's kind of fucked up in the hip.
I was just like getting
mad, like, get off me bitch.
But they keep buying them and keep them.
They can't kill it.
He's like armored and what they're doing
is biting through his spine slowly.
That's how they're killing them.
They're choosing to pick a spot on a
spine and they're pulling chunks of it out
and he's like barely
noticing that they're there.
That's not an animal you want to fuck
where no fuck worth. As human beings,
we're actually quite
vulnerable in the wild,
like the our only
protection is our brains.
We don't have an exoskeleton or I
always say, think about a fucking house,
cat house Canada. If a house cat
wants to kill you, could you imagine?
Could you imagine what that's like?
Have you ever been around a feral
cat wildcat there? Scariest fucking,
they're scary.
They're really terrifying.
I've been over around feral cats that
I thought were going to attack me.
And it is a dangerous moment like where
you like this thing can do some fucking
damage. It can jump all the
way up to your face easily.
A cat can easily jump right up to
your face and bite your fucking face.
You imagine a wild cat claws.
Dig It into your head.
Won't let go biting your face
and kicking with his back leg.
That's absolutely frightening.
And they're tiny. They're tiny.
You saw my little cat let us pass.
And what does she wish she said
were like three pounds or something.
But if she wanted to fuck me up,
that'd be terrifying. In Ball. Scary.
I lived in Boston for a
summer one time and uh, my,
I was staying with my friend on
a first floor apartment and they,
I slept on the couch and the couch was
right next to the first floor windows and
they would open the window and it had
a screen and there was a neighborhood
Ferrell,
crazy maniac,
fucking like emotionally unadjusted cat
when I'm chilling, just laying there.
It would jump up onto the screen and go,
like, I wouldn't show
up, I would levitate,
like jump up off the thing and it would
just sit there and scream closet crazy.
Looking at PSI, I would have
fucking near harder about that.
Toxo plasma,
that parasite that a lot of
feral cats have in there.
No, it's a, it's a rat parasite.
It starts out in rats and it hijacks a
rat sexual reward system and gets these
rats attracted to the smell of cat piss.
So like the rats go around the cats,
the cats eat the rats, the cats get it.
And then the cats give it to
people usually from feces,
from stepping in their shit or dropping
your food in there and you pick it up.
Yeah. And it affects
human, uh, the human brain.
It affects the way people behave
and makes men more impulsive.
It's a responsible for a disproportionate
number of motorcycle accidents.
They checked people that are crashing
motorcycles and they find out that a lot
of them are infected with
this toxoplasma shit.
And in Europe it's like
really prevalent anywhere.
There's a lot of wild cats. It's really
prevalent like a Europe and France,
80% of the people are in fact, it
would toxoplasma, yes, 80 in America,
it's over 60 million.
It's really crazy.
But that cat might've had that and
it might've been just, I'm not,
I can't even describe to
how terrifying it was.
I don't think they hear a
mapped out the behavior,
the behavioral change that had,
hasn't cats because I've only heard
about the behavioral change in humans and
rats. So just really interesting
that I, I've never heard anything.
There's a guy named Robert Sapolsky,
this the,
a the leading scientist on all this shit
and he's got some amazing videos on it
and you know, he goes into
depth about how, uh, they,
they really are just sort of wrapping
their head around this, the, uh,
the extent of the infiltration of this
parasite into the, into human beings.
I mean, it's like, it might be like half
the population of the earth are fact.
It's really crazy. Yeah. I mean, because
in Brazil it's 60% and France, it's 80%.
It's, it's like it's really high and a
lot of different places in South America.
It's, it's like I said, over 60
million. That's the, the estimate.
People don't even know, you know,
mean we always talk about it. Like we,
you know what if I had it,
I was around a cat when I was young.
I had a feral cat that I raised, you
know, and uh, Brian's been around cats,
Kansas whole live. Joey Diaz has like
11 cats. What would you tell him?
He has 11 cats and a
lot of them were wild.
He's to take wild cats in and
feed wild cats outside. Wait,
what could that do to you though? We don't
know. Fucks with your brain, man. Yeah.
You know,
your immune system is supposed to keep
most of it in check and if you have a
healthy immune system, but they, they
don't know really. They don't, I mean,
it affects people in different ways.
Could you imagine everybody's just
racing that, hang around with cats.
That's just gave me a huge, huge
ruthless dick. Imagine if like,
it wasn't Viagara that you needed,
it was just,
you gotta be around a lot of cat shit.
Joey's got a Bagel.
This is, this is what happens,
bro. Here's, here's the good news.
Here's the bad news. The good news
is meant to Dick bigger and stronger.
Okay.
What's the bad news?
The bad news is you become a crazy person.
Yes.
Eating itself. Your brain is like,
in fact, when the cat parasite,
I heard a lot of people say
this cat person I saw that about
if the positive was a dick got
bigger and was hard at will.
If your Dick was like a Rhino Horn,
they can always call upon the, uh,
that hippo story made me reminded
me of that asshole with the bears,
grizzly man,
crazy theater.
And we laughed so hard.
That kind of cemented our relationship.
There was a moment and we watched,
we watched that documentary in
the theater and there's probably,
there's 40 or 50 people there and we kept,
we were the assholes.
They were likely to have fucking
done like the whole time.
And then there was a scene,
well,
I'll never forget where they interviewed
a pilot that would fly Timothy out
there and uh,
and the place is quiet and we're
sitting there watching and then they go,
what did you think when you
like would drop them off?
And he told you he was going to be with
bears for months and the guy goes, well,
honestly I thought he was retarded
and we laughed so loud
and everybody in the theater
and when we look at where did you guys
see it? We saw it in some dilemma.
I saw that in Hollywood and
the whole theater was laughing.
I saw it in a gray zone. Everybody
thought it was funny. Yeah.
I think you started with Eddie.
We were blazed. Of course. Every
moment of the movie was Hilarious,
man.
We were laughing.
It was like a God damn comedy
when he was playing with the shit
out. He's like, no dude,
it's stuck up there.
Shit. We were laughing
so hard and that's, that place
felt like it was a dean of stuffy.
I think Lemley crowd generally I
need to move to Pasadena. Yeah.
Because the ice house get myself
a mansion up there. Shit. Yeah.
Dean is where it's at.
I liked it.
It's what the San Fernando Valley intended
to be. I grew up in the valley. Yeah,
but they wanted it to be like Pasadena.
Pasadena is better.
Some hearts are got in the valley, but
summer, whenever we do the ice house,
they were like, people are fucking
really genuinely nice out here.
It doesn't feel like La.
It feels like a different type of
homeless people are all old ladies too.
There was no like homeless guys are old
ladies and they make these like tent,
like these,
these forts and they're so nicely folded
like blankets and cans are folded.
Even sad shit dude.
It's really makes me feel really bad
when I see some woman and you know,
I see her out there on her own. I don't
know why it kills me. I don't like those.
It makes me, I feel like some
old guy like to carry, so still
I see an older, I see an old, a woman
and I feel terrible.
I don't you hate seeing old,
like I'm talking to older people doing
like, like having like judge your garbage.
Like can you see like, uh, like a seven,
uh, clearly somebody in their seventies,
like just having any job really. I feel
like sometimes they like that though.
Like my mom retired and then went back
to work at a fucking Amish restaurant
gift shop just because she was bored
out of her mind. That's different.
He's like getting excited an hour.
You can see it on someone's face.
You can see when they're like, ah, I gotta
do this to get the, you know. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. That sucks. Well, you know,
it sucks because you also imagine
yourself doing that. Of course,
when you're tired and old and yeah,
you really should be resting and
enjoying your last days on this planet,
but for your fucking
transitioned into the afterlife.
But now you've got to fucking
hat on. You're working at
Chuckie cheese, you know,
hey kids, what do you want? You
want a special and you want pizza?
Do you want to try it? That's why
they be done daily. Double Dose.
This, my parents generation cause they
really got fucked in this recession.
A lot of people that are planning
on retiring can't do that now.
You worked their whole God
damn life and now what? Yeah,
there's a guy who lives down the street
from me that was trying to build a house.
He had this whole speech,
he had a plot,
picked out a really nice spot with a
beautiful view and everything and he was
putting all his money towards this and
fucking stock market crashed and all the,
all the bullshit went down the economy,
shit, the bed, he, he lost his,
he lost his savings. He lost
everything. He lost the whole pile.
Just has this lot is beautiful lot that
represents is his dreams that will never
take place and he's an older guy man.
He's so,
he's not going to be
around that much longer.
That really tells me there are people
that retired at exactly the right moment.
You know what I mean?
Like there are people who got their
money out when it was at a peak and then
there was people who like
were like literally the,
it's like a like a cliche
like buddy cop movie.
Like I'm retiring next year and you're
like that guy just from sticking around
like till may or whatever.
It was like lost his net worth 50 60
completely changed his fucking life.
Yeah, that crazy low. A lot of people
planned on, everything's staying the same.
They're like, we just got it. We're
just about to escape here and boom,
the floor falls out and not
only are you out of a job,
not only do you no longer have
a pension, but oh, guess what?
You can afford your house anymore.
Oh, well you were almost homeless. Oh,
look at this. Now you're sleeping at
your friend's house. Like Holy Shit.
You have your kids and your wife and your,
you're staying at someone else's house
and you were in their basement all huddle
up together and you're like, holy
fuck, I can't find a job. Boom.
That's what's happening to a
lot of people map. There's a,
there's a lot of people out there
that it just stopped, like the, the,
the machine stopped and everybody was
like, what's going on? Where are the jobs?
There are no jobs. There's no jobs in
Ohio. I mean there's a few clubs in Ohio,
like Toledo and Cleveland.
Yeah.
It's so sad because there's
nothing for people to do Detroit.
You got to see it like, oh no
one talks about it. But like,
I did Detroit twice this year and like,
uh, you know, there's, there's, uh,
the club isn't actually improper
Detroit, but you, you know,
you fly in then harbor that club. No,
I did. Um, I did the comedy castle,
which is a suburb of it or something.
But you drive through and like the,
you know, the fucked up
part is, um, it's actually,
I think seeing the industry places that
have closed that used to be this factory
and then all the windows are
broken out. You're like, Holy Shit,
that's a place that like 2000 people or
whatever you used to work at and it's
just gone. You ever seen those
videos where they drive down hole?
Huge. Just mile after mile of abandoned
houses. Yeah, it's like craziness.
And so it really does look like some
Mad Max Shit, you know? It looks like,
like what? What comes next? You know,
what is this like? This is a large scale.
It's Goddamn Detroit, Detroit rock city.
It's where mustangs come from. It's,
we're Corvettes come from sort of
the Bowling Green Kentucky now.
But you know what I'm saying? It's
like that's where, you know, cars,
American cars were built,
really moved to Canada.
That was his first job at
Chrysler factory. It's,
I don't know if is there anymore?
I don't know. Probably in Mongolia.
I just heard this guy on NPR,
he wrote a book about
how this generation of kids, you know,
your Momma always told you, be a doctor,
be a lawyer, being accounting.
Because those jobs you'll all,
you always have a job. Well not
now because you can outsource that.
You want your taxes done cheap, you can
send them to a guy in India that can,
that knows tax law. Same with
everything else. So this generation,
they're going to have to get creative
in terms of like how they think,
create their own jobs,
create their own way of making money.
Like those those days are slowly
dwindling down those, those trade. Yeah.
Yeah. We'll also, when you have the
Internet and you're sending files,
it doesn't matter if you send a file to
the account accountant up the street or
if you send the file to a guy on the
other side of the world. Oh yeah.
If he's willing to do it cheaper.
Yeah.
It's if our fucking very
strange time and mechanics good.
The real problem is right now we
are slowly being forced to live.
The reality to the rest of the world has
been operating under for the past few
decades. That's really what's
going on, you know? And
everybody was like, you know,
America is not a third world
country, you know? Yeah.
Well when everything becomes
the same, guess what? Yeah.
A lot of it is going to be like a
third world country because as we more
interconnect with the rest of the world,
you know,
and as our facade of an economy
slowly evaporates into nothing.
This,
yeah,
we were really are forced into a situation
that looks eerily similar to what
Russia faced. It was really, yeah. It
looks like you're really getting better,
uh, at, at many things in different,
you know, fields. Yeah. I didn't,
I saw a thing about um,
highways and freeways and
how like for a long time,
like we set the standard for light.
Like we were the first like massive
country to build like where you can you
think about it.
We don't,
we take it for granted that you
can get in a car and be like,
I want to drive to Montana. You
just, any, any other city you want,
you want to go to Louisiana, you just
take this way. You know, it just,
it's like that and we've had like the
best and like China is killing us in
highways and freeways
in quality in like uh,
the number of them and then where
you can go in them killing us.
Ordained says they kill us. The
cell phone coverage. He's like,
you're going over there.
Oh yeah.
He said he can be over there and like the
middle of nowhere in the woods and you
got five bars. Goddamn. Yeah.
Well I haven't been to China,
but I've been to South Korea and dude,
their society is way more advanced.
They feel like
their internet is way more advanced. Every
new phones are more advanced, cleaner.
They're just have, I don't
know, they're way ahead of us.
They're crushing it by a lot of shit
with their phones, but they're just,
that's just starting to
come to the phones now.
There's a thing called Google Wallet.
Google wallet is an APP that
allows you to go up to a,
when you go to the thing where
you scan your credit card,
you could look at it and if it
has like sort of this logo on it,
this Google wallet, sort of a logo. Then
what you do is you take the application,
you pull it up on your Google phones,
press it said put it right up to that
and it automatically pays for your,
your bill. So you don't even
have to swipe a credit card.
You don't have to sign shit. He
just put in your code, put it,
press your phone right up to it, Bang.
So you don't have to have a phone.
I mean you don't have to have a wallet
with credit cards anymore. Eventually.
Yeah. Eventually everything you'll
be able to buy with your phone.
I don't know if Google Wallet exists.
Do you know Brian with a
Google wallet exist for the
Iphone? I don't think so. No.
I think it just takes you to, I think
you'd do it over a website though. Oh,
over website. I don't know. No, that's
whack. You want to do it. That's one.
One knock the Google phones have over
the iPhone if they have that because
that's pretty dope.
Once it comes into focus,
once it becomes a really popular thing
that might make people shy away from the
iPhone to the droid phones
getting the new studio.
One thing I thought was really
interesting was that like home speeds for
internet or capped at around
what's the highest lately?
Like 60 or is it even at 30
megabytes? I only get, I don't,
I only get like 25 of 25 but uh,
what I have to get a business account
because it's a business space that I rent.
The internet speeds are like up to like
hundreds of gigabytes or even more.
Maybe like the upload
speeds are ridiculous too.
I think there were like five
megabyte uploads and stiff what?
I think I'm paying for two megabyte for
the fastest for a universe and it's like
that's not even fair.
It's like I almost like if I am at home
and I went to play games or ba be able
to pay for something like this.
I wish I would have to make my house
a business almost or something.
I think you could probably do that if
you can make your house a business. No,
I mean just like listed as a business.
You would have to like
not live there though.
I mean I don't think it works out what
you can, I don't know if it's the same.
Like if you have a Home Office, I
think that's still a home. Right.
I don't know though.
I mean you're building might've
been wired differently too though.
You have to take that into account.
It's a building,
you know that's a commercial building.
I mean when they wired it they might've
Wa I don't know what the story is.
What is keeping you from getting
the highest internet? You know
that's weird though. It's, it's,
it's, it's weird that like,
cause I live very close to it,
you know, and I've, I checked it.
I wonder if it's something like
they can't offer it to that,
that many people like the bandwidth
isn't there. Yeah, that's a good point.
I mean that could be,
yeah,
because people will be just downloaded
a million movies all day. It,
has anybody ever gone to jail
for stealing movies? Yeah.
What's that one movie?
The one the boring ass.
Maybe we were there like picking up bombs,
whatever that movie was at won all those
awards where it's like there's that
hurt locker,
the hurt locker there.
Those guys like I guess when
after like tons of people,
like 25,000 people or something ridiculous
like that and they just dropped a lot
of them the other day,
so they're still getting suing
people that downloaded their movie.
I'll leave that.
It's weird at the production company
actually is the one going after them.
So the production company,
they somehow or another find out who
is put these things on long and for
download and then they, they
attract, they attack them.
Yeah. They pretty much tell
like, you know, certain cases.
Could they tell by who uploaded
it? Is that what it is? I guess,
you know what they do
is they can check the,
the ips get from the
torrents and stuff like that.
And then they would have to sue
like know charter or whoever.
They made an out of some
kid a couple of years ago,
wasn't it like a kid and his
mom and they were like me,
even though everybody
had downloaded songs,
they went after some
kid and they were like,
you owe like $380,000 because this amount
per song. Yeah. But then they, you know,
I think they settled with
the medical work, but it was,
they were doing that clearly just to get
publicity for the case and make it seem
like, you know, don't you
dare dream of doing this.
It is kind of weird, man.
It's such a weird gray area.
Whether or not something that you bought
and you paid for, whether you could
distributed for music. It's really
interesting like how these paid,
uh, the companies like Spotify and
rhapsody and stuff like that really in my
opinion,
have stepped in.
And I don't really download music much
anymore because now I just pay 10 bucks a
month for Spotify and I fucking listen
to it as much as I want to. You know,
it's like a jukebox of everything.
Yeah.
Does don't you have to
be online to get that?
Uh, not all the time. I think you
can save songs to your device.
I haven't really fucked around with
it too much on that part, but uh,
I think you could also save songs.
Like I said, if you pay $10 a day,
it will download it inside
the app and then it will off.
It needs to at least connect to make sure
that you're a member still and then it
makes the,
all the songs were,
that's annoying. That's too complicated.
I'd rather get things on iTunes.
I get my shit on it.
How do you feel about
like your content though?
You know what,
man,
I think you know what I do
is very different because
first of all, as a comedian,
when you're,
you know,
when you're releasing your information
or when you're releasing your material,
rather if you like putting on
a CD or a DVD or something,
you're essentially putting
out an advertisement and
out a, uh, uh, an example of
your work that you're proud of,
that you want people to see
and enjoy, you know? And Yeah,
you want to be compensated for it.
Yeah. You want to make money for it.
But the way I roll is it,
if I download,
if I've ever downloaded
anything illegally, I've
always bought it if I liked it.
Always really was. Yeah.
Well, and even bought,
I've bought some things that I didn't
like just because I felt guilty because I
couldn't,
couldn't get it legally when I wanted to,
so I had to get it some other way. There's
no way. Most people do that though.
Yeah.
I have a problem.
I can't litter if I drop something on
the ground is I have to get it. You know?
I'll often after, if the fucking
wind is blowing, goddammit,
off the fucking chase after
this little piece of paper,
it could be a gum wrapper. Really?
Yeah. I don't like, it's nice.
I don't like leaving behind a
problem. It bugs me, you know?
So when I look at the idea
of littering psychically,
the idea of littering with your
consciousness that you, you,
you take little thing,
you do shitty little things and you
take them for granted and then you have
these little things curled
up in a fucking corner.
There's a little crumpled up papers of,
of ideas and consciousness is littered
your fucking head. I don't like it.
So if I, if a band is
good, if I buy, you know,
if somebody sends me to a youtube link
and I go, wow, that's fucking badass song.
And then there's a download link
somewhere on some site where you're not
supposed to go to. And I download it and
I like it. I always buy it. That's great.
I think you have to, I think
you're supposed to. I don't
really download anything,
any,
I mean everything I know.
Itunes, I mean, even then,
I mean like say if I
found something illegal,
I'll search to find it illegally or
buy it on Amazon, you know? Yeah.
You guys touching each other?
It was accidental that I bumped it.
Sorry if you heard about Gene Simmons,
Simmons Kid, uh, what
happened there was news. Uh,
I read this morning one
of the beer. Yeah, sure.
He's a comic book artist and Nicole One,
you want a cold?
Oh Shit. Given another. The WHO?
Who's this? Uh, Gene Simmons is kid. Yeah.
And he does comic books.
He does a Manga,
I think it's called a Japan
Japanese style Nma and thanks man.
Yeah, it's real nice guy. I actually
met him once I at the Improv,
but there's this, uh, they,
they outdid him for just completely
tracing a Japanese comic book artists and
like they have these like lineups where
they showed like face on top of phase
where they overlay it
and it's exactly him.
How old is he? 19 or 20
isn't he? He's young.
I don't know if he's 19 or 20,
but I don't know the whole story.
I don't know if like the comics,
like an old comic,
because I know I used to
draw comics just for fun.
I know that there has been
many times where I'd like,
I liked like how Spiderman was
posing or something like that.
So I would like trace his pose.
You know, you learn how to draw.
So I'm wondering is see an art student
or is he trying to sell these things?
That's where it makes me think he sells
them. I think he's pretty successful.
Kind of hard to get away from that one.
Like a trace the ship.
So the Japanese artists on his
Twitter today, uh, you know,
was confused at first,
but then he said something like,
I'm more surprised that Gene Simmons says
kid does comics or something like that.
I can't remember. But he knows about
it. He didn't seem that angry. Wow.
How did it not seem angry
though? I don't know. You know,
very polite Japanese people.
I have no idea.
I always feel about stealing now is that
like, especially with jokes, it's like,
well I can always write another one.
It sucks to have your shit. Yeah.
I could see it happening more in
comic books just for people that like,
I guess he took a lot though
that the comic was called bleach
a band for a little while. What does
he, yeah, yeah, I remember he on,
I watched the show and
the on the reality show,
his band was playing somewhere and then
his father like flew a flyer out of a
plane I was showing it was son's
bands playing somewhere and you know,
making a big deal out of
it. Wow. This is crazy. Wow.
You seeing that? It's the kid
that's on that show. Yeah.
Side by side. Not Analysis
is pretty fucking damning. Yeah. He's old
enough to know what I mean. It is. He,
he's, yeah, it's this is,
it's not just tracing it.
I mean it's like a
straight up taking almost.
Some of it is not tracing some of it.
This one's not tracing,
but it's very obvious where the
idea came from. Yeah. This is bad.
So sad. Yeah. Hmm. I miss the
Osborne through all your own stuff.
Everybody. It's weird.
I love that show. Well,
some of them were a bit of a stretch.
This is a few of them here that are a
bit of a stretch because that is a style.
What did you look up? How do you
look it up? I just Google uh,
Gene Simmons kid comic book. Okay. Trace.
Well it definitely looks like pop up.
What day?
There's no doubt about the idea
that he was influenced, you know,
he's an unquestionably,
he was influenced but there's a bunch
of these pictures that are real stretch.
Did you see what that guy on your
message board said that he, he uh,
for a living buys Google ads all the time.
And we always joke about like how I
always put bottle at the end of Google
searches. So he was making it
targeting California for the words,
but hole on the end of any kind of
sentence and it just says something like,
hey ride man.
Stop saying buy it whole or look
searching for [inaudible] as a Google ads.
Google took it down because they get,
he used the word butthole chance.
Say butthole for Google for ads. You could
sell them missiles. Yeah. This, yeah.
This is, this is crazy, man. This is weird
to watch. He really did trace this stuff.
Yeah. Yeah, you can. I mean,
they even show an overlay. They show
like, here's the original image.
It says, look, trace to
throw it. That really sucks.
It's fucking sad.
This is something that's something
that's really hard to recover from.
Well as that
appears like he's just made a career
doing this. Like he's decided to try to,
to make a career doing it this
way. Tracy. All right. Yeah.
It looks like you're gonna have to borrow
some more money from dad for awhile.
Well, I don't know man. You know, you want
to give people the benefit of the doubt.
Who knows? It seems, it seems
pretty shitty though. Sucks.
It sucks the air. Right.
Maybe he was fucking a guy.
Maybe he was just horsing
around. You know, he's
just doing horseplay while, well, why
would people think you're plagiarizing?
Don't have to ask them. Don't ask
me that. You'd have to ask them.
How was your horsing around? Have
you heard the new fad, that team,
that's the real problem in high
schools is that teens are using vodka.
So tampons to get drunk at
a,
no, no, no. This is real.
This news stories about it. Go
ahead. Look up the new store.
Girls are doing this in high school there.
They're soaking,
they're soaking tampons with vodka and
sticking them in their pussy and they're
inserting a beer bongs and they're
assholes and they're getting drunk.
People are nuts. You gotta
go for it. Nuts. Apparently.
This is what this Vod Cup tampon thing.
You got gotta do it because you
get the video teen chain using or vodka.
So tampons to get drunk.
Teens using vodka,
soak tampons to get drunk and
you're listening. Go for it, man.
Try the whole bundle where you can die.
This is the problem.
It's the alcohol is going
right into your bloodstream.
It's like shooting ivy blood. You
know, you can take things rectally.
Like there's this girl, she goes
by the name of a neuro soup on, uh,
on Youtube and she has like a
website called neuro soup I think.
And she's like kind of a famous person
in the psychedelic community because at
one point in time she
was living with this guy.
There was this gigantic LSD dealer, like
the biggest l LSD dealer in the world.
And she was a stripper.
And this is a really interesting thing
on vice.com a video where they interview
her and they talk about the crazy
times that she's been through.
One of the things, one of our videos
online is her taking DMT Ainley.
She takes DMT and sticks it in her
ass and trips for like an hour.
Wow. Yeah. Wow. Indeed. That videos.
Yeah. She put the video out there.
Good old fashion. The old fashion, I
guess she wanted to go for a longer ride.
The old fashioned way, only lasts
for about 15 minutes at the most.
What about LSD? You could put that up
your ass, but you can see my eyes. Well,
Jimi Hendrix, the, the
little legend is the,
Jimi Hendrix used to put it on his Bandana
and as he was sweating and enter into
the pores [inaudible] I've heard of it
being in socks and the people sweating
into their sis like accidentally.
I don't know if that's true,
but I'm sure it could happen.
Yeah, I'm sure that makes sense.
Branding out a dead show is always
interesting seeing happen with, um,
who is the creator of Lsd doctor,
the one that was like, God dammit, I
can't remember his name and Leery. No, no,
no. [inaudible] I don't know. I forget
the fucking guys name. God Damn it.
But anyway, uh, I believe at first
[inaudible] Albert Hoffman,
I would often, and then Albert
Hoffman when he invented it,
I believe it happened by accident.
And if I'm not, if I'm not incorrect,
I think he got it on
his hands or something.
I forget how he was initially exposed
to it. I forget the story, but, uh,
I'm pretty sure it, the first time it was
like he got it on something. I was like,
what the fuck is going on on acid
before? No, I've never done it. I said,
I've only done
Salvia DMT,
Fyedka Tampon.
Some of the craziest experience
I've ever had. US eating pot,
some of the most intense psychedelic
experiences I've ever has eating cod.
I've told her, I'm sure.
Just share some stories.
You've heard it all when it comes to
what teenagers are turning
to, to get that quick.
It's, it's pretty scary. Was with Erwin
is here with a straight story. Oh boy.
Elizabeth, right. One I've got
to tell you. See and Catherine,
two things I never thought would appear
in the same exact tampons and vodka.
Do I have your attention? Good.
Because if you're a parent,
you really still are tight.
She's went home immediately stuffed
the whole bottle of vodka or asshole.
Any city, Sally, I doing it right
now. Finance will open my asshole
when we heard how kids are getting drunk.
No Way.
So we hit up the experts to find out if
it's an urban legend or if it's legit.
There's been documented cases of people
going to the hospital with alcohol
poisoning just from utilizing it that way.
Utilizing.
Thomas spends his days patrolling
the halls of a valley high school.
He's heard firsthand how
kids are getting tipsy.
What we're hearing about is teenagers
utilizing a Tampon. So Kumon Bod kippers,
right.
Teens taking tampons,
soaking them in vodka,
damn.
Teens and inserting them in.
They're posted there.
She can't even say vagina. She says
there. That's a terrified we are.
Anything sexual in America,
it's unbelievable. Off is
definitely not there. No, no, no.
They'll insert them into their rectum.
Alright. And where she comes out
the same. So I'm, I've found the,
uh, how acid was invented. Yeah, it
was an accident. While it's recent,
the sizing LSD Hoffman accidentally
absorbed a small amount of it through his
fingertips and serendipitously
discovered the powerful effects.
He said this is his exact
words affected by a remarkable,
remarkable restlessness combined
with a slight dizziness at home.
I laid down and sank into a non
unpleasant intoxicated like condition
characterized by an extremely stimulated
imagination in a dream like state with
eyes closed, I found the daylight
to be unpleasantly glaring.
I have received an uninterrupted
stream of fantastic pictures,
extraordinary shapes with intense
kaleidoscope play of colors.
After some two hours in this
condition faded away. Wow.
So then he decided to take it on his own.
So this was by accident.
And then what he did is he took it on his
own and tried to ride home on his bike.
It was a little area
called him bicycle day.
The Guy gave herself 25
[inaudible] 25 milligrams,
which is 250 micrograms. That's
how fucking actual threats.
Threshold dose is only 20 micrograms.
Threshold dose. That means you feel it.
You feel it at 20 micrograms.
So that's the intoxication
threshold is 20 micro grams.
He takes two 50 [inaudible].
I've never found it from anybody.
I trust I,
I got some from this guy that was friends
with Andy Dick and he was out of his
fucking mind, this guy, and he's
like really wanted me to come
home and take it again? Nope. Now it's
going to ask you about going to happen.
It's getting liquid,
even getting liquid.
You've got to know that you're getting it,
man.
You've got to know that people
are taking it consistently.
It's really fucking have it tested. This
motherfucker really what it should be.
His fucking legal. And there should be
LSD like institutes where you go and, Hey,
do you want to really know who you
are? Sit down. You know what I mean?
It's all chemically simple. Are
chemically similar to, uh, to each other.
Have you all like Dmt,
Lsd,
mushrooms are all really close to
exactly. Dimethyl. Here we go. Sorry,
I don't know. I have Google on your phone.
I did ask that as a kid in
math and he said, here we go.
Because there's a video of me talking
about at least got going in that,
um, and we've talked about
it on the podcast a hundred
times, right? It's, it's a,
it's a psychedelic chemical, but it's
one of your own brain. Makes Gotcha. Oh,
I'm sorry. And all the really
powerful ones like Lsd, Lsd,
and DMT and mushrooms, they're all real
similar. They're like chemical cousins,
you know?
So it's,
it's interesting that those are the super
potent ones and they're really close
to what your own brain may
naturally LSD. I don't know man, because
I've taken that a lot in my brain.
Does not function. Did you ever
take it through your ass hole? No.
I took it out loud.
Blues I when I was 14 years old and I
was golf and I haven't got a hat on him.
Yeah. I had to retain, I had
retainers and a velvet dress,
shit and Susie and the banshees came on
and I did at the same time and I have
through my retainers across the field
at Irvine Meadows and I had to leave and
that was the end of that. Did you
ever read about how the a scary CIA,
we'd like you to test it. Yes.
The young people, short videos,
the town in France where they dose the
whole town and put it in their bread,
killed themselves, but I am the 1950s
and really are they doused a whole town.
They just experiment. And our town
in France. The Americans, yeah.
Freedom of Information Act. It's all all
available now. There's a lot of cool read
be shit they do. They're really truly
defines what the government is all about.
Yeah.
It was,
a lot of people think the government
is just us working in a different job.
It's not, it's the people that
have a history of being ruthless,
a history of being ruthless.
And that's how you get to that
position in the first place.
But the experiments that they did
on, on people are just fucking, yeah.
Horrendous. No. What was the
utility of LSD initially? It was,
they thought was going to
be a true CEO, Sarah. Oh,
I thought it was to make sure
they wanted to use it. Yeah. No,
and that's why they didn't do, they
give them steroids for that. Oh, okay.
Steroids and meth.
Crystal Meth is something that the
Japanese invented that for getting fucking
planes to crash into boats.
Gotta be all messed up and do that.
And they all met up really
well. Yeah. Yeah. That's,
that's where crystal meth a dream was.
It invented and now you can
just drive trucks on it.
Have you ever been around
people that are on meth?
Uh, in high school, I grew up here around
here actually in your neighborhood.
And that was the drug of my generation
was meth and then rave culture.
So was dropping tons
of v and taking meth, cocaine,
not so much an LSD that,
that's my generation.
Once I tried it and I don't,
I don't like how like just just do coke.
Coke is so much classier.
You fucking stay up for days making
collages and moving furniture.
It's utter chaos
because that's how I felt,
you know, because you're just
so fired up. You're like,
oh, I'm gonna do something. But
there's nothing, at least for me,
I kind of be construct just once,
once like it,
from what I understand,
Adderall cousins as well.
Even when I did Adderall, I felt like
I was getting drips and like cocaine,
whatever it triggered was the same
fucking neighborhood as drips come from
actually snorting.
It felt like it
crush it up. And we know a guy who,
uh, was, uh, like I, I talk, I
tell the story now on stage of,
of the guy who used to drive us
to the airport.
This was our driver,
like a regular guy,
cause we go to the airport so often
we use this, you know, we found a,
like a cheaper car service.
It's easier than dealing with like
driving and parking and like he was uh,
you know, like a cheap
ride, basically older guy.
And I'm like all white hair. It was
really professional. And then like,
after like 10 rides, one of those
things where like, you know,
when somebody like Mr Rogan, Mr and
you finally go, you can call me Joe.
It was like that kind of thing where I
was like, it's Tom, he's like this Tom.
I'm like, yeah. He's like, cool. Hey
Man, let me ask you something. Like,
everything changed. As soon as I said,
you don't have to be professional with me.
And he goes, uh, he goes, can
I ask you something? And I
was like, yeah. And he goes,
do you smoke weed? And I was like, ah,
yeah, I mean, I guess, yeah. He's like,
do you want to smoke some now? And
I was like, really? I was like,
I was like, yeah. All right. And then
you said, Yo, right? Yeah. Okay driver,
that's exactly what you're comfortable
with you in my life. And then he goes,
he starts smoking and then he goes,
uh, I can't drive unless I'm fucked up.
That's a quo [inaudible] God.
And then Judd Apatow,
I swear to God,
Shit
like seventies and then he goes,
and then he's like this more like this,
particularly in his early, he drives fast.
He's like, one of these, I've
been driving 50 years in La,
we've got to take this street.
And I was like, you know,
I was basically like keep it together
man. And he was like, he was like,
I've been up since, you know, three.
And then I'm like [inaudible] shit.
And I started asking him, I'm like,
have you done other drugs? He's like,
aw buddy buddy. Like I've done all. And I
was like, really? He's like coke heroin.
And he's like, there's nothing
like smoking rocks, swear to God.
And I was like 17 and he is flying
through El Barrio through the old
neighborhood. So this is an El
Salvadorian neighborhoods. Like every,
like we're going through
lights and he's like,
look at that little brown one right
there. Oh, that was a little brown guy.
He was married to a Peruvian and then he
had like an El Salvadorian girlfriend.
He's like, I love these little brown
was at oh one on the side. Yeah. Well,
and yet he was like five girlfriends and
they're all like 20 and they were all
like 20th. So we drive to
the ghetto and he'd be like,
that's where I used to buy
this neighborhood's good stuff.
God.
So we're in the, we're driving around
and I go, uh, I go, oh, I go, what?
Can I ask you something now that we're
friends, I guess, you know? And he's like,
yeah, it's true. And I was like, what's it
like to smoke crack? And he goes, oh man.
He's like, what I like to do
and when I smoked crack is like,
I'll just sit in my apartment where,
wait, stop, stop. Don't say anything.
Did he say porn? Who Watches porn? No,
no, go ahead. I'm sorry. He goes, uh,
I like to,
I like to look through the people and I
look around at what the fucks out and I
think I see all the shit I think
about what's going to happen next.
I see people walking by and I just
kind of fucking freak out, you know?
And I was like, this sounds terrible
man. But he was, he was like,
as part of the rush,
that's the rush.
You know what the [inaudible] is
rush to stop you because yeah,
everybody says everybody that I've
ever talked to him and smoked crack,
he says they watch porn
when
we fucked like animal.
Yeah. Yeah, he did say that.
Sorry, say his last name. Henry the ape.
So the best is like in
this sounds like it sounds,
I swear this is exactly how it goes.
I go, so do you still do that shit?
And he goes, Nah man, Nah,
no. He goes, well, you know,
every once in a while,
but you know what they say if you
do something every once in a while,
it's not that bad for you. And I go, I
think they mean that about like pizza,
like chocolate [inaudible] I swear to God,
every once in a while we'll,
do you remember when the
mayor of Washington DC got
caught smoking Marion Berry?
Yeah. With an FBI agent or
an informant. A prostitute.
Yeah.
You remember that shit?
He was smoking crack and
running the nation's capitol.
And then when they ask people about it,
the greatest thing was after
he got caught, this guy,
I remember this guy on TV,
they say,
what do you think about the mayor
getting caught smoking crack goes man.
And by some, a little crack
of it now. And then he said,
everybody smoke a little crack every now
and then this guy was on TV. It's like,
come on
man, stop playing. You stop playing.
Who doesn't? Who doesn't vote crack?
I smoked some great little now.
And then I was on Opie and
Anthony and he was in the hallway.
We were in the serious
studios, you know, so there's,
there's a big window you could see who's
walking down the hallway and Marion
Barry was walking down
the hallway. So, uh,
one of the interns from the opiate Anthony
show, or maybe it was, was it Eric?
Who Was it?
He went out and grabbed him,
grab Marion Barry and brought him into
one of the most hostile radio shows in
the history of the fucking human
race because of the best. So yeah,
he sits some area of barrier there and
we just started asking him questions
about getting caught with crack.
And one of the things he says,
nobody knows what was in that
pipe. Oh, what? That's you,
you were sweating and saying, I wasn't
doing that pipe. And I'm like, well,
there was a video or
you smoking Craig isn't,
nobody knows what was in that pipe like
we, wow. Wow. Still denying it political.
How political. Very.
He's still got a career.
He's still out there making it happen.
He's out there.
He was running for something. Yeah. And
he also did become arrogant, but he also,
he ran for something during
the last elections. I forget
what it was. Maybe. Well,
you know what,
man,
a lot of what being a fucking mayor is
about is not what you do with your freak
time.
It's about what you do with your,
the rest of the time they felt like
he was actually representing them.
So he was out there just keeping it real
by smoking, do a crack every now and
then. I'm there for you with that guy.
He wasn't annoying, man. Come
on with this. What is this now?
Since Ted Haggard? Yes.
Yeah. Not only is he back,
but he's brilliant and
the way he approaches it,
that everyone in his whole thing,
oh,
we have drug dealers and prostitutes
and everybody looking to be saved.
You know,
it's like we've all lost our way,
but God is still there and I'm
still going to lead you to God.
I'm still married, but he's
gay as fuck. Fuck. He's, uh,
he's just, you know, he's, he's, uh,
he's just fighting it. That shit.
You just ran the gamut.
What? You watch that,
you watch that documentary and you see
him with his wife and they're like the
drive and they're just trying to get the
car. But he's like, he's, as he's talking,
you're like, man, you would be so much
happier if you would just get up, be like,
I'm totally gay. I'll see you later.
Just go be happy man. Like you.
You don't have to be that miserable.
Well then there's that,
but there's also the intoxication of
being a leader. Yeah. He loves it.
He's addicted to that. Yeah. A lot
of the behavior is not genuine.
A lot of what his behavior is,
his,
he's behaving the way
he thinks people were,
are going to accept the way
he thinks people are going
to find admirable and how,
you know, it's like his,
his real behavior. He like,
he's not being honest with himself and
if he's not being honest with themselves,
how the fuck could he be
honest with other people?
He's gaining control and all these
other people's lives, you know, and,
and fighting off the lack of control.
He hasn't at all know he needs
to be like a leader of a church.
Needs to be the speaking right.
He wanted,
he's like praise the critical piece
of shit. You on your mind phobic.
Meanwhile he's smoking meth
and again, gay huggers, Morris,
kind of hypocritical
once all the congressmen,
absolute all the guys that tell
you how to live and criticize you.
Cora, you live. Why? Why would you
care if if you look, I don't want to,
I might not want to live on Santa Monica
Boulevard while the fucking gay parade
is going on.
I don't know.
I mean I don't want it to be so that I
can't drive it in my driveway without
tripping over dudes on my lawn.
I don't want it to be that bad.
Can you mentioned tripping
over boners that'd be so weird.
Cough out of the ground.
That piece of human shit.
Who is that?
He's running for the
Republican presidential.
He's a huge homophobic piece.
It's probably good. He also,
he also wants to, he wants to
make, not only is it really
not just abortion, he wants to take
away birth control to control the Queen.
Cause he said that's not what it's for.
If you're using birth control like
you're not there for few, well
who the fuck are you?
Stupid. Well, you know, it's,
people with their priorities
are so out of whack.
Like why would you even be that good? Why
would that be what you want to consult?
You give a shit,
people having sex,
you want to take a way birth control you
crazy answer. You want to make people,
it make it easier for people to get
pregnant accidentally because that's God's
will morons even care about what the
gays are doing because he wants some gate
dick fighting off the gay chosen now.
Right?
Real motherfucker all
day, all day, all night.
Clon off that gay trying to push it back.
No.
Say Allen dates.
It's a sad thing when you see these
poor fucking people suppressing people.
You know, what do you think about
this occupy Wall Street shit,
I haven't talked to you about this.
What's your take on all of this? Uh,
I think it's great that a group of
people want to like feel this way about,
there's a lot of inequality.
I think it's, it's great,
like collectively the problem,
like the real flaw in
occupy Wall Street and he,
the things is that there's not a clear
set of what they're trying to achieve.
It almost like this, you know, uh,
over like let's just do this
collectively as society.
We're making a statement about
being the 99% and you guys,
the 1% has and where the have nots.
But I think it would have
been more effective if they
had had like a clear list
of like this is what we want to
accomplish. And it was, it's more,
I feel like having watched
it from outside, I'm not an
expert on it by any means,
but it just feels like it's more
of a statement and you go, Oh yeah,
it makes people aware, but there isn't
really like, you know, course of action.
They're not really
trying to figure that out for sure.
So I think,
you know,
it's interesting and I
think the message really,
this if I feel like what I get from it
as if is if you really could get a lot,
and I mean a ton of people
behind a certain idea,
you can affect change.
We're not going to see,
I don't think we're seeing a lot of
change from the entire occupy movement,
but the idea,
it kind of lays out for you that like
they could take over a park or a square or
a street and disrupt that days,
you know, normal function.
And if you were to magnify that,
if you were to multiply the number of
people there and you really had people
saying we are not going to stand for this,
it leads me to believe that you would,
you could affect change. Do you know
what I mean? Sure. It's a whole culture.
No, this is what's really
interesting is that this only,
it's only been around for like what,
90 days or something like that. I mean,
how many days? Yeah. And you
know, they did a recent poll,
more than half of America supports
the occupy Wall Street movement.
We're not going to participate
during the Vietnam War.
It took five years to
achieve those same numbers.
It took a long time of protesting for
people really thought that the war was a
bad idea.
You know,
people in the 1950s had convinced
everybody that communism was going to be a
real problem.
And you know,
we were looking for communists in our own
society and they were arresting people
during the McCarthy era and
stuff like that. You know,
and I think during the 60s people
were a tad naive too. You know,
how really fucked up and
creepy the government could be.
We had just gone a
couple of generations or,
or I mean rather a couple decades
from world war two ending.
So I think a lot of people thought
that the government was, you know,
just in our army was strong and we fought
off the Nazis and we fought off the
jabs and we're fucking America and we're
not [inaudible]. And then this whole,
you know, the Gulf of Tonkin
incident happened and you know, we,
we were brought into a ward there.
There's no fucking reason to be in
Vietnam for any, any American idea,
for anything that any people here that
would have supported, they lied to us.
They lied to people they claimed were
attack when weren't they made up bullshit.
So I think,
you know,
the people are today or we are aware
of all these things in a much larger
numbers to,
to this day.
I bet a lot of people don't realize
that the impetus for us getting into the
Vietnam War was a hoax.
You know,
I bet a lot of people aren't aware to
this day of operation Northwoods or all
the plans, you know, there
was plans to blame, uh, if,
if space program things went wrong,
there was plans to blame it
on the Cubans and attack Cuba.
There was a bunch of different plans to
blame things on Cubans and attack Cubans.
Yeah. Yeah. There was a,
they were trying really hard to figure
out a way to go to war with cube cube to
the point where they were going to
fake attacks on American civilians.
They're gonna fail.
They're gonna armed Cuban friendlies to
lob mortars at Guantanamo Bay and attack
Guantanamo Bay. I mean, there's
some crazy shit. It really is crazy.
Which by the way, Guantanamo Bay,
that's pretty fucking crazy too.
When you think of these
people that are enemies,
one of them has a giant military base on
your fucking country. I've been there.
I've been up to, how's
that like, dude? Um, well,
the first thing that strikes
you really is that it's
so beautiful. Real, and that's
kind of the, the, you know, the,
the thing that stands out to you
is your, you, you imagine like,
I'm going to a military base
that also has the worlds,
one of the world's most
notorious prison camps,
and it's all in a underdeveloped,
uh,
Caribbean waters because crazy rats,
well,
they do the banana rat fucking blow
your mind, but you got to look it up.
You've got to look at it. They're
all over the, I look it up.
They're all over the island and you shit
when you first see them. Really? Yeah,
they have guys,
Holy Shit.
God, they're all over the place. Yeah.
The size of this fucking thing.
Oh,
there's some really cool
stuff. Yes. That's kind of
cute for a ride. Take a banana.
Right? Then here's how.
Here's how bad the problem is.
There's guys on base that are not like,
it's not even,
they're not even military guys.
They got hired.
They give them a 22 and their job
is at night. You just drive around,
you're shining up and you just show me
or they like,
it's not the same as a nutria. Is it
there? They're not exactly the same. No.
Look at this. Picture it there.
Right? Tell me when. Shoot that.
Shoot it when you shoot that thing,
dude, it weird things. I'm handsome.
One seat your babies every way there
right now and I think wants to innovate,
but you fucking Rad.
If you left it alone with the baby,
it would slowly eat its feet. Fuck yeah,
it would eat your baby's feet. So you see,
you see the coastline and you see the
water and you see, it's basically what,
how much of the Caribbean
is underdeveloped.
You basically see what the island
looked like. She's 500 years ago. Brian,
look at this picture. You get a
better picture of this one. Yeah.
You know that, um, they got me one night,
they made me scream high pitch
scream this, uh, you know,
a Dan Smith, the comedian.
Dan Smith. Yeah. Uh, I was,
I was there with him and a
couple other guys, Mel Hall
and uh, uh, what's his name,
Patrick to gear. We
were all there. And uh,
we get out of this pan and they
had talked about, uh, uh, we,
we pull up in the van, they're
like, there's a banana right,
right there and the
lights of the van or on,
so we get out of the van and we all walk
kind of clothes. And they know that.
They told us, you know, they eat
vegetables or like the shrub there,
they're not like predatory. So we
stopped, but it's still a gross, massive.
So I sneak up and I'm kinda like,
you know,
I'm still like six feet from it and right
as I squat down to like look and kind
of squint my eyes, Dan runs his fingers
up my, my neck like this and he goes like,
oh, there it is. And I go,
I scream and like run like I'm
terrified at this fucking thing.
It is the grossest looking for and it's
massive. It's like a fucking dog man.
It's a rat. The size of a dog you
jump. I mean it's their gross. Oh,
terrifying. And Gross Joe.
Stop masturbating willing.
Tom's Tom. I have to,
I have to relieve myself.
The fears,
the fears often Tara County
and they had like, what do they have feral
that raccoons, you couldn't feed them.
They're just like everywhere. Really.
I don't know. Cause you know there's,
there's a military base there. I did.
I didn't know that they were dangerous.
What was friend raccoons? I didn't,
I know growing up with raccoons,
I live in the La huge problem with
a raccoon. When I lived in New York,
lived in new Rochelle. Where's that?
Michelle is right outside the Bronx.
It's like a suburb.
When I moved to New York,
I couldn't afford to live in the city.
You live in the city.
It's much more expensive.
So I lived in like the summers and I
drove and I needed a car anyway because I
drove to gigs and I had to have like a
place where I could park my car because I
just,
no way I could afford to live in apartment
in New York and have us parking spot.
Like you have to buy a parking spot
somewhere. It's fucking brutal.
It's really expensive. So, uh,
I had to pull down this driveway and I
would stop my car right in front of the
garbage cans and when I
would come home at night,
it was fucking terrifying cause he's,
raccoons were big,
they were really big and they were
really well fed because they were just
fucking people's garbage cans up
left and right because you know,
you're dealing with a house after
house after house and garbage can,
if the garbage can,
garbage can.
So they're just eating constantly and
they know exactly what the food is.
So they pull the tops off that bitch
throw that motherfucker on the ground.
I mean they,
they pull them to the restaurant and I
get out of my car and this mother fucker
is looking at me like fucking backwards
up and shit and I'm thinking this thing
charges me. I'm fucked. I'm a
dad. So I got a blowgun and uh,
you know like with darts,
you know, logo, you
get that at a gun show.
Went to a gun show.
That was the only thing you get if
you don't have a license for a gun.
I got a blow gun.
Did you ever say your can
these motherfuckers must
have known I had a blow gun.
I swear to God he never came back.
Really? Yeah. The raccoon never came back.
It's almost like he has sensed
something predatory. He sends,
I was w laying a trap for his ass or he
just found some fat people down the hall,
got some awesome garbage look.
Got their garbage every night.
It's pizza cross and flock. Yeah, we got
the spot. I never saw that raccoon again,
but he was fucking huge man.
I know people in Florida that would go
hunting with a semiautomatic machine,
guns down raccoons,
flashlights and then with like
ar 15 Florida is so crazy,
Lord. It is not the south. No, it's
not the south and it's not the norm.
It's the southern most port,
part part of the United States,
but it's not considered the south.
Isn't that amazing? The south,
does anyone have anything to do with
Florida? Really? Time to south ones.
Anything to do with Florida
is when you go well learned.
Skinner came from Florida. You got me,
you got me. You got me like a hybrid.
It is like a strip mall.
The state
dirty strip mall.
Vesty even the best parts of Florida,
like whenever I'm in Miami, I loved
the people down there. They're fun,
they're fun. I love, I love
going down there and do gigs,
but I always put myself in a position I,
what if I had to move to Florida?
What would I do? I'd be like, yeah,
I just think about my kids growing
up in Florida and being raped.
It's like a hopeless [inaudible] bro. I
know. It's nice. My parents lived there.
My parents live in a real nice place.
There's something wrong with that state.
It's not a coincidence.
It's so many fucking serial killers
and psychos come from that spot.
That's also where you go.
If you're like cycling and like
we're gonna fuck some shit off
snow.
In my mind,
I grew up or I knew a lot of shady
people when I was a kid and everyone
eventually went to Florida. They all went
down to Florida. They moved to Florida.
My fucking sister moved down to Florida
or shady husband moved down to Florida.
My fucking parents moved down to Florida
and they're attracted to it. It's like
until the sky becomes a
fucking brick wall of rain.
Have you ever had that happen?
You got to stop your car to stop the car
on the highway because you can't drive.
I don't think people understand what
kind of rain we're talking about.
Eddie Bravo had a seminar in Miami.
We drove from uh,
from Fort Lauderdale down in Miami. It was
at like 15, 20 minutes. Not even right.
We're on the highway. We can't go
anywhere. You literally can't drive.
And it feels like your
car is getting fucked up.
Whooshing down. It's like a years
where the rain all in one blast.
It's incredible.
I highway stopped dead all the time.
That's not even know about that shit.
That type of rain too is
like you think like, oh,
that must be like a
tropical storm or hurricane,
which have given both of those and
they're horrifying and like crazy.
You can't believe that it's just rain.
That's just an afternoon shower.
That's just hard,
man.
That ain't shit that the hurricane is
that times a million plus flying trees
hurricane yet. Ooh. I was at a
hurricane in Boston and I remember,
I don't remember what year,
but by the time it got up to us,
everybody was just scared and huddled
in and now we were, we lived in Newton.
We were pretty far inland.
The real people that had to worry where
like the people that are on the shore
and how wicked was the hurricane.
It's wicked.
Pisser came in and talked
to every body sideways.
It's crazy. It's just like a big
hurricane though. Is it like a three?
If I had a choice between moving back
to Boston and live in in Florida,
I take Boston a fucking heartbeat.
Hit winters and all. Fuck. Yeah.
First of all, they have a sense of
humor versus Florida. You'd pick, fuck,
no doubt about it. Are you kidding
me? Human beings and Boston.
It does not compare.
Just being around the human beings,
you'd have way more fun in Boston.
[inaudible] times more fun.
I'll tell you way more fun way. The
further steps smarter too. In Florida,
it gets crazier, more aggressive. Miami,
so you might as well be
in a foreign country.
I haven't fucking passport to go to Miami.
Check you at the border.
You guys are thinking of all the
bad parts of the Florida so much.
Tommy and Tommy and I do. I mean,
I've done a bunch of gigs in Florida.
We did the Florida comedy festival. We
did theater down in Miami. We've done a,
the Improv a couple of times.
We've done a bunch of gigs. Look,
it's fun.
I'm done with that,
but I caught that place out of my diet
and the early two thousands me and Joey
Diaz used to go down there because Joey
knew the guy who was the original owner
is always like, let me get
a drawer. He and Julia,
that was back when Joey was in a dark
days and it would just get money and they
did.
The club owners would be reluctant to
give him money because he might disappear.
Call you from Havana on a fucking rap dog.
I don't know how to got here,
but it looks like I'm stuck, you
know. And uh, we would go to these,
do these shows at the Miami Improv and
the whole crowd would break out into a
fucking discussion, like over
nothing real chatty. Yeah.
I had a joke where I mentioned Oscar
de la Hoya. Somehow or another,
it was like a part of a joke that I used
to do something about getting punched
by Oscar de la Hoya and then
somebody goes, fuck Oscar de la Hoya
and it, and then it was like, he's a
bitch. Julio, Cesar Chavez is the man.
And then it became this fucking
crazy argument amongst apes.
They might as well. They
might as well. Chimpanzees is,
someone taught how to talk.
They were just the dumbest human
beings I've ever been around.
And the rest of the crowd was the people
who are forced to live around these
more on kids.
And so they would just like sighing,
like shaking her head back and forth
like, oh, I'm sorry. Yeah, but it was a,
it was a savage crowd. Like they,
they had not tamed that crowd.
And because of that, the most unruly
of the unruly, the dumbest of the dump.
We're drawn to that club and they
papered the fuck out of the room.
Your original owner was,
he was the GAC out hardcore
and he really wasn't doing it.
And so he wasn't, he wasn't taking care
of the place correctly. Apparently.
I don't, I don't know. Try it. These,
this is allegedly, this is all allegedly,
I'm not trying Miami and profits.
It's fun now. Fuck you. It's fun.
I remember the day where I was on stage
where there, this was breaking out
and I stopped in the middle of my set.
I go, you people are way too dominant.
I'm never coming back here. I'm like,
this is ridiculous. Did you come out,
you came out to to a comedy show and you
want to yell at out who's your favorite
was like the, there was the impulsiveness.
It was like there was no discipline.
There was nothing.
I mean it was like literally like you were
around the brattiest kids ever bought,
they were drinking and that somehow
or another they were 21 yeah.
You know the brattiest kids and just felt
like they could just yell things down
and it's like, does anybody ever tell
you to shut the fuck ever? I know.
Does anybody ever tell you to shut
the fuck up because this is nonsense.
This is your, you have to be a crazy
person to come to a comedy club in.
It'd be this unaware.
Well, yeah. Can I ask you something?
Because this happened to me at
the comedy store on Saturday.
Like have you ever had someone just make
a comment in the crowd or just say some
shit to you that enrages you?
Like it hits a trigger and you so fucking
hard. That's what they're trying to do.
Yeah. And you see red and you're like,
I'm going to fucking like I this guy,
big animated
troll face that. That's,
that's what they have.
They won.
What did he say?
What do you do?
It was so stupid.
Like I was talking about birth control
pill and how they market it and they
always say it's to regularly, it was a
dumb throw. It was a minute thing. Right.
And I don't usually,
I don't talk about my period.
I know that's a fucking female
comic. Cliche. And I know, and he,
he made an audible, ugh. And I fucking,
I went bonkers because he had a woman
with him and in my head I'm thinking,
asshole, you're with a
woman. You fucked that woman.
Put your mouth on her vagina.
Babies come out of that. But
yeah. Why are you so offended at the,
at the just the sheer man? I don't,
like I said, it wasn't a bit
about it. I didn't go into it.
It was a throwaway line I
had said and it immediately,
if for whatever reason I wanted
to fucking kill that guy.
Well,
because your instincts are correct.
The guys that Douche bag and what was
really going on was that the guy is
probably insecure and he probably wanted
to impress the girl by being more funny
than you or by criticizing you or
maybe came in with really close minded
expectation. Like chicks aren't
funny. His fucking truck up there, I,
you know I did well, yeah, everything
after that. Well, you know, one,
maybe he had a shut the fuck up because
he knew that he was going to get crushed
and then he was our, oh my
God, I'm getting no pussy now.
I'm a lorry Merde a loser. Yeah.
You know, he'd probably pan out.
That'll probably got a little cocky.
You fucking just flex them and he panicked
and he went into a goddamn tailspin.
Yeah,
I see.
But then like how do you deal with people
like [inaudible] say shit that makes
you like,
it just triggers your thing.
You gotta be saying, look, it's all snake
poison. This is what it is. I need help.
Can you get bit when you get there by
snake, the first time you get fucked up,
it's venomous. It's through tears.
You Up, you sick, you could die.
But after those fucking guys
and handle snakes all the time,
when they get bit those mother fuckers,
they're immune to the shed because they
give themselves injections of snake
venom. They do it on purpose. They fork.
It's like a comic forcing themselves to
do a spot of the comedy store Tuesday at
one o'clock in the morning
giving yourself snake venom.
The only people there were
junkies are fucking a waste toy.
Like it will work or you know,
drunk tourists had just
wandered in from off the street.
It's not like it's a comedy kind
of sewer audience. Right, right.
But that snake venom,
they get a little snake venom in you and
after a while you become immune to it.
And then when people yell things out,
then you can go, why are you yelling?
What's going on with you?
And then you,
then you turn it on them and then
they become a part of the show.
My issue with it is then it's
a different kind of comedy.
People enjoy it because they love off
the cuff shit. They love watching.
Hackles get destroyed.
People get a kick out of that shit,
but at the end of the day
it's a different show.
You're not doing your set anymore much.
What's much better is that you get
to do your set unfucked with, yeah,
I can do that, man. I do
question and answers why?
I'll do like an hour more and I'll
just let people yell out anything and I
talked to the people in the
crowd do that all the time,
but that's after I've already done
my material. Man, don't interrupt.
That's gross and only
people that do that are
idiots. You have to be an idiot
to yell at a movie theater.
You have to be an idiot
to yell at a comedy show,
to try to get someone's intention to
try to interrupt and inject your own
bullshit. I always tell the man, look, you
go to an open mic night, something hard.
You could do it.
I know you do.
I know you're insecure and
this is the easy way to do it,
but really you want attention, you want
attention that you don't fucking deserve,
and instead of going through the proper
channels to get this attention on,
what you're doing is trying to usurp
it from someone who has achieved it.
Here you are on the stage,
you've gone through the portal
part of getting hired by the club.
You've got television
credits, you're, you know,
you're established standup comedian,
seasoned by the road.
You're on the stage and this person
literally wants to jump into your spot.
Like automatically,
like you serve your business.
They're essentially trying to
steal your bike. Yeah, yeah.
It's, it's so, yeah. I don't agree with
the mentality. I don't understand that.
I would never,
it's fucking crazy.
I would say only losers do that shit.
You're not going to take a winner.
There's no winner in the world.
No person who's got their
shit together in the world,
who wants to yell out and cause attention
to the south of the comedy show and
that's a sign of immaturity or just a
lack of objective analysis of their own
self and the way they own,
they behave. It's total that
I was more mad at myself and
I let that guy sidetrack.
But it's good for you. Ultimately
it's good for you. It is really,
you learn from that shit cause
then you're like, why? Yeah,
fucking why did that trigger that in me?
I just wanted, I just wanted to kill him.
The worst is when they come up with your
herbs helping you out up there. Oh yeah.
I'll bring you out. Would you show up? But
I brought you been heckled a lot, right?
You get heckled, don't, yeah. No, no, not
really. I've seen you get gold. All right.
Do you not remember? No, it was a lot of
weird. No, I mean not nothing bad. Like,
maybe somebody will yell something
out, but nothing like, uh,
like where they keep on going
the whole time. You know,
where it's like a real
heckle back and forth. What
difference do you find in doing my shows
as opposed to doing just random shows
on the road.
Your shows are just fine.
Like cause they know me and that that
completely is awesome because they,
they already know my sense of humor. So
yeah, they already know you. Silly person.
Yeah. So it's already easy for you just
to start. You're totally different, right?
Yeah.
Isn't that cool?
That's the best when you have your own
audience you guys are going to have it.
Look, you know your, your podcasts,
podcasts is fucking hilarious.
And folks who haven't heard it, it's
your mom's house and it's on death squad.
So if you go to iTunes and if you want
to look specifically for there is look
for the desktop,
that squad ones that say your mom's
house and that's Tom and the lovely Mrs
Segura and a favor.
We have a lot of,
a lot of fun to do a man
we really enjoy doing it.
And we're going to put the Ice House one's
folks for everybody who's been asking.
That is also now going to
be on death squad. So a,
what it's called is the
icehouse chronicles and we
have a full studio set up in
Pasadena and it is fucking dope.
And uh,
Brian has been doing all of his podcasts
out of there now and yeah, it's awesome.
We're going to do one out
of there this Thursday.
I'm not sure who's going to do it yet,
but then we're going to have
a show there a Thursday night.
So that should be a lot of fun in a
Thursday night show is a 10:00 PM show and
uh, it's uh, get tickets
from the Ice House,
ice house,
comedy.com and get them quick cause it
will sell out. It's only 85 seats. Uh,
we did it last week and it's sold
out and it was fucking awesome.
And then crowd is cool and shit,
man,
this podcast fans are awesome.
This is the greatest,
smartest thing I've ever done.
And it totally happened by accident.
Can I ask your fans to come see me?
Where are you this week?
I'm going to be at the comedy mixed
in the great city of Vancouver
Saturday at the comedy
mixed on Bernard Street.
It's one of my favorites that
I play is down. That is, yeah,
that is the old Yuk Yuk Yuk
Yuks in Vancouver. Oh, it's the,
it's one of the best set
up rooms in the country.
Or I shouldn't say in the country,
cause Canada and not just the country
in North America. North America.
It's a perfect setup. It's
low ceilings, tight seeding,
great place. Nice crowd,
great owner, nice guy.
Nice people that work there. It's great.
Yeah. Tommy and I did it last time.
We did it. We did a theater on fraud. What
did we do on Friday night where we go,
uh, I forget the name of good here and
we did a theater on Friday night and then
Saturday night we, after the fights we
went nuts it anymore. Is that right?
I don't remember. And then after the
fights we went and did, it might've been,
and after the fights who went and did
the comedy Max? It's fucking great.
What a great little club and I started,
it used to be Yuck Arcs we did as
young Alex back in the day. Right. You,
me and who else? Who helped
did it with us? Yoshi. Yoshi.
Did it going to be on the show Thursday
and Thursday night? Yeah, I did it once.
It's got to do more shows
with Yoshi. Yeah, I like
Yoshi. Alight. He's hilarious.
He's friends with Asa, Akira. This girl
that we had on that podcast yesterday,
by the way, have you guys watched
a porn video on your TV recently?
Like an HD,
like it's completely disgusting
watching the hardcore open
up your ass hole punch.
I have a watch porn on it inside of these
terrible things for aggressive shit.
There's lot of spitting
and you're watching,
you're watching the race you're
watching right now. This guy was,
he had like equal clause and he
was proud of [inaudible] vagina.
I don't like that.
Hold the club.
I'm also not like, I mean I like watching
an aggressively done blowjob. Sure.
But when, well to a certain extent,
but when it gets into like, wow,
I'm getting like stuff that shit.
I don't like it aggressive at all.
I don't like confusing sex with rape.
I don't know. I don't mean violent.
Very, very in touch with
my chimpanzee instincts.
And I think there's probably some dark
reason why men are so much fucking
stronger than women and their hot probably
has a lot to do with nature wanting
us to hold you down and fuck the shit
out of you sometimes. Sometimes you,
sometimes you fight back and we
have to club you. Yeah. So I don't,
I don't want to ever happen to that
fucking primordial pool of being via the
aggressiveness coming from the girl.
I don't mean like a throat match
you,
that's fun to watch for a little bit.
And then when they go like they puke.
Yes. Dummy file on cock, isn't it?
I'm not gonna lie. I don't
like it. That aggressive
love Bella, Donna, because
she's very pro. Like I just,
I like her energy and
I like her as a person.
I got to meet her at Sam Tripoli's naughty
show, but when she puts a baseball bat
up her ass and not,
not the thin and the other.
And at the end you hold off on,
forget who sent me that.
I think it might've been Dunkin,
it was a long time ago.
Someone sent me that video and a,
the heading just said batter up.
And so I open the email,
you know,
it's one of those things where
someone just sends you of the email.
I opened the email and then she said,
I love people. Exclamation point,
exclamation point,
exclamation point.
And then this link and
I clicked the link in.
This girl has a bad up her ass joyfully
glow. I was like, well fuck man,
someone finally did the last
thing that there is to do.
And then I thought about it. I'm like,
wow, I wonder how long it took to do this.
And then I said, well, how
many people have done this?
So then I googled baseball bat up the
ass and there's like fucking twenty eight
thousand two hundred and eighty
four million fucking mean.
Who knows how many goddamn results there
were. But there was, it was ridiculous.
It's like there's a whole genre of porn.
Girls stick baseball bats up each other's
asses. Now. She didn't do it for it.
They can't help but take it
to the darkest level possible.
Can you say that home had doubled, did
doubling, doubling imaginary joking.
In the interview I said
something about double badge,
which is Trey Parker and Matt stone,
his band.
That's why I always say it as a joke.
I didn't think people actually
signed it and she goes, oh yeah,
a giant that were really like the center
point of a kaleidoscope of male bodies,
male bodies,
and then to Cox in her vagina and to
do that physically,
physically stand.
How does everybody find a good spot to
stand for Asians? That's not even good.
They'd have to be like, they would have
to be like Cirque de Solei dancers.
There's video that she's in note
like really good every time.
Who are we talking about?
Belladonnas I'll say Kira.
Every video she went to or
every person she went to,
it just got bigger and bigger.
She was fucking his black dude where his
dick seriously was about the size and
from my knee cap to my foot,
like an inch thick that thick and
she's just fucking any ass with that.
It just slips right in and an
ADP and it's fucking great.
I put it on 3d and didn't help
anything is that they hurry,
hurry, get busy with it.
Yeah. It's like are you ready
gen?
No.
Like gentle slow.
Well you know what it is because you
know obviously there's some editing,
some professional editing where they're
giving you is only the most extreme
aspect of the fantasy but does a lot of
it of all men abusing the women. Yeah.
This guy who was dragging her
from one part of the house,
the other party house by her hair so you
would like choke her and I was stomach
bile foam and stuff like that.
Then he would have just
dragged across into the other
room by her hair and throw in the ground
and then shove his hand in her pussy so
hard.
It was just juicing everywhere and they
would smack her and she bit him in the
hand at one point and he drew blood
and he's like, look what you did to me,
take this. And then he just put
his big cock and Hazmat is crazy.
The incidence of rape
has gone down with this
Japanese philosophy.
I don't know if it's true.
I don't know if it's makes sense.
Look,
I think sexual suppression is responsible
and then also the lack of xpression is
responsible for a lot of things that
people do where they act out and do
something fucked up.
But then are how many people are going
to be inspired by these videos to
actually do it, to get the ultimate thrill
and do it in real life. I don't know.
Do you guys ever switch it up in
the bedroom? Like Tom Dresses up
the woman and you dress up as the
guy, he'll whatever, whatever.
Here's the shoes with the heels
I put on her Wednesday, I go, well
let me ask you this time cause you're,
yeah,
you're a big sports fan.
What do you think about the whole
Oscar de la Hoya getting caught wearing
women's clothes where you just
know it just really admitted it.
He caught caught a long time.
I caught a while and he said it was
all Photoshop nonsense but he recently
admitted it because he said it's been
haunting him and apparently like this
other grant on him out,
another girl had just came out and did
an interview and said that this was like
he would do, he would corner everybody
wouldn't let the girls leave,
like intimidate them and he'd be like
wearing girls clothes and hang out with
them and talking like a girl.
I think.
I mean I totally buy it and I mean I think
it's quirky but I think you know when
you hear like a story
about somebody and you're,
your brain always does the assessment of
like, can I see this person doing that?
When I heard that initially about
Oscar de la Hoya, I was like,
you get over the like the what? What?
What's the story? And then I was like, oh,
I could see that. I can, I
could see that. Like you said,
like Bernard Hopkins did it.
I'd be like not ever was a cross dresser
and he was sure j Edgar Hoover was,
my understanding of cross dressing is
that it is not necessarily related to
homosexuality.
That doesn't make any sense to me.
Seems Pretty Queer from where I'm sitting.
It might be a different flavor of queer.
I might not be your standard genetic.
I was born gay,
queer, but it's still, I think, I think
it leads to something to it. Yeah.
There's some on and I respect
him. I look, I'm, by the way,
I have zero problem with any kink that
you have, right. If you want to wear,
I'm not criticizing him going anyway.
I don't want to get confused.
I respect that guy. I think he's
a great fighter, is great fun,
interesting guy and a very
brilliant businessman.
And if he wants to wear dresses, I think
he's wore dresses. I don't give a fuck.
You know, it's just weird. I
say that what it is to just fun.
He is fun. Guys like him. I
think he, um, uh, I think,
I think if he were to, I don't know if
he's from here. He's still like, he uh,
if you were promote fights in address,
that would be, well, there's
a Japanese, I would go watch,
I forget
the guy's name.
I'll look it up real quick because I
don't want to end this on a bad note.
There's a Japanese kickboxer
that's a crossdresser all man.
Oh yeah. He comes into the, well, he
comes, it's part of his walk in entrance.
He comes in to the,
it comes into the ring with the fucking
wig on and pigtails and dressed up like
a school girl. The fuck out
of people. I mean, he's a,
he's a bad ass kickboxer
and a tech scene that's different guys.
We don't, we don't really, you know,
it's like sort of cross dressing.
If I dress like a guys that aren't at
the most straight men don't have any
desire to wear a dress kilt.
Let your balls loose a little bit.
That's about as far as
it goes, right? Yeah.
I mean there's more utility
in me wearing pants. Yeah.
Then guys wearing a girl's Thong
before? No, it's really pointless.
Why did you wear a song?
I spent the night at the girlfriend's
house recently and I didn't have any
underwear and I think given her own
words, she's like, I only have thongs.
And I'm like, so I tried it.
It's pretty much pointless. Why?
Why do you even bother? Because
you're like, I need underwear. Right.
As long as the only thing around stupid.
What's your asshole bacteria on your
vagina to Euston facts in that way?
Yeah. You got to get some full
back cotton breathers like mommy,
where's you know that you are not supposed
to move your Dick from the dictum?
I didn't have for a while.
[inaudible] you know little girls,
I'm a little young.
Girls are oftentimes get sick because
they wiped their ass and correctly cause
they wiped their ass into their vagina.
You've got to teach them to wipe their
ass the wrong way or they can get septic.
It's fucking dangerous, man. It's
like you can get really sick,
like real bad and that's how sickening
get from going butthole to vagina. Yeah.
I never really had to deal with that. I
guess until recently. You in your mouth,
Huh? You get shit on your balls
standing up with one leg on the
front to back. Yeah. He likes his balls.
A shitty sort of a [inaudible] side
hurts less to the other side. Last,
what do you mean he abuses his ass hole?
Yeah,
he uses plugs a lot while
we're searching. Also, David,
tell him to my brother paper towels a
lot to wipe you do not flush that shit.
That will, that will destroy
your whole entire plumbing.
Nagashima that's the dude. The
dude, his name was Nagashima.
Nagashima is the Japanese gentleman who
dresses up like a girl and even in this,
look at this. Check this out. What
does he take a look at? This? Yeah,
he's a bad ass and knocked out Shinya Oak.
He's one of the best
MMA guys in the world.
This is him with a wig
on dress like a girl.
This one's a blonde one.
He wears deadlines all the time.
Shima voicemail. Oh Dude,
he's a, he destroyed Shinier.
The end of the ring that like cause yeah.
Yeah.
That's how he's looking. Here's another
one of him. Look at this this way.
It's got a blue wig on and is dressed
like a girl. I love the Japanese
and he beats the fuck out of people.
In your opinion,
is that like he's gay? This is like I'm
taking my gay rage to the ring. I mean,
I don't know for sure.
There's been some gay fighters,
but the no one's ever come out and he's
that guy. No, no. He might not be gay.
Might just be just for
fun. Boxers, MMA fighters.
Am I gay boxers as well? And Bill
Griffith is a famous, a famous by the way,
champion. And He, uh, he, uh,
there was a guy who taunted
him and the guy wound up dying.
Bernie and [inaudible],
I think the guy's name was Brittany paret.
I forget the guy's name,
but he killed him in a fight in,
I believe it was in New York,
in a boxing match.
And the guy had taunted him for being gay.
Yeah. There's, you know, there's some,
yeah,
there's gay.
That's not smart that somebody
told me about a show in New York.
I forget at what club were one of the
comics was making like, I don't know,
gay jokes,
but like doing just like you know like
gay slurs and I don't know what he was
saying and there was a big like jacked
up dude and the audience who just came
onstage and just punched him like twice
knocked about Jesus Christ about comics
is that we don't become
serial killers or pedophiles.
What about that rapist?
That was the,
the one guy was the cruise liner guy who
would go to colleges and shit and rape
girls. Asked him to pray for him who was
raped them and ask them to pray for him.
Yeah. Meal Griffith was widely known
as being a gay man and there were the,
he had a fight with this guy,
Benny Perrey in 1962 for the welterweight
championship and the guy had taunted
him about being gay and he'd
beat them to death. Jesus.
He'd beat that fucking guy to death
other than that. But other than that,
there's a few and far between people.
People have been recognized as being gay.
We told the story on the podcast about
this one guy who got caught in an MMA
promotion.
Well,
there isn't another guy who was a
out guy who fights in MMA fights.
I forget his name right now. It escapes
me. Shane, Shane Smith I think. Um,
but he's out.
Like they've done stories about him,
The New York Times and Chad Smith,
that's his name. And um, this other guy,
they caught him because they researched
his name and they found out that another
guy with the same name and done a bunch
of gay porns and then he just vanished.
She just disappeared. Stop fighting.
But other than that, no one is there,
but no one's ever come out there up.
Chad Smith character for a lot of
people. Do they tap into, yeah,
for a lot of people it'd be a big deal.
Does it happen?
Does that mean instead of tapping out,
oh, Brian, you silly goose.
And with that note, Oh,
I want to say thank you to Lorenzo
from the psychedelic salon podcast.
I listened to a couple
podcasts. I listened to the
desk squad. I listened to a,
you know, a bunch of different ones
that Kevin Smith and Mark Marin and,
and Adam Carolla when I get a chance,
but her mom's really,
I've been listening to,
yeah, your mom's house and,
and then the naughty show
and all these different ones.
But really I've been listening to
the psychedelic salon a lot lately,
so I want to thank this Guy Lorenzo
for putting that out. And you could,
you could, uh, subscribe to that as well.
It's all free. I think it's on iTunes.
I'm pretty sure it is. But, uh, it's
uh, you can find it. Go look for it.
Google it psychedelic salon. It's
the shit. And would it really is,
is a lot of really interesting talks,
you know,
with a lot of Terence Mckenna stuff
and listen to this really crazy Timothy
leary talk the other day. Really
interesting. Interesting Shit.
Um, I would like you to,
what you want to plug a yeah.
Can I tell you what happens
after Vancouver this weekend? Uh,
December 1st through the fourth I'll be
in Calgary at the lab shop or another
great club.
And December 15th through 18th I'm really
looking forward to the laughing skull
in Atlanta, which is really fun.
Yeah, so and then Christina,
we'll both for new years in
Seattle at parlor live. Yeah.
And December 14th through 17th
crackers Comedy Club in Indianapolis,
downtown baby. How often do you
guys work together? Hook it up.
We try to, yeah, it's fun. You
don't have to do it. Corny,
funny, funny. It's an I wouldn't if
I didn't think you were both funny.
I would never say that. You're both
funny on the, on the air. I really do.
You guys are both hilarious. It is
fun. It is fun. We do it in New York.
Doing black market yourself would
make your marriage a lot easier.
You don't have to. That's
true. You can kiss each other.
You could fucking bang right
before you go on the street.
You just shoot one into her and stage.
Send her up on stage dripping.
How about that? Oh yeah.
You should launch her onto
the stage with your call
and I could put, I could put DMT
and vodka on the tip of my day.
Super High.
You guys.
Thank you to the [inaudible]
in a free society.
We would have a flush like with DMT
and vodka at the end of it, but no,
and there's dirty little prison
that we live in or your confined,
you can't do what you really want to do.
Fucking government's holding me back,
goddammit. Dang to the
fleshlight. Go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link entering the code name,
Rogan. Get it in the mail, opened up,
lube it up and get your freak
on. Okay, Holla at your boy.
Thanks to entering your
name and you get 15% off.
And thank you to [inaudible] dot com try
out alpha brain and try out new mood.
Knew mood is the newest one
and I'm fucking loving it.
And there's another one called shroom
tech, which is for very athletic people.
That's based on that
quarter subs mushroom.
That's an endurance enhancer that I've
been enjoying as well on it.com o n n,
I t. And if you go to Joe Rogan, not
in that, click on the Alpha brain link.
Enter in the code name rogue and you
will save yourself 10% oh Geez. Louise,
who's looking out for you? We are
bitches. Cause you know we love you.
Thank you to Tom Segarra. Please
follow him on Twitter. It's Tom,
s e g U R A and follow Christina.
So girl,
even though she goes by the
fucking p at the end of her,
some bunch of fucking random vowels and
consonants jammed up together in some
strange soup of words that no one can.
I bet you can't even spell your name.
Can you spell your name? How often do
you spell your name wrong? Once a year.
Come on son. Terry.
Christina, Christina up. Hey,
we'll be back. Um, uh,
Doug Benson is doing it tomorrow with
Doug Benson tomorrow at 3:00 PM movies.
Then again,
we will,
we will have a podcast and we will have
a show at the ice house on Thursday
night. So there'd be the same thing.
Podcasts while it shows going on.
We're gonna podcast before the show
goes on o'clock, eight o'clock.
We're going to start the podcast and
it's just, it's a party. Okay, folks,
it's a fucking party and you're invited,
but you don't get to talk. I'm sorry.
You got to talk to,
I'm sorry you can't talk to,
but I'm happy that you're enjoying it and
we love you guys and we'll talk to you
soon,
lady.
Okay?
Okay.