Sam harris,
ladies and gentlemen.
All right,
there we go.
We're live to the world.
You're going to do a read fucked up.
I don't do that anymore.
Oh,
cool.
I do it before or after.
Um,
that way the conversation isn't garbled
by five minutes of ads.
Just got annoying.
No,
that's a good call.
Yeah.
Well there's two different versions of
this.
The one that goes up on youtube.
So the one that goes on Youtube has no
ads in it unless youtube puts up pants
and the one that goes on podcasts or
itunes rather has a,
the ads.
So there you go.
So we could just talk.
Yeah,
we're good to see you.
Good to see you too,
man.
Absolutely.
It's a,
it's an interesting time.
I know you're at an MMA fan.
Do you know about the John John's
situation?
I've heard rumors about it,
but I don't actually know how far the
misbehavior run.
So he got stripped of his title today or
yesterday actually.
They announced a new title fight between
Daniel Cormier and Anthony Rumble
Johnson.
They will be fighting for the now
vacated title.
Jon Jones is likely going to jail what
a.
It was a hit and run crash into a
pregnant woman who allegedly,
I should say it broke her arm.
She was rushed to the hospital,
but pregnant got to be terrifying for
her.
We had a car crash and smashed by a guy
runs a red light and then flees the
scene of the crime,
so he drove away.
He ran away and ran away.
Cars wrecked cars wrecked.
You see the images of her car.
I couldn't imagine unless he was driving
fucking Humvee on how he could get away.
It was pretty bad.
Was it a dui or or that we don't know
because he disappeared for like 24 hours
at least.
Probably even more a couple of days.
I think he disappeared for which,
you know,
obviously the speculation would be that
he was on something that he would worry
about getting tested for for 24 hours or
48 hours or whatever it was.
That I think of how desperate to move
and,
and hapless and move that is to run away
from the car that you're leaving in the
seed,
which is obviously traceable to you.
It's not like we're getting out of the
problem and you're leaving an injured
person there to.
Yeah,
I mean it's a disaster,
but it's worse because he actually ran
back to the car stuff out of the car and
then ran away again.
No Man id by a cop.
Right.
A disaster all across the board.
But not what we're here for.
But I know you're an MMA fan,
so.
No,
we have it.
But bringing up.
Yeah.
I actually have a question for you
though in the close topic.
Um,
and we have a list of questions that we
got from twitter but mcgregor or Aldo,
I'm.
Who knows,
that's my answer is going to be
interesting.
It's going to be very interesting fight.
We've never seen mcgregor in with
anybody remotely as talented as Josie.
Aldo.
Not even remotely.
It doesn't mean you can't win because
everybody that Mcgregor has been in
with,
he steamrolled.
He steam rolled really talented guys
like Dustin ea and just he's.
He's fucking good.
Yeah,
he's good.
He's really good,
really confident,
and he.
He really fucks with people's heads.
He's so confident and so good at
talking,
and so there's so much charisma about
him that I think it's intimidating to
his opponents.
I think when they get in there with him,
his just overwhelming belief and belief
is an incredibly powerful thing.
If you really,
truly believe that you are the best and
you say it,
your opponents have to wonder because
everybody's,
everybody questions themselves,
especially in the world of,
of fighting because you know,
one is if you were born a rhino,
okay,
and,
uh,
you were about to get into a fight with
a parakeet,
you'd absolutely be confident because
you've always been a rhino and that
parakeets just a parakeet that parakeets
fucked.
But a person is a,
is a work in progress and not just from
your fighting style,
but your ability to manage your own
mind,
your ability to manage insecurities and
anxieties.
Just the existential angst that comes
with being a human being that's
navigating their way through this
complicated world.
There's variables,
there's,
there's days you're up and days you're
down and then you add into that martial
arts and you don't get good at martial
arts unless you get your ass kicked.
There's only one way through.
I mean you can be one of those John
Jones types.
It's unbelievably physically talented
and have a leg up on a lot of people,
but even John had to get his ass kicked.
You had to.
He had to.
He had to compete and wrestling against
guys who were better than him.
He had to learn martial arts.
You had a spa.
I mean there's gonna be days.
You're up in days,
you're down.
There's no way.
So when you get in there with a guy like
conor mcgregor to take pot hole that
craziest because he's just like,
fuck,
this guy's overwhelming.
It's like if you can put on a show like
that,
if you can put your peacock feathers up
and and a puff up your back,
heres get those bristles up nice and
high like a cat when it's angry and
hunch your back up.
Like there's a reason why that exists in
nature.
Well,
it's beyond what Mohammed Ali used to
do.
She's taken it to so it's going gonna be
fascinating psychologically to see him
when he loses.
If when,
when that day comes,
it will come eventually and he has lost.
He's lost to a guy named Joe Duffy who's
now in the UFC and he's very good.
This guy,
Joe Duffy is fucking very good,
but he had.
He lost since his rise to.
No,
he has not lost until you've been in the
UFC and he.
But in all fairness,
the one style that he has not faced,
which is the most difficult style,
has never faced a wrestler.
It was never faced a guy who can get in
there and get him to the ground and
outwork him and just sap his energy
wrestlers.
They get on top of you and you can't get
them off and you get exhausted trying
and they they're punching you in the
face and elbow you in the face and
punching you in the body and constantly
trying to strangle you and then the
round is up and you'd get up and the
next round comes and they do it again.
Boom.
You're on your back and boom,
you're getting punched in the face.
He's never faced a guy like that before.
All the fighters he's faced to have
chosen to stand up with him and he's a
very high level boxer.
He was amateur champion as a boxer.
He's got very good to Jitsu skills.
Very good morning ty.
Good.
Very good.
Everything.
We just never seen him against a top
flight wrestler,
but Aldo is not that.
All those.
Not that,
but although is a world class Brazilian
Jujitsu fighter,
like people who are not aware of his
ground skills.
I'll go beat a guy named Cole Breena and
an actual Jujitsu competition.
Just very high level Breanna's world
championship caliber.
So Aldo is going to present him with
some things inside the octagon that he's
never faced before.
However,
although has been fighting
professionally for a very long time,
and I'm like a race car that doesn't
ever get its tires changed or doesn't
ever get it.
Suspension redone.
Your as a human being,
your body can literally only take so
many miles.
There's only so many times you can go to
war.
There's so many,
so many sparring sessions you can take
part in only so many wrestling sessions
you can take part in.
There's just a certain amount your body
can take and we don't know when that
number is,
when when you reach that number though,
that's it,
and now there's no turning back unless
you're using testosterone or growth
hormone or some.
Some things that turn your body into the
superhuman sort of experiment to.
Unless he's doing that,
which we've seen from Vito Belfort,
Vito Belfort's,
the only guy who actually got better as
he got older talking to my guy from UFC
12,
miracle of science.
It's exactly what it is.
Absolutely fascinating,
and you can't completely discount his
training because this training is what
made him better,
but his ability to recover was
essentially supernatural.
You know,
he's fighting.
I'm in the same car that Jones is
supposed to fight.
He's fighting Chris Weidman,
but now Nevada has made testosterone
replacement therapy illegal.
So his last three performances,
which are some of the best performances
of his career,
the knockout of Michael bisping knockout
of Luke rockhold and the knockout of Dan
Henderson.
Those were all while he was on
testosterone.
So yeah.
Okay.
Yeah,
so things get weird now.
Now you see what a 37 year old man
really looks like,
you know,
optimizing hormones as best he can
naturally.
Hopefully.
Yeah.
Well 37 sounds young.
It sounds like that level of
testosterone.
Well,
you know,
it's also the,
the level of testosterone have a regular
37 year old man versus the level of
testosterone for someone going through a
camp when you're going through those
camps is absolutely brutal.
Like Jon Jones and Daniel Cormier,
they both got tested randomly before.
They're,
their um,
title fight and their testosterone
levels were so low.
People will weren't wondering like,
Hey,
maybe these guys are doing something.
Maybe they were doing steroids and that
made their testosterone levels drop,
but what's most likely it's testosterone
to epitestosterone that was very low
testosterone levels.
Most likely.
It's just the brutality of training.
It's so hard.
It's so hard to do.
You,
you,
you showing up everyday exhausted and
your muscles are sore and your body's
exhausted.
You've got to go through it all again
tomorrow and you're getting kicked and
punched and you lifting weights and
you're doing sprint and you jumping up
on boxes and and then the next day all
over again and your body just can't keep
up,
especially when you get into your
thirties.
Yeah.
All right,
well the answer that and I will watch it
with interest.
It's going to be very exciting.
Let me know if you want to go.
It's in.
I,
we'll talk about that.
We'll talk about Sam Harris goes to the
fights as a neuroscientist to disturb
you at all.
When you're seeing these guys getting,
getting their heads rattled to you when
you're.
You're very aware of what's going on
behind the scenes.
In the actual brain itself.
Yeah.
Well,
I just,
I just talked about this in my blog with
this writer Jonathan Gottschall,
who I told you about it at one point.
I'm trying to get him on the podcast.
Yeah,
he's great.
And um,
so we had a conversation which we
publish the transcript of,
but he,
he's got this book that the professor in
the cage where he's an academic,
he's an English professor and he decided
to get really damn may and fight a real
cage match.
Um,
and so it's,
uh,
it's interesting book and so he and I
were talking about the discomfort.
We have stress seeing people get brain
damage in real time for our amusement.
And yeah,
it does make me uncomfortable,
but I'm also part of what's thrilling.
I mean,
I,
you know,
I'm as thrilled by the prospect of a
knockout too.
It's kind of,
it's not even a conscious thrill is just
when,
when things start going that way you
feel your own,
you know,
testosterone or something kick in.
And um,
but I am a,
his recommendation was that,
and I'm sure he's not the only person
who's thought of this,
he thought the gloves she'd come off and
the gloves are making it,
that you making it realistic to just
send enlist overhand rights and other
crazy punches,
you know,
full force into people's heads for,
for,
you know,
30 minutes.
Whereas if you,
if you were to,
if it was a bare knuckle fight,
you,
you couldn't really be fewer knockouts
but you couldn't deliver that kind of
brain trauma because you'd be breaking
your hands.
Now obviously there are things like
elbows and knees and kicks and so people
would still be getting hurt.
But what do you think about that?
Would that change?
If I'm a big advocate of that,
and I've said it many times,
I've said it on the air,
I've talked about it on this podcast.
I think it's a very unrealistic,
the way you're allowed to not just put
gloves on,
but also wrap your hands up.
Taping lists.
Your risk is a joint.
It flexes and when you tape it up and
they get that sucker up nice and tight,
then it becomes something completely
unrealistic.
If you punch someone with your hand
without a glove on and with no hand
wraps,
it's way easier to hyper extend your
wrist or twists or tweak or break it.
Your hand brakes.
You hit someone in the forehead for
heads are far harder than your knuckles
are.
Most likely you're going to break it
unless you hit them on the nose and the
eye on the jaw.
You're,
you're going to hurt your hand and you
can only throw so many punches like that
and even just hitting a heavy bag
without being wrapped up.
You just screw up your wrist and your
hands.
Yeah,
you have to really learn how to tighten
everything up and you have to really
strengthen your wrist and you have to
strengthen your,
your,
your hand muscles.
It's a completely different thing,
which is why the,
uh,
Kinda the karate students would hit a
mucky water,
which is a board that's wrapped with a
rope.
And the idea behind punching that board
wrapped in rope over and over again as
you develop these intense calluses all
over the front two knuckles,
which is really the only way you're
supposed to hit someone.
Those are the knuckles that are
reinforced by the wrist.
Whereas the where the pinky finger is
and the ring finger,
those knuckles are not reinforced nearly
as well,
especially if you have a larger hands
like your hand.
Like my hand spreads out past my wrist.
It doesn't go in a straight line from my
wrist to the pinky.
It actually goes out to the side so
that,
that knuckles not enforced by anything.
If you punch someone with a boxing glove
on with that knuckle,
you're fine,
right?
If you punched someone with an MMA glove
on,
it's less supported.
If you punch them on bare knuckle,
you are very likely to break your hand.
If you punched someone full force on the
forehead and you hit the with the pinky
knuckle,
you're very likely to break your hand.
It's a high possibility.
Also,
it it.
It also impedes your grappling to have
those gloves on.
Right?
Garcia went to,
yeah,
I'm so huge issue.
Marcello Garcia fought in Japan,
I believe it was,
had this guy's back and couldn't finish
them.
I was just grabbing and grabbing gloves,
gloves,
holding onto the gloves.
The guy just worked on his defense and
the gloves with a like Marcello's
specialties,
the rear naked choke and the rear naked
choke.
A big part of it is sliding your hands
underneath the guy's Chin like and we
have the glove there.
There's all this extra padding that
makes it very difficult to get your hand
in the proper position to formula to get
the choke right,
right,
right in the back of the head.
It's also very difficult to get the
glove and the back of the head,
so a lot of times you'll see in an mma
fight,
guys are used poor technique and still
finish the choke will.
They'll use their palm on the top or the
back of their head because they can't do
this.
Can't do this movement where it's
actually the back of your hand should
touch the back of your opponent's head
because all like to someone who doesn't
understand Jujitsu,
that's very complicated,
but I agree with them.
I think that a gloves would help a lot.
Yeah.
Or gloves or no gloves,
right?
Yeah.
I think would help a lot,
but I think it's also.
It would be.
It would be beneficial for everyone to
have some intensely comprehensive scans
done on a regular basis.
I don't know if that would be
prohibitive financially.
I don't know how much that would cost.
I don't know how much that would even
reveal because apparently one of the
things that is troublesome for
these nfl players is a when they die and
they do autopsies on them and they
revealed damage that they had no idea
before mean I don't know how much like
an Fmr and Mri can detect when it comes
to the actual damage.
Well it can,
but to what end because you know you're
getting it.
If you're just going to be in a job
where you have to get hit in the head,
forget about competition.
Just training,
I mean these guys train hard so they're
getting hit in the head to prepare them
to get hit in the head,
in the match.
You're just,
you.
It's not even,
it's like smoking.
It's like the causal linkage between
getting hit in the head and brain trauma
is 100 percent.
It's just a matter of it's just a matter
of how much you can you individually by
dent of luck can take until you actually
have damage that matters.
Uh,
so,
you know,
I obviously haven't had an experience
anything like an MMA fighter,
but I regret all the head injuries I
took just training as a.
Now in martial arts,
I just don't let myself get hit in the
head,
but in,
as a teenager I got hit in the head a
fair amount and I played soccer and
headed the soccer ball and that always
felt totally weird.
You know,
that you had,
did you play soccer?
You know,
he had a soccer ball.
You immediately get a kind of a rusty
taste in your mouth,
you know,
and it's just unlike anything else that
happened that day.
Except the other time you got hit in the
head,
um,
and he's not crazy that no one would
ever think that soccer or another give
you traumatic brain injury.
It's because it doesn't knock you out.
We have this until recently.
I,
I'd say like in the last couple of
decades we had this erroneous assumption
that you had to get a knockout.
You got to get knocked out that brain
damage,
but she just looked thuds just a little,
like I was talking to a doctor who said
that water skiing can give you brain
damage.
Waterskiing just hitting,
just the bouncing,
just wave riding,
you know,
like that bouncing.
That stuff can give you brain damage,
right?
Like your brain gets rattled around
inside of your head,
the connective tissue dislodges and it
doesn't heal back.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
so I spoke about this with Jonathan to
that there's obviously all of these
sports and just,
you know,
forms of recreation that that entails
some risk of injury and death.
Right?
And so,
and people should be able to do these
things in informed of the risks.
And so he,
the cheerleader and the example he
brought up,
his cheerleader,
cheerleader sometimes hit the ground and
just,
you know,
fantastically injured.
So all these things that don't
necessarily seem like high testosterone,
high risk,
you know,
you're just foolishly reckless.
Sports can be very dangerous and skiing
is very dangerous to and read a rock
climb and they're things that are,
that are even just nonviolent,
that don't entail much risk of injury
until they kill you.
Like Free Solo rock climbing,
you're climbing,
everything's.
Maybe you hurt your hands in the past,
but then all of a sudden you're dead
because you just went up 500 feet
without a rope and fell.
So there's all these kinds of risks that
people can take.
But the problem that the problem that I
think differentiates striking sports
from even something like football is
that the progress in the sport is
synonymous with the damage.
So you know,
if you and I are are,
are in a boxing match or a kickboxing
match hitting each other,
the every instance of successfully
degrading each other's performance with
respect to the head.
Hitting someone in the head is
synonymous with delivering injury to the
brain.
It's not like,
it's not incidental like in football
where,
and I was trying to tackle you.
I was not hoping to hurt your brain,
but you know,
you fell,
fell down hard and uh,
did um,
this is just a trade of,
of brain damage and um,
yeah,
so it's,
it's,
it's a interesting ethically,
you know,
I don't know.
Again,
I think people should be free to do it,
but I think people,
you know,
we should be informed about it and I
would,
I would certainly vote to pull the
gloves off and make it more.
It would just make it more realistic
combatively to.
It's insofar as you want to see what
works.
Combatively I'm more interested to see
what two people can do just with their
bare hands.
Then when they've got these,
you know,
most certainly.
And you know,
one of the interesting things that has
been brought up online,
um,
over the last couple days about this
John Jones situation,
is this a rational erratic behavior?
Does this imply that or does it somehow
or another is it,
is it correlated to brain damage?
I mean,
it certainly can be.
Can Be,
right.
I mean that's one of the issues with
brain damage.
Impulsive behavior.
Yeah.
Especially in the frontal lobes because
your frontal lobes regulate your
emotional and behavioral outbursts and
when those connections,
when either the cell body is or the
connections between the gray matter in
the frontal lobes and your,
your limbic system and your basal
Ganglia and in other areas in the brain
when that gets damaged,
yeah,
you have these classic impulse control
problems where you just,
you know,
you just reached out and grabbed the
woman standing next to you at starbucks
because you couldn't dampen the,
the impulse to do it.
You know,
that's hard for people to grasp because
again,
this should be really clear.
I am without a doubt not trying to let
him off the hook.
What he did was horrible.
If it was someone in my family that he
hit with that car,
I would be unbelievably furious.
I'm incredibly disappointed in him.
I think the UFC absolutely did the right
thing in stripping him of his title and
I think law enforcement is going to do
the right thing by putting them in jail.
I mean they're going to just.
You can't do that.
You can't hit someone with a car
and leave the scene of the crime that it
is a crime,
but there are things that people do
because they have brain damage and
that's where the real question comes up
is obviously they are responsible
ultimately for their own actions,
but what is it that's responsible for
making them do that action?
And we could.
We had this long conversation wants to
podcasts ago.
I think of bliss,
about free will and determinism.
These are variables that come into play
when it comes to the ultimate actions
that you choose to do.
The ultimate movements that you choose
to take.
The,
the,
the thought processes are questionably
dependent upon the brain itself.
If the brain is getting damaged and if
we have proven that some of the,
some of the issues with people that have
brain damage,
his impulse control.
You got to wonder,
man,
when you see fighters do wild crazy
shit.
How much of that is due to getting just
bunked in the fucking head off?
Yeah.
Except for me that it breaks down a
little differently because they,
my views on free will change the picture
of how I view moral culpability in those
situations so that even if even if we
knew his brain wasn't damaged,
right?
So he,
let's say had never got hit in the head
or we did a scan on him before the car
accident and we saw,
and it's the perfect scan is a scan of
that we'll have 50 years from now,
don't fuck ourselves up.
And um,
so we just know that he's got a totally
healthy brain,
uh,
by whatever metric of health we have.
But uh,
he got into that situation,
behaved exactly as irresponsibly as he
did the,
his behavior still is the result of
causes that he as an agent isn't
ultimately responsible for.
Now,
this has,
has certain this as sort of the
punchline,
which has certain consequences,
but one of the consequences is not that
we can't respond to his misbehavior,
that he can't,
that we can't put them in jail,
that we can't,
that we couldn't have intervened at any
point along the way to have made him a
better person.
And it said there,
there are,
there's a difference between voluntary
and involuntary behavior,
even if it's all just causally
propagated from the moment of the big
bang.
But I do view it as,
um,
I think the brain damage case is a
little bit of a red herring because it's
on some level,
it's all just Qa,
unconscious causes that the,
the person himself can't ultimately
account for.
So,
you know,
there are situations in which he,
I'm sure in his life,
behaved like a Mench,
you know,
behave totally responsibly.
And there's situations where he behaved
like this.
Um,
and he can't,
he can't account for the difference in
those two cases.
He can't account for why,
but let's just,
it's a fact that if he had gotten one
hour more sleep the night before and
hadn't had a fight with his girlfriend
and had his blood sugar level was a
little bit higher and had,
had,
you know,
I hadn't had a friend who had told him
to drink one more beer,
which he normally would have resisted
but couldn't because of all the other
factors I've just mentioned.
And that is the difference that made the
difference that caused him to be this
total misfit on the road.
Um,
whereas if you had just tweaked those
dials a little bit,
you know,
fight with a girlfriend,
one more bite of food in the morning,
he would have been.
He would have acted as you would have
acted in that case.
Say So.
Ultimately,
let's say that's true then that then
that there's something,
there's a kind of bad luck component to,
to all of this creeping in and there's a
concept of moral luck,
which is due to the philosopher Thomas
Nagel,
who,
who's done a lot of interesting work,
half of which I really agree with.
And some of it I don't,
but the concept of moral luck is that it
does seem unfair that there are many
situations in which people create
immense harms doing stuff that you and I
have gotten away with.
You know,
I mean,
they're not,
they're not worse people than we are
like,
you know,
they,
you,
you and I have both driven when we
shouldn't have driven,
you know,
we had one beer too many or were there
things that we did or you're looking at,
you look at a text,
you know,
you should never look at your phone when
you're driving,
but you decide,
okay,
I'm expecting a text and you look and
there are people who are looking at that
text right now and just,
you know,
killing some child in the crosswalk.
Right?
And their lives are going to be ruined
and you know,
they're gonna go to prison and they're
exactly like you and me.
Right?
So there's,
there's a,
there's an aspect of luck here,
but that the luck actually propagates
backward into the kind of brain you
have,
the kind of upbringing you had,
the kind of parents you had,
the kind of,
you know,
the fact that you got hit in the head as
hard as you did or didn't and no one has
made themselves.
So I'm a little bit more,
I'm less judgmental about some of these
things given my view of freewill,
but I'm not,
it's not that I'm not interested in
making the interventions that would make
a difference in whatever we could have
done to have gotten him to behave
differently.
We should have done whatever we should
need to do now to him to make society
better and to make him better and to get
restitution for the woman,
what we should do.
All that.
And so this doesn't tell locking up
certain dangerous people and it doesn't
tell,
you know,
we have to keep,
keep ourselves safe from people who are
going to reliably act badly.
And um,
and I don't know where he falls on that
spectrum,
but it's just,
it's not the difference between the
feeling you get when you hear,
oh,
it was brain damage.
I sort of have that feeling about
everything.
You know,
what if you,
if,
if we,
if he gets a brain scan,
if he goes to trial now he gets a brain
scan and we,
and we find that his brain is just
massively damaged in all the right areas
that would have eroded his impulse
control.
Right.
That would seem to let them off the hook
a little bit.
It would,
he would,
he would look like someone who is
unlucky more than he would look like a
bad person.
Right.
And I sort of see bad people as unlucky
to.
I mean,
I got recognize that there are certain
people who are quite classically bad
people.
They're psychopaths who you just,
not only can you not rely on them,
you can rely on them to be bad actors,
you know,
so you have to,
you have to be in a posture of,
of self defense with respect to these
people.
But I do view them as an unlucky on some
fundamental level.
That's I.
I shared that thought and I shared that
thought much more as I get older and I
have a more philosophical point of view
when it comes to people that live in
impoverished neighborhoods,
especially like this Baltimore thing
that was going on.
We're just having this conversation the
other day about or last podcast about
these kids at robbed the Rte reporter,
and if you've seen the video of it,
there's an to reporter interviewing
these kids that are on the street that
are causing all this havoc and Baltimore
and they start swarming this reporter
and then a robber and take her purse and
took off.
And I'm like,
imagine being one of those kids.
Imagine being in that environment.
Imagine being.
You want to talk about determinism
managing,
being born into this crime Britain
environment.
Who knows what kind of family you have,
who knows what kind of influences you
have,
who knows what kind of experiences that
you've had that you've had to react to
and protect yourself from and developed
this hardened,
thick skin and attitude and also
survival instincts.
And you also,
your your family or the people that you
can reliably count on are the people
that you hang out in the street,
your gang.
And that is the big thing with gang
violence.
One of the big things with gang
violence,
one of the dirty secrets of it is it,
a lot of it comes from broken homes.
When people don't have a strong family
environment and people they can count on
and trust.
They don't have anybody who is there for
them and then they find someone that's
there for them in the gang and the gang
becomes their new family and they will
do anything to keep that love,
to reinforce that love and we all want
to look at it as they're criminals.
They should be home by 10.
There's a curfew on the street.
It's completely unrealistic.
And if you were in their point of view
or if you were in their life rather,
and if you saw it through their point of
view,
you would probably see exactly what they
say you would.
You would look at life,
the way they look at life.
Also,
there's another variable here,
which is just just
the influence of mob behavior,
people,
people will behave in crowds in ways
that they wouldn't otherwise.
Is that.
What is that?
What's the mechanism behind that?
Yeah,
it's a facet.
Well,
I don't,
I can't speak to the mechanism
neurologically,
but it's a,
it's a fascinating social that has been
thought about for at least a century.
It's,
you know,
there was a philosopher,
I'm Elias Canetti who wrote a book
crowds and power,
which is very interesting on this topic.
I'm a crowd.
A crowd is almost like a fire,
you know,
once it gets started,
the mob will behave by its dynamics that
aren't really explained by the
individual intentions of the individuals
in the mob.
And because actually there's a great
book.
Do you ever hear this book?
Uh,
among the thugs by Bill Buford?
He,
um,
having product 20,
25 years ago.
He's,
he's a,
uh,
not really nice writer.
He,
he edited a literary magazine,
Granta I believe back in the day.
And he,
he got fascinated with the phenomenon of
soccer hooliganism and he wanted,
he just,
he went to the UK and just start hanging
out with these,
these are just die hard,
you know,
I guess they were,
I don't know,
Manchester United or arsenal fans,
but just he just got in with these guys
who are normal guys like plumbers and
electricians and people have had real
lives.
These were not just teenagers who were
thugs.
They were,
they were people who had families but
soccer was their life and they became,
they became a soccer hooligans.
And.
But what's,
what's brilliant about the book,
and again it's been at least 20 years
since I read it,
so I could be a little off in my
recollection here,
but what I recall is that he wrote it in
such a way that these guys,
he was hanging out with war.
Really the protagonist.
He got you in on their side for about 75
pages or so.
And then when they start misbehaving,
when they,
when they go to their first game against
the Italians and,
and form a mob and starting to just
marauding the streets.
And you know,
Bash kids in the head,
I mean,
it's like they start behaving like
sociopath in this crowd,
but he catches you out totally because
you are,
these are,
you're on their team for about 75 pages
and you're,
you're,
you're identified with them.
You sort of laughed with them.
You kind of,
you've bonded with them as he did and
then he reveals the level of,
of thuggery that they are capable of as
a,
as a mob.
And it was really,
it was,
as I recall,
it being a fascinating book,
but it is,
it's just a fact that,
that people will do in a crowd,
even when you see it's a part of,
it's the social proof situation where
you see everyone doing something and
that on some level,
um,
gives you license to do it.
So the end,
there's kind of a,
it's just contagious.
We wouldn't see when you see people
breaking windows or jumping on a car or
turning over a car or alluding there,
it takes a less of any individual to
participate in that.
You know,
it takes less for you to go in and grab
a television set when you've seen 100 of
your neighbors do it then if you have
and you wouldn't have that morning,
just woken up deciding to rob the store
yourself.
Um,
so it's a,
um,
I mean we all like to think we're the
sort of people who would stand against
the mob.
We would be the German who would've hid
Jews in our basement and stood against
the Nazis and,
and,
and you can multiply those cases ad
Nauseum,
but what a lot of psychological science
shows that the.
Yeah,
there are those people,
there are the people who will stand
against the tide of imbeciles who are
going to do something heinous,
but most people are part of the tide and
it's just a very common phenomenon.
The social license.
That's a really interesting way to
describe it because that is what,
what it is right here.
I mean,
isn't that a big part of war mean?
A big part of war is doing things that
you would never do on a normal basis and
in a normal scenario,
on a regular basis,
you are asked to put bullets under other
human beings.
One of the things that I thought was
really interesting about,
uh,
the,
the controversy about American sniper,
the Chris Kyle movie was he was talking
about what it was like the first time he
killed someone and that he is in a book,
I don't believe this was in the movie,
but that he had this feeling before he
shot someone like,
is this okay?
I can actually do this,
is it's okay to do this.
And then he grew to enjoy it and then he
grew,
it became commonplace and normal and
he's like,
yeah,
they're bad guys and I'm going to shoot
him,
but this license,
the social license and then is a
accentuated with this,
this mob mentality.
That's mean you're,
you're a part of an army and you have an
enemy and it's the life or death
consequences of life or death scenario
that you're a part of it.
The whole thing is escalated.
It's the highest level of that type of
behavior that we have in,
in society,
in our culture today.
Well,
interesting.
Interestingly,
it takes a lot to get people to kill in
war.
I think there's some myths around how
easy it is for soldiers to shoot at the
bad guy.
But there have been studies done in
prior war is where some shocking
percentage of soldiers either never
fired their guns or fired above their
targets on purpose.
They didn't want to kill anyone.
And that's been,
uh,
and,
and so some of the discipline of
training soldiers has been against the
grain of those tendencies trying to get
people to actually try to kill the other
person.
Um,
and,
you know,
I think we've become more successful
probably doing that.
Uh,
you know,
this is not something I know a ton
about.
I just know that this,
this research is out there and what the
main dynamic I think with,
with soldiers is you are trying to keep
your buddy safe and he's trying.
He or she now is trying to keep you safe
and that,
that,
you know,
they're,
they're not only firing at you,
trying to kill you,
they're trying to kill your buddy or
just did and slash or just,
you know,
wounded him or her and now it's just a
very simple dynamic that you're just,
you've bonded with the person to your
right and to your left and you guys are
really in it together and it's a matter
of keeping you just going home safe,
you know?
And so what's going to,
what is required in that situation?
Well,
you got to shoot at the people in the
other trench.
Um,
and so every,
so now obviously there are aspects of
war making that don't fit that mold and
some of the more disturbing aspects that
actually require less of us in terms of
like you're dropping bombs from 30,000
feet or you're flying a drone from an
office park out outside of Las Vegas or
wherever they were,
wherever they are.
And so we find that customers telescopic
approach to war,
different ethically.
And I think it is,
it's different in a variety of ways that
are interesting,
but I think it's,
it's,
yeah,
it's not so much that that war unleashes
in most people,
this blood lust that is,
that they're,
you know,
they're struggling to contain in the
civilized world and adjust that once
the,
the tap is open in a foreign country,
you just have Rambo's everywhere that
people are really conflicted about what
they do and a lot of people try to not
do anything of consequence.
There is a great episode of one of Dan
Carlin's podcasts,
one of the hardcore history podcast
about world war one,
and I believe it was about the Germans
and the English that they had been in
battle with each other and they had sort
of,
without verbally agreeing to this,
they had sort of agreed to a ceasefire
during lunch.
Oh yeah.
It was fascinating.
Do you know the story?
Yeah.
Yeah,
please.
Because I've heard a,
I knew the story,
but I've also listened to Dan's podcast,
which is think I got from you.
It's just fantastic.
He's the best size.
I think that all of all of them are
great,
but that series on world war one is just
a masterpiece.
It's just,
it's really,
um,
you know,
he's doing something remarkable there.
Um,
but yeah,
that's where they,
this trench warfare was the most brutal
of just,
it was just this,
uh,
you know,
horror compounded upon horror endlessly
for years to no evident gain.
I mean,
these people,
they're there,
there fighting for yards of ground
forever and just tens of thousands of
people are,
are dying and they're,
they're basically camped out on the
decomposing bodies of the people who
died before them.
And there is just,
it's the most horrible version of
warfare you've ever heard about.
And then there's this no man's land
between the trenches where you know,
people who will kind of run out there
trying to make an incursion into the
enemy trench will get caught on barb or
they'll get a shot and then you'll hit
you.
So you have this spectacle of people
injured and dying.
People in the no man's land between the
trenches,
you know,
howling for hours and hours and hours
and misery.
And when someone goes to try to rescue
them,
they get shot and,
and so,
but there were periods where the,
the two sides just a agreed that this
was just,
and again,
how that was communicated was kind of
interesting.
I don't actually recall the details
there,
but it was,
there was a kind of a tacit agreement
that emerged where,
okay,
we're going to let you get your,
we're not going to shoot it to you when
you get the,
the,
the injured person or the dead bodies.
Um,
and there was one Christmas,
I believe where they just basically went
out and the exchange cigarettes and you
know,
had an impromptu soccer game and they
just,
they basically called the war off at a
certain point and then got chastised by
the higher ups for,
for doing that.
And then the war started all over again.
But yeah,
they actually socialized at one point.
It's amazing.
It really is an amazing depiction of
what must have been an impossible place
to be in,
to try to imagine being a person
standing on the decomposing bodies for
being forced to shit in a coffee cup.
And throw it over the top of the trench
and I mean and know that no one's
getting out of this.
I mean you might be one of a thousand
people that's going to die in the next
couple of hours.
You might be,
you know,
you,
you might make it to next week,
you might not.
I mean,
and just the stress that you're dealing
with the,
the non human aspect of that life,
like this is not a normal thing that you
ever expected to deal with.
There's not a normal set of scenarios is
not your,
your,
your brain,
the way you grew up,
you are not prepared for this life.
You're just thrust into it and it
doesn't make any sense.
And then to have that all sort of eroded
to the point where on Christmas you guys
are hanging out and then the,
the generals come in and say fuck this.
You got to kill those people.
And next thing you were killing each
other again.
Like,
so you have this brief glimpse of,
you know,
some utopia inside of,
of war.
Yeah.
Well,
what was so weird about that war in
particular was that the run up to it was
so romanticized and idealistic.
I mean you had a kind of a war fever
that,
that happened throughout Europe where
this was just looked at as in the
rosiest possible terms like this is just
the true glory of,
of manhood to be an expressed.
Finally we have a,
it's like it was approached like the
World Cup or something.
I'm sure it was like pure exuberance
around the prospect of fighting this
war,
uh,
in many quarters.
And you know,
that you'd be surprised if that ever
happened again.
And so it's a little bit like what's
happening with Ge Jihadists,
but they have beliefs that,
that caused that to make more sense.
I mean,
they,
they believe they're gonna go to
paradise when they get killed in this
war.
So it's.
But it's hard to map your own psychology
onto the cream of,
of English youth where they were just
just going off with this,
this level of enthusiasm,
having no idea or I guess part of it it
was they had no idea just how horrible
it was going to be.
But they,
um,
yeah,
the,
it's,
you know,
you read homer and war is this glorious
thing.
The,
the war ethic you get from,
from ancient civilizations is something
that we have,
I think largely outgrown,
but you can really see it in world war
one,
don't you think?
A lot of people had that similar
attitude post nine slash 11,
especially when the World Trade Center
towers went down and there was this flag
waving fewer in America unlike anything
I'd ever seen.
I remember post 9:11.
I remember driving down the street.
I'm leaving the street near my house and
entering into this main street and every
car,
every car had an American flag.
Every car.
It was insane.
I mean,
it was,
uh,
if you,
if you did,
I didn't have an American flag.
I was looked at odd,
you know,
like this is,
this is,
this is an unprecedented time in history
and then all these people were signing
up for war.
All these people were signing up because
they wanted to go over there.
They wanted to fight the good fight,
and then you start hearing things from
people like,
like Pat Tillman,
who left a career as an nfl player,
very promising career as a pro athlete
and all of a sudden he's over there and
this war and his impression of it was
that it was acute clusterfuck.
It was nothing like what he wanted.
It was nothing like what he expected and
he was very verbal about that.
Very,
very,
very openly critical about that.
And a lot of people think that's one of
the reasons why he died.
You know,
there's a giant conspiracy theory that
they killed him because he was talking
to him.
He's killed by friendly fire.
He was killed by American troops and
there was.
The conspiracy theory was that they shut
him up because he was so openly critical
of what was going on over there,
that it wasn't what he thought it was
going to be.
He thought it was going to be this
incredibly organized group of heroes
that went over there to fight these evil
bad guys that are held mountain
destruction and suicide bombing their
way into the America to kill the
American dream mean.
This is the idealistic version of it.
Well,
I think there is an idealistic version
of good and bad actors in this case.
It's just the reality of fighting this
war is so messy and that it's.
Yeah,
it's,
it's you.
Afghanistan I think was pretty clear cut
morally that we had to do something
against al Qaeda and by definition,
once the Taliban wouldn't release Osama
bin Ladin to us,
we had to do something against the
Taliban.
I mean,
that's.
He was.
And they were sheltering him.
Um,
and so I didn't,
I didn't feel ethically conflicted over
that,
but that was such a mess.
I think you're,
you're so going into Afghanistan,
the reality of what it takes to go into
Afghanistan and kill the bad guys is so
messy that there's arguably no good way
to do it.
There's no,
there's no way to do it,
which at the end of the day is going to
look like a success.
And so the men,
maybe that's something we're now
learning that you have to,
um,
this is so messy that you have to be,
you really have to pick your moments,
uh,
and the,
and the far more surgical than we've
ever been inclined to be.
And,
and,
and not even think about defeating the
enemy ultimately,
but just kind of keeping the enemy at
bay containing this problem for long
enough to change minds or change culture
in science in some other way.
Because even in,
in this case,
I think it was,
it was very clear cut,
you know,
we're killing members of al Qaeda was,
was a good idea.
And I think it's still a good idea.
It's just,
you know,
you have a drone strike,
kills some of them and also kills some
of the hostages as we now see.
And it also kills some of the people
standing too close to the bomb blast and
it's ethically messy,
you know,
so it's,
it's at.
But I think there are instances of it
that are certainly necessary,
but someone has to be thinking very
clearly about how we proceed in a world
where there really are people trying to
destroy us.
It's not that there's,
there's no bad guys,
there are bad guys.
Um,
was that where the foreign policy
argument comes into play because some
people say those bad guys are bad guys
because of us foreign policy because of
the way we have intervened and dominated
really can natural resources.
You think it's confused?
Yeah.
So before we dive into that,
I'm looking at a list of topics that
were brought up by our twitter people
and I'm just,
I'm just gonna I'll read the list just
so we have it in our heads and you can
decide what you want to deal with here,
but Islam,
anything but Islam.
Abby Martin,
abby,
Martin,
Abby Martin.
Um,
so I think we have to deal with Abby
Martin.
Abby,
who is a good friend.
I love abby.
She's crazy though,
uh,
in a good way,
but she's,
she's wild.
And she accused you of being one of the
new atheists with your anti Islamic
rhetoric and uh,
you know,
that's nothing new to you.
You accused of that in the past.
Um,
did she misrepresent your point of view?
Did you listen to it?
Yeah,
I did.
I did listen to it.
And should we play it or no?
I don't think you need,
you don't need that.
But what did she say and what would do
not agree with what she said?
Well,
she said it was really interesting
listening to her because.
So I listened to the whole podcast and
she didn't mention me until like the
second hour.
I'm,
I'm listening to this.
I'm thinking I'm actually,
I'm actually having a conversation with
you in my head as I'm listening to this
and I'm thinking and show you.
It's kind of remarkable what you are
able to do here because you're having a
conversation with her.
If I have,
from my point of view,
you were just drinking from a firehose
of bullshit,
right?
It's just like she is what she's saying
the so much wrong with what she's saying
and,
but yet you're in a position to have a
conversation with her.
That is where there's just like a ton of
goodwill and it doesn't run to the
digital and you can have a conversation
with me in the same vein,
but then I was thinking I could not.
I mean,
I'm sure she's a perfectly nice person
and I would,
you know,
I would,
I would be very nice talking to her,
but I,
I have a feeling now of more or less
total hopelessness,
talking to someone as polarized on these
issues as,
as I view her to be a.
and so I was kind of praising you in my
mind thinking that I couldn't do what
you're doing here.
At that instance,
she just mentioned me,
right?
So it's like,
it was like one of those bad scenes in a
movie where he let the television starts
talking to the,
to the character.
She just,
she just kind of called me out and then
represented more or less totally
misrepresented my views.
Um,
so,
so she said,
she said many things that are just
inaccurate,
which we can talk about,
but,
but in terms of,
uh,
what she attributes to me,
she said that I only care about
intentions,
right?
So that all intentions are all that
matters.
So if we kill a billion people but meant
well,
we're fine and if and if,
if the Muslims kill a million people but
don't mean well,
they're far worse than we are ethically.
And that's intentions are all that
matter.
And she was,
I think in her defense.
I mean,
she's,
I'm sure she's never read anything I've
written,
but she was reacting to a snippet of a,
a podcast where I push back against some
of the things that Noam Chomsky has
said.
Um,
and I have,
I haven't thought that I,
I've,
I've said in my first book that Chomsky
doesn't value intent,
the,
the ethical role of intentions enough.
And I said something very brief in a
podcast that bounced around.
And so that's what you heard.
So she misconstrued me,
their intentions are not all that
matters,
obviously,
but intentions do matter.
So if someone,
if someone stabs you right,
the difference between them doing it on
purpose because they want to kill you
and then doing it by accident because
they were cutting,
you know,
you guys were cooking in the kitchen and
they didn't know you were there.
They turned and they stuck a knife into
your belly.
Um,
it's,
it's a world of difference ethically,
right?
So,
and,
and the,
the crucial difference is the person's
intentions tell you a tremendous amount
about what they're likely to do in the
future.
The Guy who stabbed you once because he
wants to kill you is very likely going
to stab you again until you're dead,
right?
I mean,
he's trying to kill you.
The,
your friend in the kitchen who stabbed
you by accident is going to be rushing
you to the hospital in the next
instance.
This is a kind of addition dent,
disingenuous comparison because I mean,
are you describing the difference
between accidentally killing civilians
with us with a,
like a surgical strike in quotes of a
drone strike versus killing someone with
a suicide bomb?
What are you trying to kill as many
people that are random as possible.
So I'm just,
I'm using a very idealized example just
to show you that the role of intention
is not all that matters because getting
stabbed still sucks.
Right?
So if you assume the same stab wounds,
you still have the same problem,
but one of them,
one of your scenarios is completely
innocent and accidental.
Yeah.
The other one is murderous intent.
Okay.
So,
so those are,
those are the extremes,
right?
So then you can have gradations along
that continuum,
right where you have,
and some were more in the middle would
be you're trying to kill a bad guy and
you accidentally killing it on the same
person as well.
Absolutely.
And,
and it's,
it's totally an or,
or you or you think you've got the bad
guy and you've just got bad intelligence
and you just,
all you kill isn't innocent person,
right?
You could be,
let's say you were being totally
surgical.
You're a sniper.
You're going to just kill one person
with one bullet,
but you've got the wrong person through
no fault of your own right or worse yet
the bullet goes through that person and
kill someone else.
Oh,
so all kinds of scenarios like that.
And,
and they're,
they're very common scenario I think,
which is your bombing,
the bad guy.
You're reasonably sure you're bombing
the bad guy and he really is the bad
guy,
but you're also reasonably sure that
you're going to injure or kill some
innocent people and you're okay with
that because the reality of fighting war
is you never get the bad guy standing
all alone 500 yards from the next
person.
So if you can,
if you want to fight this war with
drones,
say you have to accept some level of
collateral damage.
Now I don't actually,
I mean I am not privy to any kind of
intelligence,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not in those circles and I'm not,
I'm not one of those people,
so I don't know just how Obama or anyone
in a position of responsibility makes
those calculations what is acceptable
collateral damage,
but we know that some level of
collateral damage is acceptable because
otherwise it would be impossible to
fight war at all.
Right.
So a,
we know that some level of collateral
damage is acceptable.
Just driving on our roads.
We 30,000
people die every year on our roads.
We could dial that number down to zero.
Right.
If you,
if,
if we were committed to no death on our
roads,
we could get there.
We would just all have to drive five
miles an hour.
Right.
But the difference is that when you're
driving,
you're not intending on someone.
It's an unintended consequences that
transportation is a big difference
between that and the unintended
consequence of violence.
So we'll know which is definitely.
Let's get into that.
Let's see it.
Let's see if there is.
This is an unintended consequence,
unintended but foreseeable consequence,
in fact,
certain consequence of our keeping the
speed where it is,
right?
You and I both know like let's say we
could vote,
vote on this,
you know,
what do you want the speed limit to be?
It's,
you know,
let's say it's 75 miles an hour.
We know that if we reduced it to five,
there'd be some other costs and,
and I'm sure there'd be some other ways
in which people might die.
It would be harder to get you an
ambulance,
get into the hospital,
would be hitting a traffic jam and some
people would die on the way the hospital
site.
But leave that aside,
we would save tens of thousands of lives
every year if we just took all the fun
out of driving and,
or just forget about that,
forget about it.
Let's keep the speed limit exactly where
it is,
but no matter what car you have,
there's a governor on it and you cannot
go past the legal speed limit ever.
Right?
So if you're in a 25 mile an hour zone,
know whatever your car is,
you've got a porsche or whatever you
like to drive.
It can only go 25 miles an hour,
not a,
I'm a mile and hour more,
no matter how he hit the throttle.
And that would be true in every zone
there.
People would resist that and their
reasons for resisting it is just that it
wouldn't be driving will be less fun
right now.
That is a.
If anything is indefensible when you're
talking about kids being killed,
that is right as a,
as a far more superficial commitment
than wanting to get the higher ups in Al
Qaeda who are trying to at some point
blow up an American city.
Right?
But imagine if as many innocent people
died from driving from one activity,
like think about the amount of people
that die.
They do,
but they don't.
but the numbers are nowhere near.
What about the numbers,
numbers,
numbers.
What are the percentage of people that
have in it died?
The innocent people that have died
because of drones more than 80 percent.
More than 80 percent.
I don't actually.
I just have to plead ignorance on that.
I don't know those numbers.
They're crazy.
They're very high or very high,
but.
But hold on.
Wait,
wait,
wait for a second.
Because you were talking about something
like driving for $30,000
a year.
Every year.
Reliably.
Last 10 years has been 300,000
people.
How many people who drive on a daily
basis wind up driving their whole life
and never killing anybody?
Most.
Well how many drone strikes,
but that's why.
How many drones trikes wind up not
killing innocent people.
Almost none,
but that's not necessarily the way to
analyze it or at least I would argue
that's not the way,
but let's just talk about numbers for
instance,
because another problem I had with Abby
Martin,
she was using this number $2 million
debt in Iraq and Afghanistan.
Where did she get that number?
There's no that no credible person is
using that number.
What do you think the number is the
number?
Almost certainly in order million.
No,
no.
That.
That number is almost certainly an order
of magnitude to high it in the sober
estimates are like 200,000
and most of that most is the result of
sectarian violence,
right?
It's not,
we didn't kill 200,000
people.
We went in to Iraq and this if of we're
mostly talking about Iraq,
that the numbers are much higher there
than an Afghanistan.
We went into Iraq.
We,
we did some very stupid,
understandable things and also some very
stupid things,
but we took the lid off of a,
a simmering civil war that the real
catastrophe of rack apart from our going
in in the first place,
which I never supported.
But the real catastrophe is that having
gone in,
we failed to anticipate the level of
sectarian hatred and we did very little
to,
to hedge against it.
And we kicked off a civil war which
someone like Abby Martin,
clearly things we are entirely
responsible for.
So when we know when she,
uh,
death squads are taken out,
the power drills and drilling holes into
the heads of their neighbors and the
Sunni or returning the favor,
that's us.
We are culpable for that.
Now I don't accept that,
uh,
these people were there,
they're killing one and they've got a
blood feud going back over a millennium
now and we pop the cork on it in Iraq
and that's a terrible thing to have have
collaborated in and we probably
should've foreseen it.
So if we're culpable,
it's for not having anticipated certain
of these consequences of our actions,
but we are not the people.
We are not the Sunni,
her killing Shia and we're not the Shia,
Herculean,
Sunni.
And the same is true in,
in Afghanistan.
We are not the Taliban who,
who,
who are blowing themselves up in crowds
of fellow Afghans as a way of making
their country ungovernable so that we
have to leave right now.
Again,
you could fault us for not having
anticipated this closely enough and or,
or done something effective to prevent
it.
And ironically,
which faulting faultiness for in that
case probably in Iraq is once we saw how
bad this was getting,
you're faulting us for leaving,
right?
You the argument there is the
compassionate thing to have done there.
If insofar as we could have anticipated
the rise of Isis and all of the that you
just this consequent death hold death
toll,
you're faulting us for leaving because
we,
because our political interests and our
stomach was no longer aligned with this
project and you know,
so that's the,
I'm not sure that's an argument that
someone like Abby Martin wants to make,
that we should have stayed longer than
we should've spent more money than that
we should have killed more people in an
effort to keep the locals from killing
so many more people.
So anyway,
this,
the,
the number 2 million is plucked out of a
bad dream.
I don't know where she got 2 million who
was setting up,
I don't know anything to 100 than me.
Obviously you're not going over there
counting bodies.
So who was saying it's $200,000?
Who's saying it's 2 million?
Okay.
Well,
so I'll tell you I'm the highest number
that at one point seemed credible,
was based on a Lancet article.
Lancet is a British medical journal,
very well regarded,
but it has something.
Jamie just put this up on the screen
here,
what is this from Jamie rack body,
so that's 200,000,
but what is,
who was making this Iraq body count?
Dot Org website.
It says,
let's read what it says,
documented civilian deaths from
violence.
One hundred and 38,000
to 156,000
total violent deaths including
combatants 211,000
and this is a.
What is this up from says from following
the 2003 invasion,
but is this different?
I think this is total counting.
They keep counting.
So there are different ways to do this.
One is you can,
you can count bodies,
right?
And and the information there is not
perfect because some people die and
their death doesn't get reported.
You know,
not everyone has a death certificate so
you can count,
you can count bodies,
you can get reports of of of the actual
deaths.
The other thing you can do is you can
estimate the amount of death that would
have occurred in the absence of an
invasion and then compare the rate,
the reports of a statistical sample of
an area and compare the reports of death
based on the past based on,
yeah,
based on what's happening now and you
see a differential there and then you
extrapolate to the rest of the
population and so that's what the
authors of this Lancet article,
they did that and they came up with a
number,
a 600 or 650,000
and that article has been widely
criticized.
Not to the point of it being
unpublished,
but I don't think it's been retracted,
but I don't think any serious person
thinks that article is representative of
the facts.
And so what they did for instances they
they took.
They would take a cluster of I think 40
homes in an area and asked the people
who has died,
who do you know who has to,
who has died and how did they die,
and then they would get.
They would just based on that sample.
They do that in many different sites
around Iraq.
Based on those samples,
they will extrapolate to the rest of the
population and they came up with $600,
650,000.
So one criticism I read about that
article was that they,
they seem to have focused on areas in
near major thoroughfares in big cities
where you know,
where I eds were far more common than
other places and in those same cities or
in other places in Iraq.
So like so places like the very place
you would,
you would most likely plant an Iud is a,
is a non especially representative place
to poll all the families in the area to
see whether they've lost loved ones in
the war.
Right.
So that,
that was one way to get an unrealistic
number.
The other thing is that the,
it seemed that there were just some
shady things with the researchers where
they weren't releasing their data,
their and their methods and the
communication with them broke down.
And so anyway,
the sober people trust who focus on
these things,
I think that's a fictional number.
And that's one third,
not even one third of what abby is
working with.
Excuse me.
I think I caught Arboreta.
It's cold.
Just just watching that podcast,
I think I got his goal.
I think that we can agree that even
200,000
people dead is a tremendous tragedy.
Horrific,
tremendous tragedy.
So was the semantics argument over
whether or not it's tenfold that number
or whatever it is you just disagree
with?
That's not okay.
Manix is a bad word.
Tenfold,
tenfold.
And,
but even more important is we didn't go
in and kill 200,000
people.
We went in and killed,
I'm sure some tens of thousands of
people,
many of whom were were,
you know,
the baptist,
the Revolutionary Guard.
Right.
And we unleashed a Maelstrom of internet
dating,
sectarian conflict,
religious conflict,
and we fail to contain it and it would
have taken more blood and treasure to
contain it.
And um,
so it's,
it's a,
it's a huge problem.
I'm not minimizing the horror of Iraq.
I can,
I,
I never supported our invasion of Iraq,
the things I've said that have been spun
as supportive it are drawn from
conversations with the sort that you and
I are having now.
So if for instance,
I've said things like,
am I might've been on your podcast,
I said at one point,
um,
even if we had gone into Iraq for purely
humanitarian reasons,
right?
Let's,
we're going to go in to remove Saddam.
He's a criminal,
he's a psychopath.
This was a hostage situation.
We're going to get him out of there and
we're just going to dump money on these
people to commit to so that the standard
of living rises to something like Marin
County.
Right?
So this is our goal.
That's actually our intention,
right?
Even if that were the intention,
it still would've been a nightmare.
We still would have been unleashed the
sectarian horror.
We still would have had suicide bombers
against us.
Now I believe that to be true,
right?
So I say something like that and some
people listen to this conversation and
they say,
well,
Sam thinks that we went into a rack for
humanitarian reasons.
He thinks we went into a rack just to
make it like marine county.
Right.
So that's the sort of pushback I get
from the Abbey Martins of the world.
No,
I've never,
I've never said that.
I'm just saying that,
that the truth is so sinister that even
if our intentions were perfectly benign
and we're just trying to raise the
standard of living there and make,
you know,
even just give them the freedom to
practice their own religion.
Right.
So we're trying to make this like
Nebraska,
um,
it would have been a bloodbath given the
beliefs of,
of sorts of people who now populate a
group like Isis.
So anyway,
that's,
that's my claim.
So this is just one aspect of what you
disagreed with.
What she said.
Well,
it just,
so her 2 million number,
the 2 million down to the ground.
I mean she's,
she's just has this,
she's a lefty.
She,
she's well shoot,
but she has a kind of confabulatory
style.
Again,
I'm not really denigrating her
personally,
but I don't know her.
I'm sure she's,
she's a good person,
but there's a style of talking that you
run into with people where there's just.
It's kind of confabulatory we're just
sort of talking and it sounded good and
you're just sort of spitballing,
but you're using numbers,
right?
You're new,
you're using numbers like 2 million or
you're saying things like,
our biggest export is weapons.
The landmark research proves the US led
war on terror has killed as many as 2
million people,
but this is a fraction of the western
responsibility for deaths in Iraq and
Afghanistan over the last two decades.
Last month,
Washington DC based Physicians for
social responsibility released a
landmark study concluding that the death
toll from 10 years of the war on terror
since the nine slash 11 attacks is at
least one point $3 million.
It could be as high as $2 million and we
just finished it just so we can get to
it.
90 seven page report by the Nobel Peace
Prize winning doctor's group is the
first to tally up the total number of
civilian casualties from the US led
counterterrorism interventions in Iraq,
Afghanistan,
and Pakistan.
Right.
Okay,
well,
so,
so clearly that's where she got this
number.
She got it from somebody who got over
there.
Um,
I think that number is the sorts of
people I taught.
So for instance,
when I as a sanity check when I heard
Abby Martin,
I sent an email to my friend Steven
pinker who is an incredibly sober
scientist.
I'm just a very careful researcher.
He was,
he wrote this truly landmark book on the
decline of violence in the last century
that the better angels of our nature
came out a few years ago.
He was like 800 pages on this topic,
very data driven book.
And uh,
he's,
he did a tremendous amount of research
for this and he's,
um,
he's an incredibly well respected
Harvard scientist.
So I pinged him about this and I said,
I'm hearing in liberal circles that we
killed 2 million people in,
in Iraq and Afghanistan.
Sir,
is there any chance that this is true?
And he bailed.
He said,
more or less.
What I'm saying to you now that this is,
it's almost certainly in order of
magnitude too high,
the highest briefly credible study was
the lands that one that was,
I don't know,
I'm,
I didn't know about this and I don't
know what he in particular would say
about this study,
but undoubtedly they use the same sort
of extrapolation methods.
They're not counting bodies.
They're there,
they're doing based on where the ambient
level of death over the years.
They think it's gone up by the tune of 2
million,
uh,
in those,
in those countries.
Um,
but anyway,
so,
so Steve said,
no,
this is,
this is a totally fanciful number and
here's why.
And he broke it down for me.
And then I did,
did a little more reading on the topic,
the,
but again,
the crucial,
I think it really matters whether the
number is 200,000
or 2 million.
I don't want to be loose on that.
But the crucial ethical difference is
did we go in and perform our own sort of
final solution against the Iraqis and
the Afghanistans trying Afghanis trying
to kill millions of people a Hitler or
did we wander into a situation where we
unleashed a civil war and are we
culpable for that and I don't think we
are.
We're culpable for something,
but we're not.
We are not the Sunni's killing the Shia
and vice versa.
You believe that that is the majority
of.
Absolutely.
I don't know if that necessarily the new
study necessarily agrees with that.
I'm sure.
Well,
I.
I would be astonished if they didn't
that Lancet study.
It says it's,
it's likely to be far more accurate than
the figures initially.
Which study is likely to be the 200,001,
655,000
deaths.
So wait a minute.
The people who were saying it may be 2
million,
but it's at least 100.
According to the PSR started the must
disputed Lancet Study Lancet study that
estimated 500,
655,000.
I us up to two,
2006 and over a million until today by
extrapolation was likely to be far more
accurate than the IBCs figure.
In fact,
there were four can confirms a virtual
consensus among among epod,
demolish a epidemiologist on the
reliability of the Atlanta is coming
from the so I don't want to totally.
I'm not saying I'm not open to this
information,
but the website you are pulling this
from is just just trash,
right?
Middle East is just.
I mean this.
This is the.
These guys publish the serial plagiarist
who's been stalking me,
who I vowed not to name.
I missed.
Just the stuff they publish is just pure
insanity.
I mean Google me on this site and you'll
get madness jobs,
so they're.
They're talking about a study.
They didn't perform the steps,
but I can't publish it in real time.
I can vet their representatives that
study and see who the hell.
Who was at say perform that study.
I can't read that.
PSR physicians the social response.
So that's a real group.
But again,
the problem only one problem here is
that this whole area has become so
politicized that it's hard to even,
you know,
like Amnesty International has
embarrassed itself with supporting a
jihadist organization in the UK and they
just at the 11th hour pulled out their
support,
but the,
for,
for a very long time,
they were just in the same trench with
jihadists and not knowing it or,
or,
or they should have known it.
I mean people were telling them,
but they were still,
they were very slow to realize it.
So I don't,
you know,
you don't know,
um,
you should be slow to,
to,
uh,
take even a humanitarian organizations
word for the significance of a given
study.
Um,
but,
you know,
I would find,
I would find it frankly amazing if we
had killed anything like that number of
people and why.
Well,
I would,
I would find it amazing if that number
of people had died,
I would find it.
I,
it's,
it's unthinkable to me that we killed 2
million people.
It's over 12 years of war.
But even if you killed,
you know,
mentally you just know where all this
death is coming from,
you know,
where the bombings that the Iud is,
that truck bombs that,
the blowing up of mosques,
we're not doing that.
Right.
So that's the body count when you look
at,
when you look at the penalty,
we're paying for killing people and when
we look at how much we don't have our
own soldiers don't want to die
unnecessarily in our own cabinet level
of casualties.
We're not on the,
on the other,
on the other side of all those guns.
I mean we've done just a tremendous
amount of internet seeing violence in
both Afghanistan and Iraq and that is
just killing,
you know,
like a bomb will go off and 100 people
at a mosque will be dead.
So Abby Martin,
I think,
I don't think I'm being uncharitable
here.
I think she thinks we're responsible for
that,
for the Sunni Shia violence.
Yes.
Okay.
So whatever the number is,
that's,
that's your argument with that.
You were saying that I was swimming in a
sea of bullshit before that,
right?
What else was bullshit?
Well,
I think,
um,
I,
I don't remember all the details,
but.
So for instance,
one thing she said is that our main
export his arms,
that's not true.
That's not true.
So it may be what does our main export.
I think our main export is like
machinery,
like everything,
everything you like,
farming equipment and pumps and road
making those corn.
That was a guess.
I think it's technically know it's,
I think it's airplanes and I mean
everything they find out everything
that's a machine I think is.
So maybe arms falls into that category,
but when you look at machines,
number one to $119,000,000,000
in machines,
13 point five percent of total exports.
Number two,
electronic equipment,
171 billion oil,
$157 billion.
Number three vehicles,
$135 billion number for aircrafts and
spacecrafts,
$124.
Billion.
Number six,
medical tech,
net technical equipment,
84 billion.
Number seven gems,
precious metals and coins,
65 billion.
That's interesting.
Number Eight,
plastics,
63 billion.
Number nine,
pharmaceuticals,
43 billion coming in strong with the
Viagra.
Number 10 organic chemical.
So guns aren't even in the top 10
machines.
Yeah,
but I'm sure that.
Well you got,
you have to think that weaponry is
somehow spread across aircraft machines
and aircraft vehicles.
I,
well,
I mean I'll cut her the,
the benefit of the doubt there that be
there is because you know that,
that let's find a more comprehensive
list that actually includes arms because
it seemed that that's pretty sneaky as
if it is machines and she might be
somehow or another will say it's export,
you know,
$50,000,000,000
in arms a year.
I don't know what it is,
but it's um,
and that's,
that's a whole nother conversation
whether we should be doing that.
I think that's suicidally stupid in
certain cases that we're arming people
who are eventually going to be using
these arms against us or our friends.
But conspiracy theory would be that
that's how they perpetuate this whole
constant cycle of war.
So you have to keep arming your random.
Well No.
So I think the economic interests of
defense contractors is not something
that I am especially sanguine about.
It's not,
you know,
I think that the,
the,
the role of the possible role of
corruption there and a concert of
callous indifference to the effects of,
of being in this business.
I think that's,
that's a very real concern.
But so to say that we,
this is our main export is bombs
essentially.
That's not true.
Now maybe what she meant to say is we
are the main export of weaponry in the
world.
It's probably just,
which is probably true,
but that's not what she said.
Or maybe she said both and I only heard
one.
No,
I think you're correct in what she said
she might be getting.
You know,
that's the problem.
Unless you're doing the look.
We live in a world that's so broad and
comprehensive that unless you're doing
the actual research herself and not just
doing it,
but doing it over a long period of time
and very meticulous,
most likely you don't know the actual
numbers unless there's very few things
that I could talk about with utmost
certainty that aren't involved directly
in my own life.
And when you deal with numbers,
like numbers of imported guns,
export had guns,
people dying in a place that you've
never even visited.
Boy,
you were relying on a lot of people's
data.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
And one thing that really is depressing
is the degree to which people are.
So this conversation is so politicized
that you just even signed the climate
change conversation.
The fact that there are people who are
too,
you can always find someone with a phd
to sit up there and say,
you know,
I don't think cigarettes caused cancer.
Right?
I mean,
you can find those people.
You can find the people who are,
who are engineers who say that nine
slash 11 had to be an inside job because
you know,
the melting point of steel,
blah,
and you can find on all these issues
you,
you get incredibly politicized science
and it's so,
but if certain things don't pass the
smell test and 2 million to me,
2 million people doesn't pass the smell
test.
Certainly if you're going to say that we
killed those 2 million people that we,
we,
you know,
did we,
we did double the level of a Rwandan
genocide intentionally.
That was what we did.
That just seems completely
masochistically hallucinatory to me.
I see your point.
Um,
I don't know who's right,
but I see your point now.
Was there anything else that she said
that you needed to dispute?
Um,
I don't think so.
I mean,
the thing I can say just categorically
is that what she said about my concern
about intention is,
is just not true.
It is.
If you intentions matter because they
are the best predictor as to what the,
what the person is likely to do in the
future.
If you know someone is killing people
because he intends that he wants that,
he wants to cause grief and suffering
and death will then you know this is a
person you have to jail or kill and this
is not a good actor.
If someone does it because they.
They did it by accident or they didn't
foresee the consequences of their
actions or they were trying to get the
bad guy and they they,
they produce collateral damage.
It's a very different scenario and the
at the body count may be the same.
And so the thing I faulted Chomsky for
in the past is that he seems to talk
about situations where all you need to
concern yourself as with his body count.
So that.
The example I dealt with in my first
book,
the end of faith was a,
and this was in reaction to a short
book.
He did right after nine slash 11 called
nine slash 11.
He talked about the Clintons bombing of
the shift of a pharmaceutical plant in
Sudan,
in retaliation for the embassy bond
bombings.
Al Qaeda bombings in Kenya in the
nineties.
And he talked about this bombing of the
pharmaceutical plant as a,
as a great atrocity,
seemingly equivalent to the atrocity of
nine slash 11 or worse,
um,
because of the,
of the consequences for Sudan of having
their for half the supply of
pharmaceuticals destroy,
they couldn't,
you know,
people would die from preventable
illness as a result of this.
Well,
what an incredible atrocity except,
you know,
the representation of our government was
not.
And I think any rational thinking on
this topic,
which would suggest that our intention
was not to destroy a pharmaceutical
plant.
We claim to be bombing what we thought
was a chemical weapons factory were run
by al Qaeda and we wanted to degrade
that capacity of theirs after they hit
just bombed to embassies in east Africa.
So,
um,
let's just say that's true,
but who knows what our actual intentions
were.
But if,
if our intention was to bomb a chemical
weapons plant that we didn't know was a
pharmaceutical plant and we bombed a
pharmaceutical plant that was being used
for peaceful purposes.
And as a result,
tens of thousands of people didn't get
their medicine and died.
That is not an equivalent atrocity to
intentionally killing tens of thousands
of people.
Right?
It's a,
it's,
it's an instance of bad luck.
You were trying to get the bad guys.
We bombed it in the middle of the night
as far as I know,
Clinton didn't even think anyone would
be there.
Right.
So it's possible that we weren't trying
to kill anyone per se.
We were just trying to bomb a chemical
weapons plant.
If you accept that to be true,
then the fact that tens of thousands of
people died as a result doesn't have the
same ethical significance.
It is much more like you and I are just
trying to get home at 55 miles an hour,
but we're participating in a system
that's going to kill 30,000
people this year based on our speed
limits.
We're not intending to kill any of those
people.
Right?
It's just.
And,
but perhaps we should have foreseen.
So it was bad data was bad data.
Well,
no,
I mean that's,
that's what our government said about
his actions.
Now let's say,
let's say that's not true.
Let's say,
um,
let's say it was a pharmacy,
let's say we knew it was a
pharmaceutical medical plans,
but we also thought it was a chemical
weapons plant and we bombed it really
knowing what the bat,
you know,
we thought we were going to get the
chemical weapons facility,
but we also knew we were going to
destroy all of their,
their pharmaceutical infrastructure and
that would have cascading bad effects
that all things considered.
We didn't care that much about.
Right.
Let's say,
let's say it was that the place on this
continuum of,
you know,
moral callousness,
well that's still different than trying
to kill 10,000
people by taking away their medicine.
Right?
It's,
it's,
um,
it's May,
may,
May.
In My,
in my view,
it may not be so different and it's
something that we would be culpable for.
But I think you have to what Matt,
the reason why intentions matter is
because they are,
they're the clear expression of what we
are committed the ends to which we're
committed.
If the kind of world we want to live in.
And so you have.
I mean,
this is what I did in that first book I
asked them,
this is a thought experiment I called
the,
um,
the perfect weapon where I said,
well,
you know,
just imagine what a group would do if
they had perfect weapons,
right?
Where they know there's no such thing as
collateral damage.
They could just target everyone they
wanted to target.
They would never hit the,
you know,
the sound been lawns mom who happened to
be standing too close to him.
They just go,
they're just going to hit Osama bin
Ladin.
Um,
so what would any one group do with the
perfect weapon?
What would Bibi Netanyahu do with
perfect weapons?
What would Hitler have done with perfect
weapons?
What would Bill Clinton do with perfect
People like Chomsky and Abby Martin talk
about the Clintons and the bushes and
the net and Yahoos and the Dick Cheney's
of the world.
And I'm not necessarily equating all of
those people,
but they're all,
they're all sort of in a certain area
for me.
I'm,
uh,
as though they would act with the
perfect weapon exactly the way Hitler or
Osama bin Laden or Saddam Hussein would
act with the perfect weapon that we have
a level of malevolence,
a level of commitment that makes you so
much of what she was saying essentially
that kind of the,
the intentions of our government are to
go around the world killing Brown
skinned people and that was a pick a
phrase she used and that,
and the spirit in which he talked about
our culpability on the world stage is
very much in the sense that we have
intentionally murdered millions of brown
skin people because we don't care about
them.
And maybe it's part of the reason why
we,
we want them dead.
Right?
Um,
and that's,
I do not believe that's the situation
we're in.
I believe.
I certainly unbelief that someone like
President Obama wants to create massive
collateral damage.
And if you gave him the perfect weapon,
I'm reasonably sure he would target the
bad guys.
People who,
if you and I could vote on whether these
people should go down 90,
we would have a 90 percent convergence
with him.
Right.
We wouldn't find ourselves in the
presence of a,
of a psychopath who just was so amped up
on his power to kill that he would be
killing,
you know,
and frank.
Right.
Whereas there are people who really did
kill and frank because they intended to
kill hand,
frank and everyone like her.
Right.
There's a difference.
Is there any culpability?
Is there any.
Do you put any blame on the United
States government and our foreign policy
and our decisions as far as the
domination of global natural resources,
whatever we've done overseas is,
is that in any way responsible for the
hatred that these people have for
America in the first place?
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
and beyond the hatred,
uh,
responsible for our alliances with
people who commit outright human rights
by Saudi Arabia.
Yeah.
So the fact that we can't just break all
ties with Saudi Arabia,
the fact that we can't twist their arm
and get them to behave like civilized,
a civilized culture,
a culture on the world stage at this
point.
So they're,
they're jailing and,
and caning bloggers.
This is one,
a atheist blogger.
I'm a Rafe Badawi.
I'm sorry if I'm mispronouncing his
name.
Um,
you know,
it's a,
it's an absolute scandal.
The fact that we can't apply more
pressure to them and that isn't as far
as I can tell,
entirely explained by our dependence on
oil and our unwillingness we have the
technology to break this dependence on
oil.
The fact that we have such entrenched
financial interests that's keeping us
tied to oil.
Um,
and that,
that the whole military industrial
complex is tuned to safeguard those
interests for,
for us in the world that have those
interests have been,
they've been monetized,
they been controlled,
well monopolize,
roll back the clock 50 years there I'm
sure was not an alternative to being
dependent on oil.
Right.
There's a certain point.
So we're totally dependent on oil.
Civilization just needs petrochemicals
to survive.
And they all happen to be buried in the
ground,
in inconveniently,
under the palaces of these religious
maniacs,
the that may have been the situation
then.
So how culpable we are are we for
securing our interests and not just we
the US,
but you know,
the west at that point by,
by entering a relationship with the
house of sowed.
That's one question that may have been a
marriage of necessity and there have
been marriages of necessity with
tyrants,
I think in the past,
but now the fact that we can't sprint to
the finish line and get off of oil,
right?
We know this is a dwindling resource,
we know is a disaster for climate
change.
We know that there would be a,
uh,
the,
the financial and technological
renaissance that's waiting if we all
just grab Elon Musk's coattails and,
and,
and go towards sustainable energy.
Um,
all of this,
you know,
our interests and what we're funding
both sides of the war on terror.
It makes absolutely no sense.
So we should just make a full court
press in the direction of
sustainability,
energy security,
and getting ourselves into a position to
say to the people like the Saudis,
you treat your bloggers better or we're
going to bankrupt you,
right?
I mean,
it's just,
you all,
all their wealth is coming down of the
ground,
right?
So the moment we don't need this wealth
or need to defend it,
what would be in a much better position
to demand that they,
that people treat women better
throughout the world and they treat,
you know,
they,
they honor free speech,
etc.
So I think it's a scandal that we,
we are not,
uh,
doing that and I think we asked,
we are culpable for doing that,
but given the,
given what would happen to us in the
near term if we lost access to oil.
And again,
I'm not juSt talking about us,
I'm talking about europe and just the
whole world.
it's a,
it's been a very difficult situation to
be in and it's understandable that we
have gotten into this situation,
but I don't find it understandable now
that we,
we aren't,
um,
you know,
sprinting away for it.
So fucking
define your point of view.
Your point of view is more of a
pragmatic take on what the world is
currently at this stage.
It's not your,
you're not taking away the
responsibility of the United States
government.
You're not saying that they haven't made
horrific decisions.
You're not saying that they haven't been
manipulated by these gigantic
corporations that are profiting off of
the war that we're currently involved
in,
that you were just saying that if you
want to look at the actual reality of
the good guys and the bad guys and
where,
where the world is fucked right now.
There are certain things that have to be
done and there are certain
people that have to be taken out.
If you do not,
you put everyone else at risk.
Is that,
is that a good?
That's fair.
Well,
I guess I would only tweak it add that
and I.
This is the ipad saying this for 10
years,
at least,
are now closer to 15 years and It just
never gets heard.
I can grant someone like chomsky,
you know,
80,
90 percent of his thesis.
Right.
So yeah,
I think he's,
he pushes forward into kind of a
masochistic voodoo a little bit.
But,
but we have done horrific things
historically.
Right.
And,
and the question is just how far you
want to roll you.
You'll walk back in your,
in your time machine.
But you know,
starting with,
you know,
our treatment of the native americans on
up and it depends on who,
who the we is.
But we be in the United States,
right?
So we get,
we get here,
we start behaving badly and we behave
badly for a very long while and we have
done terrible things.
And yet it is also true that we have
enemies we haven't made.
We have people.
There are people who have had the
benefit of everything the west has to
offer,
who are waking up today deciding to join
isis for reasons that have nothing to do
with us foreign policy or if they do
have something to do with us foreign
policy.
It's based on a theological grievance.
It's not based on any real political
concern for the lives of the
palestinians is based on you've got
infidels too close to muslim holy sites.
Um,
and you have the problem.
The,
the intellectual and moral problem I've
spent more time focused on is the
problem of someone like jihadi john,
right?
The guy who has got a degree in computer
science,
right?
He comes from a middle upper,
middle class background in the uk.
He's got all the opportunity anyone
could want that.
There are at least 3 billion people,
probably something like 5 billion
people,
excuse me,
who would,
who would trade places with him to be in
a position of such opportunity in this
world.
And yet,
the opportunity he wants to take is to
move to Iraq or Syria and,
you know,
cut the heads off of journalists and aid
workers,
journalists and aid workers.
They're not know navy seals.
They captured.
They want to kill the aid workers.
It's not an accident,
it's not,
it's not something that,
it's not like a perversion of their
impulse is not like,
oh,
I would really wish this guy wasn't an
aid worker or a journalist,
you know,
but when he's the only guy we have no,
this is,
this is their commitments or that
horrible.
Right?
And,
and,
um,
you have to explain how,
and this is something that someone like
abby martin and someone like noam
chomsky is the phenomenon.
they really don't explain how is it that
someone with all the opportunity who's
never been victimized by anyone,
how is it that he is committed to the
most of horns and profligate misuse of
human life where he's just his risk
ready to burn up the world,
right?
And now how do you get tens of thousands
of people like this coming from a first
world societies and map.
And so then,
so given that,
given that phenomenon,
then what explains the commitments of
the people who don't have all those
opportunities right there,
the people who are born in these
societies are shell shocked and had been
mistreated at who,
who are,
who have understandable grievances
against us,
right?
They are part of the collateral damage.
We've been bombing over there after.
All right?
So it's no mystery that they would hate
the west,
right?
Some of them.
I meAn,
some of them still love the west,
some of them still are trying to get
out.
Some of that I hear from,
I fear I hear from atheist in these
countries who don't hate the west.
I mean they don't follow.
They don't follow abby martin's line on
this.
They don't,
they don't.
They understand why we were bombing in
their neighborhoods.
Right?
But,
um,
the fact is this is really like a
science experiment there,
prIstine cases of people who have no
rational grievance,
who devote their lives to waging jihad
and they're not mentally ill and they're
not.
And that's,
that's the,
that's the problem that I,
that,
that problem is scaling thing that I
worry about is that as a meme that is
spreadable you don't have to ever meet
anyone affiliated with a terrorist
organization to get this idea into your
head.
And,
and so that's,
that's the piece I have focused on.
Um,
and it's not that I've denied the
reality of the other pieces.
Is this related in any way to just a
natural instinct that's a certain amount
of people have to be contrarians.
I mean there's certain amount of people
that when they,
when they find any sort of large group
that's in power,
they want to oppose them.
If they find a band that's popular,
they want to hate it.
If they find a political party that's in
control,
they want to oppose it.
There's a certain amount of people that
are just natural contrarians.
When they find a group that is
absolutely committed and completely
involved in an ideology to the point
where they're rabid about it,
it becomes attractive to them and they
want to join that resistance to fight
against the death star that is the
United States.
I'm not religious by any stretch of the
imagination,
but what I am is curious and one of the
things that I like to do is I like to
watch a really pious or really obsessed
religious people.
I love to watch videos of them because I
find it fascinating and there's a
certain amount of.
When I see the islamic scholars that are
talking in absolutes,
absolute confidence about their beliefs,
there's a certaIn amount of that that I
personally find attractive.
I don't want to join isis.
I don't want to become a muslim,
but when I see someone almost like what
we're talking about with conor mcgrEgor
earlier where he just fucking believes,
man.
When someone believes I was watching
this guy.
I forget his name,
but he's a guy from.
He lives in the uk and he's this rabid
islamic scholar that he.
All of his tweets are on.
How islam is superior and it doesn't
have to be adjusted like the laws of
modern society and secular wisdom is
inferior to the islamic wisdom and blah,
blah,
blah.
I watched this guy do this youtube video
where he's describing how islamic
culture is superior to western culture
in terms of the way they manage money
and he made a lot of fucking good points
and made a lot of good points about
wealth and about,
uh,
about building economies and about how
you,
you know,
you take a company that's only worth
$100,000,
but you could sell it for a million
dollars or you know,
trade it,
you know,
you have stocks and this is invisible
wealth and islam doesn't allow invisible
wealth because that's how society is get
crushed and that's how we're other
economies crumble.
And I'm watching this guy with his moral
certainty and his extreme confidence in
what he's saying absolute.
And it becomes compelling.
And I'm not joining.
I'm not,
I'm not saying that he got me,
but I'm saying that I'm just absolutely
admitting there's a per a certain aspect
of human nature that gets compelled to
join groups.
Oops.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Well,
there's something,
there's that component of it which,
which I understand,
but there's also just the,
the religious ecstasy component,
the aesthetics,
the emotional component of it,
which I really understand and I'm
susceptible to so far.
I have a blog post leaves called islam
and the misuses of ecstasy where it's
actually the first blog posts I ever
wrote where I realized I could not
possibly have written this in book form
or in a newspaper because it relied on
embedded video.
And the only way to have done this with
was with embedded video.
And um,
I wrote this,
I think in,
you know,
once again over protest the,
something was said about me by glenn
greenwald or somebody to show it.
Yeah.
The charge had been that I totally lack
empathy,
right?
Like,
I'm not,
I don't even know what it's like to be,
you know,
what these people are getting out of
their religion.
Right.
I've just demonized a whole people I
don't understand religion and so I wrote
this blog post to trying to indicate how
far from the truth that was.
So I wrote.
So I,
I put the example of the call to prayer,
right?
Which I think,
I mean there,
there are some that sound kind of ratty,
but a nice call to prayer I think is one
of the most beautiful sounding things
humanity has ever produced,
right?
I mean,
I,
that,
that hits me,
that gets into my bones,
right?
I don't,
I don't have to imagine what a devout
muslim,
his feeling when he hears the call to
prayer.
I think it's absolutely beautiful.
Right?
And without even knowing the length.
Exactly.
right.
And I'm not without ever having been a
muslim or believe in any,
you know,
if that sound and again to your
listeners can just read that blog post,
I only dimly remember what I wrote,
but if that's,
if that ritual was purposed as to
towards some other end,
right?
If that ritual just was signifying,
you know,
let's all get up in the morning and
consider how profound human
consciousness is and consider our
togetherness on this,
you know,
rock spinning through empty space and
realized that we just have this common
project to make the world beautiful.
Right?
If that was what that meant,
right?
I would just want a minaret,
you know,
right next to my house in the,
I mean I would just,
I would,
I would be totally on board with,
with,
with the,
the experience of,
of,
of participating in that.
so I'm totally empathetic there.
And I.
So I went through many other instances
of this where something I'm seeing in
the muslim world,
I,
I really grok how beautIful and
meaningful and captivating this is for
people.
But then at the end I put in a,
a,
um,
a quranic recitation and sermon by a.
Forgot his name now,
but some shake who's got,
you know,
like 10 times the number of twitter
followers you have,
right?
I mean,
so he's like,
he's not a fringe figure.
He's a muslim rockstar and you know,
you see the translation of what he,
he's given this tear filled recitation
of the koran,
which again is beautiful,
right?
He's a great,
he's a great singer and I'm at the end.
It's a packed house in wherever it was,
Saudi Arabia,
Yemen,
and um,
but what is being said there is so
ethically ugly right center essentially
celebrating that the tortures of hell,
right?
And just,
just expressing a certainty that,
that,
that infidels are going to go to hell
and how,
you know,
this is a,
you have to organize your life around
this question,
but just how to,
how to escape the torments of hell.
And the only way to do it has to be a
true believer in,
in the koran and mohammed,
etc.
And this is at the center of the,
of the,
the mandola of their ethical concern.
There's nothing matters but nothing,
nothing in this life matters but
avoiding hell fire.
And so there's kind of a ghastly
perversion of this impulse that I think
many of us feel.
I certainly feel it to transcend
yourself,
to experience bliss and ecstasy and
compassion.
And um,
and you know,
it's,
it is very much,
it's very much like burning man for
people.
I mean it's like if,
if,
imagine at burning man,
whereas just as ecstatic as it was
attracting all the smart people that it
attracts but strewn throughout,
it was a message of just true
divisiveness like everyone else who's
not here is going to be tortured for
eternity and they deserve it and we
shouldn't be their friends and we should
fuck them over any way we can when we
get out of this place.
And if god had wanted to enlighten them,
he would have,
but he hasn't.
So we're the only ones here and,
and it just kind of an a,
a durable message of us and them
thinking that just cannot be dissolved.
Right?
That's what's going on in the muslim
world.
And,
and that's a huge problem because it
does,
it's pulling all the strings of,
you know,
I mean,
it's not just islam.
Obviously christianity has a version of
this and,
and all religions and principle have a
version of this,
but there are differences there.
There is no version of jihad that know
there's no buddhist jihad.
It's not to say that buddhist can't do
terrible things and it's not to say you
can't find buddhist reasons for doing
terrible things,
but their jihad,
jihad martyrdom,
paradise.
TheSe,
this,
this is the jewel,
you know,
horrible jewel that,
that so many millions of people are
contemplating in,
in an islamic context.
And that's,
that's what I'm worried about and I'm
not insensitive to the,
to the experience people are having is
this version of islam,
recent in human history.
There's this extreme radical version of
this.
There are some things you can say that
have,
you know,
with wahhabism and salafi style islam
generally that have been politicized and
tuned up in a negative way in the last
century that you can say that,
but the reality is that jihad is as old
as islam and islam spread by jihad and
it isn't the original version of jihad
or on your own vices.
Oh no,
that's just.
No,
I mean there is that component to it.
There is a energy hot and an outer
jihad,
but there was always an outer jihad and
that's how muhammad spread the faith and
mohammed.
I mean,
so to answer your question very simply,
as I did somewhere,
I just said there's absolutely nothing
isis is doing.
The islamic state is doing that.
Mohammed didn't do right.
I think I said good luck finding
something significant that some
difference between.
I mean taking sex slaves,
right?
Muhammad took sex slaves and gave sex
slaves to his.
His generals.
It was totally kosher.
Kosher thing to do.
If You're going to follow the example of
stefan that kosher.
Yeah.
Nobody.
Hello?
I mean if you're going,
if you're going to follow muhammad's
example,
which is a real,
is perhaps the main lens through what
you have to look at this.
There's the.
That's just what's in the koran and
there's what's in the huddle with the
larger literature and there's the
example of muhammad,
which is,
which is a tested two in both those
literatures and in the early biographies
about him.
Mohammed was not like the buddha.
He was not like jesus.
He was not like he was not.
He was,
he was a conquering warlord,
who's succeeded,
right?
And that is an example that is very
different from the example of a guy who
got crucified or the example of a guy
spent his wife meditating and then
teaching,
right?
If,
if the buddha had been lopping heads
off,
you know,
add every sermon and advocating just
talking endlessly about when to kill
people and how many people to kill and
you know,
how many sex later,
how to treat your sex lives.
If that was,
if that was just strewn throughout the
buddhist teaching,
I would expect buddhists to behave
exactly the way we see members of isis
and al qaeda and al shabaab and boko
haram behave.
How to treat your sex slaves.
Sure.
How many.
So yes,
how do you treat your sex lives?
Why don't you taking,
taking sex?
I mean taking sex slaves,
taking immediate.
So you can.
It's not adultery if you're having sex
with sex slaves,
it's adultery.
If you're,
if you're having sex with someone,
you care about other women,
right?
Or other muslim women,
but you're convenient.
Um,
no,
you can slavery.
I mean this,
this is the horror of of abrahamic
religion.
Generally.
These are.
ThIs is why we know these are books were
not authored by a moral genius.
The bible and the koran can't give you a
basis to resist slavery.
They did slavery,
supported in both traditions,
so the fact that we have after centuries
decided to more or less unanimously that
slavery is an abomination that proves
that there's more moral wisdom to be
found outside of these books than
inside.
At least on that point and I met and I
would argue on virtually every other
point of consequence.
Now it's not that.
It's not to say they're not jams of,
of,
of moral wisdom and in some of these
books,
but they're not best found in those
books and there's so much else in there
that is just that gives you the ethic of
the taliban and that's,
and that's.
It's an inconvenient fact because it is.
This is what the fundamentalist
fundamentalist do that.
The islamists,
the jihadists,
look at the books,
know that the members of isis right now
have the theology on their side.
It's not like they're ignoring the
books.
They're looking at the books very
literally and they're saying,
you know what,
in here,
you know,
what are we,
what are we doing that you don't find in
the books?
Essentially it's like we were just.
This is just connecting the dots,
you know,
that was one of the videos that you
would post it up on your blog that you
and I discussed the guy that was
standing in front of all those people
that was talking about stoning people
for adultery or the treatment of
homosexuals and how this is not radical
islam.
This is just islam and that
was shocking and that's one of those
videos where you posted or you talk
about it and you get a million people
that get upset at you over it.
Get a million people that call you
islamophobic or what have you and get
upset about it and a lot of those are
the same people.
There was a weird thing that happened
after charlie hebdo that really kind of
freaked me oUt where there was a lot of
liberals and progressives that we're
pointing to the callousness of the
cartoons as almost a justification for
murdering a bunch of cartooniSts that,
you know,
the punching down thing kept being
discussed,
this weird liberal obsession with the
way humor is disseminated that in
somehow or another it justified or at
least a rationalize the fact that they
could just gunned down cartoonists,
cartoonists,
you're not talking about people that are
doing experiments on monkeys or people
that are a torturing animals mean you're
not talking about people that are
imprisoning other human beings.
You're not talking about people that
are,
you know,
even even stopping people from doing
anything,
just mocking them in cartoons
or,
and in this case mocking also
christianity and the vatican and many of
the things that were interpreted,
interpreted as racist,
warranty.
Even racist if You understood french or
french politics.
So it's,
it's no,
it's shocking.
And people like the people who missed
the,
the train on this,
people like gary trudeau,
the doonesbury creator.
I mean,
he just,
just,
uh,
came out against,
um,
uh,
charlene abdo and a bunch of writers who
belonged to the pen America
organization,
which is the whole point of which is to
defend free speech.
They just walked out of a gala event or
declined to show up because penn had
given charlene abdo the,
you know,
the freedom of expression award this
year as they should have.
And some prominent people,
uh,
pro laughter in protest.
And um,
it's,
uh,
no,
the faculty is that,
what,
what is that?
It's,
it's political correctness and fears
about being perceived as a racist and
this and this notion that you should,
that it makes sense to have a double
standard here where you can,
um,
that there's some trade off between
freedom of expression and freedom of
religion.
Where,
where,
when the freedom that's being claimed on
the religious side is the freedom not to
be offended,
right?
To,
not.
So,
I mean,
what,
what really,
what's happening here is some number of
muslims are demanding that non muslims
follow the taboos of islam.
So it's taboo for you to say anything
negative about the profit or even to
depict him in a drawing,
right?
That's,
that's where it gets rewarded and we
want you to follow this taboo though you
are not muslim and we feel so strongly
about this that we're going to kill you
or threatened to make credible threats
of killing you or we're just going to,
when people do kill you,
we're going to blame you for having
gotten yourself killed,
for having been so stupid and
insensitive by caricaturing the profit
and that whole.
I mean that just has to lose.
I mean that we have to.
We have to hold to free speech so
unequivocallY that all the people over
here who think that,
that there is this trade off between
religious sensitivity and free speech,
just have to realize that that they've
lost because we don't play this game
with any other religion or just think
about this analogy I've used before,
but the book of mormon,
right?
It just,
it just pillories mormonism.
It makes mormonism look ridiculous,
right?
What are the mormons do in response?
The mormons took out ads in playbill,
right?
If it was,
it was very cute.
What they did,
they took out ads.
Like if you,
if you like the play,
you know,
you come,
come and learn the real stuff.
Right.
It was just,
it was totally civil.
Good natured.
Find that either my favorite cult,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
They really are.
I like them way more than I even like
scientology,
which is my second favorite,
but,
but trey parker and matt stone are not
looking over their shoulders for the
mormon assassins,
but they've come here about muslims.
but briefly they didn't even.
They put muhammad in a bear suit.
It was just a bear.
Right.
And then they had to put the bear suit
in a van and then they pulled it off the
air war still.
I had to pull it off the air and we're
still.
It made sense for them to pull it off
the air given the actual nature of the
threat.
And so we've.
So as I've argued,
we have already lost our freedom of
speech on this issue and to the,
that one individual issue.
We've almost the only issue on earth
really.
And there are people on the liberal side
of this argument who think that is a
good thing,
that,
that is a,
that you are a racist to question the,
the,
um,
the decency of that situation and it's
just not truly so it's a completely
insane doctrine that is,
that we should not have to,
we should be able to criticize to our
heart's content without threats of
violence as we,
as we can with every other insane
doctrine.
Do you think that that's fear,
that's a fear of islam,
the fear of retaliation,
that they want to be on the side of the
others because it's so dangerous because
they are the only religion that will
come out and kill you.
And these same people I've found that
will call people out on being
islamophobic will not say a fucking peep
about anti christian rhetoric.
If you start talking shit about jesus or
christianity,
they never have a word to say about it
because it's not dangerous because it's
not dangerous to be on that side.
I think it's much more just white guilt
and,
um,
and political correctness.
There's definitely some of that as just
a sense that it's just,
it is.
If you take.
Again,
I don't mean to trash abby per se.
If you met her,
you'd love her.
She's a great person.
She's cool,
but,
but if this is,
if you take her view of our foreign
policy,
if you just agreed with her down the
line does check all those boxes.
2 million people.
We did it all.
We,
you know,
we just kill brown skin people all over
the world because we just liked to sell
bombs and that's really what our moral
core,
you know.
Then yeah.
Then we should have a fair amount of
white guilt.
Right.
Then it's understandable that you think
that more or less any a non western
population that expresses a grievance
against us has a point.
Well,
isn't there a real problem with saying
our cars?
You and I have nothing to do with that
and we're a part of this weird gang
called the United States of America.
Whenever you say us,
what we've done us.
I mean we haven't done shit,
but we're somehow another lumped into
this group.
That's a big part of it,
but we've participated in a system,
the existence of which is predicated on
some of this shit,
so existence of which existed long
before you and I are ever born.
We're born into a system.
We have zero control over.
well that.
And that's why I think that some of the
greatest ethical changes,
uh,
the greatest ethical progress for us as
a species is going to come not with each
one of us developing an ethical code
that allows us to be a hero,
you know,
personally and just bucking the system
and bucking a trend from morning till
night.
We need to design systems that are more
benign,
you know,
so it's like,
it comes down to the,
you know,
our smartphones.
Like is there a way to produce a
smartphone that is ethically benign
right now?
At the moment it seems like there isn't,
or at least we're not.
We're not being so scrupulous as to find
one.
But you mean as far as conflict
minerals?
Exactly.
All of it's like it could have,
can,
what?
Could we actually be good people all the
way down the supply chain,
slave labor,
all the way down.
Now I would pay more for that phone.
There's no question.
What do you know?
There was a phone that they were trying
to produce about that.
It was called the fair phone going and
it was non conflict minerals.
It was uh,
the.
But it was only three j.
Nobody wants a piece of shit.
That's why I'm not kidding.
But that's where it comes down to is
called the fairfax are.
Hold on.
Our better nature is so tenuous that
this,
the difference between four g and three
g could make the difference,
right?
It's like,
yeah,
let's see if they've moved up to four g,
I'll fucking buy it.
Right,
right.
It's got to be.
Nobody wants to be my look at that.
They're sold out.
Wow.
My point is no one should have to have a
bad phone to be a good person.
Right?
So true.
So we want systems that is adorable,
right?
When you see liberals with an iphone
six,
like listen son,
but it's.
No,
but it's,
it's weird.
We are those liberals to look at that
guy with a fair fall and that's what you
get when you get a fair fault.
That's perfect.
That goddamn brick,
something the size of a toaster,
the ice tea video from 1988,
that breakfast at that guy's got up to
his ear is an unfair iphone.
That
is a terrible way to sell your phone.
Why would you have that fuck of
ridiculous?
You can't put that in your pocket sun.
Yeah.
Well,
all of those people that buy those
things and have those,
those extreme liberal values,
progressive values.
You have to deal with the absolute
reality that at the very least,
your phone is being produced in a
factory where people are jumping off the
roof.
That's a fact.
Unless they're making them in Korea,
the samsung phones,
I think ethically,
I think they have like a leg up on the
iphone in the sense that you know the
fox con buildings where they have nets
installed around the building to keep
people from jumping off the roof because
it sucks so bad there,
and I've heard the argument against
that.
All the amount of people that you got to
deal with,
the fact that these factories employee
half a million people and the number of
people that commit suicide is directly
proportionate to the same number of
people that would commit suicide in the
regular population,
but they're killing themselves at work.
Like how many people kill themselves at
work?
Like that's not normal and they live at
work.
Okay,
well that's not normal either.
You got slaves.
These are essentially wage slaves.
Again,
these are situations where there's
often,
or at least sometimes no good option
immediately.
So when you think of like child labor
laws in a place like Pakistan,
I know,
but look at that phone dude,
look how beautiful that talks to you and
shit.
Come on on that screen pretty.
I'm not going to lose any sleep at night
over your own enough phone.
Thanks buddy.
Um,
I think you and I would and millions of
other people would probably.
I mean,
I know I would,
but I think millions.
If,
if we could make the problem
transparent,
we would pay more to be truly good
actors across in all of the streams of
influence and um,
but there are certain situations again
where I just mentioned,
you know,
child labor laws in Pakistan,
if you go,
if you just say no kids can work,
right?
Because this is obscene.
This is,
you know,
we haven't done this in the west for
over 100 years.
You know,
we don't want kids in stitching together
our soccer balls,
right?
These kids should be in school.
Well,
there are situations where that may be
workable,
right?
Where you get the kid out of the factory
and where he's been working 14 hours a
day and you get him into school and he's
got a better life.
But there are many situations and in
places like Pakistan,
where know what you've just done is
you've made it impossible for this kid
to work and you've further impoverished
his family because he wasn't gonna go to
school anyway.
Now he's going to find it.
He's going to be picking stuff out of a
trash heap or whatever it is.
And he,
he does that you haven't put in place
and alternative that's workable.
And so we in many pro with many problems
of this sort,
we have to find a path forward where the
first doors we open,
all the choice,
the doors we have to open,
all suck,
right?
And,
and there.
And there are there situations,
geo politically that are like that where
you can either back a guy who's a
dictator,
right?
But he's secular and he's committed to a
first approximation to soca basically
sane relations with the rest of the
world.
But he's,
he really is a dictator and he really
has a history of treating people badly.
And he's going to treat political
dissent very badly because of the
possible consequences for him if he
doesn't,
because the society's is bursting,
coming apart at the seams,
um,
or you can just let the islamists and
the jihadist run the place.
Right?
And that is a,
you know,
there's no good option and it's
understandable that we have in many
cases chosen the dictator there.
Well that was sort of the situation with
saddam hussein,
right?
Yeah.
Me,
psychopath.
Children were psychopaths,
murderers,
serial killers,
he did horrific things,
but he was very secular in the way he
ran his country.
And so There we're were facing this on
many fronts and I want to ask you this
because you have these extreme opinions
about these things.
You have these extreme criticisms.
If you could,
if ultimately someone said,
look,
sam,
you're going to be king of the world.
You are going to be the guy that gets to
sort this mess out.
We need someone to engineer a global
culture.
What would be the step that you would
take to try to alleviate some of the
suffering of the world?
Alleviate some of the bloodshed,
alleviate all these conflicts.
Is geopolitical conflicts
well in this area?
The first few things I would do it we've
already talked about.
One is I would,
I would make it absolutely clear that
free speech just wins,
right?
So whenever you got into a charlie hebdo
situation or,
um,
the danish cartoons,
you know,
the riots over those cartoons,
a we've hit,
we've had half a dozen situations like
that in the last 10 years.
Um,
the people that
even our own government can't eat what
we're fighting a war on terror and we
still can't defend free speech it when,
when those situations are up.
So for instance,
this was over the,
the innocence of muslims film on,
remember that film?
It was a youtube film that kicked off.
I'm riots everywhere.
Was that true though?
Because I,
I've heard so many versions.
Okay.
Well,
I mean the main cut benghazi thing was,
it's true that it did kick off a riots
everywhere,
but the thing that was egregious about
are
government statement there was that we
basically just rather than to take the
totally same line of saying,
listen,
in our society,
we were committed to freedom of speech
and you can make films about anything
here and it that never gives you license
to kill people,
right?
Uh,
or to burn embassies full stop.
What was adam wIth the documentary?
What it was?
It was a film called the innocent,
I think the innocence of muslims or
innocence of muslims,
um,
made by some crackpot somewhere.
And it was just a youtube video,
but it got spun as this major scandal in
the muslim world and it reliably
produced this,
this reaction of the sort that the
danish cartoons had.
And um,
we rather than just hold the line for
free speech we have in the state
department said something like,
you know,
we,
we totally repudiate this,
this attack upon islam.
And I like,
we just distanced ourselves from it just
as a way of,
of trying to contain the madness,
right?
It was,
it was a symptom of just how,
how afraid we are that this sort of
thing can get out of hand in the muslim
world because it can write you if,
if there's a rumor that occur on got
burned or if some pastor in Florida
threatens to burn the koran reliably,
doesn't people by the dozens get killed
in places like Afghanistan because
they're just,
you know,
it's in a way that a suicide bombing
between sunni and shia never produces a
response of that sort.
So It's a um,
uh,
I would hold to free speech and I would,
I would just make that because free
speech is the freedom that safeguards
every other freedom.
If you can't speak freely,
you can't.
if you can't criticize powerful people
or powerfully bad ideas,
there's just no way to,
to defend society from,
from slipping,
slipping back into theocracy or any
other kind of medieval situation.
And um,
so you have to defend free speech even
for even speech you don't like,
you know,
slightly holocaust denial laws in,
in,
in western europe.
It's illegal to deny the holocaust in
Germany and a few other countries.
I think Australia,
I'm in France and it's a ludicrous law.
You should be totally free to deny the
holocaust and then everyone else should
be free to treat you like an idiot and
you should be able to.
You should be free to destroy your
reputation,
right?
The fact that we're putting people in or
that they are putting people in jail for
denying the holocaust is totally
counterproductive and it does look like
in defensive muslim apologists,
it does look like a double standard.
You're going to put people in jail for
denying the holocaust,
but you're going to alloW,
allow sharley abdo to criticize the
profit.
How does that make sense?
Right?
I totally agree with them there.
We should not.
We should not be criminalizing any form
of speech.
So it was felt stupid.
Yeah,
and they're so.
But there are people tryIng to push
through blasphemy laws as a polItician
in the uk who recently just said he
would make islamophobia a criminal
offense,
right?
He would.
I'm sure he would make the sorts of
things I say about islam criminally
actionable in the uk,
right?
That this is a disaster at the wrong
road to go down.
So first thing,
and I think that's a hugely important
thing,
and the other piece we just talked about
is just getting off of oil.
I mean,
just imagine that one change,
right?
We could get off of oil and that would
prove beyond any shadow of a doubt that
spending your life splitting hairs about
a muslim theology and demonizing the
rest of the world and exporting madrasa
you crazy madrasa by the tens of
thousands all over the world is as the
saudis do,
it would prove it.
That is not a way to join the community
of functional nations because absent
inability to pull their wealth out of
the ground,
they have no intellectual content.
They don't.
They don't produce anything of value
that anyone wants that that's a problem
they would have to solve.
Right?
If they don't want to be beggared in in
a global community.
Well isn't that an issue?
Also with the ideology of the religion
is that you're not allowed to question
or change or manipulate the way you
approach life because it's all dictated
by their religion.
Finances.
Well,
it's part of it and just when you.
When you look at societies where they
keep half the population that the female
half a more or less hostage and unable
to get educated or to work or to drive
cars are made depending on which society
you're talking about this economically
and socially,
it doesn't make any sense if you know,
in a context where you need to produce
intellectual content to be part of the
global conversation.
So the only way they've been able to do
this is because of the fact that they
have an extreme amount of mind that
comes from more manual.
Certainly if we're talking about the oil
states.
Yeah.
And so that's.
If we,
if oil were no longer valuable and we
actually could get to a time where that
would be the case where it's an oil is
just just dirty,
a dirty fluid that no one wants to have
anything to do with.
Right.
Um,
it,
uh,
that would be,
that would be a huge change.
Now I'm sure there's another side of
this argument where it would be a
destabilizing change.
I mean,
just imagine how things will start to
run off the rails and the middle east if
oil is worthless.
Right?
And what Saudi Arabia going to be like
maybe arguably,
I think they've probably hedged their,
their beds and they have so much money
in other investments now that at least
the royal family would be fine.
But,
um,
it's a,
it's a huge part of the problem and as
you pointed out,
it keeps us double dealing and,
and,
and being,
um,
a captive to the cycle of,
of defending our very real economic
interests.
I mean really like existential interests
in terms of our energy supply,
uh,
over the years and producing,
um,
a mayhem,
as a result.
But how do you get someone to abandoned
such a rigid ideology?
How do you get someone to open their
mind up to the possibility that this was
just written by people?
There's is just a way of governing
people and keeping people in line and
which is essentially every single
religion that's ever been created.
Well,
it happens.
And actually there's another point that,
that abby martin made,
which I agree with.
I just,
I,
she,
she doesn't,
we don't agree with it for the,
we don't think this thought for the same
reasons,
but she pointed out that that religions
change,
right?
That you roll back the clock.
Five hundred or so years,
christians were burning people alive and
pro,
actively proper prosecuted people for
blasphemy.
You had the inquisition in europe and
that was every bit as much of a horror
show is what's going on in Iraq now.
So look,
christianity can be just as bad as
islam.
Now it's true as a matter of history,
that is in fact true.
There are differences between islam and
christianity that are nevertheless
important,
but the crucial pieces that christianity
did not change from the inside.
You know,
christianity got hammered from the
outside by a renaissanCe and reformation
initially,
which was bloody and horrible,
but it got hammered by a,
a,
the forces of a scientific revolution
and an attendant industrial revolution
and capitalism and the rest of culture
that didn't want to be shackled to
theocracy for very good reason.
Right?
And so like,
once you have a real science of
medicine,
you don't have to ask the priest while
your child was flopping around on the
floor.
And when the priest diagnosis as demonic
possession,
you don't take it seriously,
right?
you know,
you now,
you now have a neurologist to talk to.
I mean this is,
these are,
there's progress made outside of
religion which propagates back to
religion and applies a lot of pressure
to it.
So.
So christianity has been humbled and
mastered by the secular world,
by humanism,
by science,
by the rest of our conversation with
ourselves.
And this has not happened in the muslim
world.
And it should happen.
It has to happen.
We have to figure out how to engineer it
for muslims.
And it's not,
again,
it's not going to come from the outside,
you know,
the,
non muslims,
they're not going to force it on
muslims.
But we have to support the genuine
reformers and the people who are,
who are fighting for the rights of women
and gays and free thinkers in the muslim
world.
And the hoRrible thing is that the
liberals,
the liberals on our side don't do that.
The liberalS on our side criticize
people like me and even ayaan hirsi ali,
you know,
a former muslim who,
who has a,
was being hunted by theocrats,
rIght?
They criticize her as a bigot for how,
how unsparing her criticism is of islam.
Whereas she is fighting for the rights
of women to be equal in the muslim
world.
Right?
And so there are liberal liberalism has
just,
has truly lost the plot here.
And we have to be committed to the same.
I mean,
we,
we are concerned about the rights of
women in silicon valley,
right?
I mean,
that's how it feet.
Our concerns are now like where,
why aren't,
why isn't there an equal number of women
in venture capital?
Now,
what a fucking scandal,
right?
There are people who can go on for hours
about that.
Right?
I'm not saying it's not a pathetic
potential scandal.
Great.
Let's talk about that scandal.
But let's talk about the fact that,
you know,
girls,
six years of age are getting clear,
direct dummies by barbarians in septic
conditions.
And everyone around them think is a good
and necessary thing,
right?
Um,
and you know,
women who get raped get killed because
they brought dishonor on their family.
I mean,
this is,
this is.
There's another planet over there that
we have to interact with because it's
violent.
It's coming our way for no other reason,
but there's another reason.
There's the ethical imperative of,
of figuring out how to help people who
are,
who are hostage to a bad system.
And,
and um,
so yeah,
let's be,
let's be for women's rights globally,
but what does that look like?
That looks like a rather staunch
criticism of the way women are treated
under islam.
There's a lot of seemingly openminded
european cultures that have opened the
door for a lot of islamic immigrants or
muslim immigrants to come over to their
country.
Now they're dealing with a lot of the
issues that involve these ideologies
being a part of their culture now.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean they are in a situation similar
to ours with latin America where they
just,
they need immigrant labor,
right?
They haVe a.
They're actually worse than the us in
terms of their replacement rate.
You got a bunch of countries in western
europe who are becoming these senescent
populations.
They're just not replacing themselves
and they need immigrant labor and the
real,
the most of the available labor is
coming from,
from the muslim world.
And then you also have the problem of
political refugees who are leaving war
torn places for obvious reasons and
winding up in the closest,
closest shores,
you know,
across the mediterranean.
And um,
so yeah,
it's a,
the people they're attracting are
different from,
from the many muslim immigrants we get
in the us who are coming to work for
google or to the,
they get engineering degrees are two
different demographic largely.
Okay.
I think we've covered that suBject into
the ground or so.
So let me,
I'll just mention the things on this
list and you can send me a big kiss.
And again I don't.
I hope,
I hope what I said about abby didn't
seem mean spirited.
I'm just like,
she just,
she actually is wrong about me.
And,
and if I'm wrong about her,
I'm happy to be enlightened on that
topic.
Will be interesting to her two hours.
Sit down together.
That'd be hilarious.
You.
I'll bring the tequila.
Is that what's necessary for me to bring
my own tequila?
Um,
so what did freewill.
I think this comes up again,
a ai,
which is that something you concerned
with?
Yeah,
I did.
I actually just blogged about this and
digital and spoke about it,
but I think it was in my head to talk
about because I heard you talk about it
with someone.
It might have been duncan trussell most
likely.
I've talked about it many times,
but hey,
I just got onto this.
I'm on the bandwagon here because I
hadn't really thought about it at all.
I'm not really a scifi geek.
I don't read science fiction.
And the word in neuroscience has been
for a very long time.
And really science generally is it ai
hasn't panned out.
it's not that it's inconceivable was
something interesting is going to
happen,
but it has been old style.
Ai was really a dead end and we never
really got out of that particular
culdesac and,
and we just haven't made much progress.
And so we have,
you know,
the best chess player in the world is a
computer the size of this table,
but,
um,
the prospect of having truly general
artificial intelligence,
uh,
and super human level intelligence,
that's not something we have to worry
about in the near term at all.
But then I,
um,
I heaRd a,
as many people did a,
my friend,
my friend elan musk say something which
seemed quite a hyperbolic.
He thought it wAs the greatest threat to
humanity,
probably worse than nuclear weapons.
And there was a lot of pushback against
him,
uh,
there.
and,
but,
you know,
I actually,
I know ilan and I,
I,
I knew he wouldn't say that without any
basis for it.
And it just so happened there was a
conference that had been scheduled long
before in puerto rico in san juan that
was really like a closed door conference
for the people who are really at the
cutting edge of ai research.
It was organized by the future of life
institute,
which is a,
a,
um,
a nonprofit purpose toward,
to kind of looking at,
at the existential threat and,
and looking at,
and in this case how to,
how to create a but not foreseeing the,
the,
um,
the existential problems around the
development of ai.
And it was a conference.
I mean,
maybe there were 70 people at the
conference and it was,
it was all people who are doing this
work.
And,
um,
a couple,
I mean,
I,
I literally think I was one of maybe two
people who had sort of talked his way
into the conference.
Everyone else was just invited and they
were,
they had a good reason to be there.
And um,
what was interesting is that outside
this conference,
ilan was getting into a lot of pushback.
Like,
dude,
you don't know what you're talking
about.
Go back to your rockets and your cars,
but you don't know anything about
computers apparently.
And he was getting this pushback from
serious people.
People who like are on the edge.org
website where I also occasionally
published and you know,
roboticists at mit and people who
should,
he have a former top people at
microsoft,
people who you think are very close to
this would would say,
no,
this is 50 or 100 years out and this,
this is crazy.
Um,
and so anyway,
I went to this conference just wanting
to see what was,
what was up and what was interesting and
I frankly scary was that at the
conference even among people who were
clearly drunk the kool aid and are just
not willing to pull the brakes on this
at all.
I mean they don't even,
it's arguably,
it's hard to conceive of how you would
pull the brakes on this because the,
the,
the incentive to make these
breakthroughs,
financial aid are so huge that,
you know,
if you don't do it,
someone will.
And so everyone's just,
it's just pedal to the metal.
But,
um,
basically even the people who were going
at this most aggressively were people
who were conceding that huge.
It was not at all fanciful to say that
huge breakthroughs in artificial general
intelligence could come in,
uh,
in,
in five or 10 years.
Right?
Given the nature of the progress that
had been made in the last 10 years.
And the scary thing is that when you,
when you look at the details,
it's not at all obvious to see a path
forward that doesn't just destroy us.
It's because it's not.
You think that,
yeah,
I think most people's default bias,
and it was mine frankly go into this,
was well this,
this probably kind of like y two k,
right?
Everyone is worried that,
you know,
the clocks are going to change and all
of our computers are going to seize up
and we're gonna have a real problem on
our hands,
but that clock changes and nothing
happens.
Right?
So this is just,
you've got a bunch of nerds worried
about something that just doesn't
happen.
Right?
So is that an analogy for the situation?
And I.
And it really isn't.
It's what's going on here as you're
talking about.
And even in the most benign.
Caitlin,
let me just step back because I'm
assuming that a lot of people understand
what we're talking about here.
The,
what we're talking about is,
is producing what's called strong ai or
or often called agi,
artificial general intelligence.
You're talking about a machine that is
where the intelligence is not brittle.
It's not like,
you know,
like you know that the best chess
playing computer in the world can't play
tic tac toe,
right?
So it's like,
it.
All it can do is play chess.
So it's not,
it's not a general intelligence.
You're talking about something that is
a,
that learns how to learn in such a way
that the learning transfer is to novel
situations and it's,
it's,
uh,
doesn't degrade.
If you give it a new problem,
it won't.
It won't get worse at the other problems
that it got good at it because you're
giving it new problems now.
So you're getting something that's,
that's that scales that can move into
new territories.
They can,
they can be,
they can become better at learning.
And in the,
in the ultimate case can make
improvements to itself mean once these
machines become the best designers of
the next iteration of software and
hardware.
Well then you get this sort of,
this exponential takeoff function,
or you know,
often called the singularity where you
have something where there's a runaway
effect where they were,
it's just,
you can't.
This is now that the capacities are,
are,
um,
it's gotten away from you.
And um,
so the,
you imagine what's often said is that
we're going to build something.
The near term goal is to build something
that's human level intelligence,
right?
So you're going to build that.
We have a chess computer that's not
quite as good as a person and then it is
as good as a person and now it's a
little better than a person,
but it's still not so much better is to
be completely uncanny to us.
And we're thinking of doing that for
everything.
But the truth is that as a mirage,
we're not going to build a human level
agi.
Once we build an agi,
it's going to be better at which you'd
say,
once we build a true,
truly generalizable intelligence,
something that can prove mathematical
theorems and make scientific hypotheses
and test them,
and,
um,
you know,
everything a human can do,
it's going to be so much better than a
human because of,
for a variety of reasons.
One is that your phone is already better
than you.
I mean super human in many respects.
It has a super human memory.
It has a super human capacity to
calculate,
right?
So it's a,
it's a.
And if you hook it to the internet,
it has potential access to all of human
knowledge,
right?
So we're not going to build a human
level,
agi,
we're going to build something that is
going to be not an agi,
right?
It's going to be like a dumb chess
playing computer until it isn't,
and then it's going to be super human,
right?
And when you're talking about something
that runs a potentially a million times
or more faster than a human brain.
So you're not talking about a biological
system,
now you're talking about photons.
Um,
it could make you just,
you just do the math and you see that,
you know,
this thing is running for a week that is
the equivalent of 20,000
years of intellectual progress.
So it's just like what you get the
people alive in a room for 20,000
years,
right?
With access to all of the world's
information and an ability to model,
you know,
new experiments and computational
abilities of the sort that,
that we don't can't imagine.
And twentY thousand years from now,
what are they going to come back to you
with that,
that's going to be one week of this
machine running,
right?
So this is how this thing sort of
escapes,
like what,
how do we feel that we can control the
goals and the behavior of a system that
is capable of making 20,000
years of progress in a week.
Right?
Um,
and what,
when you hear about how they're going
about designing these systems,
it is kind of uncanny.
They're talking about designing,
you know,
like black black box and the systems
were in.
The first thing you want to do is not
give it access to the internet,
right?
You're what?
Just going to cage this thing,
right?
So because you don't want to get out,
So,
but you want to attempt it.
You want to see that it.
See if it's trying to get out,
right?
So you're going to give it like a dummy
ether net port that you're monitoring,
right?
I mean this is the,
the,
the people doing this work at the
highest level are talking about games
like this where like how do you know
whether the thing is lying to you that
tried to make.
How do you,
how do you know whether it knows about
the internet,
how do you know whether it.
So this is called a honeypot strategy.
Were you tempted to make certain moves
in the direction of acquiring more power
than you wanted to give it?
And then you can just,
you know,
shut it off immediately.
But you're talking about guys,
you know,
um,
who are a lot younger than us,
who many of whom are somewhere on the
asperger's continuum who are drinking a
lot of red bull and,
and uh,
have billions of dollars at their
disposal to,
to do this work.
And um,
uh,
there's a,
there's a huge responsibility not to do
anything that obviously destroys the
world.
And the problem is even when you think
even when you think about the most
benign versions of this,
the possibility of destroying the world
is not fanciful.
So like it just forget about what I just
said about 20,000
years of progress.
Just imagine we build this.
We have an ai.
If someone,
you know,
working for facebook or whatever builds
this thing,
it's totally with solved what's called
the control problem.
We figured out how to keep this thing
doing our bidding,
right?
It doesn't,
it's not gonna design come up with near
term goals that,
that are antithetical to human
happiness.
Like because it's just a nontrivial
problem.
If you say,
okay,
just have to be committed to human
wellbeing,
right?
If that,
if that's the foundational architecture
of the system,
um,
it depends what that means in certain
cases.
I mean,
what if the,
the thing the size,
okay,
if I'm,
if I'm committed to human well being,
I'm going to kill all the unhappy
people,
right?
Or I'm just going to plug it electrodes
into the right part of the brain of
every humAn being and give them just
pure pleasure,
right?
You have to solve these problems.
Um,
but so let's say we build something,
it's totally under our control.
It works perfectly and we don't have to
worry about the control problem.
We still have to worry about the,
the political and economic effects of
building something that's going to put
the better part of humanity out of work,
right?
I mean,
you're talking about now something they
can build further iterations of itself
where the cost of building versions of
itself now is going to plummet as more
or less the cost of raw materials.
You're talking about a,
a labor saving device of a sort that no
one has ever anticipated and we don't
have a political system that can absorb
that.
We have a political system where we
would see the cover of some,
some picture of some trillionaire on
the,
on the cover of ink magazine,
and we would hear that,
that unemployment now is it 30 percent
even among white collar people?
Um,
and so we need,
we need to,
even if we were going to,
I mean it's,
it's humbling to realize that even if we
were given the perfectly labor saving
device,
it could still,
it can screw up the world.
We couldn't,
we couldn't share,
we couldn't reliaBly share that wealth
with all of humanity,
which is of course what we should do,
but we're in a system where the chinese
and the rUssians would probably
reasonably worried that we're going to
use this thing to,
as the ultimate tool of war,
right?
Both terrestrial and cyber.
So just imagine the cyber war and the
drone war.
We could unleash on the rest of the
world if we had the ultimate war making
computer,
right?
And they didn't.
So this is like a winner take all
scenario that is unsustainable
politically.
So we have to get politically,
we have to be in a position and
economically where if this thing were
handed to us,
we could use it for benign purposes and
share the wealth and where we're not
even,
we're not there yet.
And that is the best case scenario that
isn't even dealing with any of the
problems of this thing be having a will
of its own,
which of course it would.
Is it possible that it's the next stage
of life?
Yeah.
Well that's the other uncanny thing at
this conference,
you had a few people whose names escape
me.
Unfortunately I'm,
I'm actually know the rules of the
conference where I couldn't even mention
their names if they hadn't escaped me.
So I'm really,
yeah.
whoa.
A secret rules,
whether it's called the chatham house
rules at certain conferences are
organized under in board meetings,
are organized under these rules where
you.
Because you want to encourage.
So there's no press there.
Right.
And you want to encourage just free
exchange of ideas and you can talk about
what was talked about there,
but you can't give any attribution and
you can't.
I mean,
nothing's.
Nothing's formally at puerto rico.
Oh,
you got to go to another country.
Sort of.
Not really,
but sort of.
Yeah.
I don't know that that was.
I think it was just they were looking
for good.
Whether it was in the middle of the
trees.
They had plans they wanted to go to
where that giant arecibo is not the,
uh,
one of the big telescopes they use to
search for extraterrestrial intelligence
from the movie contact.
Isn't that in puerto rico?
No,
I don't know.
A cbo disc.
That's it.
So they have some of those things in the
southern hemisphere.
So then it was.
Oh,
so your question,
your question about whether the next
day,
july,
I mean,
are we at caterpillar?
So anyone giving birth to a butterfly
that we're not aware of.
Essentially one,
one of these guys gave a talk that was
all purpose toward making that ethical
case that this is that puerto rico?
Yeah.
They're talking to aliens brown.
Not even letting you know that already.
They're already planning aliens are
making these things.
They're making an alien.
That's what an alien looks that.
But that's the thing,
this thing that then gets that weird,
like when you imagine this thing getting
away from us.
Yeah,
it would be its own.
Now whether or not it would be
conscious.
I mean I,
I am actually agnostic as to whether or
not a super intelligent computer would
by definition be conscious.
It could be unconscious,
it could be that it could be nothing
that is like to be that sort of system
or,
or it could be conscious.
But in any case,
this one guy gave a talk.
One guy gave a talk where he,
where he just speculated about this
thing taking off and more or less
standing in relation to us.
The way we stand in relation to bacteria
or snails are life forms that we just
squash without a qualm and that that's a
total totally benign acceptable.
Not,
not only acceptable but to be hoped for.
Right?
Because we are anyway and I can sort of
follow.
I can follow him there at least halfway.
If you imagine that these are conscious
and actually become the center of the
greatest possible happiness in the
universe.
Right?
So like if it's,
if you imAgine we build,
if we give birth to a conscious machine
that is essentially a god,
right,
that has interests and states of
pleasure and insight and meaning that we
can't even imagine.
Right.
That is that thing by definition,
by my definition becomes more important
than us.
Right.
Then we really are like the chickens
that,
you know,
I hope we don't kill them to eat them,
but they're just chickens and we're more
important because we have a greater
greater scope to our pains and
pleasures.
And that's not to say that I don't see
any moral problem with killing chickens.
I'm just saying that we are more
important than chickens because of the
nature of human experience and it's
possibilities.
But if we build a machine that stands in
relation to us,
the way we stand in relation to chickens
or or far beyond,
right?
I mean there's the,
there's nowhere written that the
spectrum of possible intelligence and
somewhere close to where we are.
Not only that there's nowhere written
that they cannot create far better
versions and we could ever possible no,
that's.
So that's what,
that's implicit in what I'm saying.
We're imagining that this,
this take off would be this machine
create the.
Yeah,
makes recursive improvements to itself
or to,
or to new generations.
Yeah.
So it's just,
it's changing its own code.
It's learning how to build better
versions of itself and it just,
it just takes off.
And if you put the one horrible
possibility is that this is not
conscious,
right?
That there's no good that has come of
it.
This,
this is just blind,
um,
mechanism which still is godlike in its
power,
excuse me.
And,
and it could be,
could be antithetical to our survival or
it could just sort of part Ways with us,
you know,
that's the mind fuck of all mindfox is
that we really are just a caterpillar
and we're giving birth to this ultimate
fractal intelligence that's infinite in
its span.
You could create something within like,
as you said,
a week,
20,000
years of,
of human intelligence and the greatest
minds in it could do that in a week.
And then a week later,
another $100,000
more fractal keeps going on and on and
on.
It's exponential in its in its reach and
that we really will be outdated like
almost instantaneously and sorta kinda
crazy that like as you said,
a lot of these guys that are creating
these things are on the spectrum and it
was like,
what?
What is that from an is is it?
Is it,
is it possible that this,
that these super intelligent human
beings that have a lot of them do have
the sort of asperger's he way of
approaching life and a lot of them
aren't on the spectrum.
Who did naTure sort of design that in
order to make sure that we do create
these things?
I mean if everything in life,
if life itself,
everything in life,
we will look at alpha wolves and the way
caterpillar is interact with their
environment and bugs and whatever.
All that stuff's natural is human
behavior.
Human cognitive thinking is human.
Creativity is all that nature is all
that just a part of human beings.
Ultimate curiosity almost inevitably
leading to the creation of artificial
intelligence.
And was it sort of programmed into the
system to create something far better
than,
than what we are?
Well,
I wouldn't say it's programmed into the
system or necessarily.
I think you can explain all this just by
everything being pushed from behind,
by it's,
you know,
we're following our own interests.
We're trying to survive.
We have all of the,
the,
uh,
inclinations and abilities that
evolution has selected for in us.
And we have an ability to create
increasingly powerful technology and the
but the inevitability of this is hard to
escape when they're really only two
assumptions.
You,
all you have to assume is that we are
going to build better and better
computers,
which I think you have to assume a part
from the possibility that we're just
going to destroy ourselves and,
and lose the,
the ability to do so.
But if We don't destroy ourselves some
other way,
we are going to continue to make
progress in both hardware and software
design.
And the only other thing you have to
assume that there's nothing magical
about the wetware we have inside our
heads as far as information processing
is concerned.
And that it's possible to build
intelligent machines in silicon,
right?
So,
and,
and I don't,
I don't,
I can't imagine any at this point,
serious scientist fundament mentally
down in either of those two assumptions.
I mean,
there's nobody thinks that there's
something magical about being,
you know,
neural material when it comes to
intelligent processing of information
that is underlying intelligence and
we're just going to keep making
progress.
So at some point this progress is going
to birth a generation of computers that
is better able to make this sort of
progress than we are.
And then it,
then it takes off.
And so,
and so,
it's something that the benign version
of this that some people imagine,
and this is where the whole singularity
begins to sound like a religion,
but there are many people in silicon
valley imagining that we're going to
merge with these machines.
We're going to upload our,
our consciousnesses onto the internet
eventually and become immortal and just
live in sort of the dreamscape of,
of,
you know,
the paradise,
um,
and uh,
that we have engineered into our
machines.
And,
uh,
I mean that,
that vision presupposes a few other
things that are more much more far
fetched than the first two things that
I,
first,
two assumptions I just listed.
one is that before this happens,
we will have,
we will crack the neural code and truly
understand how to upload the information
in human brain into another medium and
that you could move,
you know,
consciousness,
mind and consciousness into,
into the internet,
um,
or onto some other,
uh,
you know,
he could back yourself up on,
on a hard drive and they're just
philosophical,
fundamental.
so philosophical problems about what it
would even mean to do that,
right?
I mean,
in what sense are you surviving?
If you back,
if you copy your brain,
the full contents of your brain,
uh,
successfully into a new medium,
haven't they?
Haven't,
we just doubled you and then when you
die,
aren't you just dying every bit as much
as you would be dying if we hadn't done
that,
I mean,
that's their problems,
sort of identity that had come in there
that are sort of hard to solve.
But um,
now there are people who are looking at
this as a,
it's very much like we're,
we're building the matrix in some sense
and we're going to leap into it at the
opportune moment and it's going to be
glorious.
That is such a utopian possibility.
Like that's the utopian version x mackey
now,
right?
Which comes out.
This isn't an outright now.
Yeah.
So I haven't seen it yet,
but I mean this is what we're talking
about and that's just,
that is probably the most benign version
of it in an artificial person that's
like,
you can't distinguish it between that
and a real person,
but not if you've seen the film.
Well I haven't,
but our own consciousness is.
I mean,
it's so archaic in comparison.
If you're talking about something that
can exponentially increase in one week,
20,000
years and then on and on and on from
there,
why would you want to take your
consciousness in and download it?
I mean,
it's like a chicken asking him how his
day and check out exactly like,
well,
where am I going to go in this new
world?
And turned it into einstein.
Would it really want to go back to being
an anti preferred digging in the dirt
and just dropping my eggs and cutting
leaves and what would it do?
I mean,
ultimately this is an escapable it seems
like,
I mean,
we are our thirst for ingenuity and
innovation is just never ever going to
slow down and in and our ability to do
that is never going to slow down either
unless we,
unless a supervolcano hits or haven't
they.
And the other side of this is there's so
many problems that we would want
artificial intelligence to solve for us.
I mean,
just what you think of,
you know,
curing alzheimer's or solving global
economic problems,
or how great would it be to have a
reliably benign superintelligence,
which literally would be like an oracle,
right?
um,
or,
or a god to help us solve problems that
we're not smart enough to solve and
that,
you know,
but the prospect of building that and
keeping it reliably benign or keeping
ourselves from going nuts in its
presence,
that's just a non trivial problem which
in almost instantaneously recognize that
part of the problem is us itself,
us that,
where the problem.
That's one reasonable fear.
Yeah.
And It would also immediately recognize
like,
hey,
this planet is only got like another
billion years of reliable sunlight.
Like we've gotta get the fuck out of
here and propagate the universe.
Well,
there's a great book if you really want
to get into this.
There's the book by the philosopher nick
bostrom a and he actually might've been
the one who convinced ilan this is such
a problem.
And I,
you know,
I read his,
he was one of the organizers of this
conference and virtually everyone had
read his book at the conference.
He wrote a book called
superintelligence,
which lays out the whole case.
And virtually everything that you've
heard me say on this topic is,
is some version of,
of,
of a concern that he expresses in that
book.
And um,
It's a,
it's a,
it's very interesting because he just
goes through it,
you know,
it's like 400 pages of systematically
closing the door to every utopian way,
way this could go right for us.
And he just says like,
yeah,
well know here are the things you're not
foreseen about how,
you know,
even a,
um,
let me just have to anticipate
absolutely everything.
So if,
if,
if you're trying to create a machine
that,
that is going to read,
you know,
blocks spam,
right?
You need to create a machine that will
not as a strategy for reducing spam,
just kill people.
Right?
Mean,
that's a way to reduce spam.
And,
but it's like,
that's the only way.
Yeah.
It's like common sense things that you
can't,
you can't and you can't assume common
sense in a super intelligent machine
unless you,
unless you have engineered it into the
architecture or you have,
you have taught it,
you've built it to emulate your
strategies where they,
where you would be able to build a
machine where it would not only would
not merely emulate current human values,
it would seek to,
to be ultimately you want a,
you want a,
a,
a machine that instantiates the values
that we should have.
You know that.
Not that we necessarily do at any
moment.
And what was interesting,
one thing that's interesting to me in
thinking about this is that the moment
you think about building a machine like
this,
you realize that you have to solve some
fundamental philosophical problems.
You can't pretend that that everyone,
everyone has this equivalently valuable
values,
right?
You can't because you have to decide
what to engineer into this thing.
So do you want to engineer the values of
jihadists and is submitted to the
taliban,
get a vote on what,
how we should design the values of this
thing?
Well,
I think it's Pretty,
obviously the answer to that is no.
Um,
but then you have to cut through
basically every other moral quandary we
have,
we,
because this thing is going to be acting
on the basis of a values,
but initially wouldn't it be even if
it's independent and autonomous,
it's gonna automatically realize that a
lot of our ideas are based on our own
biological needs and that the,
a lot of those are unnecessary for it or
yet,
but we will be building it.
I mean if we're,
if we're saying we're going to build it
not to be merely self interested,
we're going to be,
we're going to build it to conserve our
interests.
Whatever those deepest interests are
ultimately utopian though.
I mean because otherwise we're building,
you know,
satan and we're building,
which is what ilan must say.
Somebody in the,
in.
Yeah.
I mean we're building something that's
just going to readjust.
We're building a wrecking ball and we're
going to swing it out away from the
planet and watch it hurdle back.
So essentially the unabomber was right.
Have you ever seen people,
a few people have done this with his tax
because there are sections of his texts
that can read totally irrational and
people are people.
Occasionally we'll put a section there
and then it's not until you turn the
page and have already agreed
with it that you see who wrote it.
UM,
but,
uh,
yeah.
Well,
yeah,
it's,
it's interesting to see that were.
We are kind of headed toward some kind
of precipice here.
Do you know how he lost his mind?
Do you know the story about ted
kaczynski?
I don't know.
He was part of the harvard lsd studies.
They dose the shit out of that dude.
Yeah,
they dosed him.
He went to berkeley.
I started teaching and saved Up all his
money from teaching and went to the
woods and started blowing up people that
were involved in technology.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's a documentary called the net and
I believe it's from Germany.
I believe it was a german documentary,
but it's very secretive,
like who was and was not involved in
those harvard lsd studies.
What people on the other side of those
studies,
and I knew richard alpert who became us
but didn't kill everybody,
didn't break everybody's brain.
No,
no,
but I mean he might've had a vision that
he chased down,
you know,
add to the final point and he recognized
from his experiences like,
whoa,
if we keep going,
this is inevitable.
And became obsessed wiTh it.
Obviously you know,
you will,
you're dealing.
One of the things that people try to
connect his various drugs with
schizophrenia and mental illnesses and
most of those have not been able to
stick because there's a certain
percentage of people that will
inevitably have issues and if those are
the percentage of people that have
issues with schizophrenia or various
mental illnesses are almost mirrored by
the percentage of people who do
psychedelic drugs,
various psychoactive drugs and develop
these mental issue.
So it might not be the cause,
but it is some,
it's a concern.
And if you get a guy who may have a
propensity for mental illness and you
dose the shit out of him with lsd,
yeah.
Might get a ted kaczynski.
No,
I think there are some people who
certainly shouldn't take any drugs there
and you know,
I'd be,
I've had bad experiences on,
on a variety of psychedelics and as well
as good ones obviously,
but the bad experiences I could see in
the wrong mind affecting you permanently
in a way that it's not good for you or
anyone else you can go off the road.
I've,
I went off the rails for a couple of
weeks once,
not really off the rails.
I was totally functional.
Most people probably didn't even know
that I was off the rails,
but uh,
my,
the way I describe it is that my grip on
reality had gotten very slippery.
Like I was kinda hanging on,
like ever done chin ups with sweaty
hands.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
I'm not exactly sure how many you can
get on before your hands give out,
you know,
and that's kind of how I felt.
I didn't feel like I had a chalk on my
hands and wrists traps.
I felt like I had a slippery grip on
reality.
Thankfully within a couple of weeks it
came back to felt normal,
but especially the first days
afterwards,
she's very intense psychedelic
experience.
That was like as boundary dissolving as
you can get there maybe might be like an
argument that there's probably several
versions of of each person based on your
reactions to whatever experiences you
have,
but that might've been version two
point.
Oh,
of me.
Like after that,
like I'm a different person.
I became a different person because of
the and that could easily be what
happened to poor old ted.
It like,
yeah,
like you said,
like some of his,
his assertions,
like if you look at the direction that
technology is headed,
I mean obviously he was fucking batshit
crazy,
but he said some things that weren't
batshit crazy.
Yeah.
Well that's the thing.
So if we can make a meme,
if you could just say ted kaczynski was
right,
right.
We'll just put that in quotes.
Put.
Put that on twitter.
His boils down to today is,
is putting a photo of you with a quote
taken completely out of context and
everybody sort of shits on it or agrees
or disagrees.
It is a and fun on,
you know,
I think it's you're,
you're doing well.
if you just,
if you never knowingly do that.
I mean if you never knowingly
misrepresent your opponent,
then you can get into Just knock down,
drag out arguments about anything,
right?
and then it's all fine,
but as long as you're interacting with a
person's actual views,
then condemn those views and criticize
those views to the to to whatever
degree.
But if you're,
if part of your proJect or the entirety
of your project is simply knowingly
sliming them with a misrepresentation of
their views because you can get away
with it because you know [inaudible],
you know their,
their views are either.
So I'm hard to understand for most
people or there's people aren't going to
take the time to do it.
That
intellectually defaming people well.
It's also that there's a desire to win.
A lot of people have that.
They apply to debates and it makes them
intellectually dishonest because they
don't want to agree that someone that
they might have a disagreement with may
have a point or two,
you mean you might disagree with the
entirety of what they're saying,
but somewhere along the line you might,
it might be possible that you could see
where they're coming from even if you
don't agree,
but you,
it just,
it throws your argument into a bad
position.
So you abandoned it.
And the thing is that the merit of an
argument has no relationship to it
source.
Really.
It's like either the argument succeeds
or fails based on the,
the structure of the argument and it's
connection to evidence or it doesn't.
Right.
And it doesn't matter if it was hitler's
argument for the destruction of the jews
or,
or you know,
ted kaczynski said something true about
the progress of technology.
It's whether it's true or not about the
progress,
progress of technology.
It has nothing to do with the source,
but people imagine that you can.
If you don't like the source,
there's no burden to actually address
the arguments.
And if you don't like the arguments as
successful rejoinder is just to trash
the source,
right?
That's neither of those are true.
If you want to deal with the,
the,
if you want to get at what's true in the
world,
you have to deal with arguments on their
merits and you have to deal with
evidence and,
and it doesn't matter if the evidence is
coming from a thoroughly obnoxious
source,
it's not sufficient to say,
well,
I,
you know,
I hate the source or as shorthand,
we'll all have to pr to,
to privilege our attention and time.
So if,
if you know,
a source is disreputable at a certain
point,
you know,
you can just decide,
well,
I don't need to hear it from this person
because I know this person doesn't
understand what he's saying and his lied
in the past.
So I'll wait to hear it from somebody
else.
Um,
so yeah,
it's not that the source doesn't matter
at all,
but you're not actually addressing truth
claims if you're just disparaging the
source of those claims.
Um,
we don't have much time left.
We have less than 10 minutes.
Is there anything else you'd want to get
into?
And then we had the only other thing on
this list,
which is just too big for 10 minutes and
we're going to get in trouble,
is people,
lot of people hit us with cops,
baltimore,
selfdefence,
violence,
weapons,
all of that stuff.
Yeah.
Um,
that's a big one.
That's an hour.
That's.
Yeah,
at least.
Yeah.
And it's also,
it's also we don't need to talk about
it.
Once artificial intelligence kicks in,
we're not going to have crime anymore.
Yeah,
we've pretty much cured it all with the
final hour.
The artificial intelligence conversation
sort of trumps the whole thing because
it was islam is not going to important
when there's robots that can read your
brain.
I mean,
we're going to not need people anymore.
So you don't need religion.
You don't need lies.
Charlie updos completely irrelevant.
It will be a footnote in history.
It'll be like there were monkeys.
They through their shit.
And then there were robots that can
think for themselves and that was it.
But forget about all that other
building,
the eiffel tower and the.
And what,
what's scary about this thing is that
it's,
it's very hard to.
I mean,
so I read the book,
I went to the conference,
I've written about this,
I've spoken about this,
I hang out with people who are worried
about this and it's actually still hard
to keep this concern and view it just,
it does feel like the moment you spend
10 minutes not thinking about it,
to start thinking about it again,
makes you feel like,
um,
maybe that's just all crazy bullshit,
but what am I really going to be a super
intelligent machine that's going to take
you to swallow the world?
RigHt?
Listen to that.
The devil's greatest trick.
Yeah.
Right now with the impressionists,
the devil's greatest,
the,
it doesn't make sense.
Yeah.
But it's in.
This is on you.
Unlike other,
I mean,
other things have this character like
it's hard to really worry about climate
change because it's an abstraction.
I mean,
it's hot out there today,
but how much hotter is it than it used
to be?
And,
you know,
um,
or you know,
during the cold war we knew that we had,
we still have these icbm is pointed in
all the wrong directions,
but um,
you know,
we're living under the continuous threat
of something going wrong and,
and annihilating the better part of
humanity and it's,
he had his heart.
It's much easier to worry about other
far more easier to worry about twitter
than it is to worry about that.
But this thing is so kind of lampoon
bubble and it's,
I mean,
this is kind of a goofy notion which
seems just too strange to even be the
substance of good credible fiction.
And yet when you look at the assumptions
you need to get on the train,
there's only two and they're not.
I mean,
and,
and they're.
And they're very hard to doubt the truth
of,
again,
we just have to keep making progress.
And there's nothing magical about
biological material in terms of an
intelligent system.
And by the time it becomes a threat to
everyone,
by the time we recognize it as a threat,
ideally it will be too late.
Well,
that's.
People have different timings of the
tate where they call the takeoff,
you know,
whether it's a hard take off or
something more gradual,
but um,
yeah,
there's a,
a,
it's the kind of thing that could happen
in secret and all of a sudden things are
different in a way that no one
understands.
And you can also make this argument that
if you look at all the issues that we
have in this world,
that so many of them are almost
unfixable without this.
Yeah.
Again,
that's what I,
that's what I said is the other side.
I said,
I think in my blog post,
the only thing scarier than the
development of strong artificial
artificial intelligence is not
developing it because we need,
we need that.
We have problems for which we need to.
Intelligence is our only asset
ultimately.
You know what I mean?
It's everything.
It's given us everything good.
Right?
And why should we accept our limited
biological,
biological intelligence?
We can come up with something infinitely
more intelligent and it's a progress in
this,
in this area.
It seems almost an intrinsic good.
I mean,
jUst because we want to,
we want to be able to whatever you want,
clean the ocean,
you want to be able to solve problems
and you want to be able to anticipate
the new,
the,
the negative consequences of your doing
good things and mitigate those.
And intelligence is just,
it's the thing you used to do that puts
on their freaK.
Everybody out.
Sam Harris out blog.
You blog,
sam harris.org,
sandbox.org
and podcast.
Sam harris on twitter.
Uh,
sam harris.
Org without twitter.
Yeah.
Thanks man.
I appreciate it.
Always a good time.
Lots of fun.
Yeah.
All right.
Much love my friends.
We will be back on friday with rich roll
until then.
See soon.
Bye.
Exactly.
Never met him,
but.