We're here in the podcast on day one of
the robots attacking the people.
It started in Tempe,
Arizona.
Someone's killed by a self driving uber.
I'm not buying those things.
Put the self driving ubers.
I'm not ready for this yet.
No chance.
It's not ready to die.
I'm not ready for planes.
They should have those things on a
closed course over a long period of
time,
you know,
and then let them drive around cities.
Yeah,
we got to build some trust.
I'm not,
I'm not trusting.
We got to have some obstacle courses.
Self-Driving.
Uber Kills Arizona pedestrian as all as
cops.
This is hilarious.
Is that an uber car?
A cop car?
Uber's.
They look like cop cars.
What's the thing on the roof?
Uh,
the camera.
It lets it drive fencers,
dude.
Fuck all that.
Not to say that a guy couldn't have done
that.
And not to say that this person,
whoever it was,
who knows what the circumstances were.
Sometimes accidents are unavoidable,
right?
I mean there are certain times where
someone makes an error.
We don't know,
but I just feel better if it's a person
making an error for some strange reason
came here.
I think uber and lyft would have like a
gang war.
They probably would.
Yeah.
If you let the algorithms take over,
it's over.
They probably fuck with each other.
Don't they like the Uber Guys?
Super aggressive as they get.
Didn't get in trouble for doing the uh,
like fake.
Oh,
that's causing problems.
Finding a real.
Is that real?
Is that a real story?
Networks.
But it was like allegations I think
because they were private getting sued,
sued each other,
whatever.
So I don't know if it ever came out and
[inaudible] yeah,
no,
there was allegations that they were
like making fake calls.
Right?
Is that what it was?
Fake requests just bailing last minute
to do you got the right idea.
Living up in the middle of the nowhere.
You got the right idea with that.
We uh,
we just got to uber but it's only two
dudes and I have both their numbers.
Say just call me.
I can just cry.
Yeah,
that's actually cool.
People are in your town a little like
2,400
slugs,
you know how to drink.
That's a fucking good place to live.
The currencies beer,
but that's the thing that was.
Everyone can do everything but no one
wants to work.
It's pretty hilarious.
Look at this.
Uber's dirty tricks.
Quantified rival counts.
Five thousand 560 canceled rides.
That's in 2014.
Is that real?
And that's right when it started.
Is that definitely.
It's on CNN so it can't be fake news.
I've never canceled an uber.
I feel really bad about it.
About never canceling.
Well No.
I mean if I canceled I'd be like,
I'd want to like tell the guy.
Yeah,
I'd be like,
hey man,
just should be a way.
If you have to cancel it to give the guy
a tip,
that's a good move.
You know,
like say I have like super last minute
cancel.
This guy's already wanted us way over
here.
Let me throw them 30 bucks.
Or are we used to five star at least
something.
Something given some money.
Give him five bucks,
five bucks per canceled ride.
That's not bad.
Right?
That's more than fair.
You're setting them back a few minutes.
You don't get anything back when they
fuck with you though.
So know you son of a bitch,
but who are people that are fucking with
you?
Is it the rare uber driver?
Every Uber I've ever been to was a
dream.
I've never had a single problem.
Have you had uber x ever though?
That's the truck.
Well,
that's just like random people with
cars.
Oh,
right,
right.
No,
I always do the one with like.
It's basically limo drivers that are
like off duty.
Yeah,
those are awesome.
If you ever uber acts,
it can get a little dicey.
Oh,
you're just with a random chick that's
having a meltdown.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I can imagine.
I mean,
she's cool.
It's not like it's a big thing,
but it's just like,
you know,
I can't pay my dsl bill this month and
you're like,
lady,
I'm right here.
It's a very small car.
This people that just.
They're working their life out,
but let's say if they're unlike a
hundred level game,
they're on level one and they're
bouncing into the walls over and over
again and they just don't seem like in
order for you to give them real advice,
you'd have to basically move into their
house.
You'd have to like give a full revamp of
the way they look at things.
You'd have to go.
Okay,
stop.
Okay.
First of all,
what are all these pills?
Second of all,
what are you eating third of all?
Like why are you talking to people like
that?
Like if you talk to people like that,
they're not gonna want to talk to you,
like you're upset that they don't like
you,
but then you act in a way that's very
unpleasant to be around.
Right.
And then you'd have to go through every
mistake this person's been.
Then you'd have to find out.
It's almost all shitty parenting.
It's like plumbing.
Yeah.
Back Down to the root system.
The roots got into the pipes or you
know,
I'll look at crack because of the earth
shifted and you're losing all this water
down here.
Yeah.
You just start screaming when you feel
threatened at all.
Like that may be a thing from your
childhood.
Yeah,
there's a lot of that out there.
There is.
Um,
I wanted to talk to you about social
media.
Okay.
Because I,
I love you too.
I think you're very good guy.
I really do.
But you are the worst representative of
yourself on social media.
I'm a lawyer myself.
It's a bad form of getting out tricky
ideas.
It's a bad form.
It's just not good.
I mean now it's,
what is it to 80 now?
Two hundred 80 characters is better than
it was 1:40
was very rough,
like 1:40.
You'd have to,
you know,
you have to really think about what
you're saying.
So you're yelling like as you're falling
into a well you have like one sentence
but you,
you are without a doubt addicted.
And I know you bailed on your phone for
awhile and you went to a flip flip on.
Yeah.
But I see these manic tweets from you
and I,
I just want to go hang out with you and
go,
dude,
what are you doing?
Why are you constantly tweeting and
attacking people and it's like sometimes
the chaos helps me.
I mean,
you're right,
right?
I'm not challenging.
That's David,
but like I see it as almost like a idea
sonar where you're just like,
I,
I get that.
I get that,
but I get that because I know you did a
really good dude and real life.
Thanks man.
So when I see this online and I see
these blurting out post just outbreak
posts,
they're just,
they're just like,
like you got diarrhea.
I mean just let me see if I could throw
the word nigger in here for a goof.
Let me see if I can say something that's
going to piss people off.
And it's just,
there's this weird thing you're doing
like this Jessalyn next thing.
Like you just decided to attack Anthony.
Jessalyn,
I'll tell you.
Did he attack?
You know what happened was someone said
that a data hurt I,
he said I was outright,
which is like the new people can believe
that they could believe that you were
outright,
but if someone tells them it's appear
outrageous tweets,
there's one or two of them,
they'd go,
oh,
this guy's an outright comedian,
and then they see you with certain
people that you've had podcast with and
talk to.
That might also be lumped in immune
ridiculously.
So like Jordan Peterson,
they lump him into.
No,
I gotcha.
It doesn't make any sense,
but they do it like I'm in luck.
I've had people on that people think are
all right.
I mean people.
People are fucking crazy.
I mean there's people out there think
Ben Shapiro is antisemetic.
That's how.
That's how I know there's no,
there's no logic at all.
Like right now,
Martin Luther King Jr would be
considered outright by certain crazy
people.
He would probably have adjusted his
views.
Don't you think?
I mean his views,
it probably changed knowing all that we
know about people today and I mean he
would be a different person.
You've got to think that guy growing up
in the 19 fifties and then beans into
the sixties as a,
the most important civil rights activist
of all time.
He was dealing with a completely
different world.
Man.
There was no social media,
there was,
there was not much consolidated power is
probably very difficult to get people to
March once they start sicking dogs on
people and blowing fire hoses on them.
I mean,
you had to be,
you had less protection and he'd had to
be more,
more rigid and conservative than just
because people would have to be just
very careful if that's,
you know,
we,
we talked about this recently,
I guess it was,
was it Danielle Lee Bailey we were
talking about about how recently slavery
was.
Was it him?
Was it Danielle might.
Might've been either way.
Um,
it's,
that's a crazy small amount of time.
Crazy 200 years ago and it's been
existed for like tens of thousands of
years and that there's more slavery in
the world today because there's more
people alive.
It's kind of tricky.
But this last percentage of people that
are slaves,
so it's kind of misleading when people
say it's more sleek slavery,
there's way more people.
That's a good point.
Yeah.
There's more everything way,
way,
way more people and there's way more
crazy people and now they all have
Internet access.
Yeah.
Because I was looking at this thing
where they were trying to trace.
You've heard about that new species of
human that they found,
I think around somewhere in the range of
a seven or eight years ago.
Dyno scions,
I think they call them.
They found them in Russia.
And what they are is,
um,
you know,
when there was neanderthal and Homo
Sapiens,
there was another one and then this
other one bread.
There's apparently they think there was
many different kinds of humans.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
But what the faith thing.
That fucking freaked me out,
they were talking about how long ago,
this was like 70,000
plus years ago that they were,
they were talking about one era and then
they were talking about the amount of
people that were alive then.
And they said something around the area
of 100,000
humans total amount that's on the four
or five right now.
Just fuck that on the four.
Oh,
five between here and West Hills.
Probably more.
And that's why we have such a vicious
instinct because at that point it's
just,
I think it got down to like 10,000
people at one point.
Yeah,
that's what I was reading the article
about.
It was also talking about um,
in Sumatra.
And we talked about this recently.
There was a gigantic super volcano that
blew up and it fucked the earth up for
like a thousand years.
And we had to survive that.
Yeah.
And now we're trying to survive twitter
storms and,
but we have those same instincts,
the same instincts that are like,
if you can't eat your dog right now,
you're going to die with the Jesuit
thing.
So what?
So I just went on his and he had already
blocked me and I had never written
anything to him.
So I just.
So I just posted that instead he got,
he has a liposuction is asked because I
thought that was funny because I didn't
want to go too big.
I was like,
well why even do that?
Like who gives a shit if he blocks you.
I just thought it was funny.
Right?
But you're attacking them publicly.
This is the thing.
It's like you have like how many
thousands of twitter followers.
Yeah,
like 120,000.
That's a lot of fucking people.
So a lot.
But he's a strong man that have messed
with me way too long,
man.
Like that's got to sting.
There's got to be like this disturbance
of peace and tranquility for no reason.
Just because he blocked.
You give a shit if people.
I hope you gentlemen,
I like you.
Go block me buddy.
I love a good guy.
He's a great joke,
right?
It's a funny guy,
man.
This is the problem is said like I'm a
colleague of his,
um,
at the comedy store with him all the
time.
We go on back and forth next to each
other all the time and you know,
just like you should attack someone when
they do something really bad,
but you know what I'm saying?
I do know what you're saying,
like the sheets stored until you
absolutely need it.
Yeah.
I'm all about that and I.
I wasn't like full attack mode.
I was being playful.
The wars started.
You're talking about him getting
liposuction and talking about him being
gay and you're talking about a.
You said a bunch of different things,
but that's after he said in response.
He said that I'm an outright the third
rate piano comic and I was like,
dude,
I just did a,
a liposuction joke,
but the thing is I'm not even mad at the
guy at all like I want.
Then again,
do a terrible job of representing
yourself.
That's a good point because it seems to
me even I had a text you.
I'm like,
what are you doing?
I know.
By the way,
I just want to give you a compliment.
I love it.
You're more critical offline.
Like you're one of the few people right
now in this world.
It's like,
oh,
what the fuck are you doing?
I love it,
but online you're chill and so many
people are the opposite.
They attack on line and apologize in the
DM and you're.
I just want to say that that's good
leadership qualities.
Oh,
well that's very nice for you,
but I'm not trying to be a leader.
I just try to be a good person.
I think if you you have an issue with
someone you should do.
You should talk to them in person if you
can,
if not on the phone,
but that one on one,
like this idea that you should
automatically blurt out what you think
about someone's public mistakes to the
rest of the world to state your
position.
Like there was a lot of the requests to
state your position after Louis C K got
in trouble.
I have no idea what actually happened.
If,
if the way that women are telling it is
100 percent true than I am,
I think it's fucking gross and
disgusting and I'm sad.
I'm sad that he had that in his head
that he wanted to do that.
I'm sad that the girls had to experience
it.
It's an uncomfortable thing,
but I don't know that and I've heard
stories about people thinking it was
funny too,
you know,
there's.
There was like this weird thing going
on,
the tribal stuff where it's like,
what side,
what side are you on?
But people were like this,
the Louis C,
k instance was the first instance so
that I can recall where people were
demanding a response,
like a public response about something.
Well,
I noticed that in entertainment with
trump,
it's like the lack of talking about
trump is now seen as endorsements.
Like when Taylor swift just didn't get
involved in the chaos.
People were calling her like,
all right man,
it's,
there's so many people just waiting,
waiting to pull the trigger and they're
doing so in such a fucking insane and
ridiculously misrepresentative way.
There was something about Jordan
Peterson,
Jordan Peterson,
I'm going to speak somewhere,
and there was these people sending
emails that he was a Nazi and Oh yeah,
schist and a racist and trans phobic and
just.
But they're just hurling.
These nuclear bombs have words with
literal.
Literally.
No.
We're no thought whatsoever about the
consequences of using these words to
describe someone who's absolutely
clearly not that of course it's when
someone can't argue another side,
they just.
That's how they shut down the
conversation,
but here's my point,
is that it elevates this manic
misrepresentation of reality because
they've agreed to not look at it
realistically.
They've agreed.
Who cares if he's not a Nazi,
we're going to fucking calm Nazi,
and in doing that you,
you,
you're,
you're escalating.
What's like,
if there's a mob mentality,
right?
It's part of what's going on.
One of the things didn't happen to mom
mentality,
so people start murdering.
People jump in.
If people killing people and you're
trying to get away the guys running at
you with a knife,
you're going to fucking kill it.
That's what people do.
It's a normal thing.
It happens with my mentality to,
to happens this with this,
these kinds of arguments,
the same kind of thing.
People could just decide they don't care
if you're right,
they're going to call you a fucking
racist.
They're going to call you a Nazi.
They could just gonna keep saying it
until you believe it.
One hundred percent.
Like this fucking Nazi Kurt Metzger.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Good to see you,
pal.
Thanks for coming,
man.
Pull up.
Get them in there.
You got him on camera then.
Good.
Good to see you buddy somewhere.
Oh,
well this room is separately heated.
This is its own little,
uh,
air conditioning and thermostat system.
Like the sauna looking good.
Yeah.
This part was built.
This was not a room.
So this room was created like a radio
studio.
Like same deal with thick walls.
All insulated and on a nice sense
of the world bunker.
Yeah Buddy.
It's all concrete.
Cement Shit.
And there's a fan that sucks pot smoke
out.
So if people are getting high,
he just.
Oh wait.
Huh?
What's the matter?
What about it?
Oh Shit.
Scenic drive.
Well today it is man.
La,
when it rains out,
it's like nothing else.
Beautiful.
Gets so green and drive over by.
Um,
uh,
when you're going over the four or five
when you come in over the top of the
hill.
Holy Shit.
It's stunning doing this area sick.
Like I,
I can't stand west Hollywood area now.
There's too many people,
too many people,
too many people to it.
I really would like to do what you're
doing.
What you're doing,
I think is ideal.
Where are you doing?
Oh,
and did you return to the land of
giants?
To.
With my wild length where we just yell
at each other and it's all good.
Did you return to lilliput?
Put as the god of those little people.
I brought home new information and gold
and silk.
Are you.
Where are you living again?
You told me in the adirondack mountains
in northern New York.
Oh,
I get a.
or just thinking about that.
Wow.
I love the idea of it sounds amazing
except for where you are.
It's got a lot of ticks that have a line
when it gets too cold in the winter to
really have that.
But it just started coming a little bit
because it's like negative 40 where I
live in the winter,
so he's Christ.
So now my 44 real negative 40 for like a
while.
That's why I got the sauna because I
just fire up and then go outside Newton
and roll around and it's just crazy.
Negative 40.
Yeah.
I don't think I've felt that before.
It's so remarkable where it's just you
go outside and you think,
if I didn't have clothing,
I have 10 minutes to live it.
It's just this wild feeling.
Well you know,
I do that cryotherapy,
which is a lot colder,
but it seems fake.
Like a million dollars was dancing a
million.
A guy on youtube,
that Italian guy who that guy is,
he puts you to videos of him dancing.
Fifty year old guy at dances on boats.
John Luca vaccine.
He's friends with Zac Efron.
Oh,
you signs with everybody?
That guy's hilarious.
He's a DJ.
He does everything.
He's an heir to have vitamin fortune or
something.
Is that what he is?
Or his grandfather didn't.
A company.
Gary Centrum grandfather.
That's so funny,
dude.
Lucas Centrum.
Centrum fortune,
that guy is living a fun life,
you know,
he's like an Italian version of Dan
Bilzerian and a lot of ways.
Yeah,
right.
That's like a thing like that old buff
rich guy,
but he's like in his thirties,
like this.
Yeah.
This guy's only his thirties with a art
attack and shit.
He did,
but it was from doing a lot of coke and
doing.
He did a lot of shit.
He told the story.
It was up for like two days,
like dancing thousand dollars.
Guy John Zika vaccine.
Hilarious.
This guy's awesome.
Doing weird stuff with his pants that
are very feminine.
Like you know,
like Lou,
those shorts when he's Italian,
if a dude.
Yeah.
But be honest.
If a dude that was wearing shorts like
that came up to you start talking to in
a men's room,
you'd go,
hey buddy,
let me get past you and get through that
door.
Oh,
we're going to have a problem now.
Those shorts shorts are more obvious,
like,
I don't want to be too judgmental,
but that's more than like an erection in
Asana is the tattoos.
I got tattoos everywhere,
everywhere.
It's his whole body and he just had
another one.
He had himself on his back.
He's got a new one called the shut the
fuck up tattoo.
It's him going like shush on his back.
I guess if I were to guess,
if I wanted to decipher that people are
talking shit behind his back this way.
He's always facing them.
Go and Shush.
It's pretty hilarious.
I like when people get tattoos to,
you know,
like it's a power like eyes on the back
of your head in prison.
Look at this.
All that writing.
That's it.
Look at all that writing.
It looks like he's got a little tiny
writing all over his body.
He's a weird guy.
It doesn't look like the stop talking
behind my back show.
She looks like I just fucked your mom.
Don't tell anybody.
It's also,
it tells also kind of passive aggressive
debt font that small because logo.
Who's going to take the time to read his
back?
Yeah.
You got to be real close that are
fucking him.
Such a great body.
Got To stop from coming.
So I read.
He does have his back.
He does a lot of body weight.
Exercise freezes himself.
That's why I brought it up because I saw
him on a video.
Freezing himself was the time you want
to do it after the show,
what does it do?
It jacks up your nor epinephrin
Epinephrin norepinephrine levels.
It produces something called cold shock
proteins that are a radical inflammation
fighters.
It's fantastic for people that have like
arthritis aches and pains.
There's a lot of older folk that go to
the place that I go to that go all the
time and they said it's just changed
their life.
Like people with hip issues.
Yeah,
because your body goes into this thing
and if you do doubles,
I like to do a double means.
I go in for three minutes,
I warm up for about 10 minutes and I go
in for another three minutes.
How much is it to do it?
A lot.
It's a good question.
Find out.
I Dunno.
It's not cheap.
Yeah,
because I only saw this fucking Julian.
Yeah.
Whenever you can go to his place.
It's going to my mountain,
man.
It's the whole thing all the time.
What it is is your body has to feel like
it's going to die and when your body
feels like it's going to die,
it freaks out and produces these anti
inflammation properties.
It's basically like twitter.
The same thing with the sauna.
You know Barry Criminal Law.
He wanted me and him went on tour.
Do that last year.
Yeah.
That guy saved my life man.
I was like in a bad way when that guy
called me.
But uh,
anyway,
we got in a car,
this guy driving on black ice and
Pennsylvania where he tries to pass,
say a tractor trailer,
you know,
some people don't want to be behind
trailer so he goes to pass it and we're
like 60,
which is the,
it's under the speed limit but it's
black ice,
you know,
so we're going next.
It felt like a jet engine sucking that.
It was just wobbling.
And so I'm in the passenger seat.
Barry was behind the driver
and we just get sucked into under the
trailer and the trailer.
Yeah.
So my head,
I mean I already got my head cut off and
I had time to say what the fuck three
times I didn't know what the fuck,
what the fuck,
and then I was like,
oh,
I got some dead.
I just remember thinking that swerved
and then the back end,
like my it started going away from the
trailer and the back end got caught
instead where no one was sitting that
got pulled in,
the windows blew in and then a drug us a
little bit and spit us out.
And we spun in Atlanta in the median.
That's insane.
It was.
And uh,
the driver was weeping.
Oh my God,
me and barry were like,
I swear to God,
like high,
like I have never felt I could do that
once a year,
like a vacation to me,
I swear to God,
I like it,
but I had to be.
I was like,
sure.
I guess my brain thing,
I'm going to die,
but I'm sure my body thought it was too.
But it felt fucking amazing.
Dude.
I never felt anything like that.
Like the be a trigger to die and they
just don't know what happens to vet.
Sometimes when they come back they don't
want to admit it.
But they got addicted to war.
Yeah,
right.
Her locker,
they can hurt law.
Just thinking of that.
Oh,
that's 100 percent legit.
They also.
There's a good Sebastian younger book
about that.
I read that based on your pod tribe.
Yeah,
and these people,
that's like the closest.
They have a field in each others when
they're in the middle of a war zone.
It's like me on twitter.
Man was weird talking about his twitter
outbursts and poor representation of who
he is as a person.
Wait,
so I don't understand.
What did you settle the matter at the
guy.
What do we say?
Nothing.
He just blocked him.
He blocked him on twitter,
so he decided to not sure he blocked.
You definitely blocked him.
So I just said something that he had
wife on his ass.
I didn't think that.
That's a good question.
I mean,
I'm not.
Whatever.
I'm not worth it.
He was never a fat guy.
Now that's what it is.
Crazy.
If it was like,
because he's really handsome man,
so it's like that is so funny to me to
light weight.
So he did do that.
No,
no,
no.
We just made.
Oh yeah.
Because it seems like a very extreme.
It's just a funny insult.
How many comics,
if you had a guest.
I've had life on their ass over.
I would.
If I had like a friend that was like,
hey dude,
I.
I do like,
like you would want to do some friend.
You have to wear like this crazy
compression close afterwards to really
do it.
It's not a joke.
Then I probably want to do is fucking
surgery.
Yeah,
right.
They're,
they're,
they're good numbing your shit up and
they're going in with a god damn pipe
that's got a vacuum attached to it and
they're roughing you up and sucking
chunks.
Violent.
It looks fucking mad at how fat you are.
Probably doesn't work because you don't
change your habits.
Either tape works,
but listen,
you're going to get fat again,
like it'll make you look good for a
little bit,
but if you don't change how you eat your
you,
your,
your static state right now where you're
at,
you're getting fatter.
Most people,
most people,
if they're overweight,
they're getting more overweight.
They're not steady at at,
you know,
whatever the fuck it is,
50 pounds over.
They keep keep going
because it's the same pattern of
behavior,
so if you get yourself sucked down
there,
I know people have done this,
get yourself sucked down with the vacuum
down to a good legitimate size.
They just balloon back up and a lot of
times there's a lot of unevenness why
people get fat and weird places because
they took out,
get a little out right around the
winter.
I feel like I got a quarter inch in
there that isn't being abused.
Fat.
It's also,
I think they're saying based fat out
your blood can get lumpy.
Fucking wouldn't be smooth.
Yeah,
like at least if you've got a natural
layer of fat,
it's like a smooth.
It feels right,
but I suppose it doesn't work.
I've seen people like,
no,
you understand I can't develop pectoral
muscles.
I had showed her nonsense.
It's nonsense because like I can't do
it.
Well,
no,
that's not true.
There's all these talk shows.
These guys are packing plants.
Yeah,
know dude,
who have one of those I know do two
implants and how did it end up for her?
Not so good,
man.
Yeah.
That's so good.
That sounds real bad.
And he wound up killing himself because
of something else.
I.
Here it is life.
Jesus Christ in the holy fuck.
Yeah.
I'd be scared.
What's under the fat?
My ass.
I got.
I don't know what's under there.
This step limits cut.
There might be a look at this,
this weird shape.
It's blood loss and maximizes post op
comfort and what they're doing is going
in on this person's stomach and just
sucking tubes of it out.
Here's the thing.
This guy's not even that fast.
No,
that's a little bit all this guy or Gal,
I don't know.
We're only looking at a building site
and Joseph was already hot.
He just was getting a little bit.
She's like handsome guy.
That's like so irreverent.
I think that's really funny how it
works.
Look at the little fucking edges on the
thing.
Oh,
that's.
This is disgusting.
This thing.
Look how like you see,
like when he was going back it up a
little jamie.
Those little things,
those holes that like little knives,
man,
like a little bit.
This is violent.
There's a good few little knives in the
end.
It's took a cat's Dick,
so he's just scooping it out of there.
Is this a woman or a man?
I don't know if someone is not that fat.
If whoever the fuck this is,
if they just got on the carb free diet
for like a couple of weeks,
it's not even like a thought.
That long of weight to lose.
I know a lady who didn't need it and got
it done.
She literally didn't need it.
I don't know.
I don't know her that well,
but I remember her friends saying how
much extreme discomfort she was in
because she had to wear essentially
elect this,
these tights.
Super tight compression pants everywhere
to keep all your ass fat together is an
amazing deal.
So debt.
What I was having my ass fat loosened a
little.
I had a hair transplant.
That was the dumbest thing I've ever
done.
One of the Feldman,
that's what he did.
I was giant scar in the back of my head.
It looks like a smile.
I wonder if that's a piece of meat.
My job.
You get like a scar from it.
Yeah.
My joke was that it's like taking people
from a town where everybody is healthy
and moving them into a town where
everybody's dying.
Feeling ones that were left elected,
new recruits the hair that was supposed
to be up there.
So where do you get it from?
Like other parts of it from the back of
your head.
They take a strip off of that now the
way they do it and a lot of places they
do it differently.
Do one individual follicle at a time.
I just was scared that it was going
bald.
I was like,
what can you do?
And they tell you they could fix it.
They're like,
oh great.
I'll just get it fixed.
But it doesn't really fix it now.
Well how come?
Because Joel Mchale from suit,
because I remember him from those Burger
King commercials where you had less hair
than I do and it all.
Now he's got Dragon Ball Z.
Wow.
It's real thick.
It's almost like more thick.
Then they start with some killer
transplant or is that just a great head
of hair man?
You remember the Burger King Commercial,
right?
I do.
Not.
Nobody does.
It was when the office was getting
popular,
not to put the American one and Burger
King at these commercials that were
Kinda like the office and he was like
the wider picture.
One Burger have thicker hair,
works better.
Every bald guys.
Fucking hair.
More hair.
I remember people with a thick hair
follicles can get away with it.
Like my hair would have looked way
better,
but I have thin hair.
The hair's themselves are thin.
So if someone has thick hair,
they could prove they could have some
pretty dramatic result of it's the right
kind of thinning.
Dirty?
No,
not even 30.
Yeah,
but what did you tell him to 31?
I think I was 28.
I just started acting on TV and I was
panicking because my hair was like,
seriously fallen out and I was like,
this shit,
it's going quick,
and I was like,
well where's it going to go and get
thicker pubes?
I knew that part of the reason why I was
making money was the way I looked.
I mean I,
I was doing stand up and I was acting in
these shows,
but I wasn't an ugly dude and it helped,
you know,
like it was getting certain kinds of
roles like boyfriend roles.
That's chicken has to go through it.
Yeah,
you can be panic because you're like,
well this is how I'm making money and I
never made any money before.
So all of a sudden I went from being
completely broke and being a super
struggling comic.
Like if I got lucky,
I was making 300 a week.
Three 50 a week was a big.
Was that bad?
That bad for a week.
Perfect.
If you're a 25 year old guy,
which is what I was trying to make it as
a comic,
then it went from that to making fucking
shit piles of money and you're like,
how do I not move back?
I'm not getting rid of this.
Figuring out a way to keep this rolling,
but if I should've just shaved my head.
I just didn't know.
Freedom.
Now even if I grew like a thick head of
hair,
I guarantee you it's still shaved my
head.
I don't want to go to a barber.
I had a really nice lady used to cut my
hair too.
I loved her.
She's fun,
fun conversations,
but I'd have to go to we're fucking
place and she'd have to come and wake up
every four day like a wine.
Where's your mommy?
Could you talk about that?
That chilling pursuit,
but I was on Samba Gb smoothies at this
dinner show where it'd be like a couple
of athletes and like a couple of comics.
Oh yeah,
and I don't because I don't really
follow sports,
but these guys were originally as a
hockey player
in some football players in which
minority and they're talking about all
these treatments they would get,
you know,
and most of them started out as beauty
treatments for,
for rich fuck in Hollywood women real.
And then they trickle down to athletes.
That's,
I swear to God they were talking about
Cryo that way,
like it was for fucking hot checks
because they are kind of like a hot
checks and kind of athlete.
You go like,
Oh yeah,
when Kathleen Turner,
like Blue Bluer face out from that shit
on steroids for arthritis.
No Way.
She didn't want to be.
You want people to know about some
illness which start to get less work.
So she just took all the jokes about how
she looked like a man.
She just took all the jokes to work and
then find the chemo.
We took kind like,
hey,
good for you man.
If he got work at it because you're not.
People are terrified a for sick.
Yeah.
I mean being going from being an
insanely hot woman.
I know rose,
that is a change of everything.
That's a change of character.
It's a character building,
sky,
losing all his money.
You find out who really liked you the
whole time,
you know?
Yeah.
Just how you interface with the world.
Like a beautiful woman.
Interfaces with the world.
Like the most popular celebrity
possible.
Beautiful woman is like Tom Cruise
everywhere she goes.
It's like Michael Cost as a bit about
the same amount of data.
It's almost the same amount of danger
too.
Have you got to watch who's coming up on
you?
Like how famous person with worse though
for girls.
Listen,
men are dangerous and that's why we have
a system called the patriarchy took
women cost been a great system to
protect women from the ages of men
called Patriarchy and we threw it.
We throw it away because the colleges.
I think it's important to talk about
Patriarchy because I feel that young 20
year old women need their own Illuminati
to talk about,
you know,
their failures on it's.
Yeah.
It's like it's Illuminati for girls
conspiracy,
patriarchy to ask for the set
definition.
There isn't one is that suspicious?
Same with racist.
There is one in the dictionary,
but that's not the accepted one.
Ask just any online feminist.
What does it mean?
There's no.
Well you can be whatever you want to be
like.
It's,
it's,
it means you're my ex boyfriend named
Gary Click of mean girls is that
patriarchy are in a position of power.
That's the patriarchy.
But men have been in the workplace for
hundreds of years more than women is
that there's a real problem.
Well,
it should be caught up.
But what about when you hear this shit
where somebody goes and people wonder
where all the female comedians like?
No.
Uh,
two people talking about it.
When Louie got shellacked by that fucked
up article,
people were saying that shit about you.
How come there's not an equal number of
female comedians to males?
Well,
because women are treated better in our
society.
Yeah.
If there's damage amount of female
Comedians,
you know,
women are being abused way more than
ever because you don't get in this job
from a happy.
This job isn't about support.
It's you get last because you fucked up.
So I hope there's not a lot of women in
it that would mean they're being raped
more does that,
but it is
also,
it's just from a female perspective of a
chick's funny.
It's harder because something happened
to her.
They can't,
but they can't talk about certain things
like,
no,
no man wants to see a woman on stage
telling politic stories or politic
jokes.
It's funny you say that,
but it did create a daily show.
Maybe you,
maybe you,
but most people in the audience for the
woman started out.
I won't rule out anything if I'll take.
I won't say any premise has hacky,
just punch line.
So if your premise is airline fucking
peanuts,
that's fine.
Tell me what your punchline is.
Maybe a punchline justifies it.
I don't,
I won't rule out any premise on the
premises or hacky,
but people probably don't want to hear
it.
But who,
you know,
it's like,
look,
if you can get people to listen to some
shit that they basically don't want to
hear.
Like,
oh great,
this is where I used to do the black
rooms I started.
So I totally agree with you.
I'm totally in agreement with you.
We're not talking about drinking caveman
coffee.
We're not talking.
I feel wired is wicked from 270
milligrams.
How many did you have?
Like.
Well,
I just started skipping one,
but I'm like,
I'm the one that's empty.
Did you black out and suck though?
Ingestion?
I just drank one.
What the fuck is this dude talking about
me?
I'm talking about most people.
When a woman goes on stage and does
stand up,
most people that are going to be in the
audience,
there's men that are just not going to
want to hear you talk about politics.
There's men that are not going to want
to talk about sex.
It's harder for a woman.
I think it's a hard.
It's a harder position.
Being a standup comic for a woman is
just harder.
So I think if it's harder,
you're naturally going to see less
people doing it and then there's
naturally less people inclined to do it,
but it's just like female mma,
like most women are not going to do it.
But guess what?
A lot of women do it.
If you're the type that does it,
you fucking do it,
but there's no fucking weird.
What about the Patriarchy in an mma?
Why Arthur equal number of women than
men?
You don't say that,
right?
They're not really fans of.
I noticed that.
Remember who the think?
That's it.
I think it's because it's an untenable
argument.
What you can't say.
This should be an equal amount of women
fighting as men because it's not getting
punched in the face area.
That's one area where we agree.
It's one area we get to a goal.
Yeah,
well men are.
They do this better.
This is.
They do it more.
They're doing it constantly and there's
some elite female athletes in mma.
Don't get me wrong,
of course rivaled the elite athletes of
men,
but they used to summit and they had the
operation when more men fucking way
more.
I mean it's not even seen with
basketball.
I was watching sport,
I hope.
Right,
but my point is the same as standup
stand is another getting punched in the
face sport.
To me that's super fucking difficult.
You take an emotional beat.
Some people don't want to do it.
It's not a judgment call.
It's not like you're better or you're
worse picks you because the people that
left that I started,
I don't know if you think of when you
started,
people thought that were funny,
that left and people that stage,
I can't believe you're still here.
It's clearly a calling at Nada.
Yeah,
you got to take a beat it.
Some people just decide to.
They've had enough.
They like,
they don't want to get off this fucking
ride.
You know?
There's a lot of guys that were like big
time touring headliners and they get to
a point though the fuck this.
We usually go to vegas or something,
right?
Yeah.
They do that.
Or they just fucking get some sort of a
writing job sometimes get writing jobs,
you know,
they started doing tree work like me,
middle of nowhere.
Just start cutting down trees.
You know,
I was,
I liked the writer's guild,
but listen,
man,
anybody who thinks that should be an
equal number of men or women in any job
and that if there's no clear evidence
that this is a neutral occupation,
that this is an occupation that doesn't
favor any gender,
like there's got to be jobs where it's
equally represented,
men and women.
Outside of that,
your job is what you choose to do with
your life.
When boys grow up playing with fucking
trucks and superheros and girls grow up
playing with dolls and they obviously
are more inclined in this direction and
men are more inclined in that direction
that we expect them to meet at any
interest and then we would that we would
force it and force it,
ruins it for women.
It makes them think that they should do
jobs that they might not enjoy and then
they get really depressed.
Right?
Yeah.
Or they think that they need to prove
themselves by doing a man's job.
Exactly.
Instead of just doing what they actually
enjoyed doing.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
it's funny.
As long as I can remember,
my mom wanted to work and she got a job
and then she was mad because she wanted
to stop working because it's um,
but uh,
I mean it just depends on the level of
need,
right?
Like what if there's like a war or a bad
economy?
So I'm guessing,
what are you going to go get people?
That's a different thing,
right?
It's different during the war,
like everybody was sort of bonded
together because they make shit
constantly.
Well,
there seems to be a much more of a uh,
you know,
sometimes my girlfriend,
my girlfriend's at college,
I was like,
I realize isn't even ties in with this
jazz night thing because I realized or
she realized that like half the bad
things that happened to her in the last
four years were social media related.
All this lyric or maybe all of them.
I'm thinking about it like if I think
all the bullshit like stress on my life
that I had in his fucking need.
It is real though.
Like I've had a couple of theaters can
say like ruined my life.
Strangers like set out.
I'm going to ruin your life.
Like where I was like,
wow,
you got a lot of dude it.
It costs money now.
It's crazy.
That's when you get theaters canceled
for.
Well,
I booked a two art schools.
I just paid them to run it like the area
and I sold it out myself and then they
would just cancel saying that I do hate
speech or something saying,
Oh,
there's one merit in Chicago and then
Brooklyn School of music just can't sign
me.
And I had to switch it that day.
Chicago and Brooklyn though are hotbeds
lubrizol Chicago was filled with and
that's like,
I'm a,
I'm a piano player.
Has Two social jihadists.
No Dude.
And I thought that was like my,
my,
my safe spot.
I'm like,
dude,
I'm a piano player.
Algo is so full of like,
dude,
everywhere is the nothing from the
neverending story.
It's just like everywhere now.
Well,
you know,
dude,
if you go to these underserved markets,
like Detroit's right there,
there's people that want to see in
Detroit.
You Go,
I'll go to Detroit.
Be fucking amazing and track.
Is that the [inaudible] areas?
And I did this place.
Oh,
small some rock,
dude.
It was tremendous.
I had a great time in Detroit.
I did that.
Fillmore did two shows there.
It was fucking amazing resource in
there.
Like seven years ago.
I was sick.
Fucking fun,
man.
They appreciate you.
Well,
it's easy to forget or happy to be
there.
You know this horse shit because this
cult that these people are in that's in
Hollywood and New York and Chicago,
religious there.
It's not the rest of the country.
People aren't,
you know,
this is the thing that you get fooled
with social media as you think this is
reality,
but it is everywhere,
but they don't like it.
That's the difference.
I like how it would connect people being
like,
oh no,
this is great.
But it is in other colleges and college
kids write me that they have to sign a
white privileged contract like the
college I've seen them,
but at least they know it means they
acknowledged their white privilege,
which is basically.
I don't know.
It's something that happens usually for
genocide or whatnot,
but we put you acknowledge your
privilege.
You have it easier.
That's amazing.
I've never heard of grow.
It's unreal.
Well,
they're giving kids in certain schools
are given kids lectures on gender and
then how some people are gender fluid,
meaning that they can switch back and
forth from male to female at anytime.
Like at what point in time do we go,
okay,
maybe that's true,
but what's the odds that that's
nonsense.
The 100 percent overwhelming.
I mean Kim,
you might be someone with some sort of a
psychological disorder where they do
bounce back and forth between being a
man,
a woman,
but at what point in time could we
recognize this as a psychological
disorder and this is just not a natural
state of being like having red hair by
the way.
Also I don't give a shit like I know
that involved me,
but why do you have to teach kids that
are fighting to be,
you know,
they go like,
well,
white is considered a default.
I'm like,
well that's because it's a majority
white population like default doesn't
mean because I don't understand what
people are finding is by default.
What do you mean?
It doesn't make any sense.
Like when people go flesh colored
bandaids or white,
which I don't even know if that's still
true,
crown bending do,
but it's literally a matter a matter of
like populate,
like why are you fighting to be default
or like the boring.
Like I became a comedian to be marginal.
Like on the margins.
I didn't want to be in the main dude.
My gone.
If I can't go on a fucking
rollercoaster.
Well the answer the bandaid thing,
it's very easy.
The time that bandaids were invented,
it was a far greater population of white
people.
Yeah,
no shit.
There's more now.
It's like they say within 30 years why
people are going to be the minority.
I think looking forward to it.
Why is my kid white?
I don't even know.
Your kid is definitely not white.
And your kids half Mexican.
Yes.
I spoke this in here by the way.
Yeah,
sure.
I'd rather use marijuana.
What do you got going on?
There are some little glass pipe.
It's a chillum chill them.
That's what these fish concert.
But chill them.
Was that thing they do with Hash a
movie?
Sure.
But that's what I mean.
So just a a one hitter.
We got joints here.
If you want to spark a joint.
I do want to smoke a joint or joint.
I think it's because it's student debt
that all this shit's happening because
of what?
Student debt?
No,
a lot of fucking.
No one's going to get a job from
underwater vagina ballet.
The economy tanked.
All of a sudden there's money to be made
and they're 60
grand in debt for underwater Vagina
Ballet.
And then they have to like justify it
somehow.
It's crazy.
First of all,
if you are an expert under water,
Vagina Ballet,
that's a marketable skill to.
But you should not be broken all under
one vagina.
Ballet.
The,
the social media.
If you noticed the news media started
taking cues from like gossip shit.
Okay.
So like tmz is almost a quaint old
respectable thing.
Now to the onion is the most value.
The Werewolf,
right?
Is that I'm going to smoke out this
waiting for you to go to.
It's okay,
but you keep drinking craft golf
whenever Gawker and fucking buzzfeed.
Basically the print media is going out
of business all of a sudden,
gossipy bullshit and all the social
jihadis.
It makes a lot of money.
Everything has got to be outraged or
uplifting click.
I said,
yeah,
and my friend who works in a no more,
but my friend Aaron knew her from a rate
when you came on race wars,
it's serious.
She was like,
yeah,
I remember.
That's.
Yeah,
may be managing.
Get her Isabelle.
Okay.
She would get sick of these fucking
generation.
She spawned with her fucking just to
sell shit too.
That's the thing.
It isn't like a big plan.
It's just like to sell.
It's the,
there's now these people,
whatever these problems are,
they're claiming they don't want them
solved.
They clearly want to have the conflict
going on forever because they make a
living on it.
There's people that just made,
they're all in patriot.
They're basically clergy,
the clergy,
this jihadi shit.
Uh,
uh,
and you're always on Patrion with the
handout who helped me go to schools and
tell kids about fucking,
you know,
hit the Werewolf General queefs or
whatever.
I know they got to like make like make
problems where there aren't any
problems,
but I think it's because of our instinct
to run away from a lion as stronger than
towards a banana.
I got offered an alternative point of
view.
Think about how often you get into
bullshit arguments online and you're a
successful comedian who's married with
children.
Now,
think of yourself as being 20 years old
at college,
talk and Shit,
writing a blog,
whatever decided you're going to take
down all of these points.
It's a natural inclination to do it and
it's also natural.
Pick a fucking side.
It's natural to decide.
You see people aggressive in one
direction.
I'm going to be on the other side and
say,
fuck those people.
Look at it again.
I'm just smoking the manliest pipe in
the world.
Don't mind me.
How dope is that?
SB pipe design on Instagram,
talking about fucking society and Shit.
Smoking a werewolf by Mr Rogen.
Well,
you can't default on any of these loans.
It's a trillion dollar debt.
Well,
that's a giant issue.
Those kids getting fucked because it's a
hustle.
They tell you you have to do it and in
some jobs you do have to do it,
but you should probably think about what
the fuck you wanna do with your life.
Ultimately before you do it.
I don't think it's a bad idea to travel
overseas to experience some things,
take some jobs,
and then get some life experiences that,
you know what,
I'm leaning towards being a this or I'm.
What interests me is that take the time
to find out what gender you are.
Don't let your out.
If you bounce
to that.
I spent 50 grand on a history education
that I could gotten from Dan Carlin
for nothing or dude,
yeah,
he's on fire history.
Florida case is sick.
He's a bad motherfucker that Danieli
about.
He's.
He's a history podcast.
Guys,
not reading books by white males for the
next month to solicit.
Just read more books of people of color.
You can read what books by white people.
Look the way I suggest,
I suggest a five to one ratio.
People of color makes no sense.
Nigeria and a Filipino and like a three
lock and have in common.
There was somethings,
not Jordan yet,
person tweeted real recently,
it was a huff post editor that was
talking about her ultimate goal of home
runs being white or less contributions
being white,
more contributions by people of color
and women and she had like this whole
breakdown in numbers,
like the numbers that they've achieved
of like how there is still working on it
of getting rid of the white voice.
Just be the white guy.
He's never done.
That's the bottom line.
What women do so much because I don't
know any black people by the way.
Who all the jibberish that you here you
think of a single black person in my
life that has ever demanded I say any of
it or agree or never say shit that
they're claiming 40 though.
So there's like people like I guess my
age and not.
You know,
it's generational too because if you
were in the twenties,
if you were hanging out with 20 year old
kids,
you'd be experiencing this will now.
They went full circle,
but they're trying to see your Dick.
Doesn't matter though,
with the racist,
like I can't even believe it's a point
where people with a straight face push
segregation under the guise of anti,
you know what I mean?
Like safe space.
So this is a colored space.
I'm like,
you know,
we had that in the fifties and shit.
The Soviet Union,
they do everything the opposite.
It's doublespeak tolerance is
authoritarianism.
Well yeah,
but say it again.
It's the opposite.
It's doublespeak where if you say
tolerance,
that means authoritarianism.
No,
it's what is,
is it enforced tolerance?
It becomes like a mandatory behavior
pattern that you're supposed to like
hate speech is free speech because this
isn't who decides.
Hey,
why don't you got this being a stupid
call I got,
I,
I have an obsession like explaining to
people who haven't.
You heard you on the show before,
they don't know about your job.
A witness,
which I never thought.
I never thought of it as a cult.
Honestly.
I never called them a call and I never
really had an anger towards it.
But when I think about it,
you know,
they didn't help.
It didn't help my fucking family.
And only hurt.
That's the thing with these religions,
they never help.
And that's what they should also seeds.
Some,
some religions I think can help certain
people.
I don't believe they don't.
Especially men's helped nicest people on
the planet.
What I'm saying is the parts that helped
were parts I didn't need the religion
for.
You didn't,
but you haven't accelerated in mind.
I saw people have their lie.
I saw a guy who was a meth head mean
this is my church.
And he had bad teeth and shit.
And then uh,
his whole family came in and all of a
sudden you got new teeth and they were
like a happy and the.
Oh,
sorry,
go ahead.
See what I wanted to hear that story.
That's what I'm talking about.
No,
I've seen that happen.
Like I don't think I'm an atheist at
all.
Like I,
I have no,
uh,
when you were under that truck,
so when you were in that accident did
contemplate like,
oh my God,
it might be going to heaven or I might
be going to hell.
I didn't even have time for that until
we were just like,
this is the end.
I'll tell you why I felt good was it was
so out of my control what was happening.
I mean not one part because usually I
think I'm going to die because I fucking
did something,
but like it was so out of my hands.
That was comforting.
Like I was like,
oh,
there's nothing.
It's just your time when it's your time,
man,
and this one,
it's not my fault.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
I'm like,
oh,
that's right.
It's an versus me.
I'm like,
I shouldn't have tweeted that is they're
stabbing.
I think this is.
This is the creepy part because the
job's witnesses and that guy with the
teeth,
he had a way to come back in,
or my ex girlfriend that got caught
shoplifting because all white girl
shoplift.
I don't know if you know that too,
because no one would ever believe it was
them passed with a rider was the queen
shoplifting white girl because who would
think she would do that?
I wouldn't ask like why would they all
do it?
So they.
And they all have,
I've almost all white girls.
I'm not sure.
I mean my church,
I'm sure there were sincere people
fucking thing to do to shoplift birth
control,
birth tests.
A Galley.
You said date had a real issue?
Yeah,
she was a real addicted shoplifts.
She got arrested hundreds of dollars of
clothes and change into different
things.
Put things on under clothes and walk out
with them and well my ex got caught and
she had to go and I didn't even know
like,
I don't even know why she didn't tell
me.
She was like,
I didn't want to tell him.
I'm like,
I don't care.
But she got caught and had to do
community service I think in like Harlan
and she was afraid to do it,
but she said like people are walking up
and thanking her for like picking up
trash with the orange vest because
people just skip out on it.
Once you do the service,
they wipe it from your record.
Basically they offer.
It's like you get caught,
you're offered a way back where you
don't have it on your record.
It's on mark it.
That's the thing that could work for
somebody that's not going to be like,
so religion has that.
If I wanted to go back and meet job as
witness,
I could go,
listen,
I was wrong.
I,
I missed being part of the truth,
blah,
blah blah,
and I can get back in.
These people have created a religion
where they catch you in some minor
mistake and they throw you into your
advantage to Kramer island or whatever
and they're fucking proud of it.
And the only way you can move ahead as
to catch someone else.
So it's much worse than religion because
there's no love or forgiveness of any
kind.
It's this empty button.
The only thing that matters is your part
of the right identity.
I mean,
it's basically just the racism as
religion,
but they use shame and that's why the
only way out of it is to not care
because shame is the only way to control
people are your biggest ways you could
control the other way.
No,
no.
For the,
uh,
for the social justice warrior religion,
like the way to do it.
I think it's important.
What you're saying is,
um,
that,
that is the files,
the same sort of patterns that these
benches and find Jesus,
it'd be happier.
No gluten free.
Jesus Christ.
Oh fuck.
It's like what you experienced as a
Jehovah witnesses the same thing like
they,
like we were talking before you got here
about them trying to cancel Jordan
Peterson speeches and these people were
sending these emails and professors were
sending emails,
calling him a racist and a Nazi and
saying he's a fascist and all these
different things like.
And what I'm saying is that when you
ramp up the fake reality to the point
where you,
you're saying things you know aren't
true,
right,
you think you're thinking of doing it
for the right reason,
to a purpose.
They do it purposely.
They think they're doing it for the
right reason,
but if they really aren't,
they're not.
They've really not a fan of Jordan
Peterson.
They would realize how crazy it is to
say he's racist.
How crazy it is to say he's transphobic
or anything.
He's not a Nazi by any stretch of the
imagination.
So he just doesn't tolerate nonsense.
It's all it is.
They want nonsense of course.
So they're proving him right by calling
him a Nazi.
Yeah,
right.
Well,
it's just,
look,
this is why I think it'll just burn
itself out eventually because.
No Man,
you can't keep throwing.
They throw people,
they throw their people away.
You add Jamie Kilstein on recently.
I didn't,
I never will.
They stick around like the hunchback and
300,
you know,
they're like,
can I get back in?
They don't,
they don't really feel that.
I know that guy from.
I started comedy.
Okay.
And Jamie was always like,
I think I talked with like a while ago
talking about,
but it was like,
you know,
he was always a dude that felt small
that it was.
I always got the impression his
girlfriend made up most of,
most of,
most of him when I knew him that he met
this girl he was married to and she put
all that shit.
She turned him into who he was because
he just like a low self esteem dude,
you know.
And uh,
I mean I can relate to that.
I can relate to a lie,
that shit of where someone's like,
all right,
somebody feels bad and they want to be
part of a group,
but that's what I'm just fascinated by.
How do you,
for yourself?
Like how do you make old?
And he's telling me all his personal
experience like Shit,
some shit I won't share it with like he
can't.
But it sounded like being in a fucking
religion and like when it went like
dirty tests,
there's literally like purity tests.
Like you heard outside ideas you better
not to listen to.
It sounded so much like we were supposed
to guard our hearts and like not even
read certain things.
You know,
like if we had doubts not say them
because you might stumble your brother
out of the faith and that's the worst
thing there is like,
okay,
just put the question side because God
forbid you say something to put stout
and Owen and then he falls out of the
truth.
It's a clever little tactic.
So they all do isolated.
The reason they got to crack down on
bullshit like comedy or whatever the
fuck or your facebook or who give.
If you give a shit about something,
somebody tweeted,
I mean you must be fucking stupid,
but that's all of them ever hurts.
Cognitive dissonance hurts where it's
like Donald Trump is Hitler.
Now give them all your guns.
Then like that hurts your brain and so
when someone shows you,
say that again,
I'm sorry.
Smoking Pot.
A lot of these same people have been all
year,
have been trying to convince everyone
that donald trump's being run by the
Russians and he's Adolf Hitler,
and then the government should have all
your guns.
It's the same as being pro free market,
but not acknowledging you're so stupid.
Both of us did.
I've certainly smoked myself.
Stupid.
Donald trump is.
To me,
he's the guy.
He's the perfect.
First of all,
the perfect president of America.
This is.
There's never been,
and I mean for whatever party or in he
is your Avatar,
man.
He is.
He is the fucking,
like everybody that thinks they can do a
job that they can't do,
but they saw something on tv,
like I could probably do that better.
Tell Him we didn't have an expert.
Just a guy like very like,
he's the candidate of the volunteer
fireman of the gender studies professor
of the fucking the vine star that became
a comedian.
Like all these people that think they
can just walk into some fucking.
He is that.
Well that's our DNA.
It's being like the earth is flat.
Give me a boat.
Is there a golden.
I'm like my truth.
And you all that shit like small.
He learned from Lewis and Clark like
though the original fucking two man
comedy duo,
we had to wait like the people that
Lewis and Clark that the explorers.
No,
she got a blood relative to that guy.
How,
how'd you know that?
Did you go to one of those genealogy
report?
Now?
My,
uh,
my dad told me he just knew.
Oh wow,
that's crazy.
Who told him?
Why am I Warren Pocahontas things?
I took the genealogy tests.
It turns out I'm gay.
Is that,
how crazy is that?
Elizabeth Warren Lady?
She was.
She's insane.
Well,
I'll take a fucking.
She won't take an ancestry test.
She went to this class,
you know,
I will say this though.
I hadn't gone on race racecourse long
time ago.
What the fuck is his name?
Shawn,
let me ask you this.
Oh,
what was built by?
We're on this little Elizabeth Warren
thing.
Do you care about what?
About whether or not she's really native
American.
She brought it up for.
She took a job,
like she robbed these job.
She's at Harvard.
She got like one of those.
She got a scholarship for being native
American.
She got a scholarship to how much native
American and she pulled the Shaun King
one 32nd.
Yeah.
But you have to understand something,
and I didn't know this,
uh,
that should have blood quantum native
Americans didn't have.
You could be fucking.
If I'm,
let's say I'm a chief and I just adopt
your Rogan.
Joe Rogan is my son.
He is now 100 percent part of my thing
no matter what.
His blood.
They didn't get hung up on that.
That came about to divvy up benefits,
you know,
after we like the real evil shit.
We did.
The natives was modern times back then.
I don't,
I mean that's what everybody did back
then.
I don't give a fuck,
but in modern times you're absolutely
right dude.
But in modern times he did some very
evil shit with them.
The blood quantum,
that was what they're kind of cool about
the most,
uh,
most native nations is they didn't get
hung up on your amount of blood when
you're in the family.
And so you could be one like Johnny Depp
when he said he got brought in the tribe
so we could play Toronto.
That's a legit thing in traditionally in
native America,
they were much cooler about racial shit.
Like,
like Europeans kind of brought that
nonsense over more,
but a kidnap people and people would
stay with them.
They better vibe the Sebastian younger
detailed how many
people would leave Western society and
joined the native Americans.
I didn't know how much it was,
like separate countries.
See if they teach American history.
That's what they should start at the
very first whatever countries were here
and then just move up through American
because it's thousands of years.
Shit,
count them.
They don't even count today.
It's really interesting shit.
Like I didn't know how populated it was.
Like two,
they were considered fauna in Canada
until the sixties or it might've been
Australia,
but they were considered like fauna.
Like,
well I might be insane.
Australia.
Yeah.
The aborigines,
they have a terrible story.
They.
They was in the 19 I saw quickly and
under guys kidnapped the average new
babies and made them raised by white
people.
They took the babies from aboriginal
families.
It's like,
where'd you get that baby?
I don't know.
They did it like a concerted effort that
we're going to try to create the.
They decided they were going to
symbolize people.
I had my buddy Adam green tree lives
over there and it'll show it.
Yeah.
He's born and raised and he works in
mining companies,
so he deals with all these different
aborigines and they all have different
languages.
They call them.
They're called a mob like instead of a
clan or a town,
they call themselves a mob.
Really?
Yeah,
and they have.
They might have a totally different name
for things.
As a guy that lives five miles away,
five miles away,
there's a bunch of totally different
names and those people stick to
themselves.
These people stick to their selves,
so the bands of them,
hundreds of them all over the place and
these.
All these different languages are all
the losing all of them.
They're going to lose all these
languages if these people get
assimilated because they're not really
written down in a lot of cases.
Do you see that?
It was on some fucking discovery.
Maybe you know one of them fucking
things,
but the oldest human language,
I think his case on people that got
wiped out by the Zulus back in the day,
like Shaka Zulu conquered them,
but the case on their language is like
the oldest thing they can find a k,
a e song son Jay,
I think.
Whoa.
But the old thing,
there's this old ass lady who knew
something about like the word and it was
like,
whoa.
She's like,
they come from animal noises,
like the lion goes bra.
And then the words they got came from
mimicking.
It was interesting as fuck.
But it's.
So,
uh,
it's such cradle of civilization shit.
But the case song I think,
I think that's like their languages.
The oldest like Prodo.
Well,
you know,
monkeys have a language that's
different,
different sounds for different things.
Like watch out,
there's a lion is a different noise than
watch out.
There's an eagle.
And these,
these biologists or what would they be?
Would they be,
if they're studying monkeys,
primatologists,
I guess he's primatologists setup these
speakers and played the sound of watch
out.
It's an eagle and all the monkeys
fucking duct and went running down the
tree and they played watch out.
There's a line and they're all looking
down,
have a language.
The language.
They have a language and they play
tricks on each other.
Like one guy will say,
hey,
watch out.
There's a line.
And they all run up the tree and he gets
the food.
I told her I was
coming on.
He goes,
oh,
you go,
you guys get all pothead excited about
the same still learning chair.
Never gonna stop either.
I don't give a fuck what anybody says.
You can't shame me into getting not
geeked out about like super volcanoes
and shit.
I'm going to freak out about it.
I don't care.
It's wicked exciting.
It's fun.
It's super volcanoes.
I would love to.
Oh,
we already talked about one before you
got here that killed most of the people.
Seventy thousand years ago.
We were talking about 70,000
years ago there was only 100,000
people.
Oh yeah.
Is this still a thing that said that?
Like when they trace the jeans bag comes
from like a population about 600 people.
Yeah.
I mean there was probably at many times
during our history we trembled dwindled
down to a very small number two.
It's crazy.
It was really cold too.
Oh fuck man.
Didn't half of North America under more
than a mile of ice.
And we made it through.
We can make it through twitter guys,
we can make it to throw it.
But you,
you gotta leave Anthony Jeselnik alone.
You got to play this.
How much weed has steered me off course.
Do you know how many people in the last
like two weeks and I mean having
conversations about or shit in their
lives are like a show and so unfollowed
me on instagram and it was like weighing
on them.
Right.
So follow me.
How come you don't follow me on
something?
And I'm like do the greatest thing that
media shit storm man.
Cause I feel like I did everything you
can do on social media by having that
happen.
I get,
I got to the limits of social media for
myself grabbing bandit.
I'm so glad.
I mean I put shit to promote on it but I
was telling you that like I'm so glad
not to be talking to people on fucking
social media.
The idea that I would give a shit and
that's like adults,
man,
like grown adults.
We're dealing followed me on instagram.
Like just thinking who gives a shit of
just blocked.
You want to,
I mean I just,
I was too aggressive,
but it's not even that,
but there's no context but there's no
context so it doesn't matter.
There's no way to take it,
right,
because it's not being said.
You could say it to somebody and they
go,
oh,
I get what he's saying and let's say
you,
he even,
he got the context.
You're trying to be funny.
Someone else is going to make it
something that's not,
that's what they did.
It's such a.
and I didn't even,
it didn't even occur to me dude.
How much like quick sand,
like,
like people that shouldn't be allowed to
make fucking eye contact with me that
I'm,
I'm having discourses with and Shit
online.
I mean just because you're getting your
head the way pete to diet people like
threatening to create whatever the shit
you hear some fucking a college speaker
complain about 10 times over.
I had coming at me from you.
I'm going to rape and murder your
neighbor.
It's explained.
Most people that don't know this
terrible thing where I said,
hey,
if you get raped,
maybe go to the cops.
On the way to posting it on facebook,
that UCB has determined guilt in a rape
case like nearly suggested.
Hit the brakes.
No one knows what the fuck you're
talking about.
So let's just explain the story to this.
Cost is so strong.
It's very.
I drink it.
He was off the charts.
He had one and a quarter and it is
fucking to crank.
I'm trying to counteract it with his
indycar.
I just want.
I want people to understand the story.
There was a guy that was accused of rape
and you had decided like they shouldn't
be tried in the court of public opinion
on social media and what you said is why
humorous wind,
first of all,
nothing with my friend.
Somebody now not even defending him.
I'm defending any but like how is this
fucking cool that this is going to be
tried on fucking facebook?
Someone's sending random message.
So and so has been found a ucb that
noted clown college has done an internal
investigation and term and so and so is
guilty of rape.
So if you have any information come in
and that's on facebook.
Did they really say it that way?
It was first in an online woman group.
Then it got leaked onto regular
facebook,
but as a representative of the UCB that
said that they didn't.
It was some fucking girl on her own.
I found out that's a big difference.
Right.
Like she said,
the umbrella of UCB.
Did she do it under the UCB twitter page
or facebook page or other?
I have no idea.
It was from twitter or something.
Whatever it is.
I mean,
she could have just been.
I saw thought.
I'm like,
chase page.
It wasn't even a thing.
The problem is if you're saying the UCB
did it and they didn't know they did
not.
They did not.
Okay.
She said that she said,
but you said that you see be determined
that it was.
I saw a post that said that.
Right,
and this is from a person,
but she said it.
The UCB didn't say it.
No,
it's not their official word at all.
Right.
Okay.
So it's just a personal,
very clear about that.
They never claimed that it was a person
who I think was like a rape counselor or
something or somebody had to deal with
like this.
There's a bunch of like a rapey job.
So something happened,
performers,
something happened between performance
and this one guy was being accused and
you said he just real simple without
knowing who's guilty or not.
You said he shouldn't be trying to call.
Here's what happened.
A guy that opened for me somewhere with
friends with I go,
Hey,
can he call you now?
First question,
why call me right?
What am I a noted rape investigator on
facebook?
I think just because I was somebody
yelled,
this is me not being aware of what to
build it up.
I would just yell out on facebook about
stuff and I had a following.
So it's almost like a,
Oh,
like a can you talk to you and then
throw your weight behind?
I think it was like,
eh,
but um,
you know,
I didn't look at it as shit,
facebook like that.
Like it was like not,
I don't understand like how people were
looking at my facebook.
It's ridiculous.
But anyway,
I talked to the guy on the phone and he
told me something I think was a lie.
I mean,
you know,
obviously I can't say one or the other,
but looking back,
I think when he told me was a lie that
people were accusing them because he
didn't book them on a show,
which just doesn't really make a lot of
sense so much.
And with that quick to pull the trigger
on a rate back,
how evil they would have to be booked
me,
he fucking crazy.
That accusation.
I couldn't believe they would be
involved in comedy but that at once
together
at eight minutes,
ah,
make a 10 or else we got rape on our
hands.
So my point was just used guilty.
This is worse because what you've done
is handed somebody a lawsuit.
You can't defame someone like that.
And it's like you can just get sued for
that.
And also this is just to be convicted
before you're allowed to say that
legally.
But to me it's not.
I mean,
it's like they're taking the campus
thing of like where we're going to have
a college campus say kick you out of
school for that rape.
You committed,
talk over each other,
but it's hard.
That's not a punishment.
That's not a punishment for rape is you
get kicked out of school.
This is gender studies.
Bullshit trickling down into real life.
Okay.
So the colleges I assume wet.
Let that,
let that go on because they don't want
to be known as a school where your
daughter could get raped.
So they let these little groups pretend
to have power and do a little tribunal
and then everybody's happy.
But we want to know what a rapist got
expelled.
That's their punishment.
Great job.
It sounds like the Catholic church
transferring people,
it doesn't sound any different.
So this is someone to.
So to me that was just like a garbage
ass.
If this guy's dangerous,
go to the fucking cops.
So,
so uh,
then I'm getting all this.
People come to me about like,
don't you dare tell a victim to go,
I don't know.
You're a victim yet though.
That's the thing.
Like when a victim says you're a victim,
if you don't believe them,
you're calling them a liar.
We have to make sure you are a victim
before we say one way or the other.
So we're getting ahead of ourselves.
But this is just basic due process shit.
I guess the argument is because
historically this is like the argument
on coming against me from finishing a
historically,
women are not believed,
uh,
which by the way,
by who other women.
Because what my experience is,
is any woman close to me,
they'd say she got raped.
I probably believer and every man I
know.
In fact I know women that get dudes into
fights over shit like that.
Especially if you're in like white trash
town where I grew up around like women
are the ones that don't believe women.
Men are the only people stupid enough to
believe women most of the time.
Okay.
So that's already a bullshit thing that
women aren't believed we.
There's lynching.
Rosewood,
remember that shit that was [inaudible]
a woman,
a white woman was just believed.
And then there's a bunch of lynchings of
black people was.
I think there's got to be instances we
should be very measured about this
because it's got to be instances in
which women weren't believed.
Of course.
Full spectrum has nothing to do.
The idea is that you can't believe him
every time.
The larger point is you'd have to look
at it as an individual case.
Every case is individual and you look at
it on it because that's fair.
It doesn't matter.
Let's say no woman in history has ever
lied about rape once.
Well,
you still have to have due process in
case it happens once.
I'm not getting sacrificed to the state
for the good of the fucking.
You know what I mean?
If it had shit happens,
it does happen.
It happens when you have something to
lose.
Like you're famous custody cases,
rape case.
Yeah,
and news stories of this going
uncritically believed when,
when by the way with someone not
believed in the media and and it turned
out.
I see a lot of people getting believed
who lot.
None of it matters though because like I
said,
that has no bearing on my individual
anything.
Like we've cleared double standards,
like when will just believe you and one
will be super skeptical.
Barry Barry crimmins like because he,
you know,
he,
if you haven't seen that documentary,
anybody listening,
uh,
call me lucky is really great because
he,
because that guy kind of heroic what he
did with a aol.
He basically,
he was raping me was for which uh,
uh,
I mean that's crazy what that would do
to somebody and he,
I think he told us talking about it
onstage first or something and he ended
up winning when the Internet was first
becoming a nationwide thing,
he was,
there was child pornography everywhere,
like pedophiles were by aol by the hour.
If you are rich and you could just
freely trade child pornography.
So he had to testify before Congress,
the Senate and AOL had a lawyer there
because they didn't want to change their
policy,
which was three strikes and you're out
for child pornography.
That's in the beginning.
They actually with a straight face,
like we have a from three strikes and
you're out policy.
Isn't that crazy that that was only like
1995 or 96 or something like that.
It's just one of the best parts of the
documentary because Barry's like,
well,
he told me,
he's like,
the guy says three strikes you're out.
Goes,
yeah,
listen,
I love baseball too.
But I love baseball more than anybody
but.
But they,
they,
uh,
the senators and congressmen were
tripping over themselves in a manly
display of being ignorant of technology
or very like really is like a quotable
dude,
like the,
he says,
but they got lot.
Oh No.
It,
all this Internet is.
I just know that pornography is bad.
Like some of them didn't know where the
fuck they were.
Robert Byrd is just like the age of
pornography where he for a school age
and at one point and the documents that
he was talking about how it was almost
like the other lawyer against him and it
was who had better stage presence.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
Where he was just clearly a better
speaker.
Like this really expensive lawyer was
just like a shitty opener.
Yeah.
He was in bow and barry got to talk to
testify,
you know,
he went over his time.
He went over his time very.
They had to change it.
But anyway,
I,
uh,
I wrote through him after that.
I saw that document.
It's like,
well,
that guy's fucking try me.
And I was like crying from that
documentary.
Uh,
well anyway,
so I got the shit.
All that shit came down on me.
People are going to bury to get them to
like denounce me,
like I hardly knew him.
So he called me up and uh,
you know what,
you have to realize a lot of this shit
because he did real work helping people
who rape victims.
Kids were building like Batman Shit.
Okay.
And basically he fucking this shit's
turf if you're a feminist or whatever
political thing.
He goes,
you understand this is turf to them.
They don't give a shit about an actual
victim.
So like,
you know,
you'll try to do something good at helps
someone and if you go to groups they
could grab it and they use it as their
little symbol or whatever.
It's never about an individual person.
I talked to this woman just a one way
when at the height of things coming down
on me for saying go to the cops and off
facebook and always people I know,
like the system has failed.
Well you,
I,
I don't know that you didn't go to the
system,
so how do you now also,
you're a white woman.
I think it'll,
it'll,
but does want to call me to be fair.
There's one to call me who wanted to.
She want to get touched me some other
creep inserted herself,
like some blogger check who initially
basically they baited me with these
nonsense.
All you guys.
That's what I'm saying.
Watch on there because nobody's talking
to you on there.
Like having a chat or there's what I
learned there.
They're baiting you to get you to say
something that they can.
They can say,
oh,
I took down such and so and it.
There's no.
I'm,
I'm from this dumb Colt,
so I'm sincerely interested in peanut
chatty cathy and people are not sincere.
They they want to make a name for
themselves,
baiting you into doing something,
get you in trouble,
and they will fucking fuck with you is
shit.
You can't believe you'd be in trouble
for saying such as.
Go to the police and not fucking
facebook if you're raped.
So,
so this woman called me in the thick of
it.
I don't know her name still okay.
Because she didn't really know anything
about me.
They're telling her I'm a rape
apologist,
which thank you for putting that next to
my name online for all time.
I have now crazy.
It's just pop up around.
It's just,
it's just to put raped by.
Explain what happened at the Improv the
other night.
Oh,
this was a few months ago.
I didn't know about some woman I've ever
met in my life right after it happened.
I think I texted you.
I couldn't believe it.
I,
my manager assistant texted me a picture
so somebody would giant glasses feel
like you told me in person I might have,
but she goes,
do you know this person?
I thought it was someone from Tim and
Eric,
like she was asking me about a cat.
I don't know where I got now.
Why Tim and Eric Personality,
that kind of weird look,
she's,
she went in the Improv and said,
Kurt Metzger raped me.
I'm here to confront him.
And uh,
yeah,
they said she was visibly not right.
Like it wasn't like,
I mean,
but just someone throwing that around
casually.
But that's because she,
they put,
they make these little shitty names.
Like what the fuck is that?
There's no such thing as that.
Okay.
No one's pro fucking Reiki magic.
There's someone out there go.
What's the little rape?
Yeah.
No,
I've never met a person out there that's
doing that is if you don't accept no
for.
Yes,
same thing.
Yeah.
If you don't accept every tenant of
fucking white girl Taliban feminism that
you love rape,
that's the fucking org.
It's like,
it's like arguing with a girlfriend that
you should have dumped three years ago.
It's a bad relationship except you're
not dating it so hostile because this is
because there are going.
We don't even know they're so into this
identity shit.
You know what it is?
Yeah.
I think part of it is um,
social media of course.
I think all of these attacks and shit or
antisocial,
they're like weird.
The way people would talk.
Well,
it's tricking these girls to the
thinking.
They're going to have their little angry
black guy moment.
But here's the thing,
you're not like black people.
You're not like a suppressed
marginalized minority,
feminine.
I don't know where they're getting that
from.
You are absolutely not an identity of
women together.
And here's how I know they proved that
at the women's March when they kicked
the prolife women out.
See Black people have to take all,
all their garbage.
Black people they have to take in their
movement because it's still don't doe,
but black people have to.
They're forced to,
to,
to bargain like a minority.
I get that women are half the population
got fucking women's March.
They kick out the prolife women.
That's a luxury you have when you're not
in the press minority.
That's when you have it pretty good.
We don't know what like what is minority
mean?
Like being one in 10,000.
That's the Asians.
That story though.
That's crazy that they know that.
No,
I did not see if you can find that
Jamie.
Yeah.
They want to see some footage.
I mean,
I wouldn't be surprised if there were
like kicking a woman.
Yeah.
Like you're not an oppressed minority.
If you can afford to kick out the
prolife women this March.
It's a crazy time too.
I mean objectively with no political
leanings left or right.
It's crazy when they're kicking out.
The people that are saying don't kill
the babies.
I now look at what it is.
I mean,
I'm not saying you shouldn't do it,
but what is it about.
You were a boarding.
Well,
you know what will eventually be at
these are people that fundamentally
refused to acknowledge.
It's like watching people that you get
divorced.
Argue the argument.
I've tried to argue this patient because
like,
my mother doesn't hate women.
She's a Christian lady that thinks it's
murder.
I think,
hey,
maybe you're killing a baby.
I don't give a fuck I.
it's not my baby.
Go do what you want.
The anti,
the pro choice or intense.
I don't care.
I don't give a fuck.
Like,
listen,
if you're the kind of person that can do
it,
they maybe you should do it.
You know,
like,
I,
I don't give a shit.
It's not,
it's not a fucking uh,
uh,
that's you and your God does to,
you know,
so,
but you know,
conversely also if you have your kid,
I also don't give a fuck about your kid
and if I don't have kids,
I just don't,
I don't think that it to you,
but I'm just saying,
I'm not like [inaudible] you're a
different amount of caffeine.
Bra is so jacked up.
Why is the women's March excluding pro
life women?
Well this is the week now.
Wait,
are they get.
Oh,
you should find someone that's saying a
should do on it.
But once I listen to the bottom line is
they go and I have talked a million
times to people that talk about they go.
It's either somewhat always emotional,
the person you're talking to and it's a,
they want to control my body as a woman.
And that's why they're anti abortion.
I'm like,
no,
they think it's baby murder.
No,
they want to control my.
Then you talked to the other people like
they want to have an immoral lifestyle
and Blah like really gets broken down.
Is that one sentence a woman's right to
choose.
Like you don't even say to choose what I
keep going.
Like they cut it off because it sounds
uncomfortable.
It's a woman's a woman's right to choose
to abort a baby.
Right.
And I think it is.
That's not my right.
That's pregnant.
I would decide if I'm fucking avenue I
couldn't care about.
I'm like Nah,
I'm going to decide.
I could only put myself in so much
choose if that's what I'd watched.
So that's why I'm for so.
But.
But rovy Wade is a very excellent
compromised,
by the way,
it's late term abortion.
See the late term abortion is fucking
gross and I understand if it's a
miserable fucking defect,
fine.
But if you look at the numbers and it's
very hard to get accurate abortion
numbers because it's so politicized.
The late term abortions are not as I
would have thought because of
deformities.
It's a lot of times they either didn't
know they were pregnant or just hit
like,
it's Kinda shitty bro.
You can see the wrong man.
But like I said,
if you as a mother could do that that
late,
Eh,
maybe you shouldn't raise a kid,
you know?
Uh,
but,
but early on,
I don't think you're murdering anything.
Like,
or if you do it early,
I think,
you know,
it's a,
it is a slippery conversation though.
And this is what people who are
ideologically attached to that left wing
dogma,
they're not willing to have this
conversation.
So if you have these pro life women,
they don't want to have a dialogue like
their mind is completely,
well,
they better listen.
Here's my other thing is just be
consistent if you're pro life because
the Catholic church is at least
consistent prolife,
they're anti death penalty.
Okay.
They're pro life.
They were against the Iraq war,
like,
okay,
go down the last birth control.
Yeah,
because you're supposed to bring more
light.
So at least you're teaching is
consistent.
I can't see in these people that are
like,
no,
if you want to have your right wing,
no social welfare state,
you're going to have to fucking allow
abortion because you're gonna have to
take help.
Take care of these fucking kids.
Are you willing to do that?
Some of them are,
but a lot of them are not,
and by the way,
if we went and blew up Iraq,
Ms Dot Christians that wanted to do
this,
there's Kelvion Christians.
They're okay.
They're like the original fucking
Christians there have babies at their
collateral damage.
You call them and that's,
that's fine.
It happens,
but okay.
What's the difference between that and
some woman in New York?
The collateral damage of on the way to
her career,
she doesn't have the baby.
If you accept that OSCE dropping bombs
on somebodies fucking pregnant wife and
killing their unborn baby because it's
convenient for us.
Thanks.
Shut the fuck up about someone getting
an abortion because you're a hypocrite.
Control life down the line.
Well,
yes,
that's a very good rant and true.
Yeah.
Well I can't go on facebook anymore.
I'll get in trouble.
That's a very good rant.
I mean,
what you're saying is right.
If the people are very convenient,
it's very inconsistent.
I think you're absolutely right.
Bitter.
I'm bitter for my religion because I'm
the sucker that would believe it.
Right?
It would dawn on me later.
Oh yeah.
We don't actually do that.
We're just,
you know.
No,
you can't fudge chip on your shoulder
because of that.
And you and I have had this conversation
a bunch of times because you'll say,
I know what these people are trying to
do with their words.
I remember this shit from when I was
told the same thing.
I'm a suppressive person,
right?
Or an apostate.
Joe Is witnesses.
I'm always in a positive thing.
It should be an ally castle title.
Well,
because dude,
I get a good title.
Ooh,
I like it,
dude.
12 apostates.
I get fucking,
uh,
really upset by that group.
Like,
don't stumble your brother once,
once.
The truth is just saying,
telling the truth.
It's not in the interest of the group to
tell the truth.
That's really upsetting.
It just really gets under my.
Well,
it should.
It's like what we're talking about,
it brings back the same thing as Jordan
Peterson thing when they're calling him
a Nazi and they're calling him a
transphobic.
I understand.
He's a professor at the University of
Toronto.
It's become very famous for battling
against Social Justice Warrior Ideology
Online,
specifically them imposing in one of
their bills and Canada.
The you have to use someone specified
gender pronouns and there if you.
If you don't do it,
it could be thought of as like a human
rights violation.
Will they have those human rights
courts,
the human rights councils up there.
It's subtle counselor.
It's a very different thing.
They don't have freedom of speech.
It's not the same as free speech is kind
of an American thing,
but what it talked about it.
What would it be?
Pronouns like Faggot,
like if you have to say that because
that would also be hate speech.
It's like this weird.
Circle me my word,
so it can't be a pronoun you parents or
identity.
There's some control over what the
pronouns will be like.
You could probably say you're a storm
trooper,
right?
You could probably get crazy,
but you probably can't say you're a
Faggot,
but what if that's your identity,
like who's to say what your identity is?
Your identity cannot be an offensive
word it because your identity is lashing
out,
hurting other people.
What if you identify as white CIS male?
That's it.
I'm a white cisgender gay.
I got no problem.
I'll call you whatever the fuck you
want.
I got no issue with that.
No issue.
Forced,
forced.
He was saying he was battling against it
very early on and almost everything he
said would happen is happening now in
terms of this overreaction culture.
Welcome.
By the way,
how come that's.
Remember Jamie Kilstein had had a
capacity of about it that a white boy
blues song he did and he goes,
oh,
I don't know what this means,
and I go,
Jamie,
I know you got to put everything on the
white males.
Now that's like the religion,
but do you want us to believe anyone
outside of a young white male knows what
the fuck's?
This means like where I used to live in
Washington heights in New York.
I want you to go out and talk to any of
Dominicans on the corner and go,
do you know you're a CIS male?
Right.
And ask her if they know what the fuck
that means.
They'll stop you.
You have to be a white super recent
thing.
Plus gender is supposed to adopt it.
Like,
okay,
I'll tell you what you want,
but why you get to pick my title.
It's also nonsense words.
It's a Marxist.
Marxism does it alliance and if you
agree to nonsense,
that's one step closer to dominance.
That's where everyone knows.
Yeah,
it is really like a religion.
You're right.
It's a consensus based religion which is
really being Vegan is kosher.
Is it that people fall into that so easy
because they come to comfortable by.
Barry told me that I didn't understand
the level because people fucking hate
themselves.
That's why they're online creating these
new identities and shit and if you don't
hate yourself,
because I.
before I had that,
that media shitstorm I,
I had,
I had alright guys would fucking try.
They all did different things to try to
ruin your life.
Like would be people pose it.
Alright guys like to be a fake you and
then go to people you kind of know like
John Daly,
who I'm like,
I know I'm bound.
No one where like,
and then as you say,
some fucked up shit.
And then they think like that's the John
Daly,
the golf guy.
Now they'll give you from kroll show.
He's pretty funny.
Dude.
Actually he's on the uh,
you.
He always is in shake daily.
Daily.
You've seen him in shared.
Trust me,
he's got like a square head.
Okay.
But uh,
uh,
but fine,
whatever.
But they will go at him a fake me.
Oh,
when Patton Oswald's wife died,
somebody as me sends them a thing with
his dead wife.
Photoshopping the ghostbusters poster.
Can you say your shitty on?
Because they all.
The whole thing was you're not.
You don't know what's funny.
So don't.
If I tell you,
you know,
there's that whole joke thief shit.
I'm like,
listen,
I,
I was there.
And also I know comedy and I know better
than you jerk off at home.
So if I tell you just know,
think I know better.
I'll just put it that way.
Maybe that's arrogant,
but I just been doing it for 20 years
and you never had the balls to get on
stage.
So I think I just know better.
They're outta here.
You're fighting with someone who's not
even here.
I started some jokes.
He fight.
No one has any idea what the fuck you're
saying,
right guys is when I defended amy,
amy and I had people like lecture and
I'm like,
don't listen,
don't presume to tell me Shit.
But.
But they're outraged.
But at the same as the social jihadis,
they all think the same reason I became
a comic.
I could do that,
but at least I did it.
You know,
if you get on stage and do it,
I'll give it to you.
But these people think they can do your
job,
but hold on a second.
In their defense,
they're looking at a film that shows
time after time that daddy made
specifically fuck her because she said,
I play a racist Republican.
The little youtube video where they took
movies fuck in the show.
Which by the way,
she doesn't write the show.
It was ridiculous and it was exactly
what the fucking sjws did to me where
they don't like you.
They think you have an agenda.
They got to destroy.
So they create this fucking,
uh,
you know,
it's like a smear job.
There were bits that were exactly the
same,
very mediocre bits that thought off,
dude,
relax,
relax.
I drank.
I Cave Man Nitros,
and you're talking to me this way.
I do.
I know this,
but you're going to run through the
wall.
And then there's a crick shaped and
print content.
So get a caveman nitrile you're,
but you're,
you're arguing against someone who's not
even here.
Why they are going at me.
That's what the problem with what you're
saying is they have evidence.
They're looking at one bit.
That's a good point.
Where if I look at the evidence and I
come to a different conclusion,
let's go with my conclusion because I
was there.
A process guy.
That's not enough.
That's not enough to convince someone,
oh,
just trust me.
You think of authoritative sheriff type
Shit.
Just trust me.
I'm not going to them.
They're coming to me,
trust me,
I'm watching this video,
I'm watching these jokes.
They're being repeated.
You're saying,
just trust me.
Chokes.
You taught.
I'm talking about sketches piece get
claimed were taken,
which is nonsense.
I was in the room.
I left the fucking cop of the room with
that shit.
That doesn't mean that you know and
watch mad TV and stop.
That doesn't mean anything because the
bits still got on the air.
So you what I'm saying like you might
not have been happening.
It doesn't matter.
That's what you have to say.
That's not what you say.
Say that.
No,
no,
no.
But that's not a job you can't,
but you can't say that.
These people don't have actual examples
of the same bits over and over again.
If they're parallel thinking,
that's fine,
but it has to be related.
But you didn't really see this,
this whole thing about this.
I'm very confused,
very confused.
The whole thing from the top down.
Look,
I don't give a shit about it.
By the way,
if they see the evidence,
right?
You have to like,
you have to be real clean,
real confrontational when you're,
when you're handling something like
that.
I won't.
First of all,
number one,
the larger issue is I'd never should be
on social media talking to any of these.
Fucks it all explaining it.
I don't owe any of you anybody
listening.
If you have a question or a judgment,
I don't owe you an explanation for shit.
I understand.
I know where the fuck you got the idea
that I do so I was wrong.
I even fucking at any answer at all
because you have people.
Hey joke thief.
Really?
That's the word about me that I'm a joke
thief from some no,
nothing and they just want to see.
I'll talk back to them to these animals
that you did steal it and you got to
explain how this was parallel.
Thank you to be many times I did.
I know,
but a lot of people haven't heard it and
you're blurting it out like that.
Someone's arguing you in the room.
I'm just pro rape.
First of all,
you guys.
Here's one thing I want to be clear.
I am probate,
a rape apologist.
I'm.
I'm pro rape,
rape and apologize for one thing.
I know Duke.
Yeah.
I'm only bringing it up.
Why?
I was getting shit.
Getting Shit for defending amy from
these.
Right.
I understand.
But it's also because you're confronting
them.
Like you're.
You're confrontational.
Yeah.
I liked.
I like being online and also it seemed
like of no consequence to me.
I'm like,
I got all this other shit going on.
I can put one your hand sit here and hit
to your dumb shit.
I was like cocky.
I understand.
But what I'm saying is from the
perspective of someone who's a standup
fan,
my hand is trembling from the Matrix.
That's crazy.
It's got some serious shit.
What the fuck is in this 270 milligrams?
Caffeine?
You probably had some coffee earlier to
see you do twitter like me where you
think it's almost like the candy crush
of words and then before you know what I
just pissed off uber or some shit.
Listen,
I'm speaking as a cave.
A nitrile caveman to you.
You're saying though is like a person
who's a fan of comedy and I am a fan of
comedy.
When I see like if I.
If I was never a standup and I saw this
all going down and I was a Kurt Metzger
Fan,
I would want Kurt Metzger to explain to
me what happened.
I would want you,
your,
your specific words on this because you
were
a writer over there,
so like as a fan,
I would want to know.
I think Kurt Metzger is a hilarious
creative comedian.
I want to know how this happened.
For you to say it defensively,
to brush it off and say that you know
better than to tell you why?
Because the way someone would come at me
immediately like who we have,
why are you speaking to me this way?
So defensive.
You already defensive.
As soon as I have somebody coming at me
a certain way,
like just your natural mode course.
Naturally,
dude,
I found out that that's one reason why
people think I'm a psycho is because
I'll react to that and no one else sees
that guy.
Yeah.
They don't got a psycho from reading
your twitter isn't enough to do is read
your tweets will hold on cause I got way
off track of what I'm trying to get to,
but just what you said,
that girl.
So,
so what I'm saying,
hey go,
maybe go to the cops and,
and don't on facebook announced to a
rape verdict.
I had this.
I'm not gonna even say her name because
he's people benefit.
Every time I fuck mentioned them.
Just go right to this idiotic blog at
night we have a back and forth.
I mock the stupid language of her
stupid.
She said asking for any details of what
happened is like reshaping the victim.
Just belief.
And I go,
so I go,
that's like I said the word rape hole in
a post mocking her language.
Okay.
She deletes her comments,
takes what I wrote and goes to these
chicks that say they're like,
look what he said about you.
Nobody cares what anyone is saying to
you.
You're the person that they've heard of.
So they only care what you say and
there's no context.
They just go.
He said rape whole.
Go ask somebody what I did that's wrong,
but they won't be able to tell you and
they'll go,
well that he said something.
Re poll is that's all they have.
Is that proven?
Do you have screenshots of the original
tweets?
A?
No,
because then people complained.
Not only could I not because I don't
delete anything that I put up.
Markers were moved.
All of that.
Facebook has removed all that because
the people I am offended so I can't even
go back and show any of the facebook
took it down.
Oh Wow.
But even if she didn't take fucking shit
off,
it doesn't matter.
Like nobody's reading her shit.
They don't give a fuck.
Which he's saying.
They're like,
oh,
the writer for Amy Schumer show is
saying,
and that's what all these people can't
believe.
It's so easy to access you and fucking
have.
You get a reaction to them and they're
amazed.
They can't believe it.
They're like,
I can talk to the fucking me and the TV
and they've built an industry around it,
so if you speak to them at all,
you're a sucker dude.
If you have any emotion about this,
you're.
I mean,
you're a fucking soccer.
Don't just don't get suckered.
That's all I'm saying.
Same thing happened to me with that,
the Black Panther stuff,
because I was just doing the reverse of
any marketing to Black Panther,
Black Panther,
Black Panther.
I was like,
finally I'm movie with black people for
black people,
so I was just like,
no white people in it pass.
Who do I relate to that really?
Because I know what you're talking
about.
Oh,
that was like the whole thing.
And then a couple of people like Jeffrey
Wright,
the actor and Don Cheadle,
they start reacting like I was serious
and I started being like,
this is sad.
Tired,
man.
I'm just
doing black mirror.
She guilt.
Did you feel like a little cool that you
got don cheadle?
Jeffrey,
did he say to you,
who's like,
how do you think it feels to me?
I'm like,
Dude,
how do you think it feels?
What?
Finish the sentence.
Sorry Matt.
I'm a little jacked up to his energy.
Got Me really good.
How would you feel watching,
you know,
growing up as a black man and watching I
only white movies and I was like,
dude,
I had Michael Jordan on my wall.
I love Karl Malone and Kung Fu movies by
way.
Still got a point.
You still got a point.
I mean,
the problem is that he didn't take it as
satire,
but he's right to.
The problem is you weren't,
you weren't being serious.
You were cracking a joke about how
people are reacting to this movie.
I love it because they're black and it's
black dude.
I'm at the worst level of being known
where like I have reached,
but I'm not famous enough for people.
Like he's a comedian.
No.
You brought that up when I got fucked.
It's like not famous enough to be like,
fine.
Famous enough to get fucked over.
Like I'm big enough where someone wants
to hunt me,
but like,
no one's like,
oh,
one bedroom in the comedian.
Some of them are like,
oh,
we must work for a college hr
departments.
By the way,
did you see the Black Panther?
No,
no,
it's good.
It's pretty fucking good though.
Annihilation.
I want to see that.
Yeah,
dude,
that's a trip.
You don't spoil it,
but it's.
I won't.
But from that [inaudible] guy,
the guy made a watch that if,
if this was such a racially uplifting
movie,
first of all,
his name,
his first name wouldn't be black.
The Black Panther.
That wouldn't be in the Black Panther
forever.
Yes.
It's like a fucking exploitation saying
shaft is like Selma.
Like when do you think they came up with
a Black Panther?
16.
By the way,
panthers are black already.
You don't need to specify that unless
you're letting me know.
The guy under the suit is black.
Well,
you know what it actually is.
It's a Jaguar.
It's the Jaguar that has spots
everywhere instead of just some spots
because Jaguars some Jack.
They're not really totally black,
like a black panthers kind of.
It's.
It's not like scientific drama.
You can't find a black jacket for they.
If you see the black ones,
you could still see like some faint
outlines of like those Jaguar little
dots and circles.
It's kind of funny.
I like David attenborough does almost
make it seem like black panthers are
more hostile.
They were like the black panthers
stocking is pray.
Well,
the snow leopard is as elusive as he is.
Grateful they're all jaguars.
Is there?
Yeah.
I think the black ones probably evolved
to be more successful hunting at night
because you can't see a god damn thing
at night in the jungle.
You don't know what black is,
I would imagine until the jungle.
No,
but I've been to the Pacific northwest.
I'm into those essentially rain forest
up there,
like there's some parts of the Pacific
northwest that are insane at night too.
Right?
Like you can't believe how dark it gets
because you don't see shit.
It's dark in at noon.
When you go through the woods,
it's dark.
Like you won't get a Tan.
It could be fucking new.
Now it can be 85 degrees out and it's
dark walking through those woods because
this canopy of leaves and super dense
tree growth,
like it's dark.
It's fucking night.
You must just hear these crazy noises.
Oh yeah man.
Like elk sound intense.
They're intense and you just hear the
sound like a dude.
Where's my point about it being dark
there?
I told about the Black Panther,
Black Panther,
the ones most likely in the jungle.
It's the same situation and the ones
that have the darkest or the less likely
to be seen and less likely or more
likely to be successful because there
attack ambush predators.
They sneak up on things and Jack,
um,
what else do they do to deer and fucking
people to that spirit is what the king
of Wakanda has come into to become the
Black Panther.
I thought it was technology.
That's actually pretty cool.
The suit is,
I think the coolest part of the movie
because it builds your forcing hit you
back like the dope.
But then his other part of his power is
they have this,
this giant they make from flowers and he
lays down and they,
I swear to God,
they give him a purple drink.
He drinks a purple drink.
Oh Jesus.
That's where he gets his other powers.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Guys watching this ad from the comic
book to the Purple Drink.
I'm like,
when they make this,
are they even because they're making it
like,
you know,
it's like guest star fucking Maya
Angelou was giving them the purple
drink,
Jewish guys.
As long as no whites were involved.
It was an exploitation comic.
It's two Jewish guys from the seventies,
like that's when it came out to put it
out.
Like finally,
you know,
let's get the origins of the Black
Panther Comic Luke Cage.
That was already out and that was a
fucking awesome.
I think that is superman.
If they were like,
what would a ghetto superman.
Almost like the old joke,
but it's fucking great.
I do.
Luke cage was cage gets to fuck.
Jessica Jones.
He.
Yeah.
Little interracial romance going on up
in that Netflix.
He has to super fucker because they're
both super fucking each other.
They're both reconstituted.
Grind,
your pelvic.
The dust.
He's fighting gentrification.
Well,
she sees him beat the fuck out of some
dudes in a bar and realizes that he's
one of them and that she's been.
She's a mutant and he's a mutant.
They get together in Buton Saxon.
Fucked up the bed.
Spoiler alert,
alert.
He can lay pipe awakened.
Looks like a guy who could lay pipe the
pipe.
If you look at them,
you go,
I bet that guy.
That guy's was sex scenes.
Was there a rumor that they really were
having sex on camera work?
It was a big one in that movie.
Angel Heart.
It's never been true time that natural
at all.
Angel Hearts.
Never true.
I think if Donald Sutherland in that
killer midget movie,
they say Mickey Work Really a bank.
Kim bessinger and nine and a half weeks,
but he did.
He,
I don't know.
I wasn't there.
I like to believe like,
I mean you're so anti religion.
You don't even want to believe rumors.
I'm not buying it is witness.
Let me tell you this.
It's like that.
And I stopped at a crack.
My back was fine.
My first,
by the way,
my first joke ever similar to that
really,
but I was like when I was 11 and my
block and Uncle Charlie,
they used to rape me everyday and he
would go,
if you ever tell anybody what I did too,
I'm going to kill your parents.
And I told everybody as your first joke,
I told everybody he never killed.
My parents are,
you know,
don't we have to deal now?
All black audiences do not enjoy that
joke at all for the fucking weird
looking for a white guy.
Did Not enter laughing at that.
They little different.
Yeah.
But,
uh,
I will say best thing,
don't we started out in those rules
because there was a crowd.
It wasn't other comics that were waiting
to get on.
Right?
It was a fucking audience.
And uh,
it,
it Kinda,
you couldn't be precious.
Yeah.
The fucking perform,
you know,
like you couldn't be one of these like
hanging in the back pocket.
Oh Dude,
you can't.
No,
you gotta perform you gotta paint.
Yeah.
And so,
and you didn't have to fucking talk
black.
We just be very confident in your own
whatever.
And crowd will go with it,
you know?
Yeah.
Just speak funny.
Just be funny.
There was a big can bring a notebook.
They see it as weakness.
They're like fucking notebook.
I see it as weakness.
Did do your homework.
Yeah.
But there's some rooms where they're
like,
oh,
that means it's like brand new.
His writing,
he's working on shit today.
The worst is when someone pretends
they're reading their notes and they do
the same bits over and over again.
Like you can't.
You just pretended.
You just looked in that book and the
name for now.
What else?
This one.
What else does that?
I'm like,
I could do your act.
Well,
it's just like people in the audience
like,
Hey,
don't don't do that.
You know,
Jay,
right.
Big J.
sure.
Were these people called them comics,
but I a comedy pause when they're not
really saying like spinning the wheels.
Trying to get some traction.
Yeah.
There's some new thing that I think
people have mistaken laughter for
support or like a pr or do you stitch
you say that to me,
they mistake it for applause.
W they've confused laughter and
applause.
You know,
it's an ideology versus like laughter's.
When someone relates applause is when
someone agrees.
Well there's too many people that are
trying for applause.
Right.
My point is like the.
You're supposed,
this is only supposed to be funny,
like when you're just trying to like say
a bunch of Shit and memorize it and say
it real fast and then to get a big
applause at the end.
Like that's.
Do you remember?
Like,
dude,
I'm not trying to change policy.
I'm starting to laugh,
but I was a kid.
I remember like Eddie Murphy,
Eddie Murphy is the biggest county in
the world and it's funny when it in the
eighties,
I remember watching stand up.
It seemed more integrated or something
like in the eighties and I swear to God
like when the evening at the Improv in a
comic strip live or on tv on like Friday
night or that's what I used to watch
stand up comedy when I was like 11 or
12.
And then the nine like death.
I remember when def jam came out and I
remember it was like,
and also racially a lot of shit seemed
more segregated and it was like,
I think the beginning of just marketing
to specific,
uh,
you know what I mean?
Like oh here's an all black show.
And,
and these had jokes on Seinfeld about
it,
like Seinfeld's market was being eaten
away with def jam.
His mother sang it to him and I didn't
think of that,
but that was the beginning.
So now it's like everybody just
specifically,
you know,
I like to hell.
It was like kind of grab bag.
When I'd watch standup it would be like,
you'd see like a Ventriloquist,
you'd see like,
you know,
Eddie,
Eddie Murphy kind of person and like
some fucking real dry person.
There'd be like La and it was more mixed
on its own.
And I,
you know,
well,
I'll tell you the solution,
I think we should do some of those,
like a Rodney dangerfield type specials
I called Rodney would do a special on
thinking of also.
But that dude,
we should do it also.
A lot of us,
uh,
you know,
if you're going to put out a special,
it takes you a couple of fucking years
or a year solid to have the material
locked down,
rock and roll.
But if you're going to do 15 minutes,
I think you're a minimum by the way.
Sometimes that's not enough.
I agree.
Great.
Nice.
I agree.
I've been doing a year and a half in
between specials and I think that's the
right amount of time.
I've got a nice juicy now two and six
months that either,
because that's shit gets hammered down
like a Samurai warrior with Louis on his
website and the fucking point is like if
there's more of those 15 minutes sets,
like you could come up with a 15 minute
set and a couple of months.
Right.
You know,
you really could,
it would be locked in.
Right?
Right.
And so if you were,
if you were doing something like that,
you could do that,
like get a prepared set over like three
or four months and have,
hey,
you know,
we're going to be filming,
we'll film some of them here,
we'll film some of them like three
months later.
So you'll know you'll have it all locked
in.
You'll know when to go do that with a
white precious.
I couldn't,
I didn't have a booking agent for the
road.
I switched managers and I was like we
can't take him until he fucking does,
uh,
does the hour.
But I'm like,
I need to work the hour out,
so I had to do it in 15 minute chunks
around the city and just do a lot of
city spots.
Oh Wow.
Which is,
I'm happy with how it came out,
but I mean it was so fucking nerve
wracking because I'm like,
I know I'm not preparing this properly.
Right,
right,
right.
Because I have to do these 15 minute
chunks of the material.
The really why didn't you catch yourself
on the road?
And like small cloud had been writing a
lot and I just like,
like I said,
I switched managers and I didn't have an
agent,
a book and I don't know how easy it was
to book you at this point.
Once I,
once I have all these people were like,
well,
you know,
I'd banished to Kramer island.
I couldn't get them to do shit for me.
I found out it's actually very easy to
go book.
Like
people actually wanted to book me
everyday.
It turns out not everybody is in this
dipshit Colt.
Uh,
the way it seems when you like online a
lot.
Well,
I just think if you can clearly explain
yourself and you can feel like,
well,
I didn't realize you don't get to see.
I used to go,
yeah,
they could do it without you.
They don't need you present to fucking
you up is whatever.
I thought,
oh.
Then they will go.
Kurt,
what did you say?
They don't.
They don't even bother with that,
but they don't care.
A lot of people just want to burn.
You just saw your media is based on this
conflict now and the patrice used to
say,
I like,
they always need us to be at war,
so they need men versus women in white
for.
They always need that going all the
time.
What district are you talking about?
People that sell that piece of shit.
Did you watch that documentary about
Gallcher and Hulk Hogan?
No,
I did not.
Oh my God,
it's on Netflix.
If you got to see it because it's
amazing.
It.
It's very heavily skewed to make you
feel bad for Gawker,
but it doesn't.
It actually makes you go,
are you shitting me?
Gawker,
like,
feel bad for cosby.
It's like,
dude,
you can't tell me that I feel bad for
fucking body think it's designed to make
you feel because they're like so whole
cogan basically because Gawker,
this is how the news media like that
despicable shit they did to Louis and
the New York Times,
which shouldn't.
The New York Times is now fat girl's
diary basically like they never
should've been allowed.
My girlfriend made that up.
I didn't make that.
That's very funny.
And he said Damn Shit.
And he's very funny,
but that's what it is.
And nonsense.
I mean like if you read the article,
there's no crime.
People just make up what?
Like what did Louis Do?
I used to ask like when that should
happen to him,
I go,
what's it Louis do wrong?
And they go,
well one time at work my boss grabbed my
tit.
I have my actual friend says to me,
I'm like,
I'm sorry I asked you what Louie did.
It's not about that.
We're going to use him as a fucking
symbol because what did he do wrong?
Ask for consent for non in like what are
you talking about?
Like why would that have to come out and
why would that be anybody's business?
It's to make him look like he's a
Weinstein for comedy.
Like Harvey Weinstein.
Right?
And by the way,
Harvey Weinstein,
that's the old casting couch,
which I'm like,
good,
get rid of that shit.
But they tried to paint Louis up a stand
up comic as if he's a producer director.
Like it is a conflict of interest.
If you have a producer come to my room,
they're like,
hey,
but another comedian at a festival,
it's reasonable.
Thank you.
Might be fucking because you're not on a
different.
The power level.
We're comedians.
We don't work for a corporation
together.
Okay,
we're an independent company and make
companies can fuck with each other.
But also that what it was is just a
weird thing that he liked to do and what
they made it out to be is like a sexual
look.
Like he's fucking a Predator and there
was no such anything.
He doesn't never surprised.
People jerk.
And now I'm going off what Louis told
me.
By the way,
I believe lily,
by the way.
Oh my God.
You're supposed to believe women.
There's a whole new thing.
What kind of an imbecile me to.
I mean,
first of all,
there's no woman on this earth who is
stupid enough to just believe women like
women know way better.
So I'm just imbecile.
People are always like,
oh,
I just that you're a woman is not
evident exhibit a,
but you do have to admit it's kind of
weird to just do like an impromptu whack
off sash.
Yeah,
it was.
It is weird unless you're talking about
sex shit back and forth like Weinstein,
but it's.
You start whacking.
You told me.
That's a point that you told me.
Tell the lies of omission.
First of all,
just,
well,
I'll just go with the article because I
don't know what trouble I'll get in
anybody's name,
but just read.
Listen,
just read the fucking article.
Okay.
There's nowhere where it says there in
Houston.
He says,
Hey,
will you watch me masturbate?
Somebody said,
no,
you didn't masturbate.
They went and said something reported or
whatever.
Supposedly,
and by the way,
the story of that that I know more
about,
it's despicable how they frame that.
The guitar comic thing,
absolutely despicable how they frame
that.
Anybody read the article?
Nobody did.
Right?
Nobody reads the read.
I read it.
He literally did nothing.
If you read John,
nevermind what I would know personally,
just read the article.
Nobody bothered to.
So all this nonsense that everybody put
out of him.
Surprised whacking off.
That's not even in there.
Okay.
Like,
like it's the first one is the guitar
duo that people thought were Garfunkel
and oates because all these young kids
can't imagine anything happening before.
Who took guitar?
Duo that Louis supposedly jerked dot.
You don't remember this now.
That's why a lot of shit hard duo that
really jerked off in front of the New
York Times was like,
dude,
I saw like some of the headlines and saw
some people commenting it online.
That's okay.
What do you just let me ask,
what do you guys think Louie did that he
got in trouble for?
I'm just,
I'm just curious.
Someone to master if he could masturbate
in front of him and then did it.
They said yes and he did it.
That's it.
Essentially asked it to people who said
no and they felt very uncomfortable and
they had to work with them.
Right.
That is the sexual harassment aspect of
it.
That's the difference.
Like if you're on a TV set,
right?
That's the only one that I went.
I'd read and went,
wow,
that's crazy.
But you were telling me something.
Yeah.
I don't know what I'm not going to.
He could say what he wants to explain
what I'm not gonna Take Shit.
That's what he told me.
No,
no need no need to.
But I'll just add to the story.
Yeah.
And,
and,
but there's a flat out agenda here.
Now what's the agenda to ruin a guy who.
Well,
I mean he's Mexican now.
I know it doesn't help his case.
This is like the Taliban,
this shit now.
Like they have to.
I bet he's a fucking Buddhist statue
that has to be exploded.
Do you understand?
We now have to take all these unfunny
people.
Okay.
That for political reasons and you can't
have evidence.
So if someone being funny that fits in
the wrong group,
there's no styling.
Kill his fucking leg.
See is like every band that ever
achieved anything,
they got to remove it.
So we're gonna throw Louis away.
Louis Ck.
We gonna throw him away with Harvey
Weinstein.
I'm sending you right now.
Jamie.
You got to put the shit up.
You're going to cry.
Yeah,
no,
you're right.
And in some ways that,
uh,
there's,
there's a Taliban going on,
but if a guy like Harvey Weinstein
existed,
you know,
there was a real fucking problem for a
lot of people for sure.
A hundred percent.
In fact,
Hollywood's fucking despicable.
Both things.
What you're saying is true.
And that's true,
but the idea that another comedian,
because back when this happened at
Aspen,
it was not a fucking.
He was a comedian who was a few more
years ahead.
Then these two girls that were also
comedians.
I've been at festivals and had sex with
This is outrageous,
but you should have done on the internet
or even industry and shit out of these
girls attractive and you were attracted
to them and you guys had consensual sex.
Is that what you're saying?
Just rape.
What the fuck did that?
Or as it's known now,
Reagan,
this guy,
88 percent of white wealth is duty,
honor,
and a privilege to get a t shirt on.
I hope that that's not really his shirt.
I hope someone,
he thinks he's a fucker and they,
they photoshop that shit out a shirt.
Maybe that's.
Maybe that's fucking despicable it.
Because first of all,
what does that have to do with me at
all?
Like let's say if I earn something for
70 percent,
I'm not in that.
When you throw those numbers up,
I want to see studies.
I want to see 88 percent.
What would that do?
Very specific number Geno.
See what do you not notice?
The fucking shit that the white,
white,
young,
white woman led fucking movement.
The social jihadis,
they're just fighting for the right to
do white men what they've always done to
black men,
which is like,
he scared me.
I want him fired.
Well,
it's also,
it's scrubbing all the meds,
so congratulations.
You get to be like an inward now.
Well,
it's also toxic femininity where it's
like the way a lot of women's instincts
are based around keeping a toddler away
from Mike light sockets,
so it's like whatever they do,
it's all good.
It's not the field instinct to do that
too as well.
Hold on,
keep going.
Keep the father away from a life socket.
All right.
Like women are more designed in general
to take care of very young children and
men are more like seven onward where
it's like if you fall down,
you hurt yourself and you learn your
lesson.
Now get out there.
Just the design that makes them do that.
How do you mean ergonomically designed
or how would they know emotionally wired
to do that where it's like women.
Once my wife first had a baby,
I really was like,
oh,
this is like.
Makes perfect sense.
That's why they have bras.
You feed a baby,
right?
Exactly.
Yeah.
Well I don't think that's a.
no,
but that's what I mean though.
It's kind of like a lot of the this sjw
mentality is that safe space.
Like if there's a group of people,
there's nothing they could possibly have
done wrong,
but protect at all costs.
Almost maternal.
Exactly.
Maternal.
I mean like this is the thing that makes
me laugh and that's the point I was
making.
You want to bother you want to mother
society,
but you,
you killed your babies.
Didn't yet have.
You shouldn't.
You don't have board us.
They didn't kill their babies.
Like you throw in the ones that got
abortions in and they're all
contaminants on the clergy.
On the levy.
Specifically the online feminist clergy,
right?
To have an abortion,
you get in the club,
you have to show you receipt card.
Lena Dunham is the classic because I
feel bad for her.
It's like she's like,
I just want to be good in my church.
I'm the guy who worked for me didn't
commit rape.
Oh,
I'm sorry he did this.
Communism.
This isn't harmless.
The body's stack like the number one
death of the 20th century was your own
government.
My own.
Wait,
wait,
who you talking to me?
Who's me?
You people and us like human government
is 60 million Russians,
a 60 million Chinese and he got Hitler.
He got like that.
Are we in of so high?
Are we in Russia?
What do you mean by that?
When you say your own government
inclusivity,
all that stuff,
it all leads to like the way to make a
forest equal is with an ax.
That's it.
And the tallest nail gets hammered down
like these are all and we're starting to
enter like a upside down world and the
left or the right wing tyranny is more
sexy.
That's why you hear about Hitler because
he's an evil guy,
but at least he had like great boots and
shit.
But like the styling is a bean counter.
That's why he has way bigger death cap.
We never hear about it because he's just
like,
let them starve.
We thought stolen.
I always would always read about Stalin
was he was Kinda like a meathead and
Lenin was the intellectual install,
like the muscle that kind of crept up,
but he was just like a fucking,
you know,
am I wrong in that?
That's what I know of.
Lenin was a little bit of both.
He was in.
He was an ideologue.
Did you read the Shit of classified
when?
Uh,
uh,
from Russia.
That stuff's donald had them working on.
No,
he wanted to make these gorilla human
hybrid soldiers.
This is when they couldn't say no to
Stalin like the later years where
whatever he said,
God,
okay,
Stalin.
He goes,
make gorilla soldiers that don't have to
eat very much.
And then they're like,
well,
gorilla is actually eat all day.
It might not be,
but don't let the soldiers that don't
have man,
half gorilla soldiers so that they
wouldn't have to eat a lot.
I mean,
it's crazy.
This shit.
Well,
if you stop clapping first he killed you
and there's this one time where there's
nine straight minutes of everyone
clapping and like,
because they knew the people knew that
the first one is stop is going to die
and someone finally passed out and they
killed them yet because that's how far
compliance goes.
It's just they keep getting you to
comply,
comply.
And that's,
that's a question I want to know about
guns and abortion.
It's like what?
Where's the line?
Because if you can't determine it,
someone's when like you were saying like
when do you think it's okay or not okay
to have an abortion?
You wait is a good fucking one day
before too.
On both sides.
There's an unreasonable argument on both
sides.
They're not willing to give it up at
all.
Right?
On both sides.
You know,
it's funny man,
because like I,
like I said I don't care about all your
kids.
However,
I don't get,
I don't get aggressive opening statement
but I don't get that.
Having been said,
I don't get why the only thing we can do
is nothing.
Like they're like,
I'm very sorry.
There's absolutely nothing that can help
them.
But if you're a gun,
a gun lover or just
shoot her or know anything about guns
and someone says air 15 and they don't
realize that a 10 is the same gun except
with bigger bullets or an sks or are
that automatic guns are already illegal
and they want to like band something
they don't understand.
Like there is no such thing as an
assault rifle.
That doesn't make any sense.
You,
you call it an assault rifle.
You noise with your mouth.
Who Cares?
We'll do.
The point is there's guns that didn't
shoot a bunch of people really easy
with.
You have ar 50.
They know what's going on.
Is it guns killing people like all this
other stuff is nonsense and people get
lost up in the minutia of it.
Like you know,
they don't know the names.
What's a bump stock do,
do you think?
Like I was in South Dakota not long ago
and the dude I was hanging out with like
a doomsday prepper.
Right?
He's a guy that worked at a club but
he's like a nice guy.
The same canned peaches.
So corny was like,
don't call me that guy man bro.
How many cans are gonna need?
Thirty years worth.
Shit doesn't go bad bro.
Good pitches are good when they're
fucking canned peaches.
Like in someone's basement.
How long has that shit last a while.
Like years does it last year's.
Yeah.
They're designed for the apocalypse.
There's like 50 shit.
That's what they'll do.
They can cause he was doing it.
Not yet.
I swear to God told me he's not.
He's a Christian,
but he's not a good Christian.
Oh,
so what do you do wrong?
I didn't.
I didn't pry,
but he.
He's not going.
He's not going up in the first like
pickup.
Oh,
he'll have to like the thing about the
Christian says you could always even on
the fucking buzzer on the Buzzer,
except Jesus and you're not during.
Not during the great tribulation that he
was planning to live through which the
stockpiles before it was going to have
to live through that and then get caught
up in the second pickup.
He won't be the disappearing out of his
clothes guy.
The problem with where both of us live,
you and I is if the shit does hit the
fan,
we're kind of far,
far too many people,
too many people in Manhattan.
Too many people in here.
It ain't good.
This is no Bueno.
I did carry that with the winter but.
But yeah,
like a winter look,
if you don't have laws you're going to
go out and you could whack 30 fucking
deer and stack those fuckers up in your
garage.
Like there's deer all over the place up
there.
You are going to have fresh water
everywhere with your car and not even
wanting to do well.
They,
some places they allow you to pick that
deer up and take it home and eat it.
Like after you hit it with your car they
should for sure.
But the thing is that they were saying
like,
what if people are targeting the deer?
Like,
well what could you do?
How much it costs the damage that a deer
does your fucking car.
Like they destroy your car.
Thousands of dollars of damage.
Who the fuck is going to do that?
And that's a lot of driving for a deer
that you could buy a tag for,
for like 50 bucks and kill with like a
knife,
like deer in my yard.
Literally just be eating my flowers and
just look at me like bitch,
you know,
this is the village.
And I'm like,
dude,
I lived in boulder when you are,
when you get out,
like in the town of Boulder,
you'll see a fucking giant mule deer
sitting on the side of the road eating
big ass book,
giant antlers just sitting there and you
can get out of the car and go,
motherfucker are you for real?
And this thing would just be looking at
you just eating there.
So convinced that no one's going to eat
them.
They just wander through the city.
It's amazing.
It's fucking amazing.
I just,
I was just in Denver,
boulder is about our outside maybe less,
maybe a little less than an hour.
It's a cool little mountain community.
Very,
very quiet.
I love it.
To the best town.
They just give you an egg a day.
It was hilarious.
I had not seen like a,
the guy with like the oakleys on top of
his fucking son.
Like,
like whoa.
The homeless white kids with the dog and
Shit I haven't seen in awhile.
That is a juicy bag in Denver.
No,
outside was like the mountain I was in
under the.
So yeah,
one of those around mountain,
like a South Park town.
Yeah,
there's,
that's where evergreen is.
Evergreen is where they grew up.
Training that Parker grew up in
evergreen.
Evergreen is fucking amazing.
It's amazing.
Just like outside of Denver,
like just outside evergreen has a
population of elk that's 100 strong to
walk through the middle of the fucking
city.
A buddy of mine lives there.
My friend Brian called.
We put a bunch of videos on his,
uh,
his uh,
instagram is instagram is the gritty
bowman or it might be gritty bowman.
He's got a podcast called degrees.
All of those things.
Even like a,
like a horse on the west banks or like a
life worth,
but like look like a fucking dinosaur to
you if you've been in city long enough,
you're like,
I can't believe is a giant fucking
animal looking at me.
I mean,
that's a look at that.
That looks prehistoric.
Yeah,
those are elk.
That's great.
I don't know who that gentleman,
his buddies that got one of those,
but he's got some videos on his
instagram somewhere of his town.
He lives in evergreen,
I believe in,
and these gigantic fucking deer just
walking through his yard.
Well,
curious.
It's on his facebook.
It says his two loves or bowhunting and
Barack Obama.
What are the odds this horn size have to
do with hammer size?
Oh yeah,
for sure.
Like hammers on them.
The bigger the elk,
the bigger the antlers.
The older.
If they keep it,
like she's trying to get rid of it.
She is in her yard.
They just wander into people's yards and
that's a female,
but that's probably a 300 pound animal
and an animal.
You know what,
man?
I'm A.
I'm a little because I love shooting,
but I'm.
I'm like,
I think that'd be a little queasy.
I just don't want to clean my like
that's what I want to.
You get used to it.
It's not even fishing.
I never did.
It's a different thing.
That fishing.
It's way more intimate.
Yeah.
Fishing,
like I don't do any remoting into your
blooded now.
I don't feel any remorse when I kill a
fish.
Hey,
weird.
By the way,
the Donner party die in Colorado.
They were.
No,
they were in.
Why wasn't it the Sierra Nevadas?
Is that what they done?
Drove through there on the way back.
He doesn't remember how long it was.
Nevada.
The Donner Party?
Yeah.
How long before you eat a guy?
Me None.
I mean no chance to look.
What kind of fucking life is this going
to be?
Am I hold on,
am I getting the story wrong?
They got trapped in the snow.
It had to eat each other,
meet each other out.
All winter.
Each other's is isn't true.
This is where father and son,
mother and daughter eating each other,
print it online and it'll be so.
It was a tragedy at any correction of it
will be ignored each other out for
months.
The entire winter months they just had
our standing 69 constant just staring at
each other.
The Bush size back then to eat,
throw.
Oh Man.
Huge.
It's chaos.
There's some dicks.
It wouldn't make it through that Bush.
Yeah,
probably a lot of them.
Just like you can have a four or five,
eight Bush.
Especially like super measuring the
butch,
like I got a five inch.
He's at beards,
they have these long ass beards and the
longer the beard,
the more desirable that Turkey is.
Balls on their nose.
Is a beard on.
No,
no,
no.
Down here it grows like a write off of
like their neck area,
like where the kits,
the chest.
It's this long thing that gets called a
Turkey beard.
Yeah.
They're like dinosaurs,
cock and balls on.
They got all that stuff,
but I forget what that's called.
It's all fucked up too.
Yeah.
What does that shit.
The red stuff like gristle or when you
see a rooster rooster's what did you
call the fucking red thing?
Never know man.
I have no idea what they call the red
thing.
I have no reason to know that.
Yeah,
put Turkeys will fuck you up too.
Fuck you.
They're aggressive in some places.
I got to do a joke about that and it
sounds like I have this personal issue
with Turkeys when I play,
because I saw a pbs thing about Turkeys.
They will never be a friend.
A Turkey.
Did you see where the guy lived with
Turkeys?
No,
he fucking.
My life is a Turkey.
If you can identify as a Turkey,
is that what was going on?
He was with them for when they hatch.
They would follow him around the second
they hit puberty.
They turn into prehistoric dinosaur.
Vicious fucking.
They're gone.
Except like lizards favorite.
Stayed with them.
Turkey boy.
His favorite Turkey.
Okay.
Yeah.
And then one day there by a log.
And this is what to me,
if you should watch this as soon as
possible.
I hope I'm not remembering this wrong
highlight,
but I swear to God.
So Turkey boy,
one day just fucking turned on him and
attack him and went for his eye.
They go for your eyes.
Favorite Turkey.
Turkey boy.
Who was like,
I thought that was going to be an in
Turkey.
Boy wouldn't have no,
he went for his eyes and a state show
reenactment with uh,
another like,
it's like an after Turkey.
I don't know how they did it was in the
union because Turkey is just go for your
fucking eyes.
Yeah.
You don't need a lot of training and
they visit Turkey.
But my joke is,
because you know as a live Turkey is
a huge size of Kat Williams and it's
like,
and it's like,
and his buddies probably didn't get very
good.
They probably weren't too compassionate
when they're like,
what?
Why did he turn on me?
Like I shouldn't trust the Turkey.
And they're like,
fucking Turkey,
man.
Well you think about a chicken.
Chicken's a ruthless.
And then now think about a Turkey.
Turkey's are giant chickens when they
haven't been bread and all the trees
where my grandfather lived in Florida
before he died,
there was all these feral cats and
chickens on their property and we feed
them.
He put this big feeder out.
It was amazing how they formed a little
society because it will be a kitten or
cat,
a chicken catcher.
They didn't have any interaction.
They just all came and ate the food.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
I mean you're watching it.
That's just crazy.
And they were listening to the cast and
kill the little chickens.
Not even at all.
A little bit crazy.
There's just plenty of food that's super
rare that a feral cat can keep it
together.
I would have never thought that until I
was watching them do it.
It was adorable.
You don't see the numbers.
Disney movie.
See the numbers of birds that feral cats
killed in America every year.
It's in the billions.
Do we need them to do it?
No.
I probably,
you know,
when you think about it,
we probably do because in Israel they're
like rats.
My,
uh,
my ex Israeli,
she told me they're like cats or not.
Same with Egypt.
I lost a chicken to a coyote last night.
I had to uh,
finish the chicken off with my chickens.
I had a,
we had a coyote in the yard,
caught it in the yard by the chickens
were out.
What do you walked up on the top of the
chicken coop and jumped over and it
chased a couple oven bit.
One of them was knock,
some feathers loose,
but one of them it actually got and
killed.
It's wild.
There's coyotes here.
Oh Dude,
it's,
it's a crazy thing to be around man.
To watch that through New York too,
by the way.
Jump the wash.
The thing jumped to the roof of this
chicken coop,
like it was nothing.
I'm talking about a six foot jump and
it's so elegant.
It's kind of beautiful and watch the way
they did it.
It was a bummer that had killed a
chicken and I had a scare it off and now
we know that they're targeting the
chickens because it's happened more than
once.
Last time it happened was like two years
ago though.
One of them keep coming back to all 10
wants to coyotes.
A Fisher cat and a raccoon.
I believe.
So.
You guys were chicken farmers.
Is that understood?
You get an egg a day per hand?
Yeah.
No,
not always,
but close in the winter.
Want to get all the exit one's price,
bro.
Dude,
we could have 20 eggs right now if I cut
this.
Come on.
Fuck this chicken.
Yeah.
I don't feel bad about killing chickens.
It's like don't kill him.
But uh,
their pets to me,
I don't eat them.
That's the kind of smart aren't the
roosters around.
Like I got videos of them follow me
around because I give him treats.
So I walk around the backyard and it's
like I'm the fucking Pied Piper of
chickens.
Like it's kind of hilarious.
Do you have any of me carrying my
daughter's bunny walk in and all these
chicks are follow me.
I'm like a mini beastmaster like away
games.
Tell how bad is how smell.
Bravo channel you feed them.
Especially when I give them these little
worm treats.
There's these dried mealworms.
They fucking love these things.
They go crazy for them so I can.
That's how I get them back into their
chicken coop.
They were pretty big chicken coop,
but when they wanted or the yard and I
want to get them back.
I take their,
their worms and shake them.
Chow.
They come running to me and then I give
him a little treat every time so that
they know that every time I shaky,
shaky,
shaky.
It's time for a treat.
And they all there so carnivorous.
They,
you've never seen as something attack
worms with the kind of passion and vigor
that the chicken suit?
No,
I'd say I've seen it.
It's terrifying.
They'll eat chicken.
You see?
Um,
uh,
a shit.
Oh,
fighting roosters and I went to Hawaii
by the way,
roosters are way different than hence
no,
no rape the shit out of anybody.
And they also just,
I mean,
they're fucking crazy about to say same
thing.
I'm like,
Oh,
you have a different point than me in
Hawaii there had been a hurricane and
like these people had chickens like
that,
that it got it.
So on the street corners,
it made me laugh.
It would look like a pimp.
It'd be like one rooster and then like a
bunch of hens behind him and he would
just go around the corner and he was a
wild chasing Hawaii every quarter.
Just see roosters.
Wow.
Wild chicken.
But uh,
I keep forgetting why you brought this
up.
Maybe because I've been in Hawaii.
Yeah,
well rapey roosters,
bird the fight,
right?
Because you know,
it's like when they go to rescue the
fighting roosters,
I didn't know they just killed them
because that's all they want to do is
fight.
So they just fucking,
if they bust one of those rings up,
they just put the route,
like just let him fucking fight.
If that's what they're into,
you know,
it doesn't seem.
They get them adopted or something.
They just fucking place.
They were bred for it.
There's championship bloodline's like
there's a reason why these things do it.
What does this say?
If that's what Jesus did and I would say
let them do it,
but it's showing us wild chickens in
Walmart in one of these fucking shopping
cart return bar things and they're
covered with chickens.
This is crazy.
Why he hadn't quite.
That's nuts,
man.
There's wild chickens now.
What's the word on killing those?
Can you.
If you want some chicken soup and you'll
have a lot of money,
are you allowed to just whack one of
those?
I hope so.
Look,
look at all of them.
That's crazy.
They don't have any predators.
See,
Hawaii is a really bananas place when it
comes to wildlife
because they used to have these burdens
called noni birds and they were.
They were so docile people.
The native just picked them up and
crack.
I mean like Dodo birds are like that
when exchanges datum extinct because
these birds had no fear.
Right?
That's interesting over there.
But they didn't bring
predators for it,
so they have like these wild pigs and
just running around everywhere.
They have to hunt them down.
Pigs are very.
Because we're on pigs,
like in South America,
that was not,
not just disease,
but the case was brought pigs that
fucked up the crops.
The native fucks.
Everything up.
Pigs turn.
You must watch all that pig shit.
Right?
They turned wild and get tusks.
Inheriting what Jamie pulled up here,
last major contributor to the key
chicken population is always a shocker
even to people who have lived here all
their lives.
[inaudible] wild jungle fowl is
protected under state law.
Like all birds of Hawaii.
The Moa is protected as an important of
nature.
Oh God.
That's a terrible idea because that
means nothing's going to eat them.
So if nothing's going to eat them,
they don't have any predators.
That means to get disease.
Not.
Yeah,
you can have abortions up until 40 weeks
out there too,
but you can't touch the chickens if you
have food for them.
They're just going to keep breeding the.
The real question is do you have food
for them?
Because if there's just a law of nature,
if there's no predators,
their population is going to match the
food supply.
Oh yeah.
Was awesome.
Did you go secret beach that no one's
supposed to know about,
but it's on every map.
Not even gas stations do that.
Oh,
wait a minute.
Which ones?
No,
I've never been to Hawaii.
I've been to a waa.
Waa.
Who is Hawaii?
Hawaii.
Hawaii is where Lulu I went and did that
in Nepali coast tour that,
that uh,
Marin told me that it,
but he took a helicopter.
But I stand up in Hawaii.
No,
my cousin got married.
She looks impossible to deny.
It's really like a rich kid that like
drops out.
You threw it in Hawaii.
Like,
let's see,
you're from here and you're some rich
kid or like sort of Williamsburg or
whatever.
That's Hawaii because you got to be
rich.
The houses,
I guess,
uh,
it's expensive because the upkeep,
because the houses degrades.
The white people live in.
There are a lot of cultural
appropriation.
Yeah.
South Park had a funny thing about it.
But look,
if you go there,
you rent a house,
don't go to a resort,
but also like the natives and it is the
only place I ever go wrong.
I'm like,
you know,
I feel like a white guilt like Alaska.
I was like,
there's no way this was better before we
got here.
Why I felt like,
Oh,
I hope you didn't fuck this up.
You know,
because it's,
I mean,
I couldn't believe it was.
I found out later because drove a
witness.
Publications have like these paradise,
you know,
would you like to live in a place like
this?
And uh,
I found out later they were based on in
Hawaii where I went because I got there
at night and so I didn't know what it
looked like.
And I woke up the morning and it looked
like the shit that I was told after
Armageddon,
God will never.
So I'm like,
what?
It looked like fucking jurassic park is
crazy.
Like these birds flying.
And we were like on a cliff.
It was crazy.
Dude.
It's so pretty.
Our falls are a helicopter through it.
It's fucking insanity.
Tell you something.
Five days is plenty.
I was doing this.
I'm like,
listen,
I have plans in life.
Like if she was dead,
it'll come live here.
There's no.
But that's where you go if you like,
I'm going to drop out of society.
There's no technology.
I used to live in key west playing piano
for tips when I literally was like,
I got.
It was like the island is.
No,
you know,
I'm like,
if I don't even know this hotel
California for me baby.
Yeah,
right.
It's like 23 just playing piano for tips
and it was just everything was going.
So it was the same deal every day,
ladies.
No,
no.
Cigarette breath.
I'm here to escape my life.
Forty two years old.
Still Kinda hot.
It was too humid.
It was a lot of movement.
But that's true,
right?
Hangs in real good.
You see a lot of really hot 50 year
olds.
That's true.
Florida,
I don't know why.
Yeah,
you got to moisturize moisture.
Yeah.
Cause dryness does fuck up your scamming
you.
It seemed different to like less house.
Like where I live is so dry.
Like I'm 21 years old right now.
I made you can really fast.
Why is it's one of those places where
you're like,
wow,
how is this America?
We flew five hours across the ocean to
get here.
This is America,
right?
I think if you just.
If I had lived there,
it would eventually become a kind of
beautiful hell am I only joy would be
showing visitors around and crystal
meth.
What if.
Which would if somebody offered you a
residency at the four seasons in Maui
and it was serious cash,
what does that mean?
Kurt Metzger doing standup every
weekend?
People come down there.
I don't know.
Let's do a three year contract.
Kurt,
what do you think?
Three years.
Okay.
Yeah.
You would do like basically what
[inaudible] does some serious gender.
You get three years for three years.
I think that's more palatable than a job
at snl.
Comedy's tough in Hawaii though because
there's no pain.
Dude.
I said the same thing.
In fact,
I don't know if you know Russman,
eve?
No.
Okay.
He's a funny kind of way,
but he.
I know the name.
I got myself on laid at this wedding.
It was like my cousin who is about to
get married,
picture and put,
but you the.
They had a joke about dolphins blow
hole.
He goes,
yeah.
don't fuck.
He goes,
I'm guys,
don't fuck them in that hole.
But if you do,
hold on,
you got a 69 to this girl had her.
I mean it was like,
it was already touching my shoulder and
shit.
Well,
and I said that at her hand,
shot off it because I didn't know they
have to worship dolphins is a god there.
There is.
It's like a.
it's like it tells jokes.
Funny Joke.
They came,
they got mad,
she got mad because it's like,
it's like the ultimate.
If you're a girl that makes her own
jewelry,
best could let you know with colorful
seashells.
So you've got these seashells,
that aura gemstone.
They're like these rainbow shells that
they're the only show you can insure.
Lloyd's of London,
which island was young.
Hawaii.
But there I brought,
I got my girl,
my ex at the time I got brody some
necklace.
I mean,
you know,
I brought back all this coffee,
you spend all this money,
they're like,
you come back and let this shit you
can't wear in society.
This is some fucking handbags.
Like what the fuck is what?
It's also,
there's a terrible thing if you're
trapped on an island with a bunch of
lamers,
like they could try to get you to be
lame.
Like if you've got a bunch of boring
people and you're stuck thinking that
show last bar.
It's all about locals and the locals are
cool,
right?
If you get lucky and get a bunch of cool
locals,
that must be awesome.
But if your locals are all dip shits,
you gotTa Fund,
there's a bunch of local celebrities
were like,
usually it's a fat guy that could sing.
He's
real cocky and like that's your Hawaiian
guy,
but it's like they know I'm going,
guy comes in and does all these covers
are like four non blondes.
Like,
Hey Jesus.
I say,
Hey,
can I sing that?
And I'm like,
Hey,
hey,
good job man.
I was like,
okay.
I like,
you know,
I'm just being nice to him that you're
dumb cover act like,
you know,
this years ago I remember,
Oh my God,
it's coffee for guy's going to die at
50.
You're pretty cocky if you're being
really negative about this guy,
they're all either in the most
beautifully.
The engineer's from premier atheists,
right?
Or 800 pounds with the Samoan,
the engineer per this incredible.
Because my inlaws are a great
description of like the perfect body.
No,
just dudes are fucking like,
because you know Joe was witnesses in
women's do.
It does very well in Ireland.
Places with Pacific islander,
his job,
his witnesses and Mormons do very well.
That's why Brigham Young University has
ways big Samoan and fucking backwards.
Yeah.
And they have big family,
big families naturally.
So it just lends itself to there,
you know.
And uh,
that's my favorite call even though the
one of the most preposterous ones in
terms of like what their background
origin story is.
When you find out about Joseph Smith
being 14 and 18,
20 and he writes about golden tablets
that contained the last work of Jesus.
And only you could read him because he
had a seer stone.
I like that because it's such a great be
the first person to say this,
but the only reason you're like,
fuck that.
It's because it's like two recently,
well not a few years to it.
No one could debate it.
Well sword up,
but a 14 year old.
He was 14.
Oh,
I didn't know that.
When I think of Biggie and Tupac,
I'm like,
they like 23.
They were kids.
Well all 14 year olds are full of Shit.
They're practicing what they can get
away with.
They make mistakes,
but he's like high level full of Shit.
Well he wasn't just high level full of
Shit.
He was probably like a compulsive liar.
Probably pathological.
And it was ultimately a con man.
I mean that's what he became.
He was the people usually you don't
realize these comments like how did they
do?
It's like people are so complicit in
that and there's people addicted to that
bullshit being conned.
And they will ben Franklin quote write
about like quacks.
Patients are the biggest liars or some
shit like they.
It's such a bizarre drug dealer
situation.
The con man and Connie,
a lot of times there's this drug
thereafter,
and I know I know people like
compulsively have to be conned or sold
or leased with psychics and people who
love psychics.
They will convince themselves.
They'll convince themselves that this
person has some secret information about
them and they were so dad.
Mike Epps has a great job.
Mike epps has never faded,
underrated,
or the silver suit.
He's gone on and I haven't seen it.
No,
that's why the best hours.
He's a funny dude.
That dude that makes me actually.
Yeah,
it's one
of the.
Say the name again,
like underrated.
Never faded or some shit.
He's in Detroit,
but I'm like old ladies.
I'm like,
uh,
uh.
Let me pass the collection plate around
too many times old ladies break breakout
of catching the spirit like they're
like,
they already done.
Sent that paid three times.
Now that's bullshit.
I got to see.
I can't do it,
but he was always talking about like,
these are old ladies that go to church.
I know that old lady,
like if they go to church and they want
to pay money to the Jesus man and,
but even they know what this is a little
bit,
you know,
the guy's not doing his end of conning
them the right way.
They.
They're not completely helpless.
They like,
oh,
this is a bullshit.
They want that Marjoe that documentaries
about that.
That guy that Steve Martin made his a
preacher,
a leap of faith is based on that and the
dude who doesn't believe in God and he's
making his move based on Mick Jagger and
he's like,
they want them to hit note.
He's getting resentful because they
wanted to be a hack and he wants to try
out new stuff and they don't know.
That's how I took it.
If you watch,
it's very interesting.
I'm fascinated by TV preachers.
Oh yeah,
man.
I think they're amazing.
I mean,
some of them are so blatantly
ridiculous.
Did you ever see the ones that were put
together?
The Jim Baker,
who was the dude who made a bunch of
ducks friend,
makes a bunch of really funny videos
with Jim Baker using all of that
survival stuff.
He had just had incredible edits of real
moments with Jim Breaker talking about
his survival food and like how you can
use the buckets of survival food as like
a bottom of a table.
So you eat there and you lift it up and
the survival food,
that's where you store it is survival
cit.
That is,
you have people sitting on it like it
makes a good chair.
You're sitting on a chair fill with
survival sales video.
This video,
there's this guy put together.
It's fucking hilarious because it's all
like some of the most ridiculous things
that he says spliced together because
they kind of run out by.
Um,
yeah,
because of Jessica Hahn.
Well,
no,
I know,
but he goes,
set up.
It was a power grab.
Maybe it's in the eyes of Tammy Faye.
That documentary because they were,
they were con artists that also got
conned by that fucking guy who was from
the faith coalition or something.
It's a,
I lived down south that will not live in
Statesville,
North Carolina at that time when he was
big.
That's not like this is south.
There's like a certain melody to get
people to say like,
yeah,
like Farah Khan does it.
Where is that going to America?
America sucks.
Basta.
Yeah.
Well I,
I don't know how you're different now.
Now he's all bald.
What does that mean?
Why does saying Boston?
Italian,
they speaking in tongues and Italian.
He's got a bunch of videos on Jim Baker.
He's got a ton of videos on him.
I think he might homeboy my test,
but he puts together these ridiculous
edits of the Jim Baker show.
Preparedness and survival.
The.
Here it is.
This is like is
good.
I love when rednecks adopt Hebrew shit.
Like it's their shit.
Oh yeah.
I'm going to blow his chauffer now and
like,
like dude,
my religion,
we had all these words.
We didn't know what to say.
And then I dated a girl who spoke Hebrew
and didn't understand how off all my
pronunciations were of everything.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
So you're was.
Yours was straight from the Jehovah's
Witnesses.
I had a my book of Bible stories where
guys reading the tape,
so I pronounce these words.
It just how Americans pronounce,
you know,
Bible words.
The Shit's not free for us.
It's for the people that likes to say
who pronounces it.
Right.
I mean there's a lot of these words.
Well,
Hebrew though that they recreated it
when the nation.
Israel is kind of interesting.
They had to re re.
It was like a lost language that had to
be rebuilt.
Rebuilt it from the ground up.
Well,
I guess not from the ground up.
I don't know.
They had to put it there,
but it now it's a fluently spoken
language and it was like dead for
awhile.
There's two different Hebrews,
right?
There's ancient Hebrew.
It's different,
right?
I guess.
Yeah.
Ancient Hebrew with the letters are also
a numbers.
Numbers in ancient Hebrew were weird.
Yeah.
I don't think they use it anymore,
but that's like the original Bible.
I mean like how many people use ancient
Hebrew teak cv can find a video.
What ancient Hebrew sounds like?
Well,
my ex's parents are Hebrew scholars,
so they went to that shit.
I want to hear what it sounds like.
Like keep.
It sounds like phlegm noises.
It all sounds like a weird fucking sad.
There's an example of that,
about that sound.
It's just a,
you know,
but I mean think about it like Chinese.
It's a very specific sound.
German,
Italian.
Have you been to China?
I've never been to China,
but Japan though.
It's worth going.
It's a lot like she sounds.
Let me hear that Shit.
Me,
aerosmith,
Macbeth.
I will.
That sounds like a little heme.
Like wow.
Little crazy.
It looks like Lord of the Rings Elf.
Elf language doesn't.
Ancient languages like Sanskrit looks so
crazy.
Know like if this was like on a
spaceship,
you would think would like that.
Look at that.
If that was on a spaceship etched into
the side of the spaceship,
you'd be like,
Holy Shit.
It's a fucking alien language.
I mean,
I don't know what any of those things
are.
I don't know what one of those numbers
is.
I don't know what the fuck those words
are.
Those letters.
That's an alien language.
That's,
to me almost more alien than a lot of
Asian languages.
That looks crazy.
Well,
that's,
that's a reason to kind of doubt that
somebody translating it,
right?
It's just like,
oh,
you looked at that jibberish and you saw
well,
scholars,
you know,
the whole thing with that is that these
ancient,
ancient languages,
like all these stories came from these
ancient languages.
Like if you go way,
way,
way back.
Shit.
So Mer,
like the epic of Gilgamesh.
There's all these Noah's Ark
similarities.
There's a lot of stuff and all these
ancient stories,
that's all probably points to some real
shit that happened for sure.
It along the way.
Just like what you're talking about with
social justice warriors and how they
behave like it's a religion.
There's like a natural compulsion for
people to be on a group and have that
group have a very clear ideology the way
up to atheism if they want it because
that's like almost a luxury I think.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
And I don't know how to just,
uh,
about thinking what I will say the DMT
shape.
Uh,
I did get like more of a,
Oh yeah,
there's more than,
oh,
there's something else there and it's
crazy because when know I read about
that shit in high school.
I read some more about that guy that,
that is the big DMT guy.
Terence Mckenna.
Yeah,
because I think he projects a lot of his
own horseshit into it,
but that stuff that Karen does or the
agenda,
just let me tell you when I,
I never felt a thing that felt so much,
like not making me hallucinate,
but like he was taking away a
hallucination and that is such,
there's something so terrifying about
that.
But it also like,
wow,
that's great.
Like you just,
you feel like there has to be just based
on the shit you would say.
Even if it's just shaking your head,
you're like,
why would that even be in my head?
It's entirely possible that whatever the
fuck consciousness is can pass from this
stage into another stage.
And the only reason why I would hesitate
to say that's exactly what happens is
because there's no proof one way or
another,
but it's the pineal gland.
Shit is not proven.
They don't know that dmt comes the
cottonwood research foundation.
They did a series of tests with rats and
they proved that live rats have a dmt
produced by the pineal gland.
It doesn't necessarily mean that humans
do too,
but they're pretty sure they did.
You like to know that your,
your lungs producer and your liver
produces it.
That's a fact.
Yeah.
So your body's producing dmt 100
percent.
Did you know that?
Or did you like,
uh,
like those hp lovecraft kind of horror
stories.
I love those.
And there's a movie made out of one of
them.
It's all about his pineal gland.
He's taking something,
mixes pineal gland swelling up.
Which one is that?
Movies on stars.
The guy from reanimator.
It's not,
it's not reanimator I'm feeling it now.
I kind of remember what you're talking
about.
I'll tell you that creepy.
The DNP has a creepy creepy because I
was totally worth doing.
But the thing that's,
you know,
whatever people say they meet entities,
right?
But I don't know if that shit is meeting
entity,
but I'll tell you the thing that just
sticks with me that I'm like,
how in the fuck is that possible is the
shapes that you,
that I could say I was well aware that
they were a bit more than three
dimensional shapes and it's so crazy to
look at that and perceive it.
And I'm like,
how on earth could I perceive this
shape?
And when I came and you can't break,
come back with it.
Like,
you know,
you see it though.
And someone's like,
have you ever seen Alex grades aren't
awesome?
No.
You haven't seen it.
Pull up Alex Gray.
He's a psychedelic artists.
I mean all of this stuff is basically
just to mean based art because
sometimes.
Oh No,
no,
no.
He's brilliant.
His stuff's something.
If it's fucking amazing for two,
one of them,
but let.
Yeah,
he draws a,
the covers for tool albums.
There's a ton of like that one.
That one specific DMT DMT.
That is dmt.
That is hardcore dmt.
Hardcore dmt.
When you do Dmt,
you see that and you see that in a way
where it's so much more spectacular than
any.
Anything you ever seen.
Normal consciousness is your body.
They're like,
are you saying you're not thinking of
your.
You're.
You look around you.
You're stupid.
If you're opening your eyes.
Here's what's crazy because you can
sort.
If you close your eyes,
it's like they're open somewhere else
and then you open your eyes.
You see reality overlaid over to tell me
this can influence the Egyptians.
Click on the one your cursors on.
Tell me that didn't influence the
Egyptians.
What?
This painting or this,
this,
these kind of trips.
Images.
DMT.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
There was.
One of the things that John Anthony West
did was he was going over that temple in
the temple and man is one of the
structures.
It's in,
in Egypt and it,
it shows different parts of it are
supposed to represent different
corridors of the body,
like different Chakras of the body and
that there was some evidence that the
eye of horus is really the pineal gland
and that's what that.
That symbol is like.
See if Google,
a pineal gland,
eye of Horus,
they think that they're.
They're so similar in the way they're
shaped.
It's entirely possible that that's what.
That's a very alternative thing,
but look how it looks,
how the thing looks on the right,
the actual pineal gland,
and look at the eye and the left.
Well,
yeah,
see that wing off the side and the way
it drops down right from the eyeball.
Boy,
that's fucking similar.
It's entirely possible that they figured
that out somewhere along the line that
through yoga breathing methods or some
sort of psychedelic drugs,
they found that they were achieving a
hallucinogenic state and they were able
to somehow or another isolate where that
state is being initiated and if it's
being initiated in dodgy,
honestly by your body,
like through psychedelic breathing.
That's probably where it's being
produced.
Well,
I don't want to sound like Schumer
defender,
but that look,
coincidentally parallel thought certain
patterns over and over again that,
but that pattern is pretty fucking
close.
You might be right,
it might be coincidental,
but the fact that it dropped a straight
line drops down right before the.
I showed again,
straight line drops down right below the
eye and the left Egypt.
That's the thing they did.
They did surgery on people in Egypt,
right?
First of all,
I thought Egypt thought the mind was in
the heart and that's why they pulled the
useless brain out through the nose.
When they mummified you like you're
telling me what their intent.
You know what I mean?
Like embalming techniques we have,
but that doesn't mean that in respect to
brain kept.
No,
they didn't look well.
I'm looking at it.
They didn't
know everything about the human body.
The way they attach significance to
something in the brain if they don't
think that's what I think through
psychedelic drugs.
I think when they were doing these heavy
psychedelic drugs,
which by the way,
we're absolutely being used by them by
tons and tons.
I could listen to the dude.
This is the thing that really blew my
mind because I was looking.
You don't want to even believe rumors.
That's what's going on.
Again,
I saw.
I looked.
You ever look at somebody while you're
on trip?
No,
I've always kept my eyes closed.
I closed my eyes and one time I opened
my eyes and look at somebody and they
had six arms,
like a Hindu.
Somebody was just saying,
I might have been telling you this at
the economy store told me at the time,
perception gets broken down and that's
the craziness.
And so then motion looks like sick.
Like Shiva.
It looked like a Hindu thing and I'm
like,
wow,
I imagine beyond that stuff and you see
something.
I mean,
it looked,
it looked to me so much,
like a vision from the intake.
Those six rm Kinda got collect that kind
of art like Buddhists and shit like
that.
Like this kind of shit because I saw
this,
I saw this image,
this exact image.
I mean this has a third eye and
everything.
The sculptor made this for me.
I don't remember his name.
Yeah.
I wish I could remember right now,
but I don't.
Um,
but yeah,
sculptor made that for me based on this
vision that I had high on dmt.
I saw an infinite number of those really
saw one hovering here and then in every
direction out from him.
There was an infinite number of those
and they were all hovering and vibrating
around me,
so it's like a fractal.
Is there like fractals,
100 percent fact geometric?
What do you think?
What do you think having done it?
Like what do you think like,
uh,
what do you think now with the empty
after la?
You know,
I,
I think I saw just a couple things,
but I don't know how long ago they were
talking about it with people,
but you have,
what's your opinion of it now as like a,
you know,
what you're seeing?
Well,
it could be anything.
It definitely could be some sort of a,
an insane hijacking of your sensory
nervous system produces this spectacular
psych duck effect that's so profound.
The solution to Jane,
a hallucinogenic effect that's so
profound that it literally is like a
transcendent experience and changes your
life.
It's totally popped out to me.
It's totally possible that it's just a
chemical thing.
What's also,
but that's also a salsa possibles,
that life itself,
that whatever the fuck life is and
especially whatever the fuck intelligent
life is not understood what
consciousness is not understood and the
this idea that things can only exist in
this realm.
That's not proven.
Also the fact that when those quantum
physicists guys start breaking down the
nature of reality and they come up with,
I don't know how the fuck they do this,
I'm just talking out my ass,
but they come up with the idea that
there's 11 dimensions.
Right?
And that they literally,
I mean,
and this is all changing and constantly
evolving and moving and they're
constantly adding to this.
It is entirely possible that there's a
bunch of other shit that's around us all
the time.
That's just not here and we have access
to it.
And when you do DMT womp,
you go into that other place.
It's entirely
settling dude.
It's like,
it's not like you're going,
it's like the shit's here.
Well,
that's why you as a skeptic,
it's very important to hear from you.
Like a guy.
Like,
I'll tell you what,
I'll.
Because I drew a shitty diagram of it,
his wife felt this is what it feels
like.
If you ever do it like this little
point,
let's say a little point is you.
This is what I felt like and these these
lines I drew.
That's like space and you're this little
point that could stabbed into space time
and all this shit.
This is all the shit that makes you
like.
It forms a point.
It's like closing your eyes and looking
at all of all of this shit is fucking
cross section of your being.
Everything being focused into making.
If you could just reverse look at it.
It feel like it's lessons.
I always feel like it's lessons.
I always feel right.
It's time to go to school,
sit down,
sit down.
Here's what's going on.
The one of the last ones,
more profound ones was a bunch of
gestures that were all giving me the
finger.
Really.
They were all circling around me like
giving me the finger like who he named
you.
Twitter is going to teach you about
twitter.
If you're tense.
60 residents all negatively gesture.
Giving you the finger.
Like how do you feel of yourself?
Are you in constant defensive mode?
And then when I sort of relaxed myself,
they they started wagging their finger
back and forth like,
Yep,
that's it.
That's it.
That's cool.
Very,
very strange that the,
the,
these things that you see but you can't
define are constantly changing.
So if you try to like say it looked like
a gesture,
it probably did for a few seconds for a
few seconds that lived like a gesture
and then it imploded and became stars
and then it sucked in and became
geometric patterns and it became neon
colored worms that we're making love to
each other and a giant infinite bundle
of yarn.
Like it becomes weirder and weirder shit
all the time.
It's hard to remember when you're done.
It's almost impossible.
Even me saying I kind of feel of having
kind of a fellowship because I don't
totally remember what I saw.
I remember what I remember to write down
or remember what I repeated.
So I'm like going back on like my
repeated versions of what I saw,
but I just,
I remember like flashes of the intense
profound nature of the experience,
their emotions to it.
Like I,
when I came out of it the first time
that this on New Year's,
the first time I did it and I fucking,
I guess I was like weeping,
but when I came out of it because you
just suddenly are awake and I had like,
I was so out of it,
it was like not.
I went,
I went from weeping like Oh hey,
what's up?
And it.
Because I had been staring some crazy
thing that we're like,
look so beautiful to me.
But.
But it was that.
It was like coming out of a dream.
I guess almost that mechanic quote that
I think what I'd be scared of is
unearned wisdom.
I think we kind of said something like,
be,
be wary of unearned wisdom where I don't
know if I can handle looking at
something that intense.
I was really a low feeling state when I
did it and I didn't give a fuck.
So I wanted to do it.
You pick up the slack,
you know,
that unearned wisdom thing.
I think I know what he's saying and I
think there's a real problem with people
acting profound when they just learned
something an hour ago saying I'm not a
qualified Sharman is a thing that people
enjoy doing and it's like,
like jizzing out their knowledge and a
lot of that is on her knowledge.
Like there's a lot of people that don't
really have a full and including me,
I've done it many times are so full of
not having a full understanding of the
topic at hand life.
Jesus judges it out.
But you look for sure you learned a lot
about yourself when you do those
experiences.
I learned a lot about myself,
learned a lot about how I interact with
people.
I saw negative thoughts like expressed
as like this dark green and black
twisted sort of pattern.
And then when my thoughts went positive,
it blossom like the most beautiful
flowers you can imagine.
It was crazy.
It was a lesson in thinking toxic Lee.
And then.
And this is probably like 2008 ish,
somewhere around the end that that was
this particular experience that
literally changed who I am,
literally changed how I talked to
people,
literally change how I feel about people
watching a negative thought being
expresses his dark patterns and then the
positive thought,
just I just let it go.
Like,
oh,
I see,
I see I'm doing it to myself.
And then boom.
And then he just relax and enjoy.
This is so beautiful and because you're
looking at something so beautiful,
that feeling of seeing beauty makes it
more beautiful and just getting more and
like tears were rolling down my eyes and
Mrs.
Stunning,
stunning experience.
It's easier to do that now besides that.
But I,
I know what you mean.
Like wish I could remember seeing it
though.
I remember it happened and I remember
the dark green and black,
but it's so.
I remember so little of what I actually
saw.
It's a total recreation in my mind,
which is a real problem with memory.
So real problem with regular memory.
Forget about something spectacularly
unique and odd as a psychedelic
experience,
but just regular memory.
I mean,
I try to think of what I did yesterday.
I know what I.
Did you ever get the information like
the last time I did it,
this is what really blew me away is
because my girl was saying I was going.
I won't forget by the way.
I forgot immediately.
It's like a joke joke.
You have to write it down.
I'm supposed to talk into a microphone,
talk into a recorder like right away
when you get out and then try to
decipher that because usually I feel
like I can't talk.
As soon as you can know,
which you to do is use the voice app on
your phone and as soon as you can talk,
hit record and just ramble.
First of all,
you're going to go,
oh my God,
I'm a fucking moron because it's going
to stop.
If you're sober,
it's going to sound so stupid.
Like I lost the inner journey and better
like on the inside.
On the outside you're just puking and
projectile shitting.
Shivering like an idiot.
That's a metaphor for twitter.
There shouldn't be a which will be on
that shit,
like not being on fucking social media
the level.
Because at one point I was,
I remember I would read like salon.com
to fucking be annoyed.
I didn't notice it like you're doing it
on purpose.
I didn't even realize how much I was
like,
uh,
my leg.
It's like a conflict addiction and it
becomes like some weird Russia people
get journal masochism no,
it's just a fucking thing of.
Especially if you have a mannequin kind
of personalities,
it's why is why you to share.
You share this,
you,
you've overcome this.
He's in the grips of it.
He's in the grips of doing battle
everyday,
puts on his fucking twitter.
I can't believe the amount of energy
spent on there,
but I'm not saying don't pull that shit
on twitter,
but don't look who gives a shit what
anybody says he has.
You've,
you've had issues with it.
Like you and I talked about it.
Were you like you would get in these
twitter beefs and you won't be able to
sleep cortisol.
It's the same thing that addicts,
he had a gambling is actually losing to
die.
Don't know.
I can't.
That's not a smart thing to do with your
time.
I can't see why that would be good for
you.
I know you think like you'd come come up
with materials sometimes with battling
that with people.
It would show me how to like this.
Like it could show you like use twitter
to represent who you are.
It's just fucking hard to represent who
you are.
It's hard in print.
It's very to.
Because my tone is so key with jokes.
Yes,
and most people don't.
It's not like your car.
The writing jokes going on there.
It's promote where I'm going to be made.
People will fucking buy a ticket if they
want to hear you.
A little insight though.
Angry.
Do I keep living an idiot?
I was coming strong.
Come on.
I thought I thought it was like I was
working.
I remember my ex would be like,
well you fucking get on fucking
facebook.
I'm like,
this is my job.
Okay.
Oh Wow.
Like in my head that's like productive
and see.
Sometimes I do write with it though,
like I won't go through my twitter and
just be like,
okay,
it's not copyrighted,
just so you know.
And also,
yeah.
Also you're just giving people become
accustomed.
See all this insight,
baseball shit they do with standup.
Is making civilians like you've never
heard that inside baseball?
Like the insiders terms?
No,
I wasn't working on a pilot.
They go,
we need more inside baseball on like in
like,
like Pete Holmes,
a show on HBO is about being a standup.
So it's like an insider's,
right?
Like that's how it's put out there,
which I'm against this showing the
process shit everybody does and that's
what I would do on.
I looked at facebook almost like a dye,
like I'm showing you.
I'll go very clearly.
Nine out of 10 of these will suck.
Okay.
Not Be worth reading it all and one in
10 will be funny maybe,
but you're not paying me for this,
so I'm just allowing you to see my
process.
You know what I mean?
I'm thinking like it's a diary,
but you don't put your diary like Anne
Frank even had to be dead for a diary to
come out.
You keep just have your shit up like
that and I'm giving it away for free and
then people are entitled to it and how
these little shitheads a little entitled
foodies.
So you're like,
how is this nothing writing about Dave
Chappelle's our that.
It's Ho hum because I was reading some
dickhead rainbow back,
Chappelle and I'm like,
where do you get the balls?
And it's because they're,
they're being made to feel like an
insider.
The same as trump is like an every man
fucking dipshit,
you know Joe Joe bag of donuts.
Like dom called.
That guy is a guy like me to talk to me.
Finally.
Everybody's about that.
Now there are.
They hate like an elite or an expert.
Experts of what I do.
People over there.
We went on several times.
Let's,
let's bring it back to the people that
are writing.
So these people that are writing these
things,
a lot of them when they're in their
twenties and we would all have done the
same thing,
the exact same thing when you're in your
twenties.
That's right.
You thought just like that when you hold
on when you were a writer and you,
you know,
if you were writing a blog for some sort
of online publication and you decided to
take an angle,
you know,
this Dave Chappelle specials,
not that big a deal,
and then just go run with that.
You would probably do the exact fucking
same thing.
There's a lot of people that do that.
Well,
no fathers review.
Like I told you,
I'm a sucker.
So I would review it and say what I
thought about the hour.
So that's not what's done.
And I know for a fact that's not how
these people do.
And if you've talked to them,
they go,
I got to say I don't like somebody
because I liked the political reason.
Uh,
yeah,
I know what you're saying.
It's not.
Nothing is based on funny.
I mean,
it was always like that,
but now there's an added political
element of not funny.
Here's a whole la La land section of it.
There's a whole section where up is down
and right is left and whatever the fuck
you say becomes doctrine.
People like to make Dane Cook a
punchline that I have half the people
that would do that.
I haven't.
They haven't made me laugh even a
little,
as much as they can cook,
so I'm wondering.
It's a free shot.
It's like carrot top people will take a
free shot at carrot top.
I don't even see these fucking punk
millennials now doing the work and built
those props.
Yeah,
carrot top is a funny guy.
He's funny.
Like he's a good comic.
Like you could go see a show.
It's a silly funny show,
but it has punchline sample.
Think they literally just a new kind of
comedy that doesn't have sort of punch
set up.
Punch line is not only good.
It's postmodern building block of the
universe.
Everything is that.
If we fix post modern comedy,
well you know what it is.
It's.
We just aren't good at it.
Right.
That's the new way are press or like
every of activist by the way will tell
you they're a comedian,
but here's the thing.
Every single one,
if they like that style and they go,
it's like,
it's like someone saying to a jazz
guitarist,
dude,
you,
you can't play for shit because you
can't play like Hendrix.
Right.
You know,
but they don't want to go to do this and
I understand that,
but I understand because I don't
appreciate music or whatever,
how I should appreciate it.
I totally get that,
but I don't think I could just walk and
play guitar.
Well,
it's just a different genre though,
because the whole thing is,
according to me,
it's other lowercase igeneration like
right out of apple products.
Well,
there's also an applied snobbishness
were the people that are not doing the
punchlines feel like what they're doing
is somehow or another better than
someone who does classic setup,
punchline sort of joke writing.
That's ridiculous.
It's ridiculous because it's not better
or worse and you know,
you don't get Brownie points just
because you're eclectic or just because.
Because you didn't know your alternative
shit was old Steve Martin bits.
Well,
Dennis Miller,
that's where it gets really funny.
Like Dennis Miller,
Dennis Miller was super alton a lot of
ways he would be telling these set of
punch punchlines about shit that you
definitely didn't know what the fuck he
was talking about and you would laugh
anyway because you didn't want to be
thought of as stupid.
There was a bunch of people that laughed
at Dennis Miller's jokes.
They didn't have a fucking clue as to
what he was saying.
Mark Twain had cancer.
Just Mark Twain wrote a whole book as a
joke.
Which book was that?
I can't remember.
I remember this.
I remember it was like having everybody,
uh,
review it and stuff,
like it was real and he was just
laughing his ass off.
I think if you write the book,
it says a joke at that point.
It sounds like you wrote a book.
It's almost like you bang a guy's a
joke.
He wrote it as a satire and people took
it as fact.
Postmodern comedy.
I was one of my first jokes in colleges.
I knock,
knock.
Who's there?
Pineapple.
Who are you to say what funny is?
Oh God,
because it's true.
It's like a.in
a,
like a painting.
It's like childhood.
You listen,
if you pay it to see me,
you can determine if I did my job and
not,
you know,
you have your take on it and people have
their take on it.
But like there's certain guys that,
you know,
they're just funny.
Right.
And you could,
you could see someone saying,
okay,
like perfect example,
setup punchline,
Mitch Hedberg.
If you say that's not funny,
fuck you,
you're lying.
Just fuck you.
Okay.
Because he's clever.
It's set up.
It's weird.
It's eight minutes for reasons outside
of the.
When people tell you someone who's funny
and they say they own funny or vice
versa,
it's because they're judging for things
that have nothing to do with the
material or the funding.
Like I've heard people say like,
oh don't like a guy that stands Julie
had a fair.
That's a fair critique,
you know?
Or.
Sure.
But that's the case with music too,
right?
Like you might not like Bob Dylan's
voice.
Like,
oh,
I don't want to hear it,
and that's a legit concern.
That's a legit concern.
Can have their thing.
I've got no issue with that.
Comedy is not just what you're saying.
It's how you're saying it's now.
It sounds to people,
but why destroy cities?
What I was saying like if you don't like
somebody's fucking coming into,
that's fine,
but they don't.
People do that with bands though.
There's groups out that need to destroy.
They're like,
but I can't trust for you to enjoy it
because I don't know how,
you know people want to take,
but how is it different than shit and on
people like nickelback don't shit on
people like nickelback will.
You're a beautiful person but it's not
real.
That's kind of the same sense.
Cool.
It seems like we just decided this up a
little bit.
Feel like I just,
I was pretending to enjoy the show.
I'm like,
are you bragging that you have that week
of a person that you were just going
with the crowd and like a thing you
didn't enjoy too trying to hurt your
feelings?
And I think you know that as well as I
do that.
I'm just reading what.
It's not so much you're arguing with a
nonsense person.
That's why I don't go on social media
too.
It's just as these arguments with people
that aren't even fucking say to me.
You don't even understand what I'm.
This is my point.
I don't say I read the Shingo.
Nothing like I save it for the Rogan
show,
but beautiful.
That's the way to go.
Great.
I'd say bring it to the Rogan show.
That's always a good move.
I love it.
I just listened.
It's,
you know,
it's fun as long as you don't get too
caught up in it.
But the reality is if I had a friend who
got into something online and uh,
it went sideways and my advice was,
okay,
you know what happens when it goes
sideways,
right?
So if there's a situation where you feel
like it's going sideways and a bunch of
people are gonna attack you for no
reason,
step away,
just step away because if you engage you
essentially trusting your emotional
state to a bunch of people that have no
concern for your wellbeing,
like they want to attack you and hurt
your feelings.
You're not going to like plead it down
to like,
well mildly upset with you.
Now they have this idea and you are the
target and you as a person who's in the
public eye as a celebrity,
you know this person is you.
You are thought of as someone who
already has some extra privilege.
You're thought of as someone who's
already already stealing something from
the rest of us.
You already get some easy free ride
because of your talent or your notoriety
or whatever the fuck it is.
So they feel like there's extra licensed
to fuck with you.
Do that too.
Where I feel like someone is so big and
powerful,
like I'm not talking to him,
ah,
is
successful enough.
In my mind I'm like,
it's not even engaging with the person.
It's like,
I dunno,
I want you to send all your tweets to me
first before you tweet.
Delay is the delay.
You send them to me,
I'll give you the thumbs up and thumbs
down.
No more tweeting.
Just texts.
Just saying shit to Barry crimmins
directly for awhile.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Same thing what I'm saying from power of
attorney over like only he has my
password.
Like I don't even know listening.
We're friends.
I don't want your password,
but I do want you to send all your
tweets to me for it.
We should try that.
That'd be so funny.
Let me tell you something about Barry,
because Barry was responsible for the
environment I came up in.
I came up in Boston,
Barry Crimmins,
he created.
He didn't create it.
He set a tone.
He said,
uh,
no hacks,
good writing,
no thieves.
He set a tone and that tone was fucking
rock solid.
And they were all these big fucking men.
Like Lenny Clarke is a big guy.
Kevin Knox was a big guy.
There were a manly men.
They weren't like these neat,
like nerdy type,
skinny little comedians.
They were fucking savages.
They did coke and they were punching
each other all the time.
They never paid taxes.
These fucking guys were animals and
Barry crimmins started the whole thing
off.
He was so good and so smart and so well
read and so aware of what's going on in
the world.
He set a tone for the entire and
everyone's scared of him.
I was terrified of him when that guy
started reaching out to me and we became
friends online.
It was like way after I'd already been
on television,
everything.
I was so happy.
I like Barry crimmins
likes me.
Oh yes.
I think you're one of the good guys and
I think you're a hero and he's telling
me all this shit.
To me it was like that was the dawn of
comedy.
He was the fucking main guy that started
it off.
Yeah.
Do you have that with people?
I felt that way when you wrote to me
Matt.
Oh,
that's nice.
Well,
yeah,
he was terrible.
He was so smart and so he was so well
versed in politics and what was going
on,
making dared not bring up Guatemala or
Nicaragua around him.
They don't talk about the conscious,
the Sandinistas,
and he was like the last progressive
like bay.
He was a left wing dude.
Believe say there's no because America
doesn't have that.
We have just reactionaries and that is
what America is.
It's all reactionary.
He was a masculine progressive,
right man.
like an aggressive fuck you masculine
progressive guy who was anti racist and
anti sexual harassment,
anti obviously anti-sex abuse because of
what's happened to him to protect her.
He would go on stage and he would ever
like a fucking,
like a professor's jacket on.
He had reached into it and pull out a
budweiser.
Every time he had a budweiser in his
pocket that was like half a shtick,
drink American beer and he put that shit
right on the counter.
Like right in front of you.
It was like half of what he did was he
was this guy that was sick of all this
fucking nonsense around him and you
know,
he had like this real clear intention of
like this is what's going to be
tolerated and this end his actors like
that too.
And you'd go to watch him.
You would literally like.
He was so powerful that you would change
like your politically.
Yes,
if you were in any way liked about him.
Is that because I don't mind anybody's
beliefs if they're like,
well thought out if you have so much of
a trend of terrain devoted to something
and if it's disgusting to you,
and I'm like,
I should.
Like when you said that privileged thing
you're talking about like where people
are taking it,
acknowledging their privilege.
Did anybody read.
I'll go read your scriptures when you
tell me about these ideas.
So the privileged checklist.
Have you ever read that?
The Peggy Mcintosh privilege was.
Who's Peggy Mcintosh?
The one that kicked off this fucking
amazing privilege concept of white
privilege based on her ideas on male
privilege.
Oh yeah.
The what it's called,
the unpacking,
the invisible,
a white privileged knapsack.
I love when they say unpacking,
I can unpack that for you.
First of all,
the first white privilege is you call it
a knapsack.
That's step one,
but it's clearly just this rich college
ladies privileges that she just saw
white privilege unpacking the invisible
backpack.
Every fucking thing that when I used to
go,
please go,
go and educate yourself.
Look,
hold on,
hold on please.
Through the work to bring materials from
women's studies into the rest of the
curriculum.
I have often noticed men's unwillingness
to grant that they are overprivileged
even though they may grant that women
are disadvantaged.
It's almost like she hates women in a
way.
Well,
this is a weird thing,
like see,
this is the thing is very important.
This kind of person thinks that your
rights are fucking privileges.
Okay,
so most of the list is going to be
things that are your basic human right
and that if,
let's say you're not getting because
you're not white,
you should be getting that.
It's not that I shouldn't be able to
move into a neighborhood I want.
It's that you should be able to also,
but they're framing it as,
no,
you have undue privilege needs to be
taken away.
Like these are my store.
Did way of looking at an actual problem.
The actual problem is real racism.
The actual problem is real sexism,
but instead of looking at that,
look at the people that are lucky that
they're not discriminated against.
A real hauling them somehow or another
somehow know perpetrators.
Yeah.
It's a real fat check way of looking at
life everyday.
It's just a real young,
shitty young girl way to look at the
world.
As long as you're not happy.
Well there's a great quote that
socialist don't love the poor.
They hate the rich.
That's a good quote and it's also.
It's also some people I'd be look buried
to me was a sincere dude and I would
listen to and he didn't have.
He would give you the shirt.
That was the other thing of that scene
as barry would not really have a lot of
money because he be paying into the
comics and he really was a guy who was
generous,
generous guy.
You know what?
I mean legitimately generous with his,
uh,
his adoration,
generous with the way promoted other
comics the way generously help people
but generous like,
you know what he did for that scene on
real.
He made that scene.
I mean everybody will admit that there
was a lot of great comics back then.
I mean,
there.
Steven Wright,
of course,
there was a lot of great guy,
Don Gavin,
who's one of the all time,
my all time greatest.
There was all these great guys that were
in that area,
but this guy had something special and
he was by far the most well read out of
all of them.
And I think like abused kids have two
roads.
You either want other people to hurt or
you want to protect people.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
And I think that sometimes early trauma
can make you like just so protective of
the week where you hate when someone
takes advantage of vulnerability.
Very high was just prince.
He had principles.
This is the thing.
It's like somebody have a fucking
principle.
The Jamie Kilstein thing.
I had people write,
write and shit.
This is like right around the time,
like ceased all facebook ads because
people are like,
well,
I guess you're happy Jamie.
I'm like,
why would I be happy?
Do you think there's like,
I wouldn't wish that shit on anybody
fucking evil shit here to keep me from
killing myself.
Very.
Clements,
he had to talk me down.
I was going to do the shit that I had
coming out on me.
You can't even believe.
Okay.
And,
and what?
I'm not,
I'm not fucking getting into all the
particulars ever again with people that
publicly.
But if I say barely fucking saved my
fucking life.
He saved you with perspective.
It gives you a better perspective.
Yeah.
I'm lucky I talked to him.
I am because I was in a fucking bad
dude.
When you're ready to do it,
it's like,
no,
this is my ignorance because I thought
that you were brushing it off like
nothing while I was freight.
Dude,
you can't even podcast about it.
I heard you talking on a podcast will go
away.
I don't remember.
Um,
it was a long time ago,
a long time to ways that I couldn't even
believe.
Okay.
And he was becoming maddening and then
it was becoming like,
it's just crazy,
dude.
And uh,
you know,
I still can't get.
I had to go through a book.
Me,
I'd be tickled to have an agent.
I,
I don't know where they went,
but it was like I was off the fucking
uh,
you know,
I just had no,
nothing.
I know work.
I had a job lined up that supposed to
get.
I fucking couldn't.
I mean,
uh,
I would just like taking it to work for
shy anyway because I like my job,
but it was crazy.
I couldn't believe the amount of shit
for something.
I don't think it's controversial,
but it doesn't matter.
Once it's a slow day and somebody picks
up and grabbed it,
I can't believe it's a soft target.
Someone would bring amy into it.
I can't believe that's why do you say
that?
That's ridiculous because for her,
but I didn't know.
There was no show show while the show
was going on.
You work for this show is done,
but you hadn't announced.
It wasn't stop,
stop,
but it just happened.
Show just ended.
So all that time before then you were
writing for,
you know,
why they would connect you to her.
It's crazy to think you don't.
What I don't get is why that would be.
No,
I get why these fucking social jihadis
do it.
I don't get why normal people validated
ever normal people.
It's outrageous to validate that people.
What do you mean with the fucking.
Anybody fucking uh,
uh,
can we.
Yes.
This needs to be addressed.
Amy,
will you please take the floor and
address this adult man,
that's not your child.
I think they have to do that because
she's thought of as a feminist and she's
thought of as a powerful woman,
a guy working for her.
I mean,
that's what the difference is because
Jay was talking about,
I was talking about to Jay because he's
like,
I never get any because we sell like I
was in.
Now I'm in the jurisdiction of them
because um,
because you were on these fucking people
in this religion,
but like they believe that's their,
like you serve at our pleasure and they,
and they get validated whenever someone
and all these fucking dipshit liberals.
Okay,
because I'm a liberal dude or I don't
know if I'm like the last of a fucking
whatever,
but they all just pandered.
They're like,
well,
it's for the best.
Don't stumble.
Your brother just,
you're not sweating.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that are
liberals feel the exact same way.
I don't feel like they're really
liberals anymore because of the far left
has taken over.
Like this space of what you can and
can't say to the point where you're
like,
really on the outs.
I don't get how they don't see trump as
their guy.
Like at that part baffles me.
Like how do you even like just the
stench be just based on these small
hands and pettiness and like,
well I think it's hilarious that as
president I didn't tell you not to body
shame shit on the hands.
It's one of the most ridiculous body
shamings ever because they're not even
that small.
I mean they're not like outrageously
small hands,
so like when they say it over and over
again,
just to fuck with them.
Clearly body shaming.
It's not like you're making fun of his
hair.
That's an obvious joke.
Every.
You can't ignore it,
but the hands like you're really going
after him if you're making fun of his
hand.
People,
its location of course.
That's the whole thing.
That's all it is.
The hypocrisy.
But like if you see what like why scene?
It's like all these people were his best
pal.
Oh yeah,
he is God.
And then he was like,
am I supposed to fall for this puppet?
I'm sorry,
Punch beat Judy this time people crying.
But like do you fall?
You cry pro wrestling.
This couldn't be more of.
They don't care though.
It's about power.
That's the thing that I had.
I had to figure out where it's like you
can prove a contradiction and be like
male strip just called them.
God don't you do that?
You,
you engage with people online like
crazy.
You go after people online and insult
them like crazy.
You just did it.
We just started though.
Do you feel like you want to or if
someone blocks you?
Yeah,
if somebody blocks you on twitter,
that's not an assault on you,
but you just go for and have enough
information,
but think about what your saying people
shouldn't do and then think about what
you do and they very similar,
right?
You want to take his work or say he's a
bad comic.
You can't be above it and in it that's
just bottom line.
Can't be.
Yeah,
it's the same thing.
Everybody is just fucking attacking
everybody.
Social War,
cannibalism going on.
There they are.
They allowed to speak to me out like you
can't look.
They went after her fucking Bruno Mars
cultural appropriation,
Bruno Mars quotation appropriation
because they're saying he's a
cooperating black music.
He's half Filipino.
That was one of the biggest on the going
and be plainly know Bruno Mars.
They're tagging Bruno Mars for cultural
appropriation and a bunch of black
artists are defending him.
Like,
what in the fuck?
He's brown hair,
Jesus Christ.
The whole thing is so ridiculous.
It's not like he's a brown guy getting
that dude.
It's a new thing.
He's not brown enough.
He's not dark enough.
Not from Africa.
Whatever the fuck it is.
If you do,
you can't be liberal enough.
We're going to get to like one state
where some gender fluid,
transgender like half black
Hermaphrodite,
but they're not left handed,
right handed privileged or the other guy
brought in my head on race wars who was
like very funny and get on the show and
like hit the worst philosophy I heard on
gnomes podcast.
I saw me out of the seller's like some
white male club and it's not the most
diverse.
You know,
like if I had a riding in cars to
comics,
it would be very diverse because that's
just who you hang out with.
I think that dude just talks a lot.
He says some shit that doesn't make any
sense.
He went after me and who the fuck was
it?
Something he was seeing?
Very nice conversation.
Totally out of context.
We were talking about how many,
um,
when kids get molested,
how many of those kids become molesters
and we were trying to figure
out like that is a real thing that does
happen.
Also where you get ingrained somehow or
another into a homosexual being aroused
homosexual rights,
what would you call it?
A boner boyfriend know that people get
like,
it's not the same as what you're talking
about.
Like young people when young people are
going through their development,
if they get arrested,
it is entirely possible or $300 but not
even molested.
If they just have a sexual experience
with a guy,
maybe if you can shape somebody's entire
fucking shit gets printed out that he
said a bunch of tweets about like us
wondering like two straight guys
wondering how many gay guys became gay
because they got fucked when they were
kids.
Like,
well that's not what we said,
but that is a study and I saw it printed
that I copy and pasted the url for an
actual study on that.
Like how many times people are molested
and they wind up becoming homosexual or
becoming a molester themselves.
Those are two real distinct
possibilities when you completely
disrupt a child's sexual cycle,
who's saying it's bad or they're not
making a judgment call a off of your
desk.
It's exactly because there's something
that happens to people when they get
sexually molested and most of it's
really bad and hypersexuality is another
one.
People become very sexual.
There's a lot of weird,
so we weren't in any way saying that gay
people are only gay because of that.
I wonder is it all.
It's been studied by scientists,
the shit about that.
It's just as good as name attached to
get it,
so that's why the seller thing,
but I gladly would have.
Mom makes me.
It makes me more careful with what I say
though and I think that's the good thing
about it,
so to leave it in the past had been way
more careless with how I say thanks.
To think that it wouldn't be
misconstrued,
especially not weaponized.
Well due to apologies are not to the
people that hate you because they want
you dead and there's no.
It's for people that like you don't
understand.
That's what you apologized for.
The people that are against you or
they're not comedy fans are learning
too,
right?
So through this whole dark journey that
you went on with all this bullshit,
you did learn that though.
So it's very valuable.
Yeah.
No dues.
Barry Barry is very helpful to me.
I know.
But you going through all this and
coming out on the other side,
the experience of doing it.
Yeah,
dude,
uh,
made a lot of things that I kinda was
told earlier that never made sense to
me.
Make a lot of like,
I remember last time we hung out Patrice
Shit.
He said to me that I didn't understand
the magnitude of what he was saying to
me until then how so like what kind of
stuff.
Just know what a devil businesses is and
how easy you get fooled into the brass
ring.
It makes you a coward when they give you
stuff to,
to let you know that that's true.
But here's the thing,
I think that's less the case now.
And this is my case,
I think because of the Internet,
I think comics essentially have created
a network of each other.
That's exactly right.
Think of the network of race wars or
skeptic tank or family.
Our Joey Diaz is a church of what's
happening now.
We're all in a network together.
Dude,
I,
I learned a lot.
The main thing is that because I only
really got work in his business because
of comics,
there was not the
history now,
which is really important,
more so than ever.
You can filter down thing,
but the network is an organic network.
Instead of someone owning you or having
a contract with you,
great.
They're like,
oh,
it's fucking funny.
Be like,
go see him.
Oh,
Gertz hilarious.
Go see him,
you know,
make us.
And so then people listen to your
podcast or to listen to your specialty
of,
Oh,
this guy's fucking hilarious.
And we've told them the truth so many
times that they believe.
And then the other thing about podcasts
that I think is amazing and then just
the Internet in general with comics
today,
is it everybody supportive of each
other?
When someone has a special coming out,
I see other people tweeting,
go check this out.
Yeah,
all the time was great about that.
So it was Ari,
but these people are,
you know,
nobody ever did that in the past.
I feel like if I like somebody,
should I go out of my way to compliment
out there.
It's like bitcoin.
It's a decentralized currency now.
A little bit.
Yeah,
it's a little bit.
And there's less of this golden ring.
So that golden ring is just fucking
acting.
Okay.
That's what it is.
And it was not acting.
It's writing about acting.
It's like reading the scripts about
complaints or casting complaints.
Not Stand up.
Complaints.
Not Our world,
man.
The problem is we fuck up.
We go to that world.
Our world is inappropriate.
Shit said behind closed doors making
each other laugh.
I'm not a teacher.
Terrible class.
I'm not here to help the class.
We're,
we're in the green room doing mushrooms,
smoking pot,
drinking whiskey,
and then we go on stage and talk crazy
shit because this is our world.
Our world is not the casting couch.
Our world is nothing to do with
auditions or this whole fucking acting
like the way actors talk to each other
and actor speak.
That's not our world.
Now.
We're not doing it.
We're not.
This is,
this is it.
It's a different world.
We're trying to come up with shit.
That's funny so that people laugh
because we liked that
because I believe the last thing is
barry said to me because they wanted to
take his special awful Louis site,
which you wouldn't do because Barry's
like a stand up dude.
I wouldn't like go with the crowds.
Trendy horseshit.
Like He.
He had principles,
but he's like,
I'm so sick of the untalented hijacking
of very real trauma to a lot of people
to further their dump Korea.
He's dead on about that.
It's people.
It's like people.
Because you know,
by the way,
the stats when they go one in five
people are rapes.
Okay.
Or women are raped.
I think that's probably just the amount
of men that are raped and women could be
double that.
Okay.
I think it's so prevalent,
but just based on the people I know in
my life.
Okay.
That's something happened to.
It's weird for something not to what
happen to you.
You see what Tim Dillon wrote about all
this after the whole Louis thing.
When Tim Dillon wrote a brilliant piece,
I think he wrote it on facebook,
but then he put it on instagram and
broke it up into pages
so that you can keep turning through it,
but he's explaining how this is an
opportunity for truly mediocre talent to
chop down someone who was head and
shoulders far better than that and they
do so by claiming the moral high ground
by virtue signaling,
by like going after him and attacking
him,
breaking down what he did.
Or you can tell people's character by
who wanted to get there.
A little kick in.
The same thing happen to me it was.
I was,
but you know,
a lot of my friends are my friends,
man.
I'm lucky.
Like I'm not.
I lost respect for a lot of people
during this whole thing and I'll tell
you who they are as soon as we shut this
fucking show down.
It's already 3:19.
Oh Shit.
You Fuck?
Yeah.
Oh and Benjamin.
As long as you promise.
Leave Anthony Jeselnik alone.
Son of a bitch get pluggy special.
A huge penis to Dotcom.
It's called,
how dare me.
It pns like he plays the piano.
Yes.
All right.
Sorry,
go ahead.
Oh,
oh,
it's my website.
Huge pns to.com.
The name of it is,
um,
uh,
how dare me shot.
And uh,
in my town that I live in your gut,
in our call,
white,
fresher than comedy central I made a
while ago.
People just now we've seen so far I
haven't seen it.
See it.
I want to see it now.
Where,
uh,
when did they film this?
She was like fucking 2015 and it's on
comedy central.
Is it on Netflix or any of those places?
It's on Netflix.
It's a,
it's probably pirated.
Go pirate it.
It's too,
it's a CD.
Like,
dude,
I just realize you're like the Doug
Stanhope of upstate New York who do
stand up in your town?
I do.
That's what Doug does.
That's a duck does down in Brisbane due
to third of the whole booking Yakov.
SMIRNOFF is his grandson.
There's a big Doug Paul Bunyan,
crazy checkered plaid.
Arizona did one and three people came to
the taping.
Like that's a lot.
That's an amazing story.
I do because I moved here to la,
so I'm doing race where?
West Coast.
Oh Shit.
We just got to know you.
Totally moved here.
When did you totally move here?
Don't tell anybody what you live for a
few months ago.
You still going to storm the fucking
Improv main room.
All right,
that's it.
Goodbye everybody.
Thanks everybody came out this weekend.
We had a great time.
Bye.