Four three,
two,
one.
Hello Peter.
Hello Joe.
What's going on man?
A whole lot.
You were just telling me something that
is one of the most ridiculous things
I've ever heard.
That you swam from Maui to Lanai.
Right?
And you're the one,
the only humans ever do that.
I am told I was the first person to swim
from Maui to when I am back.
The one way is a pretty famous swim race
that's done every year.
You're the first person to do it.
The round.
Go back.
Fuck Dude.
Why'd you do that?
How long have you got it started when I
was a boy.
They told me I couldn't do it.
What made you want to do that?
That's a ridiculous proposition.
Um,
so I got into,
I decided in,
it's going to sound silly.
I read a book in January of 2004 about
this woman named Penny Dean,
who still to this day holds the record
for the fastest crossing of the Catalina
Channel.
So it was for me from Catalina Island to
San Pedro or or a to a not you typically
swimming to point point [inaudible] and
she had done it in like seven hours and
20 minutes and I was like,
that's amazing.
I far as a crow flies,
it's 21 miles with the currents.
It's a little longer.
And I was like,
you know,
I really want to do this.
Um,
but I,
I got to learn how to swim first.
That seems that's three miles an hour
swimming.
She is a phenom.
Penny Dean had a stroke rate of 90
strokes per minute,
which I mean that might not mean
anything to someone who doesn't swim,
but like to turn to have a hand hit the
water every,
you know,
third of it.
Two thirds of a second is a remarkable
case.
Yeah.
I can't hold a cadence of that for a
hundred yards.
Wow.
And she did it for 20 miles.
Yeah.
What a beast.
She's out of control.
There's certain people like that,
man,
it freaked me out I think.
I think marathon's swimming might be one
sport where if you just look at the
numbers,
I think women are better than men.
Well there's that woman who swam from
Cuba to the United States.
Right?
She was the first person ever,
Diana,
Diane and she didn't she do it like at a
fairly advanced age.
Yeah.
I mean she's of course got an amazing
pedigree of swimming and this wasn't her
first Rodeo.
Right,
right,
right.
Why,
why do you think women are better than
men?
That's that.
I mean those of us that,
I'm not a member of this community
anymore,
but when I was,
it was one of our favorite topics of
discussion.
I think a thing,
opportunities or ideas that were put
forth were higher pain tolerance.
Something about being,
you know,
evolving to be able to give birth,
um,
just means they can tolerate pain a lot
higher.
Um,
I think another thing I've heard is
buoyancy.
You know,
women are naturally going to have more
body fat,
which provides insulation.
When you do these swims,
you're not allowed any wetsuits or aids
of any sort.
So shorts,
you're like,
you're in a speedo and single latex cap
and that's it.
And so if you can have a little,
and so I think women's hips because
they're going to have more fat on their
hips,
they,
it corrects one of the big buoyancy
issues that we have in swimming.
We didn't evolve to swim.
We're horrible at it naturally because
we swim like this.
We drag our hips through the water.
And if you think about the importance of
aerodynamics in most of the things that
we think about,
whether it be archery or race,
car driving or cycling,
you know,
in water it's that much more important
because the density of water is,
you know,
thousands of times greater than air.
So swimming is just a hundred percent
about avoiding drag.
Wow.
So that totally makes sense.
Um,
I just have been fascinated forever with
people that are capable of pushing their
brain to do things that other people
just don't think are possible.
Like a,
you know,
big foot,
200 race or like a,
any of those things.
But the swim one is particularly crazy
because you can't stop.
Right,
right.
Like,
if you're running an ultra marathon and
you just want to sit down for a couple
minutes and just take a break,
you can do that.
But if you're swimming,
there's,
you've got a damn thing you could do.
You could tread water is about as good
as it gets,
but you can't touch the boat or the
Kayak or it's an immediate
disqualification.
Oh God,
that's so crazy.
Mat.
That is such a,
wow.
So you heard about this woman doing and
that's what I read
this book and I was like,
I really want to do this.
At the time I was,
uh,
I was actually in my residency in
Baltimore and I was like,
you know,
I really want to do this and I don't
have to learn how to swim to do it.
So I started taking swimming lessons and
then,
um,
let me to make it very long story short.
Basically by about the summer of 2005,
I entered my first swim race,
which was a two mile swim race in Lake
Restin,
Virginia.
And I did it and I was like,
oh my God,
I just swam two miles in the open water.
You know,
it was hard,
but I was like,
okay,
that's the proof of concept.
Now you just got to figure out how to
make it 2025 miles.
And uh,
so I just,
you know,
went completely psycho and ratcheted up
the training.
And,
and then in October of 2005 I did my
first catalina swim.
Wow.
That's gotta be a pretty good feeling
though when you're done that you are
capable of pushing yourself to what most
people think is an impossible distance.
Yeah.
I mean,
people,
you asked a moment ago,
why do you do this?
I would say that in life,
um,
velocity means very little acceleration
means everything.
So what do I mean by that?
Right?
Like if you're going 650 miles an hour
in an airplane,
you don't actually feel it.
You only feel when speed changes,
right?
So I've always had this theory that
emotionally that's also true.
Like happiness is only interesting when
it's juxtaposed with sadness.
And so the feeling of crawling on the
shore after you've been swimming for 12
to 14 hours is amazing.
But what makes it especially amazing is
that six hours earlier you thought you
were going to die.
So you start these swims in the middle
of the night to avoid the shipping
traffic.
So that first swim boat drops you off at
Catalina island.
It's midnight.
That's a darkness.
You can't imagine like you can't even
see la from Catalina.
You have to swim for six hours before
you even see the lights of Las Angeles.
Really?
Yeah.
What do you see the stars and the
phospho like bioluminescent organisms in
the water.
Whoa.
Just incredible,
man.
That's worth the price of admission.
So every time your hand comes through
the water,
you're pulling and ripping these little
things and you're seeing the sparks and
you can't tell where the water ends in
the sky starts.
In other words,
the stars and the bio luminescence looks
like one cylinder.
Wow.
So for the first few hours,
that's cool.
But then,
you know,
my first swim,
the water was incredibly rough.
Um,
I had only swim in the ocean for two
weeks before the swim.
I did all my training in a swimming
pool,
so in a lake on the east coast.
So now I look,
I wasn't used to how to keep the
saltwater out of my mouth.
So then I was like puking my guts out
and then my,
um,
while you were swimming?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Just because at work you just stop and
puke and then keep swimming.
And then,
uh,
but then my tongue started to get really
swollen from the saltwater because
again,
as I would learn later on,
I would go on to do many more of these
swims.
But what I learned is the importance of
spitting in the water out of your mouth
very quickly.
So in a,
in a freshwater pool or lake,
you get away with more.
But in the ocean you swallow that salt
water,
you're going to get sick as hell.
So all this stuff's going on.
So by five in the morning,
you've been swimming for five hours,
you're getting cold.
You're,
I mean,
you know,
frankly,
just physiologically like your cortisol
levels are at a nadir,
you're just,
you feel horrible.
It's like,
it's a really bad feeling and you're not
even halfway there.
And it's like you don't know if you can
do it and blah,
blah,
blah.
Well,
if six hours later,
you're now crawling out of the water
feeling like you've done this amazing
thing,
that that's emotional acceleration.
That's like the greatest contrast.
I know what I mean.
I've never experienced that.
But I was,
uh,
explaining the other day to a friend of
mine about this,
a camping trip that we went on in
Montana when it was like nine degrees
outside.
It was freezing cold.
We stayed out there for five,
six days.
And then when we finally got to a hotel
room,
I took a shower and it was the most
amazing shower I've ever experienced in
my life.
And that's a small thing,
but you take a shower every day and it's
like a big deal when you do it in that
setting or,
or think about the,
the meal you've had if you've been fast,
similar situation.
Yeah,
we're starving or lost at sea.
yeah,
yeah.
I can't imagine.
That's a,
so now that you've done,
and how many of these have you done
these crazy?
He swim races or swim,
call them several.
Yeah.
Usually these major,
major ones are not racist.
You're,
you're on your own.
You have to,
you go to the Federation that oversees
that body of water and you say,
Hey,
I want to do this.
And then you,
you know,
you go through all the channels to do
it.
Like they have to have an observer there
and they,
you follow these official rules,
you can be registered as someone was
actually completed it.
Right.
And someone's there to make sure you
didn't,
you know,
you did it correctly.
Um,
I dunno,
I probably done all in probably like a
dozen of these,
but probably like six of them,
really long ones.
What's the longest?
Well,
that's a good question.
What does the Mallee one was 20 miles
there and back.
So 40 miles miles total.
The maui channel is a 10 mile channel.
So round trip is 20.
The bigger question is time in the water
because you rarely get to swim these in
a straight line.
So the Maui Lanai one,
I wanted to go Maui Lanai,
Molokai,
Maui to do the triangle and that would
have been 30 miles as a crow flies.
But we just,
you know,
boat captain wasn't willing to do it at
night because of the tiger sharps.
And during the daytime we couldn't
physiologically figure out how one could
suffer against those,
the wind,
cause the wind gets so brutal in the
middle of the day.
So even the one that I did,
which was just a there and back,
I ended up swimming for 12 hours because
on the,
the,
the first way crossing where there was
no wind took me four hours and then it
took eight hours to get back because I
was swimming like the hypotenuse of a
triangle,
right?
Like the current's going this way.
So I had to swim this way just to go in
a straight line and I still can,
I almost missed Maui,
Jesus Christ.
So I almost got swept out to Molokai
just because the current was about 1.7
knots,
which is about as fast as I can swim.
Maybe two knots.
Fuck,
that is a ridiculous thing,
man.
Why are you doing this?
This,
this,
this maniacal?
Well,
I don't do it anymore.
I mean it was certainly a,
it was an amazing season in my life,
but I think once my daughter was born,
which was 10 years ago this summer,
that's when I,
I only probably did two of these after
she was born because then the training
just got,
so I just,
you got to live in the water if you want
to do this sport,
like you got to including the winter,
you know,
like,
even in San Diego where I live,
it's still,
you know,
55 degrees in the water and you're going
to spend three,
four hours a day in the water freezing,
you know,
it's just,
so I was like,
you know,
I just don't have the,
the,
the drive to spend 25 hours a week
swimming.
Yeah.
What was the,
what was going on in San Diego when that
guy got bitten half by a shark
couple of years back.
They were training for something.
Yeah.
It's funny you remember that.
That was may of 2008 I remember that
like it was yesterday.
So at the time I lived in San Francisco,
and this is actually just before I swim,
the Maui thing,
now that I think about it,
that was 10 years ago.
I swim the Maui thing in,
uh,
June of oh six but June of,
oh wait.
So I'm doing all my training in a
swimming pool up in San Francisco
because I don't want to acclimate to
very cold water.
I actually want to be in warm water,
but I needed one long ocean swim of like
14 or 15 miles as my last training swim.
So I came down to San Diego to do it.
And just by bad luck,
I came down a few days after that guy
was killed.
Now,
this was a,
a guy,
I didn't know him,
but he was a triathlete training with a
triathlon group that they would go out
and swim every morning and I know the
beach exactly where it happened in
Solana beach.
And,
um,
unfortunately,
like most people who get attacked by
great whites,
they have a very,
they always attack the same way,
which is below and behind stealth bite
up and then they retreat.
So they're trying to basically enjoy the
praise so that their prey exsanguinate
and then they take off and then they
wait until you bleed out.
So they never saw the shark.
But you could tell from the bite marks
it was,
um,
actually had a friend who was on the
beach and saw him when he came out and
he was basically dead when he got to
shore.
He had,
he had bled to death.
The problem is,
so in this case,
the shark had bitten and cut through his
femoral arteries and veins and the
saltwater prevents you from having any
hemostasis,
so it exacerbates the blood loss.
So that's generally how folks parish
when they're out of the water.
Um,
you know,
a bunch of other swimmers came to his
rescue.
And Luckily that commotion prevents the
Sharks from wanting to come back.
So three days later I go out and I'm
swimming at that beach because I swam
from my,
my training swim was La Jolla up to
Solana beach and back.
And I got to tell you like three days
after a guy dies where you're swimming.
It is,
it was about one of the most,
uh,
mentally challenging training swims to
be like,
cause you can't see like the water at
that part of the beach is so murky,
you know,
and you're only a couple of hundred
yards off shore that like you can barely
see your hands when you're swimming.
Um,
and so you're just thinking this the
day.
Oh Dude.
Yeah.
I'm not interested in that.
I can't see why.
You know,
there's just something about sharks too.
I mean there,
to me,
one of the most terrifying thing for
it's first of all were so inept in the
water.
I mean,
even a person like you is a great
swimmer.
Yeah.
We're,
we're a joke.
Yeah.
What we are in comparison to what they
are.
It's just you're,
you're throwing yourself into the world
of a super predator.
And to know that one just jacked a
person just a few days before and you're
out there swimming.
Yeah.
Although I will say this,
you know,
when it's all said and done,
all of the close encounters I've had,
probably the scariest moment I've ever
had in the water was doing a swim from
Santa Rosa to Santa Barbara.
So Santa Rosa Island,
which is the second furthest North
Channel Island.
You've got San Miguel,
Santa Rosa,
Santa Cruz,
and Anacapa represent the top four
channel islands.
So we did this November swim.
It was a nighttime thing.
Again,
swimming from Santa Rosa Island to Santa
Barbara.
And uh,
at about five in the morning,
maybe six in the morning,
you're just starting to get enough light
where you can see and you're out there.
So you really have amazing visibility.
And I looked down probably 40 feet and I
see this enormous thing swimming like
this,
which is how sharks swim.
And I see the dorsal fin and the
position that freaks me out.
And the tails this way.
But all of that is shark,
right.
And I like,
you know,
like lift up out of the water,
kind of hyperventilate for a second.
And I'm thinking to myself,
all right,
you got to make a judgment call here.
If that's really a great white,
you probably ought to get out of the
water.
But if you,
the moment you are out of the water,
that's it.
The swim was over.
Like you just spent like months doing
this,
like it's done.
So then I convinced myself,
and I think I'm right.
I think it was a dolphin on its side
because a dolphin on its side with its
fin would get stale.
Fin would be the same way and it could
swim that way.
So in the end,
I just kept swimming.
But I mean,
that scared the shit out of me.
Well,
they have seen quite a few of them off
the coast of Malibu.
There's a,
Oh,
there's tons.
There's no question they're there.
They are way more plentiful than we
realize.
And all you can do is talk to the
fishermen.
Like the fishermen will tell you,
they're like,
you're like off core and auto.
I mean it's like nonstop great whites.
Really?
Oh yeah.
Why are you freaking me out?
The good news is they see us all the
time and most of the time they realize
we're not what they want.
They want seals.
Yeah.
The,
the,
whenever they attack us,
they're making a mistake.
Now is there a s like a suit you can
wear your Kevlar suit to protect,
protects you from getting bitten in
half?
No,
but this is so funny.
You bring this up.
I became obsessed with this thing called
the uh
oh,
what was it called?
Christ.
You,
you,
you put the thing on your ankle.
Like you had like a little velcro thing,
you'd wrap it on your ankle and had a
tail like this long,
you know,
like four foot long thing and it was
charged and it sends out an electrical
impulse that um,
disturbs the shit out of the sharks.
The sharks knows is an Oregon that
census electricity.
So when a shark,
like it could be pitch black,
it could be salt water and they can
still scope you ma,
you know,
from hundreds of yards away based on the
electrical activity of your heart.
And that Oregon is their nose.
So this little thing,
I forgot what it was called,
like the Shark Taser or some shit.
It puts out a signal that like tazes
them and they don't want to get within
like,
oh there it is.
James caught up here,
the world's first shark deterrent band.
It's called the shark bands worn on the
wrist or ankle it,
I don't know.
I thought it had a different name,
but because the one that I was going to
get and did a ton of research into,
had a really long tail hanging off it
and that became the problem.
He's uses patented magnetic technology
to repel sharks.
So the tail was a problem because of the
drag?
No,
because it would,
it sounds silly,
but it would come up and zap you in the
nuts.
So you'd be so they became unbearable to
practice swimming in this thing.
Cause you're like every 37 seconds you'd
get zapped by the tail.
Um,
and I was just like,
yes.
I like how it says reduced the risk.
Oh yeah.
Hey,
can I get some numbers?
Please
tell I went to see a reduced by how much
fy one,
7%.
Um,
and then it also is a leash for your
surfboard too.
You can use one of those,
the trap,
a tier,
a strapped to your ankle.
But
yeah,
no,
it's going to come to me like in an
hour.
I'll remember what this silly thing was.
Jamie.
You'll probably find it.
Yeah,
off of Catalina.
I know it's one of the best shark
fishing places in the world.
I have a friend of mine who told me that
if you think about like wild places on
earth that are just overrun with
predators and terrifying like Predator
prey activity.
Catalina island is one of the top spots
in the world.
I was like,
what are you talking about?
He's like,
I'm telling you man,
the shark fishing off Catalina Island is
fucking insane.
And then I watched a television show
just,
you know,
synchronicity a couple of days later and
it was these guys shark fishing off of
Catalina.
I was like,
what in the fuck?
I could have never guessed the catching
Makos mostly.
And it's actually my recollection
because we swam around Catalina ones as
well.
The backside is way more aggressive than
the front side.
The side that faces the Pacific side
they'd rather than face as Los Angeles.
Yeah,
there's way more crazy stuff out.
Yeah.
I think that's exactly where they were.
It looked pretty nuts.
I mean they were bringing in these 15
foot sharks.
I mean it was like,
what in the fuck?
These are just floating around out
there,
you know,
it's uh,
I mean,
I guess of course they are,
right.
I mean it's a,
there's a lot of fish out there as well,
so I'm sure they Adelina is amazing.
Pretty crazy.
I'd,
I'd swim to it,
I'd swam from it.
I just want him around it.
I'd done the only thing and I'd never
stepped foot on it except at the
beginning or end of a swim until five
years ago.
I went there for a vacation,
like actually just went to avalon for
you know,
three days.
I'm like,
it's not a place I could live.
It's a little too quiet,
but for three or four days.
It was amazing.
I think people hunt on Catalina.
They've got huge buffalo there.
Is that what it is?
Yeah,
so apparently there was a movie that was
made there back in the 20s or something
like that.
Let a bunch of Buffalo,
they had a bunch of Buffalo.
Yeah,
for the movie and I guess they never
liked to corral or something.
She shits is totally overrun with
Buffalo.
Well there was one of the channel
islands that they had actually turned
into a bow hunting destination.
Like they had brought in a bunch of
deer.
I think they brought in stags and a
bunch of weird exotic shit and they put
him on this island.
I think they even had elk and then
biologists just weren't having it.
They were like,
this is just so out of whack.
And so they had them eradicated and the
way they do that is it's pretty
gruesome.
They just gunned down from the air and
just leave the bodies.
Yeah.
They just decided that they were to
invasive species regardless of how
valuable they might have been.
Two people that wanted to go there and
eat them,
you know,
they just decided just for the ecosystem
alone,
it's just,
and there's no predators there and they
weren't going to turn the fucking island
to wild kingdom and bring wolves or
something in there,
which would be pretty God damn crazy.
Imagine if there was an island you go
and they just had wolves and elk running
around an island just,
well,
that's it.
I'm not surprised that we'd gotten them
all down.
At least say make it open season for
hunting or something like that.
They could have been productive about
it.
They,
that's an interesting perspective.
Cell Biologists look at it in terms of
the entire ecosystem,
right?
They look at in terms of the plants,
the amount of waste,
fecal waste,
if these animals are leaving behind the
fact that they're,
they're literally eating everything that
they can on the sound.
They're not supposed to be there.
And then they're competing with whatever
things are native to that island.
Yeah.
And probably,
I mean,
you've kind of thousand pound elk.
It's not supposed to be on a fucking
island.
This thing's just eating everything it
can and they don't,
they don't have a winter either.
So it's just like the whole,
like they're just not supposed to be.
The channel islands.
Islands
themselves are kind of amazing.
I mean,
most people know of Catalina,
but you know,
there's eight of them and now two of
them,
you can't step foot on a,
I think it's allowed to,
no,
San Clemente and San Nicolas through
military basis.
So we tried to do a swim from San
Nicolas back to Los Angeles.
This was a relay swim because it's like
an 85 mile swim.
And I spent like six months researching
it,
speaking to a bunch of naval officers.
I was like,
Hey,
is there any way we can cause you
officially to have to start a swim,
you have to be able to touch dry land
and be out of the water.
And they're like,
yeah,
you can't come on the island.
So in the end,
what we decided was we were just going
to do a stealth landing,
you know,
by the time they came down and screamed
at us and shot at us,
we'd have been off the island.
But,
uh,
then we got to the,
now the other big thing I've been
saying,
nick,
is that's real shark territory because
that's where the elephant seals live.
And so when we got out there,
we literally could not get to shore
because of the elephant seals.
Like we're,
we're 200 yards off sand neck.
And you know,
this is after I'd taken a full two days
to get out there.
I mean,
this place is really hard to get to
because the water is brutal and you're
not in a huge boat.
And,
uh,
yeah,
you're looking at like thousand pound
elephant seals that are just like
licking their chops,
looking at you,
trying to get in the water.
What would they do with you?
I didn't want to find out,
but they're not predatory,
right?
I mean I don't think I know.
I mean I think they're aggressive is
hell.
Did you see that video of the little
girl that's sitting on a dock and a seal
jumps up and grabs her in the ass and
pulled her under the water?
Do you ever see that Jamie?
Yeah,
and I didn't think that seals ever did
something like that before.
I Dunno.
I did see a special once about how
dolphins could be kind of aggressive
with each other.
Like they could harm,
you know Lou,
this is,
the seal is sitting there and this girl
see line actually look at this.
It comes up and they think,
yeah,
but I think it was probably looking for
a handout and these people weren't
giving it to her.
Oh.
And then she turns her,
he says,
yeah,
fuck that thing.
I'd be like,
I'd be right back.
Fill that fucking puddle with led.
That was fast.
Yeah.
They jumped up fast.
They,
they're predators.
I mean,
they eat things.
Yeah.
The 19 plants in the water,
they're eating fish and shit,
you know,
whatever they can get ahold of.
They probably birds and stuff too.
They're probably used to scoop and
things up,
but I bet that what that's from is them
getting to acclimated to people.
Yeah.
Feeding them.
Oh,
sure.
Yeah.
There's a,
they have an issue in boulder where
boulder is a,
if you're been Colorado.
Yeah,
yeah.
Beautiful.
Right.
Gorgeous.
Super Liberal.
Like as progressive as it gets.
Right.
You ever been to San Francisco?
Oh,
I have.
Yeah.
I think boulder is right up there,
but there's less people in there that,
you know,
everyone's real healthy and active and
hiking and stuff like that.
They don't allow hunting for mountain
goats on the weekends because there's so
many people hiking and going.
They don't want people killing these
mountain goats in front of them because
people freak out.
Even though they have decided that they
have to control the population and kill
a certain number of them to keep the,
um,
but so many people go out there that
these things aren't scared of people.
So it's created this really weird
situation where if you are hunting them,
you're,
you're almost hunting something that's
domesticated.
People feed them cheetos.
So much so that a friend of mine was
talking about it,
that he was up there with his daughter.
His daughter opened up a bag of cheetos
and the goat walked right to a wild
goat,
lives out in the fucking woods,
walked right up to his daughter and they
were laughing.
She opened up the bag of cheetos and put
it and he stuffed his head in the bag of
cheetos.
He knew what to do.
And he's in this guy who was talking
about this is a hunter and he's like,
this fucking goat has like cheeto dust
all over its face.
Like it's the craziest thing.
It's face is all red with a cheeto dust.
And it's sitting there chewing these
cheat,
like it's done it before and it's just
read that goat had diabetes I think
probably eventually,
right?
Yeah.
I was in Costa Rica.
This is another similar situation and we
were staying at this four seasons out
there and the monkeys have gotten very
accustomed to people being there.
And so,
um,
they come by and they hang out and they
were like trying to get things from you.
And um,
my daughter opened up a package oreos
and the monkey just jumped onto this
little ledge,
like a couple feet away from her.
And uh,
and my wife was like,
I really don't think it's a good idea
that we feed this thing oreos.
And I said,
wow,
you know,
it's probably going to get eaten by a
fucking crocodile anyway.
I mean,
it's going to food poisoning it.
Is that what you're thinking?
I mean,
it's not going to eat this every day.
It's not going to be a normal part of
its diet.
But we hand the monkey and Oreo,
it pops open the Oreo and starts chewing
on the frosting like a little kid.
And then we're like,
oh,
this little fucker probably gets these
things every week.
Right,
so it begs the question,
does he know how to do that?
Because he's watched some human do it,
or we innately wired to do that with
Oreos.
Ooh.
I think he knows how to do it because
someone's giving them Oreos so many
times.
Then he knows that the good stuff,
the good stuff,
the mental,
they should just sell that at a pace.
I don't know.
I think it'd be good.
I think.
I think the middle is only good because
you can,
you can contrast it with the,
it comes back to the contrast.
Exactly.
Yes.
Thank you.
Right.
I think you're really right.
I think it was just pure middle.
It'd be pretty gross.
If they probably sold pure middle,
nobody would buy it,
but if they sold those black cookies by
themselves,
no one by those fucking gross things
either.
Like should.
Yeah.
This gets worse.
Cookies like those key,
what'd you eat?
The white stuff.
You're like,
all right,
I'll eat this stupid ass black cookie.
It's a sunk cost and Cole cookie.
Here it is.
Here's a little monkey doing it.
Look,
they grab it from you and they just
fucking love o worry.
Look,
they look at him opening up,
immediately open it up and start chewing
that white stuff.
Yeah.
Crazy.
And we had,
um,
there's a thing that is called the
[inaudible] Monday.
Have you ever heard of those?
It's a,
it's related to the raccoon.
It's this weird animal that lives mostly
in central and South America and it has
a northern range that extends into
Arizona all the way up into Mesa.
I think,
um,
like it gets into the areas where it
gets cold.
But Arizona I think is the only state in
the u s that has it.
But it's this weird looking monkey
raccoon thing that is so domesticated
that we gave it some grapes.
Here it is.
We gave it some grapes and this little
fucker,
there it is.
I mean,
look at that weird little thing.
It came and uh,
sat,
we had like a little,
a patio area in the hotel room and he
came and sat down with us and so calm
that it sat and went underneath one of
the chairs.
And took a nap after we gave it some
grapes,
like while we're hanging around,
my daughters are running around making
noise and this thing's just chilling.
It's like a pet.
It was a total pet.
Yeah.
There they are.
They're cool man.
Weird looking things.
People eat them apparently.
Apparently they hunt them in Arizona.
He's eating Nachos.
Yeah.
I mean after seeing this as just like,
I don't think I can hunt that.
I'd have to be pretty hungry to eat one
of those.
They're so cute.
Little face,
weird little animal man.
Really interesting.
Yeah.
Our relationship with animals is very
odd when they get into close proximity.
Yeah.
We,
we've got a wicked coyote problem and
San Diego and at least in the part I
live in and you know,
it's just one of those things once we
got rid of mountain lions,
because nobody wants mountain lions
around the coyotes running a muck.
Is that what it is?
I think,
I mean I was talking to a friend of mine
about this the other day actually,
and he was saying that there's probably
only like in our neighborhood there's
probably only like two mountain lions
left and the,
the coyotes just,
they've exploded there.
There's so many of them around.
Like it doesn't really bother me that
much.
I mean I could kind of like listening to
them howl,
but you know,
if you,
if they get into your chicken coop.
Yeah,
I had one killed chickens just a few
weeks ago.
Yeah,
yeah.
I have a got video of a dead chicken.
It's such a bummer man.
We chase it away.
It was on the roof of the chicken coop.
The way they jump,
it's so stunning.
Like they're so graceful.
Like I've never seen anything that moves
like that in the wild.
The way it coyote does,
they,
there was a six foot fence.
It's on the ground.
It jumps to the top of the six foot
fence,
almost like it's,
it's under different gravity rules than
us and touches the top of the fence and
then boom,
it's on the top of the chicken coop.
I mean in like a second,
like I haven't seen that.
That would be,
yeah,
it's crazy.
I have video of one of them jumping my
fence.
Um,
I caught one of them with a chicken in
his mouth,
jumping the fence,
jumped the six foot fence with a chicken
in his mouth.
Just jump point,
touch the top of the fence with his
front paws back.
Paws went over right behind it and it
was gone.
It's crazy.
Um,
but you know,
look,
they,
we need them.
We need them to kill the rabbits and the
rats.
And if we didn't,
we'd have a giant,
like here's what,
that's what I tell my daughter,
cause she,
she like gets all stressed out that
there's coyotes and around walking
around her house.
And I was like,
well first of all,
they're pretty skittish of us.
And boy,
they keep those roads under control.
They really do.
You need them for that.
But there's a coyote problem across the
country.
They're the only animal that's in every
single state in every single city.
Now,
every single city,
there's,
there's coyotes in Manhattan.
Come on,
I'm not bullshitting in the park.
They've found them in the park.
They found them in the bronx.
They found them in abandoned buildings.
Yeah,
there's a great book I read called
America by a past guests of the podcast,
Dan Flores.
He's a a wildlife historian,
so it's fascinating.
There are really,
really unusual animal in that.
When you shoot one,
they yell out,
here's this wizards,
coyotes in New York City.
Look at this in fucking New York City.
Dude,
she hit in New York City,
New York City Police Department.
Coyote running down the street.
Yeah,
they're everywhere,
man.
They have,
they have a real problem with them in
Chicago.
I thought I could escape them when I'm
in New York.
No,
you can't escape them anywhere.
They're in all 50 states now.
They've completely extended the range.
And the reason why they extended their
range is because we,
we went after them.
We hunted them down.
You know,
they were able to eradicate wolves and
the way they were able to eradicate
wolves is they would kill the Alpha and
then they would take a,
an animal like a horse,
they would shoot it and then they would
fill it up with strict nine.
And so then they would rub the Alpha,
the body of the Alpha all over this,
this carcass of the horse.
And then the other wolves would come and
smell that the Alpha had been there and
then they would eat the wolf or eat the
horse rather and die.
And so they were able to do this and
essentially use this method plus
shooting them and things like that to
eradicate them from the west.
Because of ranchers and cattle farmers,
they've never been able to do that with
coyotes.
When you shoot a coyote,
if they do roll call,
like when you hear them howling,
if one of them is missing,
it's sends the females,
it sends some sort of a signal where
their bodies produce more pups.
So if ones missing,
instead of having like three pups,
she'll have six.
So you make more coyotes when you kill
them and they extend the range.
When you persecute them,
they just extend their range.
It's,
they're fucking crazy animal.
They are wicked smart man.
They've been chewing at the roof of my
chicken coop,
trying to get in.
I came outside the other night,
my dog,
I have a,
I have three dogs,
but one of them is a golden retriever
and that dog has fucking zero instincts.
I mean it's,
it is just,
it's a little human.
It's like,
it's like a little marshmallow.
It's just a,
yeah.
So he's fun.
No go running with and stuff.
He's a great dog sweetheart of a dog.
Great pet.
But like,
he's like,
what's going on over there?
What's happening?
There's a fucking coyote on the roof,
dude.
What do you mean what's going on over
there?
They're literally chewing the shingles
off the roof outside.
One job to do.
He'll bark.
He's not interested.
He's just one.
He's only a year old too,
but he's just curious.
You know,
it's uh,
it's,
it's very weird living in proximity with
all these things because where I live,
you know,
we have a lot of hawks,
lot of owls,
lot of coyotes and occasionally amount
line.
And I've seen,
I saw a bobcat once,
which is pretty interesting.
I've never seen one of those.
They're weird looking.
So we're looking thing to see one of a
friend of mine,
um,
I put it up on instagram.
Cvu find it.
It's fucking old.
It's an old one on instagram.
Um,
a friend of mine had a coyote or a
bobcat break into her chicken coop and
kill every one of our chickens and the
coyote.
There it is.
Look at that fucking freaky bitch.
How'd you find it so quick?
You're an animal.
Jamie's a bobcat.
Just get the best searching skills of
all time.
But look at that.
That's in my friends.
Chicken coop.
He says a bunch of murder chickens
scattered around it.
Look in that things face.
Yeah.
Fuck that.
That look is fuck you.
Yeah,
they'll look is fuck you lady.
Yeah.
It killed your chickens.
Why you have mount side.
Ooh.
Ah,
crazy man.
So,
uh,
how do you know Jocko does,
is how we got connected to the folks at
home.
So John's like,
prepare to get your brain blown out on
the side.
My friend over,
I said,
all right,
let's do it.
So,
uh,
I met Jocko through one of my really
close friends,
a guy named Kirk Parsley,
who's a,
also a navy seal,
a former seal.
And um,
Kirk said,
hey,
you gotta meet my friend Jocko.
Basically it's just like you guys,
you just gotta meet Jocko.
You just have to experience Jocko.
That was basically,
it was like a ride.
Yeah.
So,
so I'm at Jocko,
we obviously connected pretty quickly.
And then,
um,
I think,
oh,
this was before Jockos book had come,
his first first book had come out and I
said,
I got to introduce you to one of my best
friends,
this Guy Tim Ferriss,
who I'm obviously,
you know,
tim.
And um,
cause Tim's always looking for,
you know,
a great guest on a podcast.
And so I called Tim and I said,
look,
you got to just trust me on this one.
Sight unseen.
Just have Jocko come to San Francisco
next week.
Just I don't need to say anything else.
It will be worth it.
And I,
luckily I had enough credit in the bank
with Tim.
I'd done it.
I'd been successful on enough sight,
unseen recommendations,
but I think the Jocko when was the best
one ever,
because he called me after he called me
while Jocko was still there and he's
like,
yeah,
that was pretty intense.
Yeah.
I send them an email after that podcast
on my,
that's one of the best podcasts I've
ever heard in my life and I made a post
about it.
Chaco responded to the post and then I
got Jocko on and then I end,
Tim convinced Jocko to do his own
podcasts.
Yeah.
And now it's huge.
I mean,
his podcast,
I get text messages all the time from
people thanking me for telling them to
listen to it.
And then I get tweets from people
thanking me for talking Jocko in it,
doing it because it's just this app.
Just,
just,
there's outliers in this world,
you know,
in,
in everything.
There's outliers in athletics,
there's out.
But when it comes to like discipline and
motivation and just,
just when you look at someone who is
just undeniable,
like Jocko is one of those guys,
he's just undeniable.
He's,
he's a specimen.
He's definitely
off the graph.
Yeah.
I'd met him a long time ago when,
uh,
he was training with Dean lister and
dean was fighting in the UFC.
I remember meeting him and I'm like,
what's that guy's deal?
Certain dudes that have got that whole
lot of shit going on behind their eyes.
You're like,
okay,
guys seen some stuff,
you know.
Yeah,
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you a funny Jocko story.
I don't think I,
I guess I can tell this story in public.
It's pretty funny.
So Jocko was in New York.
I just,
after his book came out and um,
you know this and I was like,
look,
I want to,
I want to juice you.
Some of my,
my,
my buddies who run hedge funds here,
because some,
a lot of what Jocko does is they,
you know,
he and his partner,
they consult with,
with guys like this doing leadership
stuff.
And so we went up to the offices of one
of my friends who has this very famous
hedge fund.
And his office is like on the 50th floor
on park.
And it's looking at,
it's like a beautiful view down park and
we're just,
and we're just sitting there in his
office just shooting the shit.
And I forget how it came up,
but somehow,
um,
we were just talking about like,
like how good is a sniper?
Like what does it actually take?
And,
um,
and then of course we're,
we're talking very specifically about,
um,
I can't believe I'm blanking on his
name.
Um,
Chris,
I'm the Bradley Cooper played him in.
Yeah,
Chris Kyle were talking cause cause
Chris Kyle had been,
um,
part of Jockos uh,
team.
Uh,
I forget which seal team,
maybe it was he when he was seal team
two.
But,
um,
in fact,
I think Jocko said,
he goes,
you know,
yeah.
Chris was a part of my team for more of
his kills than any of his other kills.
And so then we were like,
like what sets him apart?
I mean,
obviously any snow navy seal sniper has
gotta be amazing.
But Chris took it to another level.
What,
what was it?
And He,
and he said,
okay,
let me show you what it was.
So he said,
we walked us over to the window and he
goes,
okay,
you see that guy in that hat over there?
Like about a mile down the,
you know,
you can basically see it cause we're
like a pink hat or something.
I said,
yeah.
He goes,
okay,
if you're a sniper,
you gotta be able to lay down,
not move and put your eye up against
this thing and like look out at him and
you can't,
if you ever take your eye off that
you're going to lose the sight.
So you gotta be able to stay in that
position and I'm moving to it.
He goes,
I forgot what the number was,
but Jocko said the average navy seal
sniper can stay in that position without
moving.
I glued to the site for x number of
minutes and I forgot what the number
was.
Maybe it was like 15 minutes.
He's like,
Chris could do that for two hours.
He could lay in that position,
not moving and not taking his eye off
that thing with one eye shut for hours
and he,
you know,
he's just like,
he just had a different,
he just had a different gear and um,
it was just an amazing,
I mean,
I mean those are some of my favorite
moments with Jocko is when he like can
tell you something that is like,
like they're like maybe three people in
the world that would understand why that
matters.
You know,
sniping is fat is really fascinating,
right?
Because just sharp shooting,
just being able to shoot something at a
distance and long distance shooting is
a,
it's,
it's a big sport.
I mean for,
in terms of target shooting,
I mean there's guys that are out there,
they're shooting 1500 yards
and doing it competitively.
That's a crazy distance.
Amazing.
It's crazy distance.
But when you think about it,
you got a rifle,
it's on arrest,
you're sitting,
you're either on a bench or you're prone
or whatever it is.
You're lying down most of the time.
This is all it is.
It's this with your finger pull,
pull,
boom.
Some people are way better at that.
Just think of that coordinating your
vision,
getting the radical set on the target,
polling that and without movement.
The outliers are the people who can do
that.
And you've got to think like when you,
when you break down physical movements,
right?
Like he watched gymnastics routine in
the Olympics,
like holy shit and it flips and the land
and they stick and it's incredible.
But now break it down to just the
movement of your trigger finger,
pull,
play,
no movement.
You know,
I mean it's,
I'm sure you've shot guns,
but it's hard to like if you shoot
pistols and you have dummy rounds,
you know,
like a lot of people and they mix in
dummy rounds so that they find out that
they're a jerk and a trigger.
And when you see,
like I was watching a video with,
um,
Tim Kennedy and Tim Kennedy was a
shooting at the range and he's,
he's pulling bang,
Bang,
and it goes click.
And he goes,
Woo,
look at that trigger control like it.
Cause it was,
he put,
the way he pulled it,
it didn't go off target,
it didn't move.
It was it,
there was no punch to it,
you know,
but you gotta fucking practice for
forever just to be able to do that.
Just to not anticipate the recoil of the
gun and Yank and move and twitch and
just controlling the mind.
I mean,
it's a fascinating thing to me that
just,
just pulling this one thing or you would
think fucking anybody could do that.
I can show you how to do that.
You know,
like,
like I've had friends that say they want
to go hunting.
Uh,
you know,
I want to go hunting.
You know what,
what do I do?
Where do I get a boat?
I'm like,
slow down.
Let's get your rifle.
Because I could teach you how to shoot a
rifle.
We could,
we could get someone that we could cite
in your rifle,
go to the range,
we'll cite it in under a hundred yards,
get ya a good accurate rifle.
And then all you have to do is kind of
keep it together.
A rifle,
we get into a hundred yards of a wild
pig,
you're going to be able to kill this
thing 100% you got years before you're
gonna be able to shoot that thing with a
bow.
I mean,
fucking years.
First of all it is,
and the bow is like,
my wife said this to me awhile ago,
she said,
of all the things you do,
she's like,
archery seems to be the only one where
even if you don't have a good day,
you're still happy.
Like if I,
if I,
if I'm on the race track and I'm driving
a race car or if I'm,
you know,
swimming or whatever,
and I just have a bad day,
like I don't,
I'm just not firing on all cylinders
like it,
you know,
just kind of pisses me off.
Right?
There's something about archery where
even if I'm not having a good day,
like
maybe it's an extension of what you're
talking about with the trigger finger.
So for me,
I got an artery because of tim and the
story
that the thing that he told me,
which obviously for anyone who has,
yeah.
The thing that he told me that
immediately made me be like,
I want to do this.
It was just anything that requires that
much perfection just seems great.
And he was like,
yeah,
you don't take a shot unless you can
kill the animal.
Like,
you know?
And so like you might take one shot in
two days,
like it's,
it's gotta be a kill shot and the kill
shots got to look like x,
y,
and Z.
And I was like,
oh,
that's like you gotta be dialed in.
So it was this idea of back tension,
you know,
it was sort of like,
wow,
you're taking a perfect shot.
Like it's all in the Rhomboids,
you know,
it's all back here and you've got to be
able to do,
as you said,
you've got to completely be able to
eliminate any anticipation,
any of this business.
And Yeah.
And so I think that,
I think of archery for me is almost like
a meditation.
Like,
if you,
like I'm talking in the way,
like Sam Harris would talk about sort of
consciousness and the way you are so
hyper aware of what you're doing that
yes,
you can daydream and your mind can
wander.
But if you actually start to imagine the
sensations of every part of archery,
in many ways it feels like meditating.
So I think that's why I'm just like,
you know,
and I never really thought about it with
shooting a rifle.
Um,
cause I don't have much experience with
guns,
but I'm guessing it's very similar.
But as you said,
like the,
the,
the difference between the good and the
great and that is less obvious,
you know,
at a distance.
Yeah.
I think a offhand shooting a rifle and
shooting a bow,
I bet.
Um,
just as accurate at 60 yards as the
average person is not a sniper,
but the average person with a rifle,
you can be pretty fucking accurate.
You can't off a bench.
So there's,
there's some similarities.
There's,
there's a similarity to having the,
you have to have perfect technique.
You have to have the right stance.
You have to make sure that you know
everything's locked in and your,
your structure is correct.
But I agree with you that I think it's
some sort of a meditation.
I also think there's something to
hitting a target that is in our DNA
that's connected to hunting,
that's connected to survival,
that's connected to the thousands of
years that people through arrows and
fucking what did that,
what does that thing called?
What's that thing called?
That they had a lot of,
yeah.
Is that,
I say that Atlatl right?
Yeah.
You know what I'm talking about?
That's like a,
an advanced spear throwing thing and
then archery and just,
I think when a person would hit a deer,
they knew their tribe was going to eat.
Right.
And so there's this like charge and you
get a small amount of that juice when
you hit a target.
Yeah,
no,
I'm sure there's,
there's gotta be dopamine that's being
secreted when we send to do that.
It's the greatest feeling in the world.
It shouldn't make sense.
Like when you looking at someone doing
it,
you're like,
what do you give a fuck if that Arrow
goes in there?
It doesn't make any sense.
Like why does it make sense?
But there's a fucking sat like Jamie
laughs at me cause I'll hit the bullseye
from 45 yards.
And I'm like,
yes.
It's like you get this little Whoa,
you get a little a little burst man.
I just liked the whole experience,
even the sound.
So sometimes like when my veins get
holes in them,
like sometimes you put a broadhead
through or are you put like a field tip
through another one.
And now obviously sometimes if you trash
the vein,
the air,
it doesn't work.
But like usually just a single hole and
a vein,
we'll produce a sound that is the
greatest sound you've ever heard when
that Arrow leaves to whistle.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I love it.
So when certain broadheads certain
vented broadheads they whistle,
it was still too much.
They give you all the heads up.
Yeah.
So that whole experience of like the
perfect release,
you know,
even when you surprise yourself,
like I've been,
I switched over to this Carter
revolution release about a back tension
release.
Yeah.
It's the most pure back tension.
It's better than the honey.
Cause the honey,
you could still cheat a little bit.
You know,
if you were getting lazy,
you could twist,
twist and exactly right.
But the evolution,
there is no cheating.
Right.
You can't,
you so you,
you can surprise yourself with a shot.
Yeah.
So there's no anticipation.
That's,
you can't explain this to people who
don't do it.
And you notice that now you can't,
they're like,
what are you rambling about?
Boring the shit out of me.
I have tried to explain this to people
who don't know what I'm talking about.
I was trying to explain it to Alexander
Gustafson,
who's in here the other day and he's a
hunter too.
And he,
but he only hunts in Sweden.
You can't bow hunt.
It's not legal.
Oh.
And uh,
uh,
he wanted to learn how to shoot a bow.
And so I was explaining that I put my
finger on this trigger.
My fingers sits on the trigger.
I use a Carter too.
I use it a first choice.
It's the name of the race.
I go my finger and my thumb is on the
trigger,
but I never squeeze it.
Yup.
The squeezing is all done with my back
cause I pull,
then it just goes off and look,
you can see his head was like,
why?
Why would you?
But you could just do that.
Right.
Why don't you just do that?
You don't know.
It's so counter intuitive.
But um,
once I got into it,
Tim actually sent me this book on back
tension and then I just devoured it.
I mean it was sort of like the reading
the Penny Dean Book,
you know,
is tim doing this a lot now?
Not as much as he should be.
Um,
but uh,
trying to hunt with it.
Yeah.
Tim,
oh,
hunt.
And um,
I actually got it so far.
I know he's,
he's hunting rifles.
No,
no,
no.
He's hot.
He goes,
he's,
he's been on bow hunting trips.
That's in fact what got me into it
because about two years ago,
he was getting ready to go to a trip do
at five day trip in Colorado.
And he called me and said,
um,
hey,
I want to talk with you about like some
training and some nutrition to like get
ready for this because it's going to be
kind of an extreme whole deal.
You know,
you're at altitude,
you're running around like crazy.
You've got to be able to like,
like sprint and then be totally relaxed.
And so he's like,
you know,
can you help me think about how to train
and what the nutrition would be?
And I said,
okay,
tell me more about what the demands are.
And the more he told me,
the more I was like,
why am I not doing this?
This sounds really fricking awesome.
So that's so,
uh,
and he's got an awesome video of,
of,
uh,
of this.
Uh,
he took,
I mean probably he only took one shot
and like the whole five day trip and it
was a perfect kill.
It kill.
It was a huge bird and I can't even
remember what it works.
Yeah.
It was like a bird on the ground,
like some huge ass bird,
but it wasn't a Turkey.
It was like,
I don't remember what it was,
but the shot,
he was like,
you know,
it was one of those things where it was
like,
cause it,
you know,
like all my practices on stationary
targets,
right.
So it's a totally new dimension when
it's like the things doing this.
So it was flying.
It was,
it was like kind of like either running
on the ground or about to fly or
something.
Anybody hit it in motion.
I mean,
it was a great shot.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Wonder what the fuck that would be.
I don't know what it was.
I'll have to ask him.
Big Bird in North America.
Did he shoot a fucking eagle to shooting
the Pelican?
Definitely wasn't me.
Yeah.
I was reading something about the goose
problem about,
uh,
how the goose population has exploded
because,
uh,
farmlands and that,
they,
they literally don't,
they don't know what to do with the
certain population of different kinds of
geese that are flying into this country
from Canada.
It's funny to say this.
I was in Toronto,
um,
three weeks ago and it,
which is where I'm from and though I
don't go off,
and we were,
I was with my brother and we were up
taking the kids to some place and sure
enough,
like we're walking from one area to the
other and these geese come up and they
kind of start posturing.
And I'm thinking,
what the fuck?
And my brother's like,
Gavin moving.
Clearly one of us is near one of their
eggs.
And I was like,
why?
He's like,
Oh yeah.
He goes,
these are the most aggressive creatures
and they're big.
They're pretty big.
So I was like,
fair enough.
Let's just keep walking.
Don't make eye contact.
They're big,
but you can cook them,
so fuck them.
Get out of here.
God Damn Geese.
Yeah.
Um,
there's a,
there's a certain type of geese that
they call Ribeye in the sky because they
have a delicious red meat to them.
What does that call which fucking God
damn it.
Um,
but they're very plentiful in Texas.
Yeah.
They hunt them in Texas and they,
they literally,
it's the meat,
like is it modeled?
It looks like a Ribeye.
It's crazy.
Sandhill cranes.
You sandhill crane.
That's what it is.
It's not something you don't know.
He's a fucking wizard with the Google
massly with Google.
Everyone is a wizard,
but Jamie's an extra wizard.
He's really getting at an India.
Yeah.
But that is what they call them.
So it's,
um,
it's actually a common phrase because
it,
I've had friends that say it might be
the most delicious meat in the world.
I mean,
it tastes like a,
like a,
like a wad Gu ribeye and it's flying
around and you could shoot like fucking
10 a day.
It's crazy.
Like I have friends that hunt these
things and you know,
they're fun.
They're mostly in
Texas.
I don't know where they are,
but my friends who have hunted them,
hunted them in Texas and I'm sure they
fly all across the country.
But it,
yeah,
it's a crane.
It's not a goose.
Yeah.
I've never been,
I've only been bird hunting twice.
I went once with Anthony Bordain,
uh,
for his TV show.
We hunted pheasants and he shot one and
then we cooked it and ate it.
That was fun.
I shot at one and missed and then I shot
a Turkey once,
which is pretty interesting.
Wild Turkeys.
Very good.
Very delicious.
But um,
you know,
it's,
um,
when I,
I like mammals,
I like eating mammals.
I prefer,
I prefer red meat.
I think it's just better for you.
I think it's more nutritious.
It's more exhilarating.
There's something about the,
the meat itself,
just,
it tastes better.
No,
I haven't met too many foods.
I don't like really,
you just sit and eat it.
Well,
with the kind of exercise that you do,
I'm sure you're,
you almost have a voracious appetite.
Uh,
I mean,
I do,
but nothing like what I used to be.
And I fast pretty much every day doing
16 hours.
What are you doing?
Um,
it depends.
So when I'm in,
I split my time between New York and
California.
When I'm in New York,
it's absolutely one meal a day,
no ifs,
ands or buts because it's just the
schedule is such that,
you know,
I'm seeing patients in the morning and
afternoon and I don't want to do,
I don't want to waste time to eat.
So what do you doctor in?
Uh,
cause that's a good question.
I mean,
uh,
I trained as a surgeon and did cancer
surgery.
Uh,
but I,
my practice is based on longevity.
So it's sort of how do you apply
nutrition,
exercise,
sleep,
stress management,
endocrinology,
lipid,
Ology,
supplements,
hormones,
all that stuff.
Like how do you engineer,
how to make somebody live longer as soon
as my clinical interest.
Um,
so yeah,
so in New York I eat one meal a day,
so it's basically like a 22 hour fasting
window and then I'm feeding within a two
hour window.
Wow.
When I'm here.
Um,
it's about this,
well,
I mean,
yesterday and today it's the same.
Like,
you know,
today it's just been kind of a busy day.
I won't eat until dinner tonight,
but,
um,
my short fast would be 16 hours where I
would eat kind of short fat.
That would be a short,
fast one for me really to do.
You got to get in touch with your
evolutionary.
So I had this discussion with a friend
this morning because he was saying to
me,
he can't do 16 hours.
Well he's a pussy.
No.
And I was like,
my studies a puzzle.
You just told them no,
but I said,
you got to understand if,
if our ancestors couldn't function when
they were hungry,
we wouldn't be here.
So it's,
it's not just that starvation,
uh,
short term adaptation to starvation is,
is necessary.
It's probably beneficial.
Uh,
in other words,
you know,
during these short periods of
deprivation of food,
you know,
we get just a little bit more
epinephrine and Norepinephrine,
we just get a little bit sharper,
a little bit better.
Um,
I,
I can't even,
I can't even remember what it's like to
eat three meals a day.
It's been so long,
really.
I mean I've been doing crazy shit for 10
years.
Nutritional wise.
Like I'm gonna spend three years in
ketosis where we go from a one day I was
in Ketosis for three years.
Um,
lots of fasting,
but I think intermittent fasting or time
restricted feeding probably at least
five years.
And what does for people listening,
what are the benefits of that?
Well,
I mean if you're,
if we're going to get really technical,
we have to be clear that I think a lot
of the benefits are overstated and a lot
of the benefits or things that we've
only studied in animals.
So there's a guy named Satchin panda at
the Salk Institute in San Diego who's I
think one of the world's experts on time
restricted feeding.
But
you know,
for example,
a 16 hour fast and a mouse produces
unbelievable results.
If you take a group of,
you know,
certain types of mice are strains of
rats or other rodents and you in a 24
hour period period,
deprive them of any nutrient for 16
hours,
but then for eight hours,
let them eat whatever the hell they
want.
They can't gain weight.
So,
um,
and the,
and the reason we think is that it,
once you give a long enough period of
time when the animal can ramp up,
it's uh,
the like the enzymes in the liver that
are responsible for fat oxidation.
I mean they just basically become fat
burn.
I hate that term fat burning machine.
It's so overused,
but that's bay.
They basically just become unbelievably
efficient at metabolizing fat.
So,
um,
we have to be careful that when we
extrapolate that,
cause you and I have a very different
metabolism than a mouse,
like a 16 hour fast to a mouse is much
longer than it is to us.
So I don't know if those benefits would
extend.
Um,
also it's not entirely clear the time
restricted feeding will produce the
longevity benefit that we see in other
sort of fasting or fasting mimicking
types of diets.
Um,
so for me,
what it comes down to is,
I mean,
honestly,
it's just an easier way.
It gives me a much more liberty with
what I eat during my feeding window.
I don't have to be nearly as restrictive
when I'm feeding.
Um,
if I have that period off it just,
just in terms of like my physiologic
response.
Secondly,
there's a convenience thing.
Like I kind of hate being tethered to
eat.
I like knowing that hey,
if I get into a pinch,
like I don't have to eat right now and
if I'm sitting on the airplane and
they're serving dog shit,
I don't have to eat.
I can wait another five hours until I
eat.
Um,
I also just feel much more steady in my
energy levels.
I,
I kind of vaguely remember like 10 years
ago when I was kind of like eating a
normal diet,
how I always had this low in energy
after lunch.
Like there is the post lunch,
pre dinner.
I just don't feel good.
Like not that I feel bad,
but like I'm not sharp.
I'm not in my a game and I don't even
remember what that feels like anymore,
which is not to say I feel great all the
time,
but I definitely don't have that
vacillating energy level.
Yeah.
I've said that to be,
but when I eliminated most carbs from my
diet,
you know,
and I have a friend of mine who you
talked to his trainer about that and his
trainers like you're crazy.
Eat bread,
eat pasta,
don't listen to him like no,
don't listen to him.
Like just,
just google it.
That stuff's fucking terrible for you.
If you want to eat carbohydrates,
get it from fruits,
you know,
get it from some natural sources.
But just if you have a trainer that's
telling you to eat bread,
get a new fucking trainer.
Cause it's just,
it's not what you need.
And it's nothing wrong with eating if
you want to occasionally and in small
doses.
But when I eliminated most of that stuff
from my diet,
I felt the exact same thing.
I felt that midday nap desire go away
and they're just the fogginess about
like you at the end of the day like,
Oh God,
I'm fucking tired.
And then I'd have to drink a cup of
coffee to get ramped back up again.
And this is like never ending cycle of
having this insulin spike and then this
crash.
And that is,
uh,
that's from carbohydrates.
It's from refined carbohydrates and you
know,
having too much fucking sugar in your
body and everybody does it.
It's like,
oh,
this will be funny for your,
so,
so google my name and just put like
Peter Attia fat and um,
you'll,
you're,
you're going to see a picture of me when
I was a swimmer because all this time we
were talking about me swimming.
You're assuming like I'm a fit dude.
I was fit but fat dude,
fitbit,
fat fit but totally fat.
And this is what you eating.
Oh,
nonstop carbs.
But they're there.
I am.
See on the left there,
well I wouldn't say you're fat.
I would say you got got a little paunch
anya.
I Dunno.
Wait,
wait,
there's another picture,
uh,
after I swim across Lake Tahoe,
go to that.
That one right there.
Yeah,
go gut there fella.
I Dunno.
It's like you boozing it up,
but it's also the way you're sitting
down.
Stood up,
sucked it in for a picture on instagram.
Might look okay.
I don't know.
I was definitely,
you know,
probably what?
Maybe 30 pounds heavier.
Wow.
But,
but,
but you know,
body fat was much greater and what were
you eating?
Oh,
I mean I probably went through three or
four bottles of power,
a two day training all day and you know
every postworkout was a carvery feed and
so you're in sort of this vicious
glycogen dependent state people that
it's,
it's crazy that there's so many folks
out there that are living their life
that don't even understand that this is
a process they're going through.
They just think this is eating and
exercise.
This is what happens,
but it's not your body lit.
If you shot,
cut that off,
push it away,
enter into a completely different food
source.
Just change the way you,
you eat,
your body will change and that that just
that concept that people,
that sounds like horseshit it sounds
like,
what are you saying you you're what are
you offering some miracle cure your
already?
No,
I'm saying you will change the dimension
of life that you operate in.
It will change because you won't be the
same person.
You won't like who you are is dependent
upon a lot of things.
But one of them is how much energy you
have and how you feel,
whether you're crashing,
if you change the way you eat,
you change the energy you have,
you changed the,
you feel
it'll change.
Your behavior will change your choices,
it'll change your ambitions,
it'll change your potential.
I mean,
there's so many things that will change.
But there's an interesting question
which I've,
I've,
I,
I spend some time thinking about and
I've sort of accepted the fact that we
might not know the answer,
which is when I was growing up,
I was exercising like crazy.
Not as much as I was when I was
swimming,
but I mean,
sorry,
more than I was when I was swimming,
but I ate like I had the world's worst
diet growing up,
so I would eat breakfast was a bowl of,
um,
like a box of cereal.
So I'd take like one of these tupperware
bowls.
It was this big and fill it with a full
box.
So each day I would have just a box of
cocoa puffs or whatever.
I would start the day.
And then lunch was a full loaf of bread,
which would seven sandwiches plus a
plate of fries,
plus a big tub of like,
like a two liter jug of orange juice.
But I was training six hours a day,
right?
So I would,
you know,
run 10 miles in the morning in the gym,
boxing like it was,
you know,
you know what that shit is like.
I mean,
it's ridiculously energy expending.
But the point is,
I had a hard time holding my weight and
I was a middleweight one 60 walked
around at one 58 who walks around below
their fight weight.
So,
you know,
my waist was 28 inches.
I was probably four and a half percent
body fat.
And I was eating anything and everything
you could put in front of me.
And then something happened in medical
school where that shit just stopped and
I wasn't even eating as badly at the
time.
But all of a sudden the metabolic
adaptation just vanished.
And you know,
I mean,
I wish someone had,
could study this,
meaning you would have to take a group
of individuals and do muscle and fat
biopsies over their course of their
life,
or at least during this window when we
think this is happening.
And I think for many of my patients or
just even friends,
like it seems that this happens kind of
in your thirties if you're a guy,
uh,
for women,
it's,
it's harder for me to tell because I
think pregnancy can interfere with this.
Um,
so sometimes we get a bit of a skew to
answer,
but if I had to hypothesize,
I think that we go from having a lot of
lipid protein lipase on muscle cells and
not much on fat cells to the reverse.
So when I was 16 and invincible,
my muscles had a lot of this enzyme lpl
on it that could just absolutely take
whatever I was throwing at them and turn
it into energy for the muscle.
Whereas when that lpl exists on a fat
cell,
you're basically just going to store
more fat.
And now why that would happen over time?
I mean,
we could guess reasons,
but I'd love to know if that's the case
because I still can't really figure out
like why is it today?
I am so carbohydrate sensitive.
When there was a day when I could eat,
you know,
I was probably eating seven or 8,000
calories a day of which 80%,
we're probably carbohydrates.
When I was growing up and was lean and
mean.
Did you experience a crash at all and
the like post,
afternoon crash,
post lunch crash?
It's a good question.
Back then,
I don't think I did that much back in
the day.
Which would also speak to the idea of
better fuel partitioning,
fuel partitioning,
meaning that sort of technical term for
where your body knows to go to access
energy.
You know,
are you going to glycogen,
are you going into the fat?
Um,
and then where are you storing energy?
So I,
so I suspect I was just better at fuel
partitioning as a kid,
which I'm sure most of us were.
Um,
anyway,
it's kind of,
of course the real question.
And the reason we care about this as
like what could you do about it,
right?
Like what,
you know,
for example,
like that's probably one of the reasons
why testosterone as,
as,
as testosterone goes down,
you're going to get fatter,
all things equal.
And part of the reason is testosterone,
upregulates,
lpl and hormone sensitive lipase and all
of these other enzymes in the direction
of making you leaner versus fatter.
So,
um,
but that I,
I just don't think that that's enough of
it.
You know,
I think there's something else that's
going on that's triggering that decline.
So for you at this 22 hour window of not
eating,
what do you think the benefits are other
than your energy and slight spikes in
nor epinephrin and some other hormones?
Well,
I don't think there's sufficient
evidence at this point in time,
that time restricted feeding is going to
impact my longevity.
So I think that's the big claim.
And it's the big claim this thing.
What is the claim?
Like?
What are they saying?
Oh,
I mean,
I think the claim would be that fasting
mimicry,
which could be,
you know,
like what,
say valter Longo talks about where you
do a five day hypo caloric diet of 750
to a thousand calories a day for five
days,
followed by 25 days of ad libitum
feeding,
meaning eat whatever the hell you want.
Um,
uh,
in terms of total caloric content,
um,
you know,
the claim is well that's going to
enhance longevity and,
or you know,
doing a 16,
eight or 18 six is going to enhance
lifespan.
So just to take a step back,
um,
I am only aware of,
uh,
three things that have universally
extended lifespan across all model
organisms.
So if you think of like all,
you carry what's right,
if you go from yeast to worms to flies
to mammals,
the only things that uniformly extend
life,
um,
or almost uniformly is caloric
restriction and or dietary restriction.
So total reduction in calories during
the lifetime and,
or reduction of certain subsets of those
calories.
So there's a super famous experiment
that was done.
Um,
actually if anyone's interested,
I wrote about it.
It's on my blog somewhere,
but it's basically this,
the best experiment ever done in chloric
restriction was between monkeys.
And there was a group at the NIH and a
group at the University of Wisconsin and
it was like a 19 year experiment or
something like that.
So you could really study the impact of
caloric restriction over these things.
And that experiment showed us that
caloric restriction,
extended lifespan,
if you had a really shitty diet and it
did not extend lifespan if you had a
really good diet,
counterintuitive,
but it also spoke to the idea that
dietary restriction probably matters.
So in other words,
if you're eating a regular diet of
Mcdonald's every day,
and then we put your counterpart eating
70% of Mcdonald's every day,
that's going to move the needle.
But in the Wisconsin,
uh,
and,
and the NIH experiment,
when you took the monkeys that were
eating kind of,
it wasn't their natural food,
but it was less horrible food.
The caloric restriction did not extend
lifespan.
So that threw a wrench in everyone's
understanding of caloric restriction.
And there are certain strains of mice
that also don't seem to be enhanced in
terms of lifespan,
meaning just time on,
on earth.
Um,
but for the most part nutrient
deprivation,
um,
pretty ubiquitously extends life.
The second thing that uniformly extends
life across this is a drug called
rapamycin,
which is kind of like my favorite drug
in the whole world.
I mean meaning it's like I think it's
the most important drug in in terms of
this space,
not necessarily because it's a drug that
will all be taking though I do believe
that is the case,
but more importantly because of what
it's taught us about the nutrient
sensing pathway and its target,
which is this protein called Tor,
the target of Rapamycin or m torres,
you probably heard of it as mechanistic
target of rapamycin and wrap a and
inhibits that.
Now it's a bit complicated because
there's two variants of it.
There's something called [inaudible]
complex one and mtor complex too.
And if you take rap in mice and day in
and day out every day,
which for example transplant patients
do,
it's an immune suppressant.
That doesn't seem to really extend
lifespan.
But if you take it in a pulsatile way,
you selectively get this m torque one
inhibition without the m torque to
inhibition that seems to produce
longevity big time.
How does that work?
How would you take it selectively?
Well,
um,
this is sort of one of my main clinical
interests,
um,
because I,
uh,
obviously I'm waiting for the day when I
can start taking it and ultimately,
you know,
feel that it's safe enough that I could
give it to patients.
Um,
if I'm extrapolating from all of the
best data out there.
So that's looking at the work that's
come out of a guy named David Sabatini,
his lab.
David's a guy at mit,
he's a professor.
He's actually the guy that when he was a
medical student,
I'm doing his phd in 1994 actually
discovered how wrap a mice and works in
mammals.
He's actually the guy that coined
mechanistic target of Rapamycin,
mtor work as a name.
And so now whatever we are almost 25
years later,
um,
you know,
he's still running the powerhouse lab
that understands it.
So if you look at all of the literature
that's coming out of their lab,
coupled with a guy named Matt K,
Berlin at the University of Washington
who's doing rap and mice and studies in
dogs along with the work done by someone
named Joan Manic who was at the time at
Novartis has now at a company called
restore bio and a few other people.
My intuition is that somewhere between
two to six milligrams every five to
seven days is probably the sweet spot.
Um,
but you know,
am I confident enough in that to say
that we should all be taking it?
Not yet.
There's a couple things that like,
I want to be able to measure before we
do that,
but um,
you know,
in the animal data,
the stuff's remarkable.
If you look at Matt k Berlin's dog data,
it's remarkable.
Like,
what are they doing with it?
Well,
so for you,
you own a dog,
you know this,
right?
I mean,
if you,
if you look at outside of euthanasia or
accidents,
how to dogs die,
they basically die of cancer and heart
and,
and they get dilated cardiomyopathy.
So it's a different type of heart
disease in humans get,
they don't get atherosclerotic disease,
they get heart failure.
Their,
their hearts just get too too,
too big.
And their ejection fraction,
which is the amount of blood,
the percentage of blood that leaves the
ventricular chamber with every
contraction that is,
that number goes down.
Bad things happen.
Now to put that in perspective,
you and I sitting here,
couple of normal fit dudes,
we probably have a resting ejection
fraction of 60% and if like we went out
there and like killed it and work out as
hard as we could at peak,
we might get that up to 80 85% ejection
fraction.
So once the ejection fraction gets below
30% you know a person starts to become
very symptomatic.
Well,
Matt took these dogs that had low
ejection fractions to begin with and I
forget what the exact number was,
but it might've been like below 40% are
below 30% put them on a rapid mice and
for 12 weeks and in just 12 weeks saw an
absolute 10% improvements or not didn't.
That means that's not going from 30 to
33,
that's going from 30 to 40% f
improvement.
Um,
in other words,
this is hard to measure an effect in 12
weeks of a drug.
Um,
and certainly you're not gonna be able
to measure a longevity impact over that.
So much of the study that's being done
with this is looking at surrogate
markers that we assume would portend
longevity.
So Matt's work focusing on,
um,
the ejection fraction,
uh,
mannix work was focused on immune
response,
which again was,
so this was the turning point for me.
This was like December of 2014 was like
when everything in my professional world
shifted in terms of my interest towards
like rapamycin is the thing I want to
know everything about.
Because when I was a surgical resident,
you know,
we used to give rapamycin out,
like it was cotton candy to all the
transplant patients.
It was an amazing drug that
revolutionized transplant physiology
because it had far fewer side effects
than massive doses of prednisone and
things that we used to have to give
patients.
Now you could give them much less
prednisone and you could give them
rapamycin or cousins of mice and like fk
five Oh six
and what you're doing with that stuff as
you're suppressing the immune system so
the body doesn't reject the organ.
Exactly.
Now when you do that,
does that leave them to south double to
illness or disease?
Would that be the case with wrap on
minds in person taking him for
longevity?
That's the dollar question.
And so I think in two,
so in a moment I want,
I'll,
I'll tell you the story of how wrapping
mice and came to be because I think it's
the most interesting story in biology
certainly in the last 25 30 years.
But when it was approved in 1999 by the
FDA,
it was for this indication,
it was an immune suppressant.
It was 10 years before anybody figured
out that,
oh wait,
this could also extend life.
And they're in,
you had this paradox which was waiting.
How can an immune suppressant extend
life?
I mean everybody acknowledges that
immunity is a court,
you know,
element of health.
And so in December of 2014 I feel like
it was like almost Christmas Day.
I remember thinking this is like the
best president I've ever got.
Um,
mannix group published this paper,
which they did in a group of about 320 a
65 year olds ish.
So they put them into four groups.
There's a placebo group,
there was a group that got,
and it wasn't actually wrapping mice and
it was ever,
ever alignments,
which is an analog of rep mice.
It's basically the same drug.
So there's a group that got one
milligram every single day,
five milligrams once a week,
20 milligrams once a week.
They did this for something like eight
to 12 weeks and then they washed out,
meaning they got nothing for eight to 12
weeks and then they were hit with a flu
vaccine.
And then the scientists measured the
immune response doing these really
complicated as where you look at t cell
function.
So relative to the placebo,
paradoxically all groups.
And I said paradoxically,
because even the group that got one
milligram once a day all saw an increase
in immunity,
which is a good thing.
But the five and 20 group saw an even
bigger response.
The people who just got five once a week
or 20 once a week.
So on even bigger response.
But the group that took 20 once a week
had more side effects.
And the biggest side effect of rap and
mice and acutely as these awful,
awful mouth sores called aptos ulcers.
They're nasty,
they're brutal.
Um,
I used to get them all the time just
from I think sleep deprivation,
uh,
or any,
you know,
something that was weakening my immune
system.
So it's an internal source,
not,
and not like a cold sores,
canker.
So it's a,
it's a really nasty type of canker sore.
Yeah.
So,
um,
I want,
once I had one so bad that I was like,
this is when I was in residency and I
was like,
it was just driving me nuts.
So I went to the or and I got a bunch of
Lidacain,
which is a local anesthetic.
And I went into the call room and I just
grabbed my tongue and just injected like
Lidocaine in it.
And just when I did that,
somebody walked in and I've got like
blood dripping down from my mouth and
I've got a needle in my mouth.
And they're like,
and I'm like,
no,
no.
It's not what you think.
I swear it's Lidacain.
They're like,
ah,
dude.
Ah,
we,
I got you in to help.
You know,
we were support groups for people.
Like you lie to Keynes.
Disgusting.
I had my,
a deviated septum fixed and they shoved
the lidacain up there.
You know,
it's,
it's hard stuff.
And the rest of the day I just felt like
shaky and just weird.
And then I realized,
oh,
this is like a,
almost like a cocaine type thing.
Like,
do you know why we have wida cane
because of cocaine or,
yeah,
it's a guy named William Stewart Hall
stead who was,
uh,
so near and dear to my heart because he
was the original,
he was the founding surgeon at Johns
Hopkins and one of the original four
horsemen.
So the four main physicians that
basically have shaped medicine in this
country all started out at Hopkins.
Uh Oh,
slur in medicine,
Hopkins in surgery and two other guys,
Walsh.
And I'm blanking on the,
Kelly was the third one.
Um,
and he basically figured out,
cause you gotta remember like there was
a day when surgery was staggeringly
barbaric.
Like prior to ether surgery was like,
all right,
can you hold them down?
Like gag him,
get him drunk,
gag him and like we're gonna do our
thing.
It's crazy.
So God,
I used to know all of this shit.
I don't remember any of the exact dates
anymore,
but it was like kind of like mid 18
hundreds to late 18 hundreds when up at
Massachusetts General Hospital.
I forget the name of who it was,
but someone basically came up with
ether.
So ether became the first form of
anesthetic.
But you know,
you were sort of knocking people out.
Well,
it was,
you know,
fast forward probably 20,
30 years when Halstad figured out that
this thing called cocaine could provide
local anesthetic.
So he began experimenting with like
crazy and of course in the process
became patently addicted to it.
So you have this entire generation of
surgeons at Hopkins from that early era
that were completely coke addicted,
so halstead and all of his first
generation of residents.
Um,
and then of course from that we got
lidacain be pivot cane,
all of these things that don't have the
same properties.
But to this day,
cocaine is still used and,
and most people don't realize it,
but cocaine's a schedule two drug
meaning it actually has a medical
application.
I'm like heroin,
which is scheduled one and the dea and
marijuana.
That's right.
But,
um,
the cocaine is schedule two and it is
still used in some ent surgery,
um,
because it has some favorable properties
over even lidocaine and Bupivacaine for
nasal surgery.
Did you know that they still use cocoa
leaves for flavor and Coca Cola?
They actually extract the cocaine from
it.
Use the coca leaves and the cocaine goes
to medical for,
I didn't know that.
I had cocoa tea for my first time,
uh,
this summer.
Like real Kokoda Latte,
but like brought up from my coco.
That's what it is.
Oh yeah.
It's great.
I could not get enough of that stuff.
You can't shut the fuck up on it though.
That's a weird sort of high.
It's a very strange thing.
It's very talkative sort of high.
I thought it was just everything about
it was like just for Cheetah leaves.
You ever done that?
Like in Peru or no?
No,
I've never done it either,
but apparently it's really interesting
like the,
it's like a coffee sort of a thing and
it's got flavonoids.
It's actually,
yeah,
it's actually probably healthy for you.
I just love plants in general.
We think of the coca leaves as producing
cocaine we think of as inherently
negative.
But the leaf itself,
like if you just don't extract it,
it's actually really good for you.
Well that's the thing.
I mean I and that you know,
even like thinking about the difference
between eating fruit versus eating Oreos
for sugar.
Yeah.
Like nature's pretty good at regulating
how fast this stuff.
So in the case of fruit,
like how quickly does fructose hit your
liver?
There's a sort of governor built into
it.
If you're eating raspberries,
like could you get nonalcoholic fatty
liver disease from eating enough
raspberries?
Yeah,
probably.
But it's like go crazy.
You needed to become a full time job.
Or you could just drink a giant gallon
of orange juice every day.
If that would do it,
just do it.
There was a lot quicker because most
people think of fresh squeezed orange
juice as being,
oh,
you're eating healthy.
Yeah.
Look at you over there with your fresh
squeezed on your juicing as totally
healthy,
super healthy.
Meanwhile you're just drinking a big old
glass of sugar.
You literally,
your body doesn't know the difference
between that and a Coke Cola.
Very little difference between the two.
Unfortunately,
Cole's got some other stuff in there,
caffeine.
But other than that,
just the sugar itself.
Yeah.
Your liver would have a hard time
telling the difference.
So crazy.
Most people would think a glass of
orange juice at breakfast as a healthy
choice.
Yeah.
Glass of champagne from mountain dew.
It might be better.
Might get more shit done.
Yeah.
So this a,
the dosage of one five and then 20.
So,
so that,
that study,
I remember reading that and thinking,
okay,
if it's,
if you looked at that study,
you realize if you're going to be in the
placebo,
the one a day,
the five once a week or the 20 once a
week,
the five once a week was the way to go.
And cause you got sweet spot.
That's right.
You got all the benefit of 20 more
benefit than one and the fewest side
effects.
And how long has this study,
that was an eight week intervention with
an eight week wash out was enough to see
the enhanced immunity.
Do you think that a longer term study is
necessary to see like what the body
adapts?
Yeah,
absolutely.
I mean all this stuff is in its infancy
now.
My,
my shtick is,
um,
so,
so right now wrapping my son's off
patent,
right?
So the drug was approved in [inaudible]
99 by the FDA.
But this is after an unbelievable,
amazing story of like how,
you know,
this drug almost got lost forever.
Like,
uh,
you know,
so,
so there is no economic incentive for a
company to,
you know,
figure out how to do this thing with
rapamycin.
Um,
and even ever alignments.
I think ultimately Novartis,
and I'm saying this with no actual
knowledge other than just my own
speculation,
but I suspect Novartis was like,
well,
you know,
we're not going to play this game just
with ever alignments.
And that's I think why it probably spun
into this other company,
a restore bio to,
to sort of combine it with other agents.
Um,
but at,
at an n of one level,
what I'm kind of interested in doing is,
um,
you know,
using myself as a Guinea pig to start to
measure the benefits of it.
Because my hypothesis is three things
have to be true if rapamycin is working.
And I could be wrong,
but,
but this is my hypothesis and this is
what I test with,
with,
with other scientists is if you were
taking ramp in mice in at the right
dose,
um,
so assume you're not getting all the
nasty side effects,
you're not getting the mouth sores and
stuff like that.
Three things have to get better.
One,
your glucose metabolism should at least
get no worse but potentially better.
I suspect it's a function of where you
start.
So there is one doctor in New York who
has like a rap on mice and practice.
I think he's in there,
he's in the bronx actually.
And I've talked to him a bunch.
And when he,
when he started at himself,
he said like the improvements were
remarkable just in terms of glucose
metabolism,
but I think he was starting at a pretty
bad spot.
But if maybe you are,
I took it,
we might not notice much getting better,
but we definitely should not get worse.
So that's easy to measure clinically do
as an oral glucose tolerance test would
give you that answer.
But two things should get significantly
better.
The first is immune function should get
Not Worse.
There is no clinical way to measure
that,
but we do know how to measure it.
I mean when I was doing my post doc,
it was in an immunology lab.
Like I know how to do that as say I just
don't have like $1 million worth of
equipment to measure it.
What is the difference in the dosage
even in the high end at 20 versus what
you would give someone if they got a
kidney transplant?
Yeah,
typical transplant dose would have been
like two,
three milligrams every day.
Okay.
So it's quite a bit different.
It is and it's different on two levels
because you know when you're giving it
every day at a lower dose,
you stint still end up producing tissue
levels that might even be comparable to
where that person was getting with the
spike of 20 and in general,
this isn't always true,
but in general in pharmacology side
effects are the result of certain side
effects are the result of the nadir dose
and certain side effects of the result
of the peak dose.
So with every drug,
you kind of have to understand this a
little bit.
But going back to this rap at mycenae
thing and the third thing that has to be
true in my opinion,
it could be full of shit,
but I think the third thing that has to
be true if you're taking the right dose
is you need to see an uptick in
autophagy.
And um,
so just as if you,
does that mean a toffee is this process
where the body,
the cells start eating themselves.
So it's kind of like a programmed cell
death,
although technically we reserve that
term for something called apoptosis.
But when you're fasting,
what's,
why would fasting produce a benefit?
I mean,
I think the most logical explanation is
enhanced the toffee g.
So the body basically has to prioritize
in the absence of nutrients,
the underperforming cells are basically
told each herself and you know,
we can recycle some of your components.
Maybe this mitochondria is worth saving.
This golgi apparatus is worth saving.
And then we selectively,
when we refeed repopulate the better
cells.
And in many ways I think wrap mice and
can do that in a pill.
So the problem is we don't have a blood
test to measure autophagy.
So in,
in the,
in the lab,
when you measure autophagy,
you need muscle biopsies or they
typically even just sacrifice the
animals.
Um,
this has become a very hot area.
So the Nobel prize in medicine and
physiology was awarded for the genetic,
um,
basically the elucidation of the genetic
regulation of Autophagy in,
uh,
actually it's 2016 so it's very recent,
about a year and a half ago.
This is what the Nobel prize was awarded
for.
But what I'm hoping is that we can
develop a signature for autophagy with a
blood test.
So I believe that you should be able to
look at someone's blood and look at all
of the metabolomics,
all of the small molecules,
all of the proteome.
And there should be a signature.
It should look different from the way we
look when we're,
you know,
fast it or read a story fully fed.
Otherwise,
would you just take a sample of the
muscle tissue,
like punch something out?
Yeah.
And,
and I'm,
I mean,
I'm willing to do at all and I probably
will,
we're just trying to get what's called
an irb and institutional review board.
So to do these kinds of studies in
humans,
even if I'm the only subject and it's
just like,
I don't care what you do to me type of
thing,
we still have to get an irb.
So we're working on getting an n of one
irb so that we can take muscle biopsies,
fat biopsies for me,
blood tests,
and then start to actually look for that
signature.
Would it vary in where you got it from?
Like would you want your muscles yeah,
more than one muscle group?
It's a very good question.
I don't know the answer.
Hmm.
Um,
I probably have to talk to people who
have a lot of experience doing this with
animals,
but it,
it actually wouldn't surprise me.
Like if I were going to do it,
I would just start in the legs because
the muscles in the legs tend to be the
harbinger of what's going on in the
body.
So,
for example,
one of the first signs of diabetes,
like a decade before you get diabetes.
One thing that if you're actually doing
this kind of testing in people it you'll
notice glucose,
insulin resistance,
and the muscles of the legs.
So once the legs start to get insulin
resistant,
you're on a glide path to bad things
happening.
I'm fascinated by legs first of all,
from years of martial arts,
but also because over the last year or
so I've been doing a lot of running and
it's one of the only muscle groups that
I could work out every day.
I can,
I can run hills every day and I'm not
sore like that.
That's not even possible for any other
group.
I mean,
I can kind of do that with boxing.
You can hit the bag and as far as like
Ryan hills is essentially like
plyometrics,
like you're pushing your entire weight
up and then you're catching with the
other leg and pushing it up.
You can't do that with,
you can't bench press every day.
You're fucking arms would fall off.
I mean,
there's probably someone out there doing
it.
That's proven me wrong,
but there's nothing like the amount of
endurance that you have in your life,
but it can just be an adaptation that
you've had as well.
I mean,
when I was a competitive cyclist,
I mean there were definitely days when I
would,
especially when we did like multi day
events,
like there were days when it's just like
you're beaten down.
Yeah,
yeah.
You're going to learn in the first 10
minutes.
Like everybody else is riding together,
you're riding alone.
The fatigue level though is
significantly different than it
different than it would be if you were
doing something with your arms every
day.
It seems like your ability to,
you can definitely recruit more.
That's probably part of it.
Like more tissue.
I think you have more options like you
can,
you know,
especially if you really have good
proprioception.
But for example,
like if you're dead lifting,
you know,
I actually think,
um,
if you,
so,
so you know how you have like the
positive and negative motion,
concentric,
eccentric motion of a weight.
If you're willing to do away with the
negative,
you can lift heavy every single day.
So there's this guy named Ryan.
Oh,
unfreaking believable.
So you do,
I've seen people doing that.
You know,
I saw that,
uh,
Andre Galvao on his instagram the other
day was doing dead lifts and just
dropping the weight.
And I was like,
that seems weird to me.
So when I was a cyclist,
this was my training,
uh,
and it was all put together by this guy
named Ryan flarity who actually
introduced,
that was another one of my sight unseen
introductions to tim for a podcast.
It's a great podcast with Ryan flaherty
on,
and he's a,
I call him the guru of speed.
He,
this is a guy who likes singlehandedly,
I shouldn't say singlehandedly.
I mean he's on the shoulders of many
other people who have done great work,
but,
but it has,
has really done an amazing job at
figuring out how to make people run
fast.
And,
um,
it's a very long story and I mean,
he does such a great job on the podcast.
I won't go into it,
but,
but for the purpose of this discussion,
one of our interest was,
hey,
could we translate everything you've
learned about sprinting into cycling?
And his biggest observation was the
following.
If he took a hundred runners and lined
them up and new,
like before they ran,
knew how,
how hard they could hit a force plate
treadmill.
He could predict the order in which
they'd finished the race.
So force plate treadmill as its name
suggests a treadmill,
but it's a special treadmill where it
measures the force that you hit and that
the higher that number divided by your
bodyweight,
that became what he described as mass
specific force.
That number,
if you rank order it is the order in
which people would finish the run.
So it kind of makes sense if you think
about it,
right?
The harder you can hit the ground
relative to your own weight,
the higher you go and the higher you go,
the longer you traveled with each
stride.
So you saying bolt has the highest ever
force plate measurement,
um,
calculation and it's,
I forget what his ratio is.
I want to say he's like 6.9 or seven
times more force than his body weight
every time he hits,
if fricking staggering.
Wow.
So then Ryan's,
once he figured all this stuff out,
his next question,
this is when he was working at USA
track.
His next question was,
could you train this?
In other words like,
okay,
if Joe runs a 4.9 40 and we want to get
that down to a four five can that be
done?
And it turned out the answer was
categorically yes.
You have to do two things.
You have to get stronger and you have to
get lighter.
So how do you do that?
And that's when he came up with this
idea of we do hex bar dead lifts,
we lift really heavy.
So you're only doing fives,
fours,
threes or twos,
never more than five reps.
And so you'll do five sets every single
day and you'll pick it.
So some days it will be five sets of
three,
some days it's five sets of five,
whatever it is.
And you're off.
And they're very well prescribed.
Like you know at what percentage of your
one rep Max you're doing these APP and
it's up drop up,
drop up,
drop.
So you're never getting the Actin myosin
filament to tear pass because that's
what happening in the negative is the
act and the act acting is coming off the
myosin and that is creating a micro tear
in the muscle.
And that's what the muscle rebuilt.
That's why we get larger when we lift
weights.
But when you drop it,
you unload the muscle when you're
relaxing it.
So the is not going to get bigger.
So you're getting all the benefits,
all the strength,
which is primarily around the type two b
muscle fiber,
um,
and without the,
without the size.
So anyway,
when,
when I asked Brian,
hey,
could we do this in cycling,
we did this experiment,
which was,
he kind of came up with,
this was for me and two other guys who
were very good cyclists.
Like I was like,
I'm a popper.
But these guys were like cat one,
cat,
two collegiate cyclers cyclists.
But they were like my training partners.
So we did this thing where we did the
same routine that he had the sprinters
doing.
And it's a bit more complicated than
I've described because you're also
juxtaposing the positive only with
something called a post activation
potentiation,
which you may have already experienced
this,
but I don't know if you've ever tried to
do plyometrics after deadlifting,
but it seems counterintuitive that you'd
be able to do more,
but you can really,
yeah,
it has to be a heavy dead lift and
attributes of numbers or no more in
terms of distance,
like more in terms of vertical.
So your highest,
um,
uh,
like plyometric jump is going to come
after you've done like,
you know,
three sets of three at,
95% of your one rep Max three sets of
three dropping or using essential.
No,
definitely.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Wow.
And so we would super set the
plyometrics with the dead lifts and you
would do this every day.
And I'm so Ryan,
you know,
he,
he runs a training camp where he has,
um,
typically the top 10 college prospects
every year just before the NFL combine
come down.
And I mean the changes he makes in their
time,
like Johnny Menzel was one of them.
So obviously Johnny Menzel has
obviously,
you know,
not panned out in the pros,
but most people kind of forget how good
an athlete he was.
And when he showed up to camp,
I forget what his time was,
but I want to say it was about,
I don't know,
you could probably look this up for me.
You know,
it was three tenths slower than what he
ultimately ran at the combine.
And He,
I think he had the fastest or second
fastest quarterback time at the combine
after just 12 weeks of doing this.
Wow.
I mean,
it was unbelievable
how fast he can get these guys to run.
I saw something the other day that I'd
never seen before.
It's an East centric bike.
It,
it changes back and forth.
Heard of this thing.
You're the second person to tell me
about this.
I think I saw it yesterday.
In fact,
now that I think about it,
it was east sensor can concentric,
but it,
it,
it alternates.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And it,
it looked really weird.
It,
it,
it forces movement and you're resisting
the movement.
See if you can find that Jamie.
It's like an East centric,
I forget what it's called,
but uh,
like someone sent me this like,
Hey,
this thing is amazing.
I was like,
it's a bike.
The fuck you talking about look
different than that.
The one I saw was also different.
It looked,
it was a wreck.
I think it was like a recumbent.
Yeah.
That's what I saw too.
He centric.
Yeah.
You're spelling it wrong.
No,
it was coming up though.
Oh,
it says just centric.
okay.
Huh.
East centric exercise bike.
Try that.
It,
but it's the thing is it,
it alternated between east centric and
concent trick.
It wasn't just the one with the red and
the top row looks like it.
What does that pediatric Er Aragon,
I don't know.
It's on it.
It's for little kids.
Well,
whatever.
I,
I wish I had saved it cause I was like,
I'm never buying this.
But you know,
it just looked interesting.
It's just like,
there's always these new methods of
stimulating the body and tricking it
into doing things.
And,
uh,
I guess that's essentially what a lot of
people,
the way a lot of people think of
intermittent fasting,
you're kind of stimulating the body.
You're hacking it,
tricking it.
You know,
and I wonder,
you know,
one of the things that Ryan and I talked
about was could we ever adopt his
training system to swimming?
And in,
in running and cycling,
it's primarily going to be quads,
Hams,
glutes have to be the muscles that do
it.
And in row things like,
what would you,
we were talking about like,
you really got to be able to get the
lats fired,
but how do you get the last of fire at
such a weight?
And then without having to do the
negative as well.
So we just couldn't really kind of
figure out how to do it.
And they're,
so we adopted part of his technique to
swimming,
which was the actual training routine
meaning.
So one of the big misconceptions,
if you're trying to go fast is that you
need to still train slow.
But the reality of it is like,
you know,
if you're trying to run a marathon at,
call it a pace of two 15 you know,
world class marathon runner,
there's not a lot of benefit to be
spending much time running at a pace
slower than that.
If anything,
you want to be running slightly faster.
That,
so you know who meb is,
the American marathoner who won the
Boston marathon three years ago.
No.
So amazing marathon or um,
he's the,
I think he's the only person to have won
the New York Marathon,
the Boston Marathon,
and to have won an Olympic medal and
marathon.
He won a silver medal in the 2004 Athens
Games.
But when he won the Boston Marathon,
he was like 38 years old,
which in marathon parlance is,
you might as well be a hundred.
And he had not really had a great race
in the previous few years.
So he had been effectively written off
in the sport and Ryan actually helped
train them and all they did was apply
this principle of sprinting into
marathon running,
which was all right matt,
if you want to win the Boston Marathon,
you need to be able to travel like four
inches further with every step you take
taking the same number of steps at the
same cadence that you currently run.
And they,
you know,
Ryan did the math and said that means
you're forced number has to go from
where it is now,
which I think was 1.7 meaning he could
only dead lift 1.7 times his body
weight.
You have to get that until like 2.6 or
something.
And so when meb train for the Boston
Marathon,
he was focusing heavily on these dead
lifts and doing much shorter,
faster runs.
And you know,
I mean if you watch the video of his
Boston marathon when it's incredible,
like you know,
he just takes off and like leaves
everybody behind him and they're like,
yeah,
there's no way he'll be able to keep
that up.
We'll let them go.
And they couldn't write them in.
Wow.
Do you think that someone's going to
build a break too?
But that's the big,
we were just talking about the other
day.
Some guy got really close.
What'd you say?
He hit Jamie like two oh six or
something.
I think someone's gone closer to the
nighttime.
Then that guy in Germany last year go
even closer.
I think it was two oh two or something
along those lines.
And you think that this sort of method
is what they're using?
So I don't know if I'm allowed to talk
to you about this stuff publicly.
Um,
don't worry.
No one's listening.
Um,
so,
so short answer is yes,
I think this can be done.
Um,
everything has to be perfect,
right?
Meaning you have to have the perfect
athlete trained to peak at the right
time.
You need the right humidity,
like everything has to fire on all
cylinders.
But just as there was nothing
physiologically special about a four
minute mile when Roger bannister broke
it,
it was more of a psychological barrier.
Um,
you know,
I'm not suggesting for a moment that
this will be easy,
but you know,
we're going to get there.
I mean like this can happen.
That is incredible.
If you think about how fast you're
running to run 26 miles in two hours and
two minutes.
Staggering.
I don't think people understand like
what?
Uh,
I mean I was never a great runner.
I could,
I was about a two 50 marathon,
two 55 marathon when I was a boxer,
but never trained as a runner.
Like it was just,
I just ran so much and I was pretty
fast.
But like when I think about how hard I
would have to run to bust out a to 50 to
two 55 and to think like,
was there any chance I could have ever
got that down to a two 30?
It's a,
that is such an enormous change in pace.
It's,
it's,
I,
I don't know that I ever could have done
that regardless of all the training
tricks in the world.
And what kind of diet of those guys
following?
Well,
I know personally I can't speak to what
the other guys do,
but I think a lot of those guys are in
the state of where I was when they were
younger.
Meaning like I,
they can probably get away with a lot
more.
Um,
if you look at the physiques,
if most of these guys,
they're,
they're perfectly built,
like I'm talking to elite level,
I'm talking about like anyone who runs a
marathon.
But if you're talking about like the
people who were going to win the
marathons,
they are basically all engine and then
chassis in the right place.
That's basically all they come down to.
Right?
I mean they are enormous cardiovascular
system,
very strong quads,
Hams,
glutes,
and then everything else is very tiny.
When you say enormous,
like is literally the size of their law
and you actually look at,
well I mean it's all relative,
but when you look at their frame,
their thorax is going to be larger.
And is it expanded because of the
training?
I think so.
I mean sense you never know cause and
effect.
Sometimes you could argue like maybe
these guys were,
maybe the people who are drawn to those
sports are the ones that are,
you know,
are drawn to come to be elite in those
sports already had a genetic
predisposition.
That's sort of my feeling is it's a bit
of both.
Lance Armstrong,
it doesn't have a very large heart.
Um,
I don't know.
I think what lance had that was pretty
unique,
even amongst the world's best,
which is what he competed with.
Of course,
I think his lactate threshold was a lot
higher than most people genetically.
Yeah.
And then of course,
any,
and again,
you know,
I mean,
I know it's such a controversial topic,
although my view is I think that every
single cyclist,
at least from 1991 till 2011 was on
highly,
you know,
augmented programs.
So you know,
that Lance one seven of those years,
um,
in the,
in that context just tells me that he
was,
you know,
training harder and being more specific
to the race.
I mean,
what people don't understand is like,
lance only peaked for one race a year.
Like everything that that team us postal
did was geared for that one race.
Um,
and also when you really look at how
much doping they did it,
well actually it wasn't that much.
Like,
you know,
when they were blood transfusing,
it might've been two units over the
course of a race.
And I'm not saying that that wouldn't
help.
It would help a lot,
but that's nothing compared to what
people were doing just a few years
before lance came along.
So Lance one,
I think his first one in [inaudible] 99
the guy who won before that in
[inaudible] 98 was Marco Pantani before
that was going to be on,
oh,
rick,
in 97 and before that was gonna be horn
reese,
bjorn [inaudible],
his nickname was Mr 60 because his
hematocrit was always over 60.
That's fricking like how that guy didn't
die of a stroke.
I don't know.
It's not from EPO.
Yeah.
Lance never had a credit over 50 to my
knowledge.
They would basically always titrate with
EPO and,
or hemoglobin up to 50 which was the
trigger.
So,
you know,
but,
but I think,
and again,
I,
I've never,
I don't know lance at all,
so I certainly don't know anything about
him beyond like the little bits that I
had read over time.
But I do think his lactate tolerance was
remarkable,
meaning,
um,
you know,
we measure lactate in athletes,
swimmers and cyclists when they're,
you know,
trying to figure out what their
performances and as far as I can tell,
there are seem to be these two
phenotypes.
There's the one phenotype where people
can tolerate staggeringly high amounts
of lactate.
And,
and again,
it's not lactate per se that is causing
the pain that you're experiencing.
It's the hydrogen ion that accompanies
the lactate.
Um,
so lactic acid,
the acid part of that is a hydrogen ion
and that's actually what's poisoning the
muscle and preventing the muscle from
having this effortless Actin Myosin Act,
you know,
contract release,
et Cetera.
But we use lactate as a proxy cause
we're lactate is high,
the hydrogen ion is high.
And there were some people who can just
holler rate,
like incredible doses.
I used to work with Olympic swimmers and
uh,
I mean there were just a couple of these
guys like they could actually be
standing with a lactate of 24 I mean
when I was competing,
if I had a lactate above 16 or 17 I
couldn't be standing like that was just
too much pain.
Like I was on the floor.
If I was over 17 I was puking and I saw
dudes that could stand there at 24 I've
fact,
one of my good friends,
he,
he won a gold and a silver medal in the
Sydney Olympics and retired from
swimming in 2004 then came back to swim
masters.
So and was like,
he actually was trying to make a
comeback to make the 2012 Olympic team.
And when he was training for that,
like I would poke him between races and
I saw him get out of a 402 the
individual medley race,
which is the hardest swim race of them
all.
The 400 I am is,
I mean you might as well just shoot
yourself.
It's so painful.
He got out of that.
Had a lactate of 18 two minutes later,
not two minutes later,
maybe seven minutes,
they are jumped on the blocks and 100
breast race,
you know,
came out with a lactate of 21 and that
kind of thing.
So there are those guys.
And then I think at the other end of the
spectrum,
the word on the street is guys like
Michael Phelps or at the opposite end of
that where they are so efficient at
shuttling lactic acid out of the cell
back to the liver where this thing
called the Cori cycle actually turns
lactate back into glucose that they
never have high levels of lactate.
Now again,
all of this is sort of were,
you know,
speculation because I don't,
I think they were very hush hush about
phelps as numbers,
but I heard from reliable and reasonable
sources that he would rarely have a
lactate of of 8.0 including when he's
breaking world records.
Whoa.
Which for me at 8.0 like I'm smoking and
joking like that's fine,
but for you know,
he was so efficient at getting rid of it
that yeah,
he could,
you know,
set the world record in the 400 I am and
have a lactate of eight.
Again,
I don't know if this is true,
but,
but I've,
there's certainly a plausible mechanism
by which it could be,
well,
it's fascinating that this could
potentially all be engineered,
right?
That like through use of crispr or
something else,
you could take all these various facets
of performance enhancing modalities,
extend a person's ability and so many
different ways and create a super
person.
Yeah,
of course.
It's interesting,
right?
Once he started genetically doing it,
if you could,
does it become cheating in the same way?
Like would we,
would we have,
if you have someone like Phelps who has
this genetic predisposition to getting
rid of lactose lactaid and you take
someone like me,
you probably has none of that and you
know,
you juice me up to his level.
Is that cheating?
I mean it is.
I don't know.
I mean those are the questions.
I mean,
this is why people like Daniel Coyle who
are so critical of Lance Armstrong say
cause cause on the one hand you'll have
camps and say,
look,
it's the great equalizer.
Like why don't we just let everybody
dope and steroid argument with them and
may as well.
Well and and frankly it's more my
argument,
but I have a different reason for
arguing that way,
which is I think having done these
sports and nowhere near at the high
level that those guys do it.
I just know how destructive they are.
Like the Tour de France is the most
unhealthy thing on the face of the
earth.
I've heard that it's healthier to do to,
to Tour de France on steroids than it is
to do it off sterile absa fucking loot
Lee.
When those guys finish the Tour de
France,
they are osteopenic.
I mean their bone density has eroded
their muscle.
They have lost so much muscle mass.
I mean it is a devastating grueling
event.
Now nothing's going to completely
ameliorate that.
But like,
if we think that like watching these
guys killed themselves,
riding six hours a day,
hitting peak thresholds of,
you know,
six watts per kilogram,
if we think there's anything
physiologically reasonable about that,
we're out to fucking lunch.
But is that the point?
I mean,
isn't that the point is that you can
push your mind to do something your body
absolutely doesn't want to do.
So you should be rewarded for,
for that.
And these guys are in a league of their
own,
I mean,
professional cyclists for some of the
toughest athletes out there.
I mean,
obviously every athlete at the peak of
their game is remarkable and,
and no disrespect to like the best
running back in the NFL,
but like,
you can't even compare that to what a
guy does for,
for workload for sure.
Yeah.
For just the pain,
like the absolute sheer discomfort.
Um,
and the physiologic torture and the
duration of it and all of these other
things.
Well,
you see it in their faces to those guys.
Like when they retired,
they look like they're 10 years older
than they are.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean they've lost all of the fat.
A lot of them,
you know,
they just,
if you don't have fat in your face,
I mean you age dramatically,
they just look exhausted too.
I mean,
it looks like it's just drained them
like they've forced to live 30 years
inside of 10.
Yeah.
So it's like,
what if we just say,
guess what?
Everybody's allowed to use whatever
amounts of EPO,
blood testosterone to be at the 80th
percentile of what we consider normal.
So everybody is allowed to walk around
with a hemoglobin of 14.7 or up to 14.7
or 15 or cheat that,
right?
Wouldn't they?
I mean,
if you allow people to use,
but I also think like the,
the testing on this stuff is so like,
it's so jv now there's this idea called
the biological passport.
There was introduced many years ago,
which basically,
look,
we're going to develop a signature for
every person and now if you deviate much
from your signature will,
that'll be the trigger.
Um,
and the argument again by certain
people,
and I think Daniel coyle argued this a
lot in um,
one of his books that he wrote ripping
apart lance was the reason.
It's the reason doping is unfair because
the everybody does it argument doesn't
hold water is because if you're a person
who naturally lives at a hematocrit of
47,
you're only getting a slight improvement
going from 47 to 50.
If you're a person who naturally lives
at 43,
you going from 43 to 50,
you get a much bigger advantage to which
I say,
yeah,
but that's true on a relative basis.
But an absolute level,
if everybody's walking around with a
hematocrit of 48 to 50,
they still have the same oxygen carrying
capacity.
It does level the playing field.
The concern though isn't,
I would believe the concern is you don't
want people to think that the only way
to do this sport is to take drugs.
Well absolutely.
And it's also worth putting in in mind
that,
and this is sort of my pet peeve with
this whole drug and sport thing is like,
I mean
personally I don't really give a shit.
I mean I just have bigger things I care
about.
Then like how many steroids barry bonds
took to hit all those home runs.
But what really does chap my ass is when
people don't actually understand how
steroids work,
right?
Like it bugs the shit out of me when
people assume that if you take steroids
you will have,
you know,
you will hit that many,
home runs or you will run this fast or
lift this much.
The only thing that steroid is doing is
enabling you to recover faster from the
brutal work that it takes to actually do
those things.
So you know,
all the,
if I,
if I shot myself full of Epo,
I mean you've probably seen ICARUS,
right?
I mean I thought that was,
I thought he did it.
I thought bit Bryan Fogel that prideful
of that.
A really good job of showing like,
I mean,
and he was a pretty good responder to
the EPO.
I think he did a growth hormone.
Testosterone,
an EPO.
I mean you saw in the end of the day he
f he finished worse the second year
round because his bike ran out of,
exactly.
That's my point.
You see like people don't realize like
one little thing makes all the
difference from a performance
standpoint.
Yeah.
He probably would have done a little bit
better,
but it's not because the drugs were in
him per se.
It's because the drugs that were in him
allowed to train more.
So the reason he was a fitter rider the
second year was because his watts per
kilo were hired because of how much more
he trained the drugs enabled him to
train that much harder.
Yeah.
That's what it does.
It allows you to train harder so you
recover better.
So you have more output.
Correct.
But we don't want young kids to think
that the only way to do this is start
taking steroids and fuck up your
endocrine system.
And that's,
no,
of course not.
But we also want to keep in mind like
see,
it almost requires like a broader
discussion,
which is like why do we care?
Well we care in combat sports because it
allows you to inflict more damage and
no,
no.
I'm saying like why would,
why do,
why do it?
Let's just say I'm not a professional
athlete.
Okay.
Why do I actually care how fast I run or
how fast I ride or any of these other
things?
Well,
because you want to brag about it.
So maybe or weight,
right?
So maybe there in lies the problem.
I mean,
I mean I,
you know,
when I stopped cycling competitively,
I think a big part of it was I just
realized that performance and longevity
stopped being colinear.
They started to become somewhat
orthogonal.
They started to deviate.
In other words,
the things that I was doing that we're
enhancing my performance and I'm not
even talking about drugs,
I'm just talking training wise.
It seemed to come at the expense of what
I believed was going to make me live
longer.
So specifically the,
the thing I cared most about was
cardiovascular health.
Now the incidence of atrial fibrillation
in highly trained athletes is 10 times
higher than that of non athletes.
So like that's a little
counterintuitive,
right?
Why would people who have such amazingly
fit cardiovascular systems have 10 times
the risk of this horrible condition
called atrial fibrillation,
which yeah,
many people have it but not young.
You're not supposed to have that when
you're 40.
And it's usually associated with
cardiovascular disease.
And yet people are,
you know,
showing up with these,
I mean I have four patients who have had
to get ablations for atrial
fibrillation.
What does an ablation and ablation is a
procedure where they stick a catheter up
through the femoral artery in the vein
and then they burned pieces of the heart
specifically around the,
um,
uh,
pulmonary veins and they basically are
trying to burn away and create,
um,
uh,
or remove the ability of the electrical
system to move in this way.
So what's basically happening with,
with this type of athlete's heart is,
um,
when your heart is constantly being
exposed to that high stretch,
high ejection fraction load,
you're basically stretching out the
electrical system cause the electrical
system of the heart runs within its
muscles.
So as you stretch it out a certain group
of people and we don't know why certain
people are susceptible and certain or
not,
but they just developed this,
um,
this dysrhythmia.
So you're soldering the motherboard as
it were.
Yeah.
You can possibly think of that.
Right?
You're like creating new lines to block
the,
the connection.
Oh,
that's fucking crazy.
Yeah.
So think about it.
Someone said once,
and I don't know if that's true,
maybe you'd be able to have some insight
there that there is a concept that your
entire life,
you have a certain amount of heartbeats.
Does that make sense?
Oh No,
of course.
I've heard it many times.
I don't know if that's correct.
I,
that's fucking scary.
I don't,
I don't tend to agree with that.
Um,
because I,
I,
you can't compare one beat to the other.
I mean,
you,
you can't,
you know,
it's hard for me to say that,
an 80 to 90% ejection fraction beat
under incredible load is the same as the
beat that I'm,
you know,
like it is beat per beat,
the same as the beat I experience when
I'm sleeping and my heart's writing,
you know,
my heart's beating at 40 beats per
minute.
I think,
um,
maybe there's a directional truth to
that,
but I,
I feel like when you're talking about
human longevity,
it's a game of inches.
And that is like something that's
probably directionally true within a
mile.
Now when you're talking about human
longevity and you,
you know,
and you're thinking about all these
different things that you could do to
extend,
how much of that is supplementation and
do you supplement?
Like are you,
are you a person who takes colloidal
minerals or are you a person that is
interested in antioxidants?
Like what,
what do you do in terms of that?
Um,
so I,
my view on longevity is it's just,
it's the hardest problem there is.
And so you gotta have every,
like I'm agnostic about what the
approach is.
So I want to understand everything that
you can do with respect to,
you know,
food,
drugs,
supplements,
hormones.
And to be clear,
the only difference between a drug and a
supplement is one's regulated and one is
not.
But you know,
and I,
I have patients that'll say things like,
oh,
you know,
doctor,
I don't want to take that drug.
I'd rather do it naturally.
Can I do it?
And it sort of like,
well,
okay,
you,
you don't want to take a stat and,
but you do want to take red yeast rice.
Well they both inhibit HMG coa
reductase.
The enzyme that catalyzes the first step
of cholesterol synthesis.
You're willing to take one that you buy
in a drug store that's totally
unregulated and you're not willing to
buy the one that comes from a drug
company where the FDA has their foot up
the ass of the company making it to make
sure it's perfect.
That just strikes me as a false
equivalent.
So I only say that to just say like,
I think everything should be on the
table and then the question should be,
how do you decide what to do?
So,
um,
uh,
there are absolutely a bunch of
supplements that I take.
Um,
but I don't have kind of a one size fits
all approach to it because I think
you've gotta be able to kind of measure
what's going on in a person,
get a baseline and figure it out.
So,
you know,
I mean,
my guess is you've had a million people
on the show that can talk your ears off
about,
you know,
which paypal,
which people should take methylated
vitamins versus which shouldn't,
and if you have this mthfr mutation
versus this one,
should you be taking this versus that.
I think all of those things are valid.
Um,
some of the stuff that I find even more
interesting is actually a lot less sexy
and I don't have a good answer for it.
But,
um,
you know,
looking at,
for example,
vitamin D levels.
So,
you know,
you see a huge disparity and the vitamin
D levels people have.
And it begs the question to all people
run effectively at the same vitamin D
level.
Um,
and is that a function of not just their
own individual,
like how much sun they're getting,
but more importantly like potentially
genetically where they're from.
So I'm starting to feel like people who
have northern European,
uh,
blood might actually run better at a
lower vitamin D level than people like
me who,
you know,
come from places near the equator where
maybe just evolved to see more sunlight
and have more vitamin d.
What's your ancestry?
My parents are both from Egypt.
Oh,
interesting.
Um,
so,
and the range,
like when you look at a laboratory test,
when you check somebody vitamin D,
like the range that's offered is 30 to a
hundred is optimal say range.
Yeah.
I'm like,
that's,
that's probably not the range,
you know,
so,
so I personally think the range is
probably 40 to 60,
but I also measure something called
parathyroid hormone that allows me to
further titrate that range and stuff
like that.
Well when you talking about this,
it's really obvious,
really clear that there's so much data
to go through that it's,
we're,
we're learning this and [inaudible],
I don't want to say it's in its infancy,
but if we look back a thousand years now
and we will most certainly say their
understanding of this science is at its
infancy.
Yeah,
for sure.
I mean,
the issue is how do you make sense of a
problem or how do you try to solve a
problem which is unsolvable.
And,
and the reason I say that is the
following,
um,
you know,
you have what I call kind of the
medicine 1.0 world,
which was,
I define that as everything that took
place before Francis Bacon.
Um,
you can probably tell me when that was.
I'm going to guess Francis Bacon is like
1650 to 1670 or something like that.
But that was basically the first person
to come along and codify the scientific
method.
So anything that came along before the
scientific method may have been correct.
Meaning there were things that were
certainly done back then that proved
helpful,
but they weren't grounded in a principle
of science.
In other words,
you know,
even a blind squirrel is gonna find nuts
sometimes.
And then we basically through,
you know,
following the Qaddafi,
the,
the elucidation of a scientific method,
the development of statistics to
actually make sense of data.
We then got into the sweet spot where I
think we are now,
which is medicine 2.0 and to me,
medicine 2.0 is really good at solving
problems that are amenable to relatively
short,
simple clinical trials.
And there has been no better example
than in this space than infectious
diseases.
So like if you think about the
unbelievable improvement in human
longevity that has come from
antibiotics,
antiviral therapy for HIV,
I mean remember 30 years ago,
Hiv was a lethal Li,
no questions asked lethal condition.
Today it's a chronic disease for
virtually every patient with HIV.
It's a chronic disease today,
meaning you will die with HIV,
not from HIV.
That is,
that's almost hard to fathom when you
consider how shitty we are at addressing
other chronic diseases like heart
disease,
cancer,
Alzheimer's disease.
So the problem is if you want to know
the answer,
should I eat this way or that way?
Should I exercise this way or that way?
Should I take this drug or that drug or
this supplement or that supplement to
live longer?
We can never know the answer in humans
because there is no clinical trial that
can answer that question.
And we can do that experiment in
everything that's not human.
But we've already learned the hard way
that what happens in not humans doesn't
necessarily extrapolate to humans.
And we can do things to be slicker about
it.
You know,
when you study rhesus monkeys for 20
years,
it's certainly more interesting than
studying mice for one year.
But in the end,
you know,
there's still animals in captivity.
They're still not in the same
environment and all these things.
So my view on this topic is the only way
to go to this kind of medicine 3.0 is
you've got to have kind of a strategy
around how you think about it.
And so in many ways that's,
that's if,
that's what I spend most of my time
dealing with is what is a strategy for
longevity that becomes a scaffolding
upon which you anchor every new piece of
data.
Because I mean,
I know things today from a data
standpoint,
I didn't know 10 years ago and to your
point,
even in five years we'll look back at
stuff we're doing today and thank God we
have more data.
Is that still the right thing to do?
Um,
and so that strategy to me is,
is sort of fundamentally based on three
bodies of literature.
And the first is is like what did we
learn from centenarians so that people
who naturally live to a hundred,
um,
they have the advantage or that body of
literature has the advantage of being
based on humans.
It has the disadvantage of it not being
experimental.
So we,
you know,
like we don't know like what cause and
effect was.
And then secondly,
if you look at all of the animal
literature or nonhuman literature where
you can actually do the experiments,
what's common there?
And then if you look at the underlying
molecular mechanisms,
so if you,
I feel like if you tie those three
together,
you come up with a general scaffolding
for what it means to live longer and
live healthier,
then we can try to look at one thing at
a time and say,
hey,
vitamin D,
yay or nay antioxidant,
Yay or nay.
So when you're,
it's,
it's gotta be very time consuming for
you.
We'll have a research team.
That's when I started this practice
about three years ago,
I realized like I was losing the battle.
I,
my ability to sit down and read
scientific papers was like shrinking.
So I hired an analyst,
you know,
he,
I,
he had worked with me in the past.
He was amazing.
I brought him over full time to do this.
Then another one that another,
I mean now I have four full time
analysts and I mean as this practice
grows and or you know,
whatever,
I have the revenue to justify it.
Like I'll have 10 analysts one day and
this practice,
and even that's not enough.
I mean approximately 100,000 papers are
published every month on pub med,
Jesus Christ.
So I forgot I did the math on that one.
So I think it's like three papers a
minute.
It's pretty stunning when you think
about the amount of human achievement
that we've experienced just in our
lifetime in that regard.
Like how many people are working on
understanding just the mechanisms and
the human body and this data is just
piling up as we speak.
Yeah,
but the problem is the signal to noise
ratio is almost zero.
So I would say conservatively 90%,
if not 99% of that is completely
useless.
Really.
Absolutely.
Um,
actually wrote about this once.
so when a paper comes out,
if it is never cited again,
meaning for the remainder of time,
no one ever even goes back to reference
that paper.
You could probably make the case that
that paper is not relevant.
And if you then further strip out auto
citations,
meaning the only time it's ever cited is
when the author then goes back and cites
his or her own paper.
Something like 70 or 80% of patients of
papers never get cited outside of an
auto citation.
Again,
is this because they're not relevant or
does it possible to get lofts lost in
the shuffle?
Like some of them might be worth
something?
Probably possible,
but I would bet it is much,
much more the former than the latter.
And then on top of it,
a lot of stuff comes out and then years
later you realize it was wrong,
you know,
or it was.
And that's more often the case that it
was wrong through an honest mistake then
wrong through a dishonest mistake.
But there's still a lot of wrong through
dishonest mistake.
Stuff's coming out there as well.
So how much of this data is forcing you
or causing you to alter your own
patterns?
Well,
we,
we believe internally that probably 100
papers a month enter the literature that
are relevant to what we do.
Meaning it means some of the literature
that comes out,
like,
you know,
the rheumatology literature might be
relevant to them,
but that's not what I do.
That's crazy.
Three a day.
Yeah.
So that's why when I say I want 10
analysts,
you see why it's like it's you got it.
Because first of all it's finding those
papers too.
So how do you do that?
Like what we subscribe to a whole bunch
of services that basically prefilter a
bunch of shit for us.
And then we have a system where we go
about kind of pulling that stuff.
So you get those three a day and then
they bring them to you.
How do you have the time?
No.
So is the thing,
and I,
it's funny you say that.
I was like,
literally as I was driving here today,
I was talking to my buddy of mine and I
was like,
dude,
I'm the fucking bottleneck and I hate
it.
I'm now the bottleneck because the
analysts are now turning out stuff
faster than I can even provide ancillary
feedback.
Cause my job is like,
you know,
you hire great people who are smarter
than you and like you just guide them,
you just point them in the right
direction.
So what we mostly do is create programs
where we're going out and looking for
new knowledge.
So for example,
one of the questions that is tormenting
me right now because I still don't know
the answer is,
is there any benefit to taking human
growth hormone from a longevity
perspective?
There's clearly a performance benefit.
Growth Hormone is probably the single
most abused drug in all of sports.
There's no question about that.
But,
um,
is there a way to take it where it makes
you live longer?
I've never prescribed growth hormone to
a patient.
Um,
because frankly I'm not yet confident
that I know the answer to that question.
But I feel like it's worth knowing,
right?
Cause I can certainly make a teleologic
argument for why growth hormone can be
helpful.
But I can also make a teleologic
argument for why it can be harmful.
And so like many things,
your knee jerk reaction to something can
often be wrong.
And My kneejerk reaction to growth
hormone has historically been causes
cancer because why?
Well,
growth hormone tells your liver to make
igf insulin like growth factor and you
know,
two thirds of tumors seem to thrive on
igf.
So ostensibly you would think,
well,
growth hormone can't be right.
But then one of my analysts,
Bob Kaplan pointed out to me a year ago,
he's like,
you know,
Peter,
I've been thinking about this.
And he's like,
given how ubiquitous growth hormone is
in sports and how long it's been
ubiquitous in sports,
like,
I mean,
this was the drug that turned around us
Olympic athletes in the late seventies,
early eighties.
Um,
he's like,
where's the body count?
Like we're all of these people dying of
cancer from all these years of
staggering growth hormone use.
Yeah,
I,
we don't really see it.
When we went back and looked at
literature,
I mean,
we found that the data on growth hormone
and igf are not nearly as straight
forward as people have made it out to
be.
In fact,
there's,
uh,
I mean,
I could draw it actually for you,
not that anyone who won't necessarily
see this,
but at least you'll see what I'm talking
about.
If this is percentile so higher,
and this is igf level,
right?
So,
okay.
Igf Level,
most people are listening to this.
Oh,
actually it's talking about that before.
Yeah.
So the overall mortality curve for igf
and growth hormone is like a j curve,
meaning low igfs really high mortality.
Okay.
Yes.
As you go from about the 70th or 80th
percentile up to the 90th percentile,
there's a slight increase in mortality.
But this is not what you would think of.
Like you would sort of,
if you were just reading the headlines,
you would think it looks like this.
Right?
So there's a sweet spot.
Not only that,
if you,
this is overall mortality.
What if you parse this out by disease?
Well,
that's when it gets really interesting.
So cancer's curve looks like this.
Very similar.
Yes.
But Alzheimer's curve looks like this
heart disease curve looks like this.
So describe that to people that are
listening.
So what that means is,
so for example,
Alzheimer's disease and heart disease
have an almost monotonic reduction in
risk.
As igf gets higher and higher and
higher,
it's only cancer that seems to have that
uptick.
We're risk starts to actually rise once
you cross past the call at 70th
percentile.
And so when you integrate all of these
curves together,
that's why you see this slight uptick.
Now again,
this is epidemiology,
so one has to take this with a grain of
salt,
but this is to me,
when I saw this graph,
which Bob put together,
I don't know,
a while ago I was like,
wait a minute,
this doesn't jive with my preconceived
notion of like growth hormone is bad.
This warrants way further exploration.
And so what that basically turned into
is now an enormous internal project that
will take us probably a year to complete
and we'll constantly be updated.
Like we did this already with
testosterone two years ago.
We put together like a 40 page white
paper on the topic and then at least
once every two weeks it gets updated.
Every time a new paper comes out and
basically asking the question like,
is testosterone replacement beneficial
or harmful and under what situations
should it be considered versus not?
And again,
the goal is to do this and emotionally,
and that's hard to do because for
reasons I'm not entirely clear on
basically everyone's kind of just
emotional about this stuff.
Well there are emotional about steroids
because of all the press about Barry
bonds and you know,
all the different baseball players that
got caught with it.
Is,
is it,
is it getting,
is it the cheating aspect of it?
100%.
Yeah.
I think that's exactly what it is.
I think people consider taking any kind
of hormone,
whether it's growth hormone or
testosterone as cheating.
Even if you're talking about older
people that take it like,
uh,
I was,
looking at one of those ads,
you know,
they have those ads for hormone
replacement that is really old looking,
Jeffry life I think.
Is that his name?
Doctor Life Jack.
And he's fucking,
he's got a full six pack controlled like
a gorilla.
And,
uh,
my friend was like,
God,
that can't be healthy.
I'm like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Look at him.
I go,
what do you think a 70 year old dude is
supposed to look like?
They're supposed to be knocking on
death's door.
That guy looks like he could fuck his
way through a building full of teenage
girls.
You know?
He's like,
I shouldn't say teenage 20 year old,
21 or 19.
He looks like a man who's really fit and
healthy with an old guy's head.
Yeah,
it's weird.
And I was like,
you know,
if it's not healthy,
then what is it?
If that's not healthy,
like,
oh,
he's going to die of cancer.
He's going to die of a heart attack.
He's going to die.
Period.
If you look at his head,
how much time would you give him?
I gave you a,
if I gave you a bet,
okay,
we have $1 million bet.
Uh,
give you an over under of 10 years.
How many,
how many years are you going to give
this guy?
You're going to give him 20.
You gonna give them,
wait,
you're moving the over under,
you said I had the only,
I had a 10 year window on that.
Right.
You get,
you get to tell you take over.
I'll take over on the tenure.
Okay.
Um,
what do you,
how many years would give them
impossible to know if,
am I allowed to talk to him first?
No,
no,
no fucking clue.
You're looking at a magazine,
right?
No,
no,
no I can't because I got to know his
family history.
I mean honestly they of course your
parents will tell me more about how long
you'll live then what you look at.
70 in America is basically death's door.
No,
I think today.
Well,
so that's a complicated question
actually,
which is actually prompts another
analysis who just kicked off in the 10
year range.
Yeah,
no.
So it,
it,
it depends how you ask the question.
So the question is what is the average
life expectancy of a man and a woman
today in the United States?
And I,
I mean,
someone's going to correct me,
so I feel like it doesn't matter what I
say.
I think it's 79 and 81 respectively for
a man and a woman today.
But the more interesting question is
this one,
which is,
so what year were you born?
67 okay,
so in 1967 what was the annual life
expectancy or the average life
expectancy of a man and a woman?
And we could look that up,
but I'm guessing it would have been.
Let's see,
life expectancy has been going up at 0.3
to 0.6% per year.
We could back out that kegger and let's
just say for shits and giggles,
like the number was 60 69 or 73 or
something like that.
I promise you,
you are going to live longer than that.
What was it?
67 67 all right,
so do,
would I take the bet that you're going
to live longer than 67 even though that
was the median life expectancy the year
you were born?
Hell yeah.
I'll take that all day long.
And so what we're actually putting,
this isn't just a dumb analysis we do.
I don't even know why we're doing this.
Sometimes we just do dumb shit that has
no bearing.
But what I want to do is create a graph
of actual life expectancy as realized
versus projected life expectancy in the
year of birth.
My hypothesis is that is always a
positive number.
What I want to know is what's the
derivative on it?
Is it increasing or decreasing?
So I think that science is accelerating
our longevity and that that's one of my
proof points is that we are constantly
underestimating how long we can live.
Now,
on the other end of that spectrum,
I am not one of these futurists who
thinks like there's in mortality out
there.
You know,
I would be,
if right now I could sign a piece of
paper that would say,
Peter,
are you willing to commit to a lifespan
right now?
So you're willing to acknowledge that if
there's some major breakthrough,
you'll miss out on it.
But I guarantee you this duration,
like what would you take right now if I
said,
Joe,
you can be a hundred and and be fully
functional at a hundred so when you're a
hundred you're going to get run.
Yeah,
you're going to be like,
you're going to be like a fit 60 year
old at a hundred.
So you're still working out.
You're still shooting pretty good.
Yeah.
Would you take it?
Nope.
In other words,
you're willing to bet that by the time
we get there.
Yeah.
Because when it's over it's over anyway.
So I mean to me I think most people have
a greater sense of confidence about
where technology goes now that I think
they're really only been a handful of
step function changes in longevity.
So,
um,
you know,
the production of infant mortality was
huge.
Like once we actually figured out how
the fuck to deliver babies and not kill
moms,
like that was a big deal that had a step
function improvement in human longevity.
The next one was really sanitation.
Like once we figured out that like don't
shit where you drink huge improvement in
human mortality.
Hilarious.
It's amazing.
Right?
Then we take that shit for granted now.
Right.
And then the third one was basically
germ theory.
You know,
starting with lister and going all the
way to Fleming when we figured out like,
you know,
if you,
if you cut open a cadaver and then go
and deliver a baby,
that's bad.
Um,
because there were these microscopic
things that none of us anticipate,
right?
We haven't had a step function
improvement in mortality and nearly a
hundred years.
So what's next?
Now I think there were a couple of
potentials for that,
but what I don't know as if like they're
going to happen in my lifetime,
in your lifetime,
but I want to buy the optionality to
stick around for it by doing all this
incremental little shit.
It will these three plus papers a day
and the options are increasing.
It's,
it's just seems to me that it's,
there's a trend,
right?
The trend is,
as you,
as you're saying,
there is an increase of longevity,
but it's not a huge increase.
Right.
Um,
but our understanding of the human body
is,
that's,
that seems to be pretty radically
improving,
especially in terms of nutrition,
nutritional absorption and the
mechanisms behind nutrition on some
level.
Yeah.
And on some level I still feel like
we're in the dark ages because you
recognize the potential or you know?
No,
because I think,
I think I'm just humbled by how hard it
is to actually take care of people.
Like I,
I think so I was about,
I'm about as good or responder is you're
going to have to carbohydrate reduction.
So doing something as simple as just not
eating carbs and not eating sugar,
like completely changed my health.
I mean at 40 if you compare the 40 year
old me to the 30 year old me,
like the 40 year old is like literally
twice as healthy as the 30 year old me.
And that was through something as simple
conceptually simple as making this
radical dietary shifts.
And by what standards are you saying
that you're twice as healthy at 40 than
30 how will you now 45 and but what,
what is the,
I mean again,
I'm speaking a bit glibly even let's
just talk objective.
Yeah.
So like what would be my lip had levels,
what would be my triglyceride levels?
How much body fat do I have?
What's my vo two Max like by all of
those metrics,
like everything was just so much better
at 40.
Um,
I mean,
and,
and so I've split yet I've seen a lot of
patients where you take the carbs out of
their diet,
it doesn't matter.
You know,
you,
you felt that you,
you make them fast,
you do this,
you know,
the only thing that you just can't fix
some of the underlying metabolic
problems.
Like what kind of problems?
No,
I think some people are just so insulin
resistant that it becomes really hard to
fix them without doing draconian stuff.
I mean,
I have one patient who he's really now I
think going to in many ways become the
poster child for,
he's definitely the toughest case I've
ever had and why he's such an amazing
guy is he was actually able to do
something that's really hard to do,
which is stick to something with
complete blind faith in me.
Even when it didn't feel good,
even when I knew it would take a long
time to see the results.
So he,
he's probably five foot eight ways to 35
at the start.
So five,
eight to 35 metabolic syndrome,
huge amount of fatty liver disease.
I'm not the typical patient in my
practice.
Most of my patients are kind of young,
healthy people who want to like,
you know,
want this and mortality thing.
But um,
this is someone who doesn't fit that
description probably 70 years old,
uh,
on like,
you know,
for drugs,
for blood pressure,
10 gregory heavy for a seven year old.
Yeah,
it is.
Yeah.
Oh,
and his,
and he just had a hip replacement.
You basically couldn't walk,
you know,
everything was,
and we had tried carbohydrate
restricting him before.
It just didn't work.
And part of it was,
I don't know how he just,
it was hard for him to stick to it and
go about,
so I just said to him,
look,
man,
I want to try something completely
fucking extreme and I want to try it for
six months,
every five days per me.
Every month you're going to spend the
first five days eating 500 calories a
day of a ketogenic diet.
And it's basically just going to be like
vegetables,
oil.
Like you're basically eating a bunch of
salad and then for the next 25 days
you're going to do a time restricted
ketogenic diet where you're only going
to eat in that eight hour window and
then you're going to repeat that every
month for six months.
And he was like,
I won't be able to do it.
And I was like,
I know,
I know.
It seems crazy.
I think you will be able to do it
because remember all that time that
you're not eating,
your body's going to have to start
eating itself.
And so you'll be all right.
And the,
I'm giving you a grossly over simplified
version of what we did,
but it was much more complicated than
that.
There's a bunch of other stuff that we
had to do to manage it as well.
Well,
I mean,
he just sent me,
I mean we were in touch all the way
along,
so it was clear that this was working,
but it was just kind of amazing to get a
picture from him two weeks ago as we
just past that six month mark,
he weighs a buck 75 whoa,
that's 60 pounds in six months.
Holy Shit.
His liver,
this is,
and that's interesting,
but not nearly as interesting to me is
the fact that his trans amylases,
which are the enzymes that the liver
makes in response to how much fat is
accumulating.
You know,
normal is like less than 40.
He was like in the hundreds and you
know,
the ultrasound showed it was just a
bunch of fat and he doesn't drink
alcohol.
So we knew it was fatty liver,
nonalcoholic fatty liver disease,
you know,
now he's in the twenties and thirties,
um,
blood pressures,
previous diet.
What was he eating?
Standing normal dude.
Yeah.
Just to say he wasn't a particularly
junk food,
you know,
he wasn't a junkie guy.
The problem is he was metabolically
broken.
So I'll come back to why I felt like
this was unnecessary intervention,
despite how draconian it was.
Um,
he's on a treadmill 30 minutes a day
now.
He couldn't walk before.
I mean,
you take 60 pounds off the treadmill.
You mean walking in?
She walks on a treadmill now.
Yeah.
You can't really recently once you get
the hip replacement.
Yeah.
Um,
so it's just,
it's basically reprogrammed him and,
and,
and so the reason I have occasionally
pulled that trick out,
although it hasn't always,
is based on this case study I read
that's very famous.
I'm sure some,
I'm,
there's gotta be someone in this show
who's talked about it,
but it was,
um,
the paper was published in either the
early seventies or late sixties,
but it was the longest ever medically
supervised fast.
So it was this guy who weighed somewhere
between 375 and 400 pounds.
He did a 382 day inpatient medical fast
where he had only water and minerals.
At the end of that,
something like 382 days,
he was down from,
call it 400 to a buck 65 this paper was
published seven years later he weighed
like a buck 70 a buck 75 the crazy thing
about that guys,
it's skin track to,
yeah,
so he didn't have that problem that a
lot of people have when they lose a lot
of weight where they have all this extra
skin,
his skin went along with his body.
Yeah.
And I wonder if that's just due to
genetic elasticity.
Yeah,
exactly.
I would like to know,
I'd like to know if he had stretch marks
when it shrank.
You know?
You know,
it's funny,
I've never tried to figure out like
whatever came of that patient.
I can't imagine he'd be alive now
though.
I know he was young at the time,
but the,
the part that interested me was that he
didn't regain all the weight seven years
later and that suggested that there was
a,
like it was a reprogram.
I was like,
you've got the blue screen of death on
the computer.
Did the hard reset.
You got to be a new person again because
I'm not of the camp that thinks like
that guy got to be 400 pounds just
because he was a glutton and a slot,
like something fundamentally broke in
that dude.
And what broke was he basically lost the
ability to partition fueled correctly.
Now,
could food play a role in that?
Absolutely.
Certainly if you eat enough shit that
can happen.
Um,
but I think it's more complicated than
that.
I think it can be epigenetic,
uh,
if not outright genetic but probably
more epigenetic.
Um,
and so I'm interested in this idea of
how do you reset people.
Um,
and again,
this is all kind of long winded way of
saying like,
one of the advantages of practicing
medicine is you get to you,
you say humble because every,
every time you think you're smart and
you're like,
I got this shit figured out.
Like,
you know,
there's like some patient who's got a
problem that you can't figure out and it
just drives you nuts.
But you realize like,
I mean even just today,
I was talking to a friend of mine,
he's not a patient,
but I mean my God,
he's just going through like this
devastating health situation.
He's been,
he has seen every doctor,
he's been to mass general,
he's been to Stanford,
he's been to hopkins,
he's been to the best hospitals in this
country.
They can't fucking come close to figure
out what's wrong with this guy.
And so as bad as that is for him,
I think that level of humility is
actually good for the profession.
It's good to what is going on with him
that they can't figure it out.
He's having these horrible neurologic
symptoms where he gets these for
circulations and muscle weakness.
And obviously the big concern about six
months ago when this started was he,
he was presenting like he had Lou
Gehrig's disease,
which you know,
obviously is about as bad a fade as you
can have.
Um,
luckily that has been ruled out and
they've done a million muscle biopsies
and all these other things,
but they don't know what's going on.
Has He altered his tie and he's taking,
no,
no.
We don't know what's going on.
It's,
it is certainly far outside of my area
of expertise.
I mean,
what we talked about today was,
look,
man,
all we really need to be doing is fixing
your symptoms at this point.
In other words,
there's understanding what's causing
this and then managing the symptoms
around it.
I think the smartest people in the
country had figured out,
they have no goddamn clue what's going
on.
Let's now figure out how to manage your
symptoms,
your energy levels,
your mood,
all of these other things.
What has,
what has he done for that?
Well,
I told him today,
I was like,
look,
I'm going to send you a kit.
We're going to do a certain blood test
on you and a certain urine test on you,
and I want to just figure out what's
going on with your four hormone systems.
There's basically four hormone systems
play a pretty big role in how we feel
and adjusting those dozen,
I'm not convinced it necessarily makes
you live longer,
but it can certainly make you live
better.
So I want to kind of understand.
I suspect he's not firing on all
cylinders on that dimension.
Whether it's a result of whatever is
going on that nobody can figure out or
not.
But I'd rather focus on something that I
think we can fix.
Yeah.
The,
the change in diet thing with that guy
where he went and fasted for 360 plus
days,
what did he eat when he got back on
food?
Great question.
I do not know the answer now.
That might be that,
that just,
I don't recall that being in the paper,
but if it wasn't,
I don't know if anybody did the follow
up,
but that's,
to me that's the interesting question to
kind of feel amazing.
Like he got his life back,
right?
Like,
and my recollection is he was a young
man.
He was in his late twenties,
I think.
Yeah.
I believe I remember that as well.
I think,
um,
I would like to find out what he's
eating now to keep his weight at the
same level.
I mean,
he must just be so thankful.
First of all,
you might be like,
I mean,
I have friends that are pretty
overweight and one that died pretty
recently who was really big and he just
had this feeling when he would meet
people.
I mean,
you talked about it a little bit,
it was just obese.
It was just this thing where you're
just,
Oh,
look at this enormous fat guy.
And then to go from that to,
oh,
there's a guy,
there's normal guy.
Yeah,
that's just a guy.
It's 168 pound guy.
Normal.
No difference between the hand.
I gotta Tell Ya,
I know we,
we love that.
We love to beat up on fat people.
We love to turn it into a character
defect.
But I gotta tell you virtually every fat
person that I know or that I've taken
care of,
they are not disproportionately eating
more than their peers in some cases,
yes,
but not unbalanced it.
The problem is that they simply do
everything incorrectly,
metabolically,
you know,
so their body is functioning correctly
and it's,
you know,
there's a genetic component.
I think there are dietary exacerbations.
I think certainly not exercising makes
things worse.
So there are lots of predisposing
factors,
but at the end of the day what's
happening is when you and I eat like
let's,
let's take a meal that,
that like if you had pancakes and
scrambled eggs,
that would be like a really good mix of,
that'd be a third carbs,
a third protein,
a third fat.
So it's like a shit ton of nutrient,
right?
If you or I ate that,
yeah,
it probably wouldn't be that good for
us.
But like we,
you know,
let's say we just finished a workout or
something like we're going to partition
such that that glycogen will first and
foremost go to replace the muscle and
liver stores of glycogen because we have
bigger muscles and our muscles are more
insulin sensitive.
We can actually disproportionately put
more glycogen into our muscles,
into the leg muscles,
cause you'll have done that,
run up the hills.
Right.
And,
and then furthermore,
when we want to recruit energy again,
we'll have the ability to actually go
back and get fat.
Especially,
you know,
in other words,
break down fat at lower atp demands than
necessarily always going to glycogen.
So in other words,
we partition fuel in a smarter way.
And these patients,
I mean you can measure this clinically
using something called rer and of course
doing other blood tests,
like they just,
they just,
they can't break down their own fat.
So their body is essentially broken in
that regard.
And that can be fixed with,
with diet.
It's a hard problem because the way I
explain it to people is,
and so clinically I'm not interested in
weight loss,
right?
I mean that's just not,
I'm much more interested in longevity
and yeah,
sometimes weight loss comes with that,
but I like if I ever get stuck doing
weight loss,
like I'll,
I'll,
I'm doing the wrong thing for my
interest.
But um,
the way I say to people when they want
to lose weight is,
look,
you don't want to lose weight.
You want to lose fat.
Let's,
let's be very clear on our semantics.
It weight is irrelevant,
right?
Unless you're a cyclist or some athlete
for whom the actual scale means
something.
But for,
for people like us,
it's you want to lose fat,
not wait.
And then when you say you want to lose
fat,
what does that mean in English?
Well,
do you want fewer fat cells or do you
want each fat cell to be smaller?
Those are totally different questions.
If you want fewer fat cells have
liposuction,
but we know that that doesn't fix you
metabolically.
So if you want fewer,
if you want to be less fat,
you have to have smaller fat cells.
Now at fat cell conceptually has two
inputs and one output.
So now I say,
let's reframe the question.
You've got a room with a hundred people
in it.
You want fewer people in the room.
What has to happen?
More people have to leave the room,
then enter the room.
So similarly,
if you have a fat cell and you want it
to be less fat,
you've got to get more fat out of it.
Then enters it.
And the fact that exits the cell exits
via a process called lipolysis and the
inputs to a fat cell or something called
De Novo Lipogenesis,
which is turning carbohydrates into fat.
And Reyes tariffs location,
which is turning fat,
like in a free fatty acid into a
triglyceride back into a fat cell.
Each of those three doors is controlled
by hormones.
And so the purpose of nutrition or
fasting or exercise or drugs or hormones
or all these things is to manipulate
those hormones in the direction of what
I call negative fat flux or what would
be referred to in the literature as fat
balance,
negative fat balance.
And the hormones that drive that are are
insulin,
hormone sensitive lipase,
testosterone,
estrogen,
cortisol being the five most important
in my opinion.
Uh,
maybe someone will disagree with that,
but I think those are the five that
ruled the roost.
And so,
you know,
how do you manipulate those?
Well,
insulin seems to be the most important
of the five and there's no better way to
lower insulin than to not eat.
So the first thing that happened to that
dude who went 382 days without anything
but water and minerals is he basically
had very low insulin levels.
In fact,
once he got into raging Ketosis,
which he got into by about day seven,
his insulin came up only to prevent him
from going into Ketoacidosis,
which was what would happen if he had no
insulin response.
In other words,
if he was a type one diabetic,
he would have died if ketoacidosis,
because he wouldn't have had the insulin
to regulate the uptick of ketones.
But if you are,
I did this because we have a normal
pancreas.
We would actually remake just enough
insulin to suppress key to genesis and
keep that Beta hydroxy butyrate level in
the,
you know,
kind of in the neighborhood of probably
seven or eight millimolar as opposed to
getting north of 12 to 15,
which is when you get into trouble.
So,
you know,
how do you manipulate insulin?
Nutrition is the first way.
If you can't fast,
the next best thing is to reduce
carbohydrates.
Carbohydrates,
obviously you're the most insulinogenic
of food,
although protein can be quite
insulinogenic as well.
It has a different response.
Um,
and then that's when you start to think
about these other things.
You know,
I've seen patients where they just can't
lose weight and I watch what they're
doing and they're doing everything
right,
but they just can't lose weight.
But then you notice their cortisol
levels through the roof.
It's hard to get rid of fat when you
have lots of cortisol.
Cortisol is a very anabolic hormone to
fat and a very catabolic hormone to
muscle,
which is the exact opposite of what we
want to stop.
The drone,
of course is the exact opposite.
Testosterone is catabolic to fat but
anabolic to muscle.
Um,
and then of course,
you know,
women have a harder time because once
women go through menopause,
they lose all the estrogen and all the
testosterone.
And so now they lose two hormones that
play a very important role in regulating
this.
So for these people that are having the
issue with cortisol levels,
that's exacerbated by stress.
Right?
So stress actually exacerbates your
weight gain.
Absolutely.
That's interesting.
In addition to a whole bunch of other
stuff,
literally eat the same diet and gain
more weight because of stress.
Absolutely.
Wow.
Again,
hormones are what's driving fuel
partitioning.
You know,
you're responsible for what you put in
your mouth,
but in many ways at that point,
like the hormones take over and decide
where it's going.
Wow.
That's fascinating.
Now you yourself,
what,
what's your diet like?
I mean you,
you told me you only eat once a day,
but yeah,
I'm one one meal a day or sometimes two
meals a day.
How many calories you're taking in,
you know,
nowhere near what I used to.
I just don't train that much anymore.
I mean,
I kind of lift three days a week and
then I,
I ride like a stationary bike,
like a Peloton or I prefer this thing
called a Whoa who kicker where you
actually put your bike on it.
So I'll do that three or four times a
week.
Um,
I would guess when I sit down to throw
down,
it's probably 3000 calories
in one meal,
Huh?
Yeah.
Although the problem is I'm a fucking
pig,
like I'm kinda discussed and like I can
eat a lot.
It's,
it's gross.
Like I gross people out of how much I
can eat.
It's pretty,
for me to only eat 3000 calories in a
sitting is like tame.
Really?
Yeah.
No,
I have an eating disorder.
Really.
I mean I sort of,
I think I have disordered eating.
Yeah.
I,
I'm seems like you just enjoy it because
you do it once a day.
No,
under any circumstance.
Like I stress eat,
I um,
I do get a dope.
Like I don't get a dopamine high from
gambling or alcohol.
Like I don't like those things are not
things that I can abuse.
Like when I'm really in a shitty place
in life,
like I,
I sued and punish myself with food.
A lot of people do.
So you could relate and as a thin man,
you know,
when you're talking to people that are
large and have the same issue,
it's a good thing to know its toll.
I mean,
I completely understand what these
people are going through,
but at least in as much as what the,
as the,
as the physiologic desire for it.
I mean,
obviously they will experience something
even worse because there's the,
like I can like,
look,
I don't have abs on,
I don't have veins in my abs anymore.
I used to,
when I was in a ketogenic diet,
you know,
7% body fat,
I was completely ripped.
I'm not ripped anymore,
you know,
relative to that,
that kind of bugs me.
But like nobody really knows that.
I mean,
nobody really gives a shit.
So I can still like look like a super
healthy dude,
a super lean dude,
even if I'm not.
Um,
but oh my God,
like when Shit's going wrong,
like I want to eat some of the worst
foods that have ever been created.
You know what I mean?
Why is that instinct there?
Why is the instinct that when you're not
feeling like for me it's tired.
Like if I'm tired,
like if I'm coming home from a Gig and
it's two o'clock in the morning,
it's very difficult for me to drive past
Wednesday's,
you know,
I want to go to Wendy's and Reno.
That could be,
that could be a course that could be an
adrenal issue.
So a lot of times we'll see when people
either turn to sugar or salt in times of
fatigue,
a lot of times it can be,
uh,
you know,
they don't have the right level of free
cortisol at that moment in time.
I always feel it's a willpower issue
because if I could just get home,
I'll cook something healthy and then I
have victory,
you know,
cause if I get home,
I know I've got healthy food at home,
I eat something really good and it's
just as good.
But there's something about also there's
like you doing something,
you know,
you shouldn't do,
there's a little weird little charge
there.
Yeah,
that's interesting.
I mean,
I guess it's different for different
people.
I think for me,
if I'm really going to be brutally about
it,
I think it's that I,
like,
I sometimes just want to punish myself
and I'm like,
you know,
like eating bad food is like when you're
bad,
you eat bad food,
you give yourself a cheat day.
Um,
you know,
I don't,
not really,
I mean,
I think these days and you know,
you've got kids,
so you know what I mean?
Cheat Day is just present themselves
often enough or other reasons.
And unfortunately,
I think for me the cheat meals are a lot
of times cleaning up a kid's plate or
something like that.
You know,
like,
I mean,
the funny thing is I just,
I really don't know why I just like
shitty food.
Like I like macaroni and cheese.
I just,
if they don't eat their macaroni and
cheese,
I got to eat it.
My kids asked me to make them peanut
butter and jelly the other day and they
don't,
each is really good.
It's fucking fantastic.
Especially with the glass of milk.
They don't need the crusts.
And I'm like,
well,
he's crushed.
Shouldn't go.
Oh God,
this happens in Africa.
That shit eat that crow.
So I ate the Krug and I thought about
all the bread with peanut butter and
Jelly.
I ate in those cross.
I basically had a fucking sandwich.
It's like I'm pretending that I'm just
eating a little,
cried a lot.
I'm worse than you,
dude.
You know what I would've done in that
situation?
I would've been like peanut butter
jellies.
Well I would have started by saying
there's not enough peanut butter and jam
on these crusts too.
Like I don't have the right ratio.
So I would have like got out of the
peanut butter and the jam and dip the
crust in there and like,
and then I would've probably made a
sandwich.
I'm just happy that I didn't need a
I'm of my own as well as their cross
cause I probably cook once,
once the fucking gates are open.
Once I'm out there making spaghetti and
meatballs like,
all right,
let's get some fucking ice cream in
Hispanics too.
You know,
what's a Merde fucking off?
Um,
so what do you,
what do you eat,
like when you sit down for these 3000
calorie meals?
Uh,
so if I'm in control of the meal,
which I usually am and I'm,
I'm super boring dude,
so it's,
um,
I like to have a salad in a bowl.
It's larger than my head.
Um,
so I was referred to that as a manly
bowl.
That's the definition of a manly bowl.
So it's gotta be like a staggering
amount of salad.
And my salad is the same every freaking
day.
It's Romaine lettuce,
it's,
you know,
tomatoes,
mushrooms,
cucumbers,
carrots.
And then the dressing is just extra
virgin olive oil,
freshly squeezed lemon salt and pepper.
So it's pretty bland salad in that
sense.
But I mean,
I can eat that all day,
every day.
And then it's a serving of protein and I
usually cycle through salmon,
pork,
steak,
you know,
get some Gamey meat,
like whatever.
I just sort of cycled through that and
then I usually have some sort of starchy
vegetable to go with it.
So,
um,
potato,
rice.
You know,
lately the last couple of weeks I've
been skipping the starch and just
mainlining extra salad and extra
protein.
Um,
but you know,
but,
but that's insane.
That's what I'm in San Diego where I
have control over what I eat more in New
York.
I never eat in my apartment.
Like I just never cook,
so I always go out and there it's a
little less regulated.
So,
I mean,
I just love Indian food.
I love Persian food.
I love food.
That unfortunately is,
you know,
got more carbs in it then I'm probably
for,
but I try to modify.
So like last week I had um,
this Bob who's actually one of my,
my head analyst,
he lives in Boston.
He came down to New York for a couple of
days.
We were doing some work and we went out
for,
he loves Indiana and I live in and so we
went out for Indian one night and we
hadn't eaten all day.
So we ordered I think seven or eight
entrees and the waiter is like,
you know,
uh,
you guys,
no you ordered seven or eight entrees,
right?
We're like,
yeah,
we got it.
We got it,
we're good.
And so,
you know,
we sort of skipped the non or maybe had
one non to split instead of,
normally I would've had like four nuns
and only had one bowl of rice.
But still a lot of carbs.
It is.
Yeah.
Naan bread is insane.
Luckily babied more of it than I did and
he's way more jacked than me,
so he can get away with eating way more
non than me.
Um,
but yeah,
that night,
I mean also those sauces are like so
fatty.
Like I'm sure that was a 4,000 calorie
throw down.
Um,
the other thing I'm,
I'm pretty good about is when I'm done,
I'm done.
So that's the other thing about time
restricted feeding that I think I get
away with more because like when I go
back to my apartment,
I will rarely have another bite.
And when I wake up in the morning,
it's like black coffee,
you know,
I'm not sneaking little shit in
throughout the day.
Like,
whereas if I'm not fasting,
it's just too easy for me to just like
skip stuff.
Oh yeah.
Like in my office,
like I shared my office in New York,
I share with another doctor who is his
office.
Actually.
I kind of sublet an office there,
but like I've never seen more shit in my
life.
Like then the stuff patients bring for
him to eat and patients bring him shitty
food nonstop doctor.
Of course they're trying to torture him
for torture and now,
I dunno maybe,
but it's like,
you know,
are drug reps will bring stuff by or
something like that.
There's just like,
there's an endless barrage of bad food
to eat,
but it's like good,
bad food.
Delicious.
Like if they were bringing like Oreos
that actually wouldn't tempt me despite
the monkey homecooked Brownie.
Yeah,
exactly.
Like I forget the name of um,
God,
I can't remember the name of some of
these bakeries up there,
but,
but yeah,
there's like some ridiculous shit that
shows up and every once in a while like
I'm like,
okay,
the fastest breaking at four o'clock
today,
give me one of those scones.
But as long as you do it with
moderation,
you think you're okay.
Yeah.
Except that my motto in life is
moderation is the only thing worth doing
in moderation.
So the problem is once I start like,
it's usually the wheels come off the bus
pretty quick.
Do you try to mitigate that with
exercise?
Like do you say that went off the rails
today?
So let's hit the gym and go hard.
It's less that it's usually I
anticipated.
And so like so.
So last week a buddy of mine went to see
the David Bowie exhibit.
Did you see it by the way,
that Brooklyn?
No.
Are you a Bowie fan at all?
Yeah.
Oh Dude.
It's there until mid June or July
Brooklyn at the Brooklyn Museum.
It is clean a couple of weeks ago,
but I was only there for two days for
the UFC and I had a show out there.
Uh,
so probably one of the best shows I've
ever seen in my life.
Yeah.
Unbelievable.
I didn't realize it,
but like it closed at 11:00 PM and
they'd just didn't have the heart to
tell me.
So I was there until midnight before
they finally came and escorted me out of
the building.
They're like,
uh,
sir.
We closed an hour ago and I was like,
damn sorry man.
So what is it?
It's like an exhibit of all of his art,
all of his music,
all of,
and it's like,
it's done.
You know when you go to museums and they
put the headphones on you and you have
to like push the button to hear the
thing.
It doesn't work that way.
Like whatever you stand near,
you get the music associated with that
plus or minus and narrative as
necessary.
But it was like,
I've never like they,
I think they had every one of his
costumes.
Wow.
It was,
it was epic.
So anyway,
that night I knew we were going to go
out for a killer dinner before in
Brooklyn before we went to the show.
And so normally I exercise in the
morning,
but that day I was like,
look,
I will,
your muscles will be a little bit more
insulin sensitive if you can exercise
about 30 minutes before you eat.
That's probably about the sweet spot.
So if I were to ride at like eight in
the morning and then not eat until seven
at night,
I Kinda,
I mean I would still eventually get the
glycogen there,
but it wouldn't be quite as easy.
It would require a little bit more
insulin.
So in that case I just modified my day
and was like,
you know,
made my schedule such that I could ride
at 5:00 PM in anticipation of that.
And I also wrote a little longer and a
little harder just you know,
like let's really crush this session so
that you know,
I can go and enjoy dinner a little bit
more.
Well it sounds like you enjoy a lot of
things.
You have a lot going on,
you've got your,
your medical practice,
you have all these different things you
participated in as far as athletics,
boxing and swimming and cycling.
What jazzes you up now?
Like what do you like,
how do you,
you obviously have a mind that requires
a lot of stimulation.
Like what,
what keeps you going?
Um,
I mean I think,
I think this longevity thing is the
perfect culmination of all of my
previous lives in terms of professional
lives.
So I mean I used to be an engineer and
then I went into surgery and then I left
that and went into management consulting
and it was a hundred like,
had nothing to do with medicine for
several years.
I just worked in credit risk modeling.
And so in many ways like when you
combine medicine with engineering,
with risk management,
that is what longevity is all about.
Like if you want to take the
practitioners,
you know the roll up your sleeves
approach that that's what it is.
So I think that scratches that itch but,
but I think for me like I have to be
sort of mastering something.
So that's where archery and race car
driving today become just total
obsessions.
And like when we were talking earlier,
it's like yeah,
I mean I don't know that I'll ever go
hunt because I don't know that I want to
spend three days,
you know,
taking 10 shots when I could be
spending,
you know,
three days taking 300 shots in my
backyard.
Like in the end,
I think what I really just obsess over
is trying to get better at something.
And the nice thing when you start things
late in life,
like I didn't get my racing license till
three years ago and I only picked up
archery two years ago or maybe a year
ago.
Like when you suck so much,
like the opportunity to get better is
awesome.
So I think the bigger itch for me is not
intellectual.
I think it's like tinkering.
It's like figuring out how to do shit
better.
Yeah.
I,
I share a similar interest and things I
suck at and that's what one of the
things that was so compelling to me
about archery.
When did you start
2013?
I think I bought,
well I bought a bow before that,
but I didn't really use it.
Uh,
2013 I think is right when I got pretty
serious about it.
You had John Dudley on your show once,
didn't you?
Yeah,
a couple times.
I wasn't skipping Bhutan.
I mean that shot through the handle of
the kettle bell was that a hundred
yards?
I think it was a little more,
but yeah.
Yeah,
that is,
that's one of my favorite things in the
world.
He's helped me a lot.
He's a remarkable archery coach and it
just a great person to just a great guy.
One saw on Instagram,
him and Jocko and the uh,
they bumped into each other in an
airport and,
and so like I saw Jocko like two days
later we had coffee one day to be clear,
Jocko head tea.
I had coffee draco's a tea guy,
but I was like,
dude,
I can't believe you know John Dudley
goes,
I dunno.
He just grabbed me in the airport and I
was like,
dude,
I,
there's shot too.
I want to see this.
He did it with a lighted nock let knock
people don't have any idea how great it
is.
They cannot fathom what he just did.
I've seen him do some regular shit.
He's a bad motherfucker when it comes to
archery,
that's for sure.
And he's helped me.
Tremendous.
Where does he live?
He lives in Iowa.
He moved to Iowa just so he can kill big
giant deer because he literally bought a
farm in Iowa,
giant chunk of land and raises it for,
he has,
he does do some farming,
but essentially what he does is raises
deer.
It doesn't raise him like there's no,
there's no fence.
Right.
It makes it very,
make it favorable for them to be there.
He has food plots that he grows.
And I mean,
I hunted on this place a couple of years
ago.
It's amazing.
It's,
it's an incredible place.
He loves it.
I just,
I remember when I bought my bow,
like I just sort of,
you know,
went into the arts,
like performance archery in San Diego is
like a place to go,
right?
Yeah.
Went in there and it was like,
okay,
here's what I want to do.
They're like,
why?
I'm like,
just want to do it.
okay,
great.
And then I remember when I got all my
kit and my setup and they're like,
all right,
you gotta go to knock on like,
you gotta just watch this dude's videos.
And yeah,
now he's literally the best.
And in terms of like,
uh,
the average person who is interested in
it,
and he's got a great podcast about it,
knock on podcast,
but he gets so geeky and technical and
his descriptions and his understanding
of it and,
and he constantly obsesses
about form and structure and,
you know,
archery.
And to me,
my history as a martial artist,
it really jives with me.
It makes sense.
Cause you could do,
you could muscle things and do them
wrong and develop bad habits and you'll
never reach your full potential or you
could do things correctly and be very,
very disciplined and focused and
understand the what,
why you're doing something and then re
really actually reach your full
potential.
There's really no other way.
And with archery specifically,
it's so satisfying.
Like as we were saying before,
when you do pull it off and you know you
do execute that perfect shot with your
rhomboids and the hand goes over the
back shoulder and you watch that Arrow
schunk go right into that bullseye.
Like yes,
I have my daughter come out and do the
slow mo shot of me from behind.
I've got like a hundred of these dumb
things on my phone and it's just like I
can watch them all day and it's like,
did I do it that I do it?
Nope,
not there.
Right.
Oh sweet.
A lot of his elbow position to the
height of the elbow.
The elbow has to be in line with the
Arrow,
you know,
and sometimes people are polling but
they're pulling in their elbows up here
instead of way back here.
Yeah.
You know,
um,
I think that's an interesting point
about certain things,
right?
So,
so to me,
the other thing I like about our tree
and race car driving is you have to
learn some emotional discipline.
You can't get pissed off and work your
way through either of those things.
You can sort of get pissed off on the
bike and it can actually charge you,
which is not to say that cycling doesn't
have technique in it,
but it plays a much smaller role.
And in the end,
the girl factor can out trumpet,
but you can't grow your way out of a
shitty shot and you cannot in a car.
If you start getting pissed,
you're done.
Absolutely done.
The same thing can be said for a lot of
things.
I think pool is one of them.
That's a big one.
Golf,
which I don't do,
but yeah.
Yeah.
Listen,
Peter,
we just did three hours,
believe it or not.
I don't believe that it's two 30
and that crazy places at a time warp.
It really is.
But,
uh,
I really appreciate this conversation,
man.
It was really fun.
So thanks man.
Thank you.
If people want to get ahold of you on
twitter,
give them your twitter address,
your website and all that stuff.
Yeah.
Peter Attia,
md on both e,
t t,
t I.
A.
I.
All right,
thanks man.
That was awesome.
Hmm.