Very nice to meet you.
Good to meet you.
How are you?
Boom.
And we're live.
Uh,
so just to give everybody a good way to
start this.
You have a book.
A book is called the desert in the sea
and you have one of the most disturbing
and craziest stories I think I ever
read.
You were kidnapped by Somali pirates and
you were held hostage for more than two
years.
Yeah.
What the fuck was that like and what
does it feel like to be a free man now?
After all that?
Are you kidding?
It feels great in America.
Wandering around the valley,
the valley where I was born and raised,
by the way,
are you?
Yeah,
this is the first time I've been back in
the valley for a couple of years now.
What,
what,
what happened and how,
how did it happen?
Long Story.
Um,
so I went to Somalia in the first place
to write a book,
a very different books about Somali
pirates right in front of me.
And um,
I.
So I'm a journalist.
I was working in Berlin at the time and
I had followed a very long trial of 10
Somali pirates in Germany in Hamburg for
about a year,
all of 2011.
And before that I had already thought
about going to Somalia because the
pirate story,
it was interesting and all sorts of ways
that I thought other writers weren't
getting to.
And I had met another journalist to a
documentary maker named Ashwin Romano
who also wanted to go to Somalia for his
own project.
And uh,
so we talked about going for a long time
and by the end of 2011,
I'm in the middle of the trial.
We all are.
Plans came together and we wound up
going in January of 2012 and we had
about 10 days of good research.
Um,
we both got pretty good material and we
were in a part of Somalia where other
journalists had gone.
So we weren't doing something that was
totally off the map,
you know.
Um,
and uh,
on the 10th day Ashwin flew off to
Mogadishu and,
um,
I went with him to the airport,
we saw him off.
And it was on the way back from the
airport that um,
a truck was waiting for our car and the
truck,
which is actually a technical,
so a battle wagon with a candidate in
the back,
stopped us,
aim the cannon through the windshield,
overpowered my Gourd and 12 guys with
Kalashnikovs pulled me out of the car.
So I was gonna put me in another car and
we drove off.
So from that moment on,
I was a captive
Jesus Christ.
And so they were obviously trying to get
some hostage.
Yeah,
no,
it was about money and I think they were
hoping for both of us,
by the way,
I'm Ashwin feels very lucky that he
didn't get captured.
So they had planned this.
Yeah.
And they were probably waiting for our
car earlier in the morning when it was
just Ashwyn's good luck that we took a
different route to the airport.
How much money were they asking for the.
Well,
so the first they asked for me was
$20,000,000,
but that was after the first week.
So I went for a week without having a
phone call home.
Um,
and in that period seals rescued two
other hostages from another part of
central Somalia,
including Jessica Buchanan in an
American and I think nine Somali guards
died in that raid and they had some Klan
relationship to some of the guys holding
me.
And so the guy's holding me were very
upset and I think that's why they asked
for $20 million and help more
importantly held onto that demand for so
long,
what they held onto it for almost a
year,
that specific number,
they wouldn't budge.
So they were in negotiations.
Yeah,
there were negotiations,
but they were,
you know,
phoning negotiations in some sense
because the Somalis weren't,
weren't really negotiating.
So for some background,
for people that are unfamiliar with the
situation in Somalia,
Somalia,
if you correct me if I'm wrong,
that area was traditionally fishermen
and yeah,
that's wrong.
It's wrong.
So that's actually the point of the
book.
That's actually one level of the title
of the desert in the sea.
So that's uh,
um,
you,
you get the idea from things that Somali
pirates like to say,
oh,
that they're just frustrated fishermen.
Uh,
that's the only part of the story.
And so that's a,
that's a very important premise in the
book.
They,
they,
um,
there are,
you know,
fishing communities on the coast and
they're being hard hit definitely by
illegal ships that come in to steal the
fish,
you know,
but that's a problem up and down in
Africa.
And because of that problem,
once Somalia had no government,
there was no navy navy to defend the
coastline,
um,
local sort of clan leaders would send
out militia boats with militiamen and
hold fishing boats for,
you know,
$50,000,
ransoms over 24 hour periods,
you know,
really nothing very much.
And they called it a license fee and
that's how you did business in Somalia
in the nineties.
We didn't hear about that.
It was too small time.
We started to hear about it when they
graduated to capturing cargo ships.
What I'd heard was that there was
illegal dumping that wasn't just
fishing,
so.
Yep.
Yeah.
And that they initially called
themselves the people's coast guard of
Somalia or the voluntary coastguard one
or
a pirate.
Um,
gangs tried to call themselves that and
they had a point,
there was no,
no one else patrolling the coast,
but that wasn't really what was going
on.
No,
no.
I was captured on land.
First of all,
every other Qa,
a hostage I met was a fisherman.
A poor fishermen captured hundreds of
miles from the Somali coast.
So that's not protecting the cost.
So what role does this stuff called cat
k,
h a t this is a,
it's a plant that they chew and it has
like a stimulant effect.
Yeah,
it's a little bit like coca leaf,
but I think actually it's a narcotic
gets you high at first.
Um,
and then you crash and you wake up
depressed and you need more.
Uh,
but these guys,
every single pirate I met was addicted,
um,
and they wound up having to sit in front
of these piles of cut every afternoon
just to get high enough for their
addiction.
And um,
then like I said,
they would,
they would crash at night and then do it
again.
In my case,
there were,
there were guards 24 hours a day,
which meant there was also a shift that
slept during the day to cut at night and
then,
and then crash in the morning.
What did you try any of that stuff?
Yeah,
I mean they,
they kept offering it to me.
It wasn't like they know take like two
or three stems with three or four times
now.
Not much,
but it changed your mood,
you know,
you could be depressed and you'd feel
better or you can be a little bit sick
and you just wouldn't feel it anymore.
Um,
but I didn't want to get addicted to it,
so I didn't,
I didn't keep pushing it.
It's that addictive.
Yeah.
Well,
I saw it.
I saw how addictive it could be with the
guards.
Uh,
you know,
a little bit on an afternoon.
Didn't make me want to keep doing it
necessarily,
but every,
every now and then I did it just for the
sake of my mood.
Yeah.
That's always in the narrative.
This cat stuff,
the,
that are some how or another unhinged
because they're on this stuff all the
time.
Yeah,
I mean you can get really unhinged in
the sense that you're,
once you're wired on it,
you're easily sort of upset and these
guys would have sometimes have
fistfights in front of me and that kind
of thing.
We're not all the time,
but yeah,
they would get,
they would get hopped up,
they would just get jittery.
And that's a very dangerous with
Kalashnikovs lying around.
So their culture somehow or another has
evolved to this point where it's
insanely common to kidnap people to the
point where if you,
if you talk about Somali pirates,
they're,
the very few countries were pirates go
after their name so easily.
Yeah.
The,
they,
um,
kidnapping became part of the culture.
That's true.
But pirate bosses which are not so
active now off the coast,
I'm also have other businesses that they
get involved in.
And so I've written about this in the
meantime to they they get involved in a
gun smuggling and also even people
smuggling on the Horn of Africa.
So,
um,
whatever it takes that kind of
equipment,
you know,
suv,
Kalashnikovs,
cheap food.
When you say people smuggling,
what do you mean?
Um,
it's a good story.
I found out,
uh,
I'm,
I'm the person that proved that on the
route between Somalia to Libya.
Um,
some former pirate bosses were active
and moving people,
so in other words,
Somalis who want to go to Libya will put
themselves in the hands of some
traffickers and some of those
traffickers might be x pirates,
but w w go there as far as just being
transported willingly,
willingly at first.
And then,
um,
there's always a place in Sudan,
it shifts from being willing to being
unwilling.
Well,
this is an issue that's been going on in
Libya recently.
You know,
I'm sure you saw the most recent slave
auctions that were videotaped and put on
Youtube,
which was,
the stories are awful.
I've heard this firsthand.
Yeah,
insanely disturbing that you're watching
a video tape of slave auctions in 2018
as well as more than disturbing it's
revival of what was going on when
slavery was legal.
So in other words,
I'm okay.
Where the,
where the Somalis are involved up to
the,
to the Libyan border is one story.
That's the story I've covered.
Um,
what happens in Libya is a different
story.
The clans and the roots that migrants
take through Libya,
the clans they put themselves in the
hands of 'em are still the same as the
clans and the routes that we used during
the slave trade.
Um,
so there's,
there's almost like a,
you know,
there's a,
there's a historical memory there of
what,
what went on and it's the same thing
happening.
Um,
so,
so I,
I suspect a lot of migrants don't quite
know how bad it can get a,
um,
the route up until Libya is probably
easier than Libya itself.
Libya itself sounds like a horror show
for the migrants.
Yeah.
Well,
it's particularly,
it's one of those bizarre things.
We have a horrible dictator like Walmart
Kadafi and he said,
well,
it's probably a good thing to get rid of
that guy.
Right?
But no,
when you get rid of them then you have
this power vacuum and apparently it's a
failed state now and it's gotten even
worse.
It's going in the direction of Somalia
right now in there,
a couple of rival governments.
I think it's a little bit more stable,
a than Somalia was after their dictator
fell,
but um,
it's similar.
There's a similar thing going on.
Um,
I,
it's true.
Gaddafi was a bad guy and,
but he was also a bulwark and he knew
that and he used that to his advantage
with a bulwark against,
against migration paths.
I've never heard that expression.
Oh yeah.
Bulwark,
bulwark.
Now what does that mean?
A roadblock.
Oh,
okay.
Um,
when you were there,
when you decided to take 10 days and
you'd done all this research,
what,
what did you expect when you went there
and what was different?
Well,
so we were careful about finding
security.
We found,
um,
a Somali elder in Berlin who could offer
the protection of his clan in Somalia
and he had done it with another
journalist,
a German journalist,
and he took us out from Galkayo,
which is a town in central Somalia out
to the coast to hope you,
which is a pirate town you might have
heard of.
And Hybrid town.
Natural Pirate town.
Yeah.
So it's all pirates.
Well,
it's in,
it's in the control of,
of pirates.
So in other words,
the government that sits in Galkayo has
no influence there.
Uh,
the pirates are the ones with who,
who can have the say.
So.
So what is their business like?
I mean,
when you say it's like a pirate town.
So the pirates are essentially in
control,
but like what else is going on there?
If you've got
control?
No,
normal Somali life is going on there.
But uh,
the,
you know,
let's say the police force would be
pirates.
Yeah.
I mean when we got there it was pretty
quiet and we didn't see much normal life
and we had a.
I'm a very organized interview and
lunch,
um,
one afternoon with a,
with a guy who turned out to be a real
pirate.
No,
that wasn't a joke.
And then we,
we left around sundown and,
and that was it.
We didn't spend a whole lot of time and
hope you
when you were there and you,
uh,
will,
you eventually got captured and taken
hostage.
What,
what was the initial experience like?
Well,
so when that happened with the,
with the technical,
with the truck at first,
my mind actually recoiled from what was
going on.
I mean,
I actually was in denial for a couple of
seconds.
I thought,
okay,
just a roadblock,
you know?
Um,
but once they captured me,
I thought this is gonna be really hard
on my family.
Jesus and they,
yeah,
they,
they beat me with their guns.
They broke my wrist,
they bloodied my scout a and they broke
my glasses.
So that's the other thing I noticed
right away.
It was like,
Shit,
I'm going to be blind.
How about uh,
your odds?
I'm nearsighted,
it's not,
not good
and this is like initial,
like right away?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
It happened in that first skirmish.
Yeah.
So your,
your wrist was broken right away because
I was trying to hold the car door closed
and they pounded on it with their gun
barrels.
Wow.
And uh,
is it hard to talk?
Uh,
no,
because now I've written the book.
I wouldn't have been able to do this
before writing the book,
but reading the book familiarized myself
with my own memories.
You know,
it made me fluent with this material,
but your physical state seems to shift
when you discuss it,
like,
oh,
maybe
your,
your shoulders have risen.
Sure.
You're like,
yeah,
I mean it's a question of,
you know,
it's just not pleasant.
I couldn't imagine.
Yeah,
I mean,
it must have been just insane.
Um,
so you said there was a long period of
time before.
Were your,
before they contacted anybody,
who do they contact?
Um,
okay.
So it was a week and they,
so I had a grant reporting grant from
the Pulitzer Center on crisis reporting.
I should've called them.
Uh,
but I had all my notes stolen,
which means all my phone numbers too.
And so when they finally brought me up
to a bluff with a little cell phone and
said,
call somebody,
I said,
well,
bring me my notes.
I need to,
you know,
find the right phone number.
I said,
no,
just call someone.
So I called my mom.
Um,
and,
and that's what happened by that.
By that time,
the FBI had informed her,
had actually come to her door and
briefed her a little on what to say on
the phone.
So,
um,
she was ready for the phone call,
you know,
she'd been sitting around for days
wondering when she was going hear from
me.
Um,
so,
but that was also true about the
Pulitzer Center was also true about my
colleagues that should be go online in
Berlin.
It was also true,
but my family in Germany,
everyone had been briefed a little bit
now.
Were they waiting for a specific reason?
Why did they wait a whole week until
they do?
It's a really good question.
I kept asking for a phone call and I
mean,
I was sitting there kind of in a panic
to,
you know,
what were they saying to you during this
week?
Said,
Oh yeah,
okay.
You have a broken arm,
right?
So you're,
you're obviously,
you're in pain,
you can't see anymore.
Yeah,
I was in,
uh,
the first,
first they took me to a Bush camp.
Then they took me with a couple of other
hostages to a prison house.
And uh,
yeah,
I had my wrist in a sling and um,
it just was,
it was painful.
It was,
it was confusing.
I really didn't know what was going on.
And then slowly they brought a doctor in
to look at the wrist and then slowly
they took us out into the bush and then
finally they do put me on the phone.
So you got medical treatment for your
wrist?
Sort of?
Yeah.
The Guy said it was,
it was probably a livestock doctor,
but the guy was,
he was a very sympathetic old,
older man,
but he said your wrist is not broken and
he put a splint on it.
And that was it.
It was broken.
Not Broken in half,
you know?
But definitely correct.
I felt I felt bones moving around in
there.
It's been rearranged.
It's been reshaped.
Did you eventually get medical treatment
when you get home for you?
Oh yeah.
What?
I got home.
But the surgery,
no,
two years and eight months later it was,
it was okay.
Fine.
Sense of functioning restaurant.
Yeah,
it's,
it's set wrong,
but it's a functioning risk.
Did you get an x Ray?
Just so you could see how weird it
looks,
didn't even bother.
Well,
now when you're there,
um,
once you get the initial phone call,
what is,
what is the process like after that?
Are they there?
Are they talking to you about what they
want?
Yeah,
they said,
okay,
do you have to demand $20,000,000 from
your mother?
Well,
I think I must have smirked or
something.
They said it's not funny.
Said yes,
actually it is.
That's not a serious demand,
you know?
Um,
but that was their opening gambit.
20 million.
What was specifically 20 million?
That's a good question.
They are the first two hostages I was
held with to say Wa fishermen.
Um,
the rent and for them was also 20
million,
but that's 10 million each.
So maybe they were just doubling it for
the American.
There was a time where they told you
that if people showed up for you that
you were going to be killed.
Oh,
sure.
They said that right away because by the
time the phone call had happened,
the raid for Jessica Buchanan and Poltis
dad had already happened too.
So,
um,
they even mentioned that to me and of
course I had no idea what they were
talking about.
I had no news,
you know,
so,
um,
I mentioned it to my mother on the
phone.
I said they're talking about a rate and
they're saying if somebody else comes
from me,
I'm going to get shot dead.
But you know,
those,
those are already the terms of a
kidnapping.
That was not a big change in my
situation.
Uh,
and my mom could tell me very little on
the phone about,
about the rescue,
but she had something positive than your
voice.
She says,
Oh yeah,
the rescue.
And I thought that doesn't sound like
the pirates of course told me the
hostages had been killed.
Like that doesn't sound like it went
bad,
but it was still another month and a
half or something before I found out the
full story.
Two and a half years is,
I know two years and eight months.
God,
now you ate with them,
you got used to them.
Did you almost become friends with them?
Sure.
I became friends with,
you know,
have friends with,
with about half the pirate guard group
that was with me at that point,
so I was held a number of places.
They also placed me on a tuna ship.
I was placed on a ship hijacked by
Somali pirates for about five months and
I think I'm the only western writer to
know life on a ship like that.
Five months for the full spring and
summer of 2012.
And then it was,
it was after that that was held on land.
I'm alone with the guards and that's
when I got to know the guards.
You must've had this feeling like
they're never going to find me.
They're moving me around and putting me
on a ship.
That was a problem.
Once the.
Especially when they put me on the ship,
I,
I felt like any progress the military
had made in finding my location would've
been completely reset.
You know,
I was terribly depressed when they first
put me on the ship.
Oh,
you were there for five months?
Yeah.
But once I was on the ship,
I felt better because there were 28
other hostages,
the crew of the ship and they were
great.
Um,
it was,
it's always better to have company when
you're a accounting.
Yeah.
So the,
the,
the other people that were running the
ship when they captured it,
they were there as well.
Yeah.
And that was a crew of 20th guys from
East Asian and Southeast Asia.
Did they speak English?
Only five of them,
so five of them were from the
Philippines and we got along with them
really good.
Uh,
everyone else we had to get to know
somehow and the ship,
they couldn't speak to each other either
because they had who's a,
like a tower of Babel on the ship.
And so they've developed their own
pigeon,
which is what sailors have done for
centuries,
you know,
it was a pigeon mixture of English and
Chinese and a few other words.
Wow.
Yeah.
That was fascinating.
I could imagine now as a writer,
you,
you had to be sort of like halfway torn.
Like,
God,
if I get out of here,
what a fucking story.
Yeah.
Uh,
yeah,
uh,
I knew I was,
you know,
living through interesting things and
gathering good material,
but um,
after at least a year or so in
captivity,
I stopped hoping that I was going to get
out alive.
I mean,
things were going so badly as far as the
negotiation was concerned that I thought
this is really the,
I'm really in deep shit now.
Is that standard for them to hold people
for that long?
Yeah,
uh,
yes and no.
Um,
I think I was held longer than any
westerner,
but the men on that ship didn't get out
for an hour for a total of five years,
just under five years they were held.
Um,
but they did get out.
Eventually they did get out in 2016.
Wow.
And I was privileged enough to go to
Nairobi and see them there.
I took him by surprise.
Wow.
So you flew out to meet them?
Well,
I was still living in Berlin and I was
following the,
the case very closely.
Um,
and the,
I helped raise some money.
The lawyers who were running it slow me
down there.
Um,
and that was really nice.
And it was nice for the guys to,
because they were obviously confused,
there was nothing but very well meaning,
but completely anonymous people around
them,
you know,
and then they were,
they kind of came out of the terminal in
Nairobi and they were still obviously
still sort of a little bit confused and
they're tapped one of them on the
shoulder and he recognized me and it was
pandemonium.
Wow.
There's a,
it was wound up on Reuters video.
I think it's available now.
How did you eventually get fried?
Uh,
they.
So my mom raised a ransom,
um,
she raised it with help from family and
friends and also some magazines.
I'd worked for some institutions in the
US and in Germany.
And um,
when she talked the pirates down to one
point 6 million,
then I got out for some reason at the
very end the pirates came down
precipitously.
The very end after two years they
holding on for like,
I think they went down to four or $5
million or something like that.
And then at the very end that came down
to what was on offer.
No explanation.
Not really accept that from my point of
view.
Um,
there were labor,
there was a labor unrest stirring among
the guards.
So in other words,
the guards were sick of holding me.
And so I,
um,
one day towards the very end,
but um,
you know,
a few weeks before I got out,
one of the guards actually said,
Michael,
we might go on strike like Detroit got,
do you need some help with that?
I can go on a hunger strike if you want.
They're like slow,
slow now.
There was one thing that I read were a
guarded left.
You alone with a loaded rifle.
It happened more than once.
What is the,
what's the thought process there in your
mind?
Yeah,
that was.
So,
especially after the first year or so.
And until how many guards you talking
about?
We're talking about seven to 15 at any
given point in,
um,
how many bullets are in the gun the.
Well,
it was a Kalashnikov sis.
A minimum of 16.
Um,
that's not enough.
It's not enough.
Um,
and there were,
there were,
there were always a few guards who were
asleep.
A few go to awake and so you go through
this thing in your head,
you think,
well,
I can grab the gun,
I can kill a few guys,
but it would be suicidal.
But I went through various scenarios in
my head all the time,
you know,
that was a,
that was a very big temptation because
the guns just lay around like junk,
you know?
Um,
and that was,
that was a dark period because the
question was not just can I blast my way
out and live,
but also should I just take care of it,
right and kill myself now because I knew
that I was causing a whole lot of
trouble for my family at home and then
we're probably military plans to come
get me,
which would put seals at risk or a
special operators at risk.
And so it's better to just check out.
And so that was on my mind often.
Especially during the second year.
Were they sympathetic characters in any
way?
I mean,
did you,
when you were around them for long
periods of time and you're taking into
consideration this life that's been
thrust upon them,
that this is the environment there grew
up in and this is the mean you,
you had to have at least in some way
gotten to know them?
Sure.
And I went there thinking,
well,
you know,
I'm going to tell their stories somehow.
Um,
did you tell them that?
Yeah.
But by the time I was captured,
that didn't matter.
No,
I'm,
yes,
of course they,
they were,
especially the ones who wanted to talk
to me.
Of course they were sympathetic.
Um,
they're the poor people.
So the,
even if it's not true that most pirates
are frustrated fishermen,
probably only about 20 percent of them
are,
uh,
all of them report,
all of them need jobs and that's why
they became pirates.
Um,
you have to layer on top of that.
The fact that it caught habit is
extremely ruinously expensive and in
Somalia,
where does that come from?
Cut.
Comes from highlands.
So it has to be grown in the mountains
of Ethiopia,
Kenya and flown in fresh.
Uh,
can't be grown in a flat hot desert
region like,
like Somalia,
Yemen,
but that's where it's popular,
especially among Muslims who can't drink
alcohol.
So,
um,
it's,
there's this whole trade in that region
of the world and most of,
most of the time it's legal.
I think they only illegal illegalized it
in Britain,
for example,
in 2014.
Really?
Yep.
I think it's illegal here,
but,
um,
the trade,
it just flows like water in that in
Somalia and the Arabian Peninsula.
So the voluntary coastguard of Somalia,
what we've been led to believe that this
is how it all started out.
How did that narrative get established?
So once they started to capture big
ships,
they fell back on that story,
which had been true up until then,
which was,
which is defending our coastline from
fishing.
So it started that way.
So did that know that right?
It's true.
And the roots of it.
Okay.
So that's what I'd heard.
What I'd heard is that it would,
it,
it started because,
not just because people were fishing out
there because they were dumping toxic
waste also.
Um,
yeah.
And that was also true,
um,
the Mafia was dumping,
we had a,
had a,
the mafia,
you know,
there were,
there were actual,
it's been sort of uncovered by Italian
journalist,
but the Italian mafia had found a way to
bring waste for a certain amount of
money down to someplace where they
thought nobody would see it again.
Um,
and that some of it washed ashore in
2004 with the Indonesian tsunami that
actually reached that part of East
Africa.
So some of those big things that the
Italians dumped over the side of their
boats wound up on the beach and Somalia.
Oh,
so an actual physical vat or something
that they can see what it was.
And I saw one of them.
Yeah.
Really?
What was in it?
I don't know,
but it was a great big sort of orange,
great big leg,
weirdly shaped cube.
How large?
A taller than me.
So at least eight feet square and it had
been used to contain some sort of toxic
waste.
That's what my fixer told me.
So.
But I had seen pictures,
similar pictures in,
um,
documentaries.
So I think it was probably true,
it's described in the book just briefly,
but um,
I,
that's the kind of thing that happened.
Certainly.
Um,
the,
the Italians were not,
or the mafia was not being very,
you know,
they were being criminals too.
So yeah,
that's the third business business.
Um,
did you watch the Tom Hanks movie?
I watched 45 minutes at the Tom Hanks
movie in Somalia.
In Somalia.
While you're captive?
Yeah.
Holy Shit.
What is that like?
Well,
I said,
well,
I knew that I knew Captain Phillips was
going to be a movie when I left.
It was already clear,
had already announced it or something.
So they had announced it when you left
and you got to watch it when Somalia.
Yeah,
because by the time,
this is towards the end of my captivity,
I had a shortwave radio,
so I was listening to the radio.
By the time it came out and went to the
Oscars,
it was all over the BBC.
So I knew about it.
I knew it was out.
I'm like,
okay,
so I'm missing Captain Phillips,
whatever,
wonder what that's like.
And then one day all the guards got new
smartphones,
pretty fancy,
smart,
and they were apparently loaded with a
new collection of films and music and
whatever to keep them occupied.
One afternoon I saw two guards just
completely wrapped by some sort of film
on the phone and I heard some American
voices.
I'm like,
I'm wondering what this film is.
And finally I said,
fuck me.
That's Tom Hanks.
So I knew what they were watching.
And two weeks later one of the guards
actually,
she handed me the phone and said,
you know,
Michael,
look.
And so I saw about 45 minutes of it.
Wow.
And of course when he handed me the
phone,
the first thing that went through my
mind is like,
okay,
I'm going to call mom,
just find a way to turn down the volume
and,
and call California.
He took the phone away before I did
that.
But I had a whole plan.
I developed a whole plan while I was
watching Captain Phillips,
you know,
get on the plane in Boston,
Logan or whatever.
Wow.
It was so atmospherically.
It was a pretty good,
pretty well done movie,
but there were a couple of scenes where
that would,
it just wouldn't have happened in real
life.
I didn't watch the movie.
Yeah.
So what was inaccurate about,
uh,
there was one scene where there was some
selection of pirates on the beach,
so in public,
um,
and I thought,
Gosh,
how did they get that?
That's,
that's,
I've never even heard of that before.
And then I thought about it and thought
and realized,
well,
that yeah,
actually wouldn't happen like that in
public.
That was just for dramatic purposes.
Um,
you know,
I was,
I was invasive their material at first
and then I realize now that I made that
up,
um,
so things like that,
but the pirates were fascinated to see
people like them and in some cases
they're friends.
I'm portrayed on screen and even though
we all know how,
you know,
the movie ends very badly for Somali
pirates.
So.
So they knew about the story that was
based on.
Yeah,
no question.
Not only that,
but one of them said that he was friends
with one of the pirates involved and I
believe him actually he had the right
clan affiliation for that.
So it's,
it's quite possible.
What was it like to see them watching
their story being depicted on the other
side of the planet?
Well,
that's what was weird is that they,
they were so fascinated by it,
but we,
you know,
otherwise they didn't necessarily like
to talk about bad news for pirates or
you know,
like I said,
when the hostages were released,
um,
or rescued in the first few days of my
captivity,
um,
I kept hearing that the hostages had
been killed.
So they like to spin things in a,
in a good way for,
for pirates in general.
So I,
I just would have assumed they would
just ignore captain phillips because it
been so badly.
They were just fascinated.
They really were.
And so what was daily life like for you?
Like you,
you ate with them?
Well,
I separately,
but sometimes in the same room they,
they made very bad food,
boiled beans and flavorless boiled goat
and that kind of thing.
Um,
but they would eat from a communal
platter is sort of elsewhere within
sight.
Um,
I didn't have to eat from the same
platter as they eat by hand by hand.
Yeah.
That's a very common in that part of the
world.
Yeah,
it really is because utensils just
aren't,
aren't that common.
And they really liked spaghetti so they
sort of wrap the spaghetti around your
fingers.
And I had done that as a free man,
you know,
I sort of sat with Somalis in and eight
that way.
But as a,
as a hostage,
I was in no mood to be that,
you know,
that friendly.
Yeah.
They,
they gave me a fork and I could eat my
on my own.
So how,
like what kind of physical state were
you in after two and a half years of
this?
Yeah,
it was pretty bad.
I was my,
um,
my immune system,
it started to fall apart.
So I don't go into detail too much about
this in the book,
but I had a staph infection and my skin
and some other kind of infection in my
ear and I was just something in my
lungs.
I was just not very,
I was sick,
um,
and I was sick constantly for several
months before I got out.
So I knew something had really changed
and I think the pirates were aware of
that too slowly.
I think that probably possibly
contributed to them lowering your ransom
possibly.
But,
but I,
you know,
not that they were sympathetic,
but uh,
it's possible they saw me sort of
reaching,
reaching my physical limit slowly.
Yeah.
Slowly.
So it's not a for.
It's actually can get you pretty quickly
now.
Yeah.
I mean they wound up just being that,
but it was raising boils on my skin and
they knew about that.
So
that's not that long ago.
Two thousand 12 to 2014 was when you
were,
when that was released and had the
infection.
I mean four years ago.
That's nothing.
Pushing four years now.
What is,
what does it feel like now to be free to
you?
Do you still have,
do,
have ptsd from it?
Do you get um,
well now I can be happy about it.
I think the day I was released I was
sort of,
I felt better in stages,
but w it wasn't sudden euphoria.
Um,
now I can be really be happy about it.
It took me about a year to get back to
full strength and the symptoms of Ptsd
that I showed when I first got out,
which included like hyper hyper
vigilance.
I'm went away slowly as I got physically
strong hypervigilance being like wake up
in the middle of the night.
Nightmares that will,
that nightmares only happened within the
first year.
I'm waking up in the middle of the
night.
That still happens.
I still don't sleep too well.
Hypervigilance,
I mean out in public,
too many people around,
you know,
like you hear with vets.
Um,
and I was aware of that as a symptom and
I felt at first when we were out in
public in Nairobi and I turned to the
FBI psychologist who was with me and I
said,
you know,
am I hypervigilant?
He said,
maybe.
Then I said,
are you here because you know,
I might have ptsd.
He said,
we don't like to put a label on
anything.
And that was his attitude towards me.
That was the attack he took.
And in my case at least it was right.
Eventually he said,
that's it.
Shouldn't I be treated for PTSD or
shouldn't I be going to regular talk
therapy or something like that.
And he said,
you know,
you don't want to pathologize anything.
In other words,
you don't want to create mentally
another condition for you,
for you to recover from,
you know,
it's enough work for your mind and your
body to recover quite naturally.
They know how to do it from the,
all that trauma.
That's very interesting because I've
heard people talk about that with other
things,
particularly with war,
that you're,
you're better off not deciding what you
have.
We're not being told what you have in my
case.
That's true.
I mean,
who knows?
I think ptsd can be so complicated.
They're,
you know,
the pharmaceutical solutions in that
kind of thing for some people,
the body of my know how to recover.
So you have to,
you have to let them.
Do they give you techniques to recover
is in instead of explaining or
discussing what the issue is,
do they give you techniques to feel
better or to,
to establish more normal existence?
I know I didn't.
I mean,
I didn't get a checklist,
but the psychologist would say,
you know,
if something's bothering you,
write it down.
Um,
but he knew I was a writer.
He,
they made sure they knew that I had a
loving family around me when I got back
and a great circle of friends in Berlin.
Uh,
that's really important.
Um,
I think everybody finds their own way.
I mean,
I knew I was weak.
I was just physical,
like a race,
you know,
when I got out,
how much weight did you lose?
I lost about 40 pounds.
And um,
when I,
when I first came out and walked around
in Berlin,
Berlin's a walking city,
so I tried to lead like normal day,
um,
my knees swelled up in my ankle,
swelled up and they were really painful.
So it was like I just played a game of
football or something.
You weren't moving while you were there?
Yeah,
not enough.
I did yoga,
but I didn't go for a jog around the
room or something like you sometimes
hear for prisoners.
And if I'd done that I think they would
have been social to startle the,
they would've shot me,
uh,
but
I was not in any kind of shape for,
for normal life when I got out.
And in fact one day when I got back from
Berlin,
I tried to run for a street car.
I just didn't have the musculature for
it.
I simply didn't have a stride to run.
I could not run well,
I thought that was really weird.
Um,
but one of the doctors who tested me
said,
well,
you have a protein deficiency.
And once I started to take care of that
and I went consciously to the gym and
made sure I got stronger and also put on
more muscle.
Um,
the mental things sort of took care of
themselves too.
So there's that body mind connection was
really important
and when they're telling you this,
that you have a protein deficiency that
you need,
you know,
you should exercise and take care of
your body.
And this is improving is,
are they giving you guidelines like this
is,
this is probably a good idea to try to
do this.
I mean,
are there,
are there any strategies that people
have to deal with coming out of long
term incarceration?
No,
not specific ones.
I think it was clear to everyone that I
was easily overwhelmed.
So,
um,
you know,
at one point my family sat down with me
with all the paperwork that had to be
taken care of and I could only deal with
that for like an hour at a time.
So,
and the debrief paperwork,
Oh,
I'm bank things to sign and that sort of
thing.
Um,
how so?
Well,
just let,
all my affairs were in somebody else's
hands when I was for the two and a half
years,
two and a half years.
And so we had to sort of rectify a lot
of that.
Um,
you know,
I couldn't plow through it and then an
afternoon or in a week I had to do it in
stages and it was the same thing with
like a debriefing with the FBI,
which I did for three weeks.
I couldn't always do it for the entire
day.
What would happen?
My brain would like to actually seize
up.
I mean I actually would just,
I got,
I mean you said earlier when I talk
about it,
I go like this.
My whole body would like constrict and I
would simply,
part of me would just shut down.
He,
you've,
you've leveled off now physically like
your shoulders,
but I'm looking at you right now from
our conversation.
Yeah.
But I don't feel
when you started talking about it,
your shoulders,
it seemed like started to almost visibly
rise up
probably.
Yeah.
But I'm saying when I first got out,
I must have been much more exact cause
paralytic.
No,
I mean I,
I just,
something inside me just shut down.
Yeah.
So it,
you're,
it just wouldn't,
you.
You just didn't have the capacity to sit
down and concentrate on anything.
It wasn't concentration.
It was a sense of overwhelm.
Yeah.
Well,
concentrating on too many things at
once.
I think it was also,
I was also overwhelmed by too many
friends,
you know,
too many people in the room because too
many social cues to read.
I didn't have that with the pirates.
It was real clear.
I was the hostage.
They were the guards in some sense we
were enemies and that was it.
And we had real simple things to say to
each other and that was it.
And that was my life for,
for a couple of years after the,
um,
after the ship,
it was not complex.
And so when I got out the complexities
of a more comfortable life,
but um,
you know,
more elaborate life were really
difficult.
You're obviously,
you were aware of the time that you were
struggling with this.
You were aware that it was difficult,
real clear,
but what were you confused by that
difficulty?
No,
not confused.
I wasn't sure how it was going to
recover,
but I,
I knew to take it slow and taking it
slow as important.
Now.
How did you ultimately recover the.
Yeah,
one,
one day at a time like that.
I mean I've consciously got better
physically.
I'm going to consciously did yoga and
went to,
went to the gym consciously eight.
Well My,
my um,
my doctor said don't follow a vegetarian
diet but eat a full diet and make sure
you get enough protein.
Why not have a vegetarian diet?
So you need protein,
but you,
you need a lot of protein,
animal protein specifically
now,
what is your situation now?
Is that you said you still,
you still have a hard time sleeping and
what is it a nightmare issue or is it an
anxiety issue?
No,
not nightmares,
but for some reason when it gets so in
Somalia,
when it came time to go to bed,
at least for a long period,
they would chain up my feet and I would
have to lie on a mattress under a
mosquito net.
And that was it for 12 hours.
So now when it comes time to sleep,
um,
instead of tired,
I get anxious and then it's possible
that I,
I might wake up,
you know,
fully awake after only four hours.
So I take Melatonin.
It's nothing,
it's nothing.
I don't take hard drugs to sleep,
but I take a little assistance.
Yeah.
Wow.
Now this book that you wrote of the
desert in the sea,
how,
how difficult was it to sit down in
front of a computer and sort of
recapture these thoughts
and transcribe them?
Yeah,
they're well.
So that was also sort of blood and
sweat.
The research was blood,
sweat and tears.
And so it was the writing.
But um,
I did know at least this the facts of
the story.
So I put those down first and then we
went back and did how it felt.
So the putting everything down,
which a writer likes to do,
you know,
all at once in one sort of great active
creation,
um,
that,
that would have been a little
overwhelming.
So I did it in layers and that was the
way to go.
What were you like before this and what
do you like now and what's different?
I think my,
my basic self is the same,
but I,
I,
I'm more patient.
Um,
I'm more grateful.
So just getting out alive,
um,
made me certainly grateful to be around.
It was great to see my family and
friends again and if I ever start to
feel ungrateful for something,
I have this well of memory that can go
back to um,
that's essential.
And I think in Somalia I also learned to
forgive,
which was,
you know,
not an easy process and it's something,
but I think it's something very
essential.
How so how'd you learn to forgive?
Um,
so we talked about picking up a
Kalashnikov.
I was going to do that.
I thought about doing that and it was an
internal debate for really long time
until one point where I'm actually heard
something on the radio from the pope,
the new pope I'd never even seen before,
and he gave a very good homily about
what forgiveness meant and that
resonated and at some point I made a
conscious decision to forgive the guards
who were around me,
you know,
these are the lowest lowest ranking
guys,
but they were making my life miserable
and I made a conscious decision to
forgive them and I had to do that over
and over and that made my mind a whole
lot more,
more stable and suddenly settled,
which means that unless I had done that,
I probably would have picked up a gun
and killed myself,
if not them or both.
That's fascinating that a speech by the
pope could resonate so strongly with you
while you were in captivity.
Just forgiveness.
Forgiveness wouldn't have had to be by
the pope,
but he.
He was pretty good.
That's something that people play,
pay lip service to and you know,
you hear people saying you should live a
life of forgiveness.
And it's healthier for you,
but no one can really understand that
the way you have.
For me it was life and death.
Wow,
man.
I mean,
I can't wait to read your book.
It is a crazy story.
You're doesn't mean.
It's just such an insane experience.
Was that your,
your just your well,
of experiences like what you can draw
upon is so different from most people
that you're interacting with you.
It must almost feel like you're going
through life interacting with privileged
children sometimes,
but the.
So first of all,
which is very happy to be back in.
Yeah.
In the world I grew up in.
So that's the main thing.
Um,
but yeah,
that comes up.
Sometimes you don't.
When people complain about things,
for example,
oh,
it's so fucking Horny,
right?
Yeah.
You should try hot in Somalia prison
where you're shackled to a bed.
Right?
Exactly.
Yeah.
We're idiots and traffic.
I'm a much more patient drive and so is
my mother by the way.
Oh,
I'm sure.
And so happy to get her son,
but right.
Yeah.
She's the heroine of the story.
I mean she really,
she really took.
Oh,
the
enormous amount.
So is it like to see her after two
years?
It was incredible.
No,
I mean it was obviously she was on my
mind and all my friends and family were
on my mind while I was in Somalia and
just to see somebody that I'd been
thinking about all this time and it's
sort of hypothetical way,
um,
again in real life and the way that I
really thought I wouldn't was
overwhelming.
It was really,
really fantastic.
Now had you gone to dangerous places for
journalism before Somalia?
Where did you go on?
Uh,
so for my second book,
sweeten some.
I surfed in Gaza.
Wow.
Um,
and I'd been to northern Iraq and some
other places,
but this was easily the most dangerous
thing you do in Gaza.
Uh,
W I went to see the Gaza Surf Club and I
actually went surfing with them.
The Gaza Surf Club.
This exists.
Yeah.
What is that?
Um,
so it's a group of Palestinians who
liked to surf but who don't have enough
surfboards.
And uh,
so they organized into a club first to
share a couple of surf boards that they
had found.
And managed to manage to buy,
um,
and also to receive donations from a
group of surfers and Tel Aviv who
thought these guys should have boards.
And so there's a relationship.
Grew up between a group in Tel Aviv
called surfing for peace and the Gaza
Surf Club.
So Jews in Tel Aviv or donating
surfboards to Palestinians.
Wow.
It's completely wonderful.
It's a grassroots peace initiative,
you know,
it's been going on for years now,
but I'm one of the eloquent things that
the leader of,
um,
the,
the surfing for pease group said was
we're not getting anywhere on an
official level so we better do something
on sort of a grassroots level.
I think it's marvelous.
Wow.
Um,
what do you do now?
Oh,
I.
So seeking out danger was never the
point.
You know,
I tried not to shrink from it,
but that was not,
you know,
I'm not a thrill seeker and that's not
the what I'm trying to base my career on
or anything like that.
Um,
right now I'm writing a novel,
so that should keep me seated for.
What's it about a two bedrooms,
drones.
That doesn't sound peaceful.
It's not what I'm not gonna say anymore
about it.
Yeah,
I get it.
Um,
do you ever anticipate yourself
traveling for journals and began?
Oh,
travel.
Yeah.
But just nothing like this.
No,
I don't need to do dangerous travel
anytime soon.
No,
no.
Yeah.
Some people just want to jump right back
into the fire.
Yeah,
that's not.
But that was not the point in the first
place.
Right.
What was the point like?
What did you hope to get out of this
trip to Somalia?
Well,
so when,
one thing that I noticed while I was
watching the trial and,
um,
in,
in Hamburg was this clash between a
modern liberal state,
which is what Germany is.
And so it was America by the way.
Um,
and in our case at crime and Germany in
fact is newer than the United States in
the sense that its constitution was
written in 1949 when nobody was thinking
about piracy.
So the laws against piracy or extremely
lenient in,
in German law in a way that they're not
in Spanish or American law,
um,
we have laws that date back to when it
was a capital crime
and basically the Germans didn't know
how to deal with these guys and uh,
I thought it was fascinating in the
first place that this ancient crime had
revived after a couple of centuries of
relative quiet,
you know,
and um,
so that tension on its own was
interesting and that was worth a book
because nobody was quite approaching it
that way,
you know?
Uh,
so that tension is still interesting and
that tension is still alive.
So there's certainly threats to modern
liberal states going on around the
world.
So what were the trials in Berlin?
Uh,
there was a trial in Hamburg and I was
going back and forth from Berlin.
It was 10 guys from Somalia who I tried
to hijack a cargo ship that belonged to
a,
um,
a German ship ship company that was
based in Hamburg A.
I think they were overpowered by the
Dutch navy,
but the Dutch handed him over to the
Germans.
In fact the Dutch said,
okay,
we'll do this as long as we don't have
to try them because everyone knew from
the outset that there was going to be a
problem.
Uh,
trying Somalis will.
In what way?
Um,
in Europe in general,
but especially in Germany,
I think there's a actually a law against
shipping them back to Somalia because
it's considered not a safe place.
Um,
for them,
even for them.
And I think that's nuts.
Once they were convicted,
I think they should have been deported
after they served their time.
That's so bizarre.
But,
but if they were shipped back to
Somalia,
how would they be treated?
Like what is the government like in
Somalia?
And good question sanely corrupt.
I asked some of my parents about that.
It is corrupt.
It's a,
it's either corrupt or nonexistent.
So the,
the government is Somalia are focused
around Mogadishu and it just doesn't
have that much power in the provinces.
And I was in one of the,
one of the provinces and because the
provinces don't get a whole lot of money
from Mogadishu so that they run their
own businesses,
wins in some cases,
piracy.
Um,
I asked one of my guards what would
happen if a pirate went and got thrown
into jail and some of the country and
then came back and tried to,
you know,
set up friendships again with his old
pirate buddies or whatever,
you know.
Would he be killed?
Who would he be in,
in dangerous?
No,
no,
no problem.
Probably what you were back in.
No problem.
Yeah.
I mean,
is there any sort of punishment for,
for them when they get back to Somalia?
Was there any penal system or a
potentially there is.
Yeah.
So they're not considered a crime?
There are.
Yes,
it is.
So there,
there are laws on the books,
especially in the regions and even
prisons for pirates.
Um,
the problem is that clan relationships
are a lot more important than newly
written laws.
Um,
and so even prior to go to jail,
this was true about one boss.
In my case,
I'm might cut out again.
So this guy,
this guy who was a pirate Boston,
my case wound up in jail while I was
still captive for one month in Mogadishu
and wound up walking.
Wow.
Yeah.
And he was captive for piracy I think
for having weapons that the government
didn't expect to see in one of his
houses.
So a is something off to the side,
but it's this really sketchy system of
bartering and payoffs and let's.
Oh,
you know,
and who you're related to.
And the,
there are other prisons for,
you know,
low ranking pirates and Puntland and
also in Galkayo where I was,
um,
it's a crap shoot.
How much time those guys are going to
spend in jail.
And what happened with the people in
Germany.
They got a total of seven years I think,
or an average in Germany,
in Germany.
And then what happened when they were
released?
Nothing.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's a whole separate story,
which I haven't even started.
Started to address,
but as it turned out,
a few of them went back to Somalia.
Anyway.
It probably went right back into the
business a well or something else.
No illicit or profitable or whatever.
Yeah.
And there's a wide variety of people
that they target.
They target people and individual
crafts.
The target large boats,
commercial vessels.
Yep.
They,
they did all of that.
I mean,
in fact,
I met hostages from all of those from
the whole range.
So somebody hostage.
Did you meet over the two years and
eight months?
A total of 30.
So the,
the crew on the fishing ship,
the tune of vessel was 28.
And then I met [inaudible] fishermen,
the two guys from the Seychelles.
We're small time.
So they weren't just on a small craft.
Would it say shells in the Seychelles is
a chain of islands off Africa.
It's a country that belongs to Africa.
Um,
but it has a French name.
the,
the guys on the tune of vessel,
I'm more from a,
you know,
relatively big ship.
The guys from the Seychelles,
we're from a small private craft.
And I was an example of someone captured
on land and these people that were from
the small private craft,
who were they trying to get money from?
Just anyone who knows them.
Is that how they do this?
Whoever,
anybody.
They,
of course they asked from the
government,
but the government doesn't always pay
the given government.
Yeah.
Just,
it
just.
The whole system seems so insane that
they've got,
I mean,
the key people for years and years,
but they have just a whole collection of
them and they're trying to extract money
from people that know them.
Yeah.
Uh,
as it turns out,
they're not very good at it.
So pirates are in the kidnapping
business,
but they don't always know what they're
doing.
Um,
the,
the bosses I think got used to.
I'm demanding a lot of money from
shipping companies and finding out that
if you hold a ship stubbornly for a long
time,
uh,
you got a lot of money from the
insurance company or whatever.
Um,
I,
that,
that calculation doesn't work with human
beings.
So in other words,
everyone else on earth who,
who for a human being expects of the
person's price to go down as the time,
you know,
wears on and it took a while for parents
to understand that.
Wow.
What is it,
I mean,
when you're dealing,
you're dealing with all this,
like what,
what is it like on your psyche when
you're getting two years in two and a
half years in and you,
you,
you have some sort of light at the end
of the tunnel.
What is it?
What does it feel like?
Well,
I didn't know there was light at the end
of the tunnel,
so I'm two years in.
That's where,
um,
you know,
it was either forgive the guards or,
or self destruct.
It was also by then I had also
deliberately given let go of having any
kind of hope so that,
that was the second survival strategy I
had to.
I'm not hope that I was going to get
out,
uh,
because hoping was,
had a downside,
that cycle of hope and despair was
extremely damaging my mental wellbeing.
So the after going through that cycle a
few times,
I'm like,
I have to find a different way.
One of the things that I've gotten out
of travel is I think it is your view of
the world changes.
When you see the way people are living
in different places you use your
spectrum expands.
You start recognizing like,
oh,
I might be used to southern California,
but this is not how they do things in
Ohio.
This is not how they do things in Italy.
This is not.
When you go as far as being a captive in
Somalia,
your your spectrum is massive.
I mean your view of the world being
entrenched in that life and being with
those people while they're chewing this
narcotic and carrying around coalition
of coughs and yelling at each other in a
foreign language and watching fistfights
and realizing like they don't have
anything either.
What,
how much has that changed you as a human
being and your,
your view of human life on earth?
Well,
I think enormously.
I mean I,
you're right,
it expanded my range and my,
my understanding of,
of what other people think.
They obviously come from a completely
different perspective and Somalia,
not only are they Muslim and African,
but they're also very isolated.
So Somalia as a,
as a rule has always been difficult to
penetrate for outsiders.
That was true when Richard Burton was
there in the 19th century to um,
it's,
it's a closed culture and um,
they have their own way of thinking and
also the also the language is not
related to most other languages you've
heard,
unless you,
you're familiar with languages in
Ethiopia.
Did you learn any of it?
Yeah,
a little bit.
But,
um,
I resisted learning it from the guards.
I,
when I was there,
I thought about it like,
um,
in,
in Berlin you realize that a lot of east
Germans when during the communist era
were taught Russian in school and a lot
of them hated it and I was not in a mood
to learn Somalia Somali once I was a
captive.
So,
um,
it was similar to that.
I,
uh,
I learned a few words,
but I never had a good teacher.
And of course when I was a journalist I
was relying on translators.
I would imagine that as a writer that
spectrum,
the expansion of the spectrum,
although there's no way you would ever
barter it off or bargain to have those
experiences to broaden your spectrum it,
it has to have changed the way you put
pen to paper and view the world and
your,
your ability to describe things.
Yeah,
I think you,
you realize that each individual has
certain certain boundaries,
you know,
and certain certain self definitions and
those self definitions can be
the,
the distance between one individual and
another can be enormous,
but in some sense also they're
superficial distinctions,
so yeah,
but
they're inescapable.
Reality is so alien in comparison to
someone who lives in Bel Air.
Oh,
absolutely.
Just this,
this,
just that contrast between this world
that you were so deeply entrenched in
for two in two years and eight months
like that has got to change the way you
look at human life.
Yeah.
Because the Gulf and wealth is so
enormous.
I mean,
they can't imagine that the amount of
money it takes to live in Bel Air and,
and the other way around.
I mean,
I think it's very difficult for someone
in California to imagine how little you
can get by on and how close to the
earth.
Some most people on the planet live
either.
There's a statistic
that I read once that I repeat all the
time because it still baffles me that if
you make more than $34,000 a year,
you're in the one percent of the world
of the world.
Yeah.
Possibly.
And that is probably magnified manyfold
in Ethiopia.
Yeah.
In Ethiopia and Somalia.
I mean it's,
it's very,
um,
you know,
in some ways,
although they want money all the time,
especially if they're criminals.
Um,
the,
the money that we're used to sort of
greasing our path through life around
here is just not available.
It's just not,
not part of the reality.
What do they do with money when they get
it?
Well,
it depends if,
if they're pirates,
they splash out on fancy car or fancy
cars.
Oh yeah,
no,
I was placed in fancy cars.
I mean,
really?
Yeah.
No,
pirates had great cell phones,
um,
expensive suv,
weapons that they had bought,
you know,
from abroad and maybe a weapons bizarre
Mogadishu or something like that.
Uh,
but that's not cheap either.
A,
they,
they bragged about how the,
the bullets cost like a dollar each one
of them,
I might've been wearing a band of 500
bullets.
Um,
and the cut is expensive,
so lots of things costs an enormous
amount of money in Somalia.
But if you're,
you know,
if you're a very ordinary Somali,
Somali,
you're getting by on less than a dollar
a day.
So there's the ordinary Somalis who are
not criminals or not pirates at least.
And then you asked the majority,
the majority,
and then you have these pirates that are
essentially
running through the streets and Mercedes
Benz,
they're like gangsters.
They're like gangsters.
And that's,
that's actually how one Somali,
who had some connection to Germany,
I'm described them to me,
you know,
he,
he was wandering around and got kyle
because it was his hometown in some way
or his ancestral ancestral town.
And he had met some.
This was before I got captured.
It was like they were,
you know,
they had wrapped them being from the
SUV.
Did they really?
American rap.
Who knows,
who knows?
There's lots of actually good African
rap.
Really?
Oh yeah.
Senegalese Rep.
have you ever ever heard west African
rap?
Because I love music that I don't
understand the words too.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I can send you some band names.
Please do.
Yeah.
Although when I write,
I like to listen to the stinky things
that don't understand because I can
still write and not think about their
words.
Right?
Yeah,
exactly.
When you're around these gangsters and
you do,
you get this sense of like,
Oh God,
like they,
this is,
they need this money like this.
They want to keep this going.
They're going to need more money funnel.
This is just a never ending cycle.
That's,
that's obviously how it seemed.
Yeah.
I'm the.
And that's true.
I think some of the guards,
some of the lower ranking and maybe some
of the gentler guards,
the ones who got along with me,
um,
did not necessarily want to be gangsters
for the rest of their lives.
So I think for some people the plan was
get a bunch of money and get out,
you know,
but um,
as a,
as an operation,
yeah,
it just needed,
there was no limit to the money they
needed or wanted.
And so.
So in the end the real motivation is not
illegal fishing,
but greed.
And do they have any sort of.
It initially started with illegal
fishing though,
right?
Yeah,
absolutely.
No.
Do they have any sort of ultimate goal?
Like one day I'm going to retire,
I'm going to have a mansion in the
hills.
Yeah.
So I think individually they do and some
bosses get a mansion and a big compound
and live large and then they,
they try and hire younger,
younger pirates and that of thing.
And the thing about piracy and also
terrorism.
So Al Shabaab is the Al Qaeda aligned
group in Somalia.
Uh,
Al Shabaab and pirates are the two main
corporate structures in Somalia.
So in other words,
if you're a young man and you know how
to use a gun,
those are the places you join up with.
If you want to be upwardly mobile,
if you want to impress somebody and get
promotions and make money and,
and marry a wife,
those were the most available options.
Otherwise,
you know,
you had scarce jobs.
Maybe some frustrating sheep herding or,
or fishing.
I'm a more interesting jobs in the
cities but not very many.
And then maybe a pretty well paid you
end job,
you know,
if you're lucky.
So that these things are very tempting
for young,
young Somalis and even if the pirate
bosses are no longer capturing ships on
the water,
it's fallen off quite a bit in the last
few years.
They've still got other businesses going
on,
including,
like I said,
human smuggling and gun smuggling.
Does anybody have aspirations to get
out?
Did you,
did you run into anybody that
understands that the rest of the world,
like there are opportunities to live in
a place where you don't have this kind
of systemic violence and crime?
Yes,
definitely.
I mean,
I think,
um,
they don't necessarily understand the
rest of the world very well,
but they know that somebody is in
trouble.
And so a lot of people wanted to get out
and some of the guards to talk to me
about wanting to go to Europe,
but one of them who did,
and I described him in the book,
he wound up getting married in
Mogadishu.
I found it so I,
you know,
I wound up with a wedding photograph
from him.
Wow.
So he ended up not going,
which was smart.
Didn't touch with them,
not exactly.
One guy
found me on facebook.
And of course Jesus Christ.
One of your captors,
one of the guards know that one of the
gentler guys,
one of the guys,
like when you get a message on facebook
from someone who held a gun to you.
At first I didn't want to answer him,
but slowly I realized that I could get
good information from him on facebook.
We're not friends.
I mean I've explained this before,
but we're not.
We didn't become,
I don't let him into my life on
facebook,
but no,
we messaged each other.
It's okay.
You set limits.
Sorry.
Still do you.
When you said that you,
you had forgiveness,
that was very important.
Do you.
Did you express that to him?
Um,
yes,
at least in my tone.
I mean he's,
he was one of the easiest people to
forgive.
He,
he was,
he was never obnoxious or,
or violent towards me.
I mean,
except for belonging to this violent,
violent gang.
I think he was personally never,
um,
you know,
as obnoxious as some of the other guards
could be.
Did you try
to communicate to him that the rest of
the world is different?
Did you try to communicate to him what
it's like where,
where you grew up and then your
experience as a human being is so wildly
different?
No,
it is not.
That wasn't,
that wasn't our topic of conversation.
Did you ever think of introducing that?
I got some of that information from him,
let's put it that way.
He told me a little bit about his
background and it was military as a
matter of fact,
which I think is typical.
So in other words,
a lot of them are trained gunman.
Um,
I,
I wasn't anxious to share a lot of
information with them,
but you know,
if he reads my book,
he'll learn.
It is a lot of personal background in
the book.
Wow.
It's,
it's so hard to even imagine.
You know,
there's some people that tell you things
and you're like,
oh,
I can kind of imagine that,
but your story is so fucked up.
It's almost impossible to even imagine
so unique in that you grew up in this
incredibly western world,
this,
you know,
first world,
you're in Germany and then you go to
Somalia and get captured and stay there
and alters your reality.
Yeah,
it did.
It really did.
And it was,
it's a lot more fucked up than I
expected to be.
In other words,
I didn't,
you know,
I wouldn't have wished for this.
I wouldn't have wished for this on my
family either.
I couldn't imagine.
Yeah.
Do you think about Somalia?
Do you think about what,
what it must be like to be a person
that's stuck there that lives there?
Oh,
I had plenty of opportunity to think
about that,
you know?
And that's,
that was obviously behind what,
what my guards were doing.
Um,
so that was on my mind quite a lot and
that's,
that's where he realized that actually
most of the world lives quite poor.
The Somalia is one of the poorest
countries,
so it's even under the average line for
the,
for the rest of the world.
But I'm,
no,
it's clear that
most of the world doesn't live like,
like we do in the West.
What was a day like?
They're like,
what did you typically do other than be
shackled to sleep and.
Yeah,
well it depended where I was if I was on
the ship then there was a,
um,
we slept,
I slept in the cabin along with 10 other
hostages and then we came out to the
deck in the morning and heck,
instant coffee and something for
breakfast.
And uh,
the food was not bad because it was
still an operating fishing vessel and we
got piles of rice and basically Chinese
food from the kitchen as long as
supplies lasted,
you know,
uh,
once I was on land and then I just woke
up alone under a mosquito tent and
wondered what to do that day,
you know,
I had to live in my head quite a bit if
I didn't have paper and pen to write
with,
um,
which I didn't for at least a year and
a,
I had to sort of right in my head.
I mean,
I,
I actually composed paragraphs in my
head and went through them and memorize
them.
And eventually I had a two hour routine
in the morning where I just lay,
lay still and went through these words
in my head.
That was one way to keep saying.
So you remembered the individual
paragraphs and you put them in an order.
I was revising books in my head.
So I would go through and say,
okay,
this needs work,
you know,
might as well get to it.
And then I would compose a paragraph,
refine it,
memorize it all in my head,
you know,
I have friends that do comedy that way.
They don't really write only right in
their head,
but they still call it writing.
And uh,
I found that interesting.
They said,
well,
this is the best way for me to
constantly remember it.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
I mean that's what I had to do.
Commit it to memory.
And so you sat down there and when you
were going over the material,
this was a purposeful strategy in order
to keep your sanity,
give herself some,
some order and keep my mind occupied and
when I and I would memorize that.
And then I also had like a list of names
from the ship to memorize.
So I had written all their names down
with the proper spellings.
Right.
I was still optimistic when I,
when I was on the ship.
Uh,
and so I,
I had an incredibly complex list of
names from the crewman,
um,
which I lost and so lost them.
I lost the list between the ship and
land.
So remembering their names became part
of my morning routine to,
and this is obviously phonetic,
right?
Because you're dealing with Asian
language.
I had learned to spell them though A.
Luckily when I got out I got a list of
the women's names from the FBI.
Wow.
Yeah.
Um,
when did this book come out?
Uh,
it just came out last week and uh,
um,
it's been a few years in the making.
Is it difficult to do conversations like
this?
No.
Like I said,
it's,
it's easier now that I've written it,
so I'm fluent with this material now,
but when I first got out I wouldn't have
been able to talk about it like this.
I would have,
I would've just bumped up.
I wouldn't have known where to start.
What do you anticipate doing once this
is,
once the dust settled and this is,
you know,
for firmly established and you're done
with the promos?
Uh,
well I'm,
I'm working on a new book.
So,
um,
you know,
the novel moving onto the drone on the
novel and I'm following the story,
a couple of stories in the meantime to
some,
some journalism and I worked for hostage
us at the moment too,
which is a good nonprofit that supports
families
that might have somebody in captivity
somewhere and the US government as it
turns out helps families in,
in really good ways,
um,
but in the ways that they can't,
uh,
in terms of just letting the families
know what you know,
what to expect and what might be going
on with her.
There are people,
a hostage us can step in and help.
I think your story is really important
and I think it's not just important in
terms of like your,
the,
the fact that you've had an incredibly
deep view of what it's like to live
there,
but that you,
you've got your life back.
Yeah.
And in,
in this experience of no hope and sorrow
and captivity and all the various
struggles that you went through,
you've experienced something that just
very,
very few human beings,
even in the 7 billion people on this
planet and all their struggles and
trials and tribulations,
there's what,
what small handful have been held
captive by Somali pirates and then
managed to live
well there's a network of former
captives and that's what hostage us is
about.
But you know,
how many people have been held captive,
owe more than you realize.
But there were several of us are still
alive and so it's the best people for me
to talk to when I first got out was
other people who've been captive David
road who was held hostage by the Taliban
when he was working for the New York
Times,
was also on the board of the Pulitzer
Center when I got captured.
So he followed my story.
Talking to him after I got out was
fantastic.
It was better than a psychologist and I
was aware of.
He escaped,
you know,
so I was aware of his story when I was
there.
So we were thinking about each other in
a way,
you know,
and we're friends now.
It's great talking to someone who's been
through it is psychologically the best
thing
now.
What are the numbers in terms of how
many people who've been held captive by
the Somalis?
Oh,
biosimilars
currently?
Yeah.
It's down to about four radian
fishermen.
That's it.
And then a couple of who were actually
captured by pirates and then a couple
of,
um,
Kenyon too I think were handed over to a
pirate game.
Um,
so it's much reduced,
you know,
and in fact,
in the home,
three crew when they got out was the
last big crew that was being held by
pirates.
They got out in 2016.
So the pirate era,
you might say is sort of tapering off.
Uh,
but why is that?
Oh,
because I'm white.
So it was while I was there,
pirate stopped being so active on the
water and I slowly gleaned that from,
um,
from the BBC or whatever I was listening
to and I'm like,
fuck,
I came here and write a story about
pirates.
And now it's not even a story.
You've become this,
I became the story,
it was not good,
um,
but it fell off in 2013,
maybe even a little earlier,
late 2012,
partly because the boss has shifted
their focus to other businesses and they
found it less profitable to hold people
have probably also because of my case.
I'm in my,
my case wasn't moving along and um,
but mainly because,
and this is,
this still has to be true to keep piracy
down.
Cargo ships sail now with,
with our teams,
you know,
contractors.
Um,
and it turns out a spatter of gunfire in
the water can keep a skift from coming
on.
Um,
that's enough and it should be enough.
And that,
that's really the main,
the main defense,
the naval teams that still cruise off
Somalia,
there is the,
it's a very important formality,
but I don't think they practically stop
individual cases the way in our team
does.
And there was a lot of fear about that
beforehand.
A lot of fear about putting weapons on a
civilian cargo ship or a merchant ship.
Somebody,
a few people thought there would be like
an arms race in the water and then,
you know,
pirates would come on with heavier
weapons or whatever.
It turns out not to be the case.
Now,
what did the bosses shift their
attention to?
Um,
like I said,
probably some human smuggling drugs and
weapons smuggling,
you know,
they have,
they have portfolios,
they have other businesses and they just
roll it over into something else if,
if piracy becomes too difficult.
And that's what the precautions that the
shipping industry now takes,
um,
are,
have been enough to make it too
difficult for the bosses.
Did you take any consideration or do you
anticipate in any way a cure for what
ails them?
Yeah,
in fact,
that was another idea that sent me
there.
I wanted to investigate the possibility
of,
of just joining a legitimate business in
Somalia because America went through the
same cycle three,
300 years ago.
You know,
we had pirates when we're colonials.
We had pirates,
very savage ones who sailed from the
eastern seaboard out to Africa actually
out to the Horn of Africa.
And they were very brutal to Muslims,
so it was reversed and um,
we recovered from it by becoming a
country and becoming responsible for our
own economy.
Um,
you know,
what's going on in Somalia now it's a
lot of illicit business activity,
but as business activity,
you turn it into something listed and
give people jobs.
They're not going to be pirates anymore.
Um,
and there,
there are ways to do that and I think
slowly people who have power in Somalia
or figuring that out,
but um,
it's still a lot of criminals that have
too much power in Somalia.
Michael,
I didn't want to touch a book until I
met you wanted to.
I wanted to somehow or another have a
fresh conversation and get your
perspective on this.
But I think your,
your view of the world is very valuable
and it's just very,
very different.
And I'm so happy that you got out and so
happy.
I'm so happy he wrote this book and I
can't wait to check it out.
It's available now.
The desert and the sea.
And just thank you.
Thank you for being here.
Really,
really appreciate it.
Thanks for having me on.