Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
And we're live a welcome aboard.
Jessica Rosenworcel.
Did I do it?
You did.
I was so nervous about that.
And Eddie won,
of course,
has been on the podcast many times.
Number one podcast in the world.
Oh,
thank you.
You are.
What's up brother?
How are you?
I'm chilling man.
I'm good.
I just,
you know,
I wanted to introduce you to the Homie,
the commissioner from the FCC,
Jessica Rosenworcel because things,
things where things are bad for the
Internet right now.
Well you are very concerned and a lot of
people are about net neutrality and uh,
we all have some questions about it and
we're excited to talk to you about it.
So maybe we could eliminate some of the
issues and,
and give us a,
an understanding or try to help us
understand what's at stake here and why
are people so concerned?
Well,
I think people are concerned because the
future of the Internet.
So the future of everything.
I mean,
every aspect of our lives is now touched
by that connectivity and it's a funny
thing,
but the agency where I work in
Washington,
the Federal Communications Commission
has enormous power and control over our
internet experience and for decades
we've had these policies that have been
all about Internet openness and what
that means is you can go where you want,
do what you want online and your
broadband provider can't get in the way
or prevent you from looking at some
websites are looking at some videos or
setting up some businesses,
but that changed last month in
Washington when the FCC over my
objections voted to end net neutrality
and as a result,
all of our broadband providers now have
the legal right to block websites,
to throttle content,
and to set up sweetheart paid for
prioritization deals and over the long
haul.
That could really change the Internet
and the web as we know it.
Now.
What are the arguments?
Pro Net neutrality?
I'm one of the arguments for people that
were excited about this being signed
when they were saying that net
neutrality was really only over the last
couple of years and before the last
couple of years,
net neutrality as we know it the last
everything was fine and that it'll
continue to be fine and that people are
just panicked and there was that really
bizarre video that that one dude made
where he was sharing that these are all
the things you're going to be able to
do.
You work with that cat.
I do a pie.
Yeah.
He seems like an odd fellow.
Well,
uh,
he's a,
he's a smart guy.
He's a seasoned lawyer.
I think it's fair to say he and I see
the world a little bit
differently.
Yeah.
So he doesn't,
he sees this through the eyes of big
business,
right?
He thinks that this is a free market,
let the market decide and um,
and that's what the argument.
I mean,
I've even heard mark Cuban was
arguing against it,
so I was like,
wow,
this is stunning.
Yeah.
Noodle.
For me,
the net neutrality thing is huge because
when I was in law school,
I read this one book called fighting for
air and it documented like the
telecommunications act in [inaudible]
97.
It's like boring stuff,
right?
Don't go read the Telecommunications Act
in [inaudible] 97,
but like radio mattered to me.
Remember like growing up with the radio,
like I remember they would actually
break records on the radio back in the
day,
like funk flux still does it on hot 97
and he'll break records.
He broke my boy old drew's record the
other day,
but like recently it's like clear
channel Iheartradio.
They own all the radio stations and it
really sterilized content and they play
the same songs every hour in every city
almost around the world.
And I.
When I read that book and I went to law
school,
I realized I was like,
Yo,
it was because of the deregulation of
radio that allowed for all these local
independent radio stations in every city
that we're wrapping local culture and
state culture.
That kind of eroded that means of
communication.
And I was like,
this happens to every single industry we
have,
whether it's radio,
television,
but now it's coming for the Internet and
by deregulating it you're gonna gut it
again.
And you know,
like when,
when technology started popping in,
podcast came around.
I mean that's what enabled jre and
that's why my first place to goes like
I'm a come see jail because you were one
of the innovators with this new
technology.
Well
thanks.
But I think what people are super
concerned about is things getting
blocked,
right?
That's like one of the first ones.
Is that something that we legitimately
have to worry,
I worry about?
Is it?
Good question.
Here's what I know right now.
Your broadband provider has the
technical ability to block content and
websites.
It's got the business incentive to block
or slow access to some websites if they
don't have a special commercial
relationship with them.
So now the FCC just gave them the legal
green.
Right?
Just go ahead.
And so I feel over time this is
something we need to be concerned about.
And so this open platform that was full
of independent,
independent voices,
now you've got this new gatekeeper,
your broadband provider,
they've got a lot more power than what
they used to.
How close was the vote?
It was three.
Two.
And what's the argument for this?
Well,
that's,
that's fair.
Um,
I think there's an argument that you
want government out of the way
deregulation is going to lead to more
competition and we'll have a flourishing
of new ideas and content if we just
moved government out of the way.
And even if you're sympathetic to that
argument,
here's where I think it breaks down
according to the FCC,
his own data,
half of the households this country
don't have a choice of broadband
provider.
I am familiar with this.
I'm one of them,
only have one provider that serves my
house.
So the thing is,
if you're a broadband provider started
blocking your content or throttling your
access to some video in a competitive
market,
you'd pick up,
you take your business somewhere else.
But about half of our households don't
even have that opportunity.
So to me,
the idea that the competitive market
will prevent this behavior just doesn't
fly.
Yeah.
That doesn't seem to make sense.
And that that's an issue in my
neighborhood as well.
And a lot of other people I know as
well.
I mean,
I think they make deals where only one
company,
whether it's verizon or whatever,
has an area.
Yeah.
They monopolize the areas.
They limit the opportunities and choices
and when they say deregulation,
it just anytime they deregulate things
and say,
hey,
we're going to leave it to the market
and have competition,
I think it's impossible to have that
when you have a country with such an
inequality,
income inequality gap.
Right.
That's the problem is that all right,
let's all go compete Joe.
You're not going to start a verizon.
I'm not going to start a verizon.
You know what I mean?
Like we can't compete with these dudes
and even comcast can't even compete with
verizon.
Like you know,
these dudes were all getting smashed.
So there is not actual competition.
I think deregulation works when you have
multiple players and options and that
the market actually can come into play.
But with the economy,
so top heavy right now,
I don't think there is a possibility of
company.
Yeah,
I mean listen,
competition is the best regulator we
know,
right?
We want there to be these markets where
consumers have lots and lots of choices.
But if competition is an existing,
you need a little oversight to make sure
that every consumer gets a fair shot.
Well,
it seems like that's where the real
argument lies,
that if there are monopolies and there
seemed to be in certain areas with in
regards to what kind of Internet access
you can get,
that if you don't have regulation,
then then what is going to protect the
consumer and what is going to protect
free speech.
What's going to protect it?
Say if you are on verizon and your
system is on verizon,
what have you decided to make a podcast
that criticizes verizon and everybody
says,
you know,
hey,
Eddie [inaudible] got a podcast
criticizing us.
I want to shut that down.
And they can just.
I would have been shut down a long time
ago.
Yeah.
We're not saying that they would do
that,
but they could.
Yeah.
And that's what's scary,
that's not good,
you know,
so much of our speech these days,
it doesn't take place in public places.
It takes place on these private
platforms.
So they have a lot of power and we have
to think about that as a,
as a country in a democracy,
how much openness do we want?
And then how do we create a framework in
Washington that supports that openness.
And that's really to me what net
neutrality is.
The other question I have is right,
let's say I'm the,
you know,
versus let's say a service provider Buys
Hulu,
right?
Or,
or they buy or they create their own
streaming platform called Zulu,
right?
So they start Zulu,
they could start to charge netflix more
money for using their service.
They could charge more money,
they could charge,
you know,
beats more money,
whatever,
so that they have an advantage for their
own streaming services in,
in that,
that way they can culturally control
content.
And you know,
you're so right.
And what happens is you as a consumer,
you just get online and you might not
even notice,
right?
You might not even notice they're taking
you to the video content that they have
a special pay for relationship with.
I think though the biggest harm is to
entrepreneurship.
Yeah,
that's right.
Now,
look,
you have a good idea.
You got a business,
a service.
You can go online and you can almost
instantly have global reach.
That's amazing,
but now you're going to have to figure
out is your broadband provider instead
going to shuffle off all your traffic to
someone else who's paying them on the
side?
Are you going to have a fair shot to
show your wares and your ideas to the
world?
It's harder because I start thinking
like a bad one percenter,
dude,
and I'm like,
all right,
if there's no net neutrality and I'm the
only person that can service Calabasas,
California,
Woodland Hills,
well I'm going to charge all the other
streaming providers more money to use
this and I'm going to create a
competitor and every single one of these
sectors so you can have an advantage.
If you have your show with me and if
you're on the other one,
I'm going to disadvantage you.
I'm going to tax you basically.
So right now these are concerns and
there's nothing that's actually
happening yet.
Is this.
This ruling was just passed.
That's right.
Are there any plans in place for things
that we should be concerned with and is
there anything that we can do about this
current ruling?
Yes,
there's loads because I'm not giving up
and the fight for net neutrality and I
don't want you to either.
We got a few different pathways ahead.
First in Congress right now,
they are trying to get rid of what just
happened at the FCC.
They're trying to use this law called
the Congressional Review Act that an
effect just undid everything that the
FCC just did.
So it's a way to wipe out what just
happened and while the odds are long,
there's more than 40 United States
senators who have sponsored that law and
in the house side there's more than 80
members of the House of Representatives.
So there's momentum growing in Congress
to take a look at this issue and maybe
fixed what the FCC did,
and if you're sitting out there and
thinking they're not listening to you,
we should do something totally old
fashioned.
You should pick up the phone,
call your members of Congress and your
representatives and let them know you
care about this issue because that still
today is one of the most powerful ways
of conveying your opinion to those who
represent you.
When is the vote happening on that?
It is not yet scheduled.
I think it's going to happen first in
the United States Senate and later in
the house.
I also think we are going to have
litigation.
We've already got a few states attorneys
general who want a sued to overturn
this.
We've got some big companies and public
interest groups,
so I think it's fair to say we're going
to court and then we're also seeing
activity in state houses and that we've
seen net neutrality legislation
introduced in Nebraska,
Nevada,
Washington state,
Massachusetts,
California.
Lots of places,
and I'm not sure how that all comes
together legally,
but what you see as this momentum
growing,
that people are not happy with what
Washington just did.
The thing that I'm worried about with
the state's laws.
Right,
so just to lay it out for the listeners,
right.
There's people will,
will,
the government will pass the federal
law,
but then states have their own rights to
regulate certain things.
Let's say we use marijuana laws as an
example because recently a lot of states
past legal marijuana laws,
right?
But then trump gave people the power to
enforce federal laws about marijuana
more stringently.
Right?
He was telling the federal government,
Hey,
enforce our federal marijuana laws.
What's really jeff sessions,
right?
Chefs,
yeah,
his goon is doing that,
but so how would federalism work if
states started to pass their own net
neutrality laws versus the the,
the FCC Commissioner Orleans,
yeah.
Those are hard questions.
I mean,
they'd go right to the constitution.
What's interstate?
What's within the state's authority,
but I'm just standing back and seeing
really just a lot of energy on this
issue.
There's nothing else that I've worked on
in Washington where this immediately
statehouses decided to put pen to paper
and introduce legislation and I think
that that momentum is what's really
exciting here.
Well,
I think everyone understands the insane
power of the Internet and what,
what a cultural shift that we've
experienced over the last 20 years.
I mean it's unprecedented in human
history.
There's never been anything like it in
terms of access to information,
in terms of the rate of change,
the way people look at things,
the way the issues get discussed,
the cycle of news,
which is like,
what,
10 hours now?
Stories come in and out.
I mean Hawaii just had a fake missile
attack and everybody already forgot it
already onto the next like what's the
next thing we posted?
Check my phone because I think we have
to fix that.
We should certainly happened in Hawaii.
Someone went crazy.
Still learning.
It looks like it was a state level
issue,
but you can't have things like that
happen.
We got to figure out a way in this
digital world that we get accurate
information to people faster and we we
got to come up with better systems than
the one we just saw.
You need somebody pressed a button and
send out a text that said that there's
an incoming ballistic missile.
It's a possibility of threat of an
incoming ballistic missile and this is
not a drill.
And then I have friends in Hawaii and
everyone went crazy.
People were crying in the streets,
no one knew what to do.
And of course this is a state that was
attacked,
you know,
less than 100 years ago during World War
Two.
So this is not an unusual thing for
them.
Yeah.
I had the privilege of working for
senator in a way from Hawaii years ago
and I think Hawaiians are,
you know,
they're graceful.
They're resilient,
but they live with the knowledge that
they are susceptible to some attack.
So this gave them 40 minutes,
40 minutes of their life.
And the amazing thing to me is it took
like 10 minutes or so for this to be
corrected on twitter.
Took,
took off another half hour for our
official systems to update and say,
in fact this was a mistake.
Yeah.
Once we found out,
figure that out,
let that happen.
Yeah.
But then once I figured out it was a
mistake,
I was like,
Whoa,
maybe I should ask Jessica if we could
send like a national message on my
birthday.
12 am,
March first,
and be like,
you up just a nationwide booty call.
The FCC will not be helping in that
regard.
I had to ask.
That's a big question,
but what Joe was saying about the
Internet and how it opened things up
like personally for me,
like today's Martin Luther King Jr Day.
Right.
And uh,
I remember reading letter from
Birmingham jail as a kid,
Johnathan swift,
modest proposal as a kid and Tupac a me
against world.
Those were like the three works that
made me want to write.
And I started writing since I was 15
years old.
Never gave up,
but no one would buy my writing.
Right.
The only place that would by my writing
was roto wire and I would write fantasy
sports updates for them.
I covered the magic and I covered the
knicks,
but all the way until I was like 28
years old,
no one wanted to buy my writing.
It was blog spot that it allowed me to
write in my own voice and find my own
audience and then people started to see,
whoa,
there are like weird children on the
Internet that like Eddie's writing,
like he's creating a lane and I talked
to my publisher at Random House and they
were like,
yeah,
you created a lane selling books to
people who don't buy books,
non traditional readers,
and so without the Internet,
without blogspot,
without that ability to just project my
voice and hope someone connects like I
never would have happened.
I know we're living through it in real
time,
but it is totally radical as a matter of
human history that you can reach out,
reach around the world and build
community with total disregard for
geography and find people who like
fantasy sports or something like that
and and build community around it.
That's an extraordinary thing and it has
no precedent in human culture
and with translation software.
Now language is no longer even a
barrier.
I mean it's changing and shifting as as
we speak,
new technologies are being developed.
I mean Samsung has a phone now that that
note eight where you could just
highlight something and instantly
translated.
I mean they have earbuds where you could
put that on the pixel where if you talk
to me in Spanish,
I'll hear it in English and this is
crazy stuff and this is all changed.
That does for commerce or diplomacy or
your ability to talk to me across the
table without having a translator in
some clunky way.
Try to describe what I just said.
These things are amazing and you want
all of our collective genius to drive
them and not have big Cape gatekeepers
like our broadband providers in the way.
Yeah.
It seems to be a real issue and I think
that we should look at the internet as
something different than almost all
other services because it is our
ability.
It directly affects our ability to
evolve as a culture,
our ability to exchange information.
It's,
it's so critical and it's,
it's so unprecedented and this is a very
powerful thing and you know,
people would love to have it go back to
the old way and have you get your news
on ABC and NBC and CBS and that's it.
People would love that because they
control you.
Sure.
I mean,
it would be way easier to keep the
world,
you know,
informed in the way that they would
like.
Yeah,
it will be easier for regulators in
Washington too.
I mean,
there's just disorderly chaos on the
internet,
but it,
it,
um,
it create it.
Listen,
it has challenges,
but it's unearthed communities and
created economic possibility for people
like nothing in our history.
Yeah.
I think it just,
it's changing who humans are,
you know,
I think there's more of an understanding
of each other.
There's more,
there's more compassion.
I mean,
there's also a lot of hate and there's a
lot of anger and there's a lot of.
But I think with the bad there's more
good yet undoubtedly there's much more
good.
And to me it feels like a freedom of
speech issue,
you know,
like it's if,
if this internet kind of super highways
controlled and there's toll booths
everywhere and it gets privatized.
Like,
I mean,
I lived in Florida,
we didn't have money for roads.
I saw when things got privatized,
it's you just pay more,
you don't have the same service.
It's,
it's one of those things like it has to
be regulated,
it has to be protected and it has to be
guaranteed as a thing for all human
beings.
Not even just Americans.
Well,
it's just,
it's stunning to me how many people are
against the idea of having an open
internet.
It's just,
well,
you know,
most of the polling,
I think polls are always,
you got to be careful,
right?
Because they can ask a question one way
and get an answer.
But the best one done was right before
our boat by the University of Maryland.
80 three percent of the public supported
net neutrality opposed what we were
doing.
But who are those 17 percent dummies?
That's what I want to know.
I think anything you can get the
American public to agree to at 83
percent is a pretty high.
I think it's wonderful,
but I'm stunned to meet the 17 percent
seriously,
but isn't there a bunch of people?
I feel like there's some,
and I.
I wrote about this on twitter recently
without judgment.
I said that net neutrality seems to me
to be one of those ideological issues
where if you're on the right,
you support it or if you're on the left,
rather you support it where you're on
the right,
you would like to go away.
It's almost like totally
okay.
Can you give you are a Democrat or
Republican?
You benefit from net neutrality and
internet openness.
If you're conservative or liberal,
if you're a big business or a small
business,
you benefit from Internet openness and
the history of net neutrality is
something that doesn't get discussed
enough,
which is that it began the first time
the FCC put net neutrality policy on
paper.
It was 2005 and I'm old enough to
remember that that was when President
George W dot Bush was in the White
House.
In other words,
this country's first net neutrality
policies were put on paper.
One of republican was running the FCC.
It is only in recent days.
We have characterized this as a left
right issue and I think that's a
fundamentally a mistake.
How did it happen?
Like when when object Pi proposed this
legislation and passed it,
it baffled me.
I thought net neutrality was a thing we
had all agreed on.
It was like,
we're never touching this.
How did this happen?
Well,
you know,
through a whole bunch of boring
Washington procedures whereby they
circulate our proposed rulemaking.
How did,
how did he get the power and leverage to
pass this?
I think that he was supported by people
in Washington,
including some broadband providers and
was led to believe that with
deregulation we would all be better off.
And then what?
What?
What I find interesting is Google,
Amazon,
facebook,
these,
these big power players used to be very
vocal net neutrality,
keep the internet free,
things like that.
They're not as loud as they used to be.
They seem to just be quiet on it.
What do you think is going on there?
Well,
first I want to point out that those big
companies through their association are
gonna be intervening in the lawsuits in
favor of net neutrality.
Yeah,
so that's true.
Yeah.
But to me net neutrality has never
really been about big companies.
It's about who's going to be the next
digital platform,
who's going to be the next startup and
the next player.
I'm the big companies can always find
ways to build relationships and manage
this kind of lack of neutrality online
with their leverage that come from size.
It's.
It's a question of who's going to start
something up that you and I may not see
because they didn't pay off their
broadband provider.
It's the entrepreneurship that has me
most concerned likes new small business.
Yeah,
so when I was saying that there's a.
seems like an ideological rift.
There's certain people that are not very
well versed in this issue,
that automatically side one way or
another.
This is a thing that we do in this
country culturally,
right?
Left thing.
You see it a lot with global warming.
Will you have a conversation with
people?
They say that global warming's,
so natural process,
natural cycle of the earth goes through
it and he talked to them about how much
research they've done on it.
It's almost none if they fall into these
ideological groups and those pull
yourself up by your bootstraps,
right wing,
you know,
there's this sort of conservative way of
thinking that the let the market decide
and this is that,
that conversation.
I don't think that's an honest
conversation if you're dealing with
monopolies in,
in regards to Internet access,
which I think a lot of and I am and you
are,
a lot of people are.
It's a giant part of living in America.
Yeah.
And that tribalism that you're
describing right now,
it's really deteriorating the quality of
our dialogue in Washington.
We've got to find a way to fix it
because,
um,
we're not going to move ahead without
actually having some back and forth on
these things.
This is like the one issue where I'm
like,
it actually brings people together.
80 three percent of people support it.
Percent.
Yeah.
It's undeniable.
But it.
That's what's scary about this country
now,
is that even when so many of us agree
about something,
when one very powerful group,
a lobby,
the broadband companies get behind
somebody with some control,
like they can push the needle.
You know,
it's funny if you am I
email inbox,
which was an explosive thing leading up
to this vote was full of people writing
and telling me their stories,
but a whole bunch of that more like,
you know,
I'm a registered Republican but I want
you to know,
or I supported the president,
but I believe net neutrality is really
important.
It was striking to me like once you get
out of the talking head types.
Yeah,
she found is that there was really broad
based support for net neutrality.
Well,
what's stunning about this
administration is how trump's
administration is just going ham for
business.
They are going ham for offshore
drilling.
They're going ham for diminishing state
parks and starting to tap into
resources,
whether it's mining or fracking or
keynotes.
The world's gonna end in 25 years or
something and he's like,
just go.
Just take it all.
Here's the thing.
He doesn't have 25 years.
Yeah,
and so the world is gonna end in 25
years.
I mean,
if you're a 72 year old guy,
how much time do you have left?
If you have 25 years,
those last 25 years,
you're,
you know,
you're barely there.
Yeah,
it's insane.
There's nothing going to be left after
this administration.
Well,
it's real weird.
It's because it lets you know,
like people used to think,
wow,
the president is that much power.
Look at what's happening.
Yeah.
There's,
there's a,
a giant shift in environmental policies.
Environmental Protection Agency has been
gutted is that's the scary stuff.
The scary stuff is how much emphasis is
placed on business and how little on the
world in which we live.
I mean,
we have to balance that out.
It's also
how we got to focus on the future,
right?
Yes.
It is not a given that we're going to
succeed in everything.
If we don't start planning and when I
think about the world my kids are going
to inherit,
it's going to be digital.
They're going to be consequences.
Why don't we start doing something about
that right now?
There's not a lot of urgency.
It's one of the weirdest parts of being
a person as people look so short term
and they always feel like someone's
gonna fix it.
You know?
I mean,
isn't that the,
the attitudes som was going to fix
bulger right now.
The economy's booming.
Java's test is at all time low and
they'll just start throwing all the good
stuff your way.
But yeah.
Well,
when you just start raping the
environment and the business has go,
hey,
as a lot of process,
a profit to be made here,
let's,
uh,
let's get going.
Let's start hiring some people.
Yeah.
It's like all the money goes to defense
and Department of Education is good at
department of Energy has gutted
department of Environment's all these
things are gutted.
Everything that has to do with art,
even present and future,
it's good at the,
the only thing that's going on in his
business and defense.
And what's the argument for that?
The argument for that is that as
business booms,
as the economy will be trickled down and
they'll be more opportunities for
businesses to clean up the environment
and profit off of it and yeah,
but it's never work.
Commissioner,
can you like trickle down?
Economics has never worked in the
history of the history.
I have my doubts about it.
Yeah.
I've heard every pro and con for it.
It's it,
it.
I think at the very least the trump
administration and I'm trying to look at
it through rose colored glasses is a
fascinating experiment and in so many
different ways,
but it's also I think made us all more
conscious of our role as citizens.
Yes.
People have to talk back to Washington.
They have to speak up.
We need our representatives to hear what
people think and I think we got a little
comfortable there.
Believe in the system just runs by
itself,
but it does better when people
participate and I think that there's a
lot more demanded of us now as citizens
no matter where you fall on the
political spectrum.
I think it woke us all up to that fact.
Besides just calling state reps,
senators,
what else can people do?
Um,
uh,
participate in letter writing campaigns,
get things in your editorial page,
you know,
I don't mean a big papers.
I wrote something for the La Times about
this awhile ago,
but um,
I mean in your,
your local papers,
tell them why it's important.
Tell them how you built a business using
online activities and how maybe going
forward that's going to be a little
harder.
I think I'm making efforts to make sure
that people understand this at a local
level is really powerful.
What's very disturbing to people that
320 million people can view how many we
have 3:20,
somewhere in there that,
that can be affected by five people.
It's crazy,
right?
It's insane.
Five unelected bureaucrats because look,
that's who we are.
Have this extraordinary power over what
we can watch.
So he hear and learn.
I think that um,
there's something in that that strikes
me is not right.
And the idea that in the end,
just three of them voted to roll back
this open.
So three people changed it for $320
million people.
That's crazy.
That doesn't seem like the end three
people by the way,
who were not voted in.
So they're unelected,
which was bananas.
I mean,
there's no question about it.
That's a terrible idea.
Like if you gave people the option,
he said,
hey,
do you think that five people should be
able to decide whether or not the 320
million plus plus the rest of the world
really?
Because if you're a super podcast gets
cut off,
you know,
you're not gonna be able to reach the
Canada either.
Who Do you think that they should be
able to stop access to?
Information people define slide
83 percent of the American public to
it's.
It's insane and that's the type of shit
that makes me feel trapped in this
country sometimes because we did an
elect these people,
you know?
Yeah.
I think.
I think you gotta make a choice which is
you got to choose to be optimistic
because it's the only force multiplier
we have,
which is you're going to decide that if
something's not right,
you're going to call,
you're going to write letters,
you're going to write editorials that
you're to build campaigns around things
because in the end that's the only way
to change things and if all of us felt a
little of that spirit,
Gosh,
today,
if not every day,
I think that that would make
extraordinary difference and we're
already seeing its impact in Washington.
There are more people showing up in the
capital city for votes for marches.
There are more people reaching out to
their members of Congress than ever
before and I just think we're going to
have to sustain that energy if we want
to create some real change.
I think it's about more people who have
an opinion of values that are
trustworthy in the community running.
I think more people need to run because
for awhile we've.
I've actually looked at government as
something like I may be,
could never be part of.
This is a totally different thing,
like I just,
I,
I researched the candidates and I go
vote and that's,
that's my interaction with it,
but I'm starting to realize that even if
you don't want to run or even if you
want to run it,
it's a possibility and you number one,
you can encourage your other friends to
go run and you can look at who is trying
to start campaigns.
Like I'm 35 now and,
and Dara friends from law school.
Then they're like,
hey,
I'm thinking about running,
you know,
like I want to throw a fundraiser,
who should I speak to?
And then you know,
there's a guy that I played basketball
within a basketball league.
He was like,
I'm going to try to run for governor of
California.
I'm like,
good luck,
but like I'm going to follow what you're
doing and I think more people need to
run.
But if you're not running,
hold the people that are running
responsible,
ask the difficult questions like be a
part of the kind of vetting of that
candidate and be hands on in the process
of that person's candidacy.
Are you running for president with
Oprah?
No,
no,
no.
I'm not running mind.
Thing is,
is that,
you know,
I think we all need to have a stake in
the cats that are running in and ask the
questions that need to be asked because
you know,
I've been one of the people that just
shows up maybe two weeks before the
election,
two weeks before the deadline of like
the,
the absentee ballot and I go research
for two weeks and I go check out all the
pros and cons of each candidate and
after two weeks I decide,
but you know,
I should be involved more than that.
I said as it announce your congressional
run right here.
Right now.
I'm too busy.
This is not the problem though.
The people that we would want to run for
president or whatever,
elected official oftentimes are too
busy.
I mean,
I think if you ran.
I mean I'm not really clean up.
You could really do it.
I'm not running.
You got a bigger platform than I do.
I'm interested in.
I just,
I don't see important though.
You find a way to participate in public
life and give back whether you run or
support someone or encourage your
friends and they don't have to be the
person who was the student council
president in high school.
Muslim people out there.
My thing with candidates say,
great,
so joe,
we've had disagreements on the show.
We disagree about certain things.
We just screwed up.
Well,
it was a.
It was the minimum.
A university changed my mind based.
By the way I changed.
There was a knee jerk reaction to you.
We've talked about this.
I was talking about universal basic
income and net neutrality was sorta
nerdy,
nerdy about ubi.
I think you
automatically,
knee jerk goes,
ah,
don't do that.
It's bad for human nature.
You give people money,
they get lazy,
but then I thought about.
I said,
no,
you're just giving them food and
shelter.
You give people food and shelter.
You're still leaving open ambition and
you're also freeing them up for the
possibility of perhaps exploring things
that they would really truly love to do
where they have,
and I think when we,
when we started dealing with automated
vehicles,
automated trucks and trucking and
shipping and driving is a giant
business.
It's a huge part of what people have to
like.
There's some extraordinary percentage of
men who drive for a living and if you
eliminate that,
you're going to have a lot of people out
of work.
You have.
We have automation that's coming to
factories and all these different
places.
It's going to eliminate the need for
humans cut out all the human error or
what are we going to do with all those
people and what are we gonna do with all
those jobs and how do you give these
people this newfound possibility,
this,
this avenue for exploring new potential
career paths.
What will the best way is have their
money taken care of in terms of like
food and shelter,
like have given them the freedom to
explore ideas?
Yeah,
because it's a benefit a lot of people
have and then they do work and you take
that stress off their plate,
but I talked about the conversation
because we had it.
We had a good discussion about it and
then it went on for weeks on twitter.
We kept talking and then we both kind of
came around on on things and I was like,
Yo,
this is great and when I think about
candidates,
I think about I would vote for somebody
who they're
going to stick to their guns and they're
gonna do what they said they would and
their values aren't going to change once
they go to DC.
That's all you can ask for from a
person.
Be honest about who you are and be who
you are when you go to DC,
future of civilization,
right?
Like where are we now and where this
insane change that we've experienced
over the last 20 years because of the
Internet.
What is,
what is it going to be like in 20 years
from now?
And what happens to the average person,
the average human being.
We have this idea that you're supposed
to show up nine to five for a job and
that's what you do and then you work
until you're retired,
but that's all something that people
invented.
I mean there's all of.
This is a new thing in terms of human
history.
This is not the only way human beings
can live and the idea that this is the
only way to use our tax money or
resources is the way we're doing it
currently.
That doesn't seem to be that logical and
I would like people to have more
opportunity to innovate and create and
more freedom where they don't feel
shackled down.
Like there's a lot of people out there
that just feel shackled down by just the
need to feed themselves and survive.
Yeah.
And also just even school,
like I started reading and listening to
these podcasts about sleep.
Right.
And it's a.
it's a scientific thing.
Some people are not morning people.
She's laughing,
but like reading or listening to
podcasts about sleep,
you will.
You could get information at Somnia
listening to pat.
No,
but I listened to this dude and he was
talking about like it's a scientific
thing.
Some people are on a different body
rhythm,
they just don't do well in the morning
and he looked at schools in the school
schedule and the school schedule is
based on mom and dad's.
They have a nine to five based on
traffic and let's try to get these kids
into school for high school.
The earliest.
Then middle school later than elementary
school after that and some people
because they're morning people did just
suck at such a disadvantage and
highschool,
college.
This is like kind of an educational
industrial complex.
If you don't fit in,
if you're not cookie cutter and the way
your body and your mind works,
you're not going to be successful.
And and speaking of what Joe's talking
about is I think I genuinely believe
like even some of the silliest people
I've met,
everybody has some sort of genius it.
We're just not like fostering the
unearthing of that and like,
look,
there's some.
There's some hilarious stuff that
happens at Bauhaus at the restaurant,
but I tell myself every time I'm like,
all right,
like this guy totally messed up making
this bow.
This guy totally messed up.
Butchering this chicken blake.
Find a place where he can succeed,
like put him in a position to win and
that's a lot of responsibility.
It's a lot of responsibility.
It doesn't always work out,
but.
But usually it does.
Usually you find out like,
you know what?
That guy's really good at making the
sauce,
you know,
like put them on the sauce.
Like you have to find a place where
people to be successful,
but our society have to find their own
funding.
Yeah.
The problem is if you do have a nine to
five job and you're trying to feed
yourself and get along,
you're going to have less chances to
innovate.
You're going to left,
left chances to take risky decisions and
just try things out.
That is why Internet openness is so
important though,
because this was a platform and a space
for you to go experiment,
build community,
find communities,
figure out what your genius might
involve,
which may not be what you're doing at
work every day.
And I think the idea that Washington is
mucking around with that is just crazy.
Well,
I definitely don't think they liked the
fact that people have this ability.
I definitely think if you could,
if the people who created the Internet
knew what they were doing when they
release this on the general public,
they probably wouldn't have liked to
give people the kind of access to
information and the ability to change
things.
What we've seen through Arab spring,
we've seen through so many different
cultures that are using this to change
the way they interact with each other.
You know,
it was interesting during our net
neutrality proceeding,
Tim Berners Lee,
who um,
uh,
invented the web and vint cerf who
invented the Internet along with some
real icons from early days like Mitchell
Baker from Mozilla all wrote us and
said,
do not change these rules.
And it seems like when you've got that
incredible genius of these people who
created this connected world for you and
told you that this agency in Washington,
it's going to really mess around with
it.
It strikes me that,
um,
we should have listened.
Well,
we definitely should have listened,
but we also shouldn't have this place
where five people get to make this
decision.
It's insane.
Yeah.
Going in what you just said,
Joe,
it's like even even like,
let's say my role at,
at,
just to explain it from my role as the
owner or manager at the restaurant is
not necessarily always my job to create
a role for somebody in find a way for
them to be successful in my restaurant.
I'm hiring a cook,
I'm hiring a manager.
Like this is the job description.
Hopefully if you're coming for this job,
you can do this.
Right?
And I think what you said really opened
some in my mind,
which is the government should not be
always prescriptive about like,
all right,
we're all going to go to school at 7:00.
You're going to study hard and you're
going to get these grades.
You're going to go to college,
like that's not a path to success for
everybody,
but what it should do is enable people
to be creative and find out what works
for them.
We need to give people the freedom to
contribute to society.
Well,
I think we're trying to manage the
masses without looking at the needs and
the ideas of the individual and
everybody has their own likes and
dislikes and creative kinks and things
that mean how many people could have
lived a life of misery but got lucky
somewhere along the line and found
something that they love and,
and pursued that.
And I think that there's not a whole lot
of guidance in that regard,
but what there is on the Internet is
examples of other people have done this
and you can connect with those people
and you can.
There's so many communities when it
comes to.
I mean to.
I'm not,
I'm don't.
I'm weird about stuff.
I,
uh,
I liked knifemaking make knives.
It's kind of ominous,
but.
No,
no,
no.
The craft of it.
I love the idea of forging things.
I just think I find that fascinating and
I follow like dozens of these guys on
instagram that make knives and hatchets
and metal work and tools and furniture
and shit.
I'm not making furniture.
I have no desire to make furniture.
I'm not even thinking about it,
but I like watching this and I like
watching these people communicate with
each other and explain the methods and
the techniques they use and this is a,
you know,
an avenue where a young kid could see
something like that and go,
I want to make furniture.
Like that seems like a cool thing.
Like look at this amazing
that is too,
like when you were growing up,
you wanted to do that.
You're going to go to some library and
go to that close to it and look things
up.
You would never see the video content
that the number of people doing that at
all.
It's so casually and quickly legitimizes
it for you as something to think about
two or pursue.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
I had A.
I had a knife made out of meteor.
It's made out of media.
How?
How hard is media steel?
It's metal,
it's iron.
Oh Wow.
They make it with the iron that came out
of a media.
The mousy fire arts made it for me.
How did you cop media?
I've contacted them.
I contacted him and I,
I,
well I knew there's a guy named Steve
Kramer that makes somebody made one for
Anthony Bourdain and uh,
and I want what he got out.
One of those.
He's got a fucking meteor knife.
How do I get to meet your knife?
So my kitchen knife is made from a
media.
Damn.
Yeah.
Cleopatras and was made by that time.
Got a step by my knife.
Game up because I just,
I still just use the cleaver man.
I'm so like ancient Chinese with my
chopping.
Just to cleaver.
Well it's not the wrong with a
cleveland.
This is,
it just looks cool because I know it
came from bad.
I could,
yeah.
No,
I could expand the arsenal.
Adam,
media chef's knife to tell everyone that
came from a meteor when they come into
your kitchen.
So you just sort of impressive.
He showed it to a couple of people.
I just got it recently,
but it's a,
I just,
I think that this new world of,
uh,
of the Internet in terms of like is the
ability to explore these communities and
like you said,
video,
like see the video of someone like this
clock,
this a russell bill made this clock for
us,
that the grandfather clock.
I mean,
that dude made that all of the metal.
He welded it all,
put it all together.
I mean this,
this kind of stuff to me is so
fascinating and I don't just like it
because I'm interested in the craft of
it all.
I like it because I see it as an
opportunity for people to get out of the
grind.
Like you can make things if you can make
things and sell things.
If you have an Internet connection and
you have an instagram account which is
free and you have an iphone,
you take your phone,
you film something,
you
next thing you know you're selling
things.
I mean,
we,
it's an incredible time for like
opportunity to escape.
The biggest lie people fall for is that
they're,
they're bad at something or they're not
valuable.
It's like you may be bad in this
structural definition of a human being
that goes to school and gets a nine to
five job.
I was terrible.
I was terrible at it.
Yeah.
I got fired from a Boston market.
I got fired from the waterworks like I
couldn't work anywhere.
I got fired as a landscaper.
People's lawns.
I couldn't do anything,
but then it's like when you become in
control of your own shit and you go do
what you're passionate about,
it's like,
well then I became successful and I try
to tell people all the time,
like,
if this doesn't work for you,
the straight and narrow,
it doesn't work for you.
Like think of a way to think about what
you think your strengths are and play to
that.
Don't let anyone tell you you're a
failure.
You're unsuccessful because you don't
fit.
The stereotype I think is really
important though for successful people
like yourself to tell their failure
stories.
We don't do that enough.
Well,
I mean I lost a restaurant because I
sold all.
You can drink four Loko like that was
like I went out in flames.
You can drink for local sounds like a
liability when you're good at telling
stories,
but I think that that's true.
Generally,
I feel like I wish I could ask every
member of Congress to tell a failure
story.
They would never do that.
Those people are trying to pretend
they're something different.
Well,
I was a terrible law student.
Anything more explosive like before you
ever sell for local at a lemonade stand?
I can tell you I absolutely never did
that and probably never will.
Any other failures?
Uh,
yeah.
I got some parenting failures that I'm
going to save my children from
announcing in public
call.
Good call.
Yeah.
I feel like it's important for people to
relate,
right?
They have to be able to say,
oh,
Eddie wasn't always a successful guy.
Like he was a 19 year old kid wants to.
That was also struggling.
That's very important.
It's very,
it's.
I think it's one of the most important
things that people can understand that
failure is an opportunity to learn and
that horrible feeling of failure is
really your friend.
Does that horrible feeling motivates you
to change?
I mean I feel all the time I played
basketball yesterday.
We had a double header.
I was,
I was cooking on a grill.
I was making lamb skewers for four hours
in the morning when straight from the
kitchen to this basketball game and San
Gabriel valley playing with.
It's like an Asian basketball league.
So I'm actually like kind of toll like
um,
like a small forward and there's like
little younger dudes at 25 running
around me.
I did not have played well the first
game I was washed the second game and
these kids probably like 23,
four years
old running past me,
elbowing me and I got so mad and I act
it out.
I started like yelling at them.
I started like beefing and I got home
and I told my fiance about it and she's
like,
Yo,
why are you beefing with these kids?
They're 25,
like,
like your old.
Of course they're gonna run by you,
you playing a double header and you came
out of the kitchen.
And it was funny because I was like not
willing to let it go.
But then I was like,
I got to work on myself like every
single day,
like I fail at something and I failed at
being like the elder statesmen in the
basketball.
We're being composed,
being composed.
I lost my composure and I started making
fun of these kids for no reason.
And I was like,
that's not me.
You know,
like basketball sometimes brings out the
worst in me,
but I was like,
all right,
today I'm going to be a better person.
We'll go back to that week,
next week I'm gonna be like a nice dude.
And if some kid washes me in west me in
the face,
it gets fine.
Well
Times you just need to experience it so
that you know,
okay,
I just have to be more composed when
that comes up and when you didn't expect
to experience it.
And then someone hits you with that
elbow,
you're like,
what?
Fuck you man.
And the next thing you know,
it's intense
boxing,
basketball,
it's the most like sports system.
Most humbling thing for me.
I'm not built for it.
I kind of built to fail at sport,
but you try anyway.
I try because I try because it's the
thing I'm the worst at,
so I always wanted.
Well,
it's great for the mind.
The thing about sports is you're forcing
your body to do things that are
uncomfortable and in doing that you're
not just exercising your body.
You're also exercising your mind and
that's one of the things that I always
try to relate to people that are
negative about physical exercise and
exertion because they think that it's
some sort of a frivolous venture that's
just vanity.
Just want to look good or use your body,
but there's a mental aspect to having
the ability to push through discomfort
that is extremely valuable and if you
don't have that switch where you can be
comfortable being uncomfortable because
you've done it a million times.
If you don't,
then you're.
You're gonna be panicky.
You're going to be weirded out by it,
and that is a mental weakness.
So in that ability to push through
discomfort helps you not just in
physical exercise and exertion,
but it also helps you in work.
I'll give you have to push through
certain work things instead of getting
up and getting another cup of coffee,
figuring out what the fuck you're doing,
figure out what,
what's this problem you're working on?
Concentrate like focus you get out,
get after it.
Be comfortable being uncomfortable.
I don't believe in trickle down
economics,
but I believe in trickle down mental
strength,
you know what I mean?
I start in the gym every morning and
like whatever happens in the gym,
it humbles me.
It gives me like,
you know,
some kind of like energy and I bring
that throughout the day.
Like what got you hooked in Jujitsu?
Well,
I've done martial arts since I was a
little kid,
but I think there's something that is
inescapable in my life at least,
and that is that there is no disconnect
between the mind,
the body,
that they're all one thing and that you
can work them individually but not
really because when you working your
body,
you need the mind to do that.
The intensity of my workouts is one of
the most important aspects of it and
that's fuel 100 percent by my mind.
It's not by my body
and Plato said that since fifth century,
he always wrote about like how training
the body is just as important as
training
the rest of your martial arts.
I mean it's just,
it's everything because your high level
problem solving with bad physical
consequences,
you're,
you're trying to avoid injury and
humiliation and all these various things
that are a part of martial arts and in
the meantime you're trying to maintain
composure under pressure and you're
tired and you have to understand the
ability to push and push through
discomfort and push through exhaustion,
but it also fuels the mind.
It's very important.
Yeah.
Fighting that three round fight.
I was like my first three round fight.
I got so scared.
I was shaking the whole time,
but I just told myself,
dude,
there's no backing out in the ring.
You have to go forward.
Keep going forward.
And like just out of fear.
I'm a pressure fighter.
Do you mean like just out of fear,
like I have to be a pressure fighter
because I don't think in my first fight
I knew I did not have like the in me to
counter or or do what like the game plan
was.
I was like,
I just have to pressure like I have
these hands and move these feet.
But then I got through.
I got lumped up a few times.
I won the fight,
but I was like,
whoa.
I feel like I could do anything now.
And so now I keep sparring and I keep
fighting because I,
if I can be composed in the ring with
someone trying to kill me,
then like I,
I can be composed on a podcast or in a
meeting or negotiation.
It's,
it's the best.
Martial arts
is a vehicle for developing your human
potential.
Then that those things are all connected
and it's a,
it's a critical lesson for,
for young people and if you can push
through hard workouts,
you could push through whatever career
path you want.
You're trying
breaches me respect too because it's
like you can get bodied anytime you can
get dropped at any time,
like be grateful for when you have both
arms and legs and you're standing on
your two feet because you could be
dropped at any second.
So.
But I mean,
do,
do you do physical activities?
Sports?
Yeah,
I know she'd been waiting to jump in
this conversation.
Well,
I grew up in new England in cold
country.
Where?
In Connecticut?
Connecticut.
Outside of Hartford.
Okay.
You're one of those people,
is that.
It's like a westport and I think my
girls from the westport in New York
City.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
She from West Florida.
So I grew up skiing all the time and uh,
I still love skiing.
I still,
I need the thrill of flying off of
something that makes me uncomfortable in
order to relax in a perverse way.
So when I have vacations,
that's what I do.
I take my kids who right now live in DC
with me and it's pretty flat there.
So you got to go take them to see some
mountains and you got to go make sure
that they go down something that's a
little bit too steep every single time
because I.
You build some
resilience when you get down something
like that and you turn around and say,
well I did that.
I can do some other things.
I think there's some resilience in
living in Connecticut too
cold,
weird and plus it's not really a state.
Connecticut's like a highway between New
York and Boston now I would.
Connecticut,
Rhode Island,
California.
People if you're not crossing.
Oh,
I married someone and grew up in Boston.
Boston,
Boston
have ideas.
I never would have thought you were from
Boston where I was born in New Jersey,
but I grew up in Boston,
got rid of it,
hurt myself on tv when I was 19 and I
was like,
fuck that accent.
So embarrassed.
Listen to my own accent.
Go home and I hear people with New
England accent and it feels like sweet
and comforting.
It's great putting drunk there was
drunk.
It seems like it's normal.
Can you do.
Can you do a little bit of one right
now?
Uh,
I could see.
I thought you like listening to the
Utah.
I thought you were from the south for a
second.
No,
no,
because you don't have a new England
accent.
No,
no,
but I've been living in Washington for a
little while.
Plus she's a politician.
You got to get rid of the shit.
You have the ill politician like the
meter talking.
It's on like a metronome smooth.
It's good.
It's a good thing.
Do you ever.
Do you ever do this thing with your
hands?
Like Clinton used to do the thing where
you hold your phone like that do this
thing what we need to do in this
country.
I never understood that.
People would always tell me when I do
voiceover,
like slow down,
slow down and like I can't slow down.
My voice totally changes.
If I slow down,
I just got to come,
like shot out of the case.
True.
If you go back to Washington,
you decide with your congressional
campaign,
it's all going to happen.
You are going to slow down when you
speak.
Yeah.
Like you can hear your periods and
commas.
I just run through sentences with trump
as president.
I think all bets are off.
I think you do whatever you want.
No,
I don't think there's any rules can call
into other countries.
Shitholes.
You can get crazy.
Joel.
I'm telling you.
I really think you should run.
You can bring mad people together.
What does that mean?
I'd use you bring people together and
also like I think number one.
Number one,
like I think you're one of the few dudes
who can get the like really wild white
people to like think about things like
consider them.
Be Like have some perspective and
empathy.
Like the wildlings internet walk.
Yeah.
I,
I really believe it.
Joe,
as the guy that's like,
alright,
the crazies trust him and then like he,
he,
he can get them to think about things
from a different perspective.
I don't know if that's good.
No,
it's a good thing dude.
Like you appeal to you appeal to like
all people but like,
like I meet a lot of people,
they run up on me like,
Yo,
you're on Jerry.
You're pretty left.
You're a little,
you're a little crazy,
but I enjoyed talking to you and I'm
like,
Yo,
thank you man.
Like I,
I mean I come on the show so I can speak
to a different audience than just like,
you know,
hip hop,
Asian dudes in my dms
dudes that like Migos and soy sauce,
like
it's not that big
niche.
There's a weird thing about the
listeners of this podcast.
If they don't,
they're not left or right.
No,
it was like a weird mixture of people,
but that's good.
That's so much more of that country
right now.
I mean we're,
we're not gonna,
we're not gonna do things if we don't
start listening to each other.
Like I don't usually identify as left
his people call me that.
But it's like your content on the show
galvanizes cats from like all around
around the
world.
Well,
I,
I don't identify as left either,
but I do when it comes to so many issues
when it comes to gay rights,
when it comes to civil rights,
when it comes to just across the board
things that you would automatically
consider liberal,
but also the freedom to express
yourself.
Like that's,
that to me is the marketplace of free
ideas is one of the most important
aspects of developing a civilization.
It's one of the most important ways that
we understand about each other and you
got to have an open mind.
It's like I was saying like you bring up
that universal basic income and I was
like,
get the fuck out of here with that.
And then I thought about it afterwards
and I was like,
maybe there's some,
maybe I,
I always liked to explore my reactions
to things and if I had a reaction to
something and I automatically dismiss
it,
I go,
okay,
was that valid or did I just dismiss it?
Because it's easier than to have a
nuanced perspective that's formed over
time and a lot of critical thinking.
And so I stopped and thought about it
all and I think at the very least it's
something that merits consideration and
maybe it could be a of some sort of a
project.
Let's go.
Let's see.
Let's see if that works.
Yeah,
we have some countries doing that right
now though.
They're different than us culturally.
And I think culturally as part of it,
that is a problem.
Well,
America is just so based on competition.
Competition is so powerful over here and
I think that's good.
And I also think that's bad because
ultimately it's like if you could grab
trump and and,
and get him on mushrooms and lead,
explain just somehow or another let the
universe explained to him,
this is a temporary experience.
You're trying to gather up all this
money and gather up all these resources
and gather up all this influence when
this is all fleeting.
It's sand,
it's slips between your fingers.
There's no way you can grasp it for
real.
The real experience is the shared
moments that we have with each other and
the more we can enhance that for the
people around us,
the more you can use your power to
enhance people's perspective,
change people's way of interfacing with
this world that we live in and we
recognize that we're all just living
together.
We're all just a part of this community,
this competition thing.
Most of the competition is with
yourself,
most of it,
the vast majority of it,
and those other people that you're
competing with,
you should cherish them because their
fuel,
all those people,
instead of looking at them as the enemy,
those people are your friends.
Although your most bitter rivals are the
greatest motivators you're ever going to
experience.
Those are the people that are going to
push you,
but don't be toxic about it.
Yeah,
you can be.
You can be.
You can be peaceful about it.
Yet Joe,
I love competition because it's number
one.
It's amazing to watch like,
you know,
low,
uh,
Klitschko Anthony,
Joshua,
I think greatest fighter like the last
20 years,
like hazing,
boxing,
match for that boxing match,
Loma Chenko,
Reagan's.
That's not competition,
you know,
like that.
That was,
that's an experienced though.
That's,
that's an experience.
Total diss snatching.
Have a soul.
Well,
he's a different animal.
Loma Cenk goes a different thing.
The Matrix.
Do you know the story about his dad?
Would his dad made him do know,
made him stop boxing and do a Ukrainian
dance for four years.
That's why he's got that ridiculous
footwork because footwork is everything.
And I know he does a number association
too,
which is crazy.
But what I was saying about competition
is like,
you know,
Pete piloting and was we need
competition.
We need competition.
Like,
but who is competing with service
providers?
There is no competition.
It's just beating up on a bomb.
You know,
it's like we all live to watch great
competition,
but you have to foster competitors.
You need actual competitors for there to
be competent.
Imagine if what we're experiencing with
Internet was also with food.
Imagine if like only certain people
could bring you your food.
Yeah.
You know like,
Oh,
you live in Charleston.
Yeah,
you gotta get your food from Mike.
Yet it's basically like growing up
eating food in Orlando.
There's like one in a category of food
for your mind.
Yeah.
Food for your mind is real.
I mean the fuel that you get them,
the information that you get from the
Internet,
that is fuel for your mind and whether
you get it in the form of actual food or
whether you get it in the form of
information.
These are both very critical things that
you need a wide variety of different
sources for,
but you bring up a good point.
Even just,
let's say food delivery,
right?
It started off,
you would call the restaurants and it
was difficult.
You had to save the menu from every
restaurant.
Then seamless comes around and they're
like,
all right,
we're putting all the menus on here and
we're just helping facilitate.
You get things from the restaurant,
but it wasn't like for restaurants we
didn't necessarily like seamless because
then you had to have your own delivery
workforce.
They took a big cut of what you were
making and in a lot of restaurants they
didn't even break even using seamless,
so then like places like caviar came
around and postmates came around and
they supply the service,
the delivery people,
the consumer pays more for the delivery
and the restaurant makes their money and
it's like,
whoa.
Now that actually created competition
between delivery services.
Now you have an evolution and now you
know everybody gets what they want.
You get service all happened over the
Internet.
It was all kind of little little folded
menu,
the kitchen drawer,
right?
Like that's how we used to do it and if
you lived in New York you get home and
it's just like 20 Sushi,
making
empire,
putting something under my door,
a lot of slip and fall in your own
apartment cases from those wickets.
What happened and what's happened
through the Internet in terms of people
not drinking and driving because of
Uber.
That's changed the way people get
around.
If I went to high school with Uber,
I would have been good.
When.
When?
When were you in front of the comedy
store?
Lift is blocking the Goddamn driveway to
the comedy store.
Nine out of 10 times when you're allowed
to leave.
There's a car pulled up there which is,
look,
it's,
it's an inconvenience,
but man,
it's so nice to see drunk people just
getting driven around.
They need to be.
They may be jumping around.
It's interesting.
We don't talk a lot about the safety
element of that,
but it's so amazing.
It's also young people are not buying
cars like they used to.
Used to be that getting a car entailed
your freedom.
Right.
And one more device centric where you go
and what you do with virtual physical
car anymore.
You were segregated because I went to a
school where people were bused in from
different parts so you could be friends
with someone at school,
but if they don't have a car or they
live 45 minutes,
you can't be friends,
but now you can all meet each other up.
You can,
they,
you know,
they may not be able to rent the car or
have a car,
but they can take uber and meet you up.
Yeah.
And that really is another aspect of the
Internet that a lot of times we don't
take into consideration is cellular,
mobile apps,
apps are the Internet.
I mean it is everything through the
Internet,
but it's in this little device that you
keep in your pocket and twitter,
facebook and instagram and all these
different live in a mobile first world.
Anyone who's building a website now,
it should be built for that device
because that's the first place most
people experience that online.
And the only concern that I have about
that though is that,
you know,
ultimately we want people to not just be
digital consumers but to be digital
creators.
And some people
think more of us should be.
I don't,
I don't think people building things
should be,
you know,
a bunch of guys in hoodies in their
twenties.
I think that,
no,
I agree with the digital world should
look as diverse as all of us.
Yeah,
sure.
I hope on a going forward basis,
we're going to fix this internet
situation with net neutrality.
And we're also going to diversify the
universe of people who build things for
our online more.
Well,
we really see that in the podcast world.
The podcast world is extremely diverse.
There's so many different Po.
I mean whatever you're into,
you can find a category and a whole
shitload of people that are making
podcasts about it and it's really sad.
Five podcasts on sleeping.
You probably haven't done a ton on food,
right?
Food food is actually,
when I was working on this net
neutrality should I have worked with the
today show and they wanted to find
someone who built a business online and
they spent time with this woman,
I think it was Laura's kitchen and she
had basically started just putting
videos on Youtube,
showing herself and how she was cooking
and then you know,
that morphed over time into a book and a
big empire and she built something from
it and it's amazing.
If you look at how much cooking has
evolved from just hobby online to actual
business,
it's extraordinary.
It's undeniable.
I mean for,
for younger people listening,
they're,
oh,
they're probably just like guys,
we know like the,
like everything.
It's,
it's undoubted.
Everything happens on the Internet and
so for it to become this thing that's
not regulated is insane.
It's like it's like getting our roads
taken away.
You don't want like regulation,
which you want is just a little bit of
oversight to make sure that it's fair.
I think that's a good way to put it
because I don't.
I think when we break in a regulation or
deregulation,
we lose the point.
The point is you just want a little
oversight to make sure it's fair and
open to all equal playing ground in that
everybody's allowed to come to this and
recognize it as an important resource
that it is.
The ability to distribute information is
critical to changing the culture,
the way we interface with each other,
the way we talk,
the experiences that we share,
the way we have access to all these new
ideas and information.
It's just shifting things that this
radical warp speed,
warp speed,
it's just.
It's the weirdest time ever and so for
this to be a monkey wrench thrown into
the gears of this by five people,
three shoes,
three,
sorry,
present company.
Yes.
It's just,
it's,
it's hard to imagine that that's going
to stick,
but with this administration,
it's not stunning because it seems like
net neutrality being dissolved favors
these big businesses that would like to
maximize their profits.
And Net neutrality is the ultimate
populist issue,
right?
Because it empowers all of us online.
So.
Yeah.
So write letters,
make calls,
be annoying.
You have to be annoying.
Run,
run,
run for president
in 2020 Eddie and Oprah.
Eddie,
Joe,
and Joe's a good ticket,
bro.
I'm not doing it,
but good luck.
Good luck.
You and Oprah.
I think you're going to be living your
best life.
What's that mean?
What does oprah appraisal?
Oh my bad boy.
Oprah.
Is that part of the secret?
You're going to have to work with your
running mate on that.
So,
um,
this
w,
the situation that we're in right now,
do you,
are you confident that there is real
potential for it to be reversed?
I am optimistic that the American public
are awoke and they're paying attention
now and they're making a Ruckus.
I mean,
we had millions of people write us at
the FCC when I got appointed to the FCC,
I didn't think millions of people knew
what the FCC was.
I think that's extraordinary and I'm not
ready to give up.
Well,
the last time the FCC was in the
mainstream news is when you guys were
finding Howard Stern.
That predates my tough course.
Does that was also during the George
Bush administration.
How'd you get to the FCC?
So before I was appointed,
I served as counsel to the Senate
Commerce Committee and um,
I worked there for Senator Rockefeller
for a long time and first senator in a
way before that.
And um,
so I,
I got like a front row seat at a whole
bunch of digital issues with how we deal
with our wireless spectrum,
how we change our television technology.
So,
you know,
I'm a real kind of nerdy Washington
thing,
but also a new way to see how everything
is changing in our economy because of
digitization.
What's your thoughts on
cryptocurrencies?
I'm,
you know,
so I have no special authority on this
except that have microphones in front of
me.
Um,
that being said,
yeah,
right.
Uh,
I'm less interested in cryptocurrencies
than I am in Blockchain,
which is the ledger that they use to re
to record exchanges in cryptocurrency.
It's anonymous and it can be used by
anyone.
It's extremely low cost and I think
they're open questions about how you can
make government and a lot of business
services more efficient using blockchain
that I think are really interesting and
I have yet to be explored.
That's what I'm excited about.
What's one way a business could use
blockchain?
Um,
I'll just make this up.
Say there's some kind of a,
you export fruit.
Someone puts a bag of that fruit on the
table and they say,
well,
we know that there are certain fields
that fruit comes from,
you know,
there might be a disease in it.
How can you figure out how that fruit
got here from the field?
You know,
you can go back through your supply
chain and call everyone and get them to
tell you how long it sat over here and
who held it and put it in the truck.
The question is,
if you can come up with a digital way
where everyone as a collective just
contributes to that along the way,
can that be low cost?
More efficient and more effective?
I think it will change supply chain
economics in a really big way and we
don't fully understand the consequences
for our economy yet,
but I think it's coming.
Oh,
that,
that makes sense.
Kind of like a wikipedia
for each thing.
Yeah.
Did it with food for you?
So.
No,
no,
no.
That makes sense.
That makes a lot of sense.
No dogs.
Yeah.
Um,
I,
you look at,
here's,
here's high,
high level nerd,
but our airwaves around us,
right?
Our wireless airwaves,
that power,
all of our phones,
we have to divide them up.
You don't see it,
but it's like if there's a zone so that
your phone works,
the television works,
all of these things,
you know,
but we also have a whole bunch of
airwaves that are only used sometimes,
but what if we could create like
secondary and tertiary rights to use
them so that our phones were more
powerful.
And what if the best way to do that was
to use something like blockchain.
I mean there's,
there's so many ways I think the
recording ledger for cryptocurrencies
could make our economy more efficient
and more powerful.
And so that's what I'm interested in and
that's probably because I don't own any
bitcoin.
Yeah.
I know people also in journalism have
been talking about keeping articles on
blockchain so they,
like Internet articles don't go
anywhere,
you know,
because people can just erase a website,
like a website,
uh,
goes out of business.
Then all of the articles on that website
are gone.
So some people are putting websites on
Jean,
figuring out how we maintain our history
in this digital world is actually,
it's a real thing.
Yeah.
Especially a lot about that.
It's like cultural preservation,
right?
If we have some sort of a solar flare
and it kills the grid and we lose hard
drives and we there,
that's real.
That actually could be a real thing.
Yeah,
and blockchain.
It's kind of an answer from keeping
information.
My hope is that we're going to
eventually shift to voting online.
Does it do that,
do that?
I think the state of Oregon that makes
experiments with that,
we should study that.
We should make voting easier.
Yes.
That's what it comes down to and make it
more convenient for people,
but then the thought is,
well,
if they're so stupid,
lazy,
they can't make their way to a voting
booth.
Do we really want their opinion to be
expressed?
I think the busiest politician we talked
about politics,
just let us know
you have a job.
If you've got kids you're trying to work
there for now and then you find out your
polling place is open from nine to five.
Right.
That's a good point.
It's insulting.
I mean,
I know that when I voted in the
election,
the last election,
presidential election,
I think you can guess the last election
in Washington,
I had to wait 35 minutes before I got
in,
in the middle of my day also.
So that's,
that's,
that's a commitment.
It's a commitment I'm willing to make.
It's a commitment.
I'm privileged enough to take that time
and make it.
We got to make it easier.
I'm absolutely joking around and I
really do think that we should make it
much easier to vote and I think you
should be registered to vote the same
way you're registered to drive.
I mean if you have a driver's license,
I think you should be registered to
vote.
I think it should be just that easy and
I think you should be able to do it
online and I think if you have a social
security number,
you should be able to vote.
I think it should be
really using and I think that's not
outside the realm of possibility.
I think we're,
we're operating on these antiquated
systems and we've accepted them as fact
and this is the way things are and I
just think that it's nonsense.
It's not a good system.
Totally.
Yeah.
I mean like if you live in Florida.
I remember when I was trying to vote in
Florida,
like the polling stations were in
churches and I'd go and it was,
it was an uncomfortable thing to go to a
church where I'm pretty much the only
Chinese guy voting,
you know,
a lot of people say really wild things
to you in mind.
Like when you're waiting to vote.
And I'm like,
I would have to vote online.
Like when they say,
well you probably go on for the carry,
Huh?
You know what I mean?
Because it's like the John Kerry year
for carry and it's not your business
bro,
you know?
But also I'm like,
why do I have to go vote at a church?
Like I don't go to this church.
Peanut gets so intense when it comes to
voting comes struggle as are super
intense and you know,
they,
you know,
people just say things to you in a
voting line and I'm like,
this discourages a lot of people that
may have a minority opinion in the
neighborhood.
I think you should have some sort of an
understanding about what you're voting
for.
Two,
I mean I,
I would like voting to be much easier,
but I would also like there to be some
accountability.
Like you should know what you're
actually voting.
Maybe there should be like some sort of
a quick online poll or some sort of a
quick online candidates.
I think that violates the constitution.
So I'm just going to say that does it.
The constitution has nothing to do with
the Internet.
No,
nothing back then.
The constitutional meaning like old ass
shit.
I don't know.
I don't want to test for voting.
I think we're just expressing the
frustration where like a lot of people
just get ushered in like sheep to go
vote for people.
I think you're expressing that.
You want there to be accountability.
Yes.
And you want people to be aware,
I would like people to know what they're
voting about.
Participation.
You could answer what your vote if you
understand it,
you know,
like maybe there's a,
some sort of,
uh,
an amendment that's being passed or
something's being passed where you don't
understand exactly what you're getting
into and maybe there should be a way
that we find out if you understand it,
I know that you have the good intentions
for it.
But I read these cases that once you
have a test for people to vote,
I mean the powers that be.
I mean look at Gerrymandering,
you know,
like it's,
anytime you introduce that it,
it always sets like the populace back.
But I do,
I do really connect with joe sentiment,
which is like a lot of people voting
aren't,
aren't actually participating
consciously in the process.
Yeah.
I mean,
listen,
I think being a citizens of job,
you actually spend some time and think
about what's your authorizing for the
world,
what the future's going to look like and
how you're going to participate in
shaping it merely by voting I think.
I think it's a real job and I think more
people are aware of that now than they
used to be.
It's also,
there's so much to pay attention to.
It is every time lasting,
right is when the elections come around
and you just realize all the different
things that are up and you just go over
all the different issues and all the
different possibilities and you're like,
Oh God,
yeah,
I know what I did in California last
time.
Like all the propositions are like,
whoa,
this is interesting.
I actually an interesting,
but the local stuff is really important.
We spent so much time talking about
national elections,
people who around you who really have
power to change your life,
your most local representatives and
sometimes I worry that we pay the least
amount of tension to those races.
Oh yeah.
We dropped down the street and you see
some guys got a sign on his lawn for
some dude running for some shit you
didn't even know was up.
It was like,
is he a politician or a realtor?
How many people do they even need to win
one of those elections?
Yeah.
That's where you start,
Eddie.
That's where you start your empire.
San Gabriel Valley.
Yeah.
Before you run,
you're the vice president with Oprah.
That's what you gotta do.
I can't do it,
man.
I can't do get a car.
Everyone gets a
basic income.
Everyone is 60 g's 60.
That's what the universal.
If you can't get 30,
30,
32.
What we settled on was 30 last time.
Thirty.
Seems like you could get by.
Yeah.
You're not going to get rich.
You're going to get by.
Which is good.
Thirty five.
I think 30 is a good place to start
trying it out in some place with 12 once
a month to 50 a week.
Thirty is good with some like alright.
If you do get a job and you make some
money,
were you really paying some taxes?
You know?
Interesting.
There was a way that automation is not
going to hit the economy at the same
time or all sectors of the economy at
the same time in the same way.
So I think it's coming faster than we
think.
Not that I'm wishing for this.
I just think it it,
it is because my stocks and robotics
keep going up that.
That's my evidence.
Well,
Elon Musk is fairly convinced that
universal basic incomes,
the way to go,
he thinks that in the future that's just
going to be inevitable because there's
going to be so many things that are
automated.
Just can be so many people that are out
of work.
Yeah.
Although I think it will change our
conception of work,
what we do to be productive individuals.
People work too much.
That's for sure.
I agree.
I think people would work way too much.
You know what I mean?
You're live and then you're dead and you
have a heart attack when you're 60.
Is that really what we're doing?
I mean,
isn't there a better way?
Well,
how about working three days a week,
you know,
or four days a week for three off.
Four on.
That seems reasonable.
I work seven,
but it's love so I don't feel like it's
work,
but none of my stuff actually.
I mean,
how many days would you do the podcast?
I do it a lot,
but I have other jobs.
Yeah.
You stand up and do the UFC commentary.
I do,
but none of them are jobs.
Same.
This is barely.
I love it.
You know,
but also you're your own boss,
which is,
which makes work way different.
Makes it different things very different
than it is for most people.
Yes.
Yeah.
That's what I want most people to
escape.
I want them to escape the grind of
having to be somewhere because someone
tells you have to have to do something
because someone tells you you have to do
it.
Yeah.
Getting a small amount of money.
Why other people make more?
I just think that the economy
always changing.
I mean,
it used to be that you were,
um,
there was an employer with many
employees.
I think increasingly we're all gonna be,
um,
the employee with many employers in that
we're going to have a web of contracts
and activities that we use to sustain
ourselves economically over time.
I think you saw that developing the
Internet and the new platforms that are
coming on board.
Um,
there's consequences of that for
healthcare and other issues that I don't
think we fully tackled.
But I think that there is change coming
that lifetime employment and preparing
for it with a single degree out of high
school is I think something that is
going to look like a historical moment
in the future.
You know,
there's a johnny naysayers out there
that I always get frustrated by it.
They were like,
yeah man,
not everybody can do that.
Not everybody can work for themselves.
Not.
Guess what?
We're not talking to everybody.
If you're not capable,
that's okay.
But there's a lot of people out there
that are capable.
They just aren't doing it.
Yeah,
they're scared.
Yeah.
And they don't have to be.
Because we were all scared.
Everybody was scared and it seemed like
comfort and,
and,
and having some sort of security,
it's a real,
a real need that a lot of people have
that confidence,
security and knowing that your bill is
going to be paid and everything's going
to be taken care of.
That's,
that's a,
that's hard for people to shake off.
Yeah.
Comfort is also a huge weakness.
I think at times,
like a lot of times,
you know,
if you're too comfortable,
you become complacent,
like challenges,
failures,
like that's where I really start to
examine myself and I'm like,
it might be better tomorrow.
Growth in comfort.
Don't go together.
Yeah,
yeah.
Um,
for anybody.
Yeah.
But then people get families and then
when you get families you don't want to
take any risks.
That's,
that's a problem as well.
People have mortgages and children and
they,
they don't want to do anything that
might put them in the unemployment line.
To be clear.
That can be a really smart and
responsible choice at some point when
you have a lot of people relying on you,
that's the most rational thing do.
Yeah.
That's a real problem.
Like a Black Jack Dealer told me last
week,
scared money,
don't make money.
You say I go try and double down,
double down,
double down.
I'm showing a four.
How did that bag?
He pulled a seven.
I got screwed because that's why you go
to Vegas.
I told them,
I was like,
this is why come to vegas to lose money.
Well,
yeah.
And you lose money and I had to tell
everyone at the table's,
I'm like professional gambling,
that's what we're here for.
Like if you,
if you hit on 17 then always hit on 70.
If you hit on 16 then or if you stay on
16 stout 16.
Bromley plus practice professional
gambling professional gambling's not on
17 though.
Right?
That's if they're showing,
they're showing like if they're showing
a face card,
some people hit.
I mean,
no,
not 70.
What I was saying.
16.
I'm at 16.
I said the wrong thing.
Like I always stay on 16.
Even if they're showing a face card,
I'm like I just stay on 16.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm conservative but then I'll double
down.
Double down.
You have the,
the hit on 17.
That's those wild white people you were
talking to are the people we need you to
turn there listening.
Cowboys.
People listen.
They're listening.
Yeah.
Uh.
All right.
I guess we probably should wrap this up.
Jessica,
tell everybody what your um,
your twitter handle is [inaudible].
It's J.
Rosenworcel.
Spell my
last name.
Uh,
so that's at j.
r o s e n w o r c e l and m.
So your advice is people should do the
old fashioned thing.
Make those phone calls.
My advice is make a Ruckus make rocking
without a little noise.
This is one of those times and I think
being a citizen requires us all to speak
up right now.
Make a Ruckus online as well.
Let people know.
And your social media,
your facebook,
twitter,
all that jazz.
And getting the pornhub comments.
Hashtag that neutrality.
Yeah,
that's not what she says.
What I said,
I can't believe you leave comments.
I can't believe I know somebody leaves
comments.
So,
um,
uh,
Mr. Eddie Wong on twitter and instagram
as well.
Same thing.
Same thing man.
Thank you brother.
Thanks for putting this together.
I really appreciate it.
It's very important when people talk
about this stuff.
Thank you Jessica for being here.
Appreciate it.
And thank you everybody for listening.
All right,
thanks Joe.